<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 18:48:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HBO, Which Was Always HBO, Is HBO Again]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/hbo-max-warner</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hbo-which-was-always-hbo-is-hbo-again.1189392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/hbo-max-warner<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Today, Warner Bros Discovery <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/max-changes-name-hbo-max-1236397399/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> that it’s changing the name of its streaming service, Max, back to HBO Max. You might think it already had “HBO” in the name, because it is HBO, except Warner Bros has gone through a multi-year debate over the extent to which the thing it owns, HBO, is actually HBO, only to land us here on, yeah no, it’s HBO.</p><p>Come with me on a journey: in 2010 HBO launched its streamer HBO Go, which was available to HBO subscribers. In 2015 the company launched <a href="https://time.com/3774026/hbo-now-launches-game-of-thrones/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">HBO Now</a>, a different streamer that could be paid for without an HBO subscription. In 2020, both of these got subsumed into <a href="https://variety.com/2020/digital/news/hbo-max-launch-date-price-streaming-1234585776/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">HBO Max</a>. In 2023, Warner <a href="https://variety.com/2023/digital/news/hbo-max-renamed-max-pricing-launch-date-1235532179/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">changed the name of HBO Max to just Max</a>, which necessitated the <a href="https://x.com/StreamOnMax/status/1662202418963070977?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tagline</a> “the one to watch for HBO,” a fact previously conveyed by having the word “HBO” in the name. More confusingly, sometimes the company just <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X6yoTKa58Qw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">called</a> it “the one to watch,” while other times it used <a href="https://www.facebook.com/streamonmax/videos/154883714124231/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">both taglines</a> in the same breath.</p><p>But now, in 2025, Max is HBO Max again. The announcement is and isn’t a surprise; at the end of March, Max <a href="https://variety.com/2025/digital/news/max-changes-logo-black-and-white-hbo-1236352161/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">changed its logo</a> to a black and white palette evocative of the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/rcmacleod.bsky.social/post/3lihxb2kg4s2f" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">original HBO colors</a>. As quoted by <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/max-changes-name-hbo-max-1236397399/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Variety</a>, WB CEO David Zaslav said of today's name change, “Today, we are bringing back HBO, the brand that represents the highest quality in media,” despite a two-year hand-wringing over that very idea.&nbsp;</p><p>CEO of streaming and games <a href="https://aftermath.site/wb-earnings-zaslav" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">JB Perrette</a> said, “We will continue to focus on what makes us unique — not everything for everyone in a household, but something distinct and great for adults and families.” This statement comes despite Zaslav saying of the <a href="https://variety.com/2023/digital/news/why-did-hbo-max-become-max-rebranding-1235626295/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">original name change</a> that Max would let “every member of the household… see whatever they want at any given time.” Perrette also said that today’s change is “really not subjective, not even controversial — our programming just hits different,” but did not clarify who was finding calling HBO “HBO” controversial, or exactly what his definition of "subjective" is. </p><p>On Twitter, the <a href="https://x.com/StreamOnMax" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Max account</a> (which as of this writing has not changed its profile pic or user name to include "HBO") is having a field day with this whole thing, <a href="https://x.com/StreamOnMax/status/1922675183422259438" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">quote-tweeting dunks</a>, making <a href="https://x.com/StreamOnMax/status/1922662280367333410" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pope</a> and <a href="https://x.com/StreamOnMax/status/1922665329332748347" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Spider-man</a> memes, and getting <a href="https://x.com/StreamOnMax/status/1922670003460944055" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">self-referential</a> about the audience response. While this entire situation is an exercise in absurdity, an official brand account getting in on it reads less like good fun and more like a marketing department desperately flailing to make sense of something that cannot be made to make sense.</p><p>Honestly, I sort of admire that Zaslav and Perrette can get up in front of people and cast this whole thing as a brave new direction instead of a symptom of their complete <a href="https://aftermath.site/how-stupid-do-they-think-we-are" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">inability</a> to understand the value of their own product, a brand of confidence those of us with self-awareness do not possess. They do not know what makes the streamer “the one to watch” or even whether or not people should be watching HBO on it. (2023: no. 2025: yes.) They are not wrong that Max has (had?) more than just HBO on it, but their strategy for how to signal that was to… pretend it <em>didn’t</em> have HBO on it, only to walk back that decision by suddenly discovering that it seems like people want to pay for HBO’s streamer so they can watch HBO. I have long given up on wanting execs to actually care about their own products, but to watch these people so thoroughly and energetically fumble the bag by nitpicking over a name like an on-the-rocks couple getting a new dog is such a public humiliation that I’d almost feel bad for them if they weren’t systematically destroying <a href="https://aftermath.site/coyote-vs-acme-fuck-david-zaslav" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">everything</a> <a href="https://aftermath.site/rooster-teeth-shut-down-warner-brothers" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in</a> <a href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-warner-bros-monolith-wonder-woman" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">their</a> <a href="https://aftermath.site/warner-bros-discovery-games-wonder-woman-monolith-shut-down" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">path</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Anyway, it’s 2025 and I guess you can watch HBO on HBO again, a thing you’ve been doing since <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_HBO" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">1972</a>.&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/sour-patch-kids-flavor-rankings"><h3>Sour Patch Kids, Ranked</h3></a><p>An objectively correct ranking of Sour Patch Kids and various Sour Patch Kids-flavored things</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/thunderbolts-marvel-avengers-cube-escape-room"><h3>Thunderbolts* Could Have Been Marvel’s Cube</h3></a><p>It could have been an escape room movie starring Florence Pugh, but we got New Avengers instead

</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/hag-capisco-office-chair-ergonomic-review-sit-weird"><h3>The HÅG Capisco Is A Great Chair For People Who Sit Weird</h3></a><p>The HÅG Capisco 8106 is an icon, but what you do in it almost isn't sitting.</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sour Patch Kids, Ranked]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/sour-patch-kids-flavor-rankings</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sour-patch-kids-ranked.1189278/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/sour-patch-kids-flavor-rankings<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Three years ago, Sonic (the drive-in fast food restaurant, not the blue hedgehog) started selling Sour Patch Kids ice cream floats — a sour watermelon-flavored slushie, soft serve vanilla ice cream, and sprinkles of chopped up Sour Patch Kids on top. Sonic itself sucks, but the Sour Patch Kids float is perfect. I’ve been chasing the pure happiness I felt after my first sip for years.&nbsp;</p><p>I’ve loved Sour Patch Kids for a long time, but the float kicked that into overdrive. I actively started seeking out new varieties and flavored items, something to fill the hole the Sour Patch Kids float left in my heart. The bad news is that nothing has ever come close. The good news is that I still got to eat a lot of Sour Patch Kids. Most are good. Some were awful.</p><p>Through years of research, this is where I’ve landed:</p><ol><li><span>Sonic’s Sour Patch Kids ice cream float</span></li><li><span>Lemonade Fest</span></li><li><span>Original Sour Patch Kids (from the Mexico factory, which I think are denser and more delicious)</span></li><li><span>Ghost’s Sour Patch Kids electrolyte powder</span></li><li><span>Peach&nbsp;</span></li><li><span>Heads (the heads are a different flavor from the body)</span></li><li><span>Watermelon</span></li><li><span>Sour Patch Kids Glow Ups (they have glow in the dark confetti and are strawberry watermelon flavored)</span></li><li><span>Trident’s Sour Patch Kids gum</span></li><li><span>Big Sour Patch Kids</span></li><li><span>Strawberry&nbsp;</span></li><li><span>Grape&nbsp;</span></li><li><span>Apple&nbsp;</span></li><li><span>Tropical&nbsp;</span></li><li><span>Sour Patch Kids Oreos</span></li><li><span>Cola&nbsp;</span></li><li><span>Original Sour Patch Kids (when they are too soft)</span></li></ol><p>And if we’re ranking the original flavors:</p><ol><li><span>Red Raspberry</span></li><li><span>Blue Raspberry</span></li><li><span>Lemon</span></li><li><span>Lime</span></li><li><span>Orange</span></li></ol><p>I’m also convinced that Sour Patch Kids quality varies heavily depending on where the candy is made. I have not done the research to determine which factory I like the best, but Sour Patch Kids can be downright awful or life-changing. Mexico <em>typically</em> has the best texture; bonus points if they’re a little stale. There are a bunch of varieties of the candies that I haven’t tried yet, but one tormets me: Sour Patch Kids Gamerz. I can’t really tell if the flavors are different, but they are gamer-shaped and, unfortunately, only available in Australia.</p><p>The last thing is that a new sour candy has actually overtaken Sour Patch Kids as my number one: the AirHeads Xtremes Rainbow Berry Sour Belts. Please note, though, that the AirHeads Xtremes Rainbow Berry Sour <em>Bites</em> are absolute trash.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/hbo-max-warner"><h3>HBO, Which Was Always HBO, Is HBO Again</h3></a><p>If I owned HBO I would just tell everyone I owned HBO, but I guess I'm built different</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/thunderbolts-marvel-avengers-cube-escape-room"><h3>Thunderbolts* Could Have Been Marvel’s Cube</h3></a><p>It could have been an escape room movie starring Florence Pugh, but we got New Avengers instead

</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/hag-capisco-office-chair-ergonomic-review-sit-weird"><h3>The HÅG Capisco Is A Great Chair For People Who Sit Weird</h3></a><p>The HÅG Capisco 8106 is an icon, but what you do in it almost isn't sitting.</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>