<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 07:59:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Salute To The 13%]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/godot-version-control-statistics-cms</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-salute-to-the-13.1243659/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Godot is a game engine that is both free and open source, meaning it's a great option for budding, first-time developers. The kind of people who, thanks to their youth and/or inexperience, may not have learned things the hard way.</p><p>By that I mean look at this statistic:</p><p>I've seen a lot of developers respond to this with either some form of "oof" or some shade of "by <em>God</em>, what are you <em>doing</em>?", and I understand the sentiment. Not using<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Version_control" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> version control</a> is akin to writing up a Word doc without autosave turned on, only <em>worse, </em>because you risk losing so much more work<em>. </em>It opens these projects up to the possibility of absolute catastrophe.</p><p>And yet...I do not want to admonish these 19.1% of people. Particularly the 13% who know what version control means and refuse to engage in the practice anyway. Rather than view this 13% as reckless, I want to salute their bravery.</p><p>See, I've spent my entire career writing in the CMS (Content Management System), which is the media's equivalent. That means I open up the platform we publish stories on--in Aftermath's case as of July 2025, a modified version of Wordpress--and write all my stories straight into it. No Notes app, no Google Docs, no Word–I write drafts and outlines straight into the CMS, edit it from there then eventually hit publish.</p><p>Writers often gasp at this as audibly as game developers have at that 19.1% of respondents to that survey, because it's risky. CMS autosave functionality is questionable at best, there are no grammar checkups, it makes it harder to share and edit your work; when it comes to reasons not to do it, the list goes on forever.</p><p>But I don't care. The cowardly shall not see heaven. If this is the platform I publish my writing on then I want to be able to tailor it to that platform--its length, its appearance, everything--from the very beginning of my writing, and if that's dicey behaviour then so be it. Let me live a little.</p><p>Same goes for this 13%! Modern life is so full of handrails and automation and supervision and authority over our platforms and actions that who are we to look at their position and assume they're in line to learn a lesson. Maybe they know what they're doing is bad and <em>do it anyway</em>, because the danger of losing their work is a slow-burning thrill, one of the few avenues left where they can exercise any kind of control over their lives on the internet.</p><p>Or maybe they're just idiots. They can, like me, be both at the same time.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/horror-anime-crunchyroll-netflix-hikaru-takopi"><h3>Your Guide To Feel-Bad-Anime Summer</h3></a><p>The Summer Hikaru Died and Takopi’s Original Sin are a throwback to the disturbing, horrifying anime of yesteryear</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/high-wheel-bike-race-frederick"><h3>The Penny Farthing Is Alive And Well In 2025</h3></a><p>The National Clustered Spires High Wheel Race takes place every summer in Frederick, Maryland</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-disability-pride-last-of-us-forza"><h3>Why Disability Journalism In Games Needs To Evolve Beyond Marketing</h3></a><p>"We’ve conditioned ourselves to believe that we’re all one big happy family"</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/godot-version-control-statistics-cms]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Your Guide To Feel-Bad-Anime Summer]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/horror-anime-crunchyroll-netflix-hikaru-takopi</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/your-guide-to-feel-bad-anime-summer.1243479/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The <a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/season" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">summer 2025 anime lineup</a> is an embarrassment of riches. While many of its catalog is top-heavy with big marquee shonen series like <a href="https://gizmodo.com/dan-da-dan-is-a-lovey-dovey-madcap-sci-fi-anime-drama-about-finding-your-balls-2000540322" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Dan Da Dan</em></a>, <a href="https://gizmodo.com/gachiakuta-doesnt-just-redefine-shonen-anime-it-anoints-itself-as-the-next-big-thing-2000622249" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Gachiakuta</em></a>, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sakamoto-days-premiere-review-netflix" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Sakamoto Days</em></a>, and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kaiju-no-8-season-1-review" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Kaiju No. 8</em></a>, what impresses me most about this new lineup is how my basket of cherry-picked, must-watch shows feels heavier than it has in previous years. Two series that I’ve become utterly captivated by are <a href="https://www.crunchyroll.com/series/GKEH2G0X4/takopis-original-sin?srsltid=AfmBOoqAal1Qp8aY0Fde1aSXQJLF8Ar56UNHq8NjM-ih_K30abgK-f_y" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Takopi’s Original Sin</em></a> and <a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/81948057" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The</em> <em>Summer Hikaru Died</em> </a>because they evoke the fleeting, nihilistic, and disturbing vibes of compelling anime from the aughts.</p><p>When I say these two anime evoke a vibe of disturbing anime from yesteryear, I mean the kind of fatalistic, dark anime that doesn’t seem to be made anymore: your <em>Higurashi</em> (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=escc512WoDw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>When</em> <em>They</em> <em>Cry</em></a>) or <em>Assassination Classroom</em>. Despite being on opposite ends of the spectrum—one being oppressively bleak and the other an absurdist riot—both anime feature big ideas wrapped in cutesy packaging with an unsettling, violent thematic throughline that would <a href="https://kotaku.com/assassination-classroom-censor-manga-shooting-florida-1850334204" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">get them banned in schools</a>. These shows were iconic at the time and still stand out in retrospect because they are so visceral. The same is true for <em>The Summer Hikaru Died</em> and <em>Takopi’s Original Sin</em>, which, despite their source material being from 2021, feel so deeply connected to a more daring era of anime history that they surpass the rest of the summer 2025 shows as nostalgic, novel, and refreshingly dark takes on horror.</p><p>Let’s start with Crunchyroll’s six-episode limited series, <em>Takopi’s Original Sin</em>.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="アニメ『タコピーの原罪』ノンクレジットOP映像｜ano「ハッピーラッキーチャッピー」" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ciFvLHCThdg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Created by <a href="https://myanimelist.net/people/56101/Taizan_5" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Taizan 5</em></a> and animated by <a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/producer/1991/Enishiya" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">studio Enishiya</a>, <em>Takopi’s</em> <em>Original Sin</em> is a blend of the normal, human cruelty of <em>Higurashi</em> with the zany mascot of <em>Assassination Classroom.</em> The series follows Takopi, an alien on Earth on a mission to spread happiness. He’s from a planet called Happy Planet and has various "Happy Tools"—magical-girl-style items like a Happy Camera that resets its subjects to the moment a photo was taken, a Reconciliation Ribbon, a red string of fate meant to make people friends instantly, and a Transformation Palette that allows Takopi to impersonate others. Takopi ends up meeting Shizuka, a lonely fourth grader. After befriending Shizuka, Takopi takes on a <em>Smiling Friends</em> mission to improve her life. The series also contains viewer advisories for suicide helpline links, adult themes, profanity, and violence, which it earns.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Takopi’s Original Sin | OFFICIAL TRAILER" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j7dxZjwIhu0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Typically, overly cutesy shows like <em>Takopi </em>is a warning sign that <em>Takopi </em>might be an evil agent meant to worsen Shizuka’s life, similar to <a href="https://kotaku.com/madoka-magica-beginnings-may-be-better-than-the-series-5950073" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Puella Magi Madoka Magica</em></a>. While Takopi is indeed an unreliable narrator with a bubbly, naive view of Shizuka’s intense bullying by classmate Marina Kirarazaka, Takopi ends up acting like a desperate visual novel player trying to save a doomed protagonist from a bad ending. Watching Takopi’s pure optimism corrupted by Shizuka and Marina’s respective perils can’t be solved by a wave of a magic wand, in tandem with the extraterrestrial ball of hope getting ground down by how Shizuka willfully rejects the idea that an eye for an eye isn’t a viable solution, is wildly captivating to watch. Like <em>Madoka Magica</em>, <em>Takopi </em>is a deconstruction of the magical girl anime trope that situates its instigator on the back foot as he realizes that magic can’t fix a <em>Higurashi</em>-coded visual novel tragedy. You start feeling for the little chibi guy whenever disaster strikes, and, instead of being met with admonishment for his misplaced meddling, he’s flashed with a glittery smile as Shizuka enlists Takopi to <em>Weekend at Bernie's</em> folks that’ve made her life a living hell.&nbsp;</p><p>Now let’s dive into Netflix’s adaptation of <em>The Summer Hikaru Died</em>.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="「光が死んだ夏」ノンクレジットオープニング「再会」Vaundy：The Summer Hikaru Died Opening" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UP7la6a1H1g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>While <a href="https://aftermath.site/dandadan-anime-science-saru-netflix" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Dan Da Dan</em></a> explores horror, <em>The Summer Hikaru Died</em> is an anime series deeply immersed in the macabre. Additionally, it's a boys' love story crackling with sensual, creepy energy that both arouses and disgusts equally. Created by <a href="https://www.animenewsnetwork.com/interview/2024-07-24/small-town-horror-with-the-summer-hikaru-died-creator-mokumokuren/.211571" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mangaka Mokumokuren</a> and animated by <a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/producer/1893/CygamesPictures" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Cyangames Pictures</a> (famous for <a href="https://aftermath.site/uma-musume-gacha-horse-racing-anime" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Uma Musume</em></a>), <em>The Summer Hikaru Died</em> is set in a familiar horror setting: a quiet rural village in the mountains. The series follows Yoshiki, a high school student mourning his childhood friend Hikaru, who mysteriously died in the mountains. However, as the title hints, Hikaru isn’t actually dead and a mysterious, menacing entity has taken root beneath his friend's skin.&nbsp;</p><p>Hikaru wises up to the facade early in the show’s first episode, but what happens next is much more interesting than if the show had gone with a traditional body-snatching mystery like<em> The Thing</em>. “Hikaru,” now a mixture of memories and affection fermenting inside his host, doesn’t just ask to keep pretending to be human; he asks Yoshiki’s permission to keep living as his best friend. To Yoshiki’s horror, he agrees—and opens the door to his small town’s occult mysteries.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Aside from <em>The Summer Hikaru Died</em>’s impressive feature film-quality animation and composition, one of the most remarkable aspects of the anime is its clear queer narrative between its leads. While people are sure to debate online over whether they’re “just friends” who explicitly say they love each other, supporters of this view can argue with their mommas because The Summer Hikaru Died being “yaoi-coded” doesn’t start to describe it accurately.&nbsp;</p><p>Deadass, there’s a scene in its second episode, “Suspicion,” where “Hikaru” asks Yoshiki to reach into his chest cavity to learn first-hand how he dispensed of a yokai that was stalking him. This leads to an overtly sensual and disturbing scene where the former shudders, muttering shit like “Yeah, that’s the spot!” prompting Yoshiki to ask “This feels good?” and “Hikaru” responding, saying “Feels just like a good pat on the head. Nobody’s ever touched me here before” between moans.&nbsp;</p><p>While “Hikaru” protests to Yoshiki (who visibly enjoyed their chest fingering despite how scary it was) for wiping his hand off on his shirt, Yoshiki blushes and looks away after “Hikaru” tells him to get a good look at his abs. The scene is hilariously capped off by Yoshiki describing his tactile chest fingering, describing it like a touching marinated chicken. A remark the anime capitalizes on with a frame of marinated chicken (<a href="https://x.com/tsuchi31478044/status/1944085827648176493" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">which the staff later enjoyed as karage</a>).&nbsp;</p><p>While other horror works like <a href="https://gizmodo.com/uzumaki-anime-review-adult-swim-junji-ito-production-ig-2000501288" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Junji Ito’s manga</a> set the gold standard for stomach-churning horror, <a href="https://gizmodo.com/uzumaki-anime-bad-animation-episode-2-jason-demarco-2000509050" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">their anime adaptations often lose their edge</a>. However, anime like <em>Takopi’s Original Sin</em> and <em>The Summer Hikaru Died</em> go beyond those shortcomings. They’re darker, sharper, and messier in ways that feel more authentic to emotional horror, resisting genre polish and pushing boundaries with every frame. They focus less on jump scares and more on existential decay, replacing loud panic with quiet unraveling. These qualities don’t just honor a past era of anime; they make them stand out amid today’s streaming riches and serve as exciting reminders of the wonder anime can still create.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/high-wheel-bike-race-frederick"><h3>The Penny Farthing Is Alive And Well In 2025</h3></a><p>The National Clustered Spires High Wheel Race takes place every summer in Frederick, Maryland</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/uma-musume-gacha-horse-racing-anime"><h3>Pretty Girl Horse Racing Game ‘Uma Musume’ Is Engrossing And Weird As Hell</h3></a><p>Breed horse girls to create even better horse girls, so that they can achieve their dream of winning races and performing a concert literally right after</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/outlier-best-mens-pants-indestructible-pants"><h3>All My Pants Are From Outlier Because They Appear To Live Forever</h3></a><p>Outlier makes pants that will survive the abuse of several presidential administrations.</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/horror-anime-crunchyroll-netflix-hikaru-takopi]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>