<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 12:13:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MindsEye Fuckin’ Sucks, Man]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/mindseye-rocket-boy-impressions-review-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mindseye-fuckin%E2%80%99-sucks-man.1217382/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/mindseye-rocket-boy-impressions-review-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Because I'm<a href="https://aftermath.site/summer-game-fest-e3-gamescom-2024" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> now a normal person who reads about video game news much the same way most of you do</a>, did you know the first I even heard about the video game <em>MindsEye </em>was only a few days ago,<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mindseye-boss-claims-games-negative-reaction-ahead-of-release-has-been-paid-for-in-concerted-effort-against-studio" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> when I read that its creators had blamed negative pre-launch coverage on paid shills</a>? What an introduction!</p><p>Given how volatile the video game community is these days, and how easily vital parts of it (reviews, social media, etc) can be weaponised against developers, I felt a pang of sympathy for the team. We've all seen how chuds can bury a game without having even played it, and this sure sounded like another example of that happening.</p><p>WRONG. This game sucks, and everything bad that anyone has ever written about it, for free or otherwise, is true.</p><p>I've tried playing the game over the last few days and have hated every second I've spent with it. I can see the outline of what was attempted here--a cyberpunk <em>GTA </em>clone, something like <em>Watch Dogs</em> meets <em>2077</em>--but what's actually here is a buggy mess of a game that looks bland, is boring to play and perhaps worst of all seems to have treated its story and dialogue with open contempt.</p><p>Given <em>MindsEye</em>'s developer is led by<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leslie_Benzies" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> prominent ex-Rockstar man Leslie Benzies</a>, the <em>GTA </em>similarities are to be expected, but like...just watch this, the first real mission you have to undertake. It does everything a <em>GTA </em>game would do, in that it gives you a car, tells you to drive somewhere to shoot some bad guys then fills the downtime with dialogue, but every single aspect of it here is just <em>dreadful</em>, from the pathfinding (look how long it takes you to get to the car!) to the stilted delivery of some meaningless lines to the limp, wet gunplay.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="MindsEye – First Hour Gameplay - No Commentary Walkthrough Part 1" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r2OGYUSIec8?start=2694&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>I cannot <em>believe</em> how bad the writing and voice acting is in this game. Actually, let me be fair: I don't know if it's the acting itself, or just the way it's all been recorded and delivered in two-line packages, seemingly in isolation, meaning nothing ever sounds like it’s part of a natural, human conversation. I was only 20 minutes into this game before it started testing my patience; by the two-hour mark I was ready to mute it and just put subtitles on.</p><p>It’s like a <em>GTA</em> clone that was delivered by ticking boxes--cars, check; guns, check; cover system, check--without ever bothering to make sure if any of those boxes were any <em>good</em>. It looks like a parody Game Awards trailer. It plays like a cancelled PS4 game.</p><p>It's so bad that streamers<a href="https://www.polygon.com/news/606496/mindseye-twitch-youtube-stream-cancel-glitches" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> are having their sponsored streams cancelled</a>. It's so bad that<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/wheres-our-mindseye-review" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> seemingly no major outlets were sent review code ahead of time</a>. There are so many bugs and glitches that<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MindsEye/comments/1l8nl48/playstation_support_have_refunded_the_game_with/?share_id=3_-brSh2YLe4KNeaeC79I&amp;utm_content=2&amp;utm_medium=android_app&amp;utm_name=androidcss&amp;utm_source=share&amp;utm_term=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Sony is reportedly offering at least this person a refund on technical grounds</a>, something it has only really done previously with <em>Cyberpunk</em>.</p><p>Some of this can be chalked up to it being <em>really hard</em> to make a good open-world game, which is why the few studios who <em>can</em> do it get paid so much and can sell so many copies. Some of it can maybe be chalked up to the fact that developers Rocket Boy<a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/former-rockstar-north-boss-nets-110m-to-launch-what-sounds-a-lot-like-a-metaverse" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> originally had plans for <em>MindsEye </em>to be part of a big metaverse grift</a>, which might explain the presence of an odd and seemingly useless creation suite within the game.</p><figure></figure><p>Whatever the reasons, and whatever the original intent, this is a very bad video game that's bad in such fundamental ways I don't know if it can ever be fixed with a patch or two. It's buggy, sure, but it's also so drab and uninteresting and by-the-numbers that it just bums me out.&nbsp;<br></p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/disney-universal-midjourney-ai-lawsuit-case-copyright"><h3>Disney’s Big AI Lawsuit Includes Some Very Damning Images</h3></a><p>Disney isn't the only one calling Midjourney a 'bottomless pit of plagiarism'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/dragon-age-the-veilguard-electronic-arts-sales-layoffs"><h3>Good Day To Everyone Except The Senior Management At Electronic Arts</h3></a><p>'The team was asked to change the game’s fundamental structure and recast the entire story on the fly'</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>