<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 10:43:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We Should Treasure Every Game That Still Gets A Nice, Physical Re-Release]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/physical-boxed-game-release-indie-lost-in-cult</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/we-should-treasure-every-game-that-still-gets-a-nice-physical-re-release.1194717/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/physical-boxed-game-release-indie-lost-in-cult<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>As the video game industry continues to move towards an all-digital future, and as people have started learning what that <em>means</em>--we are trading ownership for convenience--it feels like there's a growing awareness that, whether it be in the name of preservation or just being able to say you own something, maybe we should keep buying physical copies of video games after all.</p><p>While this includes just buying a disc from your local retailer, companies like<a href="https://limitedrungames.com/?srsltid=AfmBOoor2lMrpkHzYDxJtUz-hhtuWvaoFtNiAFJaRPWO3vX-u8xAOUOL" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Limited Run</a> have seen a space in the market for this growing appetite and begun offering <em>proper </em>boxed game experiences. Now<a href="https://www.lostincult.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Lost In Cult</a>, a company better known for its lovely books and magazines, have too.</p><p>I'm writing about this not because it's something we got in a press release--we get a <em>lot </em>of that, even though this is very much not a website that does that stuff!--but because I think this is genuinely a very cool thing, as not only are they going overboard in terms of the packaging, but they also have a very cool philosophy behind re-releasing games in a box in 2025.</p><figure><figcaption>I already own this game but I will absolutely buy it again just so I can properly <em>own </em>it</figcaption></figure><p>Lost In Cult say that every game that they release--and the initial run includes <em>Immortality</em>, <em>The Excavation Of Hob's Barrow</em> and<a href="https://aftermath.site/luke-plunkett-aftermath-game-of-the-year-2024" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> the wonderful <em>Thank Goodness You're Here</em></a>--is being run by DoesItPlay?, "a group that tests physical releases to determine their playability for the future", and that all the material they're creating, from posters to booklets, is being shared with "multiple museums and archive groups".</p><p>I dig it! You can read more about the release schedule and specifics of each game <a href="https://www.lostincult.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at their site</a>.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/going-rogue-galactic-andor-star-wars-rogue-one-tabletop"><h3>Tabletop Game Going Rogue Puts The Revolution Back In Star Wars</h3></a><p>Jess Levine, designer of Going Rogue, talks political organizing and taking the Disney out of Star Wars</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/web3-nft-crypto-game-fail-close-scam-snake-oil"><h3>Oh No, Anyway</h3></a><p>'What went wrong?'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/fortnite-ai-darth-vader-star-wars-epic-games-sag-aftra"><h3>Fortnite’s AI Darth Vader Has, Predictably, Been A Comedy Of Errors</h3></a><p>Swears, slurs, and an unfair labor practice – all in just a few days</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/wind-breaker-shonen-anime-toxic-masculinity"><h3>This Shonen Anime Fights Toxic Masculinity</h3></a><p>Wind Breaker is a shonen anime where teenage boys talk about their feelings while punching toxic masculinity in the face.</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My Watch Has Ended: Fortnite Is Back On The App Store]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/fortnite-app-store-return</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/my-watch-has-ended-fortnite-is-back-on-the-app-store.1194714/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/fortnite-app-store-return<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>After five years, <em>Fortnite</em> returned to the Apple App Store today. As someone who woke up one morning in August 2020 and tossed up a <a href="https://kotaku.com/apple-removes-fortnite-from-app-store-1844717397" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">quick blog</a> about Epic introducing its own payment system on mobile, a niche news hit that quickly spiralled into multiple high-profile court battles between massive companies that dragged on for years, I don't know what I'm going to do with myself now.</p><p>The <a href="https://x.com/Fortnite/status/1924949632628523199" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Fortnite</em> Twitter account </a>announced the news this evening, linking to the game on the App Store. As of this writing, I couldn't find it when I searched "Fortnite," but I was able to find it by searching for Epic Games.</p><p>The game's return follows a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/659246/apple-epic-app-store-judge-ruling-control" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ruling</a> at the end of April that Apple was disobeying the orders from the 2021 ruling in the case by <a href="https://aftermath.site/apples-new-app-store-policy-is-petty-as-hell" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">taking a large commission</a> from purchases outside the App Store and overly restricting how developers could point users to alternate payment systems. Following the April ruling, Epic <a href="https://x.com/Fortnite/status/1920878504284975585" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">submitted</a> <em>Fortnite</em> to the App Store once again, then <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-pulls-resubmits-fortnites-us-app-store-request-after-not-hearing-back-from-apple-all-week" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">withdrew and resubmitted it</a> when Apple didn't reply to the request. Yesterday, the judge basically <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/19/apple-fortnite-epic-games.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ordered Apple to figure it out</a>, and now here we are. In the meantime, <em>Fortnite</em> has been playable on <a href="https://aftermath.site/fortnite-phones-eu" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">some mobile devices</a> in the US and in the EU on Epic's own mobile storefront, though none of this has been as widespread or as seamless as the App Store.</p><p>To make myself the protagonist of this news story: It's kind of a big moment for me. That very first blog led me into my first foray into reading court documents, and I followed every update of the case for months, spending my weekends tediously reading through filings and looking up every legal phrase I didn't know. When one of the earliest rulings came down, I actually had a nightmare that I'd missed it, only to wake up in the middle of the night and realize I <em>had</em> missed it. The day the <a href="https://kotaku.com/everything-thats-happening-in-the-apple-vs-epic-case-1846856678" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trial</a> started I was at New York's Javits Center, listening to the <a href="https://gizmodo.com/the-epic-vs-apple-hearing-is-already-a-disaster-1846811839?_gl=1*ptlplv*_ga*NTc0Nzc5NjU1LjE3NDM3OTkzOTY.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NDc3ODA5MzgkbzYzJGcxJHQxNzQ3NzgyNjczJGoyMiRsMCRoMCRkY1EtUlFvM1VFcmEyYzRPTWtvNWRzNExseWpnVjkyNzk4Zw.." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">disastrous call-in line</a> while waiting to get my first covid shot. By the time the judge decided the case I had left Kotaku, and I found myself frantically posting my way through the court documents on social media while visiting my parents. When they asked what I was doing, I said "working," and they politely reminded me that... no I wasn't, because I didn't have a job, which was one of the first moments my departure from Kotaku really sunk in. I feel like I grew alongside this case as a journalist, while I probably devolved a little as a person, boring anyone who would listen with why, yeah it's that game with all the dances, but <em>listen</em>, Epic's arguments are actually kind of a <a href="https://aftermath.site/epic-google-app-store-ruling" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">big deal</a> if you care about tech monopolies.</p><p>And now here we are. I don't know what I'll do with all my freed-up brain space, or all the time I'll get back now that I won't feel pressured to constantly keep tabs on Tim Sweeney's Twitter. Apple <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/661032/apple-epic-games-app-store-antitrust-ninth-circuit" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">appealed</a> the April ruling, so we'll see if this is really the end, but fittingly, writing this blog has made me late to meet some friends, whom I will absolutely bore to tears with this latest update, and who will humor me politely while wishing I would stop talking about this.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/going-rogue-galactic-andor-star-wars-rogue-one-tabletop"><h3>Tabletop Game Going Rogue Puts The Revolution Back In Star Wars</h3></a><p>Jess Levine, designer of Going Rogue, talks political organizing and taking the Disney out of Star Wars</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/web3-nft-crypto-game-fail-close-scam-snake-oil"><h3>Oh No, Anyway</h3></a><p>'What went wrong?'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/fortnite-ai-darth-vader-star-wars-epic-games-sag-aftra"><h3>Fortnite’s AI Darth Vader Has, Predictably, Been A Comedy Of Errors</h3></a><p>Swears, slurs, and an unfair labor practice – all in just a few days</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/wind-breaker-shonen-anime-toxic-masculinity"><h3>This Shonen Anime Fights Toxic Masculinity</h3></a><p>Wind Breaker is a shonen anime where teenage boys talk about their feelings while punching toxic masculinity in the face.</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>