<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 03:36:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More Sports Games Should Take A Year Off]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/football-manager-26-fm26-sports-interactive-womens-league-wsl-nwsl</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/more-sports-games-should-take-a-year-off.1289400/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Last year<a href="https://aftermath.site/ea-fc-madden-nba-2k-recycled-dogshit" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> I wrote about a general malaise in the sports gaming world</a>, brought about mostly by the fact that the relentless need to release a new game every year--colliding with the ever-increasing budgets and complexity of AAA gaming--was draining the genre of innovation and chances at fresh starts.</p><p>Today, let's talk about something more positive! A rare exception to the annual grind last season was the storied <em>Football Manager</em> series, which botched its transition to an all-new engine--and a number of gameplay and interface changes that went along with it--<a href="https://aftermath.site/football-manager-25-cancelled" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">so badly that it had to miss its scheduled 2025 edition altogether</a>.</p><p>What was initially some pretty bad news has, in the end, turned into something of a blessing for the series and its fans. With the chance to actually take a breath, developers Sports Interactive have (among loads of other tweaks and revisions) been able to deliver on a long-promised feature and bring women's leagues to the game, at a scale that makes it almost a game-within-a-game.</p><p>In<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/athletic/6564634/2025/08/29/miles-jacobson-football-manager-interview-fm25-fm26/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> an interview with <em>The Athletic</em></a>, director Miles Jacobson says over 35000 women's footballers will now be in the game, with around a dozen major leagues also represented. Players will also be able to run both the men's and women's databases concurrently, meaning that while the option is there to play a men's or women's-only save, you can also manage sides across both at once.</p><p>If you're not a sports fan, this is an expected but nevertheless substantial update, as women's football has <em>exploded </em>in popularity over the past decade.<a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/mediacentre/2025/bbc-sport-record-breaking-womens-euro-2025-audience#:~:text=navbar%20(on%20mobile)-,Record%20breaking%20BBC%20Sport%20broadcast%20draws%202025's,audience%20for%20Women's%20Euro%20final&amp;text=A%20peak%20live%20audience%20of,2025%20across%20all%20TV%20broadcasters" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> The recent Euros' final broke broadcast records in England</a>, while the 2023 World Cup semi final is the<a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-australia-66531590" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> single highest-rating TV broadcast <em>of all time</em> in Australia</a>. So having it in <em>Football Manager</em> (when series like <em>FIFA/EAFC</em> have had it for <em>years</em>) is both long overdue but also, given the scale it’s finally arriving at, an extremely welcome addition.</p><p>Speaking of EA Sports, the interview also contains a fascinating insight into how the licensing for the women's leagues--sometimes a make-or-break factor for sports fans--have been worked around for their first inclusion in <em>Football Manager</em>. Jacobson says:</p><blockquote><p>...a massive thanks to EAFC, who have been really helpful throughout this whole process In most of the areas where they’ve had exclusive licences in women’s football, they’ve actually agreed to carve us out so that we can have licences as well. We can’t thank them enough.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>Huh! While there's no <em>exact</em> release date for <em>FM26</em>, the game is coming out this year, and should be ready sometime in the next few months (they've traditionally released around October-November).&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Football Manager 26 | First Look Reveal" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_cDQi5kwuHQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><figcaption>I cannot stress to you how much better this looks than the 2023 edition</figcaption></figure></div></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/civilization-7-civ-vii-layoffs-firaxis-2k-take-two"><h3>Seven Months After Civ VII’s Launch, Firaxis Workers Are Being Laid Off</h3></a><p>2K said the layoffs were part of an effort to increase "adaptability, collaboration, and creativity" at Firaxis, whatever that means</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/play-for-peace-bundle-palestine-aid-fundraiser"><h3>10 Months In The Making, Play For Peace Bundle Launches To Raise Money for Palestinian Aid</h3></a><p>‘It was important that our charity's proceeds directly went to Palestinian relief efforts’</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/32-9-long-handheld-amd-pc-steamdeck"><h3>Long Handheld</h3></a><p>ᗡ□□□□□□□□□□□□D</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/football-manager-26-fm26-sports-interactive-womens-league-wsl-nwsl]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>