<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 23:43:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RIP Discord, More Wolfenstein & Some Rockstar Bullshit: All The News From January 7-12]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/rip-discord-more-wolfenstein-some-rockstar-bullshit-all-the-news-from-january-7-12/</link>
            <guid>1404034</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">
      
    

<div data-post-info="">
      <p><span>Published:</span>
        <time datetime="2026-01-12T06:13:26">January 12, 2026, 6:13 pm</time>
      </p>
    </div>
    <article>
      <p>Welcome to Recap, a new, twice-weekly feature on Aftermath where we round up what’s been going on around video games, the internet and beyond.</p><p>🤔: Former Rockstar employees,<a href="https://aftermath.site/grand-theft-auto-6-rockstar-fired-workers-protest-nyc/"> <u>fired in the wake of unionisation efforts</u></a>, have lost their bid to remain on the company's payroll while their legal proceedings take place. A preliminary hearing was "unable to conclude that it appears likely that the tribunal will find that the principal reason for the claimants’ dismissal was their membership of the [union]".</p><figure><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2026-01-12/fired-rockstar-employees-denied-pay-by-uk-judge?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc2ODI0NzI2MywiZXhwIjoxNzY4ODUyMDYzLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJUOFJPOVVLSVVQU1owMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.27VI473B4UvIhmPh6eOoW2Crg7Pem9jtOtoGNX34Bco&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><div><p>Fired Rockstar Games’ Employees in UK Lose Bid to Restore Pay</p><p>The 31 staffers argued they were dismissed for unionizing. Rockstar said they were fired for leaking information in an online chat group.</p><p><span>Jason Schreier</span></p></div></a></figure><p><strong>Wolfenstein is (reportedly) back, baby:</strong><a href="https://aftermath.site/wolfenstein-new-order-colossus-machinegames/"> <u>Nine years after the last full and proper game in the series</u></a>, and with the United States now <em>actually </em>being run by overt fascists, developers MachineGames are reportedly returning to <em>Wolfenstein</em>.</p><figure><a href="https://kotaku.com/wolfenstein-3-in-development-machinegames-bethesda-2000657758?ref=aftermath.site"><div><p>Wolfenstein 3 Is In The Works From Developers MachineGames</p><p>The team who’s been behind the franchise since The New Order returns for the threequel</p><p><span>Kotaku</span><span>John Walker</span></p></div></a></figure><p><strong>Roblox Age Checks</strong>: After initially rolling the requirement out in regions like Australia and the UK, Roblox is getting ready to force <em>all </em>users wanting to chat on the platform to verify their age, after which they'll be lumped into a category (&lt;7, 9-12, 13-15, 15-17, 18-20, &amp; 21+) which will limit the ages of who they can talk to.</p><figure><a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/roblox-rolls-out-global-age-checks-for-any-user-wanting-to-use-its-chat-feature?ref=aftermath.site"><div><p>Roblox rolls out global age checks for any user wanting to use its chat feature</p><p>Further to the voluntary age checks rolled out to “limit communication between minors and adults” back in November, Rob…</p><p><span>GamesIndustry.biz</span><span>Vikki Blake</span></p></div></a></figure><p><strong>RIP Discord</strong>: It's been getting shittier for a while now, but news that Discord is about to go public is the surest sign yet that it's time to start bringing back forums.</p><figure><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2026-01-06/chat-platform-discord-is-said-to-file-confidentially-for-ipo?ref=aftermath.site"><div><p>Chat Platform Discord Files Confidentially for IPO</p><p>Discord Inc. filed confidentially for an initial public offering, according to people familiar with the matter, adding to a rapidly growing pipeline of venture capital-backed tech listings.</p><p><span>Bloomberg</span><span>Caroline Hyde</span></p></div></a></figure><p><strong>"Eight bucks is five bucks"</strong>: In an interview with Game File, <em>Peak </em>co-creator Nick Kaman has some funny/interesting ideas on game pricing. "Four bucks is also kind of five bucks. Three bucks is two bucks. And two bucks is basically free".</p><figure><a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/peak-interview?ref=aftermath.site"><div><p>Peak interview</p><p>“I just want to get the quote right. It’s by Sonic the Hedgehog.” An eye-opening conversation with one of the makers of one of 2025’s top video games.</p><p><span>Game File</span><span>Stephen Totilo</span></p></div></a></figure><p><strong>Cast it into the fire</strong>: There's <em>LEGO Pokemon</em> now. It's expensive, and looks like shit.</p><figure><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lego-pokemon-unveiled-but-catching-em-all-will-cost-you?ref=aftermath.site"><div><p>Lego Pokémon unveiled, but catching ’em all will cost you</p><p>Lego has lifted the lid on its previously announced Pokémon sets, which include Pikachu and Poké Ball, Venusaur, Charizard, Blastoise and Eevee.</p><p><span>Eurogamer.net</span><span>Victoria Phillips Kennedy</span></p></div></a></figure><p><strong>"There's just not enough supply to go around"</strong>: We all know memory prices are going through the roof courtesy of the collective, speculative madness over AI, but it still sucks to read the specifics of what's happening.</p><figure><a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/hardware/memory/micron-says-its-not-to-blame-for-its-high-memory-prices-theres-just-not-enough-supply-to-go-around/?ref=aftermath.site"><div><p>‘This is not a Micron issue, it’s an industry issue’ says Micron about memory prices</p><p>Everyone point at AI.</p><p><span>PC Gamer</span><span>Jacob Fox</span></p></div></a></figure>
    </article>

        

      

          

  
  
  
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/rip-discord-more-wolfenstein-some-rockstar-bullshit-all-the-news-from-january-7-12/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Luke's Favourite Video Games Of 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/game-of-the-year-2025-aftermath-luke-plunkett/</link>
            <guid>1403890</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
      <p>2025 was an odd year for me and my "best of" list. Many of the titles I thought would be absolute locks for this--like <em>Battlefield 6</em>, <em>Europa Universalis V</em>, <em>Civilization VII</em> and <em>Endless Legend 2</em>--ended up getting nowhere near it!</p><p><a href="https://aftermath.site/battlefield-6-campaign-singleplayer-review-impressions/"><u><em>Battlefield 6's</em> campaign was a disaster</u></a>, and I wasn't able to play the multiplayer at all thanks to a bug where the game told me my GPU wasn't physically connected (it, uh, was), so it's been a total write-off.<a href="https://aftermath.site/europa-universalis-v-review-impressions-paradox-pc-eu5/"> <u><em>EU V </em>was fine, but as I said at the time</u></a>, it's so ambitious, and needs so much more tweaking, that it feels like a game I won't sit down with properly for another year or two.<a href="https://aftermath.site/endless-legend-2-review-impressions-early-access/"> <u><em>Endless Legend 2</em> was just a good old-fashioned disappointment</u></a>, and<a href="https://aftermath.site/civilization-vii-review/"> <u><em>Civ VII</em>, whew, man</u></a>.</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/luke-plunkett-aftermath-game-of-the-year-2024/"><div><p>Luke’s Favourite Video Games Of 2024 - Aftermath</p><p>From archaeologists to Barnsworth, it was a good year</p><p><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><p>I know it's weird to lead a list of my games of the year by talking about games that weren't on it, but those disappointments defined my 2025 in a way, and seem to be mirroring many of the various crises the wider games industry itself has faced in 2025. Namely AAA bloat and strategic mismanagement leading to dependable sequels losing their way,<a href="https://aftermath.site/civilization-7-civ-vii-layoffs-firaxis-2k-take-two/"> <u>before the resulting layoffs</u></a> threaten to simply make everything even worse.</p><p>In a way, then, putting this list together felt like a slight bummer; I'd come into 2025 <em>really </em>excited for a bunch of seemingly dependable heavy-hitters, all of which ended up letting me down. Thankfully, <em>Civ VII</em> sucking simply freed up more time to play other stuff, like all the games on this list, most of which I'd never even heard of until I sat down with them, but all of which ruled on their own merits, and my year was better for having played them.</p><h3 id="flotsam">FLOTSAM</h3><figure></figure><p>A survival city-builder in broadly the same vein as stuff like <em>Frostpunk </em>and <em>Ixion</em>, Flotsam is a game set at the end of the world that, thanks to its vibrant art style and optimistic outlook, actually feels more like the start of a new world instead. </p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/flotsam-impressions-review-city-builder/"><div><p>Flotsam Builds Some Hope At World’s End</p><p>The end of the old world is a chance for a new one</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><h3 id="tavern-keeper">TAVERN KEEPER</h3><figure></figure><p>It's always fun running a pub, pubs are inherently great, but running a pub that's truly&nbsp;<em>yours</em>, right down to the designs on the cushions and the placement of the silverware, is even better.</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/tavern-keeper-review-impressions-pc-game/"><div><p>Tavern Keeper: It’s Good</p><p>“But the only brew for the brave and true...comes from the [Redacted]!”</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><h3 id="town-to-city">TOWN TO CITY</h3><figure></figure><p>It gives me the systems of a city-builder but the elegance of a town-painter, the challenge of juggling morale but letting you cheese your way to improving it by drowning your residents in dogs and fancy clothing stores. It's given me everything I love from this genre and tossed out everything I don't, then played some wonderfully soothing accordion music over the top, just for good measure.</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/town-to-city-pc-builder-cozy-impressions-review/"><div><p>I’ve Been Playing Town To City From Dawn To Dusk - Aftermath</p><p>*Accordion plays*</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><h3 id="the-king-is-watching">THE KING IS WATCHING</h3><figure></figure><p>Every game has this wonderful tension to it, where I always feel like I'm doing well enough to survive, but never like I've&nbsp;<em>perfected&nbsp;</em>my build, a constant pull between doing well enough to progress but always feeling like I could do, and learn,&nbsp;<em>more</em>.</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/the-king-is-watching-pc-steam-review-impressions/"><div><p>The King Is Watching: It’s A Very Good Video Game - Aftermath</p><p>‘There’s no wrong way to play this! But I can’t find a right way either’</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><h3 id="mafia-the-old-country">MAFIA: THE OLD COUNTRY</h3><figure></figure><p><em>The Old Country</em>&nbsp;is not a breakthrough in third-person action, or historical story-telling. It never needed to be. This is a good book on a rainy afternoon, the latest episode in a dependable, long-running soap opera, a ticket to the 117th&nbsp;<em>Mission Impossible</em>&nbsp;movie. It's fine, and sometimes fine is great.</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/mafia-old-country-review-impressions/"><div><p>Curling Up With A Sandwich, A Warm Drink And Mafia: The Old Country - Aftermath</p><p>‘I’m genuinely wistful for a good ‘ol 7/10, last-days-of -summer video game’</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><h3 id="the-drifter">THE DRIFTER</h3><figure></figure><p>Its story of grief, love, murder and monsters plays like you're clicking rapidly through a pulpy graphic novel, and nailing that Lucasarts energy is hard! Those games were magic, making this magic by association!</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/the-drifter-point-click-adventure-game-lucasarts-king-carpenter-australia/"><div><p>I Bloody Love The Drifter - Aftermath</p><p>A homage to Lucasarts, John Carpenter and so much more</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><h3 id="to-a-t">TO A T</h3><figure><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/E-QlrrC4vFk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" title="TO A T | Coming to PC, PS5 &amp; Xbox Series X|S May 28"></iframe></figure><p><em>To A T's</em>&nbsp;attention to details really helps ground you in both the place and your character, but more importantly, it centres you on their struggles as well. This is, without making a huge deal of it, a beautiful little tale about disability, a light-hearted way of putting the player in the shoes of someone who is doing their absolute best to live their day despite the constant obstacles (and sometimes even bullying!) in their way.</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/to-a-t-game-keita-takahashi-impressions-review/"><div><p>To A T Is A Video Game That Just Makes You Feel Good - Aftermath</p><p>Believe it or not, you’re the perfect shape</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><h3 id="9-kings">9 KINGS</h3><figure></figure><p>The creativity at your fingertips, the seemingly-endless possibilities for each run given the possible combinations, the extremely cool pixel art on the cards–<em>9 Kings</em>&nbsp;is&nbsp;<em>great</em>.</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/9-kings-pc-roguelike-deckbuilder-impressions-pc-steam/"><div><p>9 Kings: It’s A Good Video Game - Aftermath</p><p>Play some cards, slaughter some guys</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><h3 id="assassins-creed-shadows">ASSASSIN'S CREED SHADOWS</h3><figure></figure><p>Long-running series ebb and flow all the time, they have highlights and lowlights, and&nbsp;<em>Shadows</em>&nbsp;was never going to be some singular act of salvation. It's just a cool video game.</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-valhalla-origins-odyssey/"><div><p>(Assassin’s Creed Has Been This Good For Ages) - Aftermath</p><p>The Assassin’s Creed enjoyer has logged on</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><h3 id="two-point-museum">TWO POINT MUSEUM</h3><figure></figure><p>Unlike loads of other management games, you can't skimp on staff in <em>Two Point Museum</em>; if you don't pay them they get angry and walk, and losing your best workers can cripple your entire operation. So look after your people! Good lesson!</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/two-point-museum-review-impressions/"><div><p>Two Point Museum: It’s Great - Aftermath</p><p>No tombs were raided in the making of this video game</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><h3 id="avowed">AVOWED</h3><figure></figure><p><em>Avowed&nbsp;</em>does not shy away from putting tough choices in front of you, but what separates them from many other RPGs is that they're choices that are tough for&nbsp;<em>you</em>.&nbsp;<em>Avowed</em>&nbsp;will show you a town and say, oh no, is this town in trouble? You could do this to try to help, which will kill a bunch of people. Or you could do&nbsp;<em>this</em>, which will kill a different bunch of people. Or&nbsp;<em>this</em>, which could kill nobody, or kill&nbsp;<em>everybody</em>. Who knows!</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/avowed-decision-choices-story-im-so-sorry-everybody/"><div><p>Every Decision You Make In Avowed Is Terrible - Aftermath</p><p>The road to hell is paved with good intentions</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure><h3 id="mika-and-the-witchs-mountain">MIKA AND THE WITCH'S MOUNTAIN</h3><figure></figure><p>I've said it before but I'll say it again:<a href="https://aftermath.site/caravan-sandwitch-impressions-review/">&nbsp;I love a small sandbox more than almost anything else in video games</a>. The island in&nbsp;<em>Mika&nbsp;</em>isn't very big, so it won't be long before you meet everyone and visit every location at least once. But that's great; it really helps the communal feel of the game that you grow to know every square inch of the place and everyone living on it.</p><figure><a href="https://aftermath.site/mika-witchs-mountain-impressions/"><div><p>Mika And The Witch’s Mountain Has Me (I’m Sorry) Under Its Spell - Aftermath</p><p>A breezy start to 2025</p><p><span>Aftermath</span><span>Luke Plunkett</span></p></div></a></figure>
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/game-of-the-year-2025-aftermath-luke-plunkett/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Smoking Behind The Supermarket With You Is A Cozy Rom-Com Manga]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/smoking-behind-the-supermarket-with-you-is-a-cozy-rom-com-manga/</link>
            <guid>1403830</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
      <p>By now, I hope I’ve made it abundantly clear that I’m an anime fan <a href="https://aftermath.site/coming-of-age-anime-call-of-the-night-vampires/"><u>born to slice-of-life romance</u></a>, but <a href="https://aftermath.site/solo-leveling-impressions-anime/"><u>condemned to a lifetime of battle shonen exposure.</u></a> So when I learned that a friend gifted another friend of mine a romance manga I’d only vaguely heard of over the holidays, I treated it like homework I actually wanted to do. I binged the entire thing in a week. Naturally, when the three of us finally met up this past weekend, my friend sheepishly admitted they hadn’t even cracked the spine yet. Which means the burden now falls to you, dear reader, to hear why <em>Smoking Behind the Supermarket With You</em> has quietly become one of my favorite recent romance reads, thanks to how effortlessly cozy it is.</p><figure><figcaption><span>Square Enix</span></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://squareenixmangaandbooks.square-enix-games.com/product/9781646092864?ref=aftermath.site"><em><u>Smoking Behind The Supermarket With You</u></em></a>, by mangaka <a href="https://x.com/jinusi822?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Jinushi</u></a>, is an office workspace rom-com tailor-made for anyone weak to kinda mean goth women who’d step on you and the oddly endearing charm of exhausted, gravely-voiced middle-aged men. It’s a bisexual harvest if ever there was one, and a rare adult romance with an unproblematic age gap.&nbsp;</p><figure><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/woclqV1wINo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" title="TVアニメ「スーパーの裏でヤニ吸うふたり」メインキャストボイスPV"></iframe></figure><p>Like “<a href="https://www.animenewsnetwork.com/interview/2025-06-04/rockin-out-with-sumiko-arai-the-guy-she-was-interested-in-wasnt-a-guy-at-all-manga-creator/.223419?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Green Yuri</u></a>” (AKA <a href="https://aftermath.site/green-yuri-nana-shojo-girls-love/"><em><u>The Guy She Was Interested In Wasn’t A Guy At All</u></em></a>) <em>Smoking Behind The Supermarket With You</em>, found its <a href="https://thetv.jp/news/detail/1084476/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>humble beginnings as a manga series published on Twitter</u></a> in the wake of the pandemic before getting picked up by Square Enix as a serial. It’s not only the first serialized series from Jinushi, but it’s also one that’s got <a href="https://www.animenewsnetwork.com/news/2025-09-21/smoking-behind-the-supermarket-with-you-tv-anime-reveals-main-cast/.229036?ref=aftermath.site"><u>an anime adaptation in the wings</u></a> in 2026. So allow me to yap about why the romance manga is heat so you can say “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6xG4oFny2Pk&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>but I was there!</u></a>” too.</p><figure><blockquote>— TVアニメ「スーパーの裏でヤニ吸うふたり」公式 (@yanisuu_anime) <a href="https://twitter.com/yanisuu_anime/status/1946132855618502947?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;ref=aftermath.site">July 18, 2025</a></blockquote>
</figure><p>From the jump, I was immediately arrested by how <em>Smoking Behind the Supermarket With You </em>wastes no time resonating with anyone trapped in the corporate grind, clinging to the tiny rituals that make the day-to-day survivable as the series’ thematic anchor. Be that stopping by a convenience store, catching the warm smile of a store clerk who unknowingly gave you just enough serotonin to make that bread, or just grab some smokes and take the edge off from a hard day's work.&nbsp;</p><p>That’s the cadence of Sasaki’s life. Sasaki is a middle-aged, overworked salaryman who every day gets berated by his boss. The series, on the whole, strikes a chord with anyone who deals with the corporate grind and finds solace in frequenting a haunt only to be graced by the beaming smile of a store clerk that gives you a boost in happy brain chemicals to continue waking up and making that bread. Or, at least doing so until you need to grab a smoke to take the edge off. That’s the case with Sasaki, who ends each day at a convenience store not just to grab groceries, but to bask in the bright, grounding presence of a cute clerk named Yamada. </p><figure><figcaption><span>Square Enix</span></figcaption></figure><p>That is, until the rhythm of his day is thrown off one night when he swings by the store late and discovers Yamada has already clocked out. Instead, he’s greeted by a leather-jacketed, pierced woman named Tayama, who casually invites him out back to share a smoke and some company. Because Sasaki is, frankly, severely face-blind in the most endearing way, he never clocks that Tayama—whom he assumes is some coworker he’s somehow overlooked for months—is actually Yamada without the uniform, <a href="https://x.com/jinusi822/status/1829923640743444748?s=20&amp;ref=aftermath.site" rel="noreferrer">customer-service smile</a>, or the practiced bubbly disposition she uses on the clock.&nbsp;</p><figure><blockquote><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/LS6xTacYqF?ref=aftermath.site">pic.twitter.com/LS6xTacYqF</a></p>— 地主⬛︎新刊1/23 (@jinusi822) <a href="https://twitter.com/jinusi822/status/1977692567988060316?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;ref=aftermath.site">October 13, 2025</a></blockquote>
</figure><p>What follows is a wonderfully lopsided pseudo-love triangle in which “Tayama” (and the rest of the store staff, fully aware of the comedy of errors unfolding) gently teases Sasaki for his obvious crush on her other self. Meanwhile, Sasaki, thrilled to finally have a smoking buddy, finds himself falling for the woman behind the polite platitudes. On paper, <em>Smoking Behind the Supermarket With You</em> is the kind of wacky setup you’d only find in a gag manga or an early-aughts rom-com—the sort of <em>Miss Congeniality</em>, <em>Princess Diaries</em> bit where a change of clothes and vernacular somehow renders a person unrecognizable. And the whole Yamada/Tayama dual identity asks for a level of suspension of disbelief from the reader that practically nudges the series into sketch comedy territory. But what makes the manga sing is that, <a href="https://youtu.be/RSOrscuIFC4?list=TLPQMTIwMTIwMjY3M6WWk_hqFw&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>beneath its deeply silly premise</u></a>, it harbors a romance that could only work between adults.&nbsp;</p><figure><blockquote><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/7slP9xWlTC?ref=aftermath.site">pic.twitter.com/7slP9xWlTC</a></p>— 地主⬛︎新刊1/23 (@jinusi822) <a href="https://twitter.com/jinusi822/status/1897839463834976469?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;ref=aftermath.site">March 7, 2025</a></blockquote>
</figure><p>A huge part of that comes down to smoking itself. As a habit, smoking is both a self-destructive vice and a symbolic pressure valve to let off some steam. But between smokers, it becomes something more intimate: a quiet ritual of shared air, time, and vulnerability so addictive that you’d jump at the offer regardless of how chilly it is outside. Simply put, it’s a sophisticated, mature mode of connection that simply doesn’t exist in garden-variety romances. For the non-smokers of the world, it’s the equivalent of loading up a YouTube video on someone else’s account or sending them a song that’s been haunting your brain—forever altering the other person’s algorithm. Folding your tiny, private time-waster into someone else’s life in a way that feels strangely tender. “Intimacy in the modern day,” as <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@theofficialnorthernlion/video/7575988525087214866?is_from_webapp=1&amp;sender_device=pc&amp;web_id=7494297314892203551&amp;ref=aftermath.site"><u>Twitch streamer Northernlion</u></a> puts it.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Square Enix</span></figcaption></figure><p>Swap out playlists for preferred cigarette brand flavors, fireside chats, and easy shared silences that stretch as long as you let them, and you get something even more specific and profound as the bedrock of a romance. It’s here that <em>Smoking Behind the Supermarket With You</em> takes its cozy premise and leans into how something as ordinary as sharing a smoke with a friend can spark a kind of honesty and intimacy that hits harder than an indirect kiss over a shared drink. The small rituals between Sasaki and Tayama—the teasing, the quiet moments, the unspoken warmth—never overstay their welcome. Instead, each chapter offers another faint glow of their ember‑warm yearning, slowly shifting from easygoing companionship into something unmistakably romantic.</p><figure><blockquote><p lang="ja" dir="ltr">３すう。 <a href="https://t.co/ZJj22t03lE?ref=aftermath.site">pic.twitter.com/ZJj22t03lE</a></p>— 地主⬛︎新刊1/23 (@jinusi822) <a href="https://twitter.com/jinusi822/status/1898637057540407566?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;ref=aftermath.site">March 9, 2025</a></blockquote>
</figure><p>The flames of that yearning are certainly aided by <a href="https://x.com/jinusi822/status/1884197016353599641?s=20&amp;ref=aftermath.site" rel="noreferrer">Jinushi’s online illustrations </a>of the two fulfilling <a href="https://x.com/jinusi822/status/1983550204868710535?s=20&amp;ref=aftermath.site" rel="noreferrer">nurse‑and‑patient cosplay</a> and <a href="https://x.com/jinusi822/status/1819346049754099821?s=20&amp;ref=aftermath.site" rel="noreferrer">other cheeky fantasies</a>. But the real magic lies in the series' quieter, less showy moments of wish fulfillment, threaded through the manga. The simple, disarming intimacy of being understood. <em>Smoking Behind the Supermarket With You</em> is the kind of romance where letting the long fuse of this oddball relationship burn at its own pace is part of the delight. After all, you can’t appreciate a cigarette if you inhale it all in one hungry pull. Beneath the disguises and crossed signals, they’re just two people who genuinely like being in each other’s orbit—and who would quietly ache at the thought of losing the small, daily comfort of talking through the weight of their days or shooting the breeze about nothing at all.&nbsp; </p>
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/smoking-behind-the-supermarket-with-you-is-a-cozy-rom-com-manga/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>