<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 19:19:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kowloon Generic Romance Is The Closest Anime Has Come To A Wong Kar Wai Film]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/kowloon-generic-romance</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kowloon-generic-romance-is-the-closest-anime-has-come-to-a-wong-kar-wai-film.1169655/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/kowloon-generic-romance<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I won’t be the last person to say that Wong Kar Wai’s cinema is good kino, seamlessly transforming the ethereal essence of raw, intangible emotions into a vivid, dreamlike work of art. From the tender ache of <em>In the Mood for Love</em> to the bittersweet unraveling of profoundly connected yet deeply lonely lovers in <em>Happy Together</em> to the existential echoes of lost love in <em>2046</em>, his films perform a kind of cinematic alchemy, unpacking the emotional weight of love and loss. Neon-drenched cityscapes become poetic reflections of yearning that feel both eternal and fleeting, captured through his hypnotic, slow-motion lens. In the words of Nicole Kidman, “Heartbreak feels good in a place likе this.”&nbsp;</p><p><em>Kowloon Generic Romance</em>, a new anime this season, hums to a similar cadence as Kar Wai’s works, blending love, mystery, and nostalgia into its atmospheric tale set in the worn-down <a href="https://aftermath.site/kowloon-walled-city-cross-section-illustrated" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">labyrinthine walled city</a>, in what might just be the closest anime has come to evoking the legendary cinematographer’s films.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Kowloon Generic Romance</em> is part mystery, part sci-fi, and all parts romance. Written and illustrated by <em>After the Rain</em> mangaka Jun Mayuzuki, it follows Reiko Kujirai and Hajime Kudo, two coworkers at Wang Lai Realty Company, whose office banter flirts with something more profound. As the name of the show bluntly suggests, their dynamic ticks all the familiar romcom boxes—lunch break debates over trying out new spots over old haunts; teasing that borders on being mean, like kids on a playground—but beneath the surface, something is off, hinting at a deeper mystery at play.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Spoilers for that.&nbsp;</strong></p><p>Kujirai and Kudo’s conversations are drenched in nostalgia, from their musings on Kowloon’s inherent charm to the way memory and love intertwine for people inside the town. When Kujirai offhandedly mentions how watermelon tastes better with a cigarette—a line that feels right at home in a Wong Kar Wai work—Kudo hesitates before saying that habit reminds him of someone he once knew. That lingering theme of familiarity resurfaces again when a waiter mistakes Kujirai for Kudo’s girlfriend. Kudo, to Kujirai’s surprise, brushes her off when she wonders if it’d be awkward if he returned with his actual girlfriend, but adds, “That’s not something you should worry about.” By now, Spidey senses are tingling something fierce.&nbsp;</p><p>Their nostalgia talk moves on to romantic dialogue tree territory when Kujirai admits their hangouts feel strangely familiar, leading to a rooftop moment that would belong in the season finale of any other romance anime. Just when it looks like they might kiss in the first episode, speedrunning past the lewd handholding stage, Kudo deflects once again, teasing Kujirai about her crow’s feet. They do wind up kissing at the close of the first episode, but it's anything but generic. In a quiet office moment, Kujirai wakes Kudo with playful prodding, and in that drowsy haze, he kisses her—like full-on French kisses her like a husband and wife on the morning of their honeymoon—only to shove her away, say my bad, and leave with a cryptic “wrong person.” It's here where the anime’s mystery crystallizes when Kujirai finds a Polaroid of them together in his drawer—except she has no memory of it or their apparent engagement.</p><figure><figure><figcaption><span>Arvo Animation</span></figcaption></figure><figure><figcaption><span>Arvo Animation</span></figcaption></figure><figure><figcaption><span>Arvo Animation</span></figcaption></figure><figure><figcaption><span>Arvo Animation</span></figcaption></figure><span><figure></figure></span></figure><p>From here on, Kujirai grapples with feelings for Hajime that are undeniably hers, despite having no memory of the past they shared. Elsewhere, Kudo struggles with maintaining a healthy distance between them, which doesn’t help her romantic confusion. At the same time, the show cuts back to his meet-cute with a pre-amnesia version of Kujirai. Contrary to her current, bashful self, pre-amnesia Kujirai was a confident, captivating presence, putting Hajime on the romantic back foot as he wistfully yearned for her. Despite their current circumstance, Kudo doesn’t display any signs of wanting to recreate their old dynamic. Whenever things look like they’re about to heat up, he reliably breaks the tension with jokes, keeping their connection at a cautious platonic distance. However, his emotions slip when Kujirai cosplays as her former self, which only pisses him off instead of making sparks fly between them again. While the mystery of their amnesia storyline unfolds in the foreground of the anime, with both sides aware of the elephant in the room without outwardly addressing it to each other, the anime delves deeply into the weight of nostalgia.&nbsp;</p><p>Beneath the romance lies a sweeping sci-fi narrative, exploring humanity’s pursuit of innovation at the expense of its essence. Hebinuma, a pharmaceutical giant, is pulling an <em>Altered Carbon</em> advertising "eternal youth and immortality" by backing up memories for Generic Terra—a still-unfinished, gaudy <a href="https://evangelion.fandom.com/wiki/Ramiel" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ramiel-looking polyhedron</a> floating above Earth. Government-funded and branded as a "romance for humankind," it's the latest in a trend of future-flung conspiratorial pharmaceutical shows that posits the pros and cons of creating a fake Earth with fake people, set in a future that echoes a vanished past. Combine the fact that folks’ tax dollars are funding the knockoff Earth populated by backup versions of people, with the show being set in a futuristic version of a setting that no longer exists, and you’ve got the pretty nifty adult romance anime on your hands.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Kowloon Generic Romance Anime and Live Action Movie - Official Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JhLqN5mYXDI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><div><p>However, there is a caveat to recommending the show to those hoping to dive into it via the anime: the manga isn’t done yet, and the anime aims to cover the entire series. This has manga readers, myself included, <a href="https://www.cbr.com/kowloon-generic-romance-manga-end/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">side-eying the anime</a>, hoping it doesn’t fumble the bag with a rushed original anime ending to coalesce with its annoyingly fast pacing.</p><p>So far, that has materialized in the show condensing each volume of the manga into 25-minute episodes. While it hasn't reached the level of car wreck anime adaptations of otherwise phenomenal manga, like <em>The Promised Neverland</em>’s second season where entire arcs were skipped in a blitz toward its finale, <em>Kowloon Generic Romance</em>’s trimmed-for-brevity approach to adapting the series into an anime does dampen the deliberate, atmospheric pacing that defined it. Apparently, viewers are meant to watch the <a href="https://www.animenewsnetwork.com/news/2024-10-10/kowloon-generic-romance-manga-gets-tv-anime-live-action-film-in-2025/.216593#:~:text=Shueisha%20announced%20on%20Friday%20that,and%20footage%20for%20both%20projects." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">anime and then the live-action</a> show to get a whole mixed-media experience with its adaptation, so I’ll hold my reservations on whether the show sticks that landing or not. Regardless, we’ll always have the manga, now <a href="https://www.animenewsnetwork.com/news/2025-04-15/jun-mayuzuki-kowloon-generic-romance-manga-is-in-final-arc/.223585" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">nearing its end</a>, which makes it the perfect time to dive into <em>Kowloon Generic Romance</em> and soak in its magical realism and unmistakable Wong Kar Wai vibes.</p></div></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Good Morning To All My Blue Prince Non-Sickos]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/blue-prince-beginner</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/good-morning-to-all-my-blue-prince-non-sickos.1169514/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/blue-prince-beginner<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The–sorry–<em>discourse</em> around <a href="https://aftermath.site/blue-prince-impressions-review" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Blue Prince</em></a> has been weird as hell. Everyone who got access to it before its launch came out of the gate raving about it. This set up a lot of expectations for its wider release; from the conversations I’ve seen, some people feel pressured to like it, or like they don’t “get” the game if they don’t. Others seem to feel they have to defend why they aren’t psyched on it, while people who love it are quick to offer advice for those who don’t. I’ve been doing my best to play the game over the last few weeks, but I’m struggling to figure out how to approach it in a sensible way.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>When the headline for this blog popped into my head after playing <em>Blue Prince</em> all Sunday morning when I meant to go outside instead, I realized I’d written a not-dissimilar blog about <a href="https://aftermath.site/balatro-steam-meta" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Balatro</em></a> early in its popularity. That was another game that 1. noted sicko Chris Person <a href="https://aftermath.site/the-nerve-of-balatro-for-being-this-good" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">loved</a>, and 2. has a depth that gobbled up players’ time in a manner similar to <em>Blue Prince. </em>Both games appear straightforward on their surface but hide a ton of discoverable strategies and secrets. This is a good thing: It rules that we’ve been getting such a wealth of <a href="https://aftermath.site/tag/lorelei-and-the-laser-eyes" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">unique</a> indie games these days.</p><p>I <em>think</em> I’m liking <em>Blue Prince</em>? I’ll admit that I’m less than 20 in-game days into it, in part because I kept watching YouTube guides and then starting new saves. I don’t think I’ve had any kind of big “ah-ha” moment over its puzzles yet. I’ve definitely realized something I thought was just set-dressing was actually a clue, and I’ve already been smugly sure I understood what a puzzle wanted only to find more information that let me know I was totally wrong. I haven’t had a moment that makes me want to sink all my free time&nbsp; into it yet, but that doesn’t mean I’m not enjoying it. I’m the happiest in the game when I draft a room I haven’t seen before because exploration is one of my favorite things in games, and I like the promise that there’s lots of new things to see that I have no inkling of yet.</p><p>But the qualities that make the game so compelling for players diving into its endless depths also make it hard to get into. I have this constant vague stress that I’m <em>missing</em> something because I’ve been told there’s so much to miss, or the feeling I have too many chores because I vaguely know there’s so much to do; at the same time, I can’t just check off these tasks during a run given the game’s interconnectedness and RNG. The exhortation to “take notes” <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/pokachee.bsky.social/post/3lmuam4o6fk2r" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">baffles</a> me: what are the notes supposed to <em>look</em> like, what am I supposed to be taking notes <em>on</em> if I don’t even know what could be a clue yet? Lately I’ve taken to organizing my notes by day, just to give them some kind of structure. It’s possible this advice doesn’t gel with me because, as a games journalist, I’m almost always taking notes when I play a game anyway, so “take notes” for <em>Blue Prince</em> isn’t as helpful advice as, say, being told I’ll need a notebook to do math for <em>Lorelei and the Laser Eyes</em>.</p><p>When I try to bring these feelings up to <em>Blue Prince </em>devotees, they struggle to offer meaningful advice. I’m not always sure what I’m supposed to be <em>doing </em>in the game in a metaphysical sense, and anyone who can nudge me in that direction has tens to over one hundred hours in the game but doesn’t want to spoil anything in a game where everything seems to be a spoiler. Sometimes it feels like the nature of press and players getting early code has a little bit accidentally ruined the game for those of us just starting: you have <em>Blue Prince </em>experts and <em>Blue Prince </em>noobs, and we’re shouting to each other across the unspeakable chasm that is the nature of the game. It feels like people who <em>love</em> the game are in love with a game I haven’t started playing yet, and they can’t do much to guide me toward that game without unintentionally ruining the process that made them fall in love with it.&nbsp;</p><p>In general I try to avoid slating myself into the category of “normal” people when it comes to video games, since I play them for work and am surrounded by other people who do the same. But in the case of <em>Blue Prince</em> I’ve realized that maybe I need to not talk to my professional peers about it and instead turn to you, our readers, and my real-life friends who are playing the game alongside me. We are playing the game that many other people played weeks or months ago, and they played that game without the lure, but also the pressure, of the passion for the game’s secrets to navigate alongside its shifting house.</p><p>How are you drowning out the noise and just… playing the game? What are you literally <em>doing</em> in a run; what do your notes look like? How are you setting goals? Are you <em>liking</em> the game–do you feel like you’re making meaningful progress, or are you, like me, constantly a little bit stressed that you’re doing it wrong? (In fairness, I feel this way about everything in my life.) How do you decide how long to play for, or when to end your play session for the night? Do you have any tips that aren’t spoilers, but also aren’t the same “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=blue+prince+tips+beginner" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NO SPOILERS</a>!” videos that tread the same ground about strategic dead ends and notebooks? Did it take you as long to realize the pun of the game’s name as it took me?</p><p>It’s cool to have an indie game that’s stoked so much passion, and I think it’s a real testament to the game’s design that it’s created such a uniquely-shaped conversation. When I’m frustrated in my runs, I do draw inspiration from the possibility that the next room I draft might be the one where I cross the threshold from <em>Blue Prince</em> curious to <em>Blue Prince</em> fanatic. I will surely get there long after everyone else has moved on to the next thing, but maybe all of us non-sickos can get there together.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/kowloon-generic-romance"><h3>Kowloon Generic Romance Is The Closest Anime Has Come To A Wong Kar Wai Film</h3></a><p>Longing, nostalgia, and an unconventional sci-fi tale make for a not-so-generic anime romance
</p></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>