<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:52:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Games Suing Two Fortnite Island Makers Over Inflated ‘Bot’ Engagement]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/epic-games-suing-two-fortnite-island-makers-over-inflated-bot-engagement</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-games-suing-two-fortnite-island-makers-over-inflated-%E2%80%98bot%E2%80%99-engagement.1319113/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Fortnite</em> maker Epic Games is suing two Michigan men, Idris Nahdi and Ayob Nasser, for allegedly abusing the <em>Fortnite</em> Island Creator program by artificially inflating engagement on their creations.</p><p>The company’s lawyers allege in a complaint filed Tuesday in the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Michigan that Nahdi and Nasser created and deployed “fake ‘bot’ player accounts to simulate real hum <em>Fortnite</em> engagement on their islands.” In doing so, lawyers write, the two men earned “tens of thousands of dollars in unwarranted payouts.”&nbsp;</p><p>“We are taking legal action against two UEFN developers who used bots to inflate their player counts,” an Epic Games spokesperson told Aftermath. “We also took down their islands and they are banned from <em>Fortnite</em>. Manipulating player engagement breaks our rules and will not be tolerated.”</p><p><em>Fortnite</em> user-generated content creators earn money from their creations with payouts related to engagement. People who create Islands in <em>Fortnite</em>—akin to Experiences in <em>Roblox</em>—earn money from a pool of money made up of 40% of revenue from Fortnite's Item Shop “and related real-money purchases.”&nbsp;</p><p>That pool of money is divided up and distributed based on two factors: <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/introducing-the-creator-economy-2-0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">player popularity and player retention</a>. The exact details of how the distribution is calculated isn’t public, but Epic Games’ lawyers say in the lawsuit that active players, active playtime, and returning players (“among other stats”) play into the calculation. Soon, <em>Fortnite</em> developers will be able to <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-developers-will-soon-be-able-to-sell-in-game-items?lang=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sell items from their <em>Fortnite</em> Islands</a> to earn additional revenue, but that hasn’t been rolled out yet. Currently, engagement is the only way to earn money from <em>Fortnite</em>.</p><p>“Before they got caught, Defendants were paid tens of thousands of dollars in unearned payments from Epic that would otherwise have been paid out to other developers who earned genuine engagement from real <em>Fortnite</em> players,” lawyers wrote in the complaint, <a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/929543657/Epic-Games-suing-two-Fortnite-Island-makers-over-inflated-bot-engagement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">which has been reviewed by Aftermath</a>. “Epic has also spent substantial resources investigating Defendants’ conduct and working to implement safeguards against unearned payments.”</p><p>Both Nahdi and Nasser entered the program months apart in December 2023 and March 2024, respectively, Epic Games’ lawyers say. They created multiple accounts with “inaccurate or incomplete personal information” to “create and publish a small number of <em>Fortnite </em>Islands.”&nbsp;</p><p>The multiple islands were a “scheme” to “disguise” the fake engagement, lawyers say. Between December 2024 and February 2025, Nahdi and Nasser created more than 20,000 fake bot accounts, according to the complaint.&nbsp;</p><p>“Defendants programmed the bot accounts to engage with Defendants’ own <em>Fortnite I</em>slands by using a cloud gaming service that allows users to play video games, like <em>Fortnite</em>, remotely,” lawyers say.</p><p>The fake bot accounts accounted for 90% of visitors to the islands Nahdi and Nasser created—and they only engaged with their Islands, lawyers say. Epic Games started to get suspicious after Nahdi and Nasser were paid out for December 2024, finding that nine out of 10 Islands created by the two were populated by 80% to 99% of engagement. Epic Games began immediately withholding portions of the engagement payments "attributable to the artificial engagement in January and February 2025.”&nbsp;</p><p>Epic Games’ lawyers say that the fake account activity dropped after Epic Games withheld payment, “indicating the Defendants were aware their scheme had been detected.”</p><p>Epic Games is suing over breach of contract, copyright infringement, and fraud. It wants the court to forbid Nahdi and Nasser from accessing <em>Fortnite</em> or any server owned by Epic Games and award damages.&nbsp;</p><p>Epic Games has been ramping up its efforts to punish people who cheat in <em>Fortnite </em>in the past few years; the company has pursued legal action against alleged cheaters recently. One <em>Fortnite</em> esports player who was caught cheating <a href="https://x.com/FNCompetitive/status/1891564240604999725" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was forced to publicly apologize</a> this year and had their prize money donated to charity. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-tournament-cheat-forced-to-pay-175k-banned-from-game-forever" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Another player lost a $175,000 lawsuit</a> in June 2025 for cheating during <em>Fortnite</em> tournaments.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/100-meters-gkids-anime-movie-kenji-iwaisawa-director-interview"><h3>100 Meters Director On Capturing The Art And Agony Of Track And Field Through Rotoscope Animation</h3></a><p>Kenji Iwaisawa hopes his film adaptation will be “the first of its kind” to bring the quiet intensity of track to the big screen</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/hades-2-ending"><h3>Hades 2’s Story Doesn’t Change The Status Quo</h3></a><p>Melinoë's journey is more about acceptance than change</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/wayward-netflix-martin"><h3>Wayward Is A Queer Exploration Of The Troubled Teen Industry</h3></a><p>Mae Martin's new Netflix show creates a *very* creepy small town</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/epic-games-suing-two-fortnite-island-makers-over-inflated-bot-engagement]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[100 Meters Director On Capturing The Art And Agony Of Track And Field Through Rotoscope Animation]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/100-meters-gkids-anime-movie-kenji-iwaisawa-director-interview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/100-meters-director-on-capturing-the-art-and-agony-of-track-and-field-through-rotoscope-animation.1319110/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In a short period since partnering with <a href="https://gizmodo.com/toho-animation-acquires-gkids-and-aims-to-bring-more-japanese-media-to-the-u-s-2000512287" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Toho</a>, GKids has established itself as the anime equivalent of the Criterion Collection. Through its theatrical rereleases of <a href="https://aftermath.site/linda-bae-doona-gkids-james-iha" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">deep-cut cult-classic films from yesteryear</a>, <a href="https://aftermath.site/gundam-gquuuuuux-is-the-sum-of-its-parts-in-the-best-way-possible" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">anime TV compilation preview films</a>, and getting in on the ground floor of <a href="https://gizmodo.com/dandadan-first-encounter-review-gkids-crunchyroll-netflix-anime-2000499028" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new hot shows</a>, GKids established a name for itself bringing fans from the hovels of their streaming home setups to that magical place where heartbreak feels good to Nicole Kidman: the theatre. Its forthcoming release, <a href="https://gkids.com/films/100-meters/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>100 Meters</em></a> by Studio <a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/producer/2663/Rockn_Roll_Mountain" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rock’N Roll Mountain,</a> taps into the big game pageantry by propelling one of the most low-key goated, yet slept-on, sports—track and field—into the limelight through the awesome artistic power of rotoscoped animation.&nbsp;</p><p>Created by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uoto" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Uoto</a>, a mangaka best known for <a href="https://gizmodo.com/netflix-orb-anime-review-madhouse-2000576670" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Orb: On The Movements Of The Earth</em></a>, <em>100 Meters </em>follows two runners: Togashi, a gifted sprinter lauded by all for his natural-born talents, and Komiya, an unconventional runner working hard to make a name for himself on grit alone. Similar to Tatsuki Fujimoto’s <a href="https://aftermath.site/look-back-gkids-tatsuki-fujimoto" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Look Back</em></a>, <em>100 Meters</em> follows the friendship-turned-rivalry of two friends from childhood through adolescence to adulthood as they struggle to meet their athletic goals without burning out or letting life’s challenges break them in their quest to become the absolute best in Japan’s 100-meter race.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="100 METERS | Official Trailer - In Theatres October 10" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oXeYSCXSFhs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>I spoke with director <a href="https://www.animenewsnetwork.com/encyclopedia/people.php?id=186313" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kenji Iwaisawa</a> about the ingenious decision to adapt Uoto’s manga using rotoscope animation, the challenges and triumphs of its implementation, and what he hopes the film will do not just for the sport but also for establishing his studio’s presence in the realm of animation on a global scale.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Isaiah Colbert: </strong><em>100 Meters</em> follows <em>Orb: On The Movements Of The Earth</em>, another critically acclaimed work from creator Uoto, which has pushed him into mainstream recognition. What attracted you to direct <em>100 Meters</em> as your latest project? How does it stand apart from other animated works you’ve helmed?</p><p><strong>Kenji Iwaisawa:</strong> I was really attracted to the world building that Uoto-sensei does in the original manga. Also, 100 meters is such a short race in a short amount of time. It’s very unusual to have that as the context of an animated movie, or anything. It’s really a first of its kind. It’s super unique, and I think that’s what really drew me into it.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Rock'N Roll Mountain/GKids</span></figcaption></figure><p><strong>IC: </strong>Rotoscoping has deep roots in animation history—often traced back to early horse motion studies. What made rotoscope animation feel like an intuitive choice for <em>100 Meters</em>, especially in capturing the kinetic intensity and emotional rhythm of running and character acting?</p><p><strong>KI: </strong>When I first started this project, I didn’t really know if rotoscoping would match it. But I think what worked out was not really when they’re racing, but, for example, the rain sequence—what happens before the race—or what happens after the race when they’re cooling down. I really thought rotoscoping matched those scenes better. I think that’s what works for the movie.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>IC: </strong>What was the most technically challenging sequence to animate, and what made it so demanding, either emotionally or logistically?&nbsp;</p><p><strong>KI: </strong>What was really difficult about this movie is the dialogue-heavy scenes—when there’s two characters talking to each other—because there’s no bodily movement. And there’s a lot of scenes like that where they’re just talking to each other. I really had to think about how to depict that to make it more interesting for the audience.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Rock'N Roll Mountain/GKids</span></figcaption></figure><p><strong>IC:</strong> Sound design in sports films is often overlooked despite being vital to their presentation. Was there any Foley work involved to capture the specific textures of runners’ footfalls, breathing, and track surfaces? How immersive did you want that sonic layer to be in <em>100 Meters</em>?&nbsp;</p><p><strong>KI: </strong>Because we use rotoscoping to take the film footage, the animation has realistic visuals. I really wanted to match the realistic visuals and have realistic sounds. This is a method that’s different from a normal animated movie. I got the live action film crew to take in the sound the way that they usually would like a sound team. I actually didn’t give them that much detailed instructions on how to take in the sound. I left it up to them, since they’re used to working on live action film.<strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p><p><strong>IC: </strong>Did Uoto-sensei participate in the adaptation? What was his reaction upon viewing the film? Did he offer any suggestions, critiques, or goals in the lead-up to <em>100 Meters</em>’ theatrical release?</p><p><strong>KI: </strong>Regarding the participation, he was really involved in the outline and script part of the film. Obviously, we couldn’t fit five volumes' worth of story into the film, so we wrote the script adapted for the film. We gave it to him, he gave us feedback, we would make adjustments, and then we’d give it back. That was repeated a couple of times, so he was pretty heavily involved in the script process.&nbsp;</p><p>As for his reaction, he really liked it. He thought it was really good. A big difference we made in the film is that we cut a lot of the monologues that the characters give when they’re running. Monologues, I think, are a specific characteristic of the manga, but he thought it was done really well, so that made me really happy.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Rock'N Roll Mountain/GKids</span></figcaption></figure><p><strong>IC: </strong>Track and field is a fundamental sport, yet it’s often underrepresented in media. The film also highlights its true-to-life depiction of modest crowd sizes with seats filled with dedicated supporters. What impact do you hope <em>100 Meters</em> has on the perception of the sport, as well as Rock’N Roll Mountain’s place in the world of animation?&nbsp;</p><p><strong>KI: </strong>Through watching <em>100 Meters</em>, if people could get interested in track and field, even if they don’t specifically get into it, if they watch this film, [and ] it adds some joy, spark, or positive impact to their daily lives, that’d be great. Rock’N Roll Mountain, my studio, was created to support my career as a director. I think my style is unique, and I also think my works are unique too. (Laughs) So if I could continue creating works through my studio, it would be nice if everyone worldwide would know the name of my studio, hopefully.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>100 Meters</em> hits select theaters on October 10 and will be available nationwide from October 12 to October 14.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/epic-games-suing-two-fortnite-island-makers-over-inflated-bot-engagement"><h3>Epic Games Suing Two Fortnite Island Makers Over Inflated ‘Bot’ Engagement</h3></a><p>Epic Games says Idris Nahdi and Ayob Nasser made tens of thousands of dollars worth of ‘unwarranted payouts’</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/hades-2-ending"><h3>Hades 2’s Story Doesn’t Change The Status Quo</h3></a><p>Melinoë's journey is more about acceptance than change</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/wayward-netflix-martin"><h3>Wayward Is A Queer Exploration Of The Troubled Teen Industry</h3></a><p>Mae Martin's new Netflix show creates a *very* creepy small town</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/100-meters-gkids-anime-movie-kenji-iwaisawa-director-interview]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>