<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 20:03:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Halifax Union To 'Pursue Every Legal Recourse' After Studio Closes Weeks After Union Vote]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/ubisoft-halifax-closed-weeks-after-unionizing-cwa-canada/</link>
            <guid>1400773</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
      <p>Ubisoft announced Wednesday it will close its Ubisoft Halifax studio and lay off 71 people. Ubisoft's closure of the <em>Assassin's Creed: Rebellion</em> and <em>Rainbow Six Mobile</em> studio comes just weeks after a group of 60 employees voted to unionize with Communications Workers of America's Canadian affiliate, CWA Canada. Seventy-four percent of the staff voted yes to <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-halifax-workers-form-a-union?ref=aftermath.site"><u>unionize</u></a> and create a wall-to-wall union including producers, designers, artists, testers, and researchers.</p><p>CWA Canada Local 30111, the chapter the Ubisoft Halifax workers joined, also includes more than a hundred workers at Bethesda Game Studios.</p><p>"Over the past 24 months, Ubisoft has undertaken company-wide actions to streamline operations, improve efficiency, and reduce costs," a Ubisoft spokesperson said in a statement to Aftermath. "As part of this, Ubisoft has made the difficult decision to close its Halifax studio. 71 positions will be affected. We are committed to supporting all impacted team members during this transition with resources, including comprehensive severance packages and additional career assistance."</p><p>The Ubisoft spokesperson did not specifically address the closure's relation—or not—to the recent union vote.</p><p>CWA Canada president Carmel Smyth said in a statement to Aftermath the union will "pursue every legal recourse to ensure that the rights of these workers are respected and not infringed in any way." The union said in a news release that it's illegal in Canada for companies to close businesses because of unionization. That’s not necessarily what happened here, according to the news release, but the union is "demanding information from Ubisoft about the reason for the sudden decision to close."</p><p>"We will be looking for Ubisoft to show us that this had nothing to do with the employees joining a union," former Ubisoft Halifax programmer and bargaining committee member Jon Huffman said in a statement. "The workers, their families, the people of Nova Scotia, and all of us who love video games made in Canada, deserve nothing less."</p><p>Ubisoft Halifax started as Longtail Studios, which was founded in the early 2000s by Ubisoft cofounder Gérard Guillemot. In 2010, <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2010-11-03-ubisoft-quebec-adds-longtail-studio.html?ref=aftermath.site"><u>several studio members were absorbed into Ubisoft</u></a>, and by 2015, <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/ubisoft-acquires-longtail-studios?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Ubisoft had acquired Longtail Studios entirely</u></a>. That's when it became Ubisoft Halifax. Before joining Ubisoft, the studio was best known for its work on the Rocksmith franchise; under Ubisoft, it focused squarely on mobile games. Ubisoft Halifax was <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20260107214109/https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/studio/halifax"><u>quickly removed from the Ubisoft website on Wednesday</u></a>. IGN reported in 2023 that <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-ubisoft-union-that-almost-was-the-untold-story-of-longtail-studios?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Longtail Studios tried to unionize in 2008</u></a>, but ultimately failed.&nbsp;</p><p>Ubisoft has been cutting costs over the past several years: laying off staff, canceling games, and shutting down studios. <a href="https://staticctf.ubisoft.com/8aefmxkxpxwl/33qBiRpCj1Z9Ib5bbfbg5r/0c7fff607779c63e137037bc5c95a000/Ubisoft_H1_FY26_Slideshow_vF.pdf?ref=aftermath.site"><u>In November</u></a>, Ubisoft shared in its earnings report that it intends to continue to reduce its fixed costs—to reduce costs by an additional €100 million by the 2027 fiscal year—on top of the €200 million reduction it had already enacted. Part of that reduction was a decrease of roughly 1,500 employees in the 12 months prior to the November earnings report. Not all of those departures were layoffs, however.</p><p>Ubisoft required a $1.25 billion investment from Tencent last year, too, to spin off the company's most successful franchises: Rainbow Six Siege, Far Cry, and Assassin's Creed. That initiative is called Vantage Studios, <a href="https://aftermath.site/ubisoft-tencent-subsidiary-ceo-charlie-guillemot/"><u>led by Charlie Guillemot and Christophe Derennes</u></a>. "Vantage Studios represents a first step in Ubisoft's ongoing transformation," <a href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-us/article/7GvucOgSm41HwFaXt2ADX1/ubisoft-launches-new-subsidiary-vantage-studios?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Ubisoft said in a news release from October</u></a>.</p>
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/ubisoft-halifax-closed-weeks-after-unionizing-cwa-canada/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>