<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 10:18:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Has Learned Nothing In The Last 11 Years]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-controversies-are-for-babies-and-racists</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-has-learned-nothing-in-the-last-11-years.1143783/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-controversies-are-for-babies-and-racists<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Depending on what you read and where you read it, you may have heard that the release of <em>Assassin's Creed Shadows</em><a href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-day-1-patch-notes-shrine-1851771221" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> has been controversial</a>. That it's been plagued by one cultural faux pas after another, from<a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/action/ubisoft-apologizes-for-using-a-real-life-reenactment-groups-flag-in-assassins-creed-shadows-concept-art-without-permission/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> iffy concept art</a> to an<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-figure-removed-from-sale-over-insensitive-design" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> ill-advised statue</a> through to<a href="https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-ubisoft-yasuke-apology-sucks" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> sincere apologies to fans over lapses in historical accuracy</a>. This has all now culminated in the game, made primarily by Westerners but set in Japan, being spoken about in Japanese parliament.</p><p>Specifically, questions about <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/assassins-creed/assassins-creed-shadows-sneakily-tones-down-the-mess-players-can-make-across-japans-religious-sites-in-its-day-one-patch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the way the game allows players to destroy religious sites</a> were recently put to Japan’s Prime Minister by representative Kada Hiroyuki; the Prime Minister’s<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/conormurray/2025/03/21/new-assassins-creed-releases-to-strong-reviews-but-sparks-anti-woke-backlash-and-roils-japanese-government/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> seemingly stern reply, stripped of all context, sounded pretty bad</a> for Ubisoft and the game! So bad that, in an attempt to smooth things over, Ubisoft have since patched <em>Shadows</em>, removing the player's ability to smash up historic Japanese temples.</p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/politics/article/3303172/japanese-pm-ishiba-condemns-assassins-creed-video-game-over-cultural-disrespect-shrine" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reading <em>some </em>headlines</a>, you'd think the game had made its biggest cultural misstep yet, and that this patch was a much-needed fix, alongside every other much-needed fix that has followed every other cultural misstep made by Ubisoft in the leadup to <em>Shadows</em>' release.</p><p>The thing is, though, it's all bullshit. Ubisoft didn’t have to patch this. You could smash up a temple in <em>Shadows </em>the same way you can smash up any room in the game, because the game lets you break every table and splinter every wooden door. There's also important context to be had concerning the exchange in Japanese parliament–mostly how unimportant it actually was–some of which can be found in this <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-prime-minister-of-japan-responded-to-a-question-about-assassins-creed-shadows-today-heres-whats-actually-going-on" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">IGN story, </a>and more of which is covered in this thread by Jeffrey Hall, Lecturer at Kanda University of International Studies:</p><p>Or, for a more succinct version of events, there's:</p><p>If the vibes of this sound at all familiar, it's because that sound you're hearing is Ubisoft walking into the same rake the company has been walking into for almost the entire public life of this video game. Thanks to a multitude of confluent factors--the game stars a woman,<a href="https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-yasuke-racism" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> the game stars a black man and is set in Japan</a>--there’s been an excruciatingly public "controversy" over the game for what feels like years now, not for normal people or for normal reasons, but simply because a subset of frothing-mouth internet weirdos don't like it, have convinced enough others to report on the idea that their opinion somehow matters, and Ubisoft just keeps on responding to them.</p><p>I can't believe Ubisoft keeps falling for the same old shit! <em>Assassin's Creed</em> has had religion in its sights, across multiple cultures and continents, for as long as it's been around, whether you're burning monasteries or <em>fighting the Pope</em>. And like I've said, the ability to "destroy" a temple in this game isn't an act of religious violence, it's simply an accidental, meaningless consequence of letting the player climb anything and sometimes break some tables. </p><p>These are absolute non-issues that require four seconds of context to dispel, but because there are some weebs out there who hate black people just as much as they love a particular idea of Japan, and at least one of them has written an email to a Japanese politician, suddenly this is an issue? And rather than explain it, Ubisoft just folds? <a href="https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-ubisoft-yasuke-apology-sucks" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Like I said last time</a>:</p><blockquote><p>The perfect response to dealing with shitheads like this is to simply live your life pretending they don't exist.<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://aftermath.site/the-acolyte-star-wars-controversy-ratings-this-is-all-terrible" target="_blank">&nbsp;Their opinions are ill-formed, bigoted and unsuitable for mainstream consumption, and so should be ignored at all costs</a>. Let them howl at the moon all they want, let their furious emails wash against the walls of your inbox, these people simply are not worth your time.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>Every word of that still applies. You do not need to apologise, or make changes for, these people! It would not have taken an exhaustive knowledge of Japanese parliamentary politics,<a href="https://www.gawkerarchives.com/how-we-got-rolled-by-the-dishonest-fascists-of-gamergat-1649496579" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> or reactionary letter-writing</a>, to know what was up here. Removing the ability to smash some stuff in one type of place but not all the others, in stark contrast to the rest of your series' decades-long stance on this, is just the weirdest line to draw. <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/assassins-creed-shadows-message-warning-animus-climbing-on-torii-gates-not-allowed-no-consequence/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">As is discouraging players from climbing over a Torii</a> (a Japanese temple gate) because <em>someone </em>is worried copycat tourists might try it; are there legitimate worries they’re going to climb over every historic castle, home and temple in the game as well?</p><p>It's embarrassing, <a href="https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-ubisoft-yasuke-apology-sucks" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">and just like last time</a>, I feel for everyone who actually worked on this game, to have it thrust once again--now, right as it's basking in<a href="https://opencritic.com/game/16792/assassins-creed-shadows" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> positive review scores</a>--into the spotlight of the culture wars by spineless company leadership.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-story-yasuke-podcast-revie"><h3>Assassin’s Creed Shadows Is Impressive, But Does The Story Work?</h3></a><p>We love how Assassin's Creed Shadows looks and feels, but does it deliver on the story it seeks to tell? We investigate on Aftermath Hours.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/valnet-report-freelance"><h3>Report: Valnet Blacklisted Freelancers Who Complained About Pay Rates</h3></a><p>A new report from The Wrap highlights low pay and a list of blacklisted writers at the company</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Kendrick Lamar And Drake’s Rap Beef Reignited The Anime Big Three Discourse]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/kendrick-lamar-drake-anime-naruto-bleach-one-piece</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-kendrick-lamar-and-drake%E2%80%99s-rap-beef-reignited-the-anime-big-three-discourse.1143579/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/kendrick-lamar-drake-anime-naruto-bleach-one-piece<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A year and some change ago, Atlanta rapper Future and producer Metro Boomin released their collaborative studio album "We Don’t Trust You." As is customary for rap album releases on streaming platforms such as Spotify and Apple Music, the features on the album were not disclosed until a few days after its release to encourage listeners to experience the entire album rather than skip to an artist they fancy, like Travis Scott, The Weeknd, Playboi Carti, and Rick Ross (for his four die-hard fans). Today, it is difficult to recall the other featured artists on the album due to Kendrick Lamar’s "<a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-news/future-metro-boomin-kendrick-lamar-like-that-number-one-hot-100-1234996590/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Like That</a>" verse, which stole the spotlight and ignited a generational rap feud between him and Drake.</p><p>We all know what followed: the world rubbernecked from their day jobs to witness the pair drop eight diss tracks against each other between April and May. Many of the tracks dropped so suddenly that only the most unemployed of the music-listening public could rise to the occasion of playing the role of Paul Revere by posting "Kendrick dropped" whenever a new track released. Their hydrogen bomb vs coughing baby feud culminated with Lamar out-rapping the <em>Degrassi </em>star by <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/music-news/kendrick-lamar-dominated-grammys-not-like-us-1236125989/#:~:text=With%20his%202024%20anthem%20%E2%80%9CNot,video%20and%20best%20rap%20performance." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">winning multiple Grammys</a> for his final diss track "Not Like Us," <a href="https://www.nfl.com/videos/kendrick-lamar-s-full-apple-music-super-bowl-halftime-show" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">headlining the Super Bowl</a>, and getting a packed stadium to sing along to the Canadian rapper being a "<a href="https://x.com/hiphop_communit/status/1803618488696611110?t=t-m1idxOWP7fVqJ6B2Gw8w&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">certified pedophile</a>" (<a href="https://x.com/cinesquetv/status/1888766681159283091?t=9VoZnH4MIsELJSMozIpNhQ&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">twice</a>). It was, and forever will be, a good time to be a K Dot fan.&nbsp;</p><p>However, one unacknowledged aspect of Kendrick, Drake, and J. Cole's feud (until <a href="https://variety.com/2024/music/news/j-cole-7-minute-drill-removed-streaming-kendrick-lamar-diss-1235969657/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post-diss clarity hit him</a>, leading him to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/04/08/arts/music/jcole-kendrick-lamar-diss-apology.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">apologize to Lamar</a> and duck out of the beef to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g6818Dx0N9k" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">live a peaceful life</a>) is how one line in Lamar's "Like That" verse breathed life into a long-quelled feud in the anime community over which shonen series is the best of all time: <em>Naruto</em>, <em>Bleach</em>, or <em>One Piece</em>.</p><p>The bar in question was a response to J. Cole’s <a href="https://youtu.be/Xty2gi5cMa8?t=116" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“First Person Shooter” verse</a> calling himself, Drake, and K Dot the big three in rap — a claim that’s pretty easy to accept in most rap circles. Lamar, ever the competitive rapper, took playful offense to that, saying, <a href="https://youtu.be/N9bKBAA22Go?t=110" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“Fuck the big three, it’s just big me.”</a> While the phrase is in reference to the trio, it also carries weight in anime circles as the term dedicated to <em>One Piece</em>, <em>Naruto</em>, and <em>Bleach</em> as the <a href="https://otaku.fandom.com/wiki/Big_Three" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">big three shonen series</a>. While greener anime fans often mistakenly treat the term as something that can be <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/anime/comments/vl0rof/the_new_big_three/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">usurped by newer series</a> like <em>Jujutsu </em>Kaisen or <em>Demon Slayer</em>, old heads have gatekept the adulation as a distinction that <a href="https://gizmodo.com/shonen-jump-big-three-future-2000501015" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">can never be duplicated</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>As soon as anime fans heard K Dot’s big three bar, they knew <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZT2nBKQdJ/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">peace among fandoms would be disrupted</a> once again with the resurgence of old internet forum debates. But this time, these debates happened on the new stage of the brainrot social media site TikTok, whose video editors took K Dot’s bar as a sleeper agent activation phrase and went wild making stylish AMVs centering either of the three anime as the one that was “really like that” while their contemporaries' best work was “a light pack.”&nbsp;</p><p>While the rap trio's beef was settled through their ability to craft scathing disses at each other's character, the anime big three TikTok beef was resolved by determining which fandom excelled in creating AMVs with their show as the superior series. The discourse evolved into the rappers being aptly personified as the three anime shows. Kendrick's anime persona was <em>One Piece</em>, as he has garnered an almost religious following of listeners who dedicate their lives to converting others to his fanbase despite the breadth of his discography being more politically charged and intimidatingly dense than his peers. (It also doesn't hurt that <a href="https://aftermath.site/luffy-one-piece-lakers" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Luffy reps Lamar's Los Angeles Lakers</a>.) Drake's anime persona was <em>Naruto </em>because he is the most popular of the three, garnering an all-encompassing reach thanks to the mass appeal of his songs servicing beginner rap listeners. This left <em>Bleach </em>as J. Cole’s anime persona, which was so uncannily appropriate one could almost call it fate. Like <em>Bleach</em>, J. Cole suffers from middle-child syndrome, often being left out of the conversation as the forerunner of the big three despite having a stylish flow of his own, even if he has not delivered a new flow or cadence in his rap performances since the trio broke into the rap scene over a decade ago.</p><p>Aside from stray anime AMVs, such as those featuring <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZT2nBtjSK/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>JJK </em></a>and <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZT2n5HYVT/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Dragon Ball Super</em></a>, TikTok video editors engaged in widespread friendly competition. My favorite AMVs had its heroes quip catchphrases after K Dot's “big three” bar, such as Naruto saying “baka,” Ichigo saying “bankai,” and Luffy giggling while hitting his Gear 5 pose. Like the Kendrick-Drake rivalry, TikTok AMVs quickly escalated, with <em>Naruto</em> fans readily admitting they were <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZT2nBsmwc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">getting their generous ramen-eating asses beaten</a> by the video editors behind <em>Bleach </em>and <em>One Piece</em>’s “Like That” edits outperforming their creative efforts.&nbsp;</p><p>If you’re wondering who won the Anime Big Three contest of 2024, it was definitively <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZT2nBq82p/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>One Piece</em></a>. Not only did the anime’s supporters work harder on the video editing front, but they also provided empirical data, such as <em>One Piece</em> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_best-selling_manga" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">selling more volumes worldwide</a> than the other series, as further proof of its superiority. They also cleverly utilized K Dot’s “Prince outlived Mike Jack” bar — comparing his influence to Drake’s comparing himself to Michael Jackson — to emphasize the <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZT2nBWdFV/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ongoing series outliving <em>Bleach </em>and <em>Naruto</em></a>.</p><p>Did Kendrick Lamar know his <a href="https://youtu.be/NPqDIwWMtxg?t=85" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“throw away”</a> big three bar would reignite an age-old anime beef through dueling AMVs at the same time as he was systematically dismantling his lesser? Probably not. But given his <a href="https://www.billboard.com/music/rb-hip-hop/kendrick-lamar-goku-hey-new-mustard-1235885909/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Goku-inspired scream </a>in his victory lap GNX track “TV Off,” I’d like to believe the reclusive rapper committed <a href="https://aftermath.site/taylor-swift-britney-spears-poptimism" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Taylor Swift levels of double entendres and deep-cut bars</a> with his lyrics just to feed the anime fans. I thank him for bringing out the competitive edge of AMV-makers for a new generation to pop out for their favorite series.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-story-yasuke-podcast-revie"><h3>Assassin’s Creed Shadows Is Impressive, But Does The Story Work?</h3></a><p>We love how Assassin's Creed Shadows looks and feels, but does it deliver on the story it seeks to tell? We investigate on Aftermath Hours.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/valnet-report-freelance"><h3>Report: Valnet Blacklisted Freelancers Who Complained About Pay Rates</h3></a><p>A new report from The Wrap highlights low pay and a list of blacklisted writers at the company</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>