<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 11:29:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Now You Can Finance In-Game Items, In Addition To Burritos]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/buy-now-pay-later-in-game-items-xsolla-affirm</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/now-you-can-finance-in-game-items-in-addition-to-burritos.1239897/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>From the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jun/12/buy-now-pay-later-fall" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">predatory morass</a> of “buy now, pay later” schemes – which <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/events/doordash-klarna-payments" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">famously and meme-ably</a> made their way to the world of DoorDash food deliveries earlier this year – arises a slimy new option: financing in-game purchases. I’m sure nothing regrettable will come of this, considering how <a href="https://aftermath.site/consumer-financial-protection-bureau-game-currency-rule-roblox" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">well-regulated</a> and famously <a href="https://kotaku.com/loot-boxes-are-designed-to-exploit-us-1819457592" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">immune to exploitation</a> in-game transactions tend to be.&nbsp;</p><p>The new system is the result of a partnership between Affirm, a prominent BNPL provider, and Xsolla, a company that makes payment software used by thousands of companies like Epic and Sega, as well as numerous free-to-play and mobile games. In <a href="https://investors.affirm.com/news-releases/news-release-details/xsolla-and-affirm-partner-help-game-developers-offer-players" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">an announcement</a> published late last month, Affirm said that its services are now “automatically available to [Xsolla partners’] players – enabling them to split purchases into interest-free biweekly payments or longer-term monthly installments for carts starting at $50.” </p><p>While the companies did not specify which games this has been applied to, it is not hard to imagine a scenario where a player piles up a heap of cosmetics in a free-to-play MMO or a bunch of currency in a battle royale and then pays off the real-world cost in installments.</p><p>The two companies went on to bloviate about how they prioritize “empowering” developers and players “by putting transparency and personalization at the center of every transaction.”</p><p>This news flew under the radar a little bit, which is why I’m dredging it up now. BNPL advocates, which tend to be the companies benefitting from this new, tech-facilitated form of debt, will tell you that they’re offering a service preferable to traditional credit, as payment plans involve fixed terms, can be interest free, and don’t require high credit scores.&nbsp;</p><p>But anybody with a functioning brain will counter that you cannot separate these things from one another as though you’re an old-timey prospector panning for gold. America is a nation built on debt, with a 2024 New York Fed report finding that American household debt sat at <a href="https://www.newyorkfed.org/newsevents/news/research/2024/20240806" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$17.8 trillion</a>. Companies large and small worm their way into the cracks of this busted foundation and, of course, extract profit.&nbsp;</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jun/12/buy-now-pay-later-fall" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Guardian</a>, research has shown that some BNPL users exhibited symptoms of greater financial distress.&nbsp;</p><p>“What you need to think about is the rest of the consumer’s portfolio. If they’re making BNPL payments … maybe they’re not paying off their credit card, maybe they’re not paying their cellphone bill, and that’s actually more concerning,” said Ed deHaan, a researcher who <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4230633" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">published a paper on the matter in 2023</a>. “They’re essentially substituting one payment for another.”</p><p>Additionally, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau – which was trying to <a href="https://aftermath.site/consumer-financial-protection-bureau-game-currency-rule-roblox" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subject games with robust in-game currency marketplaces to cursory regulation</a> before the Trump administration <a href="https://apnews.com/article/donald-trump-doge-cfpb-elon-musk-456b747c367fccbcf3b74d2893cd1a35" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">gutted it earlier this year</a> – published <a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/about-us/newsroom/cfpb-research-reveals-heavy-buy-now-pay-later-use-among-borrowers-with-high-credit-balances-and-multiple-pay-in-four-loans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a report</a> in January showing that more than 60 percent of BNPL users had simultaneous loans and held higher balances on other credit lines, and that most BNPL loans went to consumers with subprime or lower credit scores.</p><p>If you want more granular examples, social media is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KkN6I3gZfGI" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rife with them</a>.</p><p>In other words, these systems disproportionately target people who are either on a slippery slope or have already hit rock bottom. They are parasitic, yet another byproduct of rising costs, economic instability, and wealth disparity. In a functioning society, there would be no need for such a thing, which is why the ludicrous notion of financing burritos became such a pervasive meme. But here we are.&nbsp;</p><p>Unfortunately, I doubt an increasingly desperate video game industry will have any qualms with leaning on Affirm. Young people are <a href="https://www.wsj.com/personal-finance/young-american-consumer-spending-cut-f2b482e5?st=HJkcW3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">spending less on games</a> this year compared to last, but US spending on video game subscriptions, specifically, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3ltjvylgirs2g" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reached an all-time high</a> in May 2025.&nbsp;</p><p>"Looks to me that the pressures of higher prices in everyday spending categories like food and general economic uncertainty has folks looking for value," Circana video game industry analyst Mat Piscatella <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3ltjvylgirs2g" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said on Bluesky</a>.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/xbox-layoffs-microsoft-vested-unvested-shares-stocks"><h3>Xbox’s ‘Golden Handcuffs’ Are Screwing Over Laid Off Workers</h3></a><p>'Unvested shares' are something I didn't even understand last week but this week have been floored by</p></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/buy-now-pay-later-in-game-items-xsolla-affirm]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>