<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 18:00:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Players Are Creating Ships So Wild They’re Making Comic Books Fun Again]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/marvel-rivals-fandom-ships</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-players-are-creating-ships-so-wild-they%E2%80%99re-making-comic-books-fun-again.1170477/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/marvel-rivals-fandom-ships<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Many a team-based hero shooter has tried to dethrone <a href="https://aftermath.site/overwatch-league-sure-was" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Overwatch</em></a>, but <em>Marvel Rivals</em> has quickly gone from being heir apparent to <em>Overwatch 2 </em>killer. Fans have <a href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-overwatch-2-concord-best-hero-shooters-1851726774" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">dissected</a> how its free-to-play model, regular updates, and <a href="https://gamerant.com/marvel-rivals-mcu-skin-prices-backlash/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">flashy-yet-pricey skins </a>have made the game feel like a <a href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-review-hero-shooter-overwatch-netease-1851717975" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">derivative-yet-better iteration</a> of <em>Overwatch</em>’s formula, <a href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-beta-impressions-preview-overwatch-1851610920" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">without all the Blizzard baggage</a>. However, one overlooked aspect of its success among players, which also <a href="https://aftermath.site/overwatch-2-patch-pharah-mercy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">contributed significantly to <em>Overwatch</em>’s staying power</a> among its fandom, is <em>Rivals</em>’ scope for virtually endless shipping.</p><p>A not-insignificant corner of the internet is deeply invested in <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/marvel-rivals-fan-porn-rule-34-1235304254/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Venom’s unexpected tenure as the game’s resident “Girthmaster,”</a> in a flood of not safe for work Source Filmmaker animations, fan art, and <a href="https://x.com/MarvelRivals/status/1905635996643041502" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">throwing his generous symbiote ass in a circle</a> in the game proper. But the real wild card is how <em>Marvel Rivals</em>’ multiverse concept has unlocked a new frontier for unlikely romances.</p><p>We’ve already <a href="https://aftermath.site/the-pitt-mel-langdon-shipping-fanfiction-fandom" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">waxed poetic about</a> the typical tradition of fans crafting stories around their favorite media, and how shipping characters based on their undeniable chemistry is just another delightful extension of that. But these pairings are a different beast: often called “<a href="https://fanlore.org/wiki/Crack_Ship" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crack ships</a>,” a term stemming from the notion that someone must be “on crack” to dream up such a pairing, they’re typically characterized by wholly unexpected and bizarre romantic couplings. These romantic pairings involve characters who barely—if ever—interact with each other in their original stories.&nbsp;</p><p>Despite Marvel comics already teeming with canon ships like Sue Storm and Mr. Fantastic, <em>Marvel Rivals</em>’ multiversal madness has produced crack ships that are strangely compelling because, somehow, no comic book reader or writer has galaxy-brained their way to these compelling match-ups before. What’s more, comic book fans are <a href="https://x.com/DukeOfGotham/status/1912286864439910662" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">waiting</a> to see what new pairings <em>Rivals</em> players, some of them having their first foray into the comic book universe through the game, come up with next. As Aftermath’s resident fandom whisperer and internet culture anthropologist, I couldn’t pass up the chance to spotlight some that are logical, out of pocket, and oddly compelling.&nbsp;</p><p>Many of these ships are spurned by developer <a href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-microsoft-muse-ai-xbox-avowed" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NetEase Games</a> through unique voice line interactions in the game’s match waiting room. A few standout examples include <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hK1dX4sm15Q" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Venom confessing their crush on Scarlet Witch</a> or Groot delighting in being able to communicate with Emma Frost thanks to her telepathy, relishing in her not having to decipher the inflections of him saying his name. These interactions have spawned lukewarm ships, such as Human Torch and original game character Luna Show, due to their whole fire and ice theme; <a href="https://x.com/PoposhiRat/status/1890430807941992822" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Loki and Mantis</a> for their shared quirky outsider vibes; and Winter Soldier and Hawkeye for being old man yaoi. <a href="https://x.com/AztexArts/status/1874092450920464466" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Spider-Man</a>, <a href="https://x.com/smerfols/status/1899206596363997596" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Psylocke</a>, and <a href="https://x.com/nekitoototo/status/1891598968498336100" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Magik </a>are essentially a grab bag of pairings with just about anyone, with Parker being a laid-back guy who can gel with almost anyone, and the other two being the cool, calm, and collected <a href="https://the-dere-types.fandom.com/wiki/Kuudere" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">kudere</a> archetypes that heroes vie for attention from. One of the oddest pairings I’ve stumbled upon is between <em>Guardians of the Galaxy</em>’s <a href="https://x.com/hashtag/StarKnight?src=hashtag_click" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Star-Lord and Moon Knight</a>. I have no idea how this duo even came to be, but based on the fan art, they seem to be operating on a shared single brain cell—and honestly, it's made for a delightfully chaotic couple dynamic. Congratulations to them on whatever they have going on.&nbsp;</p><p>By far one of the most popular ships that is also fresh on the market is the pairing of Bruce Banner with Emma Frost. With a ship name EmmaBruce and an infinitely funnier nickname <a href="https://x.com/dremcclave/status/1912261214945542342" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“Twink Angst,”</a> the Emma Frost and normal purple-shirted science man ship is weirdly one of the fandom’s most compelling pairings yet. As the game’s resident Bayonetta-meets-Nico Robin, Emma Frost has been characterized as a nurturing hero <a href="https://x.com/wandasdoula/status/1908284693545443569" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">who mothers refugee mutants</a> of Krakoa and will <a href="https://x.com/EmmaFrostxoxo/status/1908393029863637071" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">eviscerate anyone who harms Jeff the Land Shark</a>. When you take that energy and mix it with a tired, worn-down Banner who just wants to snuggle up with her and rest, you’ve got a nuclear-grade ship on your hands. The ship, whose inception point appears to have spawned from Twitter artist <a href="https://x.com/Chosentragedy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Chosentragedy</a>, has gotten so immensely popular over a month that Chosentragedy has gone about making a series of short comics where <a href="https://x.com/Chosentragedy/status/1913104798901035126" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bruce introduces Emma to his nerdy hobbies</a> like playing <em>Dungeons and Dragons</em>.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Marvel Rivals</em> has become a vast playground of characters, with the promise of new additions every month, providing an ever-expanding canvas for players to mix and match together, fueling a surge of fan art that has far outpaced the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qETx3QOmEJk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Avengers</em>-era frenzy of the Marvel Cinematic Universe</a>. It’s pretty damn fantastic to see it revitalize the online comic book side of the internet.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/star-wars-zero-company-permadeath-xcom"><h3>Fine, I’ll Play Star Wars XCOM</h3></a><p>It's got permadeath, and that's enough for me</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/kowloon-generic-romance"><h3>Kowloon Generic Romance Is The Closest Anime Has Come To A Wong Kar Wai Film</h3></a><p>Longing, nostalgia, and an unconventional sci-fi tale make for a not-so-generic anime romance
</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>