<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 11:06:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Football Manager 25, An Annual Sports Game, Has Been Scrapped And Won’t Be Out This Season]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/football-manager-25-cancelled</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/football-manager-25-an-annual-sports-game-has-been-scrapped-and-won%E2%80%99t-be-out-this-season.1102863/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/football-manager-25-cancelled<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Hey, remember how back in October <a href="https://aftermath.site/football-manager-25-sports-game-delay" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">I had so many nice things to say about Sports Interactive, and the <em>Football Manager</em> studio's brave decision</a> to buck the sports gaming trend and go to the trouble of rebuilding their entire game on a new engine? Yeah, about that. </p><p>Turns out it's been an absolute disaster. First, in September 2024, <em>Football Manager 25's </em>international mode--where players could manage national sides like England and Brazil--<a href="https://www.footballmanager.com/news/development-update-football-manager-25-0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was binned</a>. Then in October (the games are normally released in November) it was delayed until March 2025. Then promises were made that the first gameplay footage for the game would be shown in January 2025.</p><p>As you can probably tell by looking at a calendar, January 2025 came and went without said footage, leading many fans to fear the worst. Fears that have proved entirely founded, as Sports Interactive today announced that they're scrapping the whole damn thing. <em>Football Manager 25</em> is being canned and there simply won't be a game in the long-running annual series released this season.</p><p>The team's statement reads:</p><blockquote><p>Sports Interactive regret to inform that, following extensive internal discussion and careful consideration with SEGA, we have made the difficult decision to cancel Football Manager 25 and shift our focus to the next release.</p><p>For the large numbers of you who pre-ordered FM25, we thank you enormously for your trust and support - we're very sorry to have let you down.</p><p>We know this will come as a huge disappointment, especially given that the release date has already moved twice, and you have been eagerly anticipating the first gameplay reveal. We can only apologise for the time it has taken to communicate this decision. Due to stakeholder compliance, including legal and financial regulations, today was the earliest date that we could issue this statement.</p><p>We have always prided ourselves on delivering the best value for money games that bring you countless hours of enjoyment, that feel worth every moment and every penny you spend. With the launch of FM25 we set out to create the biggest technical and visual advancement in the series for a generation, laying the building blocks for a new era.</p><p>Due to a variety of challenges that we've been open about to date, and many more unforeseen, we currently haven't achieved what we set out to do in enough areas of the game, despite the phenomenal efforts of our team. Each decision to delay the release was made with the aim of getting the game closer to the desired level but, as we approached critical milestones at the turn of the year, it became unmistakably clear that we would not achieve the standard required, even with the adjusted timeline.</p><p>Whilst many areas of the game have hit our targets, the overarching player experience and interface is not where we need it to be. As extensive evaluation has demonstrated, including consumer playtesting, we have clear validation for the new direction of the game and are getting close - however, we're too far away from the standards you deserve.</p><p>We could have pressed on, released FM25 in its current state, and fixed things down the line - but that's not the right thing to do. We were also unwilling to go beyond a March release as it would be too late in the football season to expect players to then buy another game later in the year.</p><div><p>Through the cancellation, every effort is now focused on ensuring that our next release achieves our goal and hits the quality level we all expect. We will update you on how we are progressing with that as soon as we are able to do so.</p><p>Thank you for reading, your patience and your continued support. Our full focus now returns to creating a new era for Football Manager.</p></div><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>There'll be sadness and frustration from Football Manager obsessives in the days and weeks to come, sure! This long-running series has a lot of equally long-running fans, who are extremely passionate about the game. But hopefully, after they've all taken a deep breath, <a href="https://aftermath.site/ea-fc-madden-nba-2k-recycled-dogshit" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">looked at the situation and the wider sports gaming malaise in general</a>, they'll be somewhat happy with this.</p><p>Sports Interactive didn't have to do this! They could have ploughed on through the years, like EA Sports have done, and release an increasingly tired sports game that slowly bled its fanbase away, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/ea-shares-slump-after-annual-forecast-cut-fans-fears-over-soccer-franchise-2025-01-23/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wondering all the while why sales were in decline</a>. It was a brave decision for SI to tear down their annual sports game and start over, and while it was a risk that has blown up in their faces <em>this season</em>, I'll repeat now what I said when the first delay was announced: "Whatever happens to <em>Football Manager 25</em>, I'm a lot more optimistic about <em>Football Manager 26</em> and <em>27</em> than I am about any other big sports game."</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/sid-meiers-colonization-pc-windows-game"><h3>Sid Meier’s Colonization Is The American Video Game</h3></a><p>No game has told the American story better, whether intentionally or not</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/esa-iicon-e3"><h3>Vowels Are Back As ESA Announces New Conference</h3></a><p>The Interactive Innovation Conference will focus on where games connect to other industries</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sid Meier’s Colonization Is The American Video Game]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/sid-meiers-colonization-pc-windows-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sid-meier%E2%80%99s-colonization-is-the-american-video-game.1102773/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/sid-meiers-colonization-pc-windows-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I've been dying to play a 4X game lately, but having yet to really dig into <em>Civilization VII</em> (which has landed to<a href="https://opencritic.com/game/17742/sid-meiers-civilization-vii" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> some pretty middling reviews</a>!), and which follows in the wake of some pretty disappointing 4X games (<a href="https://aftermath.site/humankind-re-review-amplitude-impressions-pc-sega-4x" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Humankind</em></a>,<a href="https://aftermath.site/millennia-4x-paradox-review" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> <em>Millennia</em></a>, <em>Ara</em>) over the past few years, last week I reached back for one of my favourite--albeit contentious--games of all time: <em>Sid Meier's Colonization</em>.</p><p>I started playing it mostly because it is, to this day, the most laser-focused 4X game available, and as a result the least meandering. <em>Colonization </em>is everything the genre does best--exploration, combat, building little towns and putting little guys to work--and almost none of what it has struggled most with, like convincing diplomacy and dead turns.</p><figure></figure><p>For those who have never played (or heard!) of it: <em>Colonization </em>was released in 1994 on the PC, starts in 1492 and tasks you with choosing to represent one of four imperial European nations--England, Spain, France or the Netherlands--then setting forth to found new colonies in the new world. It is, superficially, a game very much like Sid Meier's more famous series, <em>Civilization</em>, in that you drop guys on a map, build settlements and dig roads and fields between them, but with one notable difference: in <em>Colonization</em> you are controlling a nation of individual guys.</p><p>Some are carpenters, others scouts. There are soldiers, blacksmiths, weavers, priests and teachers. The key to <em>Colonization </em>is recruiting and assigning these guys--and they're all guys--to the parts of the colonies they're best suited to, in order to maximise the amount of resources you can extract, maximise the amount of stuff you make out of those resources and maximise the amount of money you can make selling that stuff back to eager European markets.</p><figure><figcaption>This screen is where you interact with your home port in Europe, buying and selling goods and recruiting immigrants to the colonies.</figcaption></figure><p>Got a colony near a forest? Get a lumberjack and carpenter in there. Next to some mountains? Ship an ore miner over from the old country, dig that metal out of the ground and get a blacksmith to turn it into tools, which you can then turn into muskets. The degree of specialisation available to your population and settlements in this game goes <em>way </em>past <em>Civ</em>, and makes the act of choosing, growing and tending to your settlements the best in the genre.</p><p>Making <em>Colonization </em>even more interesting is that events don't meander towards a finish line, but rather towards a sharp point. The aim is to build up your colonies to a sufficient strength that you can, ala 1776, break free from your mother country. This involves a war of independence where, just like 1776, a seemingly overpowering opponent can be cut down in the woods by some plucky upstarts who know the land, which they've been building on and working for over 200 years.</p><p>Between managing your colonies, tweaking your trade market, dealing with other European nations and preparing for your own [town name] Tea Party, there's never a dull moment in <em>Colonization</em>, and the way the 4X structure works so perfectly for the setting and time period makes it feel like the entire genre was made just for this. For a game from 1994 to loom so large over the genre even&nbsp; in 2025, even after all the <em>Civilization </em>games and their competitors, is testament to the strength and clarity of its design.</p><figure><figcaption>Nearly every American tribe and nation you encounter greets you warmly and offers to share the land with you, hoping for 'everlasting peace'...</figcaption></figure><p>Only, uh. There's a reason we don't really talk about it as much these days. This is also a game with substantial problems. That land you're colonising and developing isn't empty; when you first step off your ships in 1492 you discover that the new world is home to a myriad of nations and tribes, already living in settlements and cities of their own.</p><p><em>Colonization </em>may be the perfect 4X game, but it's also the perfect expression of imperialist thought in strategy video game design, of the idea that progression is everything, that the land you're invading is there to be exploited. <em>Civilization </em>has long had this issue--it's a game that too frequently equates technological progress with dominance--but while there's little introspection to be had in that game when your musketmen roll over some tribal warriors, in <em>Colonization</em> its multiple layers of history and context are unavoidable.</p><p>To its slight credit, and I'm being extremely generous relative to the time it was released here (2009's <em>Empire Total War </em>can only wish it was this nuanced), this game isn't an overt genocide simulator. It certainly <em>allows </em>for the extermination of historical Native American tribes, ranging from the Aztecs to the Sioux, and will even reward the player for doing so by freeing up more land for colonies and offering cash prizes for the destruction of larger settlements. But you are not <em>forced </em>into that route.</p><p>Players are also given the choice--an ahistorical video game fantasy--of living peacefully alongside these nations, sharing resources and knowledge and respecting traditional boundaries. You're rewarded for this too: Tribes will send people to live with you as bonus colonists, trade with you and even teach your colonists expert and much-needed skills like fishing.</p><p>These reward pathways are lopsided though, reflecting the way so much strategy gaming has been trapped within Western history's framework. Sure, there's a peaceful option on the table, but the amount of gold and resources you get for killing the indigenous people off makes it by far the most advantageous pursuit from a gameplay perspective. <em>Colonization </em>isn't <em>making </em>you commit genocide, but in recreating a specific point in history (1492) and asking you to get to <em>another </em>point in history (1776), it's basically telling you the best way to get there is to...follow that history.</p><figure><figcaption>Your conflict with the Old World is made almost inevitable by an escalating series of taxes, which eventually cripples your trade income and forces you into revolutionary action (you can't hold "parties" forever). </figcaption></figure><p>The ultimate goal of the game, regardless of which European nation you start out as, it to build your own United States of America, and the game's story as it is, told through cutscenes and your increasingly hostile diplomacy with your ruling monarch, is full of familiar-sounding ideals when it comes to the American foundational ethos. You're embarking on a brave mission. You build a colony by enduring hardships. You end up fighting a War of Independence to protect your people, to serve freedom in its opposition against tyranny. The same touchstones you see echoing throughout American history books and popular media can be found in <em>Colonization</em>.</p><p>The thing is, the narrative arc of <em>Colonization </em>is as wafer-thin as America's; you're really just building your little video game America exactly the same way the real one was built. From the mass importation of religious fanatics, ruthless opportunists and murderous imperialists, to the seizure of vast tracts of land to the genocide of entire nations.</p><p>(It's very notable the game doesn't allow for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Statute_of_Westminster_1931" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a more gradual, Canadian or Australian-style pathway to nationhood</a>, let alone one like New Zealand's, which featured<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treaty_of_Waitangi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> a formal and lasting treaty signed with the Māori people</a>).</p><figure></figure><p>The conflict between what the United States <em>thinks </em>it is and what it <em>actually </em>is has been perhaps the most dominant force in the study of American history, not to mention popular culture's depiction of it, which can range everywhere from fairy tales like <em>The Patriot</em> to <em>American History X</em>. Rarely has that played out so literally as <em>Colonization,</em> a spin-off strategy title by some guys toying with the 4X genre that has, by design or not, ended up being perhaps the most American video game ever made.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/esa-iicon-e3"><h3>Vowels Are Back As ESA Announces New Conference</h3></a><p>The Interactive Innovation Conference will focus on where games connect to other industries</p></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>