<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 04:51:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Waypoint Writers Quit Following Removal Of Articles About New Steam Policy]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/waypoint-quit-steam-vice</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/waypoint-writers-quit-following-removal-of-articles-about-new-steam-policy.1248558/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Last week, Steam quietly announced a <a href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/gettingstarted/onboarding" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new rule</a> banning “certain kinds of adult-only content” that “may violate the rules and standards set forth by Steam’s payment processors and related card networks and banks.” Following this, reporter Ana Valens wrote a series of stories on Vice’s video games vertical Waypoint about an organization called Collective Shout that <a href="https://x.com/CollectiveShout/status/1946102182325219679" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">took credit</a> for the changes on Steam as part of a campaign aimed at payment processors. Valens says Vice’s owner, Savage Ventures, demanded the removal of the articles; Valens and several other Waypoint writers quit in response.</p><p>Two articles were removed from Waypoint Sunday morning: a July 18 article titled “<a href="https://archive.ph/USxe6" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">This Group Takes Responsibility For Steam's Payment Processor Censorship Policies--They Just Implied 'Pervert Nerds' Cause Society's Problems</a> and a July 19 article titled “<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250719204151/https://www.vice.com/en/article/group-behind-steam-censorship-policies-have-powerful-allies-and-targeted-popular-games-with-outlandish-claims/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Group Behind Steam Censorship Policies Have Powerful Allies–And Targeted Popular Games With Outlandish Claims</a>.” Valens told Aftermath she was informed by Waypoint managing editor Dwayne Jenkins Sunday morning that leadership at Savage Ventures had ordered Jenkins to remove the articles; Valens informed Jenkins that she would quit her Waypoint contributing role if this happened and, once it did, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:hknazlbtwv5thavb7uw52xjz/post/3lufjdqmhxs2v?ref_src=embed&amp;ref_url=https%253A%252F%252Faftermath.site%252Fpreview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced her departure</a>.</p><p>Valens said that both articles had been edited and approved by Jenkins, though did not go through pre-publication legal review. Valens told Aftermath that, as far as she’s aware, there was no legal threat from Collective Shout or other entities over the contents of the articles, though tells Aftermath it’s “possible that [Savage Ventures] simply were afraid of one coming eventually.”&nbsp;</p><p>As <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/australian-anti-porn-group-claims-responsibility-for-steams-new-censorship-rules-in-victory-against-porn-sick-brain-rotted-pedo-gamer-fetishists-and-things-only-get-weirder-from-there/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PCGamer</a> notes, “The two retracted articles from Waypoint appear to be the first among the games press to point out the connection between Collective Shout and the recent changes on Steam, a connection which is public knowledge⁠—by Collective Shout's own statements⁠—and not an allegation made by Waypoint against the group.”</p><p>Valens discussed the situation further in a <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2517618111" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Twitch stream</a> Sunday morning, in which she claimed that Savage Ventures had previously worried about how Waypoint articles covering sexual or political topics might affect the site’s performance on Google. Valens said on stream that “I’ve been told very specifically with a number of articles that it’s an issue with… Google, Google overlords. We actually had to fight very hard to keep some of our more politically-oriented VTuber coverage up because [Savage Ventures] were nervous it was going to be too R-rated for Google… I was told especially [of issues with] Google Discover.” Valens pointed out on stream that the July 19 article had spread particularly widely on social media, including Reddit.&nbsp;</p><p>Requests for comment to email addresses for Vice and Savage Ventures bounced.&nbsp;</p><p>Following Valens’ announcement that she was leaving Waypoint, she posted on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/acvalens.net/post/3lug2bx34522v" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bluesky</a> that “Savage Ventures requested I no longer contribute to VICE… several hours after my announcement.” Later on Sunday, Waypoint writers <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/shauncichacki.bsky.social/post/3lug2qty7m227" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shaun Cichacki </a>and <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/mattvat.bsky.social/post/3lug2ywbiuc23" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Matt Vatankhah</a><strong> </strong>both announced they were quitting the site. “I can't sit back and watch Savage Ventures silence Ana and stifle actual journalism out of fear of being ‘too controversial,’” wrote Vatankhah, while Cichacki wrote that “I cannot stand by and watch [Valens] be censored for doing her job and doing it properly.”</p><p>“Dwayne was a great boss to me,” Valens told Aftermath, adding, “The team I worked with at Waypoint treated me with the utmost respect and care. They were great colleagues.” Jenkins voiced support for Waypoint’s current and former writers on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/lejenk603.bsky.social/post/3lug4fsvt4k2l" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bluesky</a>, noting “At further risk to myself, that's all I can say at the moment.”&nbsp;</p><p>Waypoint previously removed several articles by Valens about VTuber Kirsche Verstahl following Verstahl releasing an “<a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ErvbtgZ4xU4UhCbJeTBeD6G9vnmT6kLq/view" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">open letter</a>” about the coverage that read in part “I don’t want to go to court over this. But… what else am I supposed to do?” An <a href="https://archive.ph/40kfD" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">article by Jenkins </a>about harassment Valens faced surrounding her VTuber coverage was also removed. Waypoint also previously cancelled a <a href="https://www.newsbreak.com/vice-512785/4006265177530-friends-freaks-and-fans-look-forward-to-futa-fridays-featuring-on-um-fridays" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">column</a> Valens planned to write about adult games, and, Valens says, Savage Ventures, “wanted to pull <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/your-mom-and-dad-now-know-what-a-vtuber-is-thanks-to-this-arrest-maybe-sorta/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">an article I did on right-wing extremism in VTubing</a> due to its political content” and over how “such political extremism could impact our standing with Google Discover.” Valens noted to Aftermath that, despite this seeming concern over Waypoint’s content, articles about <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/zoophilia-zoophiles-animal-sex-interviews/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">zoophilia</a> and “<a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/welcome-to-the-age-of-gooning-where-porn-and-pleasure-blur-into-obsession/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">gooning</a>” appear on Vice itself.&nbsp;</p><p>Taking down articles is considered one of the cardinal sins of journalism at many outlets, especially if the outlet believes the article to be factual and to meet its editorial standards. (No public reason was given by Vice for the recent articles' removals.) Most outlets will update, edit, or amend editor’s notes to articles rather than remove them wholesale. Many outlets will also have sensitive stories go through multiple rounds of editorial and legal review before publication, though the scope of this process varies from outlet to outlet.&nbsp;</p><p>Waypoint’s process is unusual in this regard, in that Valens told Aftermath most stories, once approved by Jenkins, are edited after publication. Some sensitive stories are edited beforehand, which Valens told Aftermath happened with the July 18 story but not the July 19 one. Valens told Aftermath that "I do think Savage Ventures did not give adequate editorial support to Waypoint and Dwayne. During my time there, there wasn’t a second editor on staff to help with shepherding out news stories on any sensitive subject matters, whether my own work or others.’”&nbsp;</p><p>A lack of editors at Waypoint (or <a href="https://pressgazette.co.uk/publishers/journalism-job-cuts-2025-tracked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">many journalism outlets</a> these days) is unsurprising: Vice shuttered the original Waypoint in <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/vice-shutting-down-waypoint" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">April 2023</a>, and much of its staff went on to form worker-owned outlet <a href="https://remapradio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Remap</a>. Vice declared bankruptcy in <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/style/media/2024/02/22/vice-media-shuts-down-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">February 2024</a> and laid off the majority of its staff, then was <a href="https://variety.com/2024/digital/news/vice-digital-joint-venture-savage-ventures-vice-news-1235997565/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">relaunched</a> in May of that year under the steam of Nashville-based “<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/savage-ventures/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">venture operator</a>” Savage Ventures. In October 2024 <a href="https://aftermath.site/waypoint-vice-remap" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Waypoint began publishing again</a> with new <a href="https://aftermath.site/vice-waypoint-site-news-reopen-open" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">writers</a>. Valens said on her stream that she was paid $30 an article; a contributor to the previous iteration of Waypoint, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/nickcapozzoli.bsky.social/post/3lugc46uya22r" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nick Capozzoli</a>, said rates used to be at least $300.</p><p><a href="https://aftermath.site/freelance-video-game-journalism-rates" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Underpaid writers</a>, understaffed sites, and ownership that feels <a href="https://aftermath.site/game-informer-archives-closed-illegal" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">no allegiance</a> to the work their sites produce is pretty much <a href="https://aftermath.site/video-games-journalism-2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">par for the course</a> in games journalism these days. As experienced reporters and editors leave or are forced out of the field, and as sites fall into the hands of <a href="https://aftermath.site/kotaku-sale-keleops-go" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">private equity</a> or traffic-obsessed <a href="https://aftermath.site/polygon-layoffs-sale" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">conglomerates</a>, there’s less support for writers day to day, and less support for sites from above. Ownership that is distanced from their sites’ writers or sees those sites as revenue sources more than news outlets providing a service to readers has little incentive to stand by a site’s work or to provide it with the editorial or legal support it needs. And, as usual, it’s the writers who pay the price, whether that’s losing their jobs or feeling like it’s necessary to quit.</p><p><strong>Note</strong>:&nbsp;<em>Aftermath co-founder Gita Jackson previously worked at Vice's Motherboard, and appeared on Waypoint's site and podcast.</em></p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/warframe-old-peace-world-war-one-interview-tennocon"><h3>Warframe, Still A Space Ninja Game (Technically), Is Now Drawing Inspiration From World War I</h3></a><p>"I liken it to the moment in World War I where you have soldiers playing football on Christmas day across the trenches"</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/friendslop-peak-lethal-company-social-media-discourse"><h3>‘Friendslop’ Isn’t Real, But People Love Posting About It Anyway</h3></a><p>But people are still intent on dunking on the idea of someone saying "friendslop" and meaning it.</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/waypoint-quit-steam-vice]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warframe, Still A Space Ninja Game (Technically), Is Now Drawing Inspiration From World War I]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/warframe-old-peace-world-war-one-interview-tennocon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warframe-still-a-space-ninja-game-technically-is-now-drawing-inspiration-from-world-war-i.1248144/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>“Wait, so what kind of game is <em>Warframe</em>, exactly?” is a common refrain among people who don’t play <em>Warframe</em>, upon hearing someone try to explain <em>Warframe</em>. So here, let me help: The sci-fi space ninja shooter’s previous expansion took players to the year 1999, where – by <a href="https://aftermath.site/warframe-1999-romance-dating-tennocon-soulframe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">dating a bunch of hot people</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YtF6jiLxc88" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">listening to boy band music</a> – they uncovered key revelations about the nature of the universe. How do you follow that? Easy: World War I-inspired anime fights.</p><p>This only makes slightly more sense in context than out of it, but the beauty of <em>Warframe </em>is that it is constantly, sometimes to its own detriment, trying shit. The end result is a broad emotional palette, a decade-running narrative that can detour into tongue-in-cheek ‘90s-stalgia before pivoting back into a tale of war, woe, and what happens when one group attempts to subjugate all others. The game’s next narrative quest expansion, <a href="https://www.warframe.com/news/tennocon-2025-recap" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The Old Peace</em></a> launches later this year and takes place during the war between the Orokin, the ancient civilization that set the game’s whole story into motion, and the Sentients, Orokin creations that ultimately turned on their masters after being thrust into the dangerous Tau system. The Tenno, Orokin child soldiers forced to psychically pilot flesh mechs (and <em>Warframe</em>’s player faction), end up stuck in the middle.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="TennoCon 2025 | The Old Peace | Official Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bfoypaVNGuU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Ultimately, <em>Warframe </em>will head to an entire new solar system – the aforementioned, long-whispered-about Tau – in 2026, but this quest sets the stage by letting players venture into Tau’s past.&nbsp;</p><p>“We're really going to lean into themes of true war, and that's the state you left this moon and Tau in,” creative director Rebb Ford told Aftermath. “That way, when you go back there, you'll recognize everything in the same way a battle of old would be recognized."&nbsp;</p><p>True to <em>Warframe</em>’s name, other narrative quests have already depicted the conflict that took place during that era; this one explores a brief, brittle period of peace. A demo, which <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FSqwET8-P-Q&amp;t=21575s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">debuted today at TennoCon</a> in London, Ontario, shows one of the game’s lithe not-quite-cyborg ninjas sliding and soaring through trenches straight out of World War I as fire rains down. This turns out to be a training exercise between a Tenno and their Sentient schoolmate Adis, but the choice of imagery is no coincidence. World War I influences, creative director Rebb Ford told Aftermath, are more than skin deep.</p><p>“I’ve been kind of addicted to reading World War I novels,” she said. “[We’re going to explore] the idea that war happens so quickly when people make a decision that impacts the peace and armistice.”</p><p>As far as players understood previously, the Orokin and Sentinels fought bitterly, the Tennos turned the tide, and that was that. The idea that the two sides buried the hatchet, even briefly, is new to this expansion.</p><p>"I liken it to the moment in World War I where you have soldiers playing football on Christmas day across the trenches,” lead writer Adrian Bott told Aftermath. “That all-too-brief moment of commonality between enemies and recognizing something in one another – the idea of playing in this environment of trenches and devastation."</p><p>Of course, <em>The Old Peace</em> is not a 1:1 World War I story (space ninjas tend to get in the way of that), but the developers at Digital Extremes want players to recognize that every war past and present is a tragedy – specifically, a human one.</p><p>"I learned to be a storyteller through tourism and teaching history, and in that sense, when you forget to tell the human story inside history and abstract it to just names and dates, that's where teaching history in schools goes wrong,” principal writer Kat Kingsley told Aftermath. “When you just say 'Then this number of people died, and it happened on this day,' it just goes in one ear and out the other. One thing I think <em>Warframe </em>does really well is, it takes these epic sci-fi fantasy stories and tells them from a human aspect. It connects them to human emotions, even if they involve the wildest science fiction characters. I think with this update, we're telling a war story from a [place] of human emotion."</p><figure><blockquote><p>That all-too-brief moment of commonality between enemies and recognizing something in one another – the idea of playing in this environment of trenches and devastation.</p></blockquote></figure><p>As a result, the developers focused more on studying individuals’ battlefield horror stories, rather than the history books.&nbsp;</p><p>"I've not delved into things like historical records, the kind of thing that could distance you,” said Bott. “I've really tried much more to refresh my familiarity with [war poets], the men who were on the ground describing things. I think the idea of war poetry in itself might seem ironic, but it's not rendering something brutal whimsical in the slightest. It was finding a way to communicate what Wilfred Owen calls 'the pity of war distilled.' ... Drawing attention to it and saying 'This is the reality of what we suffer. This is what war is. This is what we went through.'"</p><p><em>Warframe </em>also boasts a long history of using music to bolster its space opera – up to and including full-band songs with lyrics and lore, so many of which now exist that this year’s TennoCon featured <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dKai40IaURo" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a nearly-stadium-sized concert</a> with multiple vocalists and a pyrotechnics show (Ford played bass in the band). <em>The Old Peace</em> leans into this particular penchant, albeit in a more somber way than <em>1999</em>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>"The song sung by the Sentients to one another as they crossed the deep gulf of space [to Tau], it's got that kind of pioneering vibe to it, but it's also got a fatalistic vibe,” said Bott. “There's a direct inspirational link between 'There is some corner of foreign field that is forever England' and 'Who but we shall distant die on that far shore forlorn.' It's that same sense of 'We know that we are fated to eventually perish on some literally alien landscape,' but that is our nature, that is our destiny.'”</p><p>"'We've been made to die,'" added Kingsley.</p><p>It’s a stark tonal shift away from <em>Warframe</em>’s previous expansion, but the developers at Digital Extremes are confident in their ability to navigate it.</p><p>"<em>Warframe</em> tries to never repeat itself beat for beat, and because <em>1999 </em>was more tongue-in-cheek and was goofier and more humorous, this is more of a return to form," said Kingsley.</p><p>"I think [giving people something like <em>1999</em>] would have been an easy thing to do, but that's why we didn't do it,” said Bott. “The intent is to deliver something that is, palette wise, completely different than what we just did, and that is something we have done again and again.”</p><figure><figcaption>Digital Extremes</figcaption></figure><p>If nothing else, it’s relevant subject matter, considering the ever-worsening state of the world. But as far as Ford is concerned, that’s always been the case.</p><p>"My mom is a very eccentric woman, and she sent me a text about two months ago. She was born in the 50s, and she said 'Ever since I've been born until the day I die, the world has been at war,’” Ford said. “She's only known war her whole life despite living in the most peaceful times, and there's never been more peace. But you can't really say that with the world we have where everything is so accessible, especially stories of what's going on with conflict and war."</p><p>"The inspiration for taking a slice of time where a treaty should have happened and what's going on, it of course is coming from anything the globe can put in front of us.” she added. “We can look at it and we can say, 'How can we make this human story about space kids that control robots be rooted in the truth of all war?'"</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/waypoint-quit-steam-vice"><h3>Waypoint Writers Quit Over Removal Of Articles Related To New Steam Policy</h3></a><p>Two articles by writer Ana Valens were removed at the demand of Vice owner Savage Ventures, the latest in multiple deletions at the site</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/friendslop-peak-lethal-company-social-media-discourse"><h3>‘Friendslop’ Isn’t Real, But People Love Posting About It Anyway</h3></a><p>But people are still intent on dunking on the idea of someone saying "friendslop" and meaning it.</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/warframe-old-peace-world-war-one-interview-tennocon]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>