<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:22:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Look Out, I’m The Bus]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/bus-bound-demo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/look-out-i%E2%80%99m-the-bus.1325428/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Let’s get this out of the way, especially if my parents are reading: I <em>can</em> drive a car in real life. I <em>haven’t</em> in about 15 years, because I live in New York City, and also because an ex-boyfriend convinced me I was bad at it, but I usually say that if there were some emergency that necessitated me operating a motor vehicle, I could do it. Despite what that ex-boyfriend insisted, I recall being a safe and thoroughly serviceable driver, if a little anxious. But I am not anxious in the <em>Bus Bound</em> demo: I am confidently terrible at being the bus.&nbsp;</p><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2095420/Bus_Bound/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Bus Bound</em></a><em>, </em>which<em> </em>has a demo as part of Steam Next Fest, sees you taking passengers around the bus routes of the city of Emberville. Excitingly, bus rides are free for passengers (<a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/society/new-york-city-bus-free-fare/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">it can work!</a>), with a character telling you that “our funding comes from the city council based on how well our passengers think we’re doing.” As you drive your route and make stops, you get a number of thumbs ups from riders depending on how well you drive; these are used to unlock new busses, bus stops, and routes.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Bus Bound - Official Announcement Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/She5fJmo-pA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Rather than simply sit back and marvel at their city’s robust free bus service, passengers have a lot of opinions. They like when I roll gently over speed bumps or get them to their destination on time. They don’t like when I slam on the brakes and honk my horn because a cop turning right on red cuts me off. They don’t like when I park too far from the curb. They <em>really</em> don’t like when I smash into cars around us because I am a god damn <em>bus </em>and a bus is freaking <em>huge</em>, its turns way wider than I think and it taking far longer to slow down than I keep planning for. The passengers make their mean little frowns and say their nasty little comments about how they <em>didn’t ask for bumper cars</em> or <em>surprise obstacle course: failed</em> and I yell “Shut up, I’m the bus!” at them as we all smash around being the bus.</p><p>There are a lot of nice touches in <em>Bus Bound</em>: you can switch from a view from behind and above the bus to the first-person perspective of the driver easily, which I found helpful for checking if cars are coming but not so helpful for remembering that I am a bus that is the size of a bus. When you put on your turn signal you get a view of your mirrors. You can customize your bus colors in fun ways. Letting passengers on and off is a nice little process of engaging the parking brake, opening the doors, and then doing it all in reverse. The game has weather; in the rain, rivulets obscured my screen until I turned the wipers on, at which point the water didn’t simply vanish but hung around, really feeling like peering through a windshield.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>It's good rain (stillalive studios/Aftermath)</figcaption></figure><p>Emberville itself is fascinating to drive through, absolutely stuffed with shops, billboards, and ads. It would be nice if you could walk around it on foot, because I kept swinging my camera around while driving to check everything out and then forgetting to focus on the road. I would like to be a passenger on my bus, or a bus driven by someone better at being a bus than me, just so I can look out the window at everything. It’s good that the city is a busy place to be; I can imagine the game’s core requirement of driving routes to grind out thumbs ups could get repetitive in the full game.</p><p>But I don’t mind the repetition. In driving sims like <em>Euro Truck 2, </em>I love the everydayness of doing my chores, driving my routes and listening to the radio and getting to places on time. Even when I drove the same <em>Bus Bound</em> route multiple times, I found it satisfying to see the same streets at different times of day, parking a little better or getting a little closer to being on time or staying below the speed limit more often. I didn’t <em>try</em> to keep causing massive pileups, or sideswiping pedestrians, or pulling out into traffic without looking. I <em>wanted </em>a calm, routine day as the bus–it’s just that the bus is a bus, and this is how busses are.</p><p>So I’m not great at being the virtual bus, but I swear I can drive in real life. And unlike the ex-boyfriend who convinced me I couldn’t, <em>I’ve</em> never clipped a mail truck while driving an empty school bus without a CDL, so whatever. (We owned a school bus. It's a long story.)</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/hasan-piker-dog-collar-kaya-nontroversy-twitch"><h3>I Can’t Believe We’re Still Talking About This</h3></a><p>CollarGate is one of the internet's dumbest psychosis events yet</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-assassins-creed-reconstruction-ubisoft"><h3>Everything Is Assassin’s Creed</h3></a><p>"You can look at 15-ish games at this point and watch, nearly yearly, the progression toward the world we live in today"</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/bus-bound-demo]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>