<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:44:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Somehow, The Threat Of A Live-Action Akira Refuses To Die]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/kodansha-studios-akira-anime-live-ation-chloe-zhao-nicolas-gonda</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/somehow-the-threat-of-a-live-action-akira-refuses-to-die.1343848/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>This year <a href="https://variety.com/2025/film/news/box-office-demon-slayer-infinity-castle-biggest-anime-opening-1236516498/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Demon Slayer: Infinity Castle</em> </a>and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/chainsaw-man-movie-reze-arc-box-office-weekend-premiere/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Chainsaw Man – The Movie: Reze Arc</em></a> played spoiler at the box office in their respective opening weekends (for the pocket-watching pundits among us), aweing moviegoers with the indescribable spark of magic animation. Anime has legs and is worth taking seriously as a new direction in cinema. Instead of addressing the 2D elephant of a lesson in the face, Hollywood said, “You know what the world really needs? More live-action anime films.”</p><p>According to an exclusive report from <a href="https://deadline.com/2025/11/chloe-zhao-manga-kodansha-studios-1236605962/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Deadline</a> (on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/kodansha.us/post/3m4qpg6tpu32x" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">manga day</a>, no less), Chloé Zhao, two-time Oscar winner behind<em> Nomadland</em> and Marvel’s <em>Eternals</em>, and Nicholas Gonda are teaming up with manga publisher <a href="https://aftermath.site/heres-the-dumb-shit-you-have-to-put-up-with-to-read-manga-these-days" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kodansha</a> to head up a global studio called Kodansha Studios. Kodansha Studios, in turn, will exist for the express purpose of creating “premium, live action movies and television series” based on manga from Kodansha. To break this down in comic book movie terms, Kodansha is pulling a DC Studios by having Zhao and Gonda become their <a href="https://gizmodo.com/james-gunn-head-of-dc-movies-and-tv-warner-bros-1849701460" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">James Gunn and Peter Safran</a>, guiding a <a href="https://gizmodo.com/report-david-zaslav-pushed-back-on-ta-nahesi-coates-black-superman-movie-for-being-too-woke-2000628090" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new era of live-action anime films</a> to a cinematic golden age. All the while, ensuring quality control, fostering healthy communication between international directors and manga creators, and developing solid scripts to bring their work to light. Hopefully, this will make the phrase “live-action anime film” less of a punchline than it has been over the past decade by utilizing Kodansha's manga catalog.&nbsp;</p><p>On paper, all of it sounds lovely, set against the haphazard wild west of <a href="https://kotaku.com/netflix-one-piece-yu-yu-hakusho-anime-live-action-netfl-1850050620" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">random-ass live-action Hollywood adaptations</a> that have seen the light of day and are looming menacingly over the horizon. But it's hard not to reflexively recoil when the Deadline piece namedrops “beloved manga” like Katsuhiro Otomo’s <em>Akira</em>,<em> </em>and go, “God dammit, they’re gonna try doing it again.”</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="The Impact of Akira: The Film that Changed Everything" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IqVoEpRIaKg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>If there is any anime that could be considered Hollywood’s Moby Dick, it is <em>Akira</em>. Still, Kodansha Studios' mere existence essentially shows that, despite decades of false starts, studio reshuffles, and directorial ghosting—such as <a href="https://gizmodo.com/warner-bros-gives-up-on-akira-remake-but-hollywood-wont-2000621686" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Warner Bros. shelving its version</a> in the early 2000s, <a href="https://gizmodo.com/jordan-peele-nope-akira-adaption-references-film-1850048374" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jordan Peele</a> politely declining, and <a href="https://gizmodo.com/taika-waititi-still-plans-on-directing-akira-eventuall-1839207999" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Taika Waititi</a> eventually withdrawing after years of development hell—<em>Akira</em> remains Hollywood’s promised-yet-elusive cash cow. With Kodansha Studios declaring its raison d’être as “premium live-action projects” (whatever that means), the thought that <em>Akira </em>might be their flagship effort feels like creative ambition and more like comedic arrogance. Should <em>Akira </em>prove to be the hill Kodansha Studios chose to die on, with the promise of guaranteed success because it’s popular, it’s hard not to stifle a laugh at the thought of it still attempting to see the light of day.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="RARE // MAKING OF AKIRA DOCUMENTARY FROM 1988 // ENGLISH SUBS" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BXsar5rpgwg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Tokyo Movie Shinsha’s 1988 <a href="https://gizmodo.com/akira-35-year-retrospective-impact-1850645834" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Akira</em></a> isn’t just a sci-fi anime film. It’s a miracle. A once-in-history convergence built on unheard-of budget, artistic labor, and technical muscle that animated over 160,000 cels and hand-painted matte backgrounds with the kind of obsessive artistry that <a href="https://www.crunchyroll.com/news/latest/2020/6/8/akira-anime-film-producer-corrects-30-year-fact-on-how-much-the-groundbreaking-film-cost-to-make?srsltid=AfmBOorrcZSOtdh698GQTcySSmgOi-xMhlmUSUnrM1vhjt7qmmXVFb0E" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">no studio today could bankroll</a>. The film isn’t just looked back on as lightning in a bottle but as a global flag-planting moment that declared anime as a cutting-edge art form worth taking seriously. Threatening to recapture it in live action isn’t just misguided—it verges on being creatively bankrupt. Undeterred by taste, history, hubris, or the sheer impossibility of doing it justice.&nbsp;</p><p>To quote YouTuber Cosmonaut Marcus in his succinctly titled video, <a href="https://youtu.be/f9I-s2UwxZk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Why I Hate Live-Action Anime Adaptations</a>, “If you agree to adapt an anime into a live-action TV show or movie for Hollywood, then it means that you are already disrespecting the source material because in any great animated work, the beauty goes beyond the story or the characters, usually it's good because it's animated.”&nbsp;</p><p>While I’m <a href="https://aftermath.site/bet-kakegurui-netflix-live-action-anime" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a bit of a sicko</a> who likes some live-action adaptations on their own merits, I agree with the latter half of Marcus’ take. Roughly 90 percent of why anime fans like the medium is the moving drawings. So reading this news in concert with Sony, through its <a href="https://gizmodo.com/sonys-potential-kadokawa-acquisition-could-tighten-its-grip-on-anime-and-manga-2000526376" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fucked up homunculus merger with Kadokawa</a>, also plans to <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/entertainment/anime-movies/sony-is-stepping-up-its-plans-for-more-live-action-movie-adaptations-of-anime-and-manga-properties/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ramp up its live-action efforts</a>, despite their direct financial success from <em>Demon Slayer</em> and <em>Chainsaw Man</em>, has me both fucking exasperated and side-eyeing Kodansha Studios playing follow the leader.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Tokyo Movie Shinsha</span></figcaption></figure><p>It’s not like Kodansha hasn’t had successes with already-made anime adaptations of its works; they're special because they're animated beautifully, filling in the gaps in manga panel artistry for anime fans without losing their artistry. And Kodansha’s library has proven to yield some of the most memorable anime films, like <em>Weathering With</em> <em>You </em>and <em>A Silent Voice</em>—<em>anime</em> films being the operative word.&nbsp;</p><p>Playing devil's advocate, there are exceptions to the rule of live action adaptations not being an entire crapshoot, but mainly as a reflection in fans' eyes in retrospect as cult classic hits with the likes of Tom Cruise and Emily Blunt-led<em> </em><a href="https://gizmodo.com/all-you-need-is-kill-anime-movie-trailer-edge-of-tomorrow-warner-bros-2000575528" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Live Die Repeat</em></a> and The Wachowskis’ <em>Speed Racer</em> (pound for pound <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vwh9ETdhrf4&amp;t=2980s" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the best live action anime film of all time</a>). There’s even been pretty decent live-action ventures in the past, like <a href="https://kotaku.com/what-we-loved-no-really-about-alita-battle-angel-1832758443" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Alita Battle Angel</em></a>, and that Netflix adaptation of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eLfE-WiHAWU&amp;pp=ygUdbGFzdCBzYW11cmFpIHN0YW5kaW5nIG5ldGZsaXjSBwkJAwoBhyohjO8%3D" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Last Samurai Standing</em></a> looks promising. But for every success, there’s also monumental failures from leveraging Kodansha’s catalogue for live-action works—your Scarlett Johansson-led <a href="https://www.wyomingnewspapers.org/?a=d&amp;d=WYWPN20170501-01.1.7&amp;srpos=1&amp;e=-------en-20-WYWPN-1--img-txIN%7CtxCO%7CtxTA-isaiah+colbert+ghost+in+the+shell-------0------" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Ghost in the Shell</em></a>.</p><p>Should Zhao and Gonda prove masterful international directors and original mangaka matchmakers, bringing underappreciated gems into the mainstream with “premium” live-action projects for works like all power to them. Works less likely to make folks reflexively throw their arms up like hearing “live action <a href="https://kotaku.com/my-hero-academia-netflix-live-action-anime-bnha-movie-1849883927" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>My Hero Academia</em></a> or live action <a href="https://gizmodo.com/naruto-live-action-film-lionsgate-1851047617" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Naruto</em></a>,” not helping themselves by going for big-spectacle, fantasy-laden shonen hits with an even larger margin for error, for the disrespect Marcus mentioned earlier, to bring it to live action and look shit. If the first of their projects is <em>Akira</em>, <a href="https://gizmodo.com/gachiakuta-doesnt-just-redefine-shonen-anime-it-anoints-itself-as-the-next-big-thing-2000622249" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Gachiakuta</em></a><em>,</em> <em>Fire Punch</em>, or <em>Shangra La Frontier</em>, because they’re popular fantastical works, then all good will for Kodansha Studios is lost.</p><p>If Kodansha Studios instead invests in showcasing its creative skills through greenlighting live-action series and films based on more realistic sleeper hits in seinen and shojo genres, like <em>Princess Jellyfish</em>, <em>Blue Period</em>,<em> Hajime no Ippo</em>, or (<a href="https://gizmodo.com/vinland-saga-creator-makoto-yukimura-looks-back-on-writing-his-pacifist-viking-epic-2000664303" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">gulp</a>) <em>Vinland Saga,</em> then, and only then, can it flirt with its strength as a studio capable of delivering on its promises for all its so-called premium projects. Do that, and I can have faith in prospective Kodansha Studio live-action adaptations of series like <em>Knights of Sidonia</em>, <em>Land of the Lustrous</em>, <em>To Your Eternity</em>, <em>Tower Dungeon</em>, and be less gun-shy about them possibly tackling <em>Akira</em>.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/i-owe-my-workday-to-criterion-24-7"><h3>I Owe My Workday To Criterion 24/7</h3></a><p>If you’re going to have cotton candy, you have to eat your vegetables too.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/europa-universalis-v-review-impressions-paradox-pc-eu5"><h3>How Am I Supposed To Review Europa Universalis V</h3></a><p>There is simply too much video game here, and it's always in motion</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-halo-white-house-trump-vance"><h3>And Also, Who Even Cares About Halo And Lord Of The Rings These Days</h3></a><p>"All of these things do have a feeling of dragging and resuscitating a corpse"</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/kodansha-studios-akira-anime-live-ation-chloe-zhao-nicolas-gonda]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>