<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 16:20:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Good Are The Skin Deep Opening Credits]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/skin-deep-credits-soundtrack</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-good-are-the-skin-deep-opening-credits.1199523/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/skin-deep-credits-soundtrack<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I'm woefully behind on checking out <em>Skin Deep</em>, an immersive sim by Blendo Games that came out at the end of April, despite the fact that it is an immersive sim and thus the ideal Riley game. I finally started playing last night; while I'm still coming to grips with what feels like its intentionally clunky controls, I absolutely love its opening credits.</p><p><strong>(Light spoilers for the narrative setup of <em>Skin Deep</em>.)</strong></p><p>Playing the early hours last night, I forgot that we hadn't seen a title sequence until the game smash-cut into an intro. Like a reward for having to suffer through a <a href="https://aftermath.site/indiana-jones-great-circle-camera" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">camera quest</a>, the game suddenly launches into a jazzy, Bond movie-style opening. It has some clever rhymes, some great riffs, and you even get to walk around a bit in an arena of giant props and furniture.    </p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Skin Deep (2025) — Opening/Intro Scene" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/z4DdKOf6f9s?start=97&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>The song tells a little narrative of facing off against a powerful enemy (who is... also you?) and shifts the vibes of the game from a slapstick comedy into something classy and intriguing. It ends, satisfyingly, on the game's title, something I'm always a sucker for. I love how the style of the song paints a contrast to my experience so far of getting myself stuck in dusty vents and running around spaceships desperately looking for a place to dump angry heads before someone else finds me. </p><p>In a <a href="https://www.startmenu.co.uk/home/skin-deep-music-interview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">conversation with Start Menu</a>, composer Priscilla Snow said the current opening was their second take, with the first being a "slinky lounge song." Snow brought on collaborators and added the song's excellent brass arrangement, and said that while the song was “definitely the most difficult track to get through... I went from dreading the theme song and being stressed and anxious about it to being excited about it" through these changes. </p><p>The whole <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/5FsGxEbvms3LEiofVe8b06" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">soundtrack</a>, or what I've heard of it so far, is a banger. It's 59 tracks, a wild amount for a game that folks say <a href="https://howlongtobeat.com/game/91393" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">isn't too long</a>. I was charmed to catch a weird electronic wisp of viral sea shanty "<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wellerman" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wellerman</a>" that has an incongruous harpsichord-sounding breakdown in it, and I'm excited to hear what else is out there as I play more of the game. I feel like we're in a renaissance of <a href="https://aftermath.site/clair-obscur-soundtrack-interview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">good game soundtracks</a> lately, which I can at least enjoy as I frantically try to chip away at my backlog of Too Many Good Games Recently.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/9-kings-pc-roguelike-deckbuilder-impressions-pc-steam"><h3>9 Kings: It’s A Good Video Game</h3></a><p>Play some cards, slaughter some guys</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/doom-bathroom-renovation-something-awful-for-sale"><h3>Please Know That The House With The Doom Bathroom Is For Sale</h3></a><p>Calling it a 'uniquely remodeled home' seems like an understatement</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/hockey-stickhandling-video-game-dangleverse"><h3>This Video Game Is Also a Hockey Training Tool</h3></a><p>Dangleverse, which I've been using to practice hockey off the rink, is in beta right now</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/geoguessr-blackout-esports-world-cup-saudi-arabia"><h3>GeoGuessr Map Makers Make Most Popular Maps Unplayable In Protest Of Saudi-Backed Esports World Cup [Update]</h3></a><p>"The GeoGuessr community is diverse and includes many members of groups that would be harshly persecuted were they to live in Saudi Arabia"</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>