<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 06:33:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beloved Loser Horse That Inspired A Generation (And An Umamusume Anime Girl) Dies]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/haru-urara-horse-death-umamusume</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/beloved-loser-horse-that-inspired-a-generation-and-an-umamusume-anime-girl-dies.1293159/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>On Friday, I went to <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/nathangrayson.bsky.social/post/3ly54pyazjk2c" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a rave</a> celebrating a series about fleet-footed anime girls based on real-life race horses. Today, the most-beloved of those IRL inspirations, a dismally untalented horse named Haru Urara, died at age 29, which is pretty old for a horse. An incredible number of people – far more than anyone ever would have expected even a scant few months ago – are in mourning.</p><p>The official Twitter account of <em>Umamusume</em>, the aforementioned <a href="https://aftermath.site/uma-musume-gacha-horse-racing-anime" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">anime horse girl sensation</a> that continues to sweep multiple nations, broke the news to fans earlier today.</p><p>“It is with heavy hearts that we share that Haru Urara passed away on September 9,” <a href="https://x.com/umamusume_eng/status/1965367711531434346" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote the account</a>, which has become <a href="https://x.com/umamusume_eng/status/1953800765572632981?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">something of a horse death tracker</a> in recent months. “The legendary racehorse's legacy serves as the inspiration for the character of the same name in <em>Umamusume: Pretty Derby</em>. We share our condolences to all the staff involved in Haru Urara's care.”</p><p>Across social media, fans have come together to celebrate the not-so-mighty mare’s life.&nbsp;</p><p>“Rest in peace, you will forever live in our hearts, our shining hope,” reads <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/UmaMusume/comments/1nce1jh/comment/nd8hotc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">one comment on Reddit</a> that’s received thousands of upvotes.</p><p>"I came to [university] to do something I loved and started hating cuz of uni and the competition, and AI is taking the role I am going with," reads <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/UmaMusume/comments/1nce1jh/comment/nd8jwp8/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">another</a>. "Haru Urara['s] story gave me a second wind, and I am going ballistic with my side projects and getting myself better. It's because Haru never gave up and enjoyed the run. Losing is never painful if you are enjoying your run. REST IN PEACE Haru Urara."</p><p>Many, many others have shared fan art of Haru Urara’s <em>Umamusume </em>character, including <a href="https://x.com/LuisArreol33565/status/1965370342681313323" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">an image of her being reunited</a> with other in-game characters whose IRL inspirations have passed.</p><p>Race horses are <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/15/medina-spirit-scandal-horse-abuse-bob-baffert" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">treated about as well as the dirt they run on</a>, and this goes double for those who underperform. The story of Haru Urara’s career ranks among the saddest; before she retired in 2004, she lost every single one of her 113 races.&nbsp;</p><p>"Race horses are destroyed when they don't win," Haru Urara’s former trainer, Dai Muneishi, <a href="https://www.scotsman.com/news/world/horse-that-never-wins-has-become-the-toast-of-japan-2459872" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">told The Scotsman</a> in 2004 (via <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/racing/millions-of-gamers-on-steam-and-beyond-gather-to-mourn-famously-untalented-horse-who-inspired-the-beloved-anime-girl-in-umamusume-haru-urara-may-she-get-all-the-grass-and-carrots-in-heaven/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gamesradar</a>). "But to my way of thinking, a horse is also a living being, and it's inexcusable to destroy it at the mere whim of humans."</p><p>Muneishi also described Haru Urara as “physically small” and fearful of other horses. As a result, training her to race was an ordeal.</p><p>The tide began to turn for Haru Urara in 2003, at the tail end of her time on the tracks, when Japanese media took notice of her unlikely record, which then stood at a mere 80 consecutive losses. That sudden surge in popularity saved her life; in 2003 her then-owner <a href="https://www.thetimes.com/travel/destinations/asia-travel/japan/horse-on-losing-trot-could-be-worlds-worst-lh9p86fnjbt" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">told The Times</a> that she’d been on a collision course with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knacker" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the knacker’s yard</a> prior to that point.&nbsp;</p><p>At the peak of her fame in 2004, Haru Urara was dubbed “the shining star of losers everywhere” and lured 13,000 spectators out to the Kochi Racetrack in Kochi, Japan where, despite being ridden by Japan's top jockey, Yutaka Take, she lost her 106th race.</p><p>At the time, <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/asia-pacific/3558275.stm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BBC wrote</a>:</p><blockquote><p>Japanese television ran footage of the race, focusing on the mare with her trademark pink "Hello Kitty" hood.</p><p>"All the fans seem to be going home happy," a reporter covering for Asahi TV said.</p><p>"They feel that it was OK for her to lose."</p><p>Correspondents say Haru Urara, the eternal loser who does not give up, has struck a chord with those Japanese who have lost most during the past decade of economic stagnation and job losses.</p><p>Her spectacular lack of success is also proving as profitable as it is inspirational. Kochi racecourse, nearly bankrupt, has seen its revenues shoot up.</p><p>Others are also cashing in with "Haru" tours, t-shirts, good luck charms said to contain a hair from her tail, books, and postage stamps. There is a pop song about her and a movie is in the works.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>Haru Urara’s career <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E3%83%8F%E3%83%AB%E3%82%A6%E3%83%A9%E3%83%A9#CITEREF%E9%80%B1%E5%88%8A%E6%96%B0%E6%BD%AE2008" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">concluded</a> with a dispute between her trainer, owner, and others about whether she remained fit to race – along with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/UmaMusume/comments/1mn9uuj/untold_stories_of_haru_urara_you_will_barely_find/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">speculation</a> about involved parties attempting to squeeze another financial windfall out of her – after which she spent the next handful of years involved in her owner’s therapy and education efforts. There were also plans to breed her with other famous Japanese horses, but they never fully materialized. Eventually, in 2013, ownership of Haru Urara was transferred to Matha Farm in Japan’s Chiba prefecture, where she lived out the remainder of her days.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Umamusume</em>’s take on Haru Urara, a pink-haired anime girl with a legion of in-game fans despite her penchant for losing, exposed the ancient race horse to a new audience. Her story resonated with younger people in the West as well. Earlier this year, they <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/sim/anime-horse-girls-are-causing-one-real-life-mare-dubbed-the-shining-star-of-losers-everywhere-to-receive-so-much-usd40-grass-she-broke-the-donation-website/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crashed a website</a> that let them donate $40 ryegrass gifts to her. In the end, <a href="https://namabokusobank.jp/article/%E3%83%8F%E3%83%AB%E3%82%A6%E3%83%A9%E3%83%A9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to the website</a>, fans donated a total grass amount of 3,410 kg, or 7,518 lbs. That is too much for one horse to eat, but I’m sure Haru Urara appreciated it on some level.</p><p>Haru Urara <a href="https://friday.kodansha.co.jp/article/438213" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">died of colic</a>, a form of gas build up that is often deadly to horses, but was apparently healthy up to that point. I find it difficult not to feel a little weird about a situation in which an animal suffered to make money for a bunch of different people, only to be declared an inspiration for never giving up despite <em>her </em>apparent desire to be doing anything else – and then a lot of other people became parasocially attached to an anime girl, further obscuring, at least in some cases, the wants and needs of real animals trapped in a broken system. But it sounds like Haru Urara lived out her final years in peace, and that’s better than nothing.</p><p>"One of these beautiful tragedies," reads <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/UmaMusume/comments/1nce1jh/comment/nd92he3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a comment</a> on the <em>Umamusume </em>subreddit. "We didn't expect it so soon, but our gal made it to 29 years old. Lived the last of them in absolute luxury and love."</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/unikat-32-33-indie-games-publisher-marketing"><h3>Running A Video Games Publisher AND Marketing Agency Sounds Absolutely Exhausting</h3></a><p>'Seeing all of your different efforts, ones that are synced by the work of many people, all being unveiled at once is a cool feeling'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/the-author-immortal-image-comics-interview"><h3>The Author Immortal Is A Metanarrative Isekai Comic That Explores The Messiness Of Separating The Art From The Artist</h3></a><p>Amid canceled creators, cultural reckonings, and A.I.’s rise, Frank Barbiere and Morgan Beem’s new Image Comics series invites readers to reclaim fantasy and confront who stories truly serve
</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-silksong-launch-gta-vi-elden-ring"><h3>All-Consuming Event Releases Like Silksong Are Growing Fewer And Further Between</h3></a><p>"Silksong and then GTA VI coming up are the two big launches that almost feel like the end of the big launch"</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/civilization-7-civ-vii-layoffs-firaxis-2k-take-two"><h3>Seven Months After Civ VII’s Launch, Firaxis Workers Are Being Laid Off</h3></a><p>2K said the layoffs were part of an effort to increase "adaptability, collaboration, and creativity" at Firaxis, whatever that means</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/football-manager-26-fm26-sports-interactive-womens-league-wsl-nwsl"><h3>More Sports Games Should Take A Year Off</h3></a><p>It gives you the time to, for example, add around 35,000 new players to a game</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/haru-urara-horse-death-umamusume]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Running A Video Games Publisher AND Marketing Agency Sounds Absolutely Exhausting]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/unikat-32-33-indie-games-publisher-marketing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/running-a-video-games-publisher-and-marketing-agency-sounds-absolutely-exhausting.1293156/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Oh boy, it's time for another instalment of<a href="https://aftermath.site/category/what-i-do" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> What I Do, our regular feature showcasing just what it is that individuals across the video game industry actually do for a living</a>.</p><p>This week we've got Michal Napora, someone who has done not one job recently, but two. And while both have something <em>broadly </em>to do with selling video games, they're also different enough to count as two hats, which is a lot of hats to be wearing in video games in 2025.</p><p><strong>Luke Plunkett: Hey man, thanks for taking the time to chat with us today. Can you tell us a bit about yourself? Who you are, how you got your start in games, that kinda stuff.</strong></p><p><strong>Michal Napora</strong>: Hi! My name is Michal and I’m the founder of video games publisher UNIKAT Label and video games marketing agency 32-33. I’ve been in the video games industry for around 12 years. I got my first taste of game marketing in my town of Perth, Western Australia, where I helped a local indie crew Gnomic Studio with their game <em>Square Heroes</em>. Totally new and absolutely naive, I tried to spread the word on this full-of-heart indie shooter while finishing off my Masters in Marketing. Once I graduated, I shot my shot and applied for a Social Media Manager role at a Polish studio called Techland. They were working on an upcoming AAA zombie horror game called <em>Dying Light</em>. A few weeks after I applied, I had a call with them. Then another. And another. Finally, a few weeks after the application was sent, they offered me a job. So I packed my bags, said goodbyes, and moved from Perth to Europe and worked on <em>Dying Light</em>. During the two years I was there, I learned a TON. My brain was a sponge, soaking it all in. It was fun, and at times stressful, surrounded by beautiful, intelligent, and insanely talented people. When the game came out and received praise (as well as social and press clout), it felt like<a href="https://www.bundesliga.com/en/bundesliga/news/borussia-dortmund-champions-league-finalists-2013-where-are-they-now-lewandowski-klopp-27291" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> we were the 2012/2013 Borussia Dortmund team - a bunch of young up-and-comers that reached the Champions League final</a>.</p><p>After two years working at Techland, I decided to do something of my own, and that’s how my boutique marketing agency 32-33 came to be. Throughout my time at 32-33, I am fortunate to count some great clients: teams such as Frogwares (<em>The Sinking City</em>, <em>Sherlock Holmes</em> series), Bloober Team (<em>The Medium</em>, <em>Blair Witch</em> on Switch), indies such as <em>Dinkum</em>, <em>Bramble: The Mountain King</em>, <em>Medieval Dynasty</em>, <em>Squirrel With a Gun</em>, and loads, loads more. Working on a variety of projects with people from all over the world is such a cool experience. It made me realise that we as people, we are all the same - we want the same things, we have similar interests, and similar loves. It’s a nice feeling to work with like-minded individuals.</p><p>And as of April last year, I started my own publishing house called UNIKAT Label. I believe it could be the first video games publisher from Perth. Our first two games were <em>POOLS</em> and <em>Dystopika</em>, and once again, I am feeling privileged that I got to work with some seriously talented people.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p><strong>LP: If you can sum it up as neatly as a business card (or two business cards) allows, what's your exact job title?</strong></p><p><strong>MN</strong>: Technically, I am a Founder. Or the hated-by-me title of CEO. Which feels too damn corporate. Founder is good.</p><p><strong>LP: So what does that involve, exactly? Like on a daily basis, and then more strategically, what is it that you do for a living across two jobs?</strong></p><p><strong>MN</strong>: As someone who runs a publisher and a marketing agency, I do a lot of varied things. At the start of each week, I plan out a list of tasks that I need to accomplish for the next 4-5 days. And as I am looking at my board, talking with people is my number one task - be it on Discord, on calls, or via email. I talk to my partner and fellow people that I work with, developers that I work with, my clients, journalists, events custodians, content creators, first and third parties (just a fancy industry term that describes companies like Xbox, PlayStation, Nintendo, Unreal, Unity, etc) and other people who are in our industry. Talking is something that I do a lot. So plan and talk.&nbsp;</p><p>Next is doing the actual work - be it writing press releases, applying for events, finalising events that I am organising myself, think about social content, and plan out marketing activities. Planning out marketing campaigns is something I enjoy a lot. I also like to take time for myself and that’s when I usually like to think through what worked well in the week, what didn’t, lessons that I should take on board and stuff to watch out for. It’s also a time when I like to look at the long term vision of what UNIKAT is all about. Thinking, reflecting, and writing in a journal really helps me out. Getting stuff out of your head into the physical world helps clear up that head and gives you space for new ideas to come out. Otherwise, stuff just ferments.&nbsp;</p><p>Reading the net - scouring it. Be it for games, opportunities, or information is something that’s on my card too. I like going down rabbit holes and coming across different communities of people. In general, I feel I have a very varied line of work. It’s fun and always keeps you engaged.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>LP: On your best day, what's the best thing about your job?</strong></p><p><strong>MN</strong>: Meeting people. I am a bit of a cheerful introvert who likes to talk. I do like the comfort of my desk and being silent when I work, but talking with people does bring a bit of a smile to my face. I have to say that about 93% of the people in our industry are fantastic people - full of charm, good energy and just want to make games. The other 7% are leeches, but you do start getting a feeling for them after some time.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>I also like the feeling of all of our hard work coming together and culminating to one specific point - be it an announcement of a new game, a demo drop, being part of an event. Seeing all of your different efforts, ones that are synced by the work of many people, all being unveiled at once is a cool feeling. And game release days are pretty special too. There is this quiet freeing point; the moment you hit release until you start seeing responses from the market is a real high - it’s like jumping out of a plane without a parachute and waiting for stuff to happen. The limbo zone. Will people like it? Will people buy it? Will it do well? That feeling of being out but not having the answers yet is sooo freeing. You don’t know what to do, or which way things will go. The reality of the situation hasn’t hit yet. I always get my heart pumping in this spot. It doesn’t last long, as answers usually come pretty soon. And once answers come through, reality hits - be it good or bad. You have a direction of what to do next. You need to plan.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>But actually, as I am typing this, the best thing to see is seeing developers happy with your and their work. It’s cheesy as fuck when I am typing this, but it’s soooo damn cool seeing devs, especially first time devs, tasting success. It reminds me of how I felt at the start as well. Seeing people lose their minds because their game is trending and featured on Steam’s front page is a wicked happy feeling - like being at a rave, you’re feeling ultra happy, the future looks optimistic, and time slows down. That’s also a very nice feeling (and the opposite of that kinda sucks).</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Pools - Official Launch Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8AFoK14RMJs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p><strong>LP: Conversely, what do you think are some of the biggest challenges you see facing over the next few years? Whether that's yourself, your business or just video games in general.</strong></p><p><strong>MN</strong>: Discoverability. The amount of games being made and pumped out is staggering. And I’m not just talking about the bad or even average ones. There are a lot of good games being made these days. It’s a fantastic position for gamers, as they get to play some amazing gems. However, for people making them, it’s harder and harder to get noticed. There is a lot of competition for eyeballs, be it press eyeballs, content creators, heck, even on Steam itself. We like to say that indies don’t compete with themselves, but they kinda do. We don’t compete for sales, we compete for attention. Some content creators get over 30 “play my game” emails a day. And I would imagine Aftermath gets their fair share of press releases too. And it’s physically impossible for you to publish all of the news. I feel that the massive amount of recent industry layoffs will create a batch of new micro-studios that will have some amazing games to show off. It’ll also mean that a lot of developers, be it big or small, will need to re-adjust their expectations when it comes to sales. And indie devs will need to face the reality of how good their projects really are. I feel a bit of a reckoning is coming. I’m really keen to see where this goes.</p><p>On the “market watch” side, I feel that with people having less and less disposable income (especially in Western countries), it’s the cheaper games that will be winners. Just like social media content, people are ok with dropping small amounts for fleeting game experiences. Play, laugh, move on. Friendslop is a good example of this. I feel that a bit of Friendsloppification might start filtering through to other genres - city builders, narrative games, shooters. Cheaper games that offer a cool experience that can be consumed within a few sessions and we “swipe up”/move on. Will AAAs die off? Probably not. There is definitely space for them too (<em>GTA VI</em> is going to kill it, looks like <em>Battlefield 6</em> will too). But games in the $30 to $50 USD price point might struggle a bit. Imagine trying to sell a $49 7/10 game now? Of course, I could be completely wrong and by 2026 the economies of the world will be roaring and we’re all going to have cash coming out of our whazoos. That actually would be cool. Let’s hope that this is what will happen. However, my pessimistic side doesn’t think it will, and that’s when all of the 7/10 and less games or games not fit for market will suffer.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p><strong>LP: Any final shout outs you'd want to give before we wrap this up?</strong><strong>MN</strong>: Huge, HUGE shoutouts to all the people I’ve met along the way! There’s too many to list individually, but looking back, definitely a huge shoutout to the Techland <em>Dying Light</em> and <em>Dying Light: The Following</em> crew. Lots of great memories there. Also a huge thanks to all of the devs and publishers I’ve worked with over the years. Thank you so much for the trust and for letting me play and market your games. Finally, to the industry, perhaps I would say let’s not be so goddamn short-term focused. It’s ok if things slow down a bit. Just think of the long-term vision, what it does to your studio and to your studio’s name. It’s ok to wait a bit to see good results. Hypercapitalism is leading to burnout, not just of people within the industry, but players too. It’s alright to slow down. Pat a cat. Or a duck. Let’s slow it down a notch.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/the-author-immortal-image-comics-interview"><h3>The Author Immortal Is A Metanarrative Isekai Comic That Explores The Messiness Of Separating The Art From The Artist</h3></a><p>Amid canceled creators, cultural reckonings, and A.I.’s rise, Frank Barbiere and Morgan Beem’s new Image Comics series invites readers to reclaim fantasy and confront who stories truly serve
</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-silksong-launch-gta-vi-elden-ring"><h3>All-Consuming Event Releases Like Silksong Are Growing Fewer And Further Between</h3></a><p>"Silksong and then GTA VI coming up are the two big launches that almost feel like the end of the big launch"</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/civilization-7-civ-vii-layoffs-firaxis-2k-take-two"><h3>Seven Months After Civ VII’s Launch, Firaxis Workers Are Being Laid Off</h3></a><p>2K said the layoffs were part of an effort to increase "adaptability, collaboration, and creativity" at Firaxis, whatever that means</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/football-manager-26-fm26-sports-interactive-womens-league-wsl-nwsl"><h3>More Sports Games Should Take A Year Off</h3></a><p>It gives you the time to, for example, add around 35,000 new players to a game</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/unikat-32-33-indie-games-publisher-marketing]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>