<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 23:06:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Songs Of Silence Rules]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/songs-of-silence-impressions-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/songs-of-silence-rules.1042356/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/songs-of-silence-impressions-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Songs Of Silence</em>, man, where has this game been hiding? Last week I had never even heard of it. For the week since I have been doing nothing but playing this game.</p><p>It's a strategy game I've seen billed as everything from a 4X to an auto battler, and many other things in between (I'll take my own swing at what it is in a second). Set in a fantasy world where two races of ancient humans have battled so long they've literally split the world in two, you can play skirmish maps or fight your way through a narrative singleplayer campaign that features both sides caught in a war that threatens to destroy them both.</p><p>For all the tags and descriptors being thrown around about this game--it comes slightly out of left field, so it's difficult to precisely pin down--I'd say the overall experience is closest to playing a <em>Total War</em> campaign if you'd given the <em>Total War</em> series to an engineer and said "trim as much of this as you can while still keeping the overall vibes". Your objective in every <em>Songs of Silence</em> game, whether in the campaign or a skirmish map, is broadly the same: take and hold settlements on a strategic map, which accrue resources you then spend on upgrades, unique buildings or new units.</p><p>Leading your armies are hero units, which in RPG style are unique and can be levelled up, and who also have special abilities they can employ on the battlefield. The armies themselves, meanwhile, are made up of a wild variety of fantasy units ranging from cheap infantry through to expensive, gargantuan behemoths. See what I mean? I'm basically describing the outline of <em>Total War: Warhammer</em>.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Songs of Silence - Official Launch Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yENpBzdm5PE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Only<em> Songs of Silence</em> does away with so much of <em>Total War's</em> faff. Diplomacy? Boring, so it's gone. Trade? Little more than tick-a-box, so it's gone too. All that's left is the heartbeat of Creative Assembly's series: the elastic to-and-fro of armies manoeuvring about a map that's always just slightly too big for them to hold down, and settling things on the battlefield in real-time when two of those armies clash.</p><p>Which is the point where <em>Songs of Silence</em> starts to get <em>really </em>interesting,<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Auto_battler" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> because it's an auto battler</a>. You're the one building the armies, deciding on their composition and arranging them into formation, but once a battle starts every unit will (mostly) run off and do its own thing, with the player left as a bystander. The only direct input you have on proceedings is to play cards, which is a lot more important than it sounds, because they're the lifeblood of <em>Songs of Silence</em>.</p><figure></figure><p>On the battlefield, each leader gets their own deck of cards with special abilities they can play, and as you progress through a game and level your generals up you'll earn both more and better cards. Defensive abilities, offensive abilities, spawning new units on the battlefield, slowing your opponent down–there's a ton of ways you can influence the battle, even if you're not micromanaging each unit individually.</p><p>As a serial auto-resolver in long <em>Total War</em> campaigns, this is great. Look, I appreciate all the work that goes into <em>Total War's</em> real-time battles, and in decisive moments I'll usually always take control of them and have a blast, but over the course of a sprawling campaign that could feature dozens or even <em>hundreds </em>of engagements, I just can't be bothered taking charge of <em>all </em>of them. <em>Songs of Silence's</em> brevity is a great middle ground here, as I get some involvement, but can then kick back and watch a battle unfold in what is sometimes just a matter of seconds.</p><p>Cards can also be played on the strategic map, replacing much of what other games would build into an interface full of buttons (<em>Songs of Silence's</em> screen is beautifully uncluttered as a result.). These can buff armies or, more commonly, allow you to build structures and improvements on your settlements. Wherever you play these cards, on the battlefield or the map, the act is immensely satisfying; there's a flashy animation and feel to dragging a card onto the map and seeing a big stone tower come roaring out of the ground.</p><p>This all comes together to create an intoxicating pace. You just glide through <em>Songs of Silence</em>, frictionless, from one task to the next, never stopping or needing to pause, dancing in rhythm between moving an army on the map, upgrading something then having a little fight. Management is brief, battles are short, it's like strategic tapas in a genre that's normally only interested in huge steaks.</p><figure></figure><p>Helping drive all this is the fact I could not ever take my eyes away from the screen. Just look at this game. <em>Songs of Silence</em> is <em>stunning</em>. The splash art, the character design, the illustrations punctuating the end of every battle, the card art, the animation of all your little armies zooming around, the unit design, the little sensory thrill of playing a card, it's all wonderful.</p><p>The old cliche isn't as robust as it once was--stuff like <em>Endless Legend</em> and even recent <em>Fire Emblem</em> games have helped--but strategic fantasy in video games is still too often a generic, nondescript thing, one series' elf blurring into another series' stout human infantry. Not here! This game looks like nothing else out there (well, maybe a little like <em>Banner Saga</em> if you squint), and the story it's telling, complete with fantastic voice-acting, is also one that's well-told. This game's got a <em>world</em>, and it is an interesting place to spend some time in.</p><p>I have no idea how this game flew under my radar for so long--I mean I do, games media is broken and Steam's discovery is almost useless because simply too many games are coming out--but hey, whatever, I found it eventually. <em>Songs of Silence</em> is one of the most refreshing strategy games I've played in a very long time, and an unexpected artistic triumph at that. It's ironic that it's an auto battler, a genre often derided for being so hands-off, because I've been glued to this all week long.</p><figure></figure></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Now’s The Best Time To Listen To Aftermath’s 52 Pickup]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/nows-the-best-time-to-listen-to-aftermaths-52-pickup</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/now%E2%80%99s-the-best-time-to-listen-to-aftermath%E2%80%99s-52-pickup.1042302/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/nows-the-best-time-to-listen-to-aftermaths-52-pickup<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Professional DC Comics expert Alex Jaffe and I have been rereading the ambitious comic book <em>52</em> and podcasting about it. We’ve just reached the halfway point, and even if you haven’t read the series before, we think this is a great place to join us.</p><p>1985’s <em>Crisis on Infinite Earths</em> is a fantastic book on its own merit, but is also a fascinating look at DC Comics’ “events,” which are a way to both boost sales and resolve tricky editorial problems. Through this, writers and artists try to cohere the DC universe from something sprawling and inconsistent into a logical world with more concrete rules. DC has had dozens of such Crisis events, some more successful than others. <em>52</em> is a series that spun off of such an event, but is so, so much better than the circumstances of its creation.</p><p><em>52</em> was an experiment in American comics that worked exactly once. After the event <em>Infinite Crisis</em>, the DC universe jumped ahead in time by one year as a way to explain the new radical status quo for the characters. To help readers learn what happened in that missing year, four of the most popular DC comics writers–Greg Rucka, Mark Waid, Geoff Johns and Grant Morrison–got together to put out a weekly series exploring the events of the DC universe in real time, week by week.</p><p><em>52</em> did not do a particularly good job of telling the editorially mandated story of that missing year, but it did something much better: it was a successful weekly comic book that revitalized several smaller DC Comics characters. For manga readers, that may sound like no big deal, but the American comic books industry does not have the infrastructure to support a weekly, full color comic book. As Jaffe and I have explored this comic in depth, we’ve learned how many times this project almost failed. Most recently, I learned that in one week, the line art got lost while in transit to the Brazilian studio that inked the book, and they had to do a rush job working off photocopies that were overnighted. The fact that this comic book was released on time every week was a miracle. The fact that it’s <em>also extremely good</em> almost defies reality.</p><p>If you haven’t read <em>52</em>, feel free to start at the beginning of the podcast and read along with us. If you just want to start listening, <a href="https://aftermath.site/52-pickup-podcast-dc-comics" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the latest, episode 27, is a great place to start</a>. Jaffe and I summarize each of the simultaneously running plotlines in the book. For Aftermath subscribers, we have a ton of bonus episodes for people who want to know more about the projects that spun off of <em>52</em>, including many aspects of the DC extended universe movies (except the Zach Snyder films, which Jaffe will not watch unless he personally receives three thousand dollars). We’ve also spoken to artists who have worked on <em>52</em>, including Greg Rucka, Mark Waid, and Geoff Johns. I have not given up on interviewing Grant Morrison, and if anyone has their contact information please do reach out.</p><p>Understanding <em>52</em> is the key to unlocking the entirety of DC comics. It is an exercise in its star writers exploring their specific fixations, working with and around an editorial mandate, and following in the tradition of <em>Crisis on Infinite Earths</em> to use fiction to solve other editorial problems. I doubt we’ll ever see a comic book like it ever again, but you may see adaptations of bits and pieces of this book in popular culture as James Gunn takes control of the DC movie universe. I mean, it already began before his tenure—The Rock’s <em>Black Adam</em> movie is directly inspired by the Black Adam storyline in <em>52</em>. But Gunn in particular has the same fondness for the freaks and losers of the DC universe as the writers of <em>52</em>, like Peacemaker, Vigilante, the Creature Commandos. His comic book inspiration for the upcoming <em>Superman</em> movie comes from a <em>52</em> writer, Grant Morrison. These are the kinds of stories and characters that truly differentiate DC from Marvel, and made a lifelong DC obsessive out of me.</p><p>Jaffe and I have already embarked on reading the second half of the series, where the narrative gets even weirder. I hope you’ll join us.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>