<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 06:09:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Buzzfeed CEO Wants To Solve The Internet’s Problems By Making His Own Version Of Those Problems]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/buzzfeed-peretti-ai</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/buzzfeed-ceo-wants-to-solve-the-internet%E2%80%99s-problems-by-making-his-own-version-of-those-problems.1106340/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/buzzfeed-peretti-ai<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>On Tuesday, Buzzfeed CEO Jonah Peretti announced his company will be launching its own social media platform, news he buried at the end of a long, tone-deaf <a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/jonah/the-anti-snarf-manifesto" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">manifesto</a> about how AI and big tech are ruining what it means to be online. This is, to Peretti’s credit, true, but if you’re worried his solution will be to stem the onslaught of journalistic job losses or fight back against the AI companies that want to fill the internet with even more crap, don’t be: he’s not doing any of that.</p><p>The manifesto is called “The Anti-SNARF Manifesto,” which is not a reference to <em>ThunderCats</em> but instead a clumsy acronym for “<strong>S</strong>takes/<strong>N</strong>ovelty/<strong>A</strong>nger/<strong>R</strong>etention/<strong>F</strong>ear,” which Peretti believes drives the current algorithmically-based news and social media ecosystems. He writes that </p><blockquote><p>The type of content that gets created and recommended is not the best content, but the content that elicits the most compulsive and predictable response from the human brain. When the platforms don’t care about content and ask the AI to maximize usage, the content evolves into what I call ‘SNARF.’ </p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>The manifesto takes aim at TikTok and Meta for focusing on technology and algorithms instead of quality content, claiming that these algorithms then lead to situations in which (emphasis his)&nbsp;</p><blockquote><p>Content creators <strong>exaggerate stakes</strong> to make their content urgent and existential. They <strong>manufacture novelty</strong> and spin their content as unprecedented and unique. They <strong>manipulate anger</strong> to drive engagement via outrage. They <strong>hack</strong> <strong>retention</strong> by withholding information and promising a payoff at the end of a video. And they <strong>provoke</strong> <strong>fear</strong> to make people focus with urgency on their content.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>Peretti believes that “Through this lens, MAGA and ‘woke’ are the same thing! They both are versions of political ideas that spread through raw negative emotion, outrage, and novelty.” He writes that “the AI-powered platforms have... delivered a MAGA President that spews SNARF and a woke counter-culture that celebrates the assassination of a health insurance executive — big stakes, lots of novelty, and plenty of anger, retention, and fear!”&nbsp;</p><p>I don’t think Peretti is wrong about content that <a href="https://aftermath.site/its-exhausting-trying-to-read-video-game-website-headlines" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">obscures facts</a> or leans into <a href="https://aftermath.site/game-rant-facebook-dragon-age" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">anger</a> to drive clicks. In contrast, here’s a sample of current Buzzfeed headlines: “<a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/mikespohr/57-hilariously-unfortunate-people-youll-probably-feel-a" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">57 Hilariously Unfortunate People You'll Probably Feel A Little Bad Laughing At</a>,” “<a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/alexalisitza/political-tweets-of-the-week-2-10-24" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">21 Political Tweets From Last Week That Made Me Look Up At The Sky And Yell, ‘OMFG, YES’,"</a> and “<a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/abbyzinman/70s-male-heartthrobs-trivia" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">These 25 Male Celebs Were Huge Heartthrobs In The '70s — But I'll Be Shocked If Literally Anyone Under 35 Can Name Them Now</a>," Buzzfeed claimed in <a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/bensmith/why-buzzfeed-doesnt-do-clickbait" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2014</a> that it “doesn’t do clickbait,” and by its own definition, I’d agree: You know exactly what you’re getting with these articles, and they even tell you how you’re going to feel about them. (You could call this, as Peretti chides SNARF for above, a “predictable response,” but anyway!) All of it is designed for social sharing and compulsive engagement based on a particular kind of <a href="https://www.theawl.com/2015/03/i-hate-myself-because-i-dont-work-for-buzzfeed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">brainrot</a> that Buzzfeed pioneered to great success, one of value-neutral <a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/catesish/help-am-i-going-insane-its-definitely-blue" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">controversy</a> and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/07/27/technology/how-buzzfeeds-tasty-conquered-online-food.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stripped-down utility</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Buzzfeed was at the forefront of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jeffbercovici/2012/11/28/this-is-your-brain-on-buzzfeed-the-science-of-viral-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">viral content</a>, arguably a precursor to the very “SNARF” Peretti rails against. The spread of that content took a hit from changing social media algorithms alongside every other outlet; in the years since, Buzzfeed has struggled to <a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/jonah/building-the-defining-media-company-for-the-ai-era" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">regain its footing</a>, so perhaps it’s no wonder Peretti spends so long being pissed off at social platforms. But Buzzfeed can’t compete not just because the internet doesn’t work like it did in the company’s heyday, but because the articles on Buzzfeed’s page aren’t <em>about</em> anything. Peretti uses the changing nature of virality to conflate Trump’s rhetoric with the widespread response to <a href="https://aftermath.site/united-healthcare-luigi-mangione" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Luigi Mangione</a>; he seems to believe these things go wide primarily because they upset people, and he doesn’t explore much difference in <em>why</em> people are upset. But in pointing out the real ways our emotions get manipulated on the internet, Peretti also seems to take aim at any kind of content that elicits <em>real</em> emotions. He’s not wrong that it’s less fun to disagree about health care and human rights than it is what color a dress is or which Golden Girl you are. But it takes a particular kind of Rich Guy Brain to spin that out into the idea that both sides are equally bad because, as he writes, “the result is an endless stream of addictive content that leaves everyone feeling depressed, scared, and dissatisfied.” People are, in fact, legitimately depressed, scared, and dissatisfied, and while I agree that plenty of news outlets and content creators lean into that to drive hollow engagement, Peretti’s view seems to fundamentally disbelieve that people earnestly want to care about real things.&nbsp;</p><p>Peretti putting the onus for some of this on AI is laughable when his own company has <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/04/20/media/buzzfeed-news-shuts-down/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">axed its Pulitzer Prize-winning news desk</a> and conducted <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/digital/buzzfeed-layoffs-new-restructuring-1235831847/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mass layoffs</a>, leaning its full weight into <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/01/26/media/buzzfeed-ai-content-creation/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI</a> and <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/buzzfeed-ai-creators-news-shut-down-1235483607/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">content creators</a> instead. If it’s algorithms over people that’s driving all this, wouldn’t the smart alternative be thoughtful content created by real people; i.e., hiring journalists? If the AI-driven social media platforms are the problem, why would the solution be for Peretti to create his own social media platform “built specifically to spread joy and enable playful creative expression”? Peretti writes that “this social media platform will use AI to give users agency instead of stealing their agency,” whatever that means technologically, and whatever “agency” looks like when held up against a platform whose defining feature seems to be “good vibes only.” &nbsp;</p><p>In the course of the manifesto, Peretti does remember that he also owns the remains of some outlets. He lays out his plans for them:&nbsp; Buzzfeed proper “will bring more fun and playfulness back to the internet with low stakes content that is pure entertainment” and also, somehow, “counter the increase of gaslighting and misinformation by speaking to our diverse audience in ways that other institutions, media, and platforms clearly won’t.” The reporters left at <a href="https://www.thewrap.com/huffpost-editor-in-chief-resigns-layoffs-danielle-belton/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">HuffPost</a> (who are now surrounded by the worst people you know in the news desks at the <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/trump-administration-throwing-more-pentagon-reporters-out_n_67a75e7fe4b077fd2382e9e9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pentagon</a>) will be “using ‘SNARF for good’” by writing, well, news. Food brand Tasty, once my favorite hate read, “will fight SNARF with utility and social connection… the Tasty app will give us our own platform to grow usage and loyalty by integrating capabilities such as AI recipe remixing, community tips and challenges, and creator-led content.”</p><p>Peretti can’t even make it through a paragraph about his own outlets before pivoting back into celebrating the very problems he rails against, an AI-driven tech platform that incentivizes creators. The main difference seems to be not just that it’s, you know, <em>nice</em> stuff, but that it’s <em>his</em> nice stuff. “I’m fed up with giving the platform companies advice about how to fix the internet, if we want this done right, we have to do it ourselves!” he writes. This is a man who claims to both “look forward to counter-programming with our human creativity fighting against the machine,” and a man who in December <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/buzzfeed-sells-hot-ones-studio-first-we-feast-rcna183956" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sold Hot Ones</a>, a wildly popular interview food show that sounds exactly like what Peretti seems to think the internet needs, except that it is made by and for actual humans, and as such cannot be turned into a tech product.</p><p>Buzzfeed has looked everywhere for relevance except in hiring real human people to make good work for other humans to read. But “hire reporters” doesn’t boost a company’s stock valuation or give it a tech product to tote around for investment. Peretti is trying to solve the problems he identifies with the same problems, just with his own bright yellow “LOL” badge slapped over them. I look forward to whatever “listicles, but it’s a social media network” turns out to be.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/beyond-citadel-indie-retro-shooter"><h3>Beyond Citadel Is Gory, Obscene, And Almost A Masterpiece</h3></a><p>Inspired by Lucasarts' Outlaws and Bungie's Marathon, Beyond Citadel is mechanically one of the best indie shooters I have played in years and absolutely not for everyone.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/sony-playstation-network-outage-psn-ps5-pc"><h3>The PlayStation Network Outage Is Modern Gaming In A Nutshell</h3></a><p>PSN went down for 24 hours, and Sony won't even give us an explanation</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Beyond Citadel Is Gory, Obscene, And Almost A Masterpiece]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/beyond-citadel-indie-retro-shooter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/beyond-citadel-is-gory-obscene-and-almost-a-masterpiece.1106319/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/beyond-citadel-indie-retro-shooter<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure><figcaption><span><p>God is in his heaven, all is right with the world. Credit: doekuramori</p>
</span></figcaption></figure></div><div><p>There are certain games or works of art that I cannot recommend without severe caveats. <em>Beyond Citadel </em>fits this category. It is an unapologetically horny game that contains brutal and graphic violence punctuated by moments of immense melancholy. It has a plot and world that is difficult to parse. It also happens to be, mechanically, one of the best made shooters I have played in years, and possibly the most successfully-realized followup to Bungie’s <em>Marathon </em>to date.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>WARNING: This article contains graphic and suggestive images that may be upsetting for some people.</strong></p><p><em>Beyond Citadel </em>is a follow up to <em>The Citadel, </em>a retro shooter by solo Japanese developer doekuramori. In both, you play a character known as The Martyr. Humanity has suffered a near extinction-level collapse, and those who remain exist through the use of cybernetic enhancement. In the first game, <em>The Citadel</em>, the remnants of humanity were enslaved by an entity known as The Sleeping God. <em>The Citadel </em>follows The Martyr’s attempt to destroy the guardian angels and kill the aforementioned slumbering deity.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>The gore in this game is very nasty. Credit: doekuramori</figcaption></figure><p><em>Beyond Citadel </em>picks up after the first game and follows a similar structure: The Martyr has returned to the titular citadel, and now must defeat seven trumpeters, all the while learning about her past. The world is bleak, surreal, and desolate, and if you’ve ever seen <em>The End of Evangelion </em>or played <em>Nier: Automata</em>, you may find the trappings rhyme a little.</p><p>There are two things that you notice when you first start playing <em>Beyond Citadel</em>. The first is the sheer degree of grotesque violence in the game, although the 2D sprites mean that it is often done cartoonishly. Enemies not only explode into gibbering viscera, they also occasionally die slowly, sometimes panting for breath as they bleed out and occasionally pointing a gun at you as they die.&nbsp;</p><p>The other thing you notice is that several of the characters are skimpily-rendered anime women. The Martyr’s outfit ranges from being a more revealing take on Leeloo’s bandage costume from <em>The Fifth Element</em> to an equally revealing riff on the costume from <em>Æon Flux</em>. When The Martyr dies, the player is often confronted with a first person view of her body being torn apart by bullets in graphic detail. In addition to this, the game features a gallery of borderline (although not fully nude) pornographic shots of The Martyr in compromising positions. Although I did not see any nudity in the game, not much is left to the imagination. Both the game’s gore and the skimpy gallery can be disabled in the menu, which is a nice option for people who just would like to play a good retro shooter.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>The Martyr's can sometimes find a backup body in case they die. Their outfit leaves little to the imagination. Credit: doekuramori</figcaption></figure><p>While <em>The Citadel </em>had a structure and quality akin to a very solid <em>DOOM </em>WAD, <em>Beyond Citadel </em>is light years better. The basic level structure of the game has increased in complexity and there is a verticality to the world that was simply not present in <em>The Citadel</em>. As your character levels up and gains new abilities like double jumps and air dashes, new pathways through the level become available to you. Instead of going down a tightly controlled corridor where enemies have the high ground, finding a secret way to the roof and dispatching opposing snipers from a higher vantage point might be the best option. <em>Beyond Citadel </em>is also masterful at slowly increasing the complexity, adding in vehicle segments where you drive tanks, mechs and aircraft that are surprisingly fun to play.</p><figure><figcaption>Boss encounters usually involve using a one-time weapon in an arena. Credit: doekuramori</figcaption></figure><p>In addition to the increased level complexity, the weapon system in <em>Beyond Citadel</em> is pseudo-tactical in style. The game gives you three settings options for how technical you want your gunplay to be: ‘load only with no jam,’ ‘load and cock,’ and ‘unload, load and cock.’ I highly recommend at least experimenting with the latter two even on an easier difficulty setting, as they add a rhythm and tension to the game that really sets it apart from other retro shooters. Being able to lean around corners also adds to the tension of being pinned down by a hail of enemy bullets.</p><figure><figcaption>The train level is very Outlaws-inspired. Credit: doekuramori</figcaption></figure><p>Individual bullets have to be accounted for, and each gun develops a distinct feel and pattern that becomes organic. These weapons also develop in complexity with various mods, which allows every gun to be viable throughout the game. On top of this, each slot has three different weapons to choose from, allowing you to customize your loadout. During my playthrough I fell in love with the Cavalry Carbine with a scoped mod, a precise medium range gun which has to be chambered between rounds. The button to chamber and aim down sight were the same, so double right clicking became a natural part of the flow of gunplay. Guns in the game also have significant bullet drop, and accounting for that while taking out an enemy from across the map feels fantastic.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Outlaws playthrough- Level 3 - The Train" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/39eH0iq27II?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><figcaption>Outlaws rocks.</figcaption></figure></div><p>Of all the guns, the carbine in particular feels like it was dropped straight out of 1997 LucasArts shooter <em>Outlaws</em>. This is not a coincidence, as doekuramori’s own Twitter bio reads “Developing Outlaws &amp; Marathon-like FPS / Gun simulator hybrid -Beyond Citadel-”. Reading the word “<em>Outlaws</em>” set my heart aflutter as I love that game dearly and, <a href="https://aftermath.site/27-years-later-lucasarts-afterlife-is-brilliant-brutal-and-few-know-how-to-beat-it" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">like the game <em>Afterlife</em></a>, feel like it remains an underappreciated gem in the Lucasarts catalogue.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Relics (PC-88) Playthrough" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iVv2IW3WrYQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>As a developer, doekuramori is unambiguous in what projects influenced their games: <em>Ghost in the Shell</em>, the work of H.R. Giger, Tohou Project, the ultraviolence of old school shooters, Tsutomo Nihei’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blame!" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BLAME!</a>, <em>Metabarons </em>by Jodorowsky/Juan Giménez and the <a href="http://www.hardcoregaming101.net/relics/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">obscure X68000 game <em>Relics</em></a><em> </em>are all named references. This fascination in a biomechanical world is something I deeply appreciate and relate to as someone who grew up on the works of Shin’ya Tsukamoto like <em>Tetsuo: The Iron Man</em>.</p><figure><figcaption>The manga BLAME! is a key inspiration. Credit: Kodansha/Tsutomu Nihei</figcaption></figure><p>The contrast between biomechanical ultraviolence and skimpily-clad anime women leads some people to conclude that the Japanese subgenre of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ero_guro" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ero guro</a> is also a distinct influence, an accusation that doekuramori refuted in an extensive Steam note for<em> </em><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1378290/view/2729698558760624504" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The Citadel</em></a> in 2020. “I am not guro artist,”doekuramori stated. “This is not a guro fetish game.” While I think it is worth fairly representing the intent of a creator, it is also fair criticism to say that when you are looking at The Martyr’s beheaded and almost nude body being ripped apart by bullets, that can sometimes feel like a distinction without a difference.</p><figure><figcaption>A diagram explaining how the world of Citadel fits together. A version of this appears in the game’s gallery only if you disable the erotic fan art in the settings. Credit: doekuramori</figcaption></figure><p>Part of what makes reviewing <em>Beyond Citadel </em>difficult is how obtuse the story can be. Some of this is a language barrier – the translation is not great, and it feels like much is being lost. Many of the explanations for how the world fits together are primarily in Japanese or on the developer’s Twitter account. Another difficulty is that there is an intentional ambiguity in how certain elements of the world fit together. Every zone ends with The Martyr defeating a large boss, setting off a bomb and presumably dying in the explosion only to be reborn later in another vessel. Between these zones, The Martyr visits a liminal space similar to the Black Lodge from <em>Twin Peaks</em> or the <a href="https://chrono.fandom.com/wiki/End_of_Time" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">End of Time</a> from <em>Chrono Trigger</em>, and meets their brother Elulu. These sudden moments of quiet and rest are often deployed in a shockingly endearing way. The Martyr is clearly several different clones, and so how real are any of these experiences, and how reliable is The Martyr’s perspective? Is the consciousness of The Martyr the same from body to body? It is clear that there is a greater plan underway that The Martyr is simply a pawn in (the term <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millenarianism" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Millenarianism</a> is thrown around a bunch near the end), but piecing how these fit together can sometimes feel like trying to solve a conspiracy.</p><figure><figcaption>doekuramori gives a lot of updates and explanations not present in the game on Twitter. Credit: doekuramori</figcaption></figure><p>As someone who likes a lot of transgressive art, I don’t really like debating the morality of surreal violence in art, but it is fair to say this game will just put a lot of people off. It should also be said that <em>Beyond Citadel </em>is not a perfect game even if you accept it on its own terms – it overstayed its welcome for me a little in the last third, although that is exacerbated if you complete all the optional side stages. And I will say I straight up did not enjoy the core motivation of the main characters once they were revealed. At the same time, I must also admit that’s clearly the entire point of the narrative – this is a world fallen from grace, and you are meant to feel severe discomfort at what The Martyr and others have done, down to the gasping mindless automatons holding their guns in while raising a single, shaking pistol at you.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>Tallboy. Credit: doekuramori</figcaption></figure><p><em>Beyond Citadel </em>is a story about sin and redemption, and it takes massive swings in its world building that could only come from a true Otaku. Even if the combination of erotic fan art and grotesque violence didn’t always congeals into something I like, it is uniquely itself. Neither the violence or sexuality are what makes <em>Beyond Citadel </em>&nbsp;a good shooter, but it is also true that only someone with those proclivities like doekuramori, a dev who straight up retweets fan hentai of his characters, could have made this game.&nbsp;</p><p>Dominic Tarason said in his review for PC Gamer that <em>Beyond Citadel</em> is a game he wants to recommend to “<a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/beyond-citadel-is-a-great-retro-fps-that-i-want-to-recommend-to-everybody-and-nobody/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">everybody and nobody</a>”, and while I understand that, I actually <em>do </em>know specifically who this game is for. This is a game strictly for the freaks, a term I would safely use to describe myself with endearment. I wouldn’t recommend this game to everyone, but neither would I make blanket recommendations for Throbbing Gristle, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sl0D6GbUdN0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">any film by Kōji Wakamatsu</a>, the French novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Necrophiliac" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>The Necrophiliac</em></a> and the undeniably gorgeous yet sadistic manga <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sh%C5%8Djo_Tsubaki" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Shojo Tsubaki</em></a>. It is too depraved for unqualified praise, too unique to ignore, and technically one of the best indie shooters I have played in years. <em>Beyond Citadel</em> is a bizarre masterpiece, one that elevates it above the corny category “boomer shooter,” and I can’t safely say you’d find the experience an enjoyable one.</p><figure><figcaption>I love the Easter eggs in this game. Credit: doekuramori</figcaption></figure></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/sony-playstation-network-outage-psn-ps5-pc"><h3>The PlayStation Network Outage Is Modern Gaming In A Nutshell</h3></a><p>PSN went down for 24 hours, and Sony won't even give us an explanation</p></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>