<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 23:44:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maybe MetaHuman Was A Mistake]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/game-awards-epic-metahuman-fortnite</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/maybe-metahuman-was-a-mistake.1045176/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/game-awards-epic-metahuman-fortnite<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Epic announced the latest round of in-game <em>Fortnite</em> voting for The Game Awards today, where players can check out the <em>Fortnite</em> islands up for an award and play a multiplayer mode in the voting area. Last year, the voting area featured a hologram of Game Awards host Geoff Keighley, as well as a model of him perched high above the proceedings. This year… um.</p><p>In a <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/news/2024-best-fortnite-island-the-game-awards" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">blog</a>, Epic contributor Brian Crecente (who I think used to be Luke’s boss, but whom I have only met once at the Gawker funeral/party) explained that “This year’s digital Keighley is clearly much improved over 2023’s version. Where last year’s hologram look was created using greenscreen video capture, this year’s makes use of <a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/metahuman" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MetaHuman</a> to deliver a more realistic depiction.” MetaHuman is a feature in Epic’s Unreal Engine that allows users to create “high fidelity digital humans.”</p><p>Crecente writes that Keighley went to Manchester to be scanned for the model, and Keighley himself says in the blog that “The results speak for themselves, I truly feel like I have a digital double!”</p><p>This is that double in-game:</p><figure></figure><p>As far as I can tell, you only see digital Keighley once the first time you enter the mode, so I doublechecked against streamers that this wasn’t just something weird my graphics card was doing. Maybe I’m getting tripped up by how un-<em>Fortnite</em> the model looks in its reach for realism; something about seeing skin textures in <em>Fortnite</em> is hugely weird, and the proportions of the face don’t feel quite right, looking neither like Keighley nor a real face.&nbsp;</p><p>Curiously, I feel like he looks better in the trailer <em>Fortnite</em> released about the mode, which seems to maintain some of the flatness and lack of detail that I expect from <em>Fortnite</em> characters:</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="The Game Awards Vote in Fortnite Island 2024" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u3JnlvOR5Xc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>While MetaHuman touts that it is creation “made easy,” I’m sure this was not easy to do, so I am not going to play armchair technician and claim I could have made something that looks less uncanny. But I also didn’t think last year’s hologram needed much improving–it looked like Keighley as a hologram, fitting with the mode and with the look of <em>Fortnite</em> in general:</p><figure></figure><p>In last year’s mode, there was also a digital version of Keighley in the gameplay area, which stood at the top of a pile of rocks that, try as I might, I couldn’t scale. I could never get close enough to take a picture, but here’s what he looked like in a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ChKvof3DP5U" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trailer</a> from 2023:</p><figure><figcaption>Epic</figcaption></figure><p>In 2023, he looks like a version of himself in <em>Fortnite</em>! In 2024, he does not; he looks like an uncomfortably semi-realistic character squeezed in front of an unrealistic game mode where you shoot at floating crystals. I’m glad that, unlike last year, he’s not perched threateningly above me, where I would be unable to escape the mental image of his creepy eyes.</p><p>Maybe MetaHuman is a good tool for creators making realistic games in Unreal; I have no idea! But perhaps we didn’t need to see it used here.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>