<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - aftermath_site</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/aftermath_site.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for aftermath_site</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 04:43:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twitch Star Kai Cenat Really Wants NYC Mayor Eric Adams To Get Police To Apologize For Taking His Friend’s Car]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/kai-cenat-eric-adams-nyc-fanum-nypd-giveaway</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/twitch-star-kai-cenat-really-wants-nyc-mayor-eric-adams-to-get-police-to-apologize-for-taking-his-friend%E2%80%99s-car.1227552/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In a meeting of the minds that is shocking only in its capacity to surprise anyone at this point, current and <a href="https://aftermath.site/zohran-mamdani-mayor-nyc-adrew-cuomo-eric-adams-minecraft" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">soon-to-be-former</a> <a href="https://defector.com/the-most-unbelievable-bits-from-nyc-mayor-eric-adamss-indictment" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">disgraced NYC mayor</a> Eric Adams recently sat down with Kai Cenat, one of the most-watched streamers on Twitch and probably the most famous from a mainstream perspective. The latter, a Bronx native, attempted to host an in-person PS5 giveaway in 2023, which – to give you an idea of how that went – has its own Wikipedia page titled “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2023_Union_Square_riot" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2023 Union Square riot</a>.” Now, fresh off the success of <a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/kai-cenat-streamer-university-what-happened.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Streamer University’s more contained chaos</a> and on the verge of hosting another giveaway, Cenat has some misgivings about how the NYPD treated him and his friends.</p><p>As part of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WxwcFDYKoL8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a video</a> promoting the upcoming second giveaway, Cenat asked Adams how he could avoid another disastrous outcome. After the two exchanged pleasantries – with Adams granting that every day in New York is “crazy,” <a href="https://defector.com/eric-adams-the-beauty-of-new-york-is-that-there-are-terrorist-attacks-and-also-stores-that-open" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">as is his wont</a> – Cenat, who until recently resided in Atlanta, Georgia and has since departed for another undisclosed city, explained why he got the sense that he’s no longer welcome in NYC. In short, Cenat feels like the police continued to bother him and his friends even in 2024, after the 2023 riot incident was resolved.</p><p>"[NYPD] be picking on us in a way,” Cenat told Adams, <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/01/30/new-york-city-council-criminal-justice-reform-bills-00138644" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a notoriously pro-cop mayor</a> who was once an NYPD captain himself. “In terms of a lot of times where police was doing things that they wasn't supposed to be doing. It made it feel like NYPD was a gang at one point. My friend [Roberto] Fanum [Gonzalez] got his car taken away for no reason [in 2024]."</p><p>Adams then asked if the NYPD impounded the car on the same day as the riot, to which Cenat replied that it had happened on "a whole different day." The incident Cenat described was, indeed, alarming, with an officer <a href="https://www.complex.com/pop-culture/a/alex-ocho/fanum-lamborghini-seized-gun-pointed-nypd" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pointing a gun at Gonzalez</a> after last summer's Bronx Dominican Parade and handcuffing him. Police proceeded to take the car, a purple Lamborghini Urus, on the basis that, as a rep later told Complex, the vehicle lacked license plates. However, Gonzalez claimed on social media that he'd received a permit for the purposes of the parade. Additionally, pictures surfaced that seemed to depict <a href="https://x.com/scubaryan_/status/1817726076715753556" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">officers posing with the car</a>.</p><p>“The police would just look at us and pick us out,” Cenat told Adams. “We had trouble the whole summer [of 2024]. … I kinda feel like coming to New York, it’ll be kinda hectic in terms of, I gotta move a certain way.”&nbsp;</p><p>In response, Adams suddenly brought up one of the handful of things <a href="https://apnews.com/article/new-york-city-mayor-adams-rats-99649a7a4ec4003e8ec5ca551d90ed25" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">he’s declared</a> <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/eric-adams-nyc-trash-wheelie-bins-b2576182.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">war on</a> during his time as mayor: <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-news/mayor-eric-adams-drill-rap-1299108/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">drill rap</a>.</p><p>"We've come a long way from where we were,” Adams said, never clarifying which time period he was referring to. “And what's happening now even in the Bronx, there's a lot of crews, a lot of folks getting into battles over drill music. They're disrespecting each others' community. And so, I have to find that right balance. I've got to make sure we're safe, but not with disgrace."</p><p>“Yeah,” replied Cenat, “I just feel like there were some points where, you know, it’ll be the cops taking the car and posing with it, and we’re basically getting laughed at. So, us being from New York, we felt some type of way in terms of, like, we can’t even embrace the city without something going on because of how big we are. We always have a radar every time we fly in. It was always something.”</p><p>Of the car incident, Adams then asked the question on everybody’s mind: “What did [police] take it for? Was he drag racing?”</p><p>Cenat, perhaps more prepared for Adams’ jazz-like stream-of-consciousness approach to conversation than Adams – who loves putting on a show but hates doing his homework – was for anything involving Cenat and his friends, somehow did not miss a beat: “No,” he said, “he wasn’t doing nothing.”</p><p>“OK,” Adams finally resolved, “we need to look at that.”</p><p>Cenat and Adams’ discussion of the 2023 riot and the upcoming giveaway was comparatively brief. The riot, which took place in August 2023, stemmed from a comedy of errors. Cenat and fellow mega-famous content creators like Gonzalez and Duke Dennis failed to obtain a permit for a gathering that ended up drawing thousands, who grew increasingly unruly as what was billed as PS5 giveaway collapsed under its own weight. A small handful of fans were injured, and 65 were <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/kidsnews/post/influencer-kai-cenat-playstation-giveaway-riot-new-york-charges-have-now-been-dropped" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">arrested</a>. Police yanked Cenat out of the ensuing chaos and hit him with charges of inciting a riot and unlawful assembly, though the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/05/07/us/kai-cenat-union-square-giveaway-riot-charge-dropped" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">charges were dropped</a> after Cenat paid $55,000 in restitution fees and <a href="https://people.com/twitch-star-kai-cenat-wont-face-charges-after-nyc-riot-8646247" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">posted an apology</a>. He also <a href="https://x.com/domainsdomain/status/1689433483058257921" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">decried fans’ actions</a> shortly after shit hit the fan. This is not to say that Cenat’s moral compass was rendered infallible by the lessons he learned on that fateful day; during the aforementioned Streamer University, for example, Cenat and friends palled around with and consistently praised YouTuber and rapper DDG, who has been <a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/halle-bailey-ddg-restraining-order.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">accused of physical and emotional abuse</a> in a restraining order filed by his ex, singer and actress Halle Bailey.</p><p>During the recent conversation with Adams, Cenat, cognizant of damage done by his previous event, asked if there was a way he could more safely run it back. Adams replied by pointing to Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves, a boxing event so wonky that one of its main fighters, Ryan Garcia, <a href="https://www.mmafighting.com/2025/5/3/24422840/ryan-garcia-compares-times-square-fight-experience-to-weird-fever-dream" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">partially blamed</a> its walled-off setup for his loss, but which nonetheless <a href="https://www.espn.com/boxing/story/_/id/45009726/an-look-day-boxing-took-new-york-s-square" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">transformed a portion of Times Square into a boxing arena</a> without descending into a riot.</p><p>"Let's look at what we just did two weeks ago,” said Adams. “We had a major, major boxing event right in the middle of Times Square. A couple hundred thousand people were there. They coordinated with the city. ... You can't still do [events] on the level you did before because now you've blown up. So now you have to do it on another level. You sit down with my team. I get the agencies involved. You map out what your plan is: ‘This is what I want to do. I want to do something to give back.’ Now you've got the city in alignment to make sure you can execute the plan."</p><p>Cenat found these terms agreeable, saying that he simply wants to “give back” to his home city after botching his first attempt.&nbsp;</p><p>He then returned to the more pressing matter at hand: “Is there a way that my friend like Fanum could probably get an apology for what happened or anything like that?”</p><p>Adams, initially confused, reiterated that he’ll look into it, and then, “if something was done wrong, [Fanum] will get an apology.”&nbsp;</p><p>Cenat then turned his attention to one last major concern:&nbsp;</p><p>"How do you get the key to the city or, like, a street sign?” he asked. “I just want to see Cenat Ave, or something like that."</p><p>“I’m looking to have Eric Ave,” Adams said, before explaining that City Council names streets, while Adams can indeed bestow the key to the city upon a worthy recipient, but only for their life’s work.</p><p>"That’ll be fire to get," said Cenat. "I just wanted to get the greenlight if I ever wanted to run back an event or run back something like [if] I can. Because, right now, I didn't know if I was able to run any event back to give back to New York because of what happened last time."</p><p>“Do it right,” Adams replied.</p><p>“Yeah,” said Cenat, “we'll do it right.”</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/lies-of-p-overture-review"><h3>Lies Of P: Overture Is The Best Parts Of The Game Executed With Confidence</h3></a><p>Lies of P: Overture proves the success of the first game was no fluke, and establishes a bold house style.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/adventure-gamers-online-casino-gambling-website-sale-parasite-seo"><h3>Adventure Games, Poker And Casinos Do Not ‘Overlap’, You Weirdos</h3></a><p>No normal person could type 'Recognizing the growing convergence between gaming and gambling'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/dont-rank-cuomo-video-game"><h3>Experience The Joy Of Rejecting Andrew Cuomo Through A Video Game</h3></a><p>Robert Yang's latest browser game lets you, too, not rank Andrew Cuomo for NYC mayor</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/kai-cenat-eric-adams-nyc-fanum-nypd-giveaway]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[To Truly Feel The Sparkle Of GQuuuuuuX’s Finale, You’ve Gotta Do Your Anime Homework]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/gquuuuuux-finale-gundam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/to-truly-feel-the-sparkle-of-gquuuuuux%E2%80%99s-finale-you%E2%80%99ve-gotta-do-your-anime-homework.1227495/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The twelfth and final episode of <a href="https://aftermath.site/mobile-suit-gundam-gquuuuuux-pronounce" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Mobile Suit Gundam</em> <em>GQuuuuuuX</em></a> has finally landed on Prime Video, bringing the curtain down on the newest installment of a mecha franchise that’s defined anime history for nearly 50 years. When I first covered its<a href="https://aftermath.site/gundam-gquuuuuux-is-the-sum-of-its-parts-in-the-best-way-possible" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> theatrical debut</a>, my knowledge of the original series came secondhand via fandom chatter. But after completing the sidequests of watching the 1979 classic and sampling its sequel, I can say with confidence: <em>GQuuuuuuX</em>’s finale delivers a powerpayoff, but only if you’ve done the homework of watching the OG show that set it all in motion.&nbsp;</p><p><em>Mobile Suit Gundam GQuuuuuuX</em>, a joint venture between studio Sunrise and Khara, boasts writing from <em>Neon Genesis Evangelion</em>’s Hideaki Anno and <em>FLCL</em>’s Yoji Enokido, mech designs from Ikuto Yamashita (of Eva fame), character art from <em>Pokémon</em> designer Take, and is directed by Kazuya Tsurumaki, the visionary behind <em>Rebuild of Evangelion</em>, <em>FLCL</em>, and <em>Diebuster </em>fame. The premise rewrites history with a twist, where the original antagonist, Char Aznable, successfully steals protagonist Amuro Ray’s titular mech, reverse engineers its specs, and alters the course of events of the original anime’s <a href="https://gizmodo.com/gundam-one-year-war-explained-gquuuuuux-2000573253" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">“One Year War”</a> in favor of his nation, Zeon. The moment Char is about to cinch success, he’s cast into a cosmic timeout, setting off the show’s actual plot. Enter Machu, Nyaan, and Shuji, three misfits who stumble into piloting Char’s rebanded Gundam and a mysterious prototype called the GQuuuuuuX years after his disappearance, sparking a new kind of battle where timelines bend and legacies collide.&nbsp;</p><p><em>GQuuuuuuX</em> is littered with deep-cut Easter eggs and mechanical resurrections, chief among them being the return of the <a href="https://www.gundam.info/feature/gquuuuuux/mecha/29/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Psycho Gundam</a>, a mech I pogged out for hard as a newfound <em>Gundam </em>fan, and I can only imagine tenured fans losing their minds. There’s even a subtle but potent tip of its hat at <em>Zeta Gundam</em>, its sequel series. These inclusions never feel intrusive. Instead, they’re the kind of thoughtful fanservice that rewards attention to viewers who “know ball” and feels earned in its execution. All of it is rendered with <a href="https://www.animenewsnetwork.com/interview/2025-06-20/cgi-veteran-hiroyasu-kobayashi-breaks-down-how-he-mech-ed-the-magic-happen-in-mobile-suit-gundam-/.224743" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">vibrant CG and 2D animation</a> that somehow walks the line between spectacle and reverence.&nbsp;</p><p>OG players like <a href="https://gundam.fandom.com/wiki/Kycilia_Zabi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lady Kycilia</a> and tragically overlooked <a href="https://gundam.fandom.com/wiki/Newtype" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Newtypes</a> like <a href="https://gundam.fandom.com/wiki/Challia_Bull" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Chalia Bull</a> return with real narrative weight as the surrogate parents, pitting Machu and Nyaan against each other, transforming their throuple with the milquetoast Shuji (until its finale, to my surprise) into a gripping space Shakespearean tragedy.&nbsp;</p><p>At its core, <em>GQuuuuuuX</em> is a story about a multiverse collapsing in on itself. But, even more so, it’s metatextually about the generational pressure that every new Gundam series carries: measuring up to the seismic impact of the 1979 series. <em>Zeta </em>came the closest, at least in my tentative steps through the Universe Century catalog. Other shows, for all their innovations, can’t escape the long shadow cast by <a href="https://gizmodo.com/gundams-char-aznable-is-still-the-most-magnificent-bast-1824117617" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Char Aznable</a>.</p><p>What <em>GQuuuuuuX</em> gets right, and audaciously so, is that it doesn’t step at the plate and gesture at Char’s legacy. Rather than fracturing timelines for the sake of novelty, the show remixes continuity with purpose, becoming a multiverse sequel that interrogates the past. At the center of that inquiry is the relationship that gave the original series its pulse: <a href="https://gizmodo.com/gundam-gquuuuuux-episode-11-char-amuro-2000617187" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Char and Lalah Sune</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Spoilers for that.</strong></p><p>In the original <em>Gundam</em>, Char, Lalah, and Amuro fall into a dynamic not unlike Zendaya and those two white bois in <a href="https://aftermath.site/challengers-soundtrack-reznor-ross-playstation-wipeout-2097-ape-escape" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Challengers</em></a>—only with psychic powers and giant robots. Char and Amuro may be bitter rivals on the battlefield, but their connection to Lalah—and the complicated, half-spoken romantic web that ties the three together—is the emotional core that gives the series its gravity.</p><p>That’s why one of the OG show’s most gutting moments was Lalah sacrificing herself in the heat of battle by intercepting Amuro’s attack meant to kill Char. Her death, delivered by the very hands of someone who loves her, sends shockwaves through both men, triggering a guilt that echoes across the rest of the original series and well into its sequel. It’s that tragic triangle, equal parts war and destiny, and doomed by the narrative that makes the original <em>Gundam </em>sing.</p><p>In many ways, <em>GQuuuuuuX</em> is once again The Char Aznable Show—a distinction that, frankly, I’d happily vote for any day of the week. The series transcends basic fanservice by steering its narrative away from the man himself and toward his ever-fraught bond with Lalah Sune, reframing her not just as a symbolic Newtype linchpin, but as the emotional culmination of the story itself. Instead of keeping her in the background as a spectral presence, the finale repositions their relationship as its final, devastating denouement.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Lalahs death" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ht1iZieFjf0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Before an alternate-timeline <a href="https://gizmodo.com/gundam-gquuuuuux-episode-9-explained-lalah-rose-of-sharon-2000610640" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lalah even appears in episode nine</a>, pilots Nyaan and Machu are drawn to a mysterious melody—the so-called “<a href="https://gizmodo.com/gundam-gquuuuuux-la-la-sound-explained-lalah-sune-char-2000596117" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lalah Song</a>”— a glittering, otherworldly beacon that ignites a sparkling light show only they can see. Dubbed the “kira kira,” it becomes a psychic siren call and their shared obsession. Think of it as <em>GQuuuuuuX</em>’s version of <em>FLCL</em>’s “fooly cooly”—a provocative phrase folks don’t entirely know the meaning of, but get its meaning.&nbsp;</p><p>It’s here that the series shifts gears from a playful alternative history remix into a genuine sequel that dares to ask a question that’s been circling the fandom for decades: What if Lalah didn’t die? Instead of delivering easy fanservice or nostalgic bait, <em>GQuuuuuuX</em> offers a rich, surprising answer that reshapes our understanding of Char, Newtypes, and the legacy of <em>Gundam </em>itself.&nbsp;</p><p>In its final act, <em>GQuuuuuuX</em> lays all its cards on the table and flips its foundation entirely. Through Machu, we meet Alt-Universe Lalah, one who has already glimpsed her tragic fate from the original timeline and comes to terms with dying to save the man she loves. However, in a twist that reconfigures the show’s stakes, we learn that the original Lalah was spirited away into Machu’s timeline, trapped in the ocean inside the ship where she died, reimagined as a living MacGuffin, “Rose of Sharon.” In the show, Lalah is once again portrayed as an object of power that the villains intend to utilize in a genocidal plan to wipe out humanity and crown Newtypes as the sole, evolved heirs of the galaxy.&nbsp;</p><figure></figure><p>Then there’s Char, who in typical fashion, has been hiding in plain sight, coming out of the shadows in a finale where all of the show’s big players butt heads. But wait, there’s more. The biggest reveal is Shiji, a character who’s essentially just …around, reveals he’s a transplant from the original <em>Gundam </em>timeline who wants to destroy Machu’s universe.&nbsp;</p><p>With each reveal, <em>GQuuuuuuX</em> peels the layers back like a mecha nesting doll—but instead of losing the plot, it deepens its emotional core. In my reading of its finale, Shuji graduates from being a minor character to the spiritual echo of Amuro’s RX-78-2, haunted by the guilt of killing Lalah across infinite timelines. His mission isn’t destruction, it’s liberation. He wants to break the cycle, to free Lalah from the narrative that’s kept her locked in tragedy for half a century.&nbsp;</p><p>And somehow, the show—crafted by true mecha freaks who spent much of production arguing over which mobile suits could win in a fight—pulls off the most emotionally resonant <em>Gundam </em>anime in years. It goes full <em>Rebuild of Evangelion</em>, not just remixing canon but offering a sequel that dares to imagine healing where OG legends and fresh-faced pilots collide in a final battle that’s both about firepower and rewriting fate.</p><p>In the chaos, I got everything I could’ve hoped for as a born-again <em>Gundam </em>fan: Lalah gifting Char a full-blown <a href="https://gizmodo.com/revolutionary-girl-utena-is-as-lynchian-as-shojo-anime-has-ever-been-2000566141" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Revolutionary Girl Utena</em></a>-style magical girl transformation, a tag-team brawl where <a href="https://www.gundam.info/feature/gquuuuuux/mecha/31/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GFreD</a> (the show’s Eva Unit One send up) and the titular <a href="https://www.gundam.info/feature/gquuuuuux/mecha/1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GGuuuuuuX</a> take on the original RX-78-2 in a handicap match so hype I found myself rooting for the legacy mech to lose. And then there’s Char getting a tender <em>Code Geass</em>-flavored finale with Lalah and queer, long overdue send off with Chalia Bull.&nbsp;</p><p>Controversially, even Amuro makes a cameo—one that hits hard in universe and feels gross in the way only anime can, by having his original voice actor Toru Furuya reprise his role following last year’s scandal where he <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/voice-actor-toru-furuya-resigns-from-one-piece-following-affair-scandal" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">admitted to having an affair and physically abusing a fan</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Distasteful as this element in the finale is, it's hard not to appreciate that <em>GQuuuuuuX</em> not only became required viewing in <em>Gundam </em>canon with gusto but also served as a gateway for newfound fans, giving the show a try and developing an interest in watching the original anime, myself included. When I spoke to director Tsurumaki about what he wanted the show’s impact to be, he said precisely that.&nbsp;</p><div><p>“<em>Gundam</em> is a series that has a long history. I watched it as a child, and it has continued on. It’s been around a long time. However, the generation of fans has really been extended. We now have many young generations who have never even watched the first <em>Gundam</em>. I think the first <em>Gundam </em>is extremely interesting, so I really want the young people to watch it because I know they will find it interesting as well,” <a href="https://gizmodo.com/gundam-gquuuuuux-kazuya-tsurumaki-interview-2000593812" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tsurumaki told me</a>. “I hope that the new generation could also watch the old <em>Gundam </em>as well. If that is materialized, I would be really happy.”</p><p>Long story short, it pulls off the impossible, weaving a standalone tale that lightly scaffolds enough context for newcomers while anchoring its emotional payoff in the deep waters of the original <em>Gundam </em>series. By the time its credits roll. <em>GQuuuuuuX</em> doesn’t just earn its place in <em>Gundam</em>’s towering legacy; it canonizes itself, making it required viewing for any fan of the original series and funneling newfound fans to check out the original.</p></div></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/lies-of-p-overture-review"><h3>Lies Of P: Overture Is The Best Parts Of The Game Executed With Confidence</h3></a><p>Lies of P: Overture proves the success of the first game was no fluke, and establishes a bold house style.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/adventure-gamers-online-casino-gambling-website-sale-parasite-seo"><h3>Adventure Games, Poker And Casinos Do Not ‘Overlap’, You Weirdos</h3></a><p>No normal person could type 'Recognizing the growing convergence between gaming and gambling'</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/dont-rank-cuomo-video-game"><h3>Experience The Joy Of Rejecting Andrew Cuomo Through A Video Game</h3></a><p>Robert Yang's latest browser game lets you, too, not rank Andrew Cuomo for NYC mayor</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/gquuuuuux-finale-gundam]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>