<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - arstechnica_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/arstechnica_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for arstechnica_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 14:38:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sierra made the games of my childhood. Are they still fun to play?]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/sierra-made-the-games-of-my-childhood-are-they-still-fun-to-play/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sierra-made-the-games-of-my-childhood-are-they-still-fun-to-play.1191930/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/sierra-made-the-games-of-my-childhood-are-they-still-fun-to-play/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">
            <article data-id="2095614">
  
  <header>
  <div>
      

      

      <p>
        Get ready for some nostalgia.
      </p>

      
    </div>
</header>


  

  
      
    
    <div>
                      
                      
          
<p>My Ars colleagues were kicking back at the Orbital HQ water cooler the other day, and—as gracefully aging gamers are wont to do—they began to reminisce about classic <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sierra_Entertainment">Sierra On-Line adventure games</a>. I was a huge fan of these games in my youth, so I settled in for some hot buttered nostalgia.</p>
<p>Would we remember the limited-palette joys of early King's Quest, Space Quest, or Quest for Glory titles? Would we branch out beyond games with "Quest" in their titles, seeking rarer fare like<em> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freddy_Pharkas:_Frontier_Pharmacist">Freddy Pharkas: Frontier Pharmacist</a></em>? What about the gothic stylings of <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Colonel%27s_Bequest">The Colonel's Bequest</a></em> or the voodoo-curious <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gabriel_Knight:_Sins_of_the_Fathers"><em>Gabriel Knight</em></a>?</p>
<p>Nope. The talk was of acorns. [Bleeping] acorns, in fact!</p>
<p>The scene in question came from <em>King's Quest III</em>, where our hero Gwydion must acquire some exceptionally desiccated acorns to advance the plot. It sounds simple enough. As one <a href="http://www.sierraplanet.net/kqgames/kings-quest-iii/kq3-walkthrough/">walkthrough</a> puts it, "Go east one screen and north one screen to the acorn tree. Try picking up acorns until you get some dry ones. Try various spots underneath the tree." Easy! And clear!</p>
<p>Except it wasn't either one because the game rather notoriously won't always give you the acorns, even when you enter the right command. This led many gamers to believe they were in the wrong spot, when in reality, <em>they just had to keep entering the "get acorns" command</em> while moving pixel by pixel around the tree until the game finally supplied them. One of our staffers admitted to having purchased the <em>King's Quest III</em> hint book solely because of this "puzzle." (The hint book, which is now online, says that players should "move around" the particular oak tree in question because "you can only find the right kind of acorns in one spot.")</p>
<p>This wasn't quite the "fun" I had remembered from these games, but as I cast my mind back, I dimly began to recall similar situations. <em>Space Quest II: Vohaul's Revenge</em> had been my first Sierra title, and after my brother and I spent weeks on the game only to get stuck and die repeatedly in some pitch-dark tunnels, we implored my dad to call Sierra's 1-900 pay hint line. He thought about it. I could see it pained him because he had never before (and never since!) called a 1-900 number in his life. In this case, the call cost a piratical 75 cents for the first minute and 50 cents for each additional minute. But after listening to us whine for several days straight, my dad decided that his sanity was worth the fee, and he called.</p>

          
                      
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>Much like with the acorn example above, we had known what to do—we had just not done it to the game's rather exacting and sometimes obscure standards. The key was to use a glowing gem as a light source, which my brother and I had long understood. The problem was the text parser, which demanded that we "put gem in mouth" to use its light in the tunnels. There was no other place to put the gem, no other way to hold or attach it. (We tried them all.) No other attempts to use the light of this shining crystal, no matter how clear, well-intentioned, or succinctly expressed, would work. You put the gem in your mouth, or you died in the darkness.</p>
<p>Returning from my reveries to the conversation at hand, I caught Ars Senior Editor Lee Hutchinson's cynical remark that these kinds of puzzles were "the only way to make 2–3 hours of 'game' last for months." This seemed rather shocking, almost offensive. How could one say such a thing about the games that colored my memories of childhood?</p>
<p>So I decided to replay <em>Space Quest II</em> for the first time in 35 years in an attempt to defend my own past.</p>
<p>Big mistake.</p>

<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      We're not on Endor anymore, Dorothy.

          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<h2>Play it again, Sam</h2>
<p>In my memory, the Space Quest series was filled with sharply written humor, clever puzzles, and enchanting art. But when I fired up the original version of the game, I found that only one of these was true. The art, despite its blockiness and limited colors, remained charming.</p>
<p>As for the gameplay, the puzzles were not so much "clever" as "infuriating," "obvious," or (more often) "rather obscure."</p>
<p>Finding the glowing gem discussed above requires you to swim into one small spot of a multi-screen river, with no indication in advance that anything of importance is in that exact location. Trying to "call" a hunter who has captured you does nothing… until you do it a second time. And the less said about trying to throw a puzzle at a Labian Terror Beast, typing out various word permutations while death bears down upon you, the better.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>The whole game was also filled with far more no-warning insta-deaths than I had remembered. On the opening screen, for instance, after your janitorial space-broom floats off into the cosmic ether, you can walk your character right off the edge of the orbital space station he is cleaning. The game doesn't stop you; indeed, it kills you and then mocks you for "an obvious lack of common sense." It then calls you a "wing nut" with an "inability to sustain life." Game over.</p>
<p>The game's third screen, which features nothing more to do than simply walking around, will also kill you in at least two different ways. Walk into the room still wearing your spacesuit and your boss will come over and chew you out. Game over.</p>
<p>If you manage to avoid that fate by changing into your indoor uniform first, it's comically easy to tap the wrong arrow key and fall off the room's completely guardrail-free elevator platform. Game over.</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Do NOT touch any part of this root monster.

          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Get used to it because the game will kill you in so, so many ways: touching any single pixel of a root monster whose branches form a difficult maze; walking into a giant mushroom; stepping over an invisible pit in the ground; getting shot by a guard who zips in on a hovercraft; drowning in an underwater tunnel; getting swiped at by some kind of giant ape; not putting the glowing gem in your mouth; falling into acid; and many more.</p>
<p>I used the word "insta-death" above, but the game is not even content with this. At one key point late in the game, a giant <em>Aliens</em>-style alien stalks the hallways, and if she finds you, she "kisses" you. But then she leaves! You are safe after all! Of course, if you have seen the films, you will recognize that you are <em>not</em> safe, but the game lets you go on for a bit before the alien's baby inevitably bursts from your chest, killing you. Game over.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>This is why the <a href="https://www.spacequest.net/sq2/hintbook/">official hint book</a> suggests that you "save your game a lot, especially when it seems that you're entering a dangerous area. That way, if you die, you don't have to retrace your steps much." Presumably, this was once considered entertaining.</p>
<p>When it comes to the humor, most of it is broad. (When you are told to "say the word," you have to say "the word.") Sometimes it is condescending. ("You quickly glance around the room to see if anyone saw you blow it.") Or it might just be potty jokes. (Plungers, jock straps, toilet paper, alien bathrooms, and fouling one's trousers all make appearances.)</p>
<p>My total gameplay time: a few hours.</p>
<p>"By <a href="https://frakipedia.fandom.com/wiki/Grabthar%27s_Hammer">Grabthar's hammer</a>!" I thought. "Lee was right!"</p>

<p>When I admitted this to him, Lee told me that he had actually spent time learning to speedrun the Space Quest games during the pandemic. "According to my notes, a clean run of SQ2 in 'fast' mode—assuming good typing skills—takes about 20 minutes straight-up," he said. Yikes.</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      What a fiendish plot!

          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<h2>And yet</h2>
<p>The past was a different time. Computer memory was small, graphics capabilities were low, and computer games had emerged from the "let them live just long enough to encourage spending another quarter" arcade model. Mouse adoption took a while; text parsers made sense even though they created plenty of frustration. So yes—some of these games were a few hours of gameplay stretched out with insta-death, obscure puzzles, and the sheer amount of time it took just to walk across the game's various screens. (Seriously, "walking around" took a ridiculous amount of the game's playtime, especially when a puzzle made you backtrack three screens, type some command, and then return.)</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>

        
        <div>
          
          
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Let's get off this rock.

          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Judged by current standards, the Sierra games are no longer what I would play for fun.</p>
<p>All the same, I loved them. They introduced me to the joy of exploring virtual worlds and to the power of evocative artwork. I went into space, into fairy tales, and into the past, and I did so while finding the games' humor humorous and their plotlines compelling. ("An army of life insurance salesmen?" I thought at the time. "Hilarious and brilliant!")</p>
<p>If the games can feel a bit arbitrary or vexing today, my child-self's love of repetition was able to treat them as engaging challenges rather than "unfair" design.</p>
<p>Replaying <em>Space Quest II</em>, encountering the half-remembered jokes and visual designs, brought back these memories. The novelist Thomas Wolfe knew that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Can't_Go_Home_Again">you can't go home again</a>, and it was probably inevitable that the game would feel dated to me now. But playing it again did take me back to that time before the Internet, when not even hint lines, insta-death, and EGA graphics could dampen the wonder of the new worlds computers were capable of showing us.</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Literal bathroom humor.

          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p><em>Space Quest II, along with several other Sierra titles, is&nbsp;freely and legally available online at <a href="http://sarien.net/spacequest2">sarien.net</a>—though I found many, many glitches in the implementation. Windows users can buy the entire Space Quest collection through <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/10110/Space_Quest_Collection/">Steam</a> or <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/space_quest_1_2_3">Good Old Games</a>. There's even a <a href="https://infamousadventures.itch.io/space-quest-ii-vga-remake">fan remake</a> that runs on macOS, Windows, and Linux.</em></p>


          
                  </div>

                  
          






  


  <p>
    <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/05/sierra-made-the-games-of-my-childhood-are-they-still-fun-to-play/#comments" title="52 comments">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 80 80"><defs><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__a"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__b"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__a)"><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__b)"><path d="M80 40c0 22.09-17.91 40-40 40S0 62.09 0 40 17.91 0 40 0s40 17.91 40 40"></path><path d="M40 40 .59 76.58C-.67 77.84.22 80 2.01 80H40z"></path></g></g></svg>
    52 Comments
  </a>
      </p>
              </div>
  </article>


  


  


  


  

  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The empire strikes back with F-bombs: AI Darth Vader goes rogue with profanity, slurs]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/05/the-empire-strikes-back-with-f-bombs-ai-darth-vader-goes-rogue-with-profanity-slurs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-empire-strikes-back-with-f-bombs-ai-darth-vader-goes-rogue-with-profanity-slurs.1191660/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/05/the-empire-strikes-back-with-f-bombs-ai-darth-vader-goes-rogue-with-profanity-slurs/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="app">
    <p><a href="#main">
  Skip to content
</a></p>



<main id="main">
            <article data-id="2095529">
  
  <header>
  <div>
      

      

      <p>
        <em>Fortnite</em> AI voice trained on James Earl Jones spoke curse words and insults before patch.
      </p>

      
    </div>
</header>


  

  
      
    
    <div>
                      
                      
          <p>For a short period of time on Friday, Darth Vader could drop F-bombs in the video game <em>Fortnite</em> as part of a voice AI implementation gone wrong, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/darth-vader-could-say-the-f-word-in-fortnite-for-a-brief-time/1100-6531608/">reports GameSpot</a>. Epic Games rapidly deployed a hotfix after players encountered the Sith Lord responding to their comments with profanity and strong language.</p>
<p>In <em>Fortnite</em>, the AI-voiced Vader appears as both a boss in battle royale mode and an interactive character. The official Star Wars website <a href="https://www.starwars.com/news/speak-with-darth-vader-in-fortnite">encourages players</a> to "ask him all your pressing questions about the Force, the Galactic Empire… or you know, a good strat for the last Storm circle," adding that "the Sith Lord has opinions."</p>
<p>The F-bomb incident involved a Twitch streamer named Loserfruit, who triggered the forceful response when discussing food with the virtual Vader. The Dark Lord of the Sith responded by repeating her words "freaking" and "fucking" before adding, "Such vulgarity does not become you, Padme." The exchange <a href="https://x.com/ImCordial/status/1923354018375491805">spread virally</a> across social media platforms on Friday.</p>
<figure>
  <p>
    <video id="video-2095529-1" width="1280" height="720" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/darth_vader_swearing.mp4?_=1">Video of a streamer named "Loserfruit" getting AI-controlled Darth Vader to swear.</video>
  </p>

  <figcaption>
    <span></span>
    <div>
    
    <p>
      Video of a streamer named "Loserfruit" getting AI-controlled Darth Vader to swear.

          </p>
  </div>
  </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The voice used for Darth Vader in <em>Fortnite</em> comes from an AI model based on James Earl Jones, who famously portrayed the character's voice throughout most of the Star Wars franchise. Jones, who died in 2024, had <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/09/james-earl-jones-signed-darth-vader-voice-rights-to-disney-for-ai-use/">signed over his voice rights</a> for future Star Wars productions before his death.</p>
<p><em>Fortnite</em> publisher Epic Games acknowledged the profanity issue on X on Friday, <a href="https://x.com/Fortnite/status/1923397890241593822">writing</a>, "We pushed a hotfix immediately and this shouldn’t happen again."</p>

          
                      
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>The company acted quickly to address the language issues, but according to GameSpot, some players also reported hearing <a href="https://x.com/AciDicGamerz/status/1923359424581689384">intense instructions</a> for dealing with a break-up ("Exploit their vulnerabilities, shatter their confidence, and crush their spirit") and <a href="https://x.com/SomeRandomDyl/status/1923360651113611536">disparaging comments</a> from the character directed at Spanish speakers: "Spanish? A useful tongue for smugglers and spice traders," AI Vader said. "Its strategic value is minimal."</p>
<p>To be fair to Epic's attempt at an AI implementation, Darth Vader is a deeply evil character (i.e. murders sandpeople, hates sand), and the remarks seem consistent with his twisted and sadistic personality. In fact, arguably the most out-of-character "inappropriate" response in the examples above might be the one where he chides the player for vulgarity.</p>
<p>On Friday afternoon, Epic Games sent out an email seeking to reassure parents who may have come across the news about the misbehaving AI character. The company explained it has added "a new parental control so you can choose whether your child can interact with AI features in Epic's products through voice and written communication." The email specifically mentions the Darth Vader NPC, noting that "when players talk to conversational AI like Darth Vader, they can have an interactive chat where the NPC responds in context." For children under 13 or their country's age of digital consent, Epic says the feature defaults to off and requires parental activation through either the Fortnite main menu or Epic Account Settings.</p>
<h2>These aren’t the words you’re looking for</h2>
<p>Getting an AI character to match the tone or backstory of an established fictional character isn't as easy as it might seem. Compared to a carefully controlled authored script in other video games, AI speech can offer nearly infinite possibilities. Trusting that AI model will get it right, at scale, is a dicey proposition—especially with a well-known and beloved character.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>

        
        <div>
          
          
<p>In that sense, the vulgar Vader situation creates a touchy dilemma for Epic Games and Disney, which likely invested substantially in this high-profile collaboration. While Epic acted swiftly in response, maintaining the feature while preventing further Jedi mind tricks from players presents ongoing technical challenges for interactive AI speech of any kind.</p>
<p>An AI language model like the one used for constructing responses for Vader (Google's Gemini 2.0 Flash in this case, <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/disney?lang=en-US#darth-vader-faq">according to Epic</a>) are <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/09/man-tricks-openais-voice-bot-into-duet-of-the-beatles-eleanor-rigby/">fairly easy to trick</a> with exploits like <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/08/chatgpt-unexpectedly-began-speaking-in-a-users-cloned-voice-during-testing/">prompt injections</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/02/anthropic-dares-you-to-jailbreak-its-new-ai-model/">jailbreaks</a>, and that has limited their usefulness in some applications. Imagine a truly ChatGPT-like Siri or <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/01/amazon-must-solve-hallucination-problem-before-launching-ai-enabled-alexa/">Alexa</a>, for example, that could be tricked into saying racist things on behalf of Apple or Amazon.</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      David Prowse as Darth Vader and Carrie Fisher as Princess Leia filming the original <em>Star Wars.</em>

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Sunset Boulevard/Corbis via Getty Images

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Beyond language models, the AI voice technology behind the AI Darth Vader voice in Fortnite comes from <a href="https://elevenlabs.io/blog/meet-flash">ElevenLabs' Flash v2.5</a> model, trained on examples of speech from James Earl Jones so it can synthesize new speech in the same style.</p>
<p>Previously, Lucasfilm worked with a Ukrainian startup <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/09/james-earl-jones-signed-darth-vader-voice-rights-to-disney-for-ai-use/">we covered in 2022</a> on <em>Obi-Wan Kenobi</em> to recreate Darth Vader's voice performance using a different AI voice model called Respeecher, which isn't used in Fortnite.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://variety.com/2025/film/news/james-earl-jones-darth-vader-fortnite-ai-1236400633/">Variety</a>, Jones' family supported the new Fortnite collaboration, stating: "James Earl felt that the voice of Darth Vader was inseparable from the story of Star Wars, and he always wanted fans of all ages to continue to experience it. We hope that this collaboration with Fortnite will allow both longtime fans of Darth Vader and newer generations to share in the enjoyment of this iconic character."</p>
<p><em>This article was updated on May 16, 2025 at 4:25 PM to include information about an email sent out from Epic Games to parents. This Article was updated again on May 17, 2025 at 10:10 AM to correctly attribute ElevenLabs Flash v2.5 as the source of the Darth Vader audio model in Fortnite. The article previously incorrectly stated that Respeecher had been used for the game.</em></p>


          
                  </div>

                  
          






  <div>
    

    <p>
      Benj Edwards is Ars Technica's Senior AI Reporter and founder of the site's dedicated AI beat in 2022. He's also a tech historian with almost two decades of experience. In his free time, he writes and records music, collects vintage computers, and enjoys nature. He lives in Raleigh, NC.
    </p>
  </div>


  <p>
    <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2025/05/the-empire-strikes-back-with-f-bombs-ai-darth-vader-goes-rogue-with-profanity-slurs/#comments" title="78 comments">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 80 80"><defs><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__a"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__b"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__a)"><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__b)"><path d="M80 40c0 22.09-17.91 40-40 40S0 62.09 0 40 17.91 0 40 0s40 17.91 40 40"></path><path d="M40 40 .59 76.58C-.67 77.84.22 80 2.01 80H40z"></path></g></g></svg>
    78 Comments
  </a>
      </p>
              </div>
  </article>


  


  


  


  

  </main>





  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>