<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - arstechnica_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/arstechnica_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for arstechnica_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 12:33:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reminder: Donate to win swag in our annual Charity Drive sweepstakes]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/reminder-donate-to-win-swag-in-our-annual-charity-drive-sweepstakes-16/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reminder-donate-to-win-swag-in-our-annual-charity-drive-sweepstakes.1068282/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/reminder-donate-to-win-swag-in-our-annual-charity-drive-sweepstakes-16/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<h2>How it works</h2>
<p>Donating is easy. Simply <a href="https://childsplay.salsalabs.org/Donate/index.html">donate to Child's Play</a> using a credit card or PayPal or <a href="http://eff.org/AT2014">donate to the EFF</a> using PayPal, credit card, or cryptocurrency. You can also support Child's Play directly by using <a href="https://my.onecause.com/fundraiser/organizations/8534d777-53ce-4d94-a537-c8e0cbb7acb0/fundraisers/fundraiser:ae0c129c-94ac-4e63-a265-20b71ac4bd03">this Ars Technica campaign page</a> or picking an item from the Amazon wish list of a specific hospital on <a href="https://childsplaycharity.org/get-involved#hospital-map">its donation page</a>. Donate as much or as little as you feel comfortable with—every little bit helps.</p>
<p>Once that's done, it's time to register your entry in our sweepstakes. Just grab a digital copy of your receipt (a forwarded email, a screenshot, or simply a cut-and-paste of the text) and send it to <a href="mailto:ArsCharityDrive@gmail.com">ArsCharityDrive@gmail.com</a> with your name, postal address, daytime telephone number, and email address by 11:59 pm ET Wednesday, January 2, 2025. (One entry per person, and each person can only win up to one prize. US residents only. NO PURCHASE NECESSARY. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/2024-ars-technica-charity-drive-official-rules/">See Official Rules</a> for more information, including how to enter without making a donation. Also, refer to the <a href="http://www.condenast.com/privacy-policy#privacypolicy">Ars Technica privacy policy (https://www.condenast.com/privacy-policy)</a>.</p>
<p>We'll then contact the winners and have them choose their prize by January 31, 2025 (choosing takes place in the order the winners are drawn). Good luck!</p>


          
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The quest to save the world’s largest CRT TV from destruction]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/retro-gamers-save-one-of-the-last-45-inch-crt-tvs-in-existence/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-quest-to-save-the-world%E2%80%99s-largest-crt-tv-from-destruction.1068279/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/retro-gamers-save-one-of-the-last-45-inch-crt-tvs-in-existence/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                      
                      
          <p>At this point, any serious retro gamer knows that a bulky cathode ray tube (CRT) TV provides <a href="https://hackaday.com/2024/10/11/are-crt-tvs-important-for-retro-gaming/">the most authentic</a>, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2018/01/video-demonstrates-the-marvel-of-crt-displays-at-380000-frames-per-second/">lag-free experience</a> for game consoles that predate the era of flat-panel HDTVs (i.e,. before the Xbox 360/PlayStation 3 era). But modern gamers used to massive flat panel HD displays might balk at the display size of the most common CRTs, which tend to average in the 20- to 30-inch range (depending on the era they were made).</p>
<p>For those who want the absolute largest CRT experience possible, Sony's KX-45ED1 model (aka PVM-4300) has become the stuff of legends. The massive 45-inch CRT was <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/crtgaming/comments/xuhbb9/biggest_trinitron_ever_the_kx45ed1_it_was_sold/">sold in the late '80s</a> for a whopping $40,000 (over $100,000 in today's dollars), according to contemporary reports.</p>
<p>That price means it wasn't exactly a mass-market product, and the limited supply has made it something of a white whale for CRT enthusiasts to this day. While a few pictures have emerged of the PVM-4300 <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/crtgaming/comments/liyitz/the_picture_of_kx45ed1_aka_pvm4300/">in the wild</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/444560212348840/posts/2936345963170240/">in marketing materials</a>, no collector has stepped forward with detailed footage of a working unit.</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      The PVM-4300, seen dwarfing the tables and chairs at an Osaka noodle restaurant.

              <span>
          Credit:

                      <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JfZxOuc9Qwk" target="_blank">
          
          Shank Mods

                      </a>
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Enter Shank Mods, a retro gaming enthusiast and <a href="https://youtu.be/e9FhIZkm4cw?si=aNcBS1vIb7zGAuuU">renowned maker</a> of <a href="https://youtu.be/9LkZLFiFLd8?si=dV99dj16GTV2N1Kt">portable versions</a> of <a href="https://youtu.be/2VOLUOIwbP4?si=l2ekVoMoisD5MpLx">non-portable consoles</a>. In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JfZxOuc9Qwk">a fascinating 35-minute video</a> posted this weekend, he details his years-long effort to find and secure a PVM-4300 from a soon-to-be-demolished restaurant in Japan and preserve it for years to come.</p>
<h2>A confirmed white whale sighting</h2>
<p>Shank Mods' quest started in earnest in October 2022, when the moderator of <a href="https://consolemods.org/wiki/CRT:PVM-4300">the Console Modding wiki</a>, Derf, reached out with a tip on a PVM-4300 sighting in the wild. A 7-year-old Japanese blog post included a photo of the massive TV that could be sourced to a waiting room of the Chikuma Soba noodle restaurant and factory in Osaka, Japan.</p>
<p>The find came just in time, as Chikuma Soba's website said the restaurant was scheduled to move to a new location in mere days, after which the old location would be demolished. Shank Mods <a href="https://x.com/ShankMods/status/1583261045316993024">took to Twitter</a> looking to recruit an Osaka local in a last-ditch effort to save the TV from destruction. Local game developer <a href="https://x.com/Bebetheman">Bebe Tinari</a> responded to the call and managed to visit the site, confirming that the TV still existed and even turned on.</p>

          
                      
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>