<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - arstechnica_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/arstechnica_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for arstechnica_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 09:08:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia’s 50-series cards drop support for PhysX, impacting older games]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/02/batman-arkham-games-among-those-losing-physx-powers-on-newer-nvidia-gpus/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia%E2%80%99s-50-series-cards-drop-support-for-physx-impacting-older-games.1112841/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/02/batman-arkham-games-among-those-losing-physx-powers-on-newer-nvidia-gpus/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<p>Nvidia's PhysX offerings to developers didn't always generate warm feelings. As part of its broader GamesWorks package, PhysX was cited as one of the reasons <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2015/05/amd-says-nvidias-gameworks-completely-sabotaged-witcher-3-performance/"><em>The Witcher 3</em> ran at notably sub-optimal levels</a> at launch. Protagonist Geralt's hair, rendered in PhysX-powered HairWorks, was a burden on some chipsets.</p>
<p>PhysX started appearing in general game engines, like <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2015/03/unity-5-game-engine-brings-enhanced-graphic-tools-new-cloud-services/">Unity 5</a>, and was eventually open-sourced, first in <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20181205103131/https://developer.nvidia.com/physx-sdk">limited computer and mobile form</a>, then <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20230528035837/https://developer.nvidia.com/blog/open-source-simulation-expands-with-nvidia-physx-5-release/">more broadly</a>. As an application wrapped up in Nvidia's 32-bit CUDA API and platform, the PhysX engine had a built-in shelf life. Now the expiration date is known, and it is conditional on buying into Nvidia's 50-series video cards—whenever they approach reasonable human prices.</p>
<figure>
    <div id="caption-2076751"><p>
              See that smoke? It's from Sweden, originally.
                              </p><p>
                  Credit:
                                      Gearbox/Take 2
                                  </p>
                          </div>
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      See that smoke? It's from Sweden, originally.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Gearbox/Take 2

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<h2>The real dynamic particles were the friends we made…</h2>
<p><a href="https://nvidia.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/5615">Nvidia noted in mid-January</a> that 32-bit applications cannot be developed or debugged on the latest versions of its CUDA toolkit. They will still run on cards before the 50 series. Technically, you could also keep an older card installed on your system for compatibility, which is real dedication to early-2010's-era particle physics.</p>
<p>Technically, a 64-bit game could still support PhysX on Nvidia's newest GPUs, but the heyday of PhysX, as a stand-alone technology switched on in game settings, tended to coincide with the 32-bit computing era.</p>
<p>If you load up a 32-bit game now with PhysX enabled (or <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/forums/geforce-graphics-cards/5/557125/rtx-5090-missing-physx-support/">forced in a config file</a>) and a 50-series Nvidia GPU installed, there's a good chance the physics work will be passed to the CPU instead of the GPU, likely <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mJGf0-tGaf4">bottlenecking the game and steeply lowering frame rates</a>. Of course, turning off PhysX entirely raised frame rates above even native GPU support levels.</p>
<p>Demanding <em>Borderlands 2</em> keep using PhysX made it so it "runs terrible," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nvidia/comments/1irs8xk/comment/mdauwh3/?utm_name=web3xcss">noted one Redditor</a>, even if the dust clouds and flapping cloth strips looked interesting. Other games with PhysX baked in, as listed by ResetEra completists, include <em>Metro 2033,&nbsp;</em><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2013/10/assassins-creed-iv-review-enormous-but-ultimately-empty/"><em>Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag</em></a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_Trek_(2013_video_game)">the 2013&nbsp;<em>Star Trek&nbsp;</em>game</a>.</p>
<p>Commenters on Reddit and ResetEra note that many of the games listed had performance issues with PhysX long before Nvidia forced them to either turn off or be loaded onto a CPU. For some games, however, PhysX enabled destructible environments, "dynamic bank notes" and "posters" (in the&nbsp;<em>Arkham</em> games), fluid simulations, and base gameplay physics.</p>
<p>Anyone who works in, or cares about, game preservation has always had their work cut out for them. But it's a particularly tough challenge to see certain aspects of a game's operation lost to the forward march of the CUDA platform, something that's harder to explain than a scratched CD or Windows compatibility.</p>


          
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Streamer completes hitless run of seven FromSoft Soulslikes without leveling up]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/02/the-god-run-dark-souls-player-beats-seven-games-at-level-1-without-taking-a-hit/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/streamer-completes-hitless-run-of-seven-fromsoft-soulslikes-without-leveling-up.1112736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/02/the-god-run-dark-souls-player-beats-seven-games-at-level-1-without-taking-a-hit/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<h2>What now?</h2>
<p>In <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2383614433">a follow-up stream on Monday</a>, Nico called his latest gaming achievement "by far the most difficult run I have ever completed. We did the same run leveled, but it is not even close to as difficult as the level 1 run. The level 1 run, the difficulty level is just insane."</p>
<p>Aside from being an incredible individual achievement, Nico's level 1 God Run helps put FromSoft's reputation for difficulty into perspective. While these games can punish failure very harshly—and require lots of arcane knowledge to play well—Nico shows that they're also designed to be fair to players with the steely nerves to attack and dodge with perfect timing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">After almost 2 years of attempts!<br>
IT'S FINALLY DONE!<br>
7 Games, 0 Hits, Character Level 1!</p>
<p>WE DID IT!</p>
<p>Here is the last fight! (and sorry that it is cinder again) 😅<a href="https://t.co/0g24MY4wRy">https://t.co/0g24MY4wRy</a></p>
<p>— Nico (@dinossindgeil) <a href="https://twitter.com/dinossindgeil/status/1891230190291788237?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 16, 2025</a></p></blockquote>
<p>With his ultimate FromSoft achievement now complete, Nico said he's "going to take a vacation now. And by vacation, I mean I'll continue doing hitless runs, I will continue being live every day... but we're going to do some smaller ones for now." In the longer term, Nico hinted that he is "going to work on one really big project again," but wasn't willing to provide details just yet.</p>
<p>If you want to follow in Nico's hitless FromSoft footsteps, he puts out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=svsAMPM9Pzc">instructional videos</a> laying out the specific paths and strategies needed to get through specific games (Pro tip: It involves a lot of well-timed rolling and memorizing attack and stagger patterns). Nico also took the time to recently <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HzQ2o0pejVQ">rank how hard he finds each game in the God Run</a>, putting <em>Elden Ring</em> in the easiest tier and <em>Dark Souls II</em> in the hardest.</p>


          
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>