<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - arstechnica_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/arstechnica_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for arstechnica_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 19:03:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chris Roberts hopes Squadron 42 will be “almost as big” as GTA VI next year]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/08/chris-roberts-hopes-squadron-42-will-be-almost-as-big-as-gta-vi-next-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/chris-roberts-hopes-squadron-42-will-be-%E2%80%9Calmost-as-big%E2%80%9D-as-gta-vi-next-year.1282248/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<h2>The long and winding road</h2>
<p>It's hard to remember now, but <em>Star Citizen</em>'s <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2012/11/star-citizens-6-3-million-haul-breaks-gaming-crowdfunding-record/">then-impressive $6.3 million Kickstarter campaign</a> came just a few months before <em>Grand Theft Auto V</em> <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2013/09/gta-v/">first launched on the PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360</a> (remember those?). But development on Rockstar's long-awaited sequel <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-6-development-began-in-earnest-in-2020-following-the-massive-success-of-red-dead-redemption-2-take-two-says">didn't start in earnest until 2020</a>, publisher Take Two says, around the time <em>Star Citizen</em> developer Roberts Space Industries was <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2020/01/crytek-cloud-imperium-battle-over-how-to-end-star-citizen-lawsuit/">settling a contentious lawsuit over game engine rights</a> and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2020/07/star-citizen-dev-offers-roadmap-for-development-of-new-development-roadmap/">rolling out a new development roadmap</a> for the game.</p>
<figure>
    <div id="caption-2114079"><p>
              A graph visualizing the growing crowdfunding for <em>Star Citizen</em> from 2012 (top) through 2022 (bottom).
                              </p>
                          </div>
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      A graph visualizing the growing crowdfunding for <em>Star Citizen</em> from 2012 (top) through 2022 (bottom).

              <span>
          Credit:

                      <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/starcitizen/comments/101iko4/another_recordshattering_year_in_funding/" target="_blank">
          
          Reddit / Rainbowles

                      </a>
                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>Of course, the development of <em>Grand Theft Auto VI</em> has happened completely behind closed doors, with developer Rockstar and publisher Take Two only occasionally offering <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/12/grand-theft-auto-vi-trailer-confirms-many-things-including-its-florida-vibes/">tiny drops of information</a> to a desperate press and fan base. By contrast, Roberts Space Industries has issued&nbsp;<a href="https://robertsspaceindustries.com/en/community/devtracker" target="_blank" rel="noopener">regular, incredibly detailed information dumps</a>&nbsp;on the drawn-out development progress for&nbsp;<em>Star Citizen</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>Squadron 42</em>, even when that kind of openness has contributed to the public appearance of internal dysfunction.</p>
<p>The massive, ongoing crowdfunding that powers the open development structure "allows us to do things without imposing the framework of a typical video game studio," Roberts told La Presse. "The players who fund us expect the best game, period. We don't have to streamline, cut jobs, or change our business model."</p>
<p>That pre-launch development cycle must eventually end, of course, and the La Presse report suggests that the full 1.0 release of <em>Star Citizen</em> is "now promised" for "2027 or 2028." While we'd love to believe that, the history of <em>Star Citizen</em> development thus far (and the lack of any provided sourcing for the claim) makes us more than a little skeptical.</p>


          
                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/08/chris-roberts-hopes-squadron-42-will-be-almost-as-big-as-gta-vi-next-year/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>