<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - arstechnica_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/arstechnica_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for arstechnica_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 10:44:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon’s Mass Effect TV series is actually going to be made]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/amazons-mass-effect-tv-series-is-actually-going-to-be-made/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon%E2%80%99s-mass-effect-tv-series-is-actually-going-to-be-made.1030446/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/amazons-mass-effect-tv-series-is-actually-going-to-be-made/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                      
                      
          <p>Confirming previous <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2021/11/amazon-is-nearing-a-deal-to-make-a-mass-effect-tv-series/">rumors</a>, <a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/mass-effect-tv-series-amazon-writer-marvel-1236203755/">Variety</a> reports that Amazon will be moving ahead with producing a TV series based on the popular Mass Effect video game franchise. The writing and production staff involved might not inspire confidence from fans, though.</p>
<p>The series' writer and executive producer is slated to be Daniel Casey, who until now was best known as the primary screenwriter on <em>F9: The Fast Saga</em>, one of the late sequels in the Fast and the Furious franchise. He was also part of a team of writers behind the relatively little-known 2018 science fiction film <em>Kin</em>.</p>
<p>Karim Zreik will also produce, and his background is a little more encouraging; his main claim to fame is in the short-lived Marvel Television unit, which produced relatively well-received series like <em>Daredevil</em> and <em>Jessica Jones</em> for Netflix before Disney+ launched with its Marvel Cinematic Universe shows.</p>
<p>Another listed producer is Ari Arad, who has some background in video game adaptations, including the <em>Borderlands</em> and <em>Uncharted</em> movies, as well as the much-maligned live-action adaptation of <em>Ghost in the Shell</em>.</p>
<p>So yeah, it's a bit of a mixed bag here. No plot details have been released, but it seems likely that the show will tell a new story rather than focus on the saga of Commander Shepherd from the games, since the games were all about the player inhabiting that character with their own choices. That's only a guess, though.</p>
<p>Amazon is currently riding high after the smash success of another video game TV series, <em>Fallout</em>, which impressed both longtime and new fans when it debuted to critical acclaim and record viewing numbers earlier this year.</p>


          
                      
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>