<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - arstechnica_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/arstechnica_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for arstechnica_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 18:20:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam will wind down support for 32-bit Windows as that version of Windows fades]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/steam-will-drop-support-for-the-last-32-bit-windows-systems-in-january-2026/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-will-wind-down-support-for-32-bit-windows-as-that-version-of-windows-fades.1302837/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<p>Though the 32-bit versions of Windows were widely used from the mid-90s all the way through to the early 2010s, this change is coming so late that it should only actually affect a statistically insignificant number of Steam users. Valve already pulled Steam support for all versions of Windows 7 and Windows 8 <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/03/steam-will-end-support-for-windows-7-and-8-in-january-of-2024/">in January 2024</a>, and 2021's Windows 11 was the first in decades not to ship a 32-bit version. That leaves only the 32-bit version of Windows 10, which is old enough that it will stop getting security updates in either October 2025 or October 2026, depending on how you count it.</p>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/hwsurvey/directx/">According to Steam Hardware Survey data</a> from August, usage of the 32-bit version of Windows 10 (and any other 32-bit version of Windows) is so small that it's lumped in with "other" on the page that tracks Windows version usage. All "other" versions of Windows combined represent roughly 0.05 percent of all Steam users. The 64-bit version of Windows 10 still runs on just over a third of all Steam-using Windows PCs, while the 64-bit version of Windows 11 accounts for just under two-thirds.</p>
<p>The change to the Steam client shouldn't have any effects on game availability or compatibility. Any older 32-bit games that you can currently run in 64-bit versions of Windows will continue to work fine because, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/11/steam-drops-macos-mojave-support-effectively-ending-life-for-many-32-bit-games/">unlike modern macOS versions</a>, new 64-bit versions of Windows still maintain compatibility with most 32-bit apps.</p>


          
                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/09/steam-will-drop-support-for-the-last-32-bit-windows-systems-in-january-2026/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>