<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 07:34:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout season 2 reportedly adds Marvel actor Kumail Nanjiani to its cast]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-season-2-reportedly-adds-marvel-actor-kumail-nanjiani-to-its-cast</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-season-2-reportedly-adds-marvel-actor-kumail-nanjiani-to-its-cast.1090860/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-season-2-reportedly-adds-marvel-actor-kumail-nanjiani-to-its-cast<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Vault-dweller-Lucy-in-Fallout-TV-show-looks-up-towards-an-unseen-character-off-screen-plus-MCU-actor-Kumail-is-on-the-left-hand-side.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Amazon/Marvel/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Kumail Nanjiani has reportedly joined the cast for the second season of Amazon's Fallout series.</p>
<p>That's coming via a recently published newsletter from <a href="https://www.theinsneider.com/p/final-oscar-nomination-predictions-kumail-nanjiani-fallout-season-2-cast-brotherhood-steel">The InSneider</a>. Amazon has not confirmed Nanjiani's casting, however, <a href="https://x.com/thegameawards/status/1882468492303388759">it is said</a> the actor - who previously appeared as Kingo the MCU's Eternals film alongside Angelina Jolie - will play "a high-ranking official within the Brotherhood of Steel".</p>
<p>Nanjiani looks set to join the likes of Ella Purnell, Aaron Moten, Kyle MacLachlan and Walton Goggins - who play wide-eyed vault dweller Lucy, squire of the Brotherhood of Steel Maximus, disgraced (at least, in the eyes of many) Vault-Tec executive Hank MacLean and the gunslinging Ghoul, respectively - when the series makes its return.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="7 Forgotten Fallout Crossovers - HOW MANY DO YOU REMEMBER?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/by58vpN5lDU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>7 Forgotten Fallout Crossovers - HOW MANY DO YOU REMEMBER?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/by58vpN5lDU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/by58vpN5lDU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>7 Forgotten Fallout Crossovers - HOW MANY DO YOU REMEMBER? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=by58vpN5lDU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In addition Nanjiani, it has also been reported that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-tv-series-second-season-lands-home-alone-star">Home Alone actor Macaulay Culkin will be heading to the wastelands for Fallout's second season</a>, allegedly as a "a crazy genius-type character".</p>
<p>Fallout's first season was a huge hit for Amazon, and was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/amazons-fallout-show-officially-renewed-for-second-season">quickly picked up for a second season</a>. Jonathan Nolan and Lisa Joy - who executive produce the show via Kilter Films - said they couldn't "wait to blow up the world all over again".</p>
<p>Production on <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-season-two-filming-begins-a-lot-sooner-than-expected">Fallout's second season began in November</a>, and in December <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-season-two-starts-filming-with-walton-goggins-back-in-character">Walton Goggins shared a close up of the show's prosthetic team applying the Ghoul's leathery, nuclear worn skin</a> on Instagram.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, devastating wildfires raged across multiple districts of Los Angeles, shutting down production across Hollywood and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/devastating-los-angeles-fires-shut-down-fallout-season-2">impacting the filming of Fallout season 2</a> along with a swathe of other projects.</p>
<p>Following these fires, a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-announces-donation-to-los-angeles-wildfire-relief">number of companies announced donations to help with relief</a> and rebuilding efforts.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077's latest patch includes DLSS 4 support ahead of next week's RTX 50 Series arrival]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/cyberpunk-2077s-latest-patch-adds-dlss-4-support-ahead-of-next-weeks-rtx-50-series-arrival</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077s-latest-patch-includes-dlss-4-support-ahead-of-next-weeks-rtx-50-series-arrival.1090797/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/cyberpunk-2077s-latest-patch-adds-dlss-4-support-ahead-of-next-weeks-rtx-50-series-arrival<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Well here we are again, with yet another <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a> patch, despite CD Projekt having officially wrapped up development on the game last year. And the headline feature this time around is DLSS 4 support, added in anticipation of Nvidia's upcoming RTX 50 Series of GPUs.
</p>
<p>
As detailed in <a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/news/51296/patch-2-21">CD Projekt's update 2.21 patch notes</a>, Cyberpunk 2077 now supports "DLSS 4 with Multi Frame Generation for GeForce RTX 50 Series graphics cards, which boosts FPS by using AI to generate up to three times per traditionally rendered frame". This, the studio notes, will be enabled alongside the release of the RTX 50 Series next Thursday, 30th January. 
</p>
<p>
Additionally, DLSS 4's arrival brings "faster single Frame Generation with reduced memory usage" that's available for users with either RTX 50 and 40 Series GPUs. Furthermore, players "can now choose between the CNN model or the new Transformer model for DLSS Ray Reconstruction, DLSS Super Resolution, and DLAA on all GeForce RTX graphics cards today. The new Transformer model enhances stability, lighting, and detail in motion."
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: Switch 2 and Mario Kart 9 have been revealed - but questions remain.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UyPgPcxLlIk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
There's more going on in today's update than that, however. Version 2.21 also features an extensive range of fixes for Cyberpunk 2077's photo mode, and addresses various issues across the likes of vehicle colour customisation and character creation. Xbox and PlayStation users also get a number of platform-specific fixes, as detailed in <a href="https://www.cyberpunk.net/en/news/51296/patch-2-21">CD Projekt's patch notes</a>.
</p><p>
Today's release follows December's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cyberpunk-2077s-22-adds-new-secrets-expanded-customisation-options-and-more">surprise 2.2 update</a>, which introduced the likes of expanded customisation options and new photo mode features - hence the focus on those particular modes in today's patch. CD Projekt's continuing support of Cyberpunk 2077 is perhaps a little surprising given the studio <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cyberpunk-2077-development-has-finally-wound-down-after-three-and-a-half-years">officially ended its development</a> last May - although a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cd-projekt-is-bringing-cyberpunk-2077-to-macs-early-next-year">Mac version</a> has since been announced for release this year.
</p>
<p>
As previously confirmed, the bulk of CD Projekt is now focused on developing <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a>, which was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cd-projekt-confirms-new-the-witcher-game-in-development">announced back in 2022</a> and finally got its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-gets-its-a-first-trailer-and-yes-ciri-is-the-star">big Ciri-focused reveal</a> last year.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>