<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 20:22:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ori, No Rest for the Wicked studio goes 'fully independent' in aftermath of Private Division closure]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ori-no-rest-for-the-wicked-studio-goes-fully-independent-in-aftermath-of-private-division-closure</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ori-no-rest-for-the-wicked-studio-goes-fully-independent-in-aftermath-of-private-division-closure.1131537/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ori-no-rest-for-the-wicked-studio-goes-fully-independent-in-aftermath-of-private-division-closure<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Take-Two had previously retained rights to latest game.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ori-will-of-the-wisps-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Moon Studios/Xbox Game Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Moon Studios - the developer behind the acclaimed Ori series - has announced it's now 'fully independent', having secured the publishing rights to its latest game, No Rest for the Wicked, from Grand Theft Auto and Borderlands publisher <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/take-two-interactive">Take-Two Interactive</a>.
</p>
<p>
No Rest for the Wicked, which released into early access last year, was originally set to be published by Private Division - the indie-focused label established by Take-Two in 2017. However, those plans changed following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/take-two-sells-private-division-label-confirms-closure-of-olliolli-world-and-kerbal-space-program-2-studios">Take-Two's decision to sell Private Division to an unnamed party</a> last year, as it shifted its focus away from smaller titles.
</p>
<p>
The sale, Take-Two revealed at the time, would include the rights to "substantially all" of Private Division's live and unreleased titles, including the likes of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/kerbal-space-program-2">Kerbal Space Program 2</a> - but the publisher confirmed it would continue to support No Rest for the Wicked, despite the sale.
</p>
<p>
Now, however - some four months after Private Division's divestment - Moon Studios has announced it's secured the publishing rights to No Rest for the Wicked from Take-Two Interactive, insisting the move will allow it to "execute our vision without restrictions." The developer's announcement coincides with a major update for the action-RPG, which will have been in PC early access for a year next month.
</p>
<p>
As for Private Division, a report in January claimed it had been <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/former-annapurna-interactive-staff-reportedly-taking-over-private-division-portfolio-following-take-two-sale">purchased by Texas-based private equity firm Haveli Investments</a>. More notably, however, the firm was said to have struck a deal with ex-Annapurna employees - who <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/annapurna-interactive-sees-exodus-of-entire-staff-as-negotiations-break-down">departed the acclaimed indie publisher en masse last year</a> following a dispute with owner Megan Ellison - to fund a new company that would distribute former Private Division titles. These include the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/kerbal-space-program">Kerbal Space Program</a> series (despite the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/take-two-sells-private-division-label-confirms-closure-of-olliolli-world-and-kerbal-space-program-2-studios">closure of its development team</a>), upcoming Lord of the Rings farming game Tales of the Shire, and Pokémon developer Game Freak's new action-adventure IP.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>