<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 15:36:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead Island 2's canned original version "would have killed the franchise", insists exec]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-island-2s-canned-original-version-would-have-killed-the-franchise-insists-exec</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dead-island-2s-canned-original-version-would-have-killed-the-franchise-insists-exec.1244076/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Deep Silver</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Cast your mind back, and you might recall <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dead-island-2">Dead Island 2</a>'s eventual, near-decade-long journey to release. Well, a former exec overseeing the project has now spoken a little more on its troubled development, claiming its scrapped first iteration would have "killed the franchise".
</p>
<p>
Dead Island 2 was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-island-2-announced">initially announced back in 2014</a>, with the expectation it would launch the following year. However, delays ensued and 2015 brought the news <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-island-2-is-no-longer-being-made-by-yager">developer Yager had departed the project</a>, with studio boss Timo Ullmann saying its vision for the project "fell out of alignment" with publisher Deep Silver. Development then <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-island-2-sumo-digital-sonic-racing">shifted to Sumo Digital</a> and finally to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/dambusterstudios">Dambuster Studios</a>, which released Dead Island 2 to a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-island-2-review-its-still-2011-in-los-angeles">solid critical reception</a> in 2023.
</p>
<p>
Now though, as <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/it-would-have-killed-the-franchise-insights-into-the-scrapped-2014-version-of-dead-island-2">reported by GamesIndustry.biz</a>, former Deep Silver head of communications Martin Wein has shed a little more light on Dead Island 2's troubled journey during a panel at Develop:Brighton. Asked for an example of when marketing or player research had helped get a development team back on track after it had veered away from a design vision, Wein specifically cited Dead Island 2, highlighting it as an instance of when he and his team had caused an "eight-year product delay".
</p>
<p>
As recounted by Wein, Deep Silver had a "major milestone with the [then] development studio" shortly after its 2014 E3 reveal. "And boy, that game sucked... It had nothing to do with what [made] the original Dead Island [...] really fun. So we commissioned a play test and got horrific feedback." Wein later told GamesIndustry. biz, "the developer wanted to pursue their vision rather than follow player feedback", and when the game remained the same at the next milestone, the decision was made to find a new studio.
</p>
<p>
"Sometimes you have to make hard decisions," Wein continued during his panel appearance. "Because we could have, at that point, put out a shit game. It might have made some money, but it would have killed the franchise... I think at that point Deep Silver did the right thing, and Dead Island 2 was a commercial success in the end. Because they took that step, and they said that we need to make a game that fits for the player."
</p>
<p>
All of which resolves at least some of the early mystery around Dead Island 2's troubles. As to its quiet time at Sumo Digital, Wein shared nothing on that period of its development - but its strange saga did at least have a happy ending. When Dead Island 2 finally released in 2023, some nine years after its announcement, the gory zombie sequel <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-island-2-shifts-1m-copies-in-its-first-weekend-of-release">successfully shifted 1m units in its first weekend of sales</a>, and was loitering somewhere around the 4m mark by February this year. Hopefully a third entry, should it ever happen, will have a smoother road to release.
</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-island-2s-canned-original-version-would-have-killed-the-franchise-insists-exec]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Candy Crush developer King reportedly replacing laid off staff with AI tools they helped to build]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/candy-crush-developer-king-reportedly-replacing-laid-off-staff-with-ai-tools-they-helped-to-build</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/candy-crush-developer-king-reportedly-replacing-laid-off-staff-with-ai-tools-they-helped-to-build.1244073/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>It's "all about efficiency and profits".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>King</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/candy-crush">Candy Crush</a> developer King is reportedly replacing laid off staff with AI tools they helped to build.</p>
<p>At the start of the month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-begins-substantial-layoff-process-across-gaming-division-king-and-zenimax-impacted">Microsoft announced around 9000 employees would be laid off</a>. This included roughly 200 staff from King.</p>
<p>Now, in a report from <a href="https://mobilegamer.biz/laid-off-king-staff-set-to-be-replaced-by-the-ai-tools-they-helped-build-say-sources/">MobileGamer.biz</a>, sources stated they've spent the last few years building and training AI tools, which will now be replacing them.</p>
<p>"Most of level design has been wiped, which is crazy since they've spent months building tools to craft levels quicker," said one source from the company. "Now those AI tools are basically replacing the teams. Similarly the copywriting team is completely removing people since we now have AI tools that those individuals have been creating."</p>
<p>They added replacing people with AI tools was "absolutely disgusting", but the focus is "all about efficiency and profits even though the company is doing great overall".</p>
<p>"If we're introducing more feedback loops then it's crazy to remove the developers themselves, we need more hands and less leadership," they said.</p>
<p>Further, some programmers have been laid off for "arbitrary reasons", said the source, claiming staff may have been removed after expressing "dissatisfaction with the company or processes".</p>
<p>Another source described King's HR department as "an absolute shitshow and has been for years", adding it's an "extreme example of an HR department whose role it is to protect the company, not the staff".</p>
<p>Back at the Game Developer Conference in May 2023, King's chief technology officer Steve Collins described to Eurogamer <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-games-industrys-response-to-ai-reverence-and-rage">the ambition for King to pivot to an "AI-first company"</a>, after it acquired Swedish AI company Peltarion in 2022.</p>
<p>AI is a "tool" that's "in the hands of our level designers and our level testers, so they use that to augment what they're able to do in those spaces," said Collins. When asked if this might mean a shift from human workers to a reliance on AI, Collins replied: "I think we still have a large number of human beings, that's the thing! What we're trying to do is: how do we scale? How do we scale or create thousands of new levels?"</p>
<p>Discussing further, Collins added: "The reality is, this sort of technology can be leveraged. What it does is, it can move people up the stack, it can move people to the point where they're being more creative, they have more agency to bring to the content creation pipeline or whatever."</p>
<p>Now, it appears to have moved people out of the company.</p>
<p>Eurogamer has contacted Microsoft for comment on this report and the claims staff will be replaced by AI.</p>
<p>ZeniMax Online Studios was also impacted by layoffs at Microsoft. Now <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zenimax-online-studios-union-speaks-out-on-microsoft-layoffs-states-those-impacted-will-depart-with-dignity">its union has spoken out</a>, stating those impacted will "depart with dignity".</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/candy-crush-developer-king-reportedly-replacing-laid-off-staff-with-ai-tools-they-helped-to-build]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ZeniMax Online Studios union speaks out on Microsoft layoffs, states those impacted will "depart with dignity"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/zenimax-online-studios-union-speaks-out-on-microsoft-layoffs-states-those-impacted-will-depart-with-dignity</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenimax-online-studios-union-speaks-out-on-microsoft-layoffs-states-those-impacted-will-depart-with-dignity.1244013/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"A future has been stolen from many of us."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Zenimax Online Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The ZeniMax Online Studios developer union has spoken out following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-begins-substantial-layoff-process-across-gaming-division-king-and-zenimax-impacted">significant cuts that impacted a vast number of staff at the studio</a>, resulting in uncertain futures for many developers and the cancellation of unannounced MMO Blackbird.</p>
<p>The union, formed in December last year, released a public statement addressing the layoffs. It confirmed that the 22 developers represented by the union who were working on Blackbird remain employed at the moment, but how long that will remain the case remains unclear.</p>
<p>It stated bargaining continues between Microsoft and the union, and while it acknowledges that layoffs may lie in the future for various represented staff, it hopes those who'll lose their jobs will " be able to depart with dignity."</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Elder Scrolls Online: High Isle Launch Cinematic" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XaI-EOVpDvo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Elder Scrolls Online: High Isle Launch Cinematic</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XaI-EOVpDvo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/XaI-EOVpDvo?autoplay=1" title="The Elder Scrolls Online: High Isle Launch Cinematic">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Check out this trailer for The Elder Scrolls Online here<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XaI-EOVpDvo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>The full statement reads as follows: "Earlier this month, Microsoft indefinitely shelved an unannounced MMORPG at ZeniMax Online Studios, a shock to the 222 ZOSU-CWA developers working on the project. It has been heartening and validating to see our game mentioned in the press and by players that would have loved to see the results of our work.</p>
<p>"Undoubtedly, a future has been stolen from many of us and our community will never experience an amazing game. However, despite discussions regarding the status of our employment, the fact is: we have not yet been laid off.</p>
<p>"While we understand that for most of us something like a layoff is inevitable, last December both the teams behind The Elder Scrolls Online (ESO) and the unannounced project voted overwhelmingly to form a union and establish ZeniMax Online Studios United-CWA (ZOSU-CWA). Worker-volunteers elected to represent the interests of our union are currently bargaining with Microsoft for the benefit of our impacted teammates.</p>
<p>"While Microsoft and ZOSU-CWA bargain over how we move forward following the project closure, the developers behind the unannounced project remain employees of ZeniMax Online Studios with full pay and benefits.</p>
<p>"On July 2nd, our lives were upended without prior notice or communication from Microsoft leadership and without clear understanding about the status of our employment. In light of this, our union came together with urgency, gathering and distributing information and resources to our affected members.</p>
<p>"Where Microsoft has failed to support the talented craftspeople who have generated billions in revenue, our union has stepped up to provide clarity and support.</p>
<p>"It is true that a layoff may be in the future for some of our members. However, as a result of our organising, we are able to ensure that those impacted will be able to depart with dignity.</p>
<p>"More importantly, the work of ZOSU-CWA will continue so that our remaining teammates - the stalwart developers of ESO - can follow in the footsteps of our colleagues across other departments and studios at Microsoft, including our union siblings at ZeniMax Workers United (ZWU-CWA). We look forward to other units who will soon ratify fair contracts that will guarantee the rights we all deserve."</p>
<p>In the wake of the MMO's cancellation, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zenimax-online-studios-head-matt-firor-announces-departure-following-widespread-layoffs-and-the-cancellation-of-in-development-mmo">studio head Matt Firor announced his departure from the company</a>. Across all studios hurt by the layoffs, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/job-losses-studio-closures-cancelled-games-what-we-know-about-xboxs-devastating-wave-of-layoffs">roughly 9,000 developers have been affected</a>, from companies including Rare, Turn10, and more.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/zenimax-online-studios-union-speaks-out-on-microsoft-layoffs-states-those-impacted-will-depart-with-dignity]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's our next batch of Xbox Game Pass games for July]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-our-next-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-games-for-july</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-our-next-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-games-for-july.1243980/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article">
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Obsidian</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Microsoft has announced the next batch of games being added to Xbox Game Pass for the rest of July.</p>
<p>This batch includes a day one release for Chinese action-RPG Wuchang: Fallen Feathers, as well as a Game Preview for Grounded 2.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Grounded 2 - Official Announce Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q0HQNOtg1WI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Grounded 2 - Official Announce Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q0HQNOtg1WI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/q0HQNOtg1WI?autoplay=1" title="Grounded 2 - Official Announce Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Grounded 2 - Official Announce Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q0HQNOtg1WI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>The full list is as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>High On Life</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) - available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, and Game Pass Standard today</li>
<li><strong>RoboCop: Rogue City</strong> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) - available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard from 17th July</li>
<li><strong>My Friendly Neighborhood</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) - available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass from 17th July</li>
<li><strong>Back to the Dawn</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) - available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass from 18th July</li>
<li><strong>Abiotic Factor</strong> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) - available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass from 22nd July</li>
<li><strong>Wheel World</strong> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) - available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass from 23rd July</li>
<li><strong>Wuchang: Fallen Feathers</strong> (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) - available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass from 24th July</li>
<li><strong>Grounded 2</strong> (Game Preview) (Cloud, PC, and Xbox Series X|S) - available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass from 29th July</li>
<li><strong>Farming Simulator 25</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) - available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard from 1st August</li>
</ul>
<p>These additions join the likes of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-whats-coming-to-game-pass-in-july">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4, Rise of the Tomb Raider, and Little Nightmares 2 from earlier this month</a>.</p>
<p>Dark fantasy game <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-a-fresh-look-at-chinese-fantasy-soulslike-wuchang-fallen-feathers">Wuchang: Fallen Feathers</a> is a twisted wuxia take on the Soulslike formula and one of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/how-black-myth-wukong-has-changed-the-game-for-chinese-developers">many action-RPGs to be released from China following in the footsteps of Black Myth: Wukong</a>.</p>
<p>Grounded 2, meanwhile, was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/groundeds-inch-high-garden-survival-is-getting-a-sequel-and-its-out-very-soon">announced back at the Xbox Games Showcase in June</a>, but Obsidian told Eurogamer <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/obsidian-says-grounded-2-wont-have-lan-multiplayer-either-and-its-a-huge-shame">it won't include LAN multiplayer</a>.</p>
<p>The following three games will leave the subscription service on 31st July:</p>
<ul>
<li>Gigantic (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Turnip Boy Robs a Bank (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information on Microsoft's subscription service, check out our guide on <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-game-pass-games-list-this-month-price-6400">all games available on Xbox Game Pass</a>.</p></div>



        </article>

  
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-our-next-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-games-for-july]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>