<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 14:46:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Darkest Dungeon 2's free Kingdoms mode gets release date alongside next paid DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/darkest-dungeon-2s-free-kingdoms-mode-gets-release-date-alongside-next-paid-dlc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/darkest-dungeon-2s-free-kingdoms-mode-gets-release-date-alongside-next-paid-dlc.1044492/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/darkest-dungeon-2s-free-kingdoms-mode-gets-release-date-alongside-next-paid-dlc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>And fan favourite character.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/DD2-SS25.png?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Red Hook</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/darkest-dungeon-2">Darkest Dungeon 2</a> will receive a major free update in January, alongside its next paid DLC.</p>
<p>Both the new Kingdoms game mode and the Inhuman Bondage DLC will release on PC on 27th January 2025.</p>
<p>Kingdoms is intended to run parallel to the game's main narrative campaign, Confessions. It tasks players with journeying from Inn to Inn across a persistent map to complete quests before time runs out.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Darkest Dungeon II - Announcement Trailer - Nintendo Switch" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A1oyJqLyFfE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Darkest Dungeon II - Announcement Trailer - Nintendo Switch</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A1oyJqLyFfE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/A1oyJqLyFfE?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Darkest Dungeon 2 - Announcement Trailer - Nintendo Switch<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A1oyJqLyFfE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Simultaneously, players will need to defend against all-new enemy factions as they complete contracts, upgrade and protect Inns. The first of these three factions will be the "rotting and ravenous beastmen".</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/darkest-dungeon-2-reveals-new-kingdoms-campaign-mode">Kingdoms mode was first revealed back in April</a> this year, but now finally has a release date.</p>
<p>The Inhuman Bondage DLC, meanwhile, will introduce a new mini-region, The Catacombs, along with a new playable hero. In The Catacombs, players will face a "corrosive, oozing threat" beneath the Kingdom. It features new enemies and items, and will be playable in both the Confessions and Kingdoms modes.</p>
<p>The new fan favourite hero, The Abomination, was an original Kickstarter backer-assisted designed character, who comes with a fully-voiced origin story along with unique mechanics and items.</p>
<p>"At Red Hook we love going against the grain," said creative director Chris Bourassa. "When asking ourselves how best to expand Darkest Dungeon 2, we were nonplussed at the conventional wisdom of simply packing in more content. Instead, we pushed ourselves to reimagine the very structure of DDII, and from that thought experiment was born an entirely new game mode: Kingdoms."</p>
<p>Darkest Dungeon 2 is available on PC across Steam and the Epic Games Store, alongside PS4, PS5, Switch, and Xbox Series X/S. Console versions of the free update and DLC will follow PC.</p>
<p>The game was first released in May 2023, with Red Hook continuing to tweak and update the game since.</p>
<p>"A copious and often brilliant, if not quite unmissable reworking of a powerfully grim fantasy," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/darkest-dungeon-2-a-lovecraftian-roadtrip-rpg-of-thrilling-and-suffocating-intricacy">Darkest Dungeon 2 review</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars Outlaws, Assassin's Creed Valhalla broken by latest Windows 11 update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/star-wars-outlaws-assassins-creed-valhalla-broken-by-latest-windows-11-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-outlaws-assassins-creed-valhalla-broken-by-latest-windows-11-update.1044453/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/star-wars-outlaws-assassins-creed-valhalla-broken-by-latest-windows-11-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Microsoft warns games can become "unresponsive while starting, loading or during active gameplay".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Female-Eivor-in-Assassins-Creed-Valhalla.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ubisoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>An array of Ubisoft games including <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/assassins-creed-valhalla">Assassin's Creed Valhalla</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora">Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</a> are broken on some devices running Windows 11 with version  update 24H2 installed.</p>
<p>As such, Microsoft has blocked the Windows upgrade for some.</p>
<p>Microsoft has acknowledged the issues on its support site, and noted that certain Ubisoft games could become "unresponsive while starting, loading or during active gameplay". It added other users may be met with a black screen.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="7 Ways Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora Is Basically Far Cry 7 (Sort Of) - NEW AVATAR PC GAMEPLAY" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lhKHnWsTnKI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>7 Ways Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora Is Basically Far Cry 7 (Sort Of) - NEW AVATAR PC GAMEPLAY</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lhKHnWsTnKI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/lhKHnWsTnKI?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>7 Ways Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora Is Basically Far Cry 7 (Sort Of). <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lhKHnWsTnKI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"To safeguard your Windows update experience, we have applied a compatibility hold on devices with these games installed," <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/release-health/status-windows-11-24h2#3448msgdesc">Microsoft wrote</a>. "These devices will not be offered to install Windows 11, version 24H2 via the Windows Update release channel."</p>
<p>The company implores users to not manually install the update if they own the affected games, which are listed below:</p>
<ul>
<li>Assassin's Creed Valhalla</li>
<li>Assassin's Creed Origins</li>
<li>Assassin's Creed Odyssey</li>
<li>Star Wars Outlaws</li>
<li>Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</li>
</ul>
<p>Microsoft has issued a <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/star-wars/outlaws/news-updates/1sXCR6GmB3Kn7OrKiy8DPO/star-wars-outlaws-title-update-140">"temporary mitigation" for Star Wars Outlaws</a>, which should prevent the game from failing and stop responding. It did note there may still be performance issues, however.</p>
<p>Microsoft is currently working on a fix with Ubisoft, promising more information when the companies know more. In the meantime, it has provided the following workaround for users who find a game stops responding to their demands.</p>
<ol>
<li>Open Task Manager. This can be accomplished by pressing Ctrl + Shift + Esc on your keyboard. Alternatively, you can right-click on the Start button and select Task Manager from the menu.</li>
<li>In the Task Manager window, look for your game in the Processes tab. It might be listed under the name of the game or the game launcher.</li>
<li>Click on the game’s name to highlight it. Then, click the End Task button at the bottom right of the window. This will close the game.</li>
</ol>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-wars-outlaws-kay-in-the-scoundrel-gear-set.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In other Ubisoft news, the publisher recently announced it was removing those really rather frustrating (read, incredibly frustrating) forced stealth sections from "almost all quest objectives" in Star Wars Outlaws.</p>
<p>Thanks to an update earlier this month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/star-wars-outlaws-finally-getting-rid-of-forced-stealth-from-almost-all-quest-objectives">players will now be able to enter combat after getting caught while sneaking</a>, rather than getting ported back to the last checkpoint and being made to start the section again.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chill town building sim Farthest Frontier sees full launch delayed into 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/chill-town-building-sim-farthest-frontier-sees-full-launch-delayed-into-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/chill-town-building-sim-farthest-frontier-sees-full-launch-delayed-into-2025.1044423/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/chill-town-building-sim-farthest-frontier-sees-full-launch-delayed-into-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Snow-falls-over-a-town-in-Farthest-Frontiers.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Crate Entertainment</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Farthest Frontier will now be released in full next year.</p>
<p>Originally, the town-building early access game was slated for its Version 1 release in 2024. But, with this year now only having a scant five and a bit weeks left (yes, really), the team has announced a change to those original plans.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Farthest Frontier - Gameplay Trailer 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9YDAfsUTOXg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Farthest Frontier - Gameplay Trailer 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9YDAfsUTOXg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9YDAfsUTOXg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Farthest Frontier - Gameplay Trailer 2024. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9YDAfsUTOXg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Developer Crate Entertainment said it had decided to postpone Farthest Frontier's full release for a number of reasons. "For starters, we feel that performance is simply not quite where we would like it to be yet," it wrote in a <a href="https://forums.crateentertainment.com/t/the-state-of-early-access-update-07/141562">post</a> detailing the delay.</p><p>"We are seeing your grand 3000+ population towns which are no doubt pushing the limits of hardware, but there is still more we could do to squeeze more frames out of the game, and we want to take the time to get it right."</p>
<p>Another reason is Crate Entertainment still has plans to add a few more bits and pieces to Farthest Frontier. This, it said, "bloats the schedule" somewhat.</p>
<p>Last but not least, the team has put its business hat on, and come to the conclusion now is not the best time to release its indie game in full. "With the holidays rapidly approaching, this is the time of year when big publishers are going to drown the market with advertising, eager for your holiday shopping coin. Similarly, February tends to be a month when everyone's wallets have just recovered from the holiday rush, so in come the big AAA releases," it reasoned.</p>
<p>As such, Farthest Frontier will now get its full launch in the spring of next year. You can check out a trailer for this new release window in the video above.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-village-square-in-Farthest-Frontier.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Crate Entertainment</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Our Bertie was rather impressed with Farthest Frontier when he gave it a whirl back in 2022.</p>
<p>"Farthest Frontier is not about going from dozens to thousands, from village to sprawling metropolis, and that zooming out you then feel as the person in charge. It's about staying small and staying close to the people you're caring for," he wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/farthest-frontier-understands-the-best-moments-of-city-builders-are-the-beginnings">Eurogamer's Farthest Frontier preview</a>.</p><p>"There's no hurry. It allows you time to let the tranquillity of the game wash over you - the gentle music, the sprawling natural world, the simplicity of surviving. It gives you time to lean in and take an interest in the small lives playing out in front of you, to watch them go about their daily work, to know their names, to check their needs are being met. It's a warm and relaxing place to be."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arcane "cinematic universe" to expand with three more League of Legends animated series]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/arcane-cinematic-universe-to-expand-with-three-more-league-of-legends-animated-series</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arcane-cinematic-universe-to-expand-with-three-more-league-of-legends-animated-series.1044402/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/arcane-cinematic-universe-to-expand-with-three-more-league-of-legends-animated-series<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Focusing on other areas of its world.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/LeagueofLegends_ArcaneMelMedarda.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Netflix / Riot Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/netflix">Netflix</a> and Riot Games' utterly brilliant Arcane will be followed by three further series exploring other parts of the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/league-of-legends">League of Legends</a> world. 
</p>
<p>
Arcane showrunner Christian Linke has now confirmed the locations in which these new stories will be set as Noxus, home to Arcane's Mel Meldarda, plus Demacia and Ionia.
</p>
<p>
Speaking to streamer <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2309678052">Necrit94</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/arcane-showrunner-confirms-noxus-ionia-demacia-league-of-legends-shows/">TheGamer</a>), Linke said these new series would tell fresh stories, but also continue some of the threads already seen in Arcane.
</p>
<p>
"We're really going wide, we're looking at every region and we really now have the ability to build a slate to tell many more stories - and continue some of them," Linke said.
</p>
<p>
Talented animation studio Fortiche will once again be at the helm for these series, after its award-winning work on Arcane's two seasons, but there's no word yet on when these new series might materialise.
</p>
<p>
Production work on the next show began a year ago, Linke noted, so hopefully we won't have another three year wait to see more.
</p>
<p>Linke had previously mentioned the development of further League of Legends shows when it was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-now-describes-arcane-season-two-as-the-final-chapter">confirmed that Arcane would end with its second season</a>.</p>
<p>"Arcane is just the beginning of our larger storytelling journey and our partnership with the wonderful animation studio that is Fortiche," Linke said in a developer update video earlier this year. "From the very beginning, since we started working on this project, we had a very specific ending in mind, which means the story of Arcane wraps up with the second season.</p><p>"But Arcane is just the first of many stories we want to tell in Runeterra. We've been with Riot through Vi and Jinx's entire journey thus far, from becoming in-game champions to characters featured in different cinematics to main characters in a TV show. Their arcs have grown so far beyond our original dreams, and we want to give the same treatment to more champions."</p>
<p>
In related news, a recent League of Legends leak has suggested the game will get a Noxus-themed season next year, as the game gets ready to host Mel herself beginning in early 2025.
</p>
<p>
"Some iffy pacing moments aside, Arcane's second and final season truly puts the money on screen," our Chris Tapsell wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arcane-season-2-review">Eurogamer's Arcane season two review</a>. "This is a striking, emotionally wrought, hard-punching climax."
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>