<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 14:31:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gears is "so back" as original voice talents are confirmed for Gears of War: E-Day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/gears-is-so-back-as-original-voice-talents-are-confirmed-for-gears-of-war-e-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gears-is-so-back-as-original-voice-talents-are-confirmed-for-gears-of-war-e-day.1030785/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/gears-is-so-back-as-original-voice-talents-are-confirmed-for-gears-of-war-e-day<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gears-of-war-e-day-marcus-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>The Coalition/Microsoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>John DiMiaggio and Carlos Ferro are reprising their roles as Marcus Fenix and Dominic Santiago in Gears of War: E-Day.</p>
<p>The announcement - which was posted to the official Gears of War X/Twitter account on the 18th anniversary of the third person shooter series - also appended a photo of DiMaggio and Ferro reunited.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Gears of War: E-Day | Official Announce Trailer (In-Engine) - Xbox Games Showcase 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EC20gLfUHeA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Gears of War: E-Day | Official Announce Trailer (In-Engine) - Xbox Games Showcase 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EC20gLfUHeA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EC20gLfUHeA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Gears of War: E-Day announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EC20gLfUHeA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"We are so back," the post teased. "On today's 18th anniversary of Gears of War, we're proud to share that John DiMaggio and lCarlos Ferro are reprising their roles as the iconic voices of Marcus Fenix and Dominic Santiago in Gears of War: E-Day."</p><p>Microsoft still hasn't given any further details on when we may be able to play Gears of War: E-Day, but with a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gears-of-war-live-action-movie-and-animated-series-in-the-works-at-netflix">movie and animated series</a> also in the works, there's a lot for Gears of War fans to look forward to, especially now DiMaggio and Ferro are back to reprise their fan-favourite "brothers to the end" partnership.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>We are so back. 🤜🤛 </p><p>On today's 18th anniversary of Gears of War, we're proud to share that John DiMaggio and <a href="https://twitter.com/RealCarlosFerro?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RealCarlosFerro</a> are reprising their roles as the iconic voices of Marcus Fenix and Dominic Santiago in Gears of War: E-Day. <a href="https://t.co/x9uaH9R0sR">pic.twitter.com/x9uaH9R0sR</a></p></div>— Gears of War (@GearsofWar) <a href="https://twitter.com/GearsofWar/status/1854584608223813638?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Gears of War 6's development <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/next-gears-of-war-game-in-the-works-according-to-new-job-listings">hadn't been much of a secret</a>, but it was finally made official in June, with confirmation that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/marcus-fenix-returns-in-gears-of-war-prequel-e-day">Gears 6 will be a prequel titled Gears of War: E-Day</a>.</p>
<p>Set 14 years before the events of the original Gears of War, E-Day tells the story of the first Locust emergence on Sera, and the world's response to that threat. It promises a return of the series' trademark third-person, cover-based shooting action, all within an "explosive" campaign combining "satisfying gameplay and emotive, character-led storytelling".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amplitude to focus on in-development projects as it splits from Sega]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/amplitude-to-focus-on-in-development-projects-as-it-splits-from-sega</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amplitude-to-focus-on-in-development-projects-as-it-splits-from-sega.1030761/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/amplitude-to-focus-on-in-development-projects-as-it-splits-from-sega<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>The companies "will continue to work together on the smooth transition of services and operations".</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Amplitude Studios has reestablished itself as an independent studio after management bought back the studio from Sega.</p>
<p>Sega says the sale follows a "period of close consultation" between Amplitude and Sega management and "concludes the structural reforms that have been taking place in Sega's European business". The publisher previously canned its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sega-has-cancelled-hyenas">plans to launch live-service shooter Hyenas</a>, with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/total-war-developer-creative-assembly-refocusing-on-strategy-games-after-hyenas-failure">job losses at UK studio Creative Assembly as a result</a>.</p>
<p>Sega acquired Amplitude in 2016. It has released <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/endless-space-2">Endless Space 2</a>, Humankind, and Endless Dungeon over that time.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Nintendo has announced new hardware, but it's not Switch 2 - so what's the point of Alarmo?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GdNKD3U-4AY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Sega Europe has today announced the sale of Amplitude Studios following a management buyout from senior leaders and employees at the Parisian studio. The move will see Amplitude go back to its roots as an independent organisation and concludes the structural reforms that have been taking place in Sega's European business," Sega said in a statement to press.</p><p>"The decision to part ways follows a period of close consultation between Sega Europe and Amplitude. As an independent studio once more, Amplitude will focus on its in-development projects and growing its own franchises, while Sega will continue to advance its strong and diverse stable of Japanese and Western IP.</p>
<p>"While Amplitude is no longer a part of the Sega family of studios, the two entities will continue to work together on the smooth transition of services and operations, ensuring minimum disruption for Amplitude employees and continuity of service for players of Amplitude games," Sega concluded.</p>
<p>"Amplitude is backed by strong, meaningful franchises, and our team is committed to creating the best games possible," said Romain de Waubert de Genlis, studio director.</p>
<p>"This decision allows us to be more agile in our approach while continuing to shape the vision that we've had from the beginning, empowering us to push boundaries and be closer than ever to our community."</p>
<p>As for what's still in store for Sega? Its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/segas-new-crazy-taxi-game-aaa-in-scope">"AAA"</a> <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/crazy-taxi">Crazy Taxi</a> reboot <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/segas-new-crazy-taxi-game-will-be-open-world-and-massively-multiplayer">will be an open-world, massively-multiplayer game</a>. It's just one of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sega-announces-flurry-of-projects-including-jet-set-radio-crazy-taxi">five fresh titles in classic franchises announced last December</a>, alongside new entries in the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/jet-set-radio">Jet Set Radio</a>, Shinobi, Golden Axe and Streets of Rage franchises.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>