<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 14:32:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed has an official mushroom kit, so you can grow delicious face mushrooms then eat them]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/avowed-has-an-official-mushroom-kit-so-you-can-grow-delicious-face-mushrooms-then-eat-them</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-has-an-official-mushroom-kit-so-you-can-grow-delicious-face-mushrooms-then-eat-them.1120365/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/avowed-has-an-official-mushroom-kit-so-you-can-grow-delicious-face-mushrooms-then-eat-them<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pok%C3%A9mon-Presents-2025.2.27-0-17-screenshot-Recovered.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>North Spore</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Obsidian role-playing game <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/avowed">Avowed</a> now has an official mushroom kit, which you can use to grow a crop of colourful fungus at home similar to the infestation that covers your hero's face.
</p>
<p>
Not convinced? How about if we told you this creeping mass of plague-like fungi was designed to be enjoyed as a snack? Just peel the mushrooms from the Avowed-branded box, and pop one in your mouth. Delicious.
</p>
<p>
This official kit comes from mushroom mail order service North Spore, which sadly does not seem to ship to the UK. Maybe that's for the best. 
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Eurogamer's Avowed review, in video form.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=equGBZBUjVg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
US residents keen to grown their own plague (actually, perfectly edible oyster mushrooms of various colours) can order an Avowed kit online for <a href="https://northspore.com/products/organic-spray-grow-avowed-grow-kit">$30 plus shipping</a>. Each kit comes with a random colour selection included, which only reveals itself when the spores bloom.
</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/spray-grow-kit-organic-spray-grow-avowed-mushroom-growing-kit-1112378420_441x.progressive.png.webp?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/spray-grow-kit-organic-spray-grow-avowed-mushroom-growing-kit-1112378416_882x.progressive.png.webp?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>North Spore</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Optionally, you can also download 3D printing details for a bear ornament to grow your mushrooms on, similar to the infected hulking enemies found within the game. Yummy.
</p>
<p>
Avowed looks to have done well enough for Obsidian, which has now hinted at more to come from its plague-ridden role-playing game. The game's director, Carrie Patel, was recently asked whether her next project would be something new - but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/avowed-director-hints-at-a-future-for-the-franchise">said it was likely she'd be back for more Avowed</a> - be that more content for the first game, or sequels.
</p>
<p>
"What Avowed lacks in gloss it makes up for with charm, depth and a playful heart," our Bertie wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/avowed-review">Eurogamer's Avowed review</a>. "It's one of this year's most pleasant surprises."
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honda reveals "life-size" Pokémon motorbike]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/honda-reveals-life-size-pokemon-motorbike</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/honda-reveals-life-size-pok%C3%A9mon-motorbike.1120257/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/honda-reveals-life-size-pokemon-motorbike<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/%E3%80%90%E5%85%AC%E5%BC%8F%E3%80%91%E3%80%8C%E3%83%9B%E3%83%B3%E3%83%80%E3%82%B3%E3%83%A9%E3%82%A4%E3%83%89%E3%83%B3%E3%80%8D%E5%88%9D%E5%85%AC%E9%96%8B-%EF%BC%81-0-40-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Honda / The Pokémon Company</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Motor company Honda has unveiled a glimpse at a Pokémon motorbike themed around Legendary creature Koraidon, star of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-scarlet-violet-walkthrough-tips-9015">Pokémon Scarlet and Violet</a>.
</p>
<p>
Koraidon, along with his buddy Miraidon, are dragon-like creatures which can be used as motorbikes in the games. So the theming is appropriate. 
</p>
<p>
But is this motorbike practical for the real world? Well, that's another matter. With spikes on its wheels and actual feet (although maybe that's a stand?), it seems like not. And that's before you get to the lack of license plate. Still, if you had the money and the space for it, you would. Wouldn't you?
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="【公式】「ホンダコライドン」初公開 ！" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ryoEWpD9NMg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>【公式】「ホンダコライドン」初公開 ！</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ryoEWpD9NMg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ryoEWpD9NMg?autoplay=1" title="【公式】「ホンダコライドン」初公開 ！">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ryoEWpD9NMg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
Honda's sneak peek of the Koraidon motorbike, made in conjunction with The Pokémon Company, is available to watch above. A full unveiling - when we're likely to find out how much this beast might cost - will come next month. 
</p>
<p>
"Honda has realised an almost life-size reproduction of the shape of Koraidon in both weight and size, down to the finest details," the company wrote.
</p>
<p>
"Honda will use its proprietary self-balancing technology to enable Honda Koraidon to walk on all four legs, and self-stand on two-wheels which is unseen in the game. This balance technology... was developed by applying the self-balancing technology cultivated in ASIMO humanoid robot research. Honda will apply this technology to realise Koraidon's 'Sprinting Build'.
</p>
<p>
This isn't the first time a Pokémon has been transformed into a motorbike. Last year, Toyota took the reigns on a Miraidon prototype - though it's unclear if that design was ever proven road-worthy (thanks, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/02/random-honda-teases-real-life-pokemon-scarlet-and-violet-motorbike">Nintendo Life</a>).
</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
Today is, of course, Pokémon Day - so be sure to keep up with all of the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/watch-todays-pokemon-presents-broadcast-here">big announcements made as part of the Pokémon Presents broadcast</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows achievements ensure you can unlock full list playing as either character]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-shadows-achievements-ensure-you-can-unlock-full-list-playing-as-either-character</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-achievements-ensure-you-can-unlock-full-list-playing-as-either-character.1120251/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-shadows-achievements-ensure-you-can-unlock-full-list-playing-as-either-character<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article">
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/76a81f35aeda88957248f78ca15db11f93c53a3b.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ubisoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Ubisoft has detailed the list of achievements for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/assassins-creed-codename-red">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a>, and said the game won't require you to play twice or pick a particular character at certain points in order to unlock every award.
</p>
<p>
The full list of achievements lies below - and they're the same across Steam, Xbox and for Trophies on PlayStation. There are no spoilers.
</p>
<p>
Not requiring multiple playthroughs is probably for the best - Shadows looks like another Assassin's Creed epic, following previous games like Odyssey and Valhalla where I clocked up playtime in the 100s of hours. 
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>We've played Assassin's Creed Shadows - is it good?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QPR9oEqn3lQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Having to finish the game once to then unlock a harder difficulty and grind for another achievement after completing that? No thank you.
</p>
<p>
"Available on day one, these Steam achievements (which are the same as the Xbox achievements and PlayStation trophies) can all be earned in a single playthrough, meaning no achievement can be missed regardless of what story choices you make," Ubisoft wrote in a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3159330/view/535468672209128051?l=english">blog post on Steam</a>. 
</p>
<p>
"And don't worry - your Leap of Fail will look just as spectacular whether you're playing on story mode or on expert level, as all achievements are unlockable regardless of difficulty level."
</p>
<p>
(At a guess, I'd say Leap of Fail will likely pop when you try to perform the iconic Assassin's Creed dive as samurai Yasuke - who is not trained for the purpose.)
</p>
<p>
Assassin's Creed Shadows' two protagonists offer two different gameplay styles (quiet assassin, or all-out samurai) and can be swapped between frequently - or not, if you so choose.
</p>
<p>
The game also features dialogue choices, though <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-shadows-has-a-canon-mode-story-option-without-narrative-choices">Ubisoft has also confirmed Assassin's Creed Shadows' canon story mode option</a> for those who want a strictly linear narrative.
</p>
<p>
Here's the full Assassin's Creed Shadows achievement list:
</p>
<p>
<strong>Visible Achievements</strong>
</p>
<ul>
<li>Art of Ninjutsu - Master the way of the shinobi</li>
<li>Art of Kenjutsu - Master the way of the samurai</li>
<li>Make it Personal - Engrave your first weapon</li>
<li>Sometimes - Perform a landing roll</li>
<li>Reeding is Fundamental - Escape conflict by using a breathing reed to hide in shallow water</li>
<li>Just Your Shadow - Distract the same enemy 3 times with shinobi bells</li>
<li>Hook, Line, and Swinger - Stay airborne by swinging from one grappling hook point to another</li>
<li>Acrobatics - Perform a Leap of Faith from a grappling hook swing</li>
<li>Adept Shinobi - Perform your first assassination</li>
<li>Master Shinobi - Assassinate an enemy through a shoji door</li>
<li>Unseen - Perform 5 assassinations in a row without being noticed or entering combat</li>
<li>Giant Slayer - Assassinate a powerful guardian in one go</li>
<li>Adept Samurai - Perform your first Finisher as Yasuke</li>
<li>Master Samurai - Parry an incoming projectile</li>
<li>Unstoppable - Use Samurai Stand before performing a Finisher on an enemy</li>
<li>This is Japan, Actually - Kick an enemy from a high place</li>
<li>Overdesign III - Perform a Finisher on an enemy that is both Poisoned and Dazed</li>
<li>Final Hearing - Sheath your weapon immediately after an enemy dies from Bleed</li>
<li>Adventurer - Shoot an enemy in the knee with an arrow</li>
<li>Test Your Might - Defeat the final enemy in the tournament</li>
<li>Kofun Raider - Complete your first kofun</li>
<li>Good Form - Complete your first kata</li>
<li>Zen Master - Complete all kuji-kiri</li>
<li>A Rare Occurrence - Complete all legendary sumi-e</li>
<li>Sole Sanctum - Unlock the Hideout</li>
<li>Chase the Morning - Add a sumi-e to the Hideout</li>
<li>Against Wood and Stone - Fully upgrade a building in the Hideout</li>
<li>Everybody Benefits! - Adopt a pet</li>
<li>Happy Place - Reach the highest point on the map</li>
<li>Pathfinder - Visit every province on the map</li>
<li>Scouting Mission - Gather information using a scout</li>
<li>Would You Kindly? - Complete a contract in each province</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Hidden Achievements</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Prologue</li>
<li>A New League Rises</li>
<li>An Oath Fulfilled</li>
<li>Fall of the Shinbakufu</li>
<li>Epilogue</li>
<li>Death Blossom</li>
<li>The Thief</li>
<li>The Toxin Master</li>
<li>The Eager Assassin</li>
<li>The Ronin</li>
<li>The Warrior Monk</li>
<li>The Sharpshooter</li>
<li>Build Your League</li>
<li>Front of the Pack</li>
<li>Better than a Bucket</li>
<li>Limitless</li>
<li>In Case of Trouble</li>
<li>Suture Self</li>
<li>Leap of Fail</li>
<li>Mortal Reminder</li>
<li>Collector</li>
<li>Made You Look</li>
</ul>
<p>Earlier this week, Ubisoft addressed the leaks of gameplay footage and story details spreading online, and said <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-responds-to-major-assassins-creed-shadows-leak-says-footage-does-not-represent-the-final-quality-of-the-game">the footage did not represent the final quality of Assassin's Creed Shadows at launch</a>.</p>
</div>



        </article>

  
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>