<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 11:55:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl's second major patch adds 1700 improvements and fixes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyls-second-major-patch-adds-1700-improvements-and-fixes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyls-second-major-patch-adds-1700-improvements-and-fixes.1111245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyls-second-major-patch-adds-1700-improvements-and-fixes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Total e-fix of the Heart.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/stalker-2-vertical-key-art.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>GSC Game World</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/stalker-2">Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl</a>'s next "major patch" is here, introducing "1700 improvements and fixes to all aspects of the game: balance, locations, quests, blockers, crashes, performance, more A-Life 2.0 fixes, you name it".</p>
<p>The team thanked players for reporting their issues - "this work wouldn't have been possible without your feedback and comments on your personal experience with the Zone" - before detailing the fixes on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1643320/view/579378232238800945">Steam</a>.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>19 Things You Need To Know Before Playing Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl - Beginners Tips.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HzRTZ-KYUpA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>It follows a previous major patch from developer <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/gsc-game-world">GSC Game World</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stalker-2-receives-first-major-patch-including-a-life-fixes">which addressed over 1800 issues back in December</a>.</p>
<p>Audio, cutscenes and VO have been improved with almost 100 fixes, "each aimed to enhance your game experience". There have also been over 450+ improvements made to Stalker 2's regions and locations, 120+ to player guidance and settings, 30+ to interactable objects and zone experience, and 130 buffs to side missions and encounters. </p>
<p>A whopping 300 adjustments have been made to main story quests, too, including issues with a boss fight and disappearing NPCs.</p>
<p>50+ bugs have been squished in your player gear and state, and over 100 when it comes to optimisation and crashing.</p>
<p>You can also expect to see improved AI, better NPC shooting accuracy, boosted stealth, and improved mutant behaviour in combat.</p>
<p>"Thanks for staying with the Zone! As always, we will continue to listen to your feedback and comments, and share game updates as soon as possible," the team concluded. "If you spot an 'anomaly' that is not supposed to be in the game, please report it to our colleagues in Tech Support Hub. That will help us investigate potential issues faster."</p>
<p>At its launch in November, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-review">Stalker 2</a> was criticised for its performance issues. However, in an interview with Eurogamer, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/delaying-stalker-2-again-not-an-option-studio-says-team-worked-until-it-was-broken-by-marathon-development">GSC Game World's CEO Ievgen Grygorovych said delaying the game was not an option</a>.</p>
<p>"You're so tired that you would just die if you say let's run an additional marathon," Grygorovych said at the time. "We didn't have a chance to say let's do it more. We just had a chance of 'let's do until this moment - the release date - as much as we can'."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft announces Rainbow Six Siege X, the "biggest transformation in the game's history"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-announces-rainbow-six-siege-x-the-biggest-transformation-in-the-games-history</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-announces-rainbow-six-siege-x-the-biggest-transformation-in-the-games-history.1111212/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-announces-rainbow-six-siege-x-the-biggest-transformation-in-the-games-history<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Rainbow Six Siege is getting its biggest overhaul ever, Ubisoft has announced, and looks set to be retitled as Rainbow Six Siege X.
</p>
<p>
This year marks the 10th anniversary of Ubisoft's ever-popular tactical shooter - the company's biggest and longest-running success of the last decade outside of Assassin's Creed. 
</p>
<p>
This weekend, Ubisoft revealed a teaser video for Rainbow Six Siege X, and described it as "the biggest transformation in the game's history" that was set to introduce "new ways to play, deepened tactical gameplay, and major upgrades all around!"
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Rainbow Six Siege X Teaser" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X4vvBU-1CCY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Rainbow Six Siege X Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X4vvBU-1CCY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/X4vvBU-1CCY?autoplay=1" title="Rainbow Six Siege X Teaser">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Rainbow Six Siege X announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X4vvBU-1CCY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
A full reveal will follow in March, on Thursday 13th at 5pm UK time, but there's a few things we can discern today. 
</p>
<p>
In a blog post, Ubisoft describes Rainbow Six Siege X as "a new era" for its game, "one that sets the stage for the years to come" that's designed to "reinforce Rainbow Six Siege's position at the top of tactical first-person shooters". 
</p>
<p>
So - a sequel, this is not.
</p>
<p>
Footage teasing next month's showcase simply features shots from the current Rainbow Six Siege, meanwhile. How different will the Rainbow Six Siege X actually look?
</p>
<p>
Fan feedback to the teaser has been positive, with many hoping that Ubisoft uses this update as an opportunity to strip back some of the many additions that have been added to Siege over the past 10 years - at least as an option, to allow fresh fans an easier route into the game.
</p>
<p>The announcement comes as Ubisoft seeks to double down on its strengths - including lots of Assassin's Creed - while <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-shadows-pre-orders-solid-in-line-with-series-second-biggest-launch">the company continues to cut costs</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tencent-and-guillemot-family-considering-new-venture-with-ubisoft-assets-report">court a potential sale</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds producer acknowledges importance of PC platform and crossplay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-producer-acknowledges-importance-of-pc-platform-and-crossplay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-producer-acknowledges-importance-of-pc-platform-and-crossplay.1111209/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-producer-acknowledges-importance-of-pc-platform-and-crossplay<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"There are more players than ever playing on PC."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Monster-Hunter-Wilds---Launch-Trailer-0-59-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Capcom</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> producer Ryozo Tsujimoto has acknowledged the importance of the PC platform, and why crossplay will be included in the game.</p>
<p>"Yeah, there are more players than ever playing on PC, including in Japan," Tsujimoto told <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/monster-hunter/monster-hunter-lead-producer-agrees-pc-gaming-is-key-for-japanese-games-there-are-more-players-than-ever-playing-on-pc-including-in-japan/">GamesRadar</a>, "so we definitely see room for the series to capture new players who haven't tried it before if that's their chosen platform."</p>
<p>Crossplay between PC and console players has been included in Monster Hunter Wilds so that "the choice is yours on which platform you want to play with, and then [you can just] go online and hunt with your friends".</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Monster Hunter Wilds Preview &amp; New Gameplay<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iYq9dW92QOg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This is also likely a reason Capcom released the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-players-can-test-their-machines-ahead-of-release-with-pc-benchmarking-tool">Monster Hunter Wilds PC benchmark tool</a>, so players can test their system ahead of release.</p>
<p>The huge audience for the game is apparent when looking at SteamDB. The beta for Monster Hunter Wilds reached a concurrent player peak of 463,798, while Monster Hunter World reached 334,684, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/monster-hunter-rise">Monster Hunter Rise</a> reached 231,360.</p>
<p>For comparison, the beta test's peak is higher than the likes of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/among-us">Among Us</a>, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/grand-theft-auto-v">Grand Theft Auto 5</a>.</p>
<p>Speaking of GTA, Take-Two CEO boss Strauss Zelnick recently discussed the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-pc-version-teased-by-take-two-boss-acknowledges-platforms-growing-importance">presumed PC release of GTA 6</a>, noting that historically "Rockstar has started with some platforms and then historically moved to other platforms".</p>
<p>"We have seen PC become a much more important part of what used to be a console business, and I wouldn't be surprised to see that trend continue," he added.</p>
<p>Square Enix is also working on an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-aggressively-pursuing-new-multiplatform-strategy-after-reports-ff7-rebirth-underperformed-on-playstation">"aggressive" multiplatform strategy</a>, releasing its biggest games on PC following PS5 exclusivity, further highlighting the importance of PC for Japanese companies. Both Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth and Final Fantasy 16 are now available on PC.</p>
<p>In another interview, with <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/monster-hunter-wilds/new-weapon-type">PCGamesN</a>, Monster Hunter Wilds director Yuya Tokuda discussed the possibility of adding a fifteenth weapon type to the game.</p>
<p>"When we start development of games such as World and, recently, Wilds, we always consider whether or not this is the time to add another weapon type,” Tokuda said. "It's not off the table for any particular reason, it’s just that we never really decided that we wanted to for the recent titles."</p>
<p>After all the tweaks and changes made to the existing 14 weapons in Wilds, it's tough to find "a 15th weapon that would actually have a place in that lineup and feel equally as valid as the other weapon types while also not overlapping with them too much".</p>
<p>Monster Hunter Wilds is set for release on 28th February across PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.</p>
<p>Eurogamer's Jim Trinca went <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-preview">hands-on with Monster Hunter Wilds</a> recently and while this series entry is more approachable, it still has its quirks.</p>
<p>"For the MonHun-curious consumer, I recommend caution," he wrote. "The FOMO is real here: Monster Hunter is just one of those things that inspires fandom envy. The people who love it do so vocally and passionately and with an infectious enthusiasm rarely seen elsewhere. But as much as Wilds is eager to roll over and present its tummy to you, it is still a Monster Hunter game, and therefore as marmitey as marmite games come."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 set for PC debut in early 2026, accessories company claims]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-set-for-pc-debut-in-early-2026-accessories-company-claims</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-set-for-pc-debut-in-early-2026-accessories-company-claims.1111206/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-set-for-pc-debut-in-early-2026-accessories-company-claims<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>We still don't have a firm console release date for Grand Theft Auto 6, but a game peripheral company has now stated it will make its later PC debut in early 2026.</p>
<p>The next entry in Rockstar's series is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-still-coming-this-autumn-confirms-take-two-despite-ongoing-delay-rumours">scheduled for consoles this autumn</a>. However, the developer along with publisher Take-Two are keeping things close to their chest when it comes to firm details, particularly on the PC front. Back in May, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-publisher-addresses-lack-of-pc-news-stating-rockstar-will-make-more-announcements-in-due-time">Take-Two said Rockstar would "make more announcements in due time"</a>, and then earlier this month it teased a GTA 6 PC release is on the cards but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-pc-version-teased-by-take-two-boss-acknowledges-platforms-growing-importance">the company tends not to "go across all platforms simultaneously"</a>.</p>
<p>Now, however, PC accessories company Corsair Gaming has suggested we could be seeing GTA 6 arriving on PC as soon as early next year.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" title="9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtaSpf-70nc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Speaking during its latest financial results, Corsair Gaming's financial VP Ronald van Veen said:</p>
<p>"GTA 6 is probably the one everyone is talking about. And we'll get a glimpse of that, I think, later on in the year for console. My understanding now, it's going to come out in the fall [autumn] for console, and then early 2026 for PC" (thanks, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/gta6s-pc-release-date-is-early-2026-corsair-gaming-believes/">VGC</a>).</p>
<p>Should this prove true, this is a pretty speedy move to PC when you consider other Rockstar releases. Red Dead Redemption, for example, first launched all the way back in 2010 across PS3 and Xbox 360. It <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-red-dead-redemption-pc-tech-review">then arrived on PC last year</a>.</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/image-(965).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/image-(964).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rockstar</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for its console debut, Take-Two head Strauss Zelnick previously said he <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-publisher-not-really-worried-about-xbox-series-s-performance">isn't worried about getting GTA 6 to work on Microsoft's lesser powered Xbox Series S console</a>.</p>
<p>Zelnick simply said the team would always "find a way to support platforms despite different levels of tech", in a bid to alleviate any concerns. "Our labels are really good at that," he said in November. "I'm not really worried."</p>
<p>For more on the game, here's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-everything-we-know-so-far-9357">everything we know about GTA 6 so far</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yes, Rare's Everwild is still in development, and Xbox is committed to giving the team the "time" it needs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/yes-rares-everwild-is-still-in-development-and-xbox-is-committed-to-giving-the-team-the-time-it-needs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yes-rares-everwild-is-still-in-development-and-xbox-is-committed-to-giving-the-team-the-time-it-needs.1110993/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/yes-rares-everwild-is-still-in-development-and-xbox-is-committed-to-giving-the-team-the-time-it-needs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"We can give those teams time."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2025-02-16-at-19.22.16.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>XboxEra / Rare</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Almost six years on from its debut, Xbox CEO of Gaming <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/phil-spencer">Phil Spencer</a> has confirmed that Rare's mysterious fantasy deer adventure Everwild is still in development.</p>
<p>Despite being first <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rare-announces-everwild-its-next-big-new-ip">revealed in late 2019</a> with a gorgeous teaser, and then <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-the-new-everwild-trailer">shown again in summer 2020</a> with a slightly-more revealing trailer, we've heard very little about the game.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="XboxEra Interviews Phil Spencer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q20AFtPXKSQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>XboxEra Interviews Phil Spencer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q20AFtPXKSQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/q20AFtPXKSQ?autoplay=1" title="XboxEra Interviews Phil Spencer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>XboxEra Interviews Phil Spencer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q20AFtPXKSQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Talking to the XboxEra podcast, however, Spencer had good news for those who feared the game may have been quietly cancelled, revealing the team was making "progress".</p>
<p>"I was recently out at Rare. It's nice to see the team with Everwild and the progress that they're making," Spencer said, when asked reflect on what first-party games still in development he was most looking forward to (thanks, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/phil-spencer-provides-rare-update-on-missing-in-action-xbox-exclusive-everwild/">VGC</a>).</p>
<p>"It has been [a while]. And we've been able to give those teams time in what they're doing which is good and still have a portfolio like we have.</p>
<p>"It's like a dream that Matt [Booty] and I have had for a long time, so it's finally good to be there. We can give those teams time."</p>
<p>Earlier today we reported that in the same podcast, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-boss-phil-spencer-says-hes-stopped-trying-to-move-all-players-over-to-xbox">Spencer said he's "not trying to move [PS5 and PC players] all over to Xbox anymore"</a>, acknowledging that players are "all so invested in where our games are", all he wants to do now is "allow more people to play" Xbox games on other systems.</p>
<p>Spencer acknowledged that whilst selling games on competitor devices means Xbox only recoups 70 percent of the sale, that 70 percent still helps Xbox "build great portfolios".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>