<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:20:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dune: Awakening griefers are parking on other players and feeding them to worms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dune-awakening-griefers-are-parking-on-other-players-and-feeding-them-to-worms</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dune-awakening-griefers-are-parking-on-other-players-and-feeding-them-to-worms.1231725/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dune-awakening">Dune: Awakening</a> griefers are pinning ornithopters to the ground in PvE zones, summoning worms with thumpers, and feeding helpless players to the monstrous beasts in otherwise safe regions of the game.</p>
<p>It works due to vehicle collision. While Funcom <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dune-awakening-patch-ends-the-reign-of-vehicular-terror-as-ramming-into-other-players-no-longer-deals-damage">removed the ability to damage other players by ramming into them with ornithopters</a>, you can still push other players' vehicles around by flying into them. What these griefers are doing is essentially parking their own flying vehicles on top of players looking to harvest spice or flour sand, stopping them from flying out of the reach of incoming sandworms.</p>
<p>This comes following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dune-awakening-deep-desert-pve-expansion">a massive patch made the PvP Deep Desert significantly safer</a> for PvE-minded players, allowing them to farm the highest tier of resources without fear of roaming ornithopter gangs. In response, those who got a kick out of hunting down these combat-averse players have seemingly taken their devious behaviour elsewhere.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dune: Awakening Review - Three Outstanding Games in One" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pDcQ9nP3s4k?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dune: Awakening Review - Three Outstanding Games in One</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pDcQ9nP3s4k?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/pDcQ9nP3s4k?autoplay=1" title="Dune: Awakening Review - Three Outstanding Games in One">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Watch our video review of Dune: Awakening here!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pDcQ9nP3s4k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>It's worth noting victims of this strategy do have ways out. They can attempt to slip out of the grasp of these griefers and fly away, or retrieve their scout ornithopter (while it has no stored cargo) with a vehicle back-up tool. However, taking the second approach still leaves you stranded on the sand with a worm approaching, forcing you to make a break for the nearest safe spot.</p>
<p>This, obviously, trapping players on the ground isn't an intended vehicle interaction. So what can Funcom do? Well, they can remove vehicle-on-vehicle collision altogether in PvE zones. This was a popular community-suggestion during <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dune-awakening-pvp-is-being-dominated-by-one-busted-technique-crushing-people-with-helicopters">the whole ornithopter squishing saga</a>.</p>
<p>The counter-argument is, harvesting spice on open sand is meant to be dangerous! While Hagga Basin isn't a PvP zone for the most part, you're still meant to keep your head on a swivel for incoming dangers. Removing this vehicle collision issue could make harvesting spice too easy.</p>
<p>It's a tricky one. Removing vehicle-on-vehicle collision is likely harder than it looks, and may have knock-on effects on the wider game. It's unlikely Funcom can flip a switch to make it work in PvP areas and not in PvE ones. There is a touch of irony with this, as an update to make the PvP endgame safer for PvE players has consequently made the PvE area more dangerous.</p>
<p>In my heart I can't really be mad at these sorts of shenanigans. Obviously for the player taking things slow and steady, happy in Hagga Basin, it would be incredibly frustrating to get pinned and eaten by a worm. But I also can't help but shake the feeling that these sorts of hyjinx add a wild west charm to Dune: Awakening, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dune-awakening-early-meta-helicopter-infested-nightmare">one I hope never goes away</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/dune-awakening-griefers-are-parking-on-other-players-and-feeding-them-to-worms]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No plans for Sonic Adventure remakes, as Sonic Team focuses on new games instead]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/no-plans-for-sonic-adventure-remakes-as-sonic-team-focuses-on-new-games-instead</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-plans-for-sonic-adventure-remakes-as-sonic-team-focuses-on-new-games-instead.1231686/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sonic Team head Takashi Iizuka has no plans to remake or remaster the Dreamcast <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sonic-adventure">Sonic Adventure</a> games.</p>
<p>Iizuka, who directed both Sonic Adventure and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/r-sa2-dc">Sonic Adventure 2</a>, is frequently asked by fans to remake the two beloved games, but he told <a href="https://www.shacknews.com/article/144842/takashi-iizuka-sonic-racing-crossworlds-interview-june-2025">Shack News</a> the effort required would be better spent on new games.</p>
<p>"I do hear that a lot," said Iizuka. "I really am appreciative of everyone who likes the Sonic Adventure series, but when I think about what it would take to bring that game up to the standards and expectations of what the modern gaming audience would want, I think it would be about as much time and energy as it would to make a new title.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds - Summer Game Fest Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3_xAuG3JfIg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds - Summer Game Fest Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3_xAuG3JfIg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/3_xAuG3JfIg?autoplay=1" title="Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds - Summer Game Fest Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds - Summer Game Fest Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3_xAuG3JfIg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"So part of me is thinking maybe I should just make a brand new title and that's why there are currently no plans."</p>
<p>Sonic Team doesn't seem averse to remakes and remasters entirely, considering last year it released <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sonic-x-shadow-generations-review">Sonic x Shadow Generations</a> - an update of the 2011 original.</p>
<p>However, both Sonic Adventure and Sonic Adventure 2 are particularly dated. And as Sonic Team continues to develop its 3D Sonic games, Iizuka previously stated the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sonic-frontiers-is-cornerstone-of-future-sonic-games-says-sonic-team-head">open zone design of Sonic Frontiers is the "cornerstone of future Sonic games"</a>.</p>
<p>Further, last year Iizuka stated there were <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/no-plans-for-sonic-adventure-3-says-sonic-team-boss-but-wed-love-to-make-it">no plans for Sonic Adventure 3 or a Chao Garden game</a> either, but said "we'd love to make it".</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the interview, Iizuka discussed the roadmap for the development team and how they decide which game to make next.</p>
<p>The three core pillars of the Sonic series are the modern 3D action games, the 2D classic games, and the racing games, Iizuka explained.</p>
<p>Looking back, it's clear the team is seeking to alternate between these each year: last year had Sonic x Shadow Generations, the year before was the 2D <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sonic-superstars">Sonic Superstars</a>, and the year before that was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sonic-frontiers">Sonic Frontiers</a>. Now there's Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds following previous racing games.</p>
<p>In addition, Sonic Team is also thinking about what new experiences and games people want in the future. "So when we think about our roadmap for content," said Iizuka, "that's what we're constantly thinking about: what are those long-running series and how can we add new?"</p>
<p>New experiences the developers have recently released include <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-murder-of-sonic-the-hedgehog-is-an-april-fools-joke-that-turned-out-to-be-real">The Murder of Sonic the Hedgehog</a>, an April Fool's joke that turned out to be real - it was quickly <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-murder-of-sonic-the-hedgehog-surpasses-1m-downloads">downloaded a million times</a>.</p>
<p>Between games and films, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/10-years-ago-we-were-fighting-to-survive-its-totally-different-now-segas-franchise-guru-on-sonics-redemption-arc">Sonic has become a global megastar in the last 10 years</a>, as Iizuka detailed to Eurogamer.</p>
<p>To celebrate the forthcoming release of Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sonic-joins-mclaren-racing-in-historic-partnership-with-sega">Sega has partnered with McLaren Racing</a> in a multi-year collaboration.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/no-plans-for-sonic-adventure-remakes-as-sonic-team-focuses-on-new-games-instead]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Plucky Squire too easy for you? The developer heard you and said 'challenge accepted']]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-plucky-squire-too-easy-for-you-the-developer-heard-you-and-said-challenge-accepted</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-plucky-squire-too-easy-for-you-the-developer-heard-you-and-said-challenge-accepted.1231668/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Devolver Digital</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The team behind picture book adventure The Plucky Squire has heard your cries of 'this game is too easy', and is introducing a new level of challenge which will 'transform' your experience.</p>
<p>This is all coming with the aptly named Challenge Update, which adds new modes, new enemies, and other features and tweaks.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Plucky Squire Review - An Ingenious Puzzle-Platformer!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Ea943e3ouk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Plucky Squire Review - An Ingenious Puzzle-Platformer!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Ea943e3ouk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4Ea943e3ouk?autoplay=1" title="The Plucky Squire Review - An Ingenious Puzzle-Platformer!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Plucky Squire Review - An Ingenious Puzzle-Platformer! <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Ea943e3ouk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The first of these new modes is known simply as Challenge. This will introduce "tougher foes" and "greater trials".</p>
<p>Then there is the Iron Squire mode, which ups the difficulty even more by giving you no second changes. It's a permadeath situation, people. "Die once, your save is gone," The Plucky Squire developer All Possible Futures wrote, wishing us all good luck.</p>
<p>As well as this increased level of difficulty, the studio is also adding the likes of dialogue fast forward and new achievements. </p>
<p>The Plucky Squire's free Challenge update is already available for those on Steam. Console versions are coming "soon". You can check out a little teaser for it all via the embed below.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreiaw4nnix7c4in4h7brw6tp5hakzll3lyp7d23mfvngi3n2s5m66ee" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:xl6ldjd4ev67q3cliukol3ax/app.bsky.feed.post/3lsjn2npg4c2d"><div lang="es"><p>⚔️ Introducing The Challenge Update! ⚔️

A huge free update that transforms your Plucky Squire experience with:

💥 Challenge Mode
💪 Iron Squire Mode
😈 New enemies &amp; variants
🎯 Minigame updates

Think it was too easy? This update might just change your mind...</p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:xl6ldjd4ev67q3cliukol3ax/post/3lsjn2npg4c2d?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p></div>— The Plucky Squire (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:xl6ldjd4ev67q3cliukol3ax?ref_src=embed">@thepluckysquire.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:xl6ldjd4ev67q3cliukol3ax/post/3lsjn2npg4c2d?ref_src=embed">June 26, 2025 at 6:19 PM</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>These changes may indeed please Christian Donlan, who in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-plucky-squire-review-the-power-of-imagination">Eurogamer's The Plucky Squire review</a> wrote:</p>
<p>"There's also a handful of pacing issues, not least that the game has a habit of interrupting its own flow to explain things. I think this comes from the game having to balance two audiences - kids and adults - but there are still a few too many unskippable conversations when even younger players will want to just get on with things."</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-plucky-squire-too-easy-for-you-the-developer-heard-you-and-said-challenge-accepted]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>