<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 13:58:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Sams from all over the world are still delivering," celebrates Kojima with latest Death Stranding milestone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sams-from-all-over-the-world-are-still-delivering-celebrates-kojima-with-latest-death-stranding-milestone</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sams-from-all-over-the-world-are-still-delivering-celebrates-kojima-with-latest-death-stranding-milestone.1149684/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/sams-from-all-over-the-world-are-still-delivering-celebrates-kojima-with-latest-death-stranding-milestone<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Sam-in-Death-Stranding-with-handcuffs-around-his-wrist.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Kojima Productions</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Many millions of us have looked for a Porter in the storm, with Hideo Kojim today announcing that the number of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/death-stranding">Death Stranding</a> players has now exceeded a not too shabby at all 20 million.</p>
<p>"Thank you very much. Sams from all over the world are still delivering. You are connecting the world," <a href="https://x.com/HIDEO_KOJIMA_EN/status/1906654046783676810">Kojima wrote on social media</a> with a nice little graphic showing Sam looking towards another Sam.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" title="9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtaSpf-70nc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>This latest figure is for players across all available platforms, and includes those who have taken Death Stranding for a whirl as part of a subscription service such as PlayStation Plus.</p>
<p>As noted by industry analyst <a href="https://x.com/ZhugeEX">Daniel Ahmad</a>, Death Stranding had sold less than 5m copies prior to its release on the likes of PC, PS+, PS5, Xbox Series X/S and Mac.</p>
<p>"Making the game more accessible has led to 20m+ players experiencing the IP prior to the launch of its sequel that will require players to own a PS5 to play at launch," Ahmad wrote on X.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Infographic-celebrating-20m-Death-Stranding-players.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Hideo Kojima</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for that sequel, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/death-stranding-2">Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</a>, to give it its full name, is set for release on 26th June, and includes <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-out-in-june-fake-snake-revealed">a new character that looks remarkably like Metal Gear Solid's Snake</a>. This was revealed during the game's SXSW 2025 showcase earlier in March.</p>
<p>Towards the end of last year, Kojima Productions shared several new snippets of footage for Death Stranding 2: On the Beach, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/death-stranding-2-footage-sees-creepy-puppet-dollman-steal-the-show-in-unexpected-dance-number">including a look at the upcoming game's very realistic photo mode and Sam Bridges' stop motion puppet companion, Dollman</a>.</p>
<p>As you would expect from a Kojima game, it all looks suitably bizarre. Are you looking forward to rendezvousing with Sam once more this summer?</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft movie is just what the world needs right now, says Jack Black]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/minecraft-movie-is-just-what-the-world-needs-right-now-says-jack-black</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecraft-movie-is-just-what-the-world-needs-right-now-says-jack-black.1149651/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/minecraft-movie-is-just-what-the-world-needs-right-now-says-jack-black<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Jack-Black-as-Steve-looks-at-some-ore-in-A-Minecraft-Movie.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Warner Bros</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Actor Jack Black believes his latest film, A Minecraft Move, is just the tonic the world is in need of right now.</p>
<p>Speaking with <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/jason-momoa-jack-black-minecraft-movie-jennifer-coolidge-1236175713/">The Hollywood Reporter</a> during the film's premiere, Black channelled his inner Burt Bacharach stating: "What the world needs now is love, sweet love."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Everything You Need To Know About Minecraft Legends Gameplay - NEW MINECRAFT LEGENDS 4K GAMEPLAY" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J90QtqvJwEg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Everything You Need To Know About Minecraft Legends Gameplay - NEW MINECRAFT LEGENDS 4K GAMEPLAY</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J90QtqvJwEg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/J90QtqvJwEg?autoplay=1" title="Everything You Need To Know About Minecraft Legends Gameplay - NEW MINECRAFT LEGENDS 4K GAMEPLAY">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Everything You Need To Know About Minecraft Legends Gameplay. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J90QtqvJwEg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"We've got to work together, my God," Black - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/minecraft-movies-second-trailer-brings-deep-steve-lore-tree-punching-square-bee">who plays Steve in the Minecraft adaptation</a> - continued.</p>
<p>The actor said there is quite simply "so much violence and war and hatred" right now, so what he loves about A Minecraft Movie is that there is "a lot of love in it and there's a lot of creativity". He added there is "some anger and violence" peppered throughout the film as well, but "in the end it's about friendship and working together to make [the world] a better place".</p>
<p>Black's sentiment was echoed by Game of Thrones and Aquaman actor Jason Momoa, who stars as Garrett "The Garbage Man" Garrison in A Minecraft Movie.</p>
<p>"I think everyone needs to escape a little bit right now," Momoa said. "It's nice to sit back and have a really fun adventure and giggle and laugh."</p>
<p>As for the rest of the cast, Black was full of praise for his co-stars, calling Momoa "worth the price of admission" alone. Then there's "Danielle Brooks, who is fantastic; Emma Myers, she's fantastic. You've got this new kid [Hansen], who is a genius. But then wild card! You didn't know you're gonna get Jennifer Coolidge?" Black enthused.</p>
<p>Oh, and in case you were already wondering, Momoa is up for making another Minecraft film down the line. "We won't let you down. We worked our ass off for you, and I think we brought the world to life. I think everybody's gonna love it," the actor said. "There's so much more to tell; I just hope the fans will be delighted and let us make more."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Jason-Momoa-in-A-Minecraft-Movie.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Warner Bros</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A Minecraft Movie is set to release on 4th April, and while Black plays Steve in the film this wasn't always going to be the case. Believe it or not, he was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/minecrafts-jack-black-was-initially-going-to-play-a-talking-pig">originally going to portray a talking pig</a> in the upcoming film.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, if you fancy some themed-food ahead of any trips to the cinema, McDonald's is offering its customers the chance to purchase a £8.19 Minecraft Movie Meal, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mcdonalds-limited-edition-8-minecraft-movie-menu-includes-amazing-collectibles-for-adults">complete with "amazing collectibles" crafted for adults</a>.</p><p><span data-fixed="false" data-hashid="" data-init="false" data-poll-position="1"></span>.



        </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Joel was right," says The Last of Us creator]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/joel-was-right-says-the-last-of-us-creator</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/joel-was-right-says-the-last-of-us-creator.1149621/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/joel-was-right-says-the-last-of-us-creator<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Ellie-at-the-end-of-The-Last-of-Us.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Naughty Dog</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The Last of Us has an ending that leaves many questions regarding Joel's actions. Was he right to do what he did? Well, The Last of Us' creator Neil Druckmann believes he was.</p>
<p>Please be aware of <strong>major spoilers for The Last of Us (the game and the first season of the show) below</strong>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Does Anyone Really Want Long Games Anymore?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D9-4YFvps5k?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Does Anyone Really Want Long Games Anymore?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D9-4YFvps5k?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/D9-4YFvps5k?autoplay=1" title="Does Anyone Really Want Long Games Anymore?">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Does Anyone Really Want Long Games Anymore? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D9-4YFvps5k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>At the end of The Last of Us, Joel executes multiple members of the Fireflies when he discovers that for them to work on a cure for the cordyceps virus, Ellie would need to have an operation that would kill her.</p>
<p>By this point in The Last of Us' narrative, Joel has come to consider Ellie to be like his own child, and having already lost one daughter, he can not bring himself to lose another one. But, whether or not Joel was right to do this has been an ongoing debate since the first game released back in 2013.</p>
<p>Now, ahead of The Last of Us season two, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-hbo-creators-answer-whether-or-not-joel-was-right-to-save-ellie">IGN</a> asked the show's cast and creators the same question, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/naughty-dog">Naughty Dog</a>'s own Neil Druckmann is firmly on the side of Joel simply doing what he had to do.</p>
<p>"I believe Joel was right," Druckmann said. "If I were in Joel's position, I hope I would be able to do what he did to save my daughter."</p>
<p>Fellow showrunner Craig Mazin added he would probably do the same thing if he was put into Joel's position. "But I'd like to think that I wouldn't," Mazin said, adding: "That's the interesting push and pull of the morality of it. And that's why the ending of the first game is so provocative and so wonderful. It just doesn't let you off the hook as a player.”</p>
<p>Mazin continued: "People get to the end of The Last of Us [the game] and there is that question, what would you do? What should you do if faced with the opportunity to save the world, if you sacrifice your child. That goes back to Abraham and Isaac. It's so profound. The notion of sacrifice to save the world."</p>
<p>"It's a difference between, OK, if I had to kill a random person to save who knows how many lives, in the abstract, you would say, well, yeah, that makes sense, of course,” Druckmann furthered. "But now, remove it from being a random person and it's your kid. Now the answer is very different."</p>
<p>Other cast members such as Bella Ramsey, who plays Ellie in the show, said that Joel did save the world, it is just that the world he saved was his own. Jesse actor Young Mazino mused: "It's like death begets death begets death and I think that's just a perfect example. And yeah, it's his world. Who cares about the world if your world isn't there?"</p>
<p>These comments echo what Troy Baker - who plays Joel in the games (and James in the show's first season) has previously stated. Back in 2020, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lets-discuss-the-last-of-us-episode-nine">Baker said he believes Joel's actions at the end of The Last of Us to be "the most selfish act ever"</a>. However, he doesn't feel the ending could have played out any other way, as, in Joel's eyes, Ellie was "his world" and as such saving her was more important than saving humanity.</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bella-ramsey-pedro-pascal.webp?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>HBO</cite></span></figcaption></figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/joel-gun.webp?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Naughty Dog</cite></span></figcaption></figure>
</figure>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-2-trailer-teases-two-of-the-games-most-impactful-scenes">second season of The Last of Us is set to debut next month</a>, and will <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-two-will-be-shorter-so-every-episode-feels-like-a-blockbuster">comprise seven episodes</a>, with one of those episodes being "quite big" in length. It will not cover the entirety of The Last of Us Part 2, with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hbo-expects-the-last-of-us-to-run-for-four-seasons">subsequent episodes expected to wrap up the narrative</a>.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-creator-neil-druckmann-curious-about-how-people-will-react-to-season-2-as-elephant-in-the-room-is-dodged">Druckmann admitted he is "really curious" about how viewers will react</a> when The Last of Us season two makes its debut.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>