<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 12:33:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chill town building sim Farthest Frontier sees full launch delayed into 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/chill-town-building-sim-farthest-frontier-sees-full-launch-delayed-into-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/chill-town-building-sim-farthest-frontier-sees-full-launch-delayed-into-2025.1044423/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/chill-town-building-sim-farthest-frontier-sees-full-launch-delayed-into-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Snow-falls-over-a-town-in-Farthest-Frontiers.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Crate Entertainment</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Farthest Frontier will now be released in full next year.</p>
<p>Originally, the town-building early access game was slated for its Version 1 release in 2024. But, with this year now only having a scant five and a bit weeks left (yes, really), the team has announced a change to those original plans.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Farthest Frontier - Gameplay Trailer 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9YDAfsUTOXg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Farthest Frontier - Gameplay Trailer 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9YDAfsUTOXg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9YDAfsUTOXg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Farthest Frontier - Gameplay Trailer 2024. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9YDAfsUTOXg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Developer Crate Entertainment said it had decided to postpone Farthest Frontier's full release for a number of reasons. "For starters, we feel that performance is simply not quite where we would like it to be yet," it wrote in a <a href="https://forums.crateentertainment.com/t/the-state-of-early-access-update-07/141562">post</a> detailing the delay.</p><p>"We are seeing your grand 3000+ population towns which are no doubt pushing the limits of hardware, but there is still more we could do to squeeze more frames out of the game, and we want to take the time to get it right."</p>
<p>Another reason is Crate Entertainment still has plans to add a few more bits and pieces to Farthest Frontier. This, it said, "bloats the schedule" somewhat.</p>
<p>Last but not least, the team has put its business hat on, and come to the conclusion now is not the best time to release its indie game in full. "With the holidays rapidly approaching, this is the time of year when big publishers are going to drown the market with advertising, eager for your holiday shopping coin. Similarly, February tends to be a month when everyone's wallets have just recovered from the holiday rush, so in come the big AAA releases," it reasoned.</p>
<p>As such, Farthest Frontier will now get its full launch in the spring of next year. You can check out a trailer for this new release window in the video above.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-village-square-in-Farthest-Frontier.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Crate Entertainment</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Our Bertie was rather impressed with Farthest Frontier when he gave it a whirl back in 2022.</p>
<p>"Farthest Frontier is not about going from dozens to thousands, from village to sprawling metropolis, and that zooming out you then feel as the person in charge. It's about staying small and staying close to the people you're caring for," he wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/farthest-frontier-understands-the-best-moments-of-city-builders-are-the-beginnings">Eurogamer's Farthest Frontier preview</a>.</p><p>"There's no hurry. It allows you time to let the tranquillity of the game wash over you - the gentle music, the sprawling natural world, the simplicity of surviving. It gives you time to lean in and take an interest in the small lives playing out in front of you, to watch them go about their daily work, to know their names, to check their needs are being met. It's a warm and relaxing place to be."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arcane "cinematic universe" to expand with three more League of Legends animated series]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/arcane-cinematic-universe-to-expand-with-three-more-league-of-legends-animated-series</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arcane-cinematic-universe-to-expand-with-three-more-league-of-legends-animated-series.1044402/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/arcane-cinematic-universe-to-expand-with-three-more-league-of-legends-animated-series<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Focusing on other areas of its world.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/LeagueofLegends_ArcaneMelMedarda.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Netflix / Riot Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/netflix">Netflix</a> and Riot Games' utterly brilliant Arcane will be followed by three further series exploring other parts of the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/league-of-legends">League of Legends</a> world. 
</p>
<p>
Arcane showrunner Christian Linke has now confirmed the locations in which these new stories will be set as Noxus, home to Arcane's Mel Meldarda, plus Demacia and Ionia.
</p>
<p>
Speaking to streamer <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/2309678052">Necrit94</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/arcane-showrunner-confirms-noxus-ionia-demacia-league-of-legends-shows/">TheGamer</a>), Linke said these new series would tell fresh stories, but also continue some of the threads already seen in Arcane.
</p>
<p>
"We're really going wide, we're looking at every region and we really now have the ability to build a slate to tell many more stories - and continue some of them," Linke said.
</p>
<p>
Talented animation studio Fortiche will once again be at the helm for these series, after its award-winning work on Arcane's two seasons, but there's no word yet on when these new series might materialise.
</p>
<p>
Production work on the next show began a year ago, Linke noted, so hopefully we won't have another three year wait to see more.
</p>
<p>Linke had previously mentioned the development of further League of Legends shows when it was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-now-describes-arcane-season-two-as-the-final-chapter">confirmed that Arcane would end with its second season</a>.</p>
<p>"Arcane is just the beginning of our larger storytelling journey and our partnership with the wonderful animation studio that is Fortiche," Linke said in a developer update video earlier this year. "From the very beginning, since we started working on this project, we had a very specific ending in mind, which means the story of Arcane wraps up with the second season.</p><p>"But Arcane is just the first of many stories we want to tell in Runeterra. We've been with Riot through Vi and Jinx's entire journey thus far, from becoming in-game champions to characters featured in different cinematics to main characters in a TV show. Their arcs have grown so far beyond our original dreams, and we want to give the same treatment to more champions."</p>
<p>
In related news, a recent League of Legends leak has suggested the game will get a Noxus-themed season next year, as the game gets ready to host Mel herself beginning in early 2025.
</p>
<p>
"Some iffy pacing moments aside, Arcane's second and final season truly puts the money on screen," our Chris Tapsell wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arcane-season-2-review">Eurogamer's Arcane season two review</a>. "This is a striking, emotionally wrought, hard-punching climax."
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chaotic dungeon creator King of Meat gets alpha test this December]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/chaotic-dungeon-creator-king-of-meat-gets-alpha-test-this-december</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/chaotic-dungeon-creator-king-of-meat-gets-alpha-test-this-december.1044363/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/chaotic-dungeon-creator-king-of-meat-gets-alpha-test-this-december<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Dungeon party game King of Meat will host an invite-only alpha this December, and you can sign up now.</p>
<p>Announced at Summer Game Fest, King of Meat is the debut game from studio Glowmade (comprising ex-Lionhead and Media Molecule developers), with publishing from Amazon Games. It tasks players with creating outlandish dungeons and then completing them with others in online co-op.</p>
<p>The alpha will take place from 4th December to 14th December for PC (Steam) and Xbox Series X/S players in North America and Europe (the test will be in English only).</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="What is King of Meat Episode 1: Co-Op Mayhem" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KbFIZ1jlMB8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>What is King of Meat Episode 1: Co-Op Mayhem</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KbFIZ1jlMB8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KbFIZ1jlMB8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>What is King of Meat Episode 1: Co-Op Mayhem<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KbFIZ1jlMB8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The alpha will include both dungeon creation and gameplay, giving players a well-rounded look at what to expect in the full release. You can take a look at gameplay in the above brand new explainer trailer.</p>
<p>There's currently no proper release date for the game, though it's expected to launch across PS5 and Switch alongside PC and Xbox Series X/S.</p>
<p>The test itself is called<a href="https://www.kingofmeat.com/en-us/news/articles/king-of-meat-lights-camera-alpha"> Lights, Camera, Alpha!</a> due to the TV show framework of the game, with this essentially being the pilot episode. The game is full of irreverent and silly humour as players take part in a televised gameshow to increase their fame.</p>
<p>You'd certainly expect that sort of humour from the developers of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/littlebigplanet">LittleBigPlanet</a> and Fable, though. I got to go <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/king-of-meat-is-a-chaotic-new-amazon-published-game-from-ex-lionhead-and-media-molecule-developers">hands-on with King of Meat</a> earlier in the year and had a fun time with its chaotic action.</p>
<p>You can sign-up for the alpha test on the <a href="https://www.kingofmeat.com/en-us/tester-sign-up">King of Meat website</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 mammoth success drives Larian to bumper £207m pre-tax profit for 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-mammoth-success-drives-larian-to-bumper-207m-pre-tax-profit-for-2023</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-mammoth-success-drives-larian-to-bumper-%C2%A3207m-pre-tax-profit-for-2023.1044360/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-mammoth-success-drives-larian-to-bumper-207m-pre-tax-profit-for-2023<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Come Lae'zel or high water.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Lae'Zel-and-Shadowheart-kiss-in-Baldurs-Gate-3.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Larian</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Larian has reportedly posted a €249m (£207m) pre-tax profit for 2023. This is, of course, thanks in no small part to the runaway success of the Dungeons and Dragon's-based <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-a-critical-success-with-critical-failures">Baldur's Gate 3</a>.</p>
<p>According to a report by the <a href="https://www.independent.ie/business/irish/dublin-firm-behind-baldurs-gate-game-posts-249m-profit-after-runaway-success/a2033961431.html">Irish Independent</a> [paywall], this bumper figure was shared within financial records posted by the Belgium-based holding company for Larian. The publication notes Larian had previously reported a loss of €214k (£178k), before Baldur's Gate 3 took the world by storm.</p>
<p>At the time of its publication, the Irish Independent stated Larian had sold approximately 15m copies of Baldur's Gate 3, and was able to pay out a €28m (£23m) dividend this year as a result of this. While Larian itself has never shared sales figures, earlier this year it was suggested that over 10m copies had been sold since Baldur's Gate 3's debut.</p>
<p>Larian's game was released on PC in August of 2023, before arriving on additional platforms. While of course <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-already-has-one-of-steams-highest-concurrent-player-counts-ever">being a hit on launch</a>, and going on to secure itself <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-sweeps-the-game-awards">swathes of industry praise and awards</a>, Baldur's Gate 3 has continued to prove popular.</p><p>Earlier this month, Larian's director of publishing Michael Douse revealed the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-has-more-players-this-year-than-its-actual-launch-year">game's average daily peak concurrents are up by a not-to-be-sniffed-at three percent this year over last year</a>. Meanwhile, its average daily active users are up by a more substantial 20 percent over last year.</p>
<p>Larian is still supporting Baldur's Gate 3 (the studio recently secured itself a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/astro-bot-final-fantasy-7-rebirth-lead-this-years-the-game-award-nominations">nomination for Best Community Support at this year's Game Awards</a>). However, it also has other irons in the fire. The studio previously confirmed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-developer-initially-started-work-on-a-follow-up-as-it-was-the-obvious-thing">Balder's Gate 4 was briefly toyed with</a> before it ultimately decided to try something new instead. </p>
<p>
Larian is yet to formally reveal its next project, it has confirmed two games are currently in the works - both of which will be based on its own IPs and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-studio-confirms-two-new-projects-will-be-our-best-work-ever">described as the studio's "best work ever"</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony reportedly prepping PlayStation 5 portable, plans to battle Nintendo's handheld dominance]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-reportedly-prepping-playstation-5-portable-plans-to-battle-nintendos-handheld-dominance</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-reportedly-prepping-playstation-5-portable-plans-to-battle-nintendos-handheld-dominance.1044357/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-reportedly-prepping-playstation-5-portable-plans-to-battle-nintendos-handheld-dominance<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
Sony is developing a portable version of the PlayStation 5, according to a new report. 
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-25/sony-working-on-new-handheld-console-for-ps5-games-to-rival-nintendo-s-switch">Bloomberg</a> states that Sony's portable PS5 project is still in the "early stages" and might not ultimately reach the market.
</p>
<p>
However, Sony is reportedly keen to re-enter the handheld gaming market and compete with Nintendo Switch. In reality, that means with Nintendo's still-under-wraps <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-everything-we-know">Switch 2</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-reveal-now-very-unlikely-before-2025-analyst-says">which is expected to launch next year</a>.
</p>
<p>
Sony already has a portable device capable of playing PS5 games - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2023-playstation-portal-review-impressive-hardware-but-is-remote-play-itself-good-enough">the PlayStation Portal</a> - although this is limited to playing streamed games only (initially from your own PS5 console, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-portal-update-adds-cloud-gaming-support-in-beta-no-ps5-required">though now also via the cloud</a>). 
</p>
<p>
Intriguingly, Bloomberg states that Sony's initial plans for the PlayStation Portal were for it to function as a standalone device, akin to the Steam Deck.
</p>
<p>Such a device would also help Sony bridge the gap between <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/topics/ps5-pro">PS5 Pro</a>, its recent mid-gen console refresh, and the inevitable PS6, which isn't expected until nearer the end of the decade.</p>
<p>
PlayStation is, of course, no stranger to handheld gaming. The PSP constituted the only serious competition Nintendo ever had in the portable console market, and sold more than 76m units. But its successor, the PlayStation Vita, fared less well - and reportedly sold around 16m units.
</p>
<p>
Microsoft <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/phil-spencer-all-but-confirms-plans-for-xbox-portable-console">also has plans to launch an Xbox handheld</a>. Speaking this month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/phil-spencer-says-no-red-lines-over-any-xbox-game-coming-to-nintendo-or-playstation">Xbox boss Phil Spencer said his company's device was also several years away</a>, however.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>