<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 14:49:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's our first batch of Xbox Game Pass titles for January]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-our-first-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-titles-for-january</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-our-first-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-titles-for-january.1076001/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-our-first-batch-of-xbox-game-pass-titles-for-january<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article">
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Diablo! EA Sports UFC 5! More!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/DIA_D1_XGP_1920x1080-579269f0df2033006d14.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Microsoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Microsoft has announced its first wave of Game Pass titles for January.</p>
<p>A number of these games are, I am sorry to say, already available to those on the higher Game Pass tier, but are now becoming available for those on Game Pass Standard.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>The Death of Console Exclusives Is Inevitable and I Don't Know How I Feel About It. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ipoW24t90fw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Here is the full list of titles heading to Game Pass in the coming weeks:</p>
<p><strong>Today, 7th January:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Road 96 (Cloud, Console, and PC) across Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass and Game Pass Standard</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>8th January:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Lightyear Frontier (Game Preview) (Xbox Series X|S), now with Game Pass Standard</li>
<li>My Time at Sandrock (Console), now with Game Pass Standard</li>
<li>Robin Hood – Sherwood Builders (Xbox Series X|S), now with Game Pass Standard</li>
<li>Rolling Hills (Console), now with Game Pass Standard</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>14th January:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>EA Sports UFC 5 (Cloud and Xbox Series X|S) EA Play for Game Pass Ultimate</li>
<li>Diablo (PC), for Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/coming-soon-to-Game-Pass-Jan-2025.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Microsoft</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As is the case with every month, the arrival of these new games means that others will be leaving Game Pass. The following games will leave the service on 15th January:</p>
<ul>
<li>Common' Hood (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Escape Academy (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Exoprimal (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Figment (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Insurgency Sandstorm (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li>Those Who Remain (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
</ul>
<p>If you want to keep playing these games after they leave Game Pass, you'll need to purchase them. On the plus side, Game Pass subscribers get a 20 percent discount.</p>
<p>For everything else in Microsoft's subscription service, you can check out our handy <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-game-pass-games-list-this-month-price-6400">Xbox Game Pass guide</a> detailing the many titles available.</p></div>



        </article>

  
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 Midnight Black DualSense Edge, headset and earbuds unveiled]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ps5-midnight-black-dualsense-edge-headset-and-earbuds-unveiled</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-midnight-black-dualsense-edge-headset-and-earbuds-unveiled.1075962/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ps5-midnight-black-dualsense-edge-headset-and-earbuds-unveiled<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>And a shiny new look for PlayStation Portal, too.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/New-Midnight-Black-Collection-%E2%80%93-Reveal-Trailer-_-PS5-0-34-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sony</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Sony has unveiled its latest accessories to get the Midnight Black treatment: the DualSense Edge wireless controller, Pulse Elite wireless headset and the Pulse Explore wireless earbuds, as well as the PlayStation Portal.
</p>
<p>
The new range joins the existing Midnight Black colour options for the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-5s-dualsense-controller-gets-black-and-red-versions">regular DualSense</a> (released back in May 2021) and the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-unveils-new-midnight-black-colour-option-for-its-pulse-3d-wireless-headset">Pulse 3D wireless headset</a> (released in September 2021), as well as the PS5's black console covers.
</p>
<p>
Sony adding more to its Midnight Black collection had <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ps5-dualsense-edge-and-pulse-headphones-reportedly-getting-black-colour-version">previously</a> been reported. As you'd expect, the range is coloured, well, black. Here's a video showing how it all looks:
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="New Midnight Black Collection – Reveal Trailer | PS5" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u5hisJyJquM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>New Midnight Black Collection – Reveal Trailer | PS5</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u5hisJyJquM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/u5hisJyJquM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Sony's PS5 Midnight Black range.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u5hisJyJquM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"Each Midnight Black accessory features a unique, rich shade of black, with sleek detailing on various buttons and accents such as the PlayStation logo," Sony says, attempting to spin the fact these are coloured black into a full paragraph, which I myself am also now guilty of.
</p><p>
The charging case for the Pulse Explore earbuds is black, the charging hanger for the Pulse Elite headset is black, and the carrying case for the DualSense Edge controller is also black. However, the carrying case for the Pulse Elite wireless headset and Pulse Explore wireless earbuds will be... felt grey.
</p>
<p>The range will go on sale via direct.playstation.com and participating from 20th February, with pre-orders open on 16th January if you're feeling super keen. Pricing is as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>PlayStation Portal remote player – Midnight Black: $199.99 | €219.99 | £199.99 </li>
<li>Pulse Explore wireless earbuds – Midnight Black: $199.99 | €219.99 | £199.99</li>
<li>Pulse Elite wireless headset – Midnight Black: $149.99 | €149.99 | £129.99 GBP</li>
<li>DualSense Edge wireless controller – Midnight Black: $199.99 | €219.99 | £199.99</li>
</ul>
<p>Fancy one?</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starfield lead quest designer says players getting "fatigued" by super long games, trumpets bitesize titles like Mouthwashing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-lead-quest-designer-says-players-getting-fatigued-by-super-long-games-trumpets-bitesize-titles-like-mouthwashing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starfield-lead-quest-designer-says-players-getting-fatigued-by-super-long-games-trumpets-bitesize-titles-like-mouthwashing.1075932/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-lead-quest-designer-says-players-getting-fatigued-by-super-long-games-trumpets-bitesize-titles-like-mouthwashing<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Former Bethesda designer Will Shen, who worked on several high profile titles such as <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-main-story-walkthrough-9352">Starfield</a> and Skyrim, has said he believes players are becoming "fatigued" with games that take hours upon hours upon hours to complete.</p>
<p>During an interview with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PCYpt9Zg7cM">Kiwi Talkz</a> (via <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bethesda-veteran-says-players-are-fatigued-by-seemingly-endless-games/1100-6528653/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f">GameSpot</a>), Shen was asked about game length and acknowledged that there are still plenty of people putting hours into Skyrim. But, do players want to invest the same amount of time into newer games coming to the market? Well, Shen feels we're kind of over that idea when it comes to new releases.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The 10 Best 2024 Games, According To Eurogamer's Video Team" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cp_91zUkG6g?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The 10 Best 2024 Games, According To Eurogamer's Video Team</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cp_91zUkG6g?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cp_91zUkG6g?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The 10 Best 2024 Games, According To Eurogamer's Video Team. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cp_91zUkG6g" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"We're reaching a point where people are fatigued, or a large section, a growing section of the audience, is becoming fatigued at investing 30-plus, 100-plus hours into a game," explained Shen. "Because they already have that. They already have the games that they will continually come back to, and adding another one to that list is a tall order. It's always a tall order."</p><p>Shen said we are now seeing a "resurgence" of shorter games that are more easily digestible (at least in terms of playtime). He pointed to Mouthwashing - a game our Katharine called a "brilliantly refreshing and unflinching horror" in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mouthwashing-review">Eurogamer's four star review</a> - as an example of how shorter games can still deliver a winning result.</p>
<p>"[Mouthwashing is] only three hours long at most, it's a very short experience," Shen said, "but part of the benefit of that is the community engagement around the story of Mouthwashing is only possible because everyone who is a fan has actually played through it all the way to the end."</p>
<p>Shen said he understood there were other factors that had contributed to Mouthwashing's success, but that he firmly believed the game's short length was one of the key reasons it was such a hit. "You can have a fan community conversation around a game that's much shorter because the shortness allows everyone to engage fully with the entirety of the product," Shen continued, adding games that go over the 10 hour mark are often left uncompleted by many players.</p>
<p>"I would say 75 percent of your players only play through the first five to 10 hours, so that's a huge fragmenting of your overall fan community base."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/mouthwashing_c5up8NB.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Mouthwashing / Wrong Organ</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>What are your thoughts on game length? Do you think shorter is sweeter, or are you still on the lookout for that one game that will become The Game you play?</p>
<p>As a quick aside, our Jim was also rather taken with Mouthwashing, so taken in fact he named it one of his games of 2024 in the Eurogamer video team's roundup, which you can watch above.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, while <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-lead-quest-designer-joins-other-ex-bethesda-developers-at-wyrdsong-studio">Shen is no longer with Bethesda</a> and working on Starfield, the studio itself still is. Last year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesdas-todd-howard-confirms-at-least-one-more-starfield-expansion-after-shattered-space">Todd Howard confirmed at least one more DLC for the space epic</a> following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-shattered-space-review">2024's Shattered Space expansion</a>. As for what that could be, fans believe a trademark for "Starborn" registered by Bethesda parent company Zenimax back in July <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesda-trademark-points-to-future-starfield-expansion-fans-believe">could point to Starfield's second expansion</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PUBG unveils chatty co-op buddy powered by generative AI that's designed to play and talk like a human teammate]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/pubg-unveils-chatty-co-op-buddy-powered-by-generative-ai-thats-designed-to-play-and-talk-like-a-human-teammate</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pubg-unveils-chatty-co-op-buddy-powered-by-generative-ai-thats-designed-to-play-and-talk-like-a-human-teammate.1075905/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/pubg-unveils-chatty-co-op-buddy-powered-by-generative-ai-thats-designed-to-play-and-talk-like-a-human-teammate<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
PUBG maker Krafton has unveiled what it's calling Co-Playable Characters (CPCs) - essentially, AI companions that are designed to move, shoot and talk like a human teammate.
</p>
<p>
The technology is powered by an on-device small language model (SLM) and Nvidia ACE technology, which uses generative AI to chat and react to your voice commands. 
</p>
<p>
In essence, it's a smart AI partner with the functionality of a chatbot built in. 
</p>
<p>
Nvidia <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/news/nvidia-ace-autonomous-ai-companions-pubg-naraka-bladepoint/">says</a> its ACE technology allows for "companions that comprehend and support player goals, and enemies that adapt dynamically to player tactics".
</p>
<p>
It's powered by a language model that's "capable of planning at human-like frequencies required for realistic decision making", Nvidia continues, as well as "multi-modal SLMs for vision and audio that allow AI characters to hear audio cues and perceive their environment".
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="NVIDIA ACE | Introducing PUBG Ally - First Co-Playable Character" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wEKUSMqrbzQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>NVIDIA ACE | Introducing PUBG Ally - First Co-Playable Character</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wEKUSMqrbzQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wEKUSMqrbzQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Nvidia and Krafton introduce PUBG Ally - your first Co-Playable Character.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wEKUSMqrbzQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
How will this work in PUBG? As seen in the video above from Krafton, players will be able to team up with a "PUBG Ally" who responds to your commands - such as finding a specific armour item, or running to your side. 
</p>
<p>
There's even the suggestion your PUBG Ally will undertake in a bit of banter. "I carry for a living," the robotic voice says. Bit creepy.
</p>
<p>
As yet there's no word on when PUBG Ally will go live in-game, but further CPCs are also on the way. 
</p>
<p>Krafton's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gorgeous-sims-like-inzoi-delayed-into-next-year-to-give-it-a-stronger-foundation">upcoming Sims-like life simulation game inZoi</a> will also use the technology, with Co-Playable Characters named "Smart Zoi" that will essentially act as human-like NPCs within the experience, designed to support your own character.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>