<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 17:10:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario + Rabbids creator says players want unique independent games "willing to tell different stories"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/mario-rabbids-creator-says-players-want-unique-independent-games-willing-to-tell-different-stories</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mario-rabbids-creator-says-players-want-unique-independent-games-willing-to-tell-different-stories.1120740/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/mario-rabbids-creator-says-players-want-unique-independent-games-willing-to-tell-different-stories<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Discusses why he left Ubisoft.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Mario-%2B-Rabbids-Sparks-of-Hope---Cinematic-Launch-Trailer---Nintendo-Switch-2-35-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nintendo</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Mario + Rabbids creator Davide Soliani believes players are looking for unique independent games that are "willing to tell different stories".</p>
<p>Soliani left Ubisoft last year after 25 years at Ubisoft and has now joined with writer Christian Cantamessa (Red Dead Redemption, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/middle-earth-shadow-of-war">Middle-earth: Shadow of War</a>, the forthcoming Perfect Dark reboot) to form a new studio, Day 4 Night.</p>
<p>Along with other former Ubisoft Milan employees, the pair are working on a new "passion project", though admitted it's a risky time in the games industry to be founding a new studio. </p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Mario + Rabbids Sparks of Hope - Cinematic Launch Trailer - Nintendo Switch" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VEAusFKB368?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Mario + Rabbids Sparks of Hope - Cinematic Launch Trailer - Nintendo Switch</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VEAusFKB368?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VEAusFKB368?autoplay=1" title="Mario + Rabbids Sparks of Hope - Cinematic Launch Trailer - Nintendo Switch">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Mario + Rabbids Sparks of Hope - Cinematic Launch Trailer - Nintendo Switch<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VEAusFKB368" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"I think stupidity made us," Cantamessa told <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/features/davide-soliani-interview/">VGC</a>, discussing the risk of a new studio. "This industry is really at a crossroads right now. We've reached the point where you have massive overheads, you need to recoup those massive investments, and it becomes really hard to sustain."</p>
<p>He explained the studio's financing, from publisher Krafton and Ed Fries' 1Up Ventures, is purely based on stock, meaning the pair have complete creative freedom.</p>
<p>"On one end, you have a situation where everyone is a bit more careful at investing money," said Soliani. "At the same time, there is a growing interest from the player towards games that are a bit, let's say, out of the chorus. They are a bit different. They are willing to tell different stories…that's what we are observing as developers and as players."</p>
<p>Cantamessa compared the current state of the industry with the collapse of Hollywood and the rise of independent filmmaking. "What you see now is the audience is aligning away from the more studio fare and towards the indie fare," he said. "So I think maybe we're in the late 60s, 70s of cinema, and we're starting to see the Bonnie and Clyde of the video game world."</p>
<p>As for the new project itself, Soliani said it's a new IP and while gameplay comes first, it's "merging with storytelling in a meaningful way".</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mario-rabbids-boss-leaves-ubisoft-after-25-years">Soliani also discussed leaving Ubisoft</a> and assured the decision was not due to poor sales of the Mario + Rabbids Kindgom Battle sequel, Sparks of Hope.</p>
<p>"The reason I left is not because I was trying to get away from Ubisoft for any specific reason, but because I was searching for something that I couldn't find there... something that we're now creating together here [at Day 4 Night]," he said.</p>
<p>"For me, Kingdom Battle was a personal project, like the one that we are doing now at Day 4 Night," he said. "It was really a love letter to Nintendo. It's not a surprise that I'm a Nintendo lover. In my office, I currently have a huge Mario plushie that my friend sent me from Tokyo."</p>
<p>Further, Kingdom Battle was a "surprise" success, but that meant the sequel was "harder to develop". "There was too much overthinking about it all around me," he said. "So to me it was a bit…it was still a joy, it was a wonderful experience because I always loved working with Nintendo and I always will."</p>
<p>However, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-ceo-admits-mario-rabbids-sequel-should-have-waited-for-next-nintendo-console">Ubisoft's comments on the game's reception</a> were "a bit hurtful for the morale of the team" Soliana admitted. "Because we just finished working for three and a half years and were super committed to creating a very good game. So, of course, it was not the kind of message that we wanted to receive back in those days.</p>
<p>"It was a bit hurtful, but nothing crazy. I think that's normal…every development team is proud of what they are doing and always searching for encouraging words, which in that situation, was maybe needed. It was a bit harsh on the team, but nothing that we didn't solve by talking internally back when we were in the company."</p>
<p>The announcement of the first Mario + Rabbids game launched <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-ubisoft-crying-man-did-next">Soliani to notoriety as Ubisoft Crying Man</a>.</p>
<p>Ubisoft itself is going through a tumultuous time at the moment. While it has the release of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/assassins-creed-codename-red">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a> on the horizon, it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-announces-studio-closure-as-it-lays-off-185-staff">closed its UK studio last month</a> and laid off 185 jobs across the business.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-acknowledges-buyout-reports-stating-it-regularly-reviews-options">company also looks poised to be sold or taken private</a>, after it was reported <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-and-tencent-considering-buyout-taking-the-company-private-report">Chinese conglomerate Tencent was considering a buyout</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FEAR Platinum joins GOG Preservation Program to "properly recognise Monolith's contributions to gaming"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fear-platinum-joins-gog-preservation-program-to-properly-recognise-monoliths-contributions-to-gaming</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fear-platinum-joins-gog-preservation-program-to-properly-recognise-monoliths-contributions-to-gaming.1120689/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fear-platinum-joins-gog-preservation-program-to-properly-recognise-monoliths-contributions-to-gaming<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article">
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Plus a long list of Lego games.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alma-in-FEAR.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Monolith</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>GOG is adding FEAR Platinum to its Preservation Program "by next month".</p>
<p>GOG announced the upcoming addition following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/warner-bros-reportedly-cancels-wonder-woman-closes-monolith-and-other-studios">Warner Bros' shock closure of its developer Monolith Productions</a> this week.</p>
<p>The team at GOG stated it was initially planning on bringing  FEAR Platinum - which along with the base game also includes both expansions - to the program at a later date, but due to the studio closure it wanted to "accelerate this release to properly recognise Monolith's contributions to gaming".</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Did F.E.A.R predict some events coming in 2025? (I mean, let's hope not...) <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wp3Mmlvq1ds" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"At GOG, we believe in celebrating the creative minds that have shaped gaming history. Monolith Productions has given players some of the most unforgettable experiences, blending groundbreaking gameplay with rich storytelling," the <a href="https://x.com/GOGcom/status/1894753901540196781">team wrote on social media</a>.</p>
<p>"To honor their legacy, we're proud to announce that <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fear">F.E.A.R.</a> Platinum will be joining the GOG Preservation Program – and sooner than planned, with other Monolith icons to join eventually as well."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/FEAR.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Monolith</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In addition to FEAR Platinum, the team is also adding a number of Lego games to GOG, DRM-free and optimised for modern systems. These games are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/the_lego_movie_videogame">The Lego Movie - Videogame</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/the_lego_movie_2_videogame">The Lego Movie 2 Videogame</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/lego_city_undercover">Lego City Undercover</a> (a particular favourite in this house)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/the_lego_ninjago_movie_video_game">The Lego Ninjago Video Game</a></li>
</ul>
<p>As well as all this, the following Lego games are joining GOG's Preservation Program:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/lego_pirates_of_the_caribbean_the_video_game">Lego Pirates of the Caribbean: The Video Game </a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/lego_indiana_jones_the_original_adventures">Lego Indiana Jones: The Original Adventures</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/lego_indiana_jones_2_the_adventure_continues">Lego Indiana Jones 2: The Adventure Continues</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/lego_batman_the_videogame">Lego Batman: The Videogame</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/legor_batman_2_dc_super_heroes">Lego Batman 2 DC Super Heroes</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/lego_batman_3_beyond_gotham">Lego Batman 3: Beyond Gotham</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/lego_the_lord_of_the_rings">Lego The Lord of the Rings</a></li>
</ul>
<p>You can <a href="https://gog.prowly.com/384160-gog-preservation-program-introduces-the-lego-series">read more on these Lego additions via GOG here</a>.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Davy-Jones-in-Lego-Pirates-of-the-Caribbean.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Traveller's Tales</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gog-announces-preservation-program-aims-to-maintain-game-compatibility-with-modern-and-future-systems">GOG announced its Preservation Program</a> in November last year, to maintain the compatibility of games with modern and future systems. Meanwhile, last month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gog-joins-europes-largest-organisation-dedicated-to-game-preservation">GOG joined the European Federation of Game Archives, Museums and Preservation Projects</a> (EFGAMP) as it continues to push for game preservation.</p></div>



        </article>

  
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>