<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 13:42:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team behind BAFTA-award winning Endling - Extinction is Forever announces next game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/team-behind-bafta-award-winning-endling-extinction-is-forever-announces-next-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/team-behind-bafta-award-winning-endling-extinction-is-forever-announces-next-game.1272630/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Rewilders: The Lost Spring has been inspired by works of Hayao Miyazaki.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Herobeat</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Developer Herobeat has announced its next game, Rewilders: The Lost Spring, which has been inspired by the works of Hayao Miyazaki and Studio Ghibli films.</p>
<p>The developer is known for its debut game Endling - Extinction is Forever, which was released back in 2022 and went on to score itself not only a BAFTA win, but a nomination at the Game Awards as well. Rewilders: The Lost Spring is a follow up to Endling - Extinction is Forever, though not a sequel. That said, the developer has promised "echoes" of its predecessor's storytelling, as well as its aesthetics and score.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>Rewilders is described as an open-world action roguelite, which will come with creature collection and metroidvania-like progression. Players will take on the role of Abi, who returns to "the poisoned surface of the world" to both rescue her family and restore the wild. "Discover corrupted biomes and face off against twisted creatures born from a failed society," reads the official blurb.</p>
<p>You can check out a trailer for Rewilders: The Lost Spring below.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Rewilders: The Lost Spring - Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7XygzJ3DSt4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Rewilders: The Lost Spring - Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7XygzJ3DSt4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/7XygzJ3DSt4?autoplay=1" title="Rewilders: The Lost Spring - Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Rewilders: The Lost Spring - Reveal Trailer. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7XygzJ3DSt4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Here is what you can expect on Rewilders: The Lost Spring's release:</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li><strong>Creature collecting:</strong> — collect Hântu, native creatures with active abilities, status effects, and passive bonuses.</li>
<li><strong>Fast-paced third-person combat:</strong> combining melee, ranged, and Hântu skills.</li>
<li><strong>Roguelite elements:</strong> with randomised rewards, enemies, and starting points plus a forgiving death and respawn systems.</li>
<li><strong>Interconnected world with metroidvania-style progression:</strong> using gliders, wall runs, grapples and more.</li>
<li><strong>Base-building system:</strong> grow plants and fruits to level up your Hântu and unlock permanent buffs.</li>
<li><strong>Narrative progression:</strong> choose between Memory or Hatred to shape your build and gameplay path.</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>Rewilders: The Lost Spring is in development for PC and consoles. It currently does not have a release date, but <a href="https://herobeatstudios.com/rewilders/">its website is now live</a>.</p>
<p><em>This is a news-in-brief story. This is part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-is-changing-to-give-you-more-of-what-you-want">our vision</a> to bring you all the big news as part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-in-video-games-18th-august-gamescom-week-and-the-games-youre-looking-forward-to-in-september">daily live report</a>.</em></p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/team-behind-bafta-award-winning-endling-extinction-is-forever-announces-next-game]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Euro Truck Simulator 2 seemingly coming to PS5 and Xbox Series consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/euro-truck-simulator-2-seemingly-coming-to-ps5-and-xbox-series-consoles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/euro-truck-simulator-2-seemingly-coming-to-ps5-and-xbox-series-consoles.1272543/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>SCS</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Cult hit Euro Truck Simulator 2 is seemingly coming to PS5 and Xbox consoles. The news comes via PSN and Xbox store listings for the game, which is yet to be officially announced for the two consoles.</p>
<p>No release date is on the store listings, but we can probably expect that news soon, presumably tied to an announcement over <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-at-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024">Gamescom</a> this week. SCS SOFTWARE had a big hit with Euro Truck Simulator 2 on PC, which as of 2024 had sold<a href="https://www.scssoft.com/press/"> in excess of 15 million copies</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/store/euro-truck-simulator-2/9nlvc6stps52">Euro Truck Simulator 2 on Xbox</a></li>
<li><a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10009049/">Euro Truck Simulator 2 on PS5</a></li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p><em>Travel across Europe as king of the road, a trucker who delivers important cargo across impressive distances! With dozens of cities to explore from the UK, Belgium, Germany, Italy, the Netherlands, Poland, and many more, your endurance, skill and speed will all be pushed to their limits. If you’ve got what it takes to be part of an elite trucking force, get behind the wheel and prove it!</em></p>
<p><em>Key Features:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Transport a vast variety of cargo across more than 60 European cities.</em></li>
<li><em>Run your own business which continues to grow even as you complete your freight deliveries.</em></li>
<li><em>Build your own fleet of trucks, buy garages, hire drivers, manage your company for maximum profits.</em></li>
<li><em>A varied amount of truck tuning that range from performance to cosmetic changes.</em></li>
<li><em>Customize your vehicles with optional lights, bars, horns, beacons, smoke exhausts, and more.</em></li>
<li><em>Thousands of miles of real road networks with hundreds of famous landmarks and structures.</em></li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p><em>This is a news-in-brief story. This is part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-is-changing-to-give-you-more-of-what-you-want">our vision</a> to bring you all the big news as part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-in-video-games-18th-august-gamescom-week-and-the-games-youre-looking-forward-to-in-september">daily live report</a>.</em></p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/euro-truck-simulator-2-seemingly-coming-to-ps5-and-xbox-series-consoles]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>