<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 05:54:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony responds to Marathon reboot director's $200m wrongful dismissal lawsuit, alleges 'disturbing communications' with female employees]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-responds-to-marathon-reboot-directors-200m-wrongful-dismissal-lawsuit-alleges-disturbing-communications-with-female-employees</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-responds-to-marathon-reboot-directors-200m-wrongful-dismissal-lawsuit-alleges-disturbing-communications-with-female-employees.1113978/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-responds-to-marathon-reboot-directors-200m-wrongful-dismissal-lawsuit-alleges-disturbing-communications-with-female-employees<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Including "sexually charged" Truth or Dare.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marathon-bungie-art-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Bungie</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Sony has responded to former <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/destiny-2">Destiny 2</a> and Marathon reboot director Christopher Barrett's $200m USD wrongful dismissal lawsuit, detailing Barrett's alleged 'disturbing communications' with female subordinates - including "sexually charged games of 'Truth or Dare'".
</p>
<p>
Barrett's departure from Bungie was first reported last March, amid <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bungies-marathon-reboot-gets-new-director-as-part-of-creative-leadership-shakeup">word of a leadership shakeup</a> at the studio. However, it was later claimed Barrett was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bungies-former-marathon-reboot-director-chris-barrett-reportedly-ousted-following-inappropriate-behaviour">fired from his role following an internal investigation</a> into accusation of inappropriate behaviour filed by "at least eight" female employees. Things took further turn in December, when Barrett <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/former-marathon-reboot-director-sues-sony-and-bungie-for-200m-claiming-wrongful-dismissal">filed a lawsuit against Bungie and Sony</a>, claiming the companies had "deliberately destroyed [his] reputation by falsely, and publicly, insinuating...he had engaged in sexual misconduct."
</p>
<p>
Barrett's list of accusations was long, but core to his argument was the claim his firing was a "premeditated scheme" concocted so Bungie and Sony could avoid paying him "nearly $50m... owed under his employment agreement". He additionally claimed he "did not do anything remotely resembling gross misconduct or 'Cause' as defined in the Retention Agreements... and there could not have been any credible allegation he did because [he] had a spotless twenty-five year track record at Bungie."
</p>
<p>
And now (via <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/sony-bungie-christopher-barrett-lawsuit-response">Game File's Stephen Totilo</a>), Sony has <a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/830250465/Christopher-Barrett-v-Sony-Interactive-Entertainment-LLC-and-Bungie-Inc-2024-1285-No-97653544-97653546-Del-Ch-Feb-12-2025-1">filed its first substantive response</a>, denying Barret's claims and detailing the events allegedly leading to his dismissal. "Multiple female, subordinate employees individually reported to Human Resources that Barrett engaged in inappropriate behaviour and disturbing written and verbal communications," it wrote, "which made them uncomfortable and fearful of retaliation if they failed to engage or reported Barrett."
</p>
<p>
"The investigation revealed that Barrett's misconduct with each employee was consistent: he targeted a lower-level, female employee he wasn't working with directly, initially engaged in friendly conversation, and progressively pushed boundaries with the employee by making subtle references to her physical appearance or expressing his interest romantically.
</p>
<p>
"Barrett attempted to create an unprofessional level of intimacy with his victims," Sony continued in its court submission. "He requested to follow personal Instagram accounts and would express anger to the women if they failed to respond to his messages. He would bring up inappropriate topics like their body, their relationships, his marriage, or his desire to date them. He would demand that they participate in sexually charged games of 'Truth or Dare' and 'Ask Me Anything'. He texted them at all hours of the day and night. He offered to buy them gifts. He often referenced his wealth and his ability to advance their careers."
</p>
<p>
Sony's filing also includes several examples of Barrett's alleged misconduct, including an incident where it's claimed he FaceTimed one female employee late at night while drunk despite requests to "recognise 'boundaries'", eventually moving to his bedroom and telling her, "I can't believe I am lying in bed while talking to [VICTIM 1]".
</p>
<p>
Barrett also allegedly contacted a second employee via Instagram direct message, telling her, "You are the holy grail. I hope you find a person worthy of your attention." After the employee responded saying she had a boyfriend who treated her very well, Barrett is said to have told her, "He better[.] Cuz I would hit on you if he wasn't." It's claimed he later made further contact, writing, "You want to be worshipped, I think? Why are you against that actually happening?".
</p>
<p>
Other incidents detailed in Sony's filing includes a "virtual game of 'Truth or Dare' initiated by Barrett", and a Microsoft Teams exchange in which he allegedly asked a female member of staff, "Are you still in PJs? [Is] it like a button down top and bottoms? Sweat pants? Lulu lemons?".
</p>
<p>
Sony adds, "Barrett’s predatory behaviour caused victims to seek guidance from other Bungie employees on how to manage Barrett’s constant boundary-pushing given that he was a long-standing, senior member of the company. Multiple victims reported to Human Resources during the investigation that they were afraid for their jobs during these encounters."
</p>
<p>
In response, Barrett's lawyers told Game File, "Sony continues to disingenuously cherry pick text messages and alleged conversations and make unsupported and conclusory statements to defame Christopher and justify terminating him to avoid paying him what he was owed under his employment agreements. It is telling that Sony does not include the full text messages as exhibits, or the full content of these conversations, and nothing in Sony’s response provides a legitimate legal or factual basis to terminate Christopher for cause.
</p>
<p>
"Christopher is confident that when all the evidence is presented, it will be clear that Sony engaged in a scheme to strip him of his role and the equity awards he earned for his 25 years of loyal service to the company."
</p>
<p>
As well as denying inappropriate behaviour during his time at Bungie, Barrett's original filing argued his former employers' actions had "irreparably harmed [him] financially, physically, and emotionally". As such, he is seeking $200m in damages - including $46K (plus interest) owed under his employment terms - and is requesting to be reinstated as game director on Marathon.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us' long-awaited Season 2 finally gets a start date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-long-awaited-season-2-finally-gets-a-start-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-long-awaited-season-2-finally-gets-a-start-date.1113888/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-long-awaited-season-2-finally-gets-a-start-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Episode 1 airing in April.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/last-of-us-two-pedro-tear.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>HBO</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Almost two years after the acclaimed first season of HBO's live-action The Last of Us adaptation drew to a close, its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-we-know-about-the-last-of-us-season-2">long-awaited second season</a> finally has a release date - with episode one set to air in the US on Sunday, 13th April.
</p>
<p>
Season two of The Last of Us picks up some five years after the events of season one, and will at least partially cover <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/naughty-dog">Naughty Dog</a>'s second game. Showrunner Craig Mazin <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-two-will-be-shorter-so-every-episode-feels-like-a-blockbuster">previously confirmed</a> the team would need more than one season to cover The Last of Us Part 2's narrative.
</p>
<p>
"The story that we're telling is much bigger than the story of season one," Mazin explained at the time. "There's just a lot more going on, it's a lot harder to produce but we want every episode to feel like its own blockbuster to be honest with you."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Last Of Us Season 2 | April 2025 | Max" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ylovT43x3yo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Last Of Us Season 2 | April 2025 | Max</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ylovT43x3yo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ylovT43x3yo?autoplay=1" title="The Last Of Us Season 2 | April 2025 | Max">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's a brief glimpse of The Last of Us' second season.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ylovT43x3yo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Season two of The Last of Us is set to span seven episodes - including one that's "quite big" in length - and will usher in a new cast of characters alongside returning favourites. Joel and Ellie are inevitably back (once again played by	Pedro Pascal and Bella Ramsey) and will this time be joined by the likes of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-casts-kaitlyn-dever-as-abby-for-season-two">Kaitlyn Dever as Abby</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-tv-series-casts-beef-actor-young-mazino-as-jesse">Young Mazino as Jesse</a>, and the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-two-adds-schitts-creek-star-catherine-ohara-to-its-cast">legendary Catherine O'Hara in an undisclosed guest role</a>.
</p>
<p>
The Last of Us' second season - part two of an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hbo-expects-the-last-of-us-to-run-for-four-seasons">expected four-season run</a> - airs on <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/hbo-max">HBO Max</a> in the US beginning 13th April. There's no word on international airdates just yet, but Sky Atlantic's ongoing partnership with HBO suggests it'll continue to be the series' home in the UK - possibly again airing simultaneously with the US for those that like to remain unsullied by social media.
</p>
<p>
Season one of The Last of Us was a smash hit for HBO, garnering significant critical acclaim and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-averaging-32m-viewers-per-episode-in-us-most-watched-hbo-max-show-in-europe">averaging over 32m viewers</a> an episode in the US. And with eight Emmy nominations under its belt - including an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hbos-the-last-of-us-wins-eight-emmys-including-outstanding-guest-actor-for-nick-offermans-bill">outstanding guest actor gong for Nick Offerman</a> in the role of Bill - expectations are invariably high for season two.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>