<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 14:45:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix invests in Danish indie studio as it seeks next western publishing hit]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-invests-in-danish-indie-studio-as-it-seeks-next-western-publishing-hit</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-invests-in-danish-indie-studio-as-it-seeks-next-western-publishing-hit.1238169/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Vaultbreakers follows Killer Inn.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>BetaDwarf</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Square Enix has invested in a Danish indie studio to accelerate development of its forthcoming ARPG, as the Japanese company continues to look to the west for another publishing hit.</p>
<p>Back in 2022, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-sells-off-western-studios-and-ip-including-tomb-raider-and-deus-ex">Square Enix sold off its large western studios</a> and over 50 intellectual properties to Embracer for $300m, including the likes of Crystal Dynamics and Eidos Montreal. It later stated this decision was "driven by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-feared-western-studios-cannibalised-sales-of-japanese-games">concerns that the titles cannibalised sales of the rest of the group</a>".</p>
<p>As such, Square Enix has most recently focused on its Japanese games (namely Final Fantasy, Dragon Quest and Kingdom Hearts), but by its own admission, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-admits-final-fantasy-7-rebirth-and-final-fantasy-16-profits-did-not-meet-expectations">the Final Fantasy games especially have underperformed</a>.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Vaultbreakers - Official Gameplay Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZzP79NRjw1I?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Vaultbreakers - Official Gameplay Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZzP79NRjw1I?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZzP79NRjw1I?autoplay=1" title="Vaultbreakers - Official Gameplay Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Vaultbreakers - Official Gameplay Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZzP79NRjw1I" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>But western publishing has still continued at Square Enix. Publishing indie hit PowerWash Simulator through its Square Enix Collective has been a huge success for the company. That's alongside publishing Life is Strange Double Exposure last year for US studio Deck Nine Games, following previous games in the series.</p>
<p>It seems that western investment is set to continue. At Summer Game Fest this year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-follows-up-foamstars-flop-with-traitors-esque-killer-inn">Square Enix revealed its new online multiplayer game Killer Inn</a>, which it's publishing for Canadian studio Tactic Studios.</p>
<p>Now it's investing in Danish studio BetaDwarf to assist with development of its Vaultbreakers ARPG, which was first announced at the start of the year.</p>
<p>"Square Enix is always looking for high-quality games and talented development studios," said Hideaki Uehara, Square Enix general manager of business development. "When I played Vaultbreakers, I was genuinely excited by the experience of connecting with other players and exploring its rich game world.</p>
<p>"After visiting BetaDwarf and learning about the team's mission and passion, we decided to invest in them to help realise their dream and bring this game to players around the world."</p>
<p>BetaDwarf CEO and game director Steffen Kabbelgaard noted the "amazing access to a combination of knowledge, talent, and resources" thanks to this partnership.</p>
<p>"We are already very far with our dream game Vaultbreakers: we have a huge amazing community, and we have already run 15+ tests with more than 50,000 players who constantly enable us to refine," added Kabbelgaard. "So getting this additional support feels amazing when we are far into production already. I can really see how this enables a home run vs having just started on an uncertain journey - yeah, I'm just really excited about our situation!"</p>
<p>Vaultbreakers is a Diablo-esque top-down ARPG set in a colourful fantasy world. It will be playable solo or in multiplayer in both PvE and PvPvE modes.</p>
<p>A beta test is currently taking place, though there's no firm release date yet.</p>
<p>Square Enix's next Final Fantasy game will be its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/long-rumoured-final-fantasy-tactics-remaster-is-real">long-rumoured Final Fantasy Tactics remaster</a>, The Ivalice Chronicles. It's set for release on 30th September across PS4, PS5, Switch, Switch 2, Xbox Series X/S, and PC (Steam).</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-invests-in-danish-indie-studio-as-it-seeks-next-western-publishing-hit]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve provides clarification following reports it pulled controversial Steam mod worldwide at request of South Korean government]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-provides-clarification-following-reports-it-pulled-controversial-steam-mod-worldwide-at-request-of-south-korean-government</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-provides-clarification-following-reports-it-pulled-controversial-steam-mod-worldwide-at-request-of-south-korean-government.1238094/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Mod criticised for "distorted historical facts".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Valve has denied reports its pulled a controversial mod from Steam around the world at the request of the South Korean government, saying the mod was only blocked in South Korea and only because it broke local laws. The mod's author is said to be behind its global removal.
</p>
<p>
Over the weekend, <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/valve-cooperates-in-banning-steam-mod-for-depicting-historical-revisionism/">Automaton</a> (citing several South Korean sources including the <a href="https://www.yna.co.kr/view/AKR20250613133900017">Yonhap News Agency</a> and <a href="https://www.thisisgame.com/webzine/news/nboard/4/?category=4&amp;n=214032">ThisIsGame</a>) reported Valve had agreed to a request by South Korea's Game Rating and Administration Committee (GRAC) to remove a mod for strategy RPG Mount &amp; Blade: Warband not just locally but overseas as well.
</p>
<p>
The mod, titled Gwangju Running Man, reportedly depicted the events of the 1980 Gwangju Uprising - in which student-led pro-democracy protests were violently suppressed by the South Korean military, resulting in significant civilian casualties - in a way that "distorted historical facts". It's said the mod (which featured military dictator Chun Doo Hwan as its cover), depicted protesters as "armed and violent criminals", framing the military's response as "justified".
</p>
<p>
As reports of Valve's response began circulating, some expressed concern that the company was now seemingly willing to remove content worldwide at the request of a country's government. Valve, though, has now provided clarification on the events leading to the Mount &amp; Blade mod's removal, saying access was restricted in March - but only in South Korea - after the company was informed it violated South Korean laws. Valve added the mod was then deleted from Steam in June by its original uploader, causing its worldwide disappearance.
</p>
<p>
Valve has, of course, been <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-accused-of-allowing-the-proliferation-of-hate-as-report-finds-18m-instances-of-extremist-or-hateful-content-on-steam">heavily criticised for its lack of adequate content moderation</a> in the past, facing condemnation for allowing the likes of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-steam-school-shooting-game">school shooting game Active Shooter</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-under-fire-as-sexually-explicit-game-glorifying-rape-is-listed-on-steam">Rape Day</a>, and, more recently, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-quietly-removes-explicit-game-featuring-extreme-sexual-violence-from-steam-in-uk">non-consensual sex game No Mercy</a> onto its store.
</p>
<p>
In 2018, following the controversy caused by Active Shooter, Valve <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-backs-away-from-content-policing-says-it-will-allow-everything-on-steam">announced it had decided to "allow everything" onto Steam</a>, provided it wasn't illegal, "or straight up trolling". While Valve has also been known to quietly remove titles when faced with significant negative public attention, it seems Gwangju Running Man specifically fell foul of its legality rules.
</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-provides-clarification-following-reports-it-pulled-controversial-steam-mod-worldwide-at-request-of-south-korean-government]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>