<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 09:44:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sea of Thieves Season 15, Wild Things, is almost here - here's what you can expect]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sea-of-thieves-season-15-wild-things-is-almost-here-heres-what-you-can-expect</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sea-of-thieves-season-15-wild-things-is-almost-here-heres-what-you-can-expect.1111533/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/sea-of-thieves-season-15-wild-things-is-almost-here-heres-what-you-can-expect<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Get ready to go on the hunt - <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sea-of-thieves">Sea of Thieves</a> Season 15, Wild Things, is almost here.</p>
<p>Setting out across the sea is about to get even more dangerous as two new ancient Megalodon have arrived, with pirates able to encounter the Feared Redmaw, a huge fanged beast that can release a "devastating" explosion.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Sea of Thieves Season 15: Official Content Update Video" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VJJ6_EMiebg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Sea of Thieves Season 15: Official Content Update Video</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VJJ6_EMiebg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VJJ6_EMiebg?autoplay=1" title="Sea of Thieves Season 15: Official Content Update Video">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Sea of Thieves Season 15: Official Content Update Video.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VJJ6_EMiebg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Season 15 also lets you sail as the Hunter's Call emissary, flying their flag and building your reputation at an increased rate, as well as embark on Raid Voyages. Complete these, and you'll "net a fine haul of Hunter's Call specific loot, helping you even more reputation".</p>
<p>"As ancient creatures stir in the deep, The Hunter's Call summons scoundrels hungry to test their skills!" the team teases.</p>
<p>"Ahead of its first update on Feb 20th, this Content Update covers all the monsters, Voyages, wildlife and more that's emerging monthly throughout Season 15: Wild Things!"</p>
<p>Sea of Thieves Season 15: Wild Things goes live on 20th February on PC, PS5, and Xbox, including Game Pass.</p>
<p>Don't forget that from now until 20th February, <a href="https://www.seaofthieves.com/news/this-month-february2025">you can face off with Ghost Fleets and Phantoms in and around Sea Forts</a>. Be cautious, though - these spectral threats won't make things easy for your crew, but for those willing to take on the challenge, "there's plenty to gain: fight your way through waves of ghostly adversaries and you can claim two Vaults filled with valuable loot!"</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Street Fighter vs Mortal Kombat will finally be possible, in Fortnite]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/street-fighter-vs-mortal-kombat-will-finally-be-possible-in-fortnite</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/street-fighter-vs-mortal-kombat-will-finally-be-possible-in-fortnite.1111530/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/street-fighter-vs-mortal-kombat-will-finally-be-possible-in-fortnite<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Characters from Mortal Kombat will finally be able to square up against Street Fighter legends such as Ryu, Chun-Li and Guile - within <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a>. 
</p>
<p>
Epic Games' ever-popular battle royale will be the first video game to officially feature characters from both fighting game franchises, when Mortal Kombat crosses over with Fortnite next season. 
</p>
<p>
The announcement that Mortal Kombat would feature in Fortnite came via artwork teasing the game's next battle pass character line-up - in which ice ninja Sub-Zero will star.
</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
Street Fighter characters have already been part of Fortnite for several years, of course - with Ryu and Chun-Li added as Shop skins back in February 2021, before their fellow fighters Cammy, Guile, Blanka and Sakura all arrived a short time after.
</p>
<p>
Fortnite even paid tribute to Mortal Kombat during this weekend's eye-catching mini live event, which featured a fight to the death between antihero Daigo and demon boss Hunter X. 
</p>
<p>
The showdown, a culmination of Fortnite Chapter 6's story so far, included a moment where Daigo appeared to have been skewered by Hunter X's sword - though there was no Fatality here. Instead, the masked fighter fought back, ultimately appearing to defeat Hunter X for good after slicing off his arm. You can watch the full event below:
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fortnite Season 2 Live Event!! 🔥" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f2vpESdv7a4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fortnite Season 2 Live Event!! 🔥</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f2vpESdv7a4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/f2vpESdv7a4?autoplay=1" title="Fortnite Season 2 Live Event!! 🔥">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Fortnite Chapter 6's first mini live event.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f2vpESdv7a4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fortnite being Fortnite, of course, there is no blood - or any realistic-looking violence at all. So, it will be interesting to see the extent to which Mortal Kombat's famously gory antics get translated here.</p>
<p>Fortnite Chapter 6 Season 2 is set to arrive later this week, on 21st February, and feature a criminals theme. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnites-new-crime-season-will-let-you-play-as-a-giant-pickle">Other new character skins are set to include a giant pickle</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>