<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 20:35:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Six minutes of Transformers: Reactivate gameplay footage leaks online]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/six-minutes-of-transformers-reactivate-gameplay-footage-leaks-online</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/six-minutes-of-transformers-reactivate-gameplay-footage-leaks-online.1078464/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/six-minutes-of-transformers-reactivate-gameplay-footage-leaks-online<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Following this week's cancellation.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/transformers-reactivate-hand.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Splash Damage/Hasbro</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Six minutes of developer Splash Damage's unreleased <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/transformers-reactivate">Transformers: Reactivate</a> have leaked online following the studio's announcement it was ending development earlier this week.
</p>
<p>
Transformers: Reactivate - an online action game for up to four players, featuring some of the franchise's most iconic characters - was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/brink-developer-splash-damage-developing-transformers-reactivate">unveiled for PC and consoles</a> during The Game Awards back in 2022. Little has been seen of the title since then - and it seemed that would likely remain the case after Splash Damage this week confirmed its cancellation.
</p>
<p>
Now, however, six minutes of leaked gameplay footage has appeared on social media, shared by an <a href="https://x.com/DpzLuna/status/1877095975665242277">anonymous Transformers fan account</a>. There's no word on how the footage was acquired, but it features a combination of third-person gunplay and vehicular traversal across an unfinished, open-world style city - seemingly from a work-in-progress developer build.
</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
Splash Damage <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/splash-damage-cancels-transformers-reactivate-says-roles-at-risk-of-redundancy">announced Transformers: Reactivate's cancellation on Wednesday</a>, saying the studio would be "scaling down" in order to refocus its efforts on other projects - leaving a "number of roles" at the company "potentially at risk of redundancy" as a result.
</p><p>
"While not being able to see the game through to release is painful," it wrote in a statement, "having to say goodbye to friends and colleagues hurts even more. We're now focused on doing everything we can to support them through this tough period, just as we are committed to caring for those who will stay with us as we build a stronger Splash Damage for the future."
</p>
<p>
The studio <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/brink-dev-splash-damage-teases-aaa-open-world-survival-game-project-astrid">previously announced</a> it was working on a new "AAA open-world survival game", codenamed Project Astrod, in collaboration with streamers Mike "Shroud" Grzesiek and Chris "Sacriel" Ball. However, no further updates have been shared since its unveiling in March 2023.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon reveals 16 titles heading to Prime Gaming in January]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/amazon-reveals-16-titles-heading-to-prime-gaming-in-january</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-reveals-16-titles-heading-to-prime-gaming-in-january.1078302/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/amazon-reveals-16-titles-heading-to-prime-gaming-in-january<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Including Zombie Army 4 and BioShock 2.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bioshock-2_QCYfIWf.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>2K Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
If you thought 2025 might finally be the year you managed get through that pesky games backlog, signs aren't looking good. You can now chuck more onto the pile, with Amazon having announced it's bringing another 16 titles to Prime Gaming in January.
</p>
<p>
This month's offerings - as is customary for Prime Gaming - arrive over the course of several scheduled content drops. That starts right now with acclaimed undersea shooter sequel <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/bioshock-2">BioShock 2</a> Remastered, side-scrolling action-RPG Eastern Exorcist, surreal puzzler The Bridge, 2D hack-and-slasher Spirit Mancer, and aeronautical arcade game SkyDrift Infinity.
</p>
<p>
Then, as January continues, Prime Gaming subscribers can look forward to the likes of celebrated deck-building fantasy RPG SteamWorld Quest: Hand of Gilgamech, acclaimed retro stealth FPS Blood West, Zombie Army 4: Dead War, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/super-meat-boy-forever">Super Meat Boy Forever</a>, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/deus-ex">Deus Ex</a>: Game of the Year Edition. The full list of incoming titles can be found below.
</p>
<p>
<strong>Available now:</strong>
</p>
<ul>
<li>Eastern Exorcist [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>The Bridge [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>BioShock 2 Remastered [GOG Code]</li>
<li>Spirit Mancer [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>SkyDrift Infinity [Epic Games Store]</li>
</ul>
<p>
<strong>16th January:</strong>
</p>
<ul>
<li>GRIP [GOG Code]</li>
<li>SteamWorld Quest: Hand of Gilgamech [GOG Code]</li>
<li>Are You Smarter Than A 5th Grader [Epic Games Store]</li>
</ul>
<p>
<strong>23rd January:</strong>
</p>
<ul>
<li>Deus Ex: Game of the Year Edition [GOG Code]</li>
<li>To The Rescue! [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>Star Stuff [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>Spitlings [Amazon Games App]</li>
<li>Zombie Army 4: Dead War [Epic Games Store]</li>
</ul>
<p>
<strong>30th January:</strong>
</p>
<ul>
<li>Ender Lilies: Quietus of the Knights [Epic Games Store]</li>
<li>Blood West [GOG Code]</li>
<li>Super Meat Boy Forever [Epic Games Store] </li>
</ul>
<p>
Additionally, Prime Gaming subscribers in the UK, US, Canada, Germany, France, Italy, Spain, Austria, the Netherlands, and Poland get access to a rotating selection of titles via Amazon's cloud gaming service, Luna. This month, these include Guacamelee! 2 Complete, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metro-exodus">Metro Exodus</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/super-meat-boy">Super Meat Boy</a>, Airhead, and The Magical Mixture Mill. That's alongside service regulars Fallout 3: GotY Edition, Fallout New Vegas: Ultimate Edition, Fortnite, and Trackmania. 
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>