<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 13:12:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hideki Kamiya on leaving PlatinumGames: "I couldn't allow myself to kill my soul"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/hideki-kamiya-on-leaving-platinumgames-i-couldnt-allow-myself-to-kill-my-soul</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hideki-kamiya-on-leaving-platinumgames-i-couldnt-allow-myself-to-kill-my-soul.1132101/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/hideki-kamiya-on-leaving-platinumgames-i-couldnt-allow-myself-to-kill-my-soul<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Praises Shinji Mikami for inspiring his career.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/959374.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Clovers / Game*Spark</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Hideki Kamiya has commented further on his decision to leave PlatinumGames in 2023, stating: "I couldn't allow myself to kill my soul in order to work in an environment that I didn't agree with".</p>
<p>In a recent interview with Japanese outlet <a href="https://www.gamespark.jp/article/2025/03/09/150183.html">Game*Spark</a> (translated by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/hideki-kamiya-wants-his-new-studio-to-inherit-the-teachings-of-resident-evil-creator-shinji-mikami/">Automaton</a>), the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/bayonetta">Bayonetta</a> creator discussed his new studio Clovers and disputed its similarity to Capcom's now-defunct Clover Studio (where he worked on Okami and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/viewtiful-joe">Viewtiful Joe</a>) is not him "clinging to the past".</p>
<p>"If there's anything I'm particular about, it's Capcom Production Studio 4," he said. "Studio 4 is where my career started, and where I learned from Shinji Mikami - a person who has been absolutely indispensable to my career, both as a creator and as my superior."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Okami sequel - Project Teaser Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mSoZgCCxyQc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Okami sequel - Project Teaser Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mSoZgCCxyQc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mSoZgCCxyQc?autoplay=1" title="Okami sequel - Project Teaser Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Okami sequel - Project Teaser Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mSoZgCCxyQc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Mikami led Production Studio 4, which was responsible for many <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/resident-evil-games-order">Resident Evil games</a>, Dino Crisis, Devil May Cry, and many more.</p>
<p>"Back then, we used to call what Mikami taught us the 'spirit of the 4th'," said Kamiya. "The reason I left PlatinumGames was because the company's way of thinking was gradually shifting towards a modern model of game development that doesn't place importance on the creators' individuality."</p>
<p>He added: "Even if it meant the end of my career as a creator, I couldn't allow myself to kill my soul in order to work in an environment that I didn't agree with."</p>
<p>Kamiya is a particularly outspoken figure in the games industry, but his output certainly has a unique and distinctive flair: from the stylish action of Devil May Cry and flamboyance of Bayonetta, to the unique visuals of Okami and Viewtiful Joe.</p>
<p>That spirit of "the creators' individuality" is also particularly apparent in, for example, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/hideo-kojima">Hideo Kojima</a>'s <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-out-in-june-fake-snake-revealed">forthcoming Death Stranding 2</a>. Where the industry contains plenty of copycat games and sequels, Kamiya's comments highlight the importance of creating fresh experiences.</p>
<p>Another Kamiya example would be the cancelled <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/scalebound">Scalebound</a>, which Kamiya worked on at PlatinumGames with Microsoft. The action game focused on a human protagonist with headphones and a smartphone in a fantasy world with a sidekick dragon. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hideki-kamiya-still-wants-to-resurrect-the-cancelled-scalebound">Kamiya recently stated his interest in resurrecting the project</a>, with a direct callout to Xbox boss Phil Spencer.</p>
<p>Kamiya also took a cheeky stab at his former employer in a video on his YouTube channel. It features a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platinumgames-loses-more-game-directors-reveals-former-vice-president-hideki-kamiya">number of prominent developers from PlatinumGames who have recently left</a> all having a drinking party.</p>
<p>Clovers, Kamiya's new studio, is working on a sequel to Okami. The announcement had <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/okami-sequel-announcement-had-hideki-kamiya-crying-with-the-fans">Kamiya "crying with the fans"</a>.</p>
<p>PlatinumGames, meanwhile, is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/how-ninja-gaiden-4s-two-protagonists-will-honour-the-series-legacy">working with Microsoft on Ninja Gaiden 4</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA's Skate doesn't yet have a full release date, but already has microtransactions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/eas-skate-doesnt-yet-have-a-full-release-date-but-already-has-microtransactions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eas-skate-doesnt-yet-have-a-full-release-date-but-already-has-microtransactions.1132095/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/eas-skate-doesnt-yet-have-a-full-release-date-but-already-has-microtransactions<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-screenshot-showing-a-group-of-skateboarders-in-Skate-overlayed-with-the-symbols-for-pounds%2C-euros-and-dollars.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>EA/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Microtransactions have been added to EA's free-to-play Skate revival during the game's closed alpha test.</p>
<p>Skate's in-game currency is known as San Van Bucks, and allows players to buy various cosmetic items. As reported by <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-adds-microtransactions-to-skates-closed-alpha/">Insider Gaming</a>, developer Full Circle said this is being added to give players a "positive experience when purchasing items from the Skate store".</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Fixed Camera Angles in Horror Games Are Scarier - Hear Me Out... <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PTnVyB1BkvQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A message to Skate's playtesters reads: "To ensure we achieve these goals at Early Access we have enabled the option to purchase and use virtual currency (San Van Bucks) in our ongoing Closed Alpha playtest.</p>
<p>"Your feedback will be greatly appreciated in providing a great experience at Early Access launch."</p>
<p>The developer has told players that any purchases made during the test will be converted back to San Van Bucks prior to the game's early access launch. The currency will be made available again at the start of Skate's early access, but players must ensure they use the same EA account.</p>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/10-years-later-ea-has-finally-announced-a-new-skate">Five years after it was first announced</a>, Skate will launch in early access later this year, although EA is yet to give us a specific date.</p>
<p>On its eventual release, Skate will be coming to PlayStation, Xbox and PC. Furthermore, it will also have <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eas-latest-skate-entry-is-live-service-free-to-play-game">cross-play and cross-progression support</a>.</p><p><span data-fixed="false" data-hashid="" data-init="false" data-poll-position="1"></span>

In other skateboarding-related news, earlier this month Activision announced <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-official-announcement-reveals-deluxe-edition-with-doom-slayer">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 and 4 were finally getting the remake treatment</a>. The upcoming combined remake will include some <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tony-hawks-pro-skater-34-is-switching-up-how-thps4-works">changes to how things work in Tony Hawk Pro Skater 4</a>.



        </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two Zenless Zone Zero actors lose jobs over AI dispute without notice, finding out alongside players]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/two-zenless-zone-zero-actors-lose-jobs-over-ai-dispute-without-notice-finding-out-alongside-players</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/two-zenless-zone-zero-actors-lose-jobs-over-ai-dispute-without-notice-finding-out-alongside-players.1132077/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/two-zenless-zone-zero-actors-lose-jobs-over-ai-dispute-without-notice-finding-out-alongside-players<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Two voice actors working on <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zenless-zone-zero-tier-list-best-characters">Zenless Zone Zero</a> have been suddenly recast due to the ongoing SAG-AFTRA strike over AI abuse, and discovered the change alongside the publication of the game's patch notes.</p>
<p>Emeri Chase, who played Soldier 11, announced they were replaced as they were "unwilling to perform work not covered by a SAG Interim Agreement during a strike for AI protections".</p>
<p>Meanwhile Nicholas Thurkettle, who played Lycaon, has also been recast despite not being a member of the union. Both actors only found out about the recasting at the same time as players, when details of <a href="https://www.hoyolab.com/article/37341958">Zenless Zone Zero's latest patch</a> went live.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Soldier 0 - Anby Character Teaser &quot;Death and Rebirth&quot; | Zenless Zone Zero" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rokzdR3JRR4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Soldier 0 - Anby Character Teaser "Death and Rebirth" | Zenless Zone Zero</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rokzdR3JRR4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rokzdR3JRR4?autoplay=1" title="Soldier 0 - Anby Character Teaser &quot;Death and Rebirth&quot; | Zenless Zone Zero">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Soldier 0 - Anby Character Teaser "Death and Rebirth" | Zenless Zone Zero<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rokzdR3JRR4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Chase posted a thread on social media to explain the situation.</p>
<p>"I'd like to clarify that there's a difference between being 'struck' and not being on an Interim Agreement," they said. "Union projects that began work prior to the strike and non-union projects are not 'struck'. But they also do not offer the Union-enforced AI rights we are fighting for.</p>
<p>"Many actors are choosing to voluntarily withhold work on these categories of projects because we feel it is the best way to support the Union's fight for the protections that are critical to our continued ability to create the art we love.</p>
<p>"I knew that by withholding work it was possible I'd be replaced, though of course I hoped they would choose to leave her silent until I was able to return. I found out the role was recast today alongside all of you."</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreieawiyf4d4snb43gqsgb6qp6aeiwnogc74yf7zgiuly7ptqhy7z34" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:eun6fzj2cssacea3u2ukfewb/app.bsky.feed.post/3lk5orkz76s2y"><p lang="en">Hey proxies,

I was replaced as Soldier 11 because I am unwilling to perform work not covered by a SAG Interim Agreement during a strike for AI protection, the outcome of which will determine the future of our industry.

Any other theories that pop up are incorrect.

🧵1/5</p>— Emeri Chase (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:eun6fzj2cssacea3u2ukfewb?ref_src=embed">@emerichase.com</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:eun6fzj2cssacea3u2ukfewb/post/3lk5orkz76s2y?ref_src=embed">12 March 2025 at 03:56</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>Thurkettle posted: "I'm learning about this as you are and I share your shock. Neither HoYoverse nor Sound Cadence has communicated with me since October. I've been fully available and recorded multiple voice jobs in that time."</p>
<p>Then, sharing Chase's post, Thurkettle followed up: "This is what I've been quiet about. I'm not SAG but what game companies want to do with AI is an existential threat. I took a personal stand to ask for protection, and had to be willing to give up the best thing that's ever happened in my professional life. I stand by my choice."</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreihwp27unqz64atz2jw3k46hw5pit2o2hkpzqymjxyon2ripoisydm" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:obrzujbni72zof5lfxpaxc4i/app.bsky.feed.post/3lk5p2iwlhk2y"><div lang="en"><p>This is what I've been quiet about. I'm not SAG but what game companies want to do with AI is an existential threat. I took a personal stand to ask for protection, and had to be willing to give up the best thing that's ever happened in my professional life. I stand by my choice.</p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:obrzujbni72zof5lfxpaxc4i/post/3lk5p2iwlhk2y?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p></div>— Nicholas Thurkettle - Voice Actor (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:obrzujbni72zof5lfxpaxc4i?ref_src=embed">@nthurkettle.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:obrzujbni72zof5lfxpaxc4i/post/3lk5p2iwlhk2y?ref_src=embed">12 March 2025 at 04:01</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>Eurogamer has contacted HoYoverse for further comment.</p>
<p>Today, Eurogamer reported the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sag-aftra-actors-strike-set-to-continue-as-union-warns-of-alarming-loopholes-for-ai-abuse-in-latest-proposal">strike from US actors' union SAG-AFTRA remains ongoing</a> as it warns of "alarming loopholes" for "AI abuse" in the latest proposal.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/us-video-game-performers-are-striking-over-ongoing-ai-concerns">strike began back in July last year</a>, with the main sticking point being the need to protect actors from AI abuse.</p>
<p>While some actors are still working despite the strike, Chase and Thurkettle's situation is a clear example of the risk actors are taking to protect their livelihoods as the dispute continues.</p>
<p>Today the union urged performers to "seriously consider the consequences" of working with game producers at this time, not only in undermining the strike but opening performers to AI misuse.</p>
<p>In related news, HoYoverse announced actor Showtaro Morikubo will no longer voice Ifa in the Japanese version of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/genshin-impact">Genshin Impact</a>.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/Genshin_7/status/1899664144800080249">social media announcement</a>, the company stated "due to various circumstances" the actors has "been forced to withdraw from the project".</p>
<p>While no further details have been given, <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/genshin-impact-ifa-japanese-voice-actor-suddenly-changed-fans-speculate-that-the-reason-is-political/">Automaton</a> reports fans are speculating it may be due to Morikubo appearing in a live reading back in 2024 called Inochigake no Shougen (Life-risking Testimonies), based on a book of the same name which contains testimonies of Uyghur people. The book likens the Chinese government's treatment of the Uyghur to the suppression and genocide of Jewish people by the Nazi party.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Netflix gaming boss departs, following move to AI role]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/former-netflix-gaming-boss-departs-following-move-to-ai-role</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-netflix-gaming-boss-departs-following-move-to-ai-role.1132074/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/former-netflix-gaming-boss-departs-following-move-to-ai-role<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Had said changes were part of "planned transition".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_j7FlaK0.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Netflix</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Netflix's first gaming boss has left the company, following a shift in role and various changes behind the scenes last year.
</p>
<p>
Mike Verdu launched and led Netflix's gaming efforts in 2021, but was <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/netflixs-mike-verdu-reveals-new-role-as-vp-of-genai-for-games">moved to a new role - VP of Generative AI for games at Netflix</a> - in November last year. At the time, Verdu said peers should "pay no mind to uninformed speculation in the media about changes at Netflix Games", as the changes were a "planned transition".
</p>
<p>
Now, Verdu has departed the company entirely, <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/netflix-mike-verdu-exit-gdc">Game File</a> has reported.
</p>
<p>
The move follows a number of shifts behind the scenes last year, including the hiring of gaming industry veteran Alain Tascan to serve as Verdu's replacement as gaming boss.
</p>
<p>
In October 2024, Netflix closed a major internal game studio led by Halo creative head Joseph Staten, and scrapped its big-budget project before it was ever announced.
</p>
<p>
By January, <a href="https://www.whats-on-netflix.com/news/netflix-abandons-release-plans-for-6-games-including-tales-of-the-shire-dont-starve-together-and-compass-point-west/?utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email">Netflix had reportedly dropped at least six other game projects</a> it was planning to publish - including cosy Hobbit sim Tales of the Shire: A Lord of the Rings Game, which will now <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tales-of-the-shire-delayed-yet-again">launch at a later date without the streaming company's involvement</a>.
</p>
<p>
And in February this year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-culls-staff-at-oxenfree-developer-night-school-studio">Netflix cut staff at Oxenfree developer Night School Studio</a>. No announcement was made on how many jobs were lost, or what the studio was working on next.
</p>
<p>
As Netflix reorganises its plans, it remains unclear how its gaming focus will look going forward - other than Verdu will not be part of it.
</p>
<p>
Last month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-is-hiking-prices-again-but-most-of-europe-has-escaped-for-now">Netflix celebrated its biggest quarterly subscriber increase in history</a> by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-celebrates-its-biggest-quarter-yet-by-putting-uk-prices-up-again">increasing its prices yet again</a>, including here in the UK.
</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego "building up" in-house game development]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/lego-building-up-in-house-game-development</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-building-up-in-house-game-development.1132053/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/lego-building-up-in-house-game-development<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2025-03-12-110104.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Lego / Epic Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Lego is working to build up its in-house game development, the company's boss has revealed. 
</p>
<p>
Speaking to <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/2f4944f4-8255-4115-8838-d2bde03588cf">The Financial Times</a>, Lego boss Niels Christiansen said the company was increasing its focus on video game experiences created by its own teams, following years of partnerships with outside companies. 
</p>
<p>
"We can definitely say, as long as we're under the Lego brand, we can cover experiences for kids of all ages, digital or physical," Christiansen said. "[In-house game development] is something we're building up. We have made quite a few investments in the future – I'd almost rather overinvest. That's the benefit of being family-owned and long term."
</p>
<p>
For over a decade, Lego games were mostly made by British studio TT Games, with a popular tie-in to a big movie franchise released every year.
</p>
<p>
For 15 years, TT Games pumped out dozens of annual Lego games with a familiar formula, based on Star Wars, Harry Potter, Marvel and DC characters. It also mounted the ambitious toys-to-life effort <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/lego-dimensions">Lego Dimensions</a>. 
</p>
<p>
But that era of Lego gaming is largely over, with only one entry - <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/lego-star-wars-the-skywalker-saga">Lego Star Wars: The Skywalker Saga</a> - in the past six years. TT Games is reportedly still working on a further title, but it is not expected in 2025.
</p>
<p>
Since then, Lego has licensed its brand to a wider set of developers - most notably <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> maker Epic Games, and the recent launch of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lego-horizon-adventures-review">Lego Horizon Adventures</a>, co-developed by Guerilla Games and published by Sony. Fortnite now has a deep integration with Lego, with minifigure versions of most of its digital skins, two large Lego game modes, and countless mini-games made by Lego itself and fans.
</p>
<p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/lego-fortnite">Lego Fortnite</a>, now rebranded to Lego Fortnite Odyssey, is a Minecraft-y offering regularly played by around 50,000 people concurrently within the main Fortnite client. Last December, the company also <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lego-fortnite-brick-life-is-a-major-new-social-game-mode-that-sounds-a-bit-like-the-sims">launched Lego Fortnite Brick Life</a>, a gentle life sim and house decoration game, to a smaller audience.
</p>
<p>
For now, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-weve-been-playing-lego-horror-cheerful-games-and-others-we-just-cant-get-into">The Lego Group has a small team of designers building and launching game concepts within Fortnite</a>, which now has an impressive replication of Lego bricks and physics baked into Epic's Unreal Engine. It'll be interesting to see what's next, as the wait for TT Games' next old-school Lego game continues.
</p>
<p>"I hope it will never be done," head of Lego gaming at The Lego Group Remi Marcelli told Eurogamer last year, of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-future-of-lego-fortnite-i-hope-it-will-never-be-done">the company's big Fortnite mode, which continues to expand</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Ubisoft execs stand trial in France, accused of harassment]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/former-ubisoft-execs-stand-trial-in-france-accused-of-harassment</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-ubisoft-execs-stand-trial-in-france-accused-of-harassment.1132038/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/former-ubisoft-execs-stand-trial-in-france-accused-of-harassment<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Fresh details surface on bosses who left company in 2020.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2025-01-27-152746.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ubisoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Three top Ubisoft employees have appeared in a French court, accused of harassing employees before their departure from the company almost five years ago.
</p>
<p>
The trio includes Serge Hascoet, Ubisoft's previous chief creative officer and right-hand man to company boss Yves Guillemot, plus the former VP of editorial and creative services Tommy Francois, and Guillaume Patrux, a game designer and director.
</p>
<p>
All three deny sexually and psychologically harassing and humiliating employees during their tenures at the company, up until <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/three-more-top-ubisoft-executives-resign-as-publisher-renews-commitment-to-fostering-an-environment-its-employees-can-be-proud-of">they resigned or were dismissed in 2020</a>.
</p>
<p>
Details discussed during the court appearance this week (thanks, <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20250310-former-ubisoft-bosses-on-trial-in-france-over-alleged-harassment-1">France24</a>) include accusations of racist comments and behaviour by Hascoet, who allegedly asked a Muslim employee if she agreed with the Islamic State terrorist group in the wake of the 2015 Paris terrorist attack. It's alleged that the same staff member had their computer desktop wallpaper changed to that of bacon, and had food placed on their desk during the fasting month of Ramadan.
</p>
<p>
A string of allegations concerning Francois includes him having regularly watched porn in the company's open-plan office, kissing colleagues, and remarking on their appearance by calling them "ugly" or a "slut". Francois specifically is accused of sexual assault for allegedly forcing himself on a young employee during a Christmas party. He also allegedly forced a young employee to perform a headstand while wearing a skirt.
</p>
<p>
Patrux, meanwhile, stands accused of psychological harassment.
</p>
<p>
The trial has now been adjourned until 2nd June after lawyers complained they had not been given long enough with the case's documentation.
</p>
<p>
Eurogamer has contacted Ubisoft for comment. 
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>