<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 21:06:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead by Daylight's Hellraiser DLC is getting yanked from sale soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-by-daylights-hellraiser-dlc-is-getting-yanked-from-sale-soon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dead-by-daylights-hellraiser-dlc-is-getting-yanked-from-sale-soon.1125324/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-by-daylights-hellraiser-dlc-is-getting-yanked-from-sale-soon<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Another one Cenobites the dust.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/pinhead-yank.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer/Behaviour Interactive</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Dead by <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/deadlight">Deadlight</a> is waving goodbye to a horror icon. Developer Behaviour Interactive has announced Pinhead - and his Hellraiser Chapter DLC - is being yanked from sale on 4th April. 
</p>
<p>
Pinhead <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-by-daylight-teasing-hellraiser-additions-removing-stranger-things-dlc-in-november">joined the Dead by Daylight roster</a> back in September 2021, following in the footsteps of other legends of horror including Halloween's Michael Myers, Nightmare on Elm Street's Freddy Krueger, and Texas Chainsaw Massacre's Leatherface.
</p>
<p>
As Hellraiser might have it though, where there's pleasure, there's also pain, and Pinhead - AKA The Cenobite - is shuffling back to his corner of Hell early next month, taking his fancy box of torment with him. As <a href="https://deadbydaylight.com/news/hellraiser-last-chance-sale/">explained in Behaviour's announcement</a>, however, he's only retreating from digital store fronts - existing owners can continue playing with old needle-bonce after 4th April, but no new purchases of the Hellraiser Chapter DLC will be possible.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dead by Daylight | Hellraiser | Official Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WhhO7o-5KjA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dead by Daylight | Hellraiser | Official Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WhhO7o-5KjA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WhhO7o-5KjA?autoplay=1" title="Dead by Daylight | Hellraiser | Official Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Dead by Daylight - Hellraiser trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WhhO7o-5KjA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
If that news has suddenly spurred you into a last-minute FOMO purchase, it's additionally worth noting the Hellraiser DLC is being removed from first-party digital stores from today, 4th March (with the exception of Switch's eShop, which says goodbye to Pinhead on 18th March), but it'll still be available to purchase via <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dead-by-daylight">Dead by Daylight</a>'s in-game store until 4pm GMT on 4th April. And to encourage a few final purchases ahead of the Hellraiser Chapter's removal, Behaviour is discounting The Cenobite and his Cosmetics by 50 precent in Dead by Daylight's store.
</p>
<p>
Behaviour hasn't explained <em>why</em> the DLC is being removed from sale (its <a href="https://forums.bhvr.com/dead-by-daylight/kb/articles/493-faq-the-hellraiser-content">official FAQ</a> goes with the line, "As with all Live-Service Games frequent updates and additions are to be expected"), but the answer is almost certainly licensing-related. Dead by Daylights's Stranger Things DLC was similarly withdrawn in 2019, although that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stranger-things-returns-to-dead-by-daylight">did eventually return</a>, implying Pinhead could also be back - if only Behaviour's legal team can solve that pesky Lament Configuration.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation wants help testing games and features using new Beta Program initiative]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-wants-help-testing-games-and-features-using-new-beta-program-initiative</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-wants-help-testing-games-and-features-using-new-beta-program-initiative.1125195/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-wants-help-testing-games-and-features-using-new-beta-program-initiative<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Single "centralised" hub now open.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/peter-parker-ps5.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer/PlayStation</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Sony has launched a new "centralised" Beta Program initiative for PlayStation, providing an easy way for the public to sign up help test PlayStation 5 and PC games, as well as various console and app features, ahead of their full release.
</p>
<p>
Sony describes PlayStation's Beta Program as a "easy, centralised place" where players can register to participate in a range of different betas. These are expected to include beta access to PlayStation 5 and PC games, PlayStation 5 console features, PlayStation App features, and even features for Sony's PlayStation website. Anyone interested in participating only needs to sign up once - invites will be send out automatically if a registered user is selected for a specific test, and they're then free to accept or decline that invition as they see fit.
</p>
<p>
"While we try to include as many players as possible in our beta programs," Sony explains in its <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/03/04/registration-for-new-beta-program-at-playstation-starts-today/">announcement on the PlayStation Blog</a>, "sometimes we may get more interest than we can accommodate. By joining this program, it enables you to be considered for beta participation, but it doesn't guarantee selection for a beta test."
</p>
<figure></figure>
<p>
Players can <a href="https://www.playstation.com/beta-program-at-playstation/">sign up via the 'Beta Program at PlayStation' website</a>, but Sony notes a PlayStation Network account is required and must be in good standing with a current email address. Additionally, participants must meet the legal age requirement in their region, and can only participate when a specific beta test is available in that region.
</p>
<p>
"A big thanks to those of you who have participated in all of the betas we've offered across Sony Interactive over the years," it concludes. "It's about to get easier and more convenient."
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>