<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 15:07:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Angry Birds maker and Sega delay Sonic Rumble release once again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/angry-birds-maker-and-sega-delay-sonic-rumble-release-once-again</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/angry-birds-maker-and-sega-delay-sonic-rumble-release-once-again.1177494/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/angry-birds-maker-and-sega-delay-sonic-rumble-release-once-again<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sega has delayed the global launch of Sonic Rumble, the mobile and PC party game from <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/angry-birds">Angry Birds</a> maker Rovio.</p>
<p>The Sonic Rumble team said "upcoming changes" such as its Rumble Ranking, Crews and Skills features will " fundamentally reshape" the game, and as such it will be postponing the release.</p>
<p>"We want to create a game that evolves and stays fun for months and years to come. To build the kind of high-quality, long-lasting Sonic game our players deserve, we need more time," <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/segas-mobile-party-game-sonic-rumble-lands-release-date">Sega wrote on Steam</a>.</p>
<p>"We know this news may be disappointing, and it wasn't a decision we made lightly. We at Sega share that disappointment, especially because we're making this call so close to the launch timing we had originally hoped for. However, we believe taking this extra time is the right choice for the future of Sonic Rumble."</p>
<p>At the time of writing, Sega has not announced a new launch date for Sonic Rumble, and its sales page simply reads the game is coming "soon".</p>
<p>In the meantime, the team will host a Q&amp;A over on its Discord channel on 2nd May at 2pm UK time. Here, it'll "answer your questions about the new features, the delay, the next steps, and more".</p>
<p>Sonic Rumble will be Rovio's first brand new game since the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sega-buys-angry-birds-maker-rovio-for-625m">studio was acquired by Sega in 2023</a> for £625m. It's a free-to-play battle royale game where up to 32 players collect rings (I mean, this is a Sonic title, after all) in competitive rounds like those seen in fellow party game <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fall-guys">Fall Guys</a>.</p>
<p>The title was initially set to make its debut sometime during the winter, but this was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sonic-rumble-segas-mobile-party-game-from-angry-birds-studio-delayed-into-spring">delayed until an unspecified spring release window</a>. Earlier this month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/segas-mobile-party-game-sonic-rumble-lands-release-date">Sega and Rovio set a release date of 8th May</a>, which is - obviously - no longer happening.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stardew Valley creator promises no more updates until Haunted Chocolatier releases]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-creator-promises-no-more-updates-until-haunted-chocolatier-releases</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stardew-valley-creator-promises-no-more-updates-until-haunted-chocolatier-releases.1177491/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-creator-promises-no-more-updates-until-haunted-chocolatier-releases<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Knew you were truffle when you walked in.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>ConcernedApe/Cadbury/Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Solo developer Eric 'ConcernedApe' Barone says he's "committed to not working on Stardew Valley" until he's "done with Haunted Chocolatier"... but, other updates will probably still come after.</p>
<p>Pixelated farming sim Stardew Valley first debuted almost a decade ago, and has since gone from strength to strength. Last year, Barone released Stardew Valley's bumper 1.6 update, which essentially boosted the game to an almost 2.0 status, introducing a vast number of features to the base game such as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valleys-16-update-is-finally-here-with-some-impressively-lengthy-patch-notes">new NPC dialogues, home renovations and turtle pets</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Let's Play Stardew Valley Multiplayer - THE ONE WHERE JOHNNY EATS AN EGG!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pLHH6x87k6U?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Let's Play Stardew Valley Multiplayer - THE ONE WHERE JOHNNY EATS AN EGG!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pLHH6x87k6U?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/pLHH6x87k6U?autoplay=1" title="Let's Play Stardew Valley Multiplayer - THE ONE WHERE JOHNNY EATS AN EGG!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Let's Play Stardew Valley Multiplayer - THE ONE WHERE JOHNNY EATS AN EGG! <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pLHH6x87k6U" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In addition to Stardew Valley, Barone is also working on his next game, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-creator-reveals-haunted-chocolatier">Haunted Chocolatier, which he announced in 2021</a>. In May of last year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-creator-wont-rush-haunted-chocolatier-better-to-have-a-good-delayed-game-than-a-bad-game-on-time">Barone said he's "not too concerned with the pressure" of releasing Haunted Chocolatier</a>, stating "it's better to have a delayed game that's actually good than a bad game that's on time".</p>
<p>But, while he may not be concerned about the pressure, he of course still does want to get Haunted Chocolatier out there at some point. So, now that the dust is settling on Stardew Valley's 1.6 update, he is shifting his focus over to his next release.</p>
<p>"I do love Stardew Valley and I care about the fans and I want the fans to have a great experience," Barone told <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/life-sim/after-getting-stardew-valley-to-a-good-place-with-update-1-6-eric-barone-is-now-fully-focused-on-his-next-game-im-committed-to-not-working-on-stardew-valley-until-im-done-with-haunted-chocolatier/">PC Gamer</a> during GDC. "So I'm always concerned with Stardew Valley and making sure that it's doing well, and that pulls me away from devoting all my time to Haunted Chocolatier.</p>
<p>"I think at some point I'm going to have to completely cut off everything else. Honestly, I've thought about, maybe I should just go into a cabin in the woods and completely get off the internet, and just say, 'Okay guys, I'll see you in two years. You won't hear from me at all and I'm going to finish this game'."</p>
<p>The developer added he is currently "committed to not working on Stardew Valley until I'm done with Haunted Chocolatier", stating that his farming sim is now in "a good place" for players old and new.</p>
<p>"I think if anyone picks up Stardew Valley for the first time in 2025, I'm very proud of it, and I think they'll have fun with it if they like this kind of game," Barone said. He also noted that he doesn't think he will ever be able to "completely cut off" Stardew Valley, except for maybe when he "[passes] away". Then, we can say the "book is closed". This <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-creator-says-he-doesnt-want-to-definitively-close-the-book-on-its-development-even-12-years-on">echoes comments Barone has made before</a>.</p>
<p>Continuing, Barone said he has been working on Haunted Chocolatier for "a few years", and now "it's like, I look at some of the stuff I did at the beginning and I'm like, 'Oh man, here we go again. I'm gonna have to redo all of this'".</p>
<p>This doesn't mean Barone thinks what he has done is bad, by any means. It's just that, "part of the problem of being, like especially a solo dev, is it takes so long to make a game". Barone said he is "literally a different person in four years", and so his opinions and feelings change.</p>
<p>"My aesthetic sensibilities have evolved," he said. Later, he joked about adding a dentist to Haunted Chocolatier's village, as well as healthy superfood chocs to savour. You can check out the full interview below.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Eric Barone talks Stardew Valley &amp; Haunted Chocolatier | ConcernedApe Interview" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/olf3wAuCfeU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Eric Barone talks Stardew Valley &amp; Haunted Chocolatier | ConcernedApe Interview</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/olf3wAuCfeU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/olf3wAuCfeU?autoplay=1" title="Eric Barone talks Stardew Valley &amp; Haunted Chocolatier | ConcernedApe Interview">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Eric Barone talks Stardew Valley &amp; Haunted Chocolatier | ConcernedApe Interview. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=olf3wAuCfeU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In January of this year, Barone revealed that, as of December last year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-continues-its-wholesome-farming-dominance-with-latest-sales-milestone">Stardew Valley had sold in excess of 41m copies across platforms</a>. Of those 41m, over half are on PC, with 26m copies sold. Meanwhile, the Nintendo Switch accounts for 7.9m Stardew Valley sales.</p>
<p>If you still fancy more Stardew Valley news, a new concert <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stardew-valley-symphony-of-seasons-concert-tour-announced-coming-to-the-uk-in-2026">known as Symphony of Seasons</a> was announced in November. The concert tour will be coming to the UK in 2026.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>