<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 15:06:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Man's Sky gets storm-ravaged gas giants and "trillions of new planets" in another major overhaul]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/no-mans-sky-gets-storm-ravaged-gas-giants-and-trillions-of-new-planets-in-another-major-overhaul</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-mans-sky-gets-storm-ravaged-gas-giants-and-trillions-of-new-planets-in-another-major-overhaul.1094715/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/no-mans-sky-gets-storm-ravaged-gas-giants-and-trillions-of-new-planets-in-another-major-overhaul<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Worlds Part 2 update out now.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/no-mans-sky-worlds-part-2-gas-giants.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Hello Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
If you thought Hello Games might be slowing down as <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/no-mans-sky">No Man's Sky</a> approaches its ninth birthday this year, think again. The studio is already back with another update for its ever-evolving exploratory space sim, and this one's an absolute whopper - expanding its virtual universe with "billions of new stars and planets", including fearsome gas giants.
</p>
<p>
Officially, today's release continues the work started in last year's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/no-mans-skys-borrows-some-of-light-no-fires-fancy-tech-for-a-planetary-overhaul-in-latest-update">Worlds Part 1 update</a> (its name, Worlds Part 2, kind of gives the game away), introducing a fresh batch of features and system overhauls contributing to an expansive universe refresh. That starts with Hello Games' new terrain generation system - borne from its work on the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/no-mans-sky-studio-unveils-procedural-fantasy-planet-adventure-light-no-fire">upcoming Light No Fire</a>) - promising "more detailed" and "far more varied" landscapes. Players can expect huge mountains and dramatic vistas, with a range of new biomes bringing their own distinctive features.
</p>
<p>
Oceans, too, have had a substantial overhaul intended to make them more realistic. Large bodies of water can now be several kilometres deep, for instance, and benefit from improved lighting and new visual effects, with Hello Games highlighting its new caustics and light shafts, alongside oceans that become much darker the deeper players explore. And once down in the depths, there are apparently some extremely weird creatures to be found.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="No Man's Sky Worlds Part II Update Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/75bfyy-XkQg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>No Man's Sky Worlds Part II Update Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/75bfyy-XkQg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/75bfyy-XkQg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>No Man's Sky - Worlds Part 2 trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=75bfyy-XkQg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Hello Games also says No Man's Sky's completely rewritten lighting engine has led to more detailed shadows, light that flickers through leaves, and much darker and more ambient caves. Additionally, water can now reflect the skies and stars, and reacts physically to the world around it - surging as huge ships fly overhead or rippling gently in the rain.
</p><p>
And that's before we get to those aforementioned gas giants - massive spheres said to be ten times bigger than No Man's Sky's previous biggest planet. Players brave enough to venture down to their deeply unstable cores will face raging storms featuring new weather hazards - and can expect an experience Hello calls "truly end-game stuff". Additionally, today's update introduces a "huge" new quest tying together various story strands No Man's Sky has been building over the last nine years, alongside the likes of improved cooking, a new Colossus Refiner, and - for those with an insatiable urge to hoard ships - starship archiving.
</p>
<p>
Furthermore, No Man's Sky is launching its next limited-time Expedition (titled Titan) in the coming weeks, giving players the chance to acquire a rare new living starship. First, however, Hello will be wrapping up the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/no-mans-skys-limited-time-expeditions-are-making-a-return-over-the-next-two-months">Redux version of last year's The Cursed expedition</a>, which is due to conclude next week. Full details of No Man's Sky's Worlds Part 2 update can be found in <a href="https://www.nomanssky.com/worlds-part-ii-update">today's patch notes</a>, and there's also a <a href="https://youtu.be/2lG2DTjP-_M">deep dive developer video</a> to accompany the release.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 remake passes another sales milestone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-passes-another-sales-milestone</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-remake-passes-another-sales-milestone.1094670/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-passes-another-sales-milestone<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>2m copies shifted in three months.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Silent-Hill-2-Review-1-14-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Konami</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/bloober-team">Bloober Team</a>'s brilliant <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-2-remake">Silent Hill 2 Remake</a> has sold more than 2m copies, publisher Konami announced today.
</p>
<p>
Silent Hill 2 Remake arrived on 8th October 2024 for PC and PlayStation 5, and quickly shifted a million units over its opening weekend. As of 23rd January, last week, the game has now sold another million copies.
</p>
<p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-2">Silent Hill 2</a> has been a breakout success for Konami and Polish developer Bloober Team, which previously was best known for other horror games such as its <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/layers-of-fear">Layers of Fear</a> series and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-medium">The Medium</a>. Next up from the developer will be fresh project based on a new IP, as well as the mysterious "Project R" set to be published by Skybound Entertainment.  
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Eurogamer's Silent Hill 2 review, in video form.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vOv1JTfPnuQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Two months after launch, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fan-cracks-mysterious-silent-hill-2-remake-photo-puzzle-revealing-secret-message-hidden-by-bloober-team">fans finally cracked a mysterious photo puzzle found hidden in Silent Hill 2 Remake</a>, revealing a chilling message from Bloober Team's development team.
</p>
<p>
"Against the odds, Bloober Team has delivered a remake that both expands the original game in just the right places, and gives careful attention to what it preserves," Vikki Blake wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-review">Eurogamer's Silent Hill 2 Remake review</a>.
</p>
<p>"It doesn't matter if you've never played Silent Hill 2 before. It also doesn't matter if you have. Silent Hill 2 Remake's heady blend of old and new delivers the best horror I've played for years."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation's Xbox baseball game ditches Game Pass]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/playstations-xbox-baseball-game-ditches-game-pass</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstations-xbox-baseball-game-ditches-game-pass.1094661/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/playstations-xbox-baseball-game-ditches-game-pass<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/mlb-the-show-25-cover.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>PlayStation / Xbox</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
MLB The Show 25 will skip its usual launch via Xbox Game Pass for the first time in years. 
</p>
<p>
The officially-licensed baseball game is notable for being <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mlb-the-show-22-is-a-playstation-game-for-xbox-and-nintendo-switch-box">PlayStation's only franchise to launch on Xbox consoles and turn up day one on Game Pass</a>. This year's entry, however, will skip Microsoft's subscription service <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-owners-have-to-fork-out-full-price-for-the-sony-developed-mlb-the-show-21-but-xbox-owners-get-it-day-one-via-game-pass">for the first time since 2021</a>. 
</p>
<p>
"The game will not be on platform subscription services in 2025," a note from Sony on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/01/28/mlb-the-show-25-cover-athletes-revealed-paul-skenes-elly-de-la-cruz-and-gunnar-henderson/">PlayStation blog</a> states, ruling it out of appearing on PlayStation Plus either.
</p>
<p>
MLB The Show 25 is also notable for being the first in the series to ditch support for PlayStation 4 and Xbox One. A Nintendo Switch version is still being released, however.
</p>
<p>
Sony has said it will reveal more about the game ahead of its launch on 18th March for all platforms. If you're really keen for this year's entry sooner, you can pay an unspecified amount extra for the game's Digital Deluxe Edition and start playing on 14th March instead.
</p>
<p>Despite regularly launching PlayStation games on PC, Sony's support of rival console platforms is still a rarity -  though last year did also see the arrival of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/lego-horizon-adventures">Lego Horizon Adventures</a> on Nintendo Switch (but not Xbox Series X/S).</p>
<p>Speaking to Eurogamer last year, Former PlayStation Studios boss Shawn Layden said <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/there-comes-a-time-when-we-all-declare-the-war-is-over-former-playstation-studios-boss-shawn-layden-on-the-future-of-video-game-consoles">there would be a time "when we all declare the war is over" between console makers</a> - though he also didn't expect to see Sony first-party games arrive on Xbox any time soon.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>