<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 14:23:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox has made "largest investment in Game Pass to date" this year, countering recent criticism of subscription service's value]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-has-made-largest-investment-in-game-pass-to-date-this-year-countering-recent-criticism-of-subscription-services-value</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-has-made-largest-investment-in-game-pass-to-date-this-year-countering-recent-criticism-of-subscription-services-value.1304232/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"We continue to engage with hundreds of partners each year."</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silksong-clairobscur-xbox-game-pass.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silksong-clairobscur-xbox-game-pass.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silksong-clairobscur-xbox-game-pass.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silksong-clairobscur-xbox-game-pass.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/silksong-clairobscur-xbox-game-pass.png?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>This year has marked Xbox's "largest investment in Game Pass to date", according to ID@Xbox boss Chris Charla.</p>
<p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/inside-xboxs-increasingly-vital-indie-publishing-operation">Eurogamer</a>, Charla discussed the current state of the subscription service in the face of recent criticism, noting positive sentiment from developers and a desire to return for future projects.</p>
<p>"The majority of partners who've had a game in Game Pass want to bring their future titles to the service," said Charla. "As a result, we've signed deals with more than 150 partners to expand the catalogue. We continue to engage with hundreds of partners each year to review upcoming titles.</p>
<p>"Last year, we worked with over 50 teams to sign their first Game Pass deal. This year marks our largest investment in Game Pass to date, and we remain focused on delivering the most exciting and diverse catalogue in gaming."</p>
<p>Xbox has received criticism for Game Pass in recent months. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arkane-studios-founder-calls-game-pass-unsustainable-model-and-one-which-is-damaging-the-industry">Arkane Studios founder Raphael Colantonio</a> described the service as "an unsustainable model that has been increasingly damaging the industry for a decade".</p>
<p>In a back and forth on social media on the "cannibalisation" of sales, Larian director of publishing Michael Douse added "smaller teams with new or riskier" games can benefit from Game Pass, but he prefers "Sony's 'lifecycle management'" method of adding games following initial sales.</p><p>Former PlayStation boss Shawn Layden discussed the perceived profitability of Game Pass in a discussion with <a href="http://gamesindustry.biz/">GamesIndustry.biz</a>. "There's a lot of debates going on," he said. "Is Game Pass profitable? Is Game Pass not profitable? What does that mean? That's really not the right question to ask anyway.</p>
<p>"You can do all kinds of financial jiggery-pokery for any sort of corporate service to make it look profitable if you wanted to. You take enough costs out and say that's off the balance sheet and, oh look, it's profitable now. The real issue for me on things like Game Pass is, is it healthy for the developer?"</p>
<p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/football-manager-player-numbers-are-through-the-roof-thanks-to-subscription-platforms-like-game-pass-and-netflix-series-boss-miles-jacobson-explains-how">Football Manager boss Miles Jacobson recently told Eurogamer</a> player numbers for the series have skyrocketed since being added to subscription platforms. </p>
<p>"We built a whole business model around it," he said. "You can't just turn around and do this - this was before we launched on the subscription platforms, we'd been talking about it. And we'd been working out what we were going to do for five years - it was a five-year journey before we went with the first experiment, and then we did another experiment, and then we did another experiment, and then we learned from those experiments, and that's when the full strategy was put in place."</p><p>In a broader interview with Eurogamer on the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/inside-xboxs-increasingly-vital-indie-publishing-operation">state of indie games on Xbox</a>, Charla noted the breadth of games showcased by Xbox at <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-at-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024">Gamescom</a>. "It is just really a recognition by Xbox of the absolute crucial need for diversity in our portfolio," he said.</p>



        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-has-made-largest-investment-in-game-pass-to-date-this-year-countering-recent-criticism-of-subscription-services-value]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Perfect Dark reboot leak: fresh info suggests studio saw gap in the market with Metal Gear Solid and Bond absent]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/perfect-dark-reboot-leak-fresh-info-suggests-studio-saw-gap-in-the-market-with-metal-gear-solid-and-bond-absent</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/perfect-dark-reboot-leak-fresh-info-suggests-studio-saw-gap-in-the-market-with-metal-gear-solid-and-bond-absent.1304187/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Fresh artwork and gameplay unearthed.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/perfect-dark-reboot-joanna.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/perfect-dark-reboot-joanna.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/perfect-dark-reboot-joanna.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/perfect-dark-reboot-joanna.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/perfect-dark-reboot-joanna.png?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Xbox</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The now-cancelled Perfect Dark reboot had an "eco sci-fi" aesthetic, an Adrenaline System, and may have been released episodically.</p>
<p>That's according to internal documentation from a former developer on the project at The Initiative shared with <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/gameplay-details-concept-screens-cancelled-perfect-dark-reboot">mp1st</a>, revealing new artwork and gameplay details.</p>
<p>The document highlighted an opportunity to capitalise on the secret agent genre, due to the absence of Metal Gear Solid and James Bond 007 during development. Ironically enough, both franchises have since returned.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Perfect Dark - Gameplay Reveal - Xbox Games Showcase 2024" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ofUi9DR9sc4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Perfect Dark - Gameplay Reveal - Xbox Games Showcase 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ofUi9DR9sc4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ofUi9DR9sc4?autoplay=1" title="Perfect Dark - Gameplay Reveal - Xbox Games Showcase 2024">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Perfect Dark - Gameplay Reveal - Xbox Games Showcase 2024<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ofUi9DR9sc4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>This may somewhat point to why <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/perfect-dark-reboot-and-new-zenimax-mmorpg-reportedly-cancelled-as-part-of-latest-microsoft-cuts">Perfect Dark was ultimately cancelled</a> - perhaps this reboot of the N64 classic from Rare wasn't able to differentiate itself enough.</p>
<p>Still, this newly unearthed documentation - which dates back to a period close to the game's cancellation this year - hints as to what players could have expected. The creative vision for the reboot aimed to reimagine the franchise while retaining the core DNA of the N64 original, with the HBO series Westworld providing inspiration for giving a classic property fresh themes and concepts.</p><p>While several systems are briefly mentioned, only the Adrenaline System is detailed. This would've been a resource regenerated over time to provide various abilities like healing and increasing damage dealt, as well as slowing time to aim with precision. Killing multiple enemies in quick succession would have extended this effect.</p>
<p>Until April of this year, the studio was working on a vertical slice (a playable proof-of-concept) that belonged to "Season 1", suggesting the game would have been released episodically.</p>
<p>Perfect Dark was properly revealed at last year's Xbox Games Showcase, with in-game footage of protagonist Joanna Dark exploring a futuristic Cairo (above). Later,<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ethangach.bsky.social/post/3lsypye2edk2v"> reports suggested this gameplay was fake</a>, though a <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/adammcdlt.bsky.social/post/3lt23bz2dwk2z">designer on the game responded</a> it was in-engine despite "some fake stuff in it".</p>
<p>The new documentation includes further artwork for the game, including an alternate design for Joanna, as well as various futuristic environments to show off its "eco sci-fi" aesthetic.</p>
<p>Perfect Dark was cancelled back in July, following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-begins-substantial-layoff-process-across-gaming-division-king-and-zenimax-impacted">layoffs across Microsoft</a>. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rares-everwild-reportedly-cancelled-following-xbox-job-cuts">Rare's Everwild was also cancelled</a>.</p>



        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/perfect-dark-reboot-leak-fresh-info-suggests-studio-saw-gap-in-the-market-with-metal-gear-solid-and-bond-absent]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>