<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 17:29:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[That's that Sabrina Carpenter joining Fortnite]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/thats-that-sabrina-carpenter-joining-fortnite</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/thats-that-sabrina-carpenter-joining-fortnite.1157466/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/thats-that-sabrina-carpenter-joining-fortnite<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
The next popstar joining <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> is Sabrina Carpenter, the Grammy-winning artist behind Espresso, Taste and Please Please Please.
</p>
<p>
Carpenter will become the next star of Fortnite Festival, complete with her own skins, musical battle pass and tracks to play in the game's Guitar Hero-esque mode.
</p>
<p>
Her arrival follows a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-hatsune-miku-crossover-coming-leaks-suggest">season headlined by Japanese virtual popstar Hatsune Miku</a>, and follows previous artists such as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/three-years-on-from-lady-gagas-infamous-tweet-fortnite-fans-think-a-concert-is-really-happening">Lady Gaga</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/more-than-10m-fortnite-players-watch-snoop-dogg-ice-spice-headline-concert-streamed-live-from-times-square">Snoop Dogg</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/billie-eilish-coming-to-fortnite-adding-weight-to-a-much-discussed-leak">Billie Eilish</a>.
</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
The upcoming Music Pass will include Carpenter's tracks Juno and Nonsense, as well as a skin you can then use throughout Fortnite. So, yes, Carpenter will soon be able to crank 90s alongside Jonesy, Peely and Fishstick.
</p>
<p>
Fun fact: Fortnite is actually Carpenter's second video game appearance, after previously popping up in 2011's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/just-dance-kids">Just Dance Kids</a> 2 as a coach.
</p>
<p>
Fortnite's main battle royale mode is a few weeks away from finishing its current season. Persistent internet whispers suggest something different will arrive on its Island next: a shorter mini-season entirely dedicated to Star Wars.  
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo eShop music won't be returning for Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-eshop-music-wont-be-returning-for-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-eshop-music-wont-be-returning-for-switch-2.1157337/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-eshop-music-wont-be-returning-for-switch-2<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sorry fans of the Nintendo shop music circa the Wii era, but we won't be getting a catchy jingle to shop along to on the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2</a>'s release this summer. And it doesn't seem likely the music will be coming back in the future either.</p>
<p>According to Nintendo Switch 2 producer Kouichi Kawamoto, there is a very sound (no pun intended) reason for not having music on the storefront. In short, nowadays many of the titles listed on the eShop have videos accompanying them, which showcase gameplay to potential customers, and Nintendo "didn't want to intrude on that".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Donkey Kong Bananza Hands-On Preview: Is It Good?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jri6l4Tz8xI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Donkey Kong Bananza Hands-On Preview: Is It Good?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jri6l4Tz8xI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/jri6l4Tz8xI?autoplay=1" title="Donkey Kong Bananza Hands-On Preview: Is It Good?">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Donkey Kong Bananza Hands-On Preview: Is It Good? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jri6l4Tz8xI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>So quite simply, "we don't have music there" Kawamoto told <a href="https://www.polygon.com/nintendo-switch-2/553440/nintendo-eshop-no-music-switch-2-why">Polygon</a>, although the Switch 2 producer did add that he still gets the Wii Shopping Channel music stuck in his head. He said he "probably booted the Wii Shopping Channel the most out of any application [on the Wii]".</p>
<p>But, while we may not be having a little boogie in our seats as we browse the Nintendo Switch 2's own eShop, it should at least me be more pleasant even if not musical experience compared to what we have now.</p>
<p>"I wanted to make sure that it was a smooth experience," Kawamoto said of Switch 2's eShop. "That the scrolling of the list doesn't stall, that it's very smooth, pages load fast."</p>
<p>I guess the proof of the pudding will be in the eating, and we will know for sure on Switch 2's release. As to when that is, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-release-date-revealed">Switch 2 is launching Thursday 5th June</a>, with a retail price of £395.99 for the console, or £429.99 should you opt for the Switch 2 and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> bundle.</p>
<p>For more on the console, our Tom has already been hands-on with the Switch 2. You can <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-hands-on-reveals-a-proper-generational-upgrade-though-its-biggest-new-idea-remains-unproven">read his Switch 2 impressions here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>