<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 07:54:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unannounced MySims games mysteriously pop up and disappear from EA app]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/unannounced-mysims-games-mysteriously-pop-up-and-disappear-from-ea-app</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/unannounced-mysims-games-mysteriously-pop-up-and-disappear-from-ea-app.1086570/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/unannounced-mysims-games-mysteriously-pop-up-and-disappear-from-ea-app<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Or were they sim-ply mistaken?</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/9ebef4b5-da42-4dff-b1e8-0e5f6f83faa7-2792257358.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>EA</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A Sims fan reckons they've stumbled upon evidence of unannounced MySims games.</p>
<p>According to redditor OyeDiego, pages for the MySims Action Bundle and MySims Beacon Bay briefly popped up on the EA app over the weekend, although neither bundle has been previously confirmed by publisher EA.</p>
<p>To bolster the claim, the poster included a screen recording of what they saw.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Nintendo Switch 2 and Mario Kart 9 have been revealed - but questions remain.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UyPgPcxLlIk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Last night, I found broken pages for MySims Action Bundle and MySims Beacon Bay in the EA app," the poster explained. "Neither had no images nor summaries, just the title, PEGI 7, and a date of 2099.</p>
<p>"It did not leave [sic] me pre-order them, so I saved them to my wish list. Today I couldn't find the games by searching for them, but they were still in my list. But Beacon Bay was causing the app to break. However, the Action Bundle was still intact.</p>
<p>"When I completely restarted the app, both games disappeared from my wishlist and I couldn't find them anymore."</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="546"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MySims/comments/1i3u3op/ea_app_leak_mysims_action_bundle_and_mysims/">EA App Leak: MySims Action Bundle and MySims Beacon Bay</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/OyeDiego/">u/OyeDiego</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MySims/">MySims</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>Whilst the OP was unable to assuage all cynics that the video was genuinely taken of the EA App, one poster <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MySims/comments/1i3u3op/comment/m7q85zx/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">said</a> in their defence: "I work as a developer. It would be a lot of work to create an EA app clone just to provide both unfinished pages and 500 error codes. Like, it would take a lot to mimic the UI and setup of the app just for bait.</p>
<p>"I don't see any reason as to why this wouldn’t be real - and the hypothetical response of removing the post kind of pushes people away from wanting to post here over Twitter."</p>
<p>Other fans hypothesise that the action bundle reads as though it's Agents and Skyheroes, whilst <a href="https://sims.fandom.com/wiki/Beacon_Bay">Beacon Bay</a> is a throwback that only players of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-3">The Sims 3</a> on Nintendo DS may remember, and could well be a brand-new MySims game.</p><p>Is the video real? Who knows. But with TheSims' 25th anniversary coming up, it's certainly plausible that a bundle of older and fan-favourite games could be on the way. We've reached out to EA and will let you know as and when we know more.</p>
<p>Talking of the 25th anniversary, all that kicks off on 4th February with a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-4-marking-series-25th-anniversary-with-huge-free-update-adding-70-new-items">"huge" free The Sims 4 update introducing over 70+ new items</a> spanning both Create a Sim and Build Buy modes. There's talk of turtlenecks and bodysuits, bike shorts, accessories, and hairdos. New furnishings, meanwhile, include "stylish" windows and doors, wood finishes for kitchen cabinets, and even a new playground pirate ship.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Never-before-seen Astro Bot level debuts at weekend PlayStation Tournament]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/never-before-seen-astro-bot-level-debuts-at-weekend-playstation-tournament</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/never-before-seen-astro-bot-level-debuts-at-weekend-playstation-tournament.1086540/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/never-before-seen-astro-bot-level-debuts-at-weekend-playstation-tournament<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2025-01-19-at-19.41.31.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Team Asobi / PlayStation</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Team Asobi has casually dropped a never-before-seen <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/astro-bot">Astro Bot</a> speedrun stage.</p>
<p>Debuted at this weekend's PlayStation tournament, the challenge - which you can see below - saw speedrunners explore the unfamiliar level to secure the fastest clear time in a bid to win the final.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PlayStation Tournaments: XP | Live from London" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9g_oTd7I8Sg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PlayStation Tournaments: XP | Live from London</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9g_oTd7I8Sg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9g_oTd7I8Sg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>PlayStation Tournaments: XP | Live from London.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9g_oTd7I8Sg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The two finalists were given five attempts to set the fastest time across a devilishly difficult level, using the flower umbrella and slo-mo to speed up the run as much as possible.</p>
<p>Team Circle's Rhys secured a win with an astonishing run-time of 34.51.6s, narrowly beating Team Square's equally-impressive 34.84.1s.</p>
<p>There was no word from the commentary team on whether the general public will eventually get the chance to run the gauntlet, too, but Bot fans are hopeful Team Asobi hasn't yet given up on patching in a cheeky cameo or two given <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/astro-bot-update-teases-surprising-bonus-cameo">several games noted in the credits have yet to be discovered</a>.</p><div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>"I've built my entire working life around [video games], my career dedicated to celebrating the best and highlighting the worst," Tom O wrote in his feature, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games-of-2024-astro-bot-made-the-best-play-for-nostalgia-this-year-and-i-dont-care-if-you-think-its-a-big-advert">Astro Bot made the best play for nostalgia this year, and I don't care if you think it's a big advert</a>. "As a job, it's as tiring and exhausting, sometimes exasperating, as any other, and it's easy to lose sight of why I chose this path all those years ago.</p>
<p>"Just for a moment, in the darkened early hours, a dim light from the DualSense painting the room in an ethereal glow, I was 12 again, and it was incredible. For that, I love Astro Bot, and I guess I love PlayStation too."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 bans another 136,000 cheaters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-bans-another-136000-cheaters</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-bans-another-136-000-cheaters.1086525/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-bans-another-136000-cheaters<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"Instances of cheating are frustrating and severely impact the experience for our community."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/COD-BO6-COD-101-TOUT-(1).webp?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Activision</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Another 136,000 ranked play accounts have been banned for cheating across both <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-2024">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> and Warzone.</p>
<p>In a detailed update shared on social media, developer Treyarch said it recognised cheaters "are frustrating and severely impact the experience for our community" but insisted it was addressing the issue, and will continue to do so "throughout 2025".</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Nintendo Switch 2 and Mario Kart 9 have been revealed - but questions remain.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UyPgPcxLlIk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Part of these efforts include "new layers of security and protections", as well as updated detection models for behavioural systems like aim botting, and "other data points", including "account trust and hardware identifiers to target serial cheaters".</p>
<p>Players can also expect new detection and warning systems for spam reporting and enhanced cross-examination tools to reduce the time it takes to review reports.</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Ahead of Season 02’s launch, we’re here to discuss what the various dev teams and studios are doing right now to address what matters to our players today:</p><p>• Cheating and bans<br>• Ability to disable cross-play on consoles in Ranked<br>• Server issues<br>• Quality of life updates<br>•… <a href="https://t.co/O6traEfwwG">https://t.co/O6traEfwwG</a></p></div>— Treyarch (@Treyarch) <a href="https://twitter.com/Treyarch/status/1880372557221884278?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 17, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>From Season 2, players can expect to see new and improved client and server-side detections and systems, too, as well as "major" kernel-level driver updates that not only improve driver security, but also reinforce the encryption process and introduce a new tampering detection system.</p><p>Treyarch stressed that "malicious reporting is against the security and enforcement policy", adding that when a user spams the report button in-game multiple times against a user – or someone uses an illegal cheat tool to spam 10,000 reports – its system "does not consider more than one single report from a player versus another (despite what cheat developers are telling players when they try to sell their illegal software)".</p>
<p>Interestingly, when a cheater is banned, the developer's system will also "detect other accounts it had regularly partied up with and raise flags for investigation to combat boosting and other cheater behaviour".</p>
<p>"We have seen community questions about detection methods, like IP-based banning," the studio explained. "We do not utilise IP-based bans for anti-cheat because they tend to take action against entire groups within a range that aren't problematic. For example, a college campus or internet café would be swept up in an IP-based ban wave when only a single machine was targeted."</p>
<p>ICYMI, as Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 readies for the release of Season 2 on 28th January, developer Treyarch has shared initial details of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6s-next-zombies-map-is-called-the-tomb-and-plunges-players-into-ancient-catacombs">Zombies mode's next map, The Tomb</a> - which plunges players deep beneath the earth, down into ancient catacombs.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>