<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 14:09:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox boss talks Switch 2 support, says Nintendo a "great partner"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-boss-talks-switch-2-support-says-nintendo-a-great-partner</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-boss-talks-switch-2-support-says-nintendo-a-great-partner.1165599/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-boss-talks-switch-2-support-says-nintendo-a-great-partner<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Halo from the other side.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Xbox-head-Phil-Spencer-overlayed-over-a-Switch-2-console.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Xbox/Nintendo/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Xbox head <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/phil-spencer">Phil Spencer</a> has reiterated Microsoft will support Switch 2, and dubbed Nintendo a "great partner".</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2 will be released on 5th June</a>, with reports that Microsoft titles such as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-reportedly-getting-halo-and-another-big-xbox-game-with-microsoft-set-to-be-a-very-big-supporter">Flight Simulator and Halo: The Master Chief Collection will be arriving on the platform</a> at some point in 2025. Meanwhile in 2022, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-agrees-10-year-deal-to-bring-call-of-duty-to-nintendo-if-activision-blizzard-buyout-goes-through">Microsoft agreed a 10-year deal to bring Call of Duty to Nintendo</a> if its then-to-be-finalised buyout of Activision Blizzard was completed (<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-has-finally-bought-activision-blizzard">which it was in October 2023</a>).</p>
<p>Now, Spencer has spoken further about Microsoft's support for the Switch successor, and stated that Nintendo's consoles were "a unique way for us to reach players who aren't PC players, who aren't players on Xbox".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" title="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More! <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9CF8nQGolWY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"It lets us continue to grow our community of people that care about the franchises that we have, and that's really important for us to make sure we continue to invest in our games," the Xbox head told <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/microsoft-phil-spencer-minecraft-movie-fallout-season-2-1236352653/">Variety</a> when asked about any Switch 2 projects.</p>
<p>"I'm really a big believer in what Nintendo means for this industry and us continuing to support them. And getting the support from them for our franchises, I think, is an important part of our future."</p>
<p>This week's comment echoes Spencer's previous words regarding Microsoft's support of Nintendo. In November last year, the Xbox exec said there was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/phil-spencer-says-no-red-lines-over-any-xbox-game-coming-to-nintendo-or-playstation">nothing stopping any of the company's games coming to Nintendo or PlayStation platforms in the future</a>.</p>
<p>Then, in January, Spencer spoke with Gamertag Radio, confirming Xbox would be supporting the Switch 2, adding he had exchanged messages with Nintendo's Shuntaro Furukawa following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/its-official-nintendo-switch-2-revealed-after-months-of-waiting">that initial console teaser</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Microsoft Gaming CEO, Phil Spencer on his legacy and the future of gaming" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mAl5yVpNc3o?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Microsoft Gaming CEO, Phil Spencer on his legacy and the future of gaming</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mAl5yVpNc3o?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mAl5yVpNc3o?autoplay=1" title="Microsoft Gaming CEO, Phil Spencer on his legacy and the future of gaming">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Microsoft Gaming CEO, Phil Spencer on his legacy and the future of gaming. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mAl5yVpNc3o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As for if the Switch 2 reveal had put any sort of pressure on Xbox to reveal what its forthcoming hardware plans - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xboxs-2025-gaming-handheld-teased-in-new-trailer">including an Xbox handheld</a> - Spencer said it hadn't.</p>
<p>"I think all of us in this industry should focus on our communities and the player base that we're building," Spencer continued. "I get inspired by what a lot of different creators do and other platform holders. But I believe in the plans that we have.</p>
<p>"Obviously, we're evolving what it means to be Xbox and meeting players in so many different places. There are 3 billion people who play video games on the planet and I get up every morning and think about how Xbox can be more relevant to the 3 billion people who play. And that's through making sure we're leading in how our games and our platform features can be available in as many places as possible, whether that's Cloud, whether it's people playing on PC, whether it's people playing on console.</p>
<p>"So we're really driven by trying to grow our franchises and our platform to be an important part of gaming for as many of those 3 billion gamers as we can reach."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Halo-The-Master-Chief-Collection.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Microsoft</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Elsewhere, it seems <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/delayed-switch-2-us-pre-orders-will-reportedly-start-next-week-depending-on-retailer">some retailers in the US will open up Switch 2 pre-orders as soon as next week</a>, following news <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-delays-us-switch-2-pre-orders-due-to-tariffs">Nintendo was delaying the process following concerns around tariffs</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Among Us 3D release date announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/among-us-3d-release-date-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/among-us-3d-release-date-announced.1165542/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/among-us-3d-release-date-announced<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Two-crewmates-in-Among-Us-3D-in-space.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Schell Games/Innersloth LLC</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Developers InnerSloth and Schell Games have announced the release date of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/among-us">Among Us</a> 3D on PC.</p>
<p>The upcoming 3D release of the space-set social deduction game was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/among-us-3d-announced-demo-out-next-week">first announced in February of this year</a>, but with that all important release date missing. That has changed now, however, with confirmation Among Us 3D launches on PC via Steam on 6th May.</p>
<p>"MARK IT IN YOUR CALENDARS," the Among Us team proclaimed on social media, with a confident use of caps lock. "3D BEANS COMING TO UR SCREENS SOON AAAAAA."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Let's Play Among Us: NEW MAP, SAME OLD CHAOS! ft. Outside Xbox, Outside Xtra &amp; Dicebreaker!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BtfF9Y1Wcwg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Let's Play Among Us: NEW MAP, SAME OLD CHAOS! ft. Outside Xbox, Outside Xtra &amp; Dicebreaker!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BtfF9Y1Wcwg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/BtfF9Y1Wcwg?autoplay=1" title="Let's Play Among Us: NEW MAP, SAME OLD CHAOS! ft. Outside Xbox, Outside Xtra &amp; Dicebreaker!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Eurogamer's video team play Among Us with Outside Xbox, Outside Xtra &amp; Dicebreaker. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BtfF9Y1Wcwg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As to what players can expect on Among Us 3D's release, well, it'll be pretty much just like the Among Us that blew up in popularity during 2020, but with an extra dimension.</p>
<p>"In this party game, Crewmates work together to complete tasks before one or more Impostors kill everyone aboard. Experience all of the same deception and deceit as the original Among Us in all three dimensions," <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3168600/Among_Us_3D/">reads the game's Steam page description</a>.</p>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>Away from games, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/among-us-sci-fi-social-deduction-is-getting-the-animated-adaptation-treatment">Among Us is being turned into an animated series</a>. On its announcement, we were given a general overview that read: "Members of your crew have been replaced by an alien shapeshifter intent on causing confusion, sabotaging the ship, and killing everyone. Root out the 'Impostor' or fall victim to its murderous designs."</p>
<p>Since then, famous faces such as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/among-us-animation-cast-rounded-out-with-jurassic-park-ratatouille-talent">Elijah Wood, Wayne Knight and Ashley Johnson have been announced as voicing various crewmembers</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Go creator Niantic lays off 68 people following $3.5bn games sale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-creator-niantic-lays-off-68-people-following-35bn-games-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-go-creator-niantic-lays-off-68-people-following-3-5bn-games-sale.1165530/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-creator-niantic-lays-off-68-people-following-35bn-games-sale<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Remaining employees now part of slimmed down spin-off focused on AI mapping.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1741739064040.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Niantic</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Niantic has made 68 employees redundant as part of its company restructuring process <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-will-be-sold-to-monopoly-go-maker-scopely-niantic-confirms">following the sale of its gaming portfolio to Monopoly Go maker Scopely - a deal worth $3.5bn</a>.
</p>
<p>
The deal has seen Scopely become owner of Niantic games <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/pokemon-go">Pokémon Go</a>, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/monster-hunter-now">Monster Hunter Now</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/pikmin-bloom">Pikmin Bloom</a>, and the new employer of the teams that work on those titles. 
</p>
<p>
These layoffs, meanwhile, come from the remaining staff at Niantic working on other projects, as the organisation slims down and effectively rebrands as a startup, named Niantic Spatial.
</p>
<p>
Niantic had previously warned of job losses among its remaining team as part of this process. Now, as detailed in a Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification (WARN) spotted by <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/niantic-is-laying-off-68-employees-after-selling-its-game-business-for-3-5-billion">Game Developer</a>, we know how many.
</p>
<p>
The company has declined to comment further about the job losses.
</p>
<p>
Niantic Spatial will focus on a refreshed version of Niantic's original core interest - creating a digital map of the planet, now using geospatial AI. The newly-rebranded company has secured $250m of capital investment, $50m from Scopely and $200m from Niantic's own balance sheet in order to move forward.
</p>
<p>
"We're in the midst of seismic changes in technology, with AI evolving rapidly," Niantic founder John Hanke wrote recently on Niantic Spatial's focus. "Existing maps were built for people to read and navigate but now there is a need for a new kind of map that makes the world intelligible for machines, for everything from smart glasses to humanoid robots, so they can understand and navigate the physical world.
</p>
<p>
"Today's LLMs represent the first step towards a future where a variety of expert models collaborate to reason and understand complex problems, and many of those problems will require deep and accurate knowledge of the physical world. Niantic is building the models that will help AI move beyond the screen and into the real world."
</p>
<p>Eurogamer recently travelled to a major Pokémon Go fan event in Italy, held shortly after the sale was announced, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/amidst-pokemon-gos-35bn-sale-fans-flock-to-italys-first-major-meetup-with-mix-of-emotions-over-games-future">heard of players' mixed emotions regarding Scopely now being in charge</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>