<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 08:26:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Black Flag actor threatened with legal action following remake slip-up]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-black-flag-actor-threatened-with-legal-action-following-remake-slip-up</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-black-flag-actor-threatened-with-legal-action-following-remake-slip-up.1259343/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Earlier this year, Black Flag actor Matt Ryan suggested Ubisoft was set to release a remake of its piratical Assassin's Creed entry, and it now sounds like the developer wasn't exactly thrilled about that.</p>
<p>Ryan portrayed Edward Kenway in Assassin's Creed Black Flag, which came out in 2013. It soon became a series favourite for many, and in recent times rumours of a remake have been making the rounds.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>These rumours were amplified again in June, when Ryan hinted not very subtly to one fan they should perhaps get ready to replay the game, implying with a bit of a 'wink, wink, nudge, nudge' that the remake was indeed real.</p>
<p>"Have you beaten [Black Flag]?" Ryan asked a fan in a clip that was shared around social media (see below). The fan confirmed they had but some time ago, to which Ryan followed up with: "Well, you might have to beat it again…"</p>
<p>When the fan suggested maybe playing through all <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-games-order">Assassin's Creed games</a>, Ryan replied: "Well, especially this one… There's a reason I say that, but I can't say anything." </p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Edward Kenway's voice actor, Matt Ryan, said this during a fan interaction. It looks like he hinted at the Assassin's Creed Black Flag Remake. 🔥</p><p>🟢 Quote:<br>“Have you beat the game?… well you may have to beat it again”<br>And <br>“There’s a reason I say that but I can’t say… <a href="https://t.co/n3PwF8Q7Ri">pic.twitter.com/n3PwF8Q7Ri</a></p></div>— Zephryss⛩️ (@TheRealZephryss) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheRealZephryss/status/1939392046151926243?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 29, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Anyway, fast forward to today, and it turns out not only was Ubisoft unhappy that Ryan had been a little loose-lipped, but the company actually also threatened him with legal action.</p>
<p>At another more recent convention, the Edward Kenway actor was asked about a Black Flag remake or remaster, to which he replied with a casual shrug and a "I don't know, mate". The questioner then pressed Ryan further, calling back to the previous video from June, when the actor then explained:</p>
<p>"Well, the thing is, that when that happened, someone was doing this [gestures towards the person filming the exchange], and I was being very free and open, but I didn't know that they actually were recording me on their phone.</p>
<p>"And then the company threatened to sue me. So [now] I say nothing." A video of the exchange was uploaded to <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@kylo_hd659/video/7532502046889528598">TikTok</a> but has since been removed. A copy is embedded below:</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Damn so it seems like Matt Ryan (voice actor for Edward Kenway) got into deep trouble with Ubisoft for hinting at the Black Flag Remake to that other guy..</p><p>He didn’t realize he was being recorded😵 <a href="https://t.co/2Vy8g6pMRr">pic.twitter.com/2Vy8g6pMRr</a></p></div>— The Hidden One (@TheHiddenOneAC) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheHiddenOneAC/status/1950940394310545618?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 31, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Eurogamer has asked Ubisoft for further comment on Ryan's Black Flag-flavoured exchanges, and will update you if we hear anything more.</p>
<p>Word of a Black Flag remake first began circulating in 2023, when it was said that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/skull-and-bones">Skull and Bones</a> studio Ubisoft Singapore was "heavily involved". Of course, Skull and Bones - which sadly <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/skull-and-bones-metacritic-user-reviews-open-to-generally-unfavourable-scores">failed to really get any decent wind in its sails following its launch last year</a> - began life as a spin-off from Black Flag.</p>
<p>At the time of this initial rumour, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-is-reportedly-remaking-rollicking-pirate-adventure-assassins-creed-black-flag">project was not expected to be completed for "at least a few years"</a>, though given we are now marching firmly into the latter half of 2025, a 'few years' is actually coming up <em>relatively </em>soon now. Stay tuned!</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-black-flag-actor-threatened-with-legal-action-following-remake-slip-up]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>