<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 11:46:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another new Resident Evil game has been announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/another-new-resident-evil-game-has-been-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/another-new-resident-evil-game-has-been-announced.1235898/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>If the upcoming Resident Evil Requiem is not enough newness for all you zombie-loving fans, then I have some good news. Today, a new strategy game based on Capcom's Resi series has been announced.</p>
<p>It's known as Resident Evil Survival Unit, and is set for release across mobile devices. While Survival Unit is being co-developed by Aniplex Inc and Joycity Corporation, Capcom is working in "close collaboration" with the studios to "ensure authenticity and quality".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Resident Evil 9 Breakdown: Everything We Know FOR SURE - Leon, Gameplay, Locations" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_hStA0MX16o?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Resident Evil 9 Breakdown: Everything We Know FOR SURE - Leon, Gameplay, Locations</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_hStA0MX16o?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_hStA0MX16o?autoplay=1" title="Resident Evil 9 Breakdown: Everything We Know FOR SURE - Leon, Gameplay, Locations">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Resident Evil 9 Breakdown: Everything We Know FOR SURE - Leon, Gameplay, Locations. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_hStA0MX16o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Details on what the game will look like and involve for now remain somewhat mysterious, though we can look forward to finding out more later this month, with a showcase planned for 10th July. It will take place at 11pm UK time.</p>
<p>The studios have said Resident Evil Survival Unit will "appeal to both longtime fans and new players". While we don't yet have a release date, it will be available globally across Japan, South Korea, North America, Europe, and Asia whenever it does arrive.</p>
<p>Along with this info, some artwork for Resident Evil Survival Unit was shared, showing a car driving down a road as a lightning storm rages. To one side, a sign for Umbrella - yes, that rather questionable corporation - declares that "our business is life itself…". The two people on the sign smile away. Oh, what poor sweet fools.</p>
<p>In terms of the Resi timeline, Umbrella itself went defunct in 2003, following the Raccoon Trials. Given this, we can perhaps surmise from the artwork that Resident Evil Survival Unit at least takes place before that time.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Capcom</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for the rest of the series,  we got our first look at Resident Evil Requiem last month, when Capcom <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/resident-evil-9-officially-unveiled-coming-february">introduced us all to Grace Ashcroft and a destroyed Raccoon City</a>. The developer once considered having Leon Kennedy take on the protagonist role for Requiem, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/leon-kennedy-actually-quite-a-bad-match-for-horror-says-resident-evil-9s-director">in the end decided he was "actually quite a bad match for horror"</a>.</p>
<p>Our Alex has been hands-on with Resident Evil Requiem already, admitting that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/i-played-resident-evil-9-and-they-heard-me-scream-in-the-booth-next-door">even the relatively small chunk he played made him scream so loudly that those in the booth next door heard him</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/another-new-resident-evil-game-has-been-announced]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light studio Techland cancels two in-development games, clarifies no staff reductions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dying-light-studio-techland-cancels-two-in-development-games-clarifies-no-staff-reductions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dying-light-studio-techland-cancels-two-in-development-games-clarifies-no-staff-reductions.1235895/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"Game development is never a straight line."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Techland</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Dying Light developer Techland has confirmed there have been no staff reductions following the reported cancellation of two in-development games.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.pb.pl/techland-z-potezna-strata-za-2024-r-1244492">Pulz Biznesu</a> (thanks <a href="https://www.gamewatcher.com/news/dying-light-developer-techland-cancels-two-upcoming-games-including-its-new-fantasy-rpg-ip">GameWatcher</a>), the developer published record losses of 135m zl (£27.4m) for 2024, as per the <a href="https://ekrs.ms.gov.pl/rdf/pd/search_df">Polish National Court Register</a>. While the two projects have not been named, it's presumed one is the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/techland-working-on-open-world-fantasy-action-rpg">fantasy RPG revealed in May 2022</a>.</p>
<p>In a statement to Eurogamer, a spokesperson for Techland said: "Game development is never a straight line, and sometimes fresh approaches are necessary to make great games. What's important here is that none of the reported changes have resulted in staff reductions. Developers were moved to other projects and are working on a number of games in our pipeline.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dying Light: The Beast — Gameplay Premiere Trailer | Summer Game Fest 2025" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M0GCr2P9510?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dying Light: The Beast — Gameplay Premiere Trailer | Summer Game Fest 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M0GCr2P9510?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/M0GCr2P9510?autoplay=1" title="Dying Light: The Beast — Gameplay Premiere Trailer | Summer Game Fest 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Dying Light: The Beast — Gameplay Premiere Trailer | Summer Game Fest 2025<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M0GCr2P9510" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Our primary focus right now is to release Dying Light: The Beast for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X/S. After the launch of Dying Light: The Beast, we will share more about future titles in due time."</p>
<p>Little is known about the fantasy RPG, though the company recruited top talent from the likes of CD Projekt Red, Arkane, and Guerrilla Games.</p>
<p>"We're very happy with what we have accomplished with the Dying Light franchise so far," said Paweł Marchewka, Techland CEO, at the time of the game's announcement.</p>
<p>"At the same time, our ambition is to introduce a brand new IP that is vastly different from what we have been doing for the past several years. We want to create a fully next-gen experience. A new fantasy epic set in a sprawling open world, fueled by the skills and experience we have gained as a team over the years, infused with new ideas, passion, and creativity."</p>
<p>Although the record losses are significant, Techland's most recently released game was Dying Light 2 back in 2022. The first Dying Light, released in 2015, was a massive hit for the company, selling 20m copies as of 2022. The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dying-light-2-has-surpassed-5m-copies-sold-since-launching-in-february">sequel sold 5m in around two months</a>.</p>
<p>The company's next release will be <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dying-light-the-beast-is-coming-out-on-25-august-revealed-at-summer-game-fest">Dying Light: The Beast</a>, coming 22nd August.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/techland-teases-multiple-unannounced-dying-light-projects-including-board-games-and-a-webcomic">Techland announced it would be releasing multiple projects in the Dying Light series</a>, including board games and a webcomic. Following these new cancellations, it seems the company is focusing on its most successful franchise.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/dying-light-studio-techland-cancels-two-in-development-games-clarifies-no-staff-reductions]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BioWare's beleaguered multiplayer shooter Anthem shutting down next year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/biowares-beleaguered-multiplayer-shooter-anthem-shutting-down-next-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/biowares-beleaguered-multiplayer-shooter-anthem-shutting-down-next-year.1235796/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>No one was laid off as a result of this decision, company assures.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bioware</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Following "careful consideration", publisher EA and developer BioWare are shutting down Anthem in January.</p>
<p>Bioware is taking the servers for the beleaguered multiplayer shooter offline on 12th January, 2026. Given that it is a fully online game, and requires an internet connection to play, this means it won't be available in any way, shape or form beyond that date.</p>
<p>As of now, Anthem players will not be able to purchase any in-game currency. Instead, players will need to use up the last of their already acquired in-game funds, as the Bioware team gets ready to sunset the servers.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dragon Age The Veilguard Review: The BEST Bioware Has EVER Been! (Spoiler-Free)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9f0BX-JXzek?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dragon Age The Veilguard Review: The BEST Bioware Has EVER Been! (Spoiler-Free)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9f0BX-JXzek?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9f0BX-JXzek?autoplay=1" title="Dragon Age The Veilguard Review: The BEST Bioware Has EVER Been! (Spoiler-Free)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Dragon Age The Veilguard Review: The BEST Bioware Has EVER Been! (Spoiler-Free). <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9f0BX-JXzek" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Anthem will be removed from the EA Play playlist next month, on 15th August. Meanwhile, if Anthem has been already purchased and in libraries, users will still be able to redownload the game and play until the servers shut down next year. </p>
<p>"We deeply appreciate your dedication, passion and support over the years and we'd like to thank you for that," Anthem's team wrote in a <a href="https://www.ea.com/en-au/games/anthem/news/anthem-game-update">post announcing the shut down</a>. It added the shut down has not resulted in any layoffs within the team. This will no doubt be a relief, given EA recently <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/despite-black-panther-cancellation-ea-still-has-at-least-three-marvel-games-in-the-works">cancelled its single-player Black Panther game and closed the developer behind it</a>, Cliffhanger Studios.</p>
<p>Anthem initially released in 2019, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioware-very-disappointed-in-anthem-launch-issues">had a rocky start</a>. In 2020, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioware-confirms-its-working-on-a-substantial-reinvention-of-anthem">Bioware then announced it was planning to overhaul its online shooter</a>, which the studio said would deliver a "substantial reinvention" of the core Anthem experience. The following year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioware-confirms-work-on-major-anthem-overhaul-has-officially-ceased">development on this major overhaul ceased</a>. Soon after, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/anthem-director-departs-bioware">Anthem's director Jonathan Warner announced he was leaving BioWare</a>.</p>
<p>"Beautiful, broken, with flashes of brilliance, Anthem is a disorganised mess in search of a reason to be," reads <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/anthem-review-shaken-apart-by-its-own-identity-crisis">Eurogamer's original Anthem review from 2019</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/biowares-beleaguered-multiplayer-shooter-anthem-shutting-down-next-year]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>