<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 14:54:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Workers at Don't Nod to strike in reaction to studio's recent redundancy plan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/workers-at-dont-nod-to-strike-in-reaction-to-studios-recent-redundancy-plan</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/workers-at-dont-nod-to-strike-in-reaction-to-studios-recent-redundancy-plan.1028739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/workers-at-dont-nod-to-strike-in-reaction-to-studios-recent-redundancy-plan<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Current project, Lost Records: Bloom and Rage, is due for release early next year.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/close-up-of-a-female-character-in-Lost-Records.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Don't Nod</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Workers at Don't Nod - the studio behind the likes of Jusant, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/life-is-strange">Life is Strange</a> 1 and 2, and upcoming release Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage - are set to strike this Friday, 8th November.</p>
<p>The strike is in reaction to the studio's redundancy plan, which it announced in October.</p>
<p>As Matt reported last month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/jusant-lost-records-studio-dont-nod-says-69-jobs-at-risk-as-part-of-reorganisation-project">69 jobs at the studio are at risk</a>, as Don't Nod initiates a "reorganisation project to ensure the company's long-term future" amid "deteriorating" financial results.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage | Lo-fi Summer Trailer. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vu0wEVY6GLU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In an open letter seen and translated by Eurogamer's sister-site <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/dont-nod-workers-to-strike-on-november-8">GamesIndustry.biz</a>, Don't Nod workers accused studio leadership of failing to take responsibility for its own shortcomings, instead using economical context as a justification for the redundancy plan.</p>
<p>"As workers at this company, we know that these failures are due to a succession of negligent acts and bad decisions from leadership," the letter reads. "We have warned leadership about these failures for years, but are not being listened to. Ultimately, we're the ones paying the price of these absurd decisions today, with the redundancy plan."</p><p>Workers accused leadership of "short-term thinking", adding "delusions of grandeur" influenced those higher up in the organisation to over-invest. "We want to save the company, but not at the price of unjustified redundancies or a deteriorated working environment," the letter closed.</p>
<p>Don't Nod's workers have laid out a number of demands, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>That Don't Nod abandons the redundancy plan</li>
<li>That employees have a voice in decision-making at the company</li>
<li>That Don't Nod CEO Oskar Guilbert be present at the negotiation</li>
</ul>
<p>The strike is set to begin at 2pm on Friday, union STJV announced, next to Don't Nod's Paris headquarters.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Dont-Nod-strike-image-showing-characters-with-a-mega-phone-and-raised-arms.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Don't Nod/STJV</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In September, Don't Nod said it had high hopes for Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage, after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dont-nod-bets-on-lost-records-bloom-rage-as-multiple-projects-fail-to-meet-expectations">Jusant and Banishers: Ghosts of New Eden failed to reach company expectations</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/life-is-strange-creators-lost-records-launches-in-two-parts">Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage is set to arrive in two parts next year</a>. The first instalment launches for PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S on 18th February 2025. The second part will then debut a month later, on 18th March.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve adds game recording function to Steam, and it works on Steam Deck]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-adds-game-recording-function-to-steam-and-it-works-on-steam-deck</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-adds-game-recording-function-to-steam-and-it-works-on-steam-deck.1028691/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-adds-game-recording-function-to-steam-and-it-works-on-steam-deck<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Steam-deck-on-a-plain-white-background.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Valve/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Valve has added a game recording functionality to Steam.</p>
<p>This feature was previously in beta, but is now available to the wider community. It's described as a "new built-in system for creating and sharing your gameplay footage".</p>
<p>Users will now be able to record, replay, clip and share their gameplay experience. This includes on Valve's handheld PC, the Steam Deck. You can see how it looks via the video below. </p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Steam's game recording. A &quot;new built-in system for creating and sharing your gameplay footage&quot;" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F_uNwS8jPsY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Steam's game recording. A "new built-in system for creating and sharing your gameplay footage"</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F_uNwS8jPsY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/F_uNwS8jPsY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Steam's game recording feature in action. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F_uNwS8jPsY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In a blog post detailing Steam's new feature, Valve said its 'Background Recording' mode will mean gameplay is "continuously saved to your preferred drive, never exceeding your specified duration and storage limits". It stated that an 'on demand' function is also available, so users can stop and start recording manually as the mood takes.</p>
<p>That aforementioned replay functionality, meanwhile, can be found in the Steam Overlay for each game on Valve's platform.</p>
<p>There will also be 'Timeline' and 'Event' markers. "The Steam Timeline appears whenever you’re actively recording," Valve said. "Timeline-enhanced games generate event markers as relevant game events happen. Steam achievements and screenshots automatically create markers as well."</p>
<p>Full details on Valve's new game recording feature, including how to save and share clips, can be found on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/gamerecording">Steam</a>.</p>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>In related news, EA recently <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/apex-legends-drops-steam-deck-support-in-bid-to-tackle-impactful-exploits-and-cheats">blocked Steam Deck players from its cooperative shooter Apex Legends</a>.</p>
<p>Stating "the openness of the Linux operating systems makes it an attractive one for cheaters and cheat developers", EA determined making its game available on the Linux system is "a path for a variety of impactful exploits and cheats."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix removing "almost all" of its Interactive Specials, but don't worry, Bandersnatch is safe]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-removing-almost-all-of-its-interactive-specials-but-dont-worry-bandersnatch-is-safe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflix-removing-almost-all-of-its-interactive-specials-but-dont-worry-bandersnatch-is-safe.1028640/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-removing-almost-all-of-its-interactive-specials-but-dont-worry-bandersnatch-is-safe<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/netflix">Netflix</a> is removing the majority of its Interactive Specials from the streaming service.</p>
<p>Speaking to Eurogamer, a Netflix spokesperson confirmed "almost all" of its interactive titles will come off the service on 1st December.</p>
<p>"Only four will remain: Black Mirror: Bandersnatch, Unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt: Kimmy vs. the Reverend, Ranveer vs. Wild with Bear Grylls, and You vs. Wild," Netflix told us.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Nintendo has announced new hardware, but it's not Switch 2 - so what's the point of Alarmo?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GdNKD3U-4AY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Perhaps somewhat fittingly, Bandersnatch is about a young programmer who "begins to question reality" as he sets to work adapting a dark fantasy novel into a video game. Set in the 1980s, Bandersnatch is described as a "mind-bending tale", which features multiple endings depending on the viewer's decisions.</p>
<p>Word of Netflix's plans first started making the rounds earlier this week, when Battle Kitty series creator Matt Layzell shared an update on Instagram. Here, Layzell confirmed Netflix would be removing their original animated series from the service.</p>
<p>"It's not the ideal future I had hoped for Battle Kitty but I'm SO grateful for everyone who watched and enjoyed the show," <a href="https://x.com/AWorkersIgnited/status/1853261942951211155">Layzell wrote</a>. "As always, a huge thanks from the bottom of my heart to the entire crew who helped me bring it to life."</p>
<p>Here's the full list of <a href="https://www.netflix.com/browse/genre/2869704">Interactive Specials</a> set to be removed from Netflix in the coming weeks:</p>
<ul>
<li>Headspace: Unwind your Mind</li>
<li>Triviaverse</li>
<li>Cat Burglar</li>
<li>Battle Kitty</li>
<li>Boss Baby: Get that Baby!</li>
<li>Jurassic World: Camp Cretaceous: Hidden Adventure</li>
<li>Johnny Test’s Ultimate Meatloaf Quest</li>
<li>Carmen Sandiego: To Steal or Not to Steal</li>
<li>You vs Wild: Out Cold</li>
<li>Captain Underpants: Epic Choice-o-Rama</li>
<li>Choose Love</li>
<li>Barbie: Epic Road Trip</li>
<li>The Last Kids on Earth: Happy Apocalypse to You</li>
<li>Escape the Undertaker</li>
<li>Animals on the Loose: A You vs Wild Movie</li>
<li>Spirit: Riding Free: Ride-Along Adventure</li>
<li>Stretch Armstrong: Breakout</li>
<li>Trivia Quest</li>
<li>Buddy Thunderstruck: The Maybe Pile</li>
<li>We Lost Our Human</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/image-(456).png?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Netflix/Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Last month, Netflix reportedly <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-closes-aaa-internal-studio-led-by-halo-creative-head-joseph-staten">closed its internal game studio in Southern California</a>, which was poised to release a AAA game. Known as team 'Blue', this was one of a handful of internal studios founded by Netflix as part of its expansion into games.</p><p>The particular team boasted staff from other major studios, including longtime <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/halo">Halo</a> creative lead Joseph Staten, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/overwatch">Overwatch</a> executive producer Chacko Sonny and art director Rafael Grassetti from God of War's Sony Santa Monica. These three are no longer at the company.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>