<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 12:12:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Online Mature app receives two additional N64 games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-online-mature-app-receives-two-additional-n64-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-online-mature-app-receives-two-additional-n64-games.1021761/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-online-mature-app-receives-two-additional-n64-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/shadow-man-remastered.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Night Dive Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div>



            <p>Two N64  games have now been added to the Mature app of the Nintendo Switch Online subscription.</p>
<p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/turok-2-seeds-of-evil">Turok 2: Seeds of Evil</a> and Shadow Man are both available right now for subscribers with the Expansion Pack.</p>
<p>Both games were known for their blood and gore - unusual on Nintendo's system - hence their inclusion in the Mature app, alongside shooters Perfect Dark and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/turok-dinosaur-hunter">Turok: Dinosaur Hunter</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Nintendo 64™ – October 2024 Game Update – Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GJgHERWE_eg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Nintendo 64™ – October 2024 Game Update – Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GJgHERWE_eg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/GJgHERWE_eg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Nintendo 64™ – October 2024 Game Update – Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GJgHERWE_eg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As a reminder, the Mature app is a separate download away from the main N64 app.</p>
<p>Turok 2: Seeds of Evil was, of course, the follow-up to the first <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/turok">Turok</a> game, in which players shoot dinosaurs with a variety of outlandishly gruesome weapons.</p>
<p>Shadow Man, meanwhile, was based on the comic book series of the same name, following a voodoo warrior with the ability to visit the land of the dead.</p>
<div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nightdives-shadow-man-remaster-gets-april-release-date-on-pc">remastered version of Shadow Man from Night Dive Studios</a> was released in 2021. This addition, though, is the N64 original. A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/new-shadowman-game-in-the-works-21-years-after-the-last">new game in the Shadow Man series</a> is also in the works.</p>
<p>These two games join <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/banjo-tooie-is-coming-to-nintendo-switch-later-this-month">Banjo-Tooie as additions this month to Nintendo Switch Online</a> (trailer above).</p>
<p>For a list of all games available, check out our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/all-nintendo-switch-online-games-available-to-play-right-now">full guide to Nintendo Switch Online</a>.</p>
<p>Will you be chasing dinosaurs or visiting the land of the dead this week?</p></div>



        </article>

  
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2 early access delayed by three weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/path-of-exile-2-early-access-delayed-by-three-weeks</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-early-access-delayed-by-three-weeks.1021740/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/path-of-exile-2-early-access-delayed-by-three-weeks<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Path-of-Exile-2-gameplay-showing-a-lush-green-area-with-a-monkey-like-enemy.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Grinding Gear Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/path-of-exile-2">Path of Exile 2</a> has had its early access release date pushed back until December.</p>
<p>Grinding Gear Games' take on Diablo was expected to release this November. However, due to some "server-side infrastructure work" that still needs sorting out, Path of Exile 2 will now be released in December.</p>
<p>"I'm really sorry about this one. People plan time off and things like that around our launches, but we just have to do it," Path of Exile 2 game director Jonathan Rogers said in a video announcing the delay.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Nintendo has announced new hardware, but it's not Switch 2 - so what's the point of Alarmo?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GdNKD3U-4AY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Path of Exile 2 itself is in good shape, the director stated, though to ensure <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mercenary-class-unveiled-for-path-of-exile-2-and-it-plays-like-shooter">microtransactions work seamlessly across both Path of Exile and the sequel</a>, a little more time is needed.</p>
<p>"We have to integrate the account systems for not only <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/path-of-exile">Path of Exile</a> 1 and 2, but also for the console realms as well," Rogers explained. "This meant changing a lot of things. Not only do we have to create a bunch of new systems, we have to make sure that all the old data is backwards compatible with them as well."</p><p>The Path of Exile 2 team wants to ensure everything is "perfect" on the game's early access launch, Rogers continued, so "nobody loses anything they paid for and nobody has their account broken". This means "a lot of load testing to make sure the whole thing doesn't fall over" on Path of Exile 2's debut, he added, as Grinding Gear is expecting a "huge number" of players.</p>
<p>Rogers admitted things had been left too late to get everything up to snuff for Path of Exile 2's November release date. "I'm really sorry," he apologised again, "this one really hurts".</p>
<p>Path of Exile 2 will now be released in early access on 6th December. Ahead of this, the developer plans to host a live stream in roughly four weeks time, with an exact date still to be confirmed. Rogers promised the team will share more on what kind of content players can expect on Path of Exile 2's launch during this stream.</p>
<p>"Until then, thank you very much for your support," Rogers concluded.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Path of Exile 2 Delayed Three Weeks" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V2zus8ux73s?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Path of Exile 2 Delayed Three Weeks</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V2zus8ux73s?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/V2zus8ux73s?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Path of Exile 2 Delayed Three Weeks. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V2zus8ux73s" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>For more, be sure to check out Jay Castello's feature: <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-date-with-path-of-exile-2-a-new-class-smoother-onboarding-and-the-reason-why-this-had-to-be-a-sequel">A date with Path of Exile 2: a new class, smoother onboarding, and the reason why this had to be a sequel</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Go Gigantamax battles will be made easier in response to mixed feedback]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-gigantamax-battles-will-be-made-easier-in-response-to-mixed-feedback</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-go-gigantamax-battles-will-be-made-easier-in-response-to-mixed-feedback.1021737/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-gigantamax-battles-will-be-made-easier-in-response-to-mixed-feedback<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>For this weekend, at least.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/0_jc9FPbRF6vg26qGO-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Niantic</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/pokemon-go">Pokémon Go</a> developer <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/niantic">Niantic</a> has announced changes to its big new Gigantamax battles feature, in response to this weekend's initial launch.
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-go-launches-gigantamax-raids-to-mixed-response-as-developer-bans-countless-players-by-accident">Fan feedback to Gigantamax has been decidedly mixed</a>, as Eurogamer reported yesterday, with concerns over the difficulty level of being able to beat the skyscraper-high monsters, and the ease of then actually catching one afterwards.
</p>
<p>
Niantic has responded swiftly, and in a statement to Eurogamer last night a company spokesperson detailed a number of changes for the game's next set of Gigantamax raids this weekend, against Gigantamax Gengar. 
</p>
<p>
Most notably, the difficulty of Gigantamax Gengar will be lowered "slightly", to make the battle easier when compared to other Gigantamax battles. 
</p>
<p>
"While we want Gigantamax to be the new high bar for a meaningful challenge in Pokémon Go, we want to make sure that players have a reasonable chance to defeat Gengar," a Niantic spokesperson told Eurogamer. "You'll still need to strategise and coordinate with your group and go in powered up to a degree, but we think this tuning will make things slightly easier to help a range of Trainers jump into Gigantamax."
</p><p>
Here, Niantic seems to agree with a common complaint I heard this past weekend - that the feature could have benefited from giving players more of a leg-up to get started. Once you have your first Gigantamax Pokémon (and after a battle or two to learn the ropes), the whole thing becomes easier. 
</p>
<p>
Other changes to Gigantamax Gengar include a bonus 25k Stardust reward for beating the boss, and an improved capture rate for snagging it afterwards.
</p>
<p>
"We want players to feel rewarded for accomplishing such a huge feat, and right now the catch rate didn't match the experience we wanted," a Niantic spokesperson said. "We'll be increasing this for Gengar and will continue to monitor other Gigantamax encounters."
</p>
<p>
There's no changes to the game's Max Particle limit, which effectively caps the amount of Gigantamax raids you can complete at two without purchasing more of the currency from Pokémon Go's shop. And there's certainly no suggestion you will be able to complete Gigantamax Gengar battles without still forming a large group of players.
</p><p>
Also, it's worth highlighting that these changes are specifically for Gigantamax Gengar this weekend, in a manner that suggests Niantic realises it needs to throw the game's community something of a bone to encourage participation in the feature once again. 
</p>
<p>
Could these changes stick? "Other Gmax encounters are unaffected for now," a Niantic spokesperson said, "but we MAY make changes to them in the future."
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 exec praises Dragon Age: The Veilguard, calls it the "first Dragon Age game that truly knows what it wants to be"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-exec-praises-dragon-age-the-veilguard-calls-it-the-first-dragon-age-game-that-truly-knows-what-it-wants-to-be</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-exec-praises-dragon-age-the-veilguard-calls-it-the-first-dragon-age-game-that-truly-knows-what-it-wants-to-be.1021578/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-exec-praises-dragon-age-the-veilguard-calls-it-the-first-dragon-age-game-that-truly-knows-what-it-wants-to-be<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/whisper-it-but-dragon-age-the-veilguard-has-me-thinking-the-unthinkable-it-looks-like-bioware-is-back">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> is finally here, and lots of people are liking it. And one person liking it very publicly is <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-a-critical-success-with-critical-failures">Baldur's Gate 3</a> developer Larian's outspoken director of publishing, Michael Douse - who's been praising BioWare's new RPG, calling it, among other things, "the first Dragon Age game that truly knows what it wants to be."
</p>
<p>
Douse isn't one to shy away from sharing his opinions on social media, of course, having recently fired shots at Ubisoft following <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/prince-of-persia-the-lost-crown">Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown</a>'s underperformance, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/larians-director-of-publishing-calls-out-baldurs-gate-3-ce-scalpers-for-making-people-sad">called out scalpers</a> for "making [people] sad", and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-boss-blasts-publisher-greed-behind-layoffs">spoken candidly</a> about the games industry's current layoff culture, noting, "None of these companies are at risk of going bankrupt... they're just at risk of pissing off the shareholders." But following the launch of Dragon Age: The Veilguard, Douse is singing a rather more positive tune.
</p>
<p>
"I've been playing Dragon Age: The Veilguard in complete secrecy (behind my backpack at the office in front of a giant window, in the kitchen)," he <a href="https://x.com/Cromwelp/status/1850949592667590700">wrote on X</a>. "From me, you may be wondering, 'Is this a game compatible with my experience during BG3' so I'll tackle it from that perspective. The answer is yes. It is to a heavy, nine-season-long show what a well-made, character driven, binge-worthy <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/netflix">Netflix</a> series is. It has a good sense of propulsion and forward momentum. The combat system is honestly brilliant (to me, a mix of Xenoblade and Hogwarts which is giga-brain genius). It knows when it needs a tentpole narrative moment, and it knows when to let you toy around with your class and exploit some of its stronger elements."
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Here's a video version of our Dragon Age: The Veilguard review.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9f0BX-JXzek" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"More important," Douse added, "to me, it feels like the first Dragon Age game that truly knows what it wants to be... If you want some character-driven romping with a strong combat system in a universe you know, love, or have heard of, it is much better than the average action game, and much less heavy than the gargantuan RPGs that may intimidate at times. In a word, it's fun!"
</p><p>
"I'll always be a [<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dragon-age-origins">Dragon Age: Origins</a>] guy," Douse continued in a <a href="https://x.com/Cromwelp/status/1850951012053295168">follow-up post</a>, "and this is not that. But at least it's something it wants to be, and not a mishmash of everything. I respect that. I like action games, like RPGs, I like it when they collide. I like shooting baddies with mage magic. Your mileage may vary!"
</p>
<p>
It's a positive outlook on The Veilguard shared by Eurogamer's Robert Purchese, who slapped Dragon Age's latest outing with five shiny gold stars in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-review">his enthusisatic review</a>. "What BioWare has managed to accomplish here," he wrote, "in the face of all the pressure it's faced since Dragon Age: Inquisition came out 10 years ago, is extraordinary. From head to toe, wing to wing, The Veilguard is exquisitely realised and full of sophistication across systems and storytelling. It's warm and welcoming, funny and hopeful, gentle when it needs to be, and of course it's epic - epic in a way I think will set a high bar not only for BioWare in years to come but for role-playing games in general. This is among the very best of them."
</p>
<p>
But back to Douse for one last observation: "I'm extremely happy BioWare gets to stick around - presumably - in these uncertain (because of moronic corporate greed) times," he concluded. "[The Veilguard is] an existential game, and a fun one at that."
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>