<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 12:12:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Official" Russian Military game depicting invasion of Ukraine released on Steam as Yunarmy propaganda]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/official-russian-military-game-depicting-invasion-of-ukraine-released-on-steam-as-yunarmy-propaganda</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/official-russian-military-game-depicting-invasion-of-ukraine-released-on-steam-as-yunarmy-propaganda.1201401/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/official-russian-military-game-depicting-invasion-of-ukraine-released-on-steam-as-yunarmy-propaganda<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Includes real-life "historical conflicts".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>SPN Studio</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A new game was released yesterday on Steam depicting Russia's invasion of Ukraine, claiming to be "officially recommended by the Russian Military".</p>
<p>The free-to-play Squad 22: ZOV is a tactical shooter from developer SPN Studio and publisher Zarobana Entertainment and is the only release from either company.</p>
<p>The game has been widely reported as Russian propaganda, raising questions on how it's been allowed on Valve's Steam platform.</p>
<p>According to the game's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3573040/Squad_22_ZOV/">Steam description</a>, it allows players to experience the "complexities of the 2014 and 2022-2024 events through compelling campaigns". In 2014, President Putin signed the Crimea annexation, while 2022-2024 refers to the country's invasion of Ukraine.</p>
<p>While the game purports to be historically accurate through its basis on "people's experience and opinions during specific historical conflicts", it has also been "officially recommended by the Russian Military for use as a basic infantry tactic manual for cadet and Yunarmy training".</p>
<p>The modern Yunarmy, or the Young Army Cadets National Movement, was set up in 2015 by Putin to encourage young people to join the military. Now it appears officially recommending video games is part of this process. As shared on the game's website, Squad 22: ZOV was <a href="https://squad22.online/army2024/">exhibited at the Army 2024 event</a>.</p>
<p>The game's website also <a href="https://squad22.online/gameteam/">boasts special military consultants</a>, including "Hero of the Russian Federation" Vlad Golovin who commanded a platoon in the siege of Mariupol. This is included as a playable mission in the game, as well as the Russian Spring of 2014.</p>
<p>The ZOV in the title refers to the use of these letters on military equipment to show support for the invasion.</p>
<p>The game also allows players to "rescue hostages" and "capture prisoners", presumably from a Russian perspective, as well as "encounter and interact with civilians".</p>
<p>Incidentally, the developer has also admitted on the Steam page to using AI "as a base for work of our 2D artists and later drawn-over in order to make them genuine art".</p>
<p>Sources told Eurogamer the game presents players as Russian soldiers "liberating" real-life Ukrainian territories, adding the free-to-play game also includes paid content for specific campaigns. That means Valve is financially enabling a military-affiliated project, though it's unclear if the Russian Military is being indirectly funded through the developer's affiliation with the organisation.</p>
<p>The Steam page itself has become a hub for coordinated propaganda and hate speech. The game has a "mixed" reaction on the platform and recent reviews are predominantly negative, but older positive reviews include pro-Russian sentiment and disturbing comments.</p>
<p>A social media account linked on Steam to the game's developer includes a post suggesting Ukraine's refusal to surrender will provide "a lot of content to make more missions in our game" (thanks <a href="https://simulationdaily.com/news/steam-russian-military-propaganda-game/">Simulation Daily</a>).</p>
<p>Further, as spotted by <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/05/27/russian-army-backed-military-propaganda-game-squad-22-zov-listed-on-steam">Game Informer</a>, the <a href="https://cpd.gov.ua/en/results/how-russia-militarizes-society-through-computer-games/">Ukrainian Centre for Countering Disinformation</a> has already had its eye on Squad 22: ZOV, describing it as "a key element in brainwashing the population, reflecting the Russian government's version of events regarding the invasion of Ukraine and glorifying military service".</p>
<p>Back in 2018, <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/593110/announcements/detail/1666776116200553082">Steam stated</a> its approach to content on its platform was "to allow everything onto the Steam Store, except for things that we decide are illegal, or straight up trolling". Instead, its focus is on giving users "control over what kinds of content they see".</p>
<p>Eurogamer has contacted Valve for details on what moderation checks were taken ahead of Squad 22: ZOV's release, and whether the game will remain on the platform.</p>
<p>Valve has recently removed some controversial games from its Steam platform, including a game which described itself as "address[ing] the Israel x Palestine conflict from a Palestinian perspective" that was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/uk-counter-terrorism-unit-demands-steam-withdraw-controversial-shooter-from-sale">removed from sale in the UK following demands by the UK's counter-terrorism unit</a>.</p>
<p>More recently, the game <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-quietly-removes-explicit-game-featuring-extreme-sexual-violence-from-steam-in-uk">No Mercy was removed following widespread criticism</a> of its content depicting explicit sexual violence.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo updates mobile app ahead of Switch 2 launch, adding GameChat and screenshot upload]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-updates-mobile-app-ahead-of-switch-2-launch-adding-gamechat-and-screenshot-upload</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-updates-mobile-app-ahead-of-switch-2-launch-adding-gamechat-and-screenshot-upload.1201353/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-updates-mobile-app-ahead-of-switch-2-launch-adding-gamechat-and-screenshot-upload<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Zelda Notes still to come.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo / Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Nintendo has updated its mobile app ahead of the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2</a>'s launch, including GameChat functionality and its improved screenshot upload feature.</p>
<p>Previously known as the Nintendo Switch Online mobile app, it's now named Nintendo Switch App in line with the change.</p>
<p>The Album feature is particularly welcome, as screenshots and videos taken on a Switch 2 console will be automatically uploaded to the app ready to be saved and shared.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Legend of Zelda games – Nintendo Switch 2 Editions &amp; ZELDA NOTES – Overview Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dmDD7JSfhcE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Legend of Zelda games – Nintendo Switch 2 Editions &amp; ZELDA NOTES – Overview Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dmDD7JSfhcE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dmDD7JSfhcE?autoplay=1" title="The Legend of Zelda games – Nintendo Switch 2 Editions &amp; ZELDA NOTES – Overview Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Legend of Zelda games – Nintendo Switch 2 Editions &amp; ZELDA NOTES – Overview Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dmDD7JSfhcE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Previously, players would need to scan a QR code on the console to link to their mobile device, which was a clunky process. Now it will work just like the PlayStation and Xbox equivalent apps.</p>
<p>GameChat notifications have also been added to the app. This is the new social feature on Switch 2 that allows players to voice or video chat with each other while playing.</p>
<p>Notifications for GameChat will now appear on the app, letting you know you've been invited to a call.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo / Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Another inclusion on the app will be the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/achievements-can-be-earned-in-switch-2-editions-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom">Zelda Notes feature</a>, used in both <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-breath-of-the-wild-walkthrough-guide-tips-4857">Breath of the Wild</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-walkthrough-tips-9343">Tears of the Kingdom</a>. This will include achievements, a voice navigation guide, and all-new voice memories not in the original versions.</p>
<p>Though featured on the app, Zelda Notes will be added on Switch 2 release day - 5th June.</p>
<p>Last week, we reported <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2s-gamechat-feature-requires-a-mobile-phone-number">GameChat will require users to register a phone number</a> to use. The GameChat website states as an "additional security measure" text message verification "is required to set up GameChat".</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-reportedly-already-out-in-the-wild-but-needs-a-day-one-update-to-function">Some Switch 2 consoles are now out in the hands of the public</a> ahead of its release next week, with videos appearing online of the console being unboxed and its initial startup menus - though they're no longer available to view online. However, the console requires a day one update to function, meaning it's not yet playable.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There's a Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles game coming to Meta Quest 3 and SteamVR]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/theres-a-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-game-coming-to-meta-quest-3-and-steamvr</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/theres-a-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-game-coming-to-meta-quest-3-and-steamvr.1201158/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/theres-a-teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-game-coming-to-meta-quest-3-and-steamvr<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Cortopia Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
The heroes in a half shell are back, and this time they're pressing right up against your eyeballs. That's thanks to their debut VR outing, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles</a>: Empire City, which is coming to Meta Quest 3 and SteamVR sometime next year.
</p>
<p>
Empire City is the work of Cortopia Studios - which co-developed last year's well-received gladiatorial bludgeon-'em-up Gorn 2 - and follows Leonardo, Raphael, Donatello, and Michelangelo in an action-adventure set on (and presumably under) the Foot Clan-infested streets of New York City following Shredder's demise.
</p>
<p>
It's an adventure described as "equal parts hard-hitting combat and an exploration of the bonds of brotherhood", and there's talk of "fluid parkour" as players - and up to three friends - scale the urban landscape. Fan-favourite villains are also promised, all readying for a walloping - in battles built around strikes and blocks - with each turtle's signature weapon.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Empire City" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NAdtmj5S84I?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Empire City</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NAdtmj5S84I?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NAdtmj5S84I?autoplay=1" title="Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Empire City">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Empire City announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NAdtmj5S84I" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
And that, apart from confirmation The Last Ronin author Tom Waltz is saving as narrative consultant, is about all we know. The teaser trailer above isn't much more informative, but you'll find a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3713650/Teenage_Mutant_Ninja_Turtles_Empire_City/">handful of screenshots over on Steam</a>. Expect more details in the run up to Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Empire City's Steam VR and Meta Quest release in 2026.
</p>
<p>
It's been busy few years for the Turtles, of course; following 2022's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/shredders-revenge-is-a-reminder-of-the-richness-and-joy-of-16-bit-animations">brilliant beat-'em-up Shredder's Revenge</a> and acclaimed 2023 movie outing Mutant Mayhem, last year brought the fairly middling Mutants Unleashed and rogue-like Splintered Fate. Strange Scaffold took on the series earlier this month, nudging it into turn-based strategy territory with Tactical Takedown, and it's already been confirmed more games - including the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tmnt-graphic-novel-the-last-ronin-will-become-a-dark-god-of-war-style-video-game">God of War-inspired The Last Ronin</a> - are on the way. As a scaly green youth once put it, "Totally tubular, dude!"
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 sequel gets a new name as pre-production phase now officially underway]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-gets-a-new-name-as-pre-production-phase-now-officially-underway</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-gets-a-new-name-as-pre-production-phase-now-officially-underway.1201137/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-gets-a-new-name-as-pre-production-phase-now-officially-underway<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>And Witcher 3 sales surpass 60m.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer/CD Projekt</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
CD Projekt's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a> sequel has officially shed its Project Orion codename and will henceforth be known as Cyberpunk 2. That's as the studio provides its latest development update, confirming it's now entered the pre-production phase.
</p>
<p>
A Cyberpunk 2077 sequel, codenamed Project Orion, was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cd-projekt-red-announces-cyberpunk-2077-sequel-future-witcher-projects-outlined">formally announced back in 2022</a>, and CD Projekt has been providing investors with progress updates on its development since then. Most recently, back in March, it revealed Project Orion was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cd-projekt-shares-witcher-and-cyberpunk-project-updates-announces-partnership-with-mobile-developer-scopely">nearing the end of its concept phase</a> and would be entering pre-production "in the coming weeks". And now, as per the <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/media/news/cd-projekt-wraps-up-the-beginning-of-2025/">studio's Q1 2025 earnings results</a>, pre-production is officially underway.
</p>
<p>
Announcing its latest development milestone, CD Projekt also took the opportunity to jettison the Project Orion codename and instead begin referring to the sequel simply as Cyberpunk 2. This doesn't, however, mean the name will permanently stick; CD Projekt <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/675651/cd-projekt-red-cyberpunk-2-project-orion">told The Verge</a> Cyberpunk 2 "just means it's another game in the Cyberpunk universe."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition — Nintendo Switch 2 Announcement Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fAbW5AY7C68?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition — Nintendo Switch 2 Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fAbW5AY7C68?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fAbW5AY7C68?autoplay=1" title="Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition — Nintendo Switch 2 Announcement Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Cyberpunk 2077 comes to Switch 2 next week.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fAbW5AY7C68" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Despite these notable developments, Cyberpunk 2's team size has only seen a modest increase since the beginning of the year, with 96 developer now confirmed to be working on the project versus 84 in February. The bulk of the studio, as expected, is currently focused on <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a>, with 422 employees assigned to the project. That's compared to the modest 49 developers working on multiplayer The Witcher spin-off Project Sirius, and the 19 on Project Hadar - which is planned to be the studio's first-ever original game.
</p>
<p>
All these production updates were accompanied by a number of sales milestones. Cyberpunk 2077 expansion <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty">Phantom Liberty</a> has, for instance, now sold over 10m copies, while <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt">The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</a> - which this year <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/inside-cd-projekt-red-when-the-witcher-3-wild-hunt-launched">celebrates its tenth anniversary</a> - has seen over 60m sales. 
</p>
<p>
As for what's next, CD Projekt has been <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-hands-on-with-cyberpunk-2077-on-switch-2-can-the-new-nintendo-console-handle-it">priming a Switch 2 version of Cyberpunk 2077</a> to release alongside the console next week, and a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cd-projekt-is-bringing-cyberpunk-2077-to-macs-early-next-year">Mac port is also on the way</a>. The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/geralt-actor-celebrates-witcher-4-protagonist-ciri-following-woke-criticism">Ciri-starring Witcher 4</a> is likely still some considerable way off, with the newly monikered Cyberpunk 2 - which will reportedly <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Eurogamer/posts/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-features-second-city-thats-like-chicago-gone-wrong-says-se/">take players to second city like "Chicago gone wrong"</a> - to follow.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>