<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 17:22:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grounded 2 is celebrating its release with a chance to win a 10-foot ant plushie you can use to frighten a child]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/grounded-2-is-celebrating-its-release-with-a-chance-to-win-a-10-foot-fluffy-ant-you-can-use-to-frighten-a-child</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grounded-2-is-celebrating-its-release-with-a-chance-to-win-a-10-foot-ant-plushie-you-can-use-to-frighten-a-child.1252503/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Forget <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/enjoy-8-inches-of-lego-shadow-the-hedgehog-this-october">eight inches of Shadow the Hedgehog</a>; forget <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/treat-yourself-to-22-inches-of-snake-with-big-boss-metal-gear-solid-3-snake-eater-statue">22 inches of Solid Snake</a> (until you're alone at least), and behold the terrifying majesty of Grounded 2's 10-foot ant plushie/gaming chair hybrid, which Microsoft is currently giving away to promote its upcoming sequel.
</p>
<p>
Grounded 2 is, of course, the follow-up to Obsidian Entertainment's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/grounded-review-a-delightful-mix-of-harsh-survival-and-warm-hearted-design">well-received 2022 co-op garden survival game</a>, which cast players as inadvertently miniaturised children - very much in the style of 80s movie favourite Honey, I shrunk the Kids - then set them loose in a backyard now transformed into a perilous landscape of towering blades of grass and truck-sized spiders.
</p>
<p>
Obsidian's sequel doesn't do much to shake up the fundamental premise - you're small again, but this time in a park - but that new location should hopefully spice things up, and then there are mounts. Yup, this time you can saddle up on insects and barrel around the place, bringing us back to that giant ant. Xbox's <a href="https://x.com/Xbox/status/1948367630902931457">giveaway</a> features a monstrous plushie version of that aforementioned mount, sprawling threateningly across your gaming room floor and equipped with a little saddle you can pop your botty on, spread-eagled and ready for more survival.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Grounded 2 | Early Access Story Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Shyth7f8zd4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Grounded 2 | Early Access Story Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Shyth7f8zd4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Shyth7f8zd4?autoplay=1" title="Grounded 2 | Early Access Story Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Grounded 2 story trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Shyth7f8zd4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
All you need do to be in with a chance of winning (as per <a href="https://rules.xboxpromotions.com/grounded2?ocid=Sweepstakes_soc_omc_xbo_tw_Photo_lrn_7.23.1">Microsoft's T&amp;Cs</a>) is repost one <a href="https://x.com/Xbox">official Xbox</a> promotional Grounded 2 post featuring the hashtag #Grounded2Sweepstakes on X, or, if your preferred social media hellscape is Instagram, comment on an <a href="https://www.instagram.com/xbox/">official Xbox</a> Grounded 2 promotional post with the phrase #Grounded2Sweepstakes. One winner will walk away with (well, awkwardly shuffle away with) that 10ft gaming ant, which Microsoft officially refers to as "gaming furniture", if you were wondering.
</p>
<p>
As for Grounded 2 itself, it launches into PC early access and Xbox Series X/S "game preview" on 29th July, and our Bertie Purchase has been having a natter with Obsidian ahead of its release. So far, Bertie's managed to glean Grounded 2 <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/obsidian-says-grounded-2-wont-have-lan-multiplayer-either-and-its-a-huge-shame">won't have LAN multiplayer</a>, that it might be the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/grounded-could-grow-into-a-trilogy-and-there-are-already-ideas-that-could-fill-a-potential-grounded-3">second part of a trilogy</a>, and even got some not entirely subtle hints we can <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/will-grounded-2-come-to-playstation-and-switch-2-grounded-was-on-all-those-platforms-teases-obsidian-executive-producer">probably expect it on Switch 2 and PS5</a>. So thanks ants. <a href="https://youtu.be/9jtU9BbReQk">Thants</a>.
</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/grounded-2-is-celebrating-its-release-with-a-chance-to-win-a-10-foot-fluffy-ant-you-can-use-to-frighten-a-child]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2XKO tournaments could start earlier than you think, due to this closed beta feature]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/2xko-tournaments-could-start-earlier-than-you-think-due-to-this-closed-beta-feature</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2xko-tournaments-could-start-earlier-than-you-think-due-to-this-closed-beta-feature.1252443/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/project-l">2XKO</a> developers at Riot Games have confirmed that the upcoming 2v2 fighting game will have a cool feature in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heads-up-arcane-fans-vi-has-been-revealed-as-2xkos-eighth-fighter-ahead-of-its-final-beta-landing-in-september">its closed beta</a> that should allow for a wave of competitive tournaments to flourish before its full release.
</p>
<p>This feature is offline play, confirmed by <a href="https://x.com/TheNitten/status/1948130703540891659">executive producer Tom Cannon</a> on the 2XKO Discord. Now that may not sound like a big deal, but there are a few quirks and considerations that make this a bigger deal than you may assume. For one, all characters are playable offline. 
</p>
<p>That means that from the closed beta launch until the foreseeable future, new characters won't have to be arduously unlocked or grinded out in-game to play with friends or at big tournaments. This is cool for everyone, but for tournament organisers who need dozens of set-ups with all characters unlocked, it's a lifesaver.
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="2XKO - Official Vi Gameplay Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B6Jntcnc6g8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>2XKO - Official Vi Gameplay Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B6Jntcnc6g8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/B6Jntcnc6g8?autoplay=1" title="2XKO - Official Vi Gameplay Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Watch the Vi character reveal trailer for 2XKO here!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B6Jntcnc6g8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>On top of that, the lack of an online connection is a massive deal for these tournaments as it lowers costs. If you rent out a venue, you often have to pay for internet access. This can be expensive for larger events in convention centres or hotels. Plus, the internet in these venues isn't always stable. In a competitive environment, having a local match fall apart due to an internet connection would be a major problem.
</p>
<p>Riot Games is essentially making this decision to lend a head to the competitive space, which even today acts as a major foundation for the genre's popularity. Be it smaller events in your local cities, or annual super-events bringing in thousands of players, the in-person experience remains central to the overall enjoyment of fighting games. 
</p>
<p>2XKO has been present at the largest of these events - Evo - in the years prior to its release. The reason being a consistent source of feedback from players of all levels of skill and a way of telling genre diehards that this new company stepping into the space understands what the core audience values. So if you're excited for 2XKO, or just want an excuse to get out of the house in September when the closed beta launches, this is certainly good news for you.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/2xko-tournaments-could-start-earlier-than-you-think-due-to-this-closed-beta-feature]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If you want yet another way to experience The Last of Us games, there's a new script book on the way]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/if-you-want-yet-another-way-to-experience-the-last-of-us-games-theres-a-new-script-book-on-the-way</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/if-you-want-yet-another-way-to-experience-the-last-of-us-games-theres-a-new-script-book-on-the-way.1252392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Naughty Dog</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A book containing the video game scripts for both of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/naughty-dog">Naughty Dog</a>'s The Last of Us games, including the first game's Left Behind DLC, is being released.</p>
<p>The tome itself has the very appropriate title The Last of Us: Part 1 and Part 2 Scripts, and is coming from the games' developer Naughty Dog in collaboration with Dark Horse Books. It will be released on 16th December, though pre-orders are open now via <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1506751326?ie=UTF8&amp;smid=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;th=1&amp;linkCode=sl1&amp;tag=sec2002-20">Amazon US</a> for $66.63. I have popped a message over to Sony to get clarification on UK availability and pricing.</p>
<p>"Relive every climactic moment in The Last of Us: Part 1 and Part 2 Scripts, from Joel and Ellie's time with Tess in Boston, to Ellie's joy while petting giraffes, to Joel's heart-wrenching decision at the Fireflies' hospital in The Last of Us Part 1. Then, dive into The Last of Us Part 2's dual-perspective story, including Abby's shocking introduction, Ellie and Dina forging a bond together, an enthralling encounter with the Rat King, and the final showdown between Ellie and Abby," reads the official blurb.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="You can now play The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Chronologically!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/97NyUvuO-tQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>You can now play The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Chronologically!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/97NyUvuO-tQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/97NyUvuO-tQ?autoplay=1" title="You can now play The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Chronologically!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>You can now play The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered Chronologically! <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=97NyUvuO-tQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Along with the scripts, this book will also include a forward from Troy Baker, who among other roles voices Joel in the Last of Us games, as well as an art gallery with work by principal character concept artist Hyoung Nam, and a cover with new art and block printing along the pages edges which have been designed to evoke "the franchise's iconic Cordyceps fungus" (see below).</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Naughty Dog/Dark Horse</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"At its beginning, The Last of Us was a series of philosophical themes - grief, unconditional love, the relentless pursuit of justice - waiting to be shaped into a story," the Last of Us' creator Neil Druckmann said, via <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/the-last-of-us-book-scripts-video-game-1236468201/">Variety</a>. "These scripts, written during the games' development, were meant to guide our team as we brought that world to life. They were never intended for public view - until now. For the first time, we're sharing them with you - hoping this rare glimpse brings you even closer to the heart of Joel, Ellie, Abby, and the world they inhabit."</p>
<p>Halley Gross, who co-wrote The Last of Us Part 2 with Druckmann, added: "Neil and I had the honour of leading this story, but the truth is, it only exists because of the remarkable team at Naughty Dog. Every moment was built by people who bring their full hearts and talent to the table. This compilation is a tribute to the studio and a celebration of what's possible when we create together."</p>
<p>Naughty Dog is really getting quite a bit of mileage out of its The Last of Us games. Along with a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-tv-show-renewed-for-season-three-and-the-second-hasnt-even-aired-yet">TV adaptation</a>, the developer also in the last couple of years has debuted a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-ps5-tech-analysis">souped-up PlayStation 5 Part 2 Remastered release</a>, as well as a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-part-2-remastered-finally-gets-itself-a-pc-release-date">PC version of The Last of Us Part 2</a> (which followed a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2023-the-last-of-us-part-1-on-pc-what-we-think-so-far">PC release</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2022-the-last-of-us-part-1-the-digital-foundry-tech-review">remastered release</a> of the first game in the series).</p>
<p>The team also recently issued an update for The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered, which <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/you-can-now-play-the-last-of-us-part-2-in-yet-another-way-as-naughty-dog-releases-chronological-mode">allows you to play through the game in chronological order</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/if-you-want-yet-another-way-to-experience-the-last-of-us-games-theres-a-new-script-book-on-the-way]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>