<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 11:10:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hideki Kamiya's "artistic spirit would die" had he stayed at Platinum Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/hideki-kamiyas-artistic-spirit-would-die-had-he-stayed-at-platinum-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hideki-kamiyas-artistic-spirit-would-die-had-he-stayed-at-platinum-games.1062273/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/hideki-kamiyas-artistic-spirit-would-die-had-he-stayed-at-platinum-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Plus the meaning behind new Okami studio Clovers.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hideki-kamiya-clovers.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Clovers</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Hideki Kamiya has stated if he'd continued working for Platinum Games his "artistic spirit [would] die".</p>
<p>The former Platinum vice-president has launched a new studio with another former Platinum employee, Kaneto Koyama, as discussed in a new interview with Japanese outlet <a href="https://news.denfaminicogamer.jp/interview/2412133p">denfaminicogamer</a>.</p>
<p>The pair have set up Clovers, which will develop a sequel to the much-loved Okami, originally developed by Kamiya at Clover Studio.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Okami sequel - Project Teaser Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mSoZgCCxyQc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Okami sequel - Project Teaser Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mSoZgCCxyQc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mSoZgCCxyQc?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Okami sequel - Project Teaser Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mSoZgCCxyQc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"This is purely my personal opinion, but I thought, 'If I continue working here, my artistic spirit will die'," said Kamiya on his reasons for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bayonetta-creator-hideki-kamiya-leaving-platinumgames">leaving Platinum last year</a> (via machine translation).</p>
<p>"I can understand the way PlatinumGames is as a company and its logic, and I was in the position of vice president myself, but as an individual named Hideki Kamiya, I was unable to embrace that way of thinking."</p>
<p>As vice president, Kamiya was "field-first" at Platinum Games - he described himself as the muscle and CEO Atsushi Inaba as the brains.</p>
<p>"The signals sent from the cerebrum are essential for muscles," Kamiya continued. "At the same time, those signals must be reliable for muscles. Until then, I had received those signals, trusted them, and worked to maximize my own strength...but with regards to the future direction of Platinum with Inaba at the helm, I was no longer able to place my trust in them and exert my strength as a muscle."</p>
<p>Kamiya has been quite vocal about his decision to leave Platinum Games, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hideki-kamiya-left-platinum-games-due-to-issue-of-trust">previously stating there were issues of "trust"</a>.</p>
<p>He then launched a YouTube channel where he discussed his next project. "I already have a clear idea in mind," he said. "I would like to translate this vision in my head into a full proposal as soon as I am able to do so. And of course, I also have an idea of what I can do to make the project a reality. But if you ask me specifically what kind of game it will be, all I can say at this stage is, 'It'll be a Hideki Kamiya game'."</p>
<p>It's unclear if that project is the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/okami-sequel-in-the-works-with-capcom-and-hideki-kamiyas-new-studio-clovers">new Okami sequel</a>, announced as in-development at this year's The Game Awards last week.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/%C5%8Ckami-Sequel-_keyart_teaser_4K_horizontal.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Teaser artwork for the Okami sequel | <span>Image credit: <cite>Clovers</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In this new interview, Kamiya and Koyama explained the Clovers name of the new studio. It's been interpreted as "C lovers", with four Cs relating to the four leaves of a clover.</p>
<p>Only three Cs are set in stone though: challenge, creativity, and craftsmanship. The fourth C is for employees to decide upon themselves.</p>
<p>In a previous interview, Kamiya stated <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/okamis-initial-sales-were-huge-failure-says-director-hideki-kamiya">Okami's sales were a "huge failure"</a> and that had the game been more successful Clover Studio probably would have continued.</p>
<p>Little is known about the new Okami game, beyond the above teaser image.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong producer on The Game Awards top prize snub: "I came all the way here for nothing!"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-producer-on-the-game-awards-top-prize-snub-i-came-all-the-way-here-for-nothing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukong-producer-on-the-game-awards-top-prize-snub-i-came-all-the-way-here-for-nothing.1062264/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-producer-on-the-game-awards-top-prize-snub-i-came-all-the-way-here-for-nothing<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/%F0%9F%94%86-SUMMER-GAME-FEST-2024-(Official-4K-60-FPS-Livestream)---LIVE-TODAY!-2p-PT_5p-ET_10p-BST_11p-CEST-42-46-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Game Science</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/black-myth-wukong">Black Myth: Wukong</a> producer and Game Science CEO Feng Ji has posted a lengthy statement following the action game's apparent snub for the top prize at this year's The Game Awards.</p>
<p>"The games nominated this year were all exceptional, but honestly, I still can't figure out what the criteria were for Game of the Year. I feel like I came all the way here for nothing!" he wrote in a post on <a href="https://weibo.com/6603744955/5111567333196223">Weibo</a> (translated on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PS5/comments/1he81dp/game_producer_of_black_myth_wukongs_post_after_tga/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">reddit</a>).</p>
<p>Black Myth: Wukong did come away with the Best Action Game and Players' Voice awards, so he didn't leave empty handed.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Black Myth: Wukong - Pre-Orders Now Available | August 20, 2024 - Confront Destiny" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zW65D4usKSs?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Black Myth: Wukong - Pre-Orders Now Available | August 20, 2024 - Confront Destiny</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zW65D4usKSs?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/zW65D4usKSs?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Black Myth: Wukong - Confront Destiny<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zW65D4usKSs" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Since last night, I've seen a lot of strong dissatisfaction and frustration in players' comments - often expressed humorously or ironically, which made me laugh," the producer continued.</p>
<p>"I completely understand these feelings and share the frustration, because behind these emotions lies not pain or malice, but dignity and confidence."</p>
<p>Feng Ji even admitted he wrote his Game of the Year acceptance speech two years ago, "only to never get the chance to deliver it".</p>
<p>It's unclear how joking he has been in his statement, especially considering the machine translation, but some have read it as rather salty. Eurogamer has contacted Game Science for further comment.</p>
<p>The producer continued to express his confidence in the game and his hopes the success of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-review">Black Myth Wukong</a> is the beginning of a new wave of high-quality, engaging games from Chinese developers.</p>
<p>Former Sony Santa Monica writer Alanah Pearce shared in a stream she witnessed a person from the Game Science team crying in the audience when the game didn't win. "It clearly meant a lot to them, they did an amazing thing, but I did find that surprising," said Pearce.</p>
<div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>Black Myth: Wukong lost out to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-game-awards-2024-winners-list-who-won-what-this-year">Astro Bot for the Game of the Year award</a>, which also won Best Game Direction, Best Action/Adventure Game, and Best Family Game. Balatro and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metaphor-refantazio">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a> also came away with multiple awards.</p>
<p>An <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukongs-big-new-patch-adds-new-shrine-challengers-a-chart-to-chart-the-journeyers-journey">update for Black Myth: Wukong</a> released last week ahead of the awards, finally bringing a much-requested map, as well as a boss rush challenge mode.</p>
<p>Its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/black-myth-wukong-xbox-delay-not-due-to-platform-limitations-microsoft-reiterates">Xbox release is still unknown</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yes, The Witcher 4's Ciri has been recast]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/yes-the-witcher-4s-ciri-has-been-recast</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yes-the-witcher-4s-ciri-has-been-recast.1062006/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/yes-the-witcher-4s-ciri-has-been-recast<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"We believe she truly brought Ciri to life in a way that is both faithful to the character and exciting for fans."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/witcher-4-crop.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>CD Projekt</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Yes, the rumours are true - CD Projekt Red has indeed recast <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a>'s Ciri.</p>
<p>Whilst originally it only <em>sounded</em> as though the character's original actor, Jo Wyatt, had been replaced in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-gets-its-a-first-trailer-and-yes-ciri-is-the-star">Witcher 4's reveal trailer</a>, the development studio has now confirmed it.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Witcher IV — Cinematic Reveal Trailer | The Game Awards 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/54dabgZJ5YA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Witcher IV — Cinematic Reveal Trailer | The Game Awards 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/54dabgZJ5YA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/54dabgZJ5YA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Witcher IV — Cinematic Reveal Trailer | The Game Awards 2024.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=54dabgZJ5YA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Ciara Berkeley was cast as Ciri for The Witcher 4 cinematic reveal trailer," the studio said in a statement to <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/the-witcher-4-ciri-voice-actor-jo-wyatt-recast-rumours/">TheGamer</a>.</p>
<p>"Ciara is a talented actress who impressed us with her enthusiasm and vocal acting skills, and in this trailer we believe she truly brought Ciri to life in a way that is both faithful to the character and exciting for fans of the series."</p>
<p>The studio did not expand on why Berkeley had been brought in to replace Wyatt, but did confirm to press that Berkeley wasn't only brought in for the trailer, but will portray Ciri in the full game, too.</p>
<p>No, your ears were not deceiving you about Geralt, either. T<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/geralt-of-town-that-was-definitely-doug-cockles-white-haired-monster-hunter-in-the-witcher-4s-reveal-trailer">hat was definitely Geralt voice actor Doug Cockle</a> popping up at the end of the Witcher 4's reveal trailer, and yes, the white-haired monster hunter will absolutely feature in some way in the upcoming game.</p>
<p>While many had assumed as much - let's be honest, it is hard to miss the gravelling tones of Cockle's Geralt - developer CD Projekt has now officially confirmed what we all thought.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>