<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 16:01:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SEGA's older executives, especially the SEGA Sammy chairman, are especially excited about the new Virtua Fighter game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/segas-older-executives-especially-the-sega-sammy-chairman-are-especially-excited-about-the-new-virtua-fighter-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/segas-older-executives-especially-the-sega-sammy-chairman-are-especially-excited-about-the-new-virtua-fighter-game.1269228/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>SEGA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Speaking to Eurogamer, producer of the new<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/virtua-fighter-6"> Virtua Fighter project</a> Riichiro Yamada revealed that there's an extraordinary level of excitement around the upcoming 3D fighting game at SEGA, especially among the company's older generation.</p>
<p>When asked about the internal mood regarding <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/virtua-fighter">Virtua Fighter</a>'s revival, Yamada stated (through a SEGA-provided translator): "In SEGA, the upper executives are very fond of Virtua Fighter, they feel it's very special to them because it has a very long history with SEGA."</p>
<p>This extends to the chairman of SEGA Sammy, Hajime Satomi. According to Yamada, he's taken special interest in the project: "He is also very fond of Virtua Fighter. He's very high up in the company and a very important guy, so even though he participates in so many meetings he doesn't really say anything. But when it comes to Virtua Fighter meetings he actually gives detailed comments because he's very fond of the series."</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="New VIRTUA FIGHTER Project | Combat Gameplay First Look - Training Stage" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KkGmeofGSw0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>New VIRTUA FIGHTER Project | Combat Gameplay First Look - Training Stage</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KkGmeofGSw0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KkGmeofGSw0?autoplay=1" title="New VIRTUA FIGHTER Project | Combat Gameplay First Look - Training Stage">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Take a look at the latest gameplay trailer for the new Virtua Fighter Project<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KkGmeofGSw0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>This excitement, according to Yamada, has trickled down to even the younger folks at the company that are unfamiliar with Virtua Fighter: "There are a lot of people in upper management who are really looking forward to this. Thanks to this hype from the upper management people, the younger generation who may not have touched or been handling Virtua Fighter before, a lot of them are very interested in being involved with the new project. [I] feel with SEGA's history, Virtua Fighter holds a very special place in every [developer]."</p><p>This should come as no surprise. Virtua Fighter is a legendary video game franchise that has sadly fallen by the wayside in recent years. It was revolutionary back in the arcade days, pushing the genre forward with a no-thrills simulation of hand-to-hand combat. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/first-in-engine-look-at-next-virtua-fighter-game-revealed">That's why the Virtua Fighter Project reveal was so exciting</a>, a technically staggering in-engine look at a game sticking to its roots.</p>
<p>In fact, Virtua Fighter only really survived in some forms in recent years thanks to the RGG games! In the Yakuza series, Virtua Fighter games could be played within the in-game SEGA arcades. This, according to Yamada, acted as a spark to get a new Virtua Fighter going.</p>
<p>"The RGG team were very good at AMD stuff, and that's why they wanted to implement those elements. But at the time, Virtua Fighter fans were a little bit sad that in order to play Virtua Fighter they had to play an RGG game. So because there was no environment where we could actually provide a Virtua Fighter game on its own to those fans, there was a feeling that we had to provide something for those fans.</p>
<p>This revival has been in discussion for a while within SEGA, but hadn't got the green light until recent years. Yamada elaborates: "The new sequel for Virtua Fighter has come up within Sega many many times, but there was approval or green light to proceed. So as for when we started to think about a new project, it's been a very long time."</p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/segas-older-executives-especially-the-sega-sammy-chairman-are-especially-excited-about-the-new-virtua-fighter-game]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mobile-only Resident Evil Survival Unit gets new cinematic trailer with music by Japanese rock band Queen Bee]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/mobile-only-resident-evil-survival-unit-gets-new-cinematic-trailer-with-music-by-japanese-rock-band-queen-bee</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mobile-only-resident-evil-survival-unit-gets-new-cinematic-trailer-with-music-by-japanese-rock-band-queen-bee.1269225/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>The trailer was produced by Quebico, the studio behind the full 3DCG animation Resident Evil: Death Island.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Capcom</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>While the quality of the upcoming mobile-only Resident Evil Survival Unit remains to be seen, the trailer certainly looks the part. Produced by Quebico, the studio behind the full 3DCG animation Resident Evil: Death Island, this cinematic overview shows off how players will be able to form teams of characters that span the Resident Evil universe in a battle against classic Resident Evil enemies.</p>
<p>Resident Evil Survival Unit is due for release as a free-to-play mobile title later this year on iOS and Android devices.</p>
<p>To add an extra dose of excitement to the trailer, it features the song "Mountain Hunt" by Japanese rock band Queen Bee.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Resident Evil Survival Unit - Cinematic Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/23K1G_-38HM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Resident Evil Survival Unit - Cinematic Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/23K1G_-38HM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/23K1G_-38HM?autoplay=1" title="Resident Evil Survival Unit - Cinematic Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=23K1G_-38HM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<blockquote><p>Avu-chan (Queen Bee) Comment</p>
<p>"I’m thrilled that our intense love song ‘Mountain Hunt’ was chosen for this exciting collaboration. The rapid-fire pacing and dynamic progression - ending with a bold ‘Next!’ I hope you enjoy every moment!"</p>
<p>About Queen Bee</p>
<p>QUEEN BEE is a Japanese rock band formed in 2009, consisting of Avu-chan (Vo), Yashi-chan (Ba), and Hibari-kun (Gt). Known for their distinctive vocals, genre-blending sound, and powerful performances, the band continues to captivate audiences across Japan and beyond. Their music consistently ranks high on both physical and digital charts, and their live shows frequently sell out. In August 2025, QUEEN BEE will embark on an international tour across Shanghai, Hong Kong, and Taipei.</p>
<p>Game Overview:</p>
<ul>
<li>Title: Resident Evil Survival Unit</li>
<li>Publisher: Aniplex Inc.</li>
<li>Developer: JOYCITY Corporation</li>
<li>Platforms: iOS (iPhone, iPad), Android</li>
<li>Price: Free-to-play (with in-app purchases)</li>
<li>Release: Scheduled for 2025</li>
<li>Regions: Japan, Korea, North America, Europe, Asia</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p><em>This is a news-in-brief story. This is part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-is-changing-to-give-you-more-of-what-you-want">our vision</a> to bring you all the big news as part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-in-video-games-13th-august-new-eurogamer-xbox-games-on-ps5-and-playstation-games-on-xbox">daily live report</a>.</em></p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/mobile-only-resident-evil-survival-unit-gets-new-cinematic-trailer-with-music-by-japanese-rock-band-queen-bee]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater - Fox Hunt will not support cross-play, Konami confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-fox-hunt-will-not-support-cross-play-konami-confirms</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-fox-hunt-will-not-support-cross-play-konami-confirms.1269138/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>No sneaking multiplayer action for you (a PS5) and your friends (Xbox) together unless you play with real boxes.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Konami</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Fox Hunt, the online multiplayer mode releasing later this autumn as part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a>, won't include cross-play. The news comes as we approach the 28th August release date of the game.</p>
<p>News comes via a post by the official Metal Gear Japan X.com account.</p>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>A machine translation of the post states that "cross-play between different platforms will not be supported."</p>
<blockquote><p>About Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater - Fox Hunt</p>
<p>A thrilling hide-and-seek based, completely original online multiplayer</p>
<ul>
<li>An online experience unique to Metal Gear that utilizes the central elements of the base game - camouflage and survival.</li>
</ul>
<p>Based on the Sneaking rule from METAL GEAR ONLINE</p>
<ul>
<li>Utilises the fundamentals of one of the popular game rules from Metal Gear Online and the sneaking gameplay elements iconic to the Metal Gear series, and the latest graphical enhancements that amplifies the tension of hide-and-seek to a whole new level.</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>Check out Fox Hunt in action in the extended trailer below:</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater - Official Fox Hunt Extended Look Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLKA9CQ9LBA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater - Official Fox Hunt Extended Look Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLKA9CQ9LBA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RLKA9CQ9LBA?autoplay=1" title="Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater - Official Fox Hunt Extended Look Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RLKA9CQ9LBA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>



        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-fox-hunt-will-not-support-cross-play-konami-confirms]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>