<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 11:26:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vision of Mana director quits NetEase to join Square Enix]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/vision-of-mana-director-quits-netease-to-join-square-enix</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vision-of-mana-director-quits-netease-to-join-square-enix.1049388/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/vision-of-mana-director-quits-netease-to-join-square-enix<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"I will do my best to make a game that many people can enjoy!"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Visions-of-Mana---Elemental-Vessels-Introduction-Video-_-PS5-%26-PS4-Games-0-16-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Square Enix</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Visions of Mana director Ryosuke Yoshida has departed NetEase to assume a new position with <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>.</p>
<p>In a statement on X/Twitter, Yoshida thanked NetEase and his development team for their support, but confirmed he quit the Chinese megacorp at the end of October and will join Square Enix in December.</p>
<p>Whilst Yoshida had been employed at NetEase subsidiary Ouka Studios, Visions of Mana was published by Square Enix - the company he has now joined.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Visions of Mana | Launch Date Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/slGNz-ySDfY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Visions of Mana | Launch Date Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/slGNz-ySDfY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/slGNz-ySDfY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Visions of Mana | Launch Date Trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=slGNz-ySDfY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"On a personal note, I quit NetEase Ouka Studios on October 31st. We were a new studio, but we were able to release Visions of Mana. I am grateful to the development team and NetEase for their support," Yoshida wrote (thanks, <a href="https://x.com/Knoebelbroet/status/1863447158667514060">Knoebel</a>).</p>
<p>It was a very good experience. Thank you all. I am happy to announce that I joined Square Enix in December.</p>
<p>"I will do my best to make a game that many people can enjoy!"</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">On a personal note, I quit NetEase Ouka Studios on October 31st. We were a new studio, but we were able to release Visions of Mana. I am grateful to the development team and NetEase for their support.<br>It was a very good experience. <br>Thank you all.<br>I am happy to announce that I…</p>— Ryosuke Yoshida (@YoshidaBeer) <a href="https://twitter.com/YoshidaBeer/status/1863418476637118944?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 2, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Yoshida stopped short of revealing what position he will take on at Square Enix, or what game or franchise he may be working on.</p>
<p>The news comes after Ouka Studios <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/visions-of-mana-developer-ouka-studios-reportedly-set-to-close-days-after-games-release">had "all but a handful of jobs" cut</a> by parent company NetEase.</p>
<p>Ouka Studios opened in 2020 and hired staff from the likes of Capcom and Bandai Namco.</p>
<p>Last week, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effect-veteran-will-pause-operations-at-fresh-aaa-game-studio-while-seeking-new-partner">NetEase told Eurogamer it remained committed to "a strong global presence"</a> despite pulling funding from Worlds Untold, the studio founded by <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mass-effect">Mass Effect</a> veteran Mac Walters, and just days after fellow <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effect-director-casey-hudsons-aaa-sci-fi-game-cancelled-studio-closing">BioWare veteran Casey Hudson announced the closure of his own new studio</a> due to similar funding issues.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK counter-terrorism unit demands Steam withdraw controversial shooter from sale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/uk-counter-terrorism-unit-demands-steam-withdraw-controversial-shooter-from-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/uk-counter-terrorism-unit-demands-steam-withdraw-controversial-shooter-from-sale.1049124/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/uk-counter-terrorism-unit-demands-steam-withdraw-controversial-shooter-from-sale<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"We've received a request from authorities in the UK to block the game and have applied such country restrictions."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_9a404d21ea814bd5b4a68e998a002969b39df491.1920x1080.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nidal Nijm Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Valve has removed a game from its British Steam storefront following a request from the UK's counter-terrorism unit.</p>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1714420/Fursan_alAqsa_The_Knights_of_the_AlAqsa_Mosque/">The FPS/TPS Fursan al-Aqsa: The Knights of the Al-Aqsa Mosque</a> - which describes itself as "address[ing] the Israel x Palestine conflict from a Palestinian perspective" - was removed when Steam contacted developer Nidal Nijm to inform him it had "received a request from authorities in the UK to block the game and have applied such country restrictions".</p>
<p>Originally released in 2022, the game was updated this month to include content reflecting aspects of Hamas' 7th October terrorist attack. A trailer for the update shows fighters that appear to be from Hamas landing in an Israeli base and graphically executing Israeli soldiers. 
</p>
<p>In an email to the Brazilian developer, Steam allegedly said: "We've received a request from authorities in the UK to block the game and have applied such country restrictions". When the developer reportedly asked if there was "a specific reason" for the UK ban and said "my game is not too much different than any other shooter game on Steam, like Call of Duty", he was told:</p><p>"We were contacted by the Counter Terrorism Command of the United Kingdom, specifically the Counter Terrorism Internet Referral Unit (CTIRU). As with any authority for a region the [sic] oversees and governs what content can be made available, we have to comply with their requests."</p>
<p>In an email to <a href="https://www.404media.co/steam-removes-oct-7-game-at-request-of-uk-counter-terrorism-unit/">404</a>, a counter-terrorism spokesperson said: "The CTIRU works closely with a range of technology, social media and online service providers, but we do not comment on specific content or any communication we may have with specific platforms or providers."</p>
<p>"The region lock of my game in the UK was clearly due to political reasons," Nijm wrote in a statement to the same publication.</p>
<p>"I do not blame Valve nor Steam, the blame is on the UK government and authorities that are pissed off by a video game," Nijm said. "On their flawed logic, the most recent Call of Duty <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-2024">Black Ops 6</a> should be banned as well. As you play as an American soldier and go to Iraq to kill Iraqi people. What I can say is that we see clearly the double standards."</p>
<p>The game describes itself "the Palestinian <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/max-payne">Max Payne</a> on steroids" and the "most BASED game of all times". It has already been banned in Germany and Australia for not going through the countries' respective classification boards.</p>
<p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1714420/Fursan_alAqsa_The_Knights_of_the_AlAqsa_Mosque/">The game</a> is still available to buy online outside of the UK, including the US. In the UK, however, the Steam page simply throws up an "Oops, sorry!" message, saying, "this item is currently unavailable in your region".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>