<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 18:45:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MindsEye, new thriller from former GTA producer and Hitman publisher, gets release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/mindseye-new-thriller-from-former-gta-producer-and-hitman-publisher-gets-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mindseye-new-thriller-from-former-gta-producer-and-hitman-publisher-gets-release-date.1148094/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/mindseye-new-thriller-from-former-gta-producer-and-hitman-publisher-gets-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ME_SM2-Robot-Running.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Build A Rocket Boy</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>MindsEye, the new game from former GTA producer Leslie Benzies, has finally been given a release date.</p>
<p>The game was originally revealed as part of the Everywhere project from Benzies' studio Build A Rocket Boy; then in October last year <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hitman-studio-to-publish-former-rockstar-and-gta-producers-mysterious-blockbuster-mindseye">Hitman developer IO Interactive announced it would be publishing MindsEye</a>.</p>
<p>Now it has a firm release date: 10th June 2025, across PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC. And there's a new story trailer to go with it too.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="MindsEye - Welcome to Redrock - Official Story Trailer | 2025" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oprmuMXtfAo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>MindsEye - Welcome to Redrock - Official Story Trailer | 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oprmuMXtfAo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/oprmuMXtfAo?autoplay=1" title="MindsEye - Welcome to Redrock - Official Story Trailer | 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>MindsEye - Welcome to Redrock - Official Story Trailer | 2025<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oprmuMXtfAo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The trailer for the action-adventure thriller introduces the near-future desert metropolis of Redrock City, as well as the eccentric tech boss Marco Silva eager to change the course of human evolution.</p>
<p>"We can’t wait for players to immerse themselves in our tightly crafted game, MindsEye, with a thought-provoking story where technology and ambition collide, and the inevitable consequences unravel," said Benzies.</p>
<p>Adam Whiting, assistant game director at Build A Rocket Boy, told Eurogamer the team isn't worried about a June release clashing with the traditional E3 and Summer Game Fest period. "It maybe allows us to actually talk to players, engage with players around that time in a meaningful way," he said. "We're just very excited for players to finally get the chance to play."</p>
<p>Further, Whiting confirmed that the developer is still working on Everywhere. "MindsEye is a standalone game, but it is kind of connected," he said. "You can access it through Everywhere as a platform, but mostly we're really focused on MindsEye."</p>
<p>Everywhere was first revealed at <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-at-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024">Gamescom</a> in 2022, though its purpose confused players and rumours swirled around cryptocurrency and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/topics/nfts">NFTs</a>. Benzies flatly denied this to Eurogamer during a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-producers-not-crypto-project-everywhere-is-part-episodic-blockbuster-part-roblox-rival">preview of the project in March 2023</a>.</p>
<p>It is, essentially, a platform for user-generated content, akin to Roblox, with MindsEye as a primary example from the developer itself of what can be achieved. More recently, MindsEye has taken centre stage with Everywhere humming away in the background.</p>
<p>MindsEye will be available as a standalone game for £54.99 / $59,99 / €59.99.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/layoffs-hit-gta-producers-everywhere-studio">company was hit by layoffs in early 2024</a>, a month after completing a fresh $110m funding round from investor NetEase.</p>
<p>Whiting noted to Eurogamer the industry's rapid expansion during the Covid-19 pandemic, which was followed by global layoffs. "We're seeing a lot of that stuff happening in the industry right now and it makes me sad because the games industry is full of so many very talented, very lovely people," he said. "But it's this period of the ebbs and flows, the peaks and troughs, and maybe it's in a bit of a trough now, but I'm sure it'll peak again soon."</p>
<p>He also noted that NetEase's recent, apparent pullback from video games hasn't affected the studio negatively. "Certainly, there's nothing that's let us to make any compromises or anything like that," he said.</p>
<p>"You know Leslie, he's a visionary, and he doesn't want to compromise on that vision for anything at all."</p>
<p>For more on MindsEye, check out <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mindseye-from-former-rockstar-developers-wants-to-revive-the-tight-linear-cinematic-blockbuster-game">Chris Tapsell's full interview with Whiting on the game's cinematic storytelling and thematic similarities to GTA</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>