<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 10:49:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation in talks to buy Elden Ring, Dark Souls developer FromSoftware]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-in-talks-to-buy-elden-ring-dark-souls-developer-fromsoftware</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-in-talks-to-buy-elden-ring-dark-souls-developer-fromsoftware.1039194/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-in-talks-to-buy-elden-ring-dark-souls-developer-fromsoftware<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Kadokawa buyout would also include Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership studio.</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>
PlayStation maker Sony is currently in talks that would likely see it acquire a controlling stake in FromSoftware, the developer behind <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-walkthrough-8042">Elden Ring</a>, Dark Souls and Bloodbourne, as part of a buyout of its owner, the Japanese publishing giant Kadokawa.
</p>
<p>
That's according to a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/sony-talks-buy-media-powerhouse-behind-elden-ring-sources-say-2024-11-19/">Reuters</a> report which claims a deal could be signed in weeks, via sources with knowledge of discussions between the two companies. Both Sony and Kadokawa declined to comment on that report.
</p>
<p>
Launched in 2022, Elden Ring has now sold more than 25m copies worldwide.
</p>
<p>
Sony already owns a 14 percent stake in FromSoftware, and already has ownership of both the Bloodborne and Demon Souls franchises. FromSoftware, meanwhile, owns the rights to Elden Ring and Sekiro.</p>
<p>This deal would likely result in PlayStation gaining the 69.6 percent stake in FromSoftware that Kadokawa holds, meaning it would hold a commanding 84 percent of the company. (Chinese giant <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/tencent">Tencent</a> currently owns the remaining 16 percent.)
</p>
<p>
Kadokawa owns various other studios, too. These include <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/octopath-traveler">Octopath Traveler</a> and Tenchu developer Acquire, which recently developed <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mario-and-luigi-brothership">Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership</a> for Nintendo Switch, Shiren the Wanderer studio Spike Chunsoft and RPG Maker developer Gotcha Gotcha Games.
</p>
<p>
Outside of video games, Kadokawa is also a huge name in anime and manga, and would be a significant addition to Sony's existing portfolio that includes Crunchyroll and Funimation. 
</p>
<p>
PlayStation's other recent purchases include UK studio Firesprite, plus Housemarque and Nixxes, all in 2021. Most recently, Sony bought the Jade Raymond-founded startup Haven Studios in 2022, currently working on Fairgame$.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>