<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:12:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With Avowed's 1.5 update, it finally gets Steam Deck verified, as well as some fancy new Ranger and Fighter moves]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/with-avoweds-15-update-it-finally-gets-steam-deck-verified-as-well-as-some-fancy-new-ranger-and-fighter-moves</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/with-avoweds-1-5-update-it-finally-gets-steam-deck-verified-as-well-as-some-fancy-new-ranger-and-fighter-moves.1245108/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Out now on all platforms.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer/Obsidian Entertainment</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Obsidian Entertainment has been quietly beavering away on its well-received fantasy action-RPG <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/avowed">Avowed</a>, and the latest of the studio's toils are now available in its newly released 1.5 update, introducing Steam Deck verification, new class abilities, and more.
</p>
<p>
Starting with that Steam Deck verification, it's exactly what it sounds like - providing enough under-the-hood tweaks to tick off all of Valve's boxes. And there's also a new 40fps frame rate limit option that's presumably been added as a part of Obsidian's handheld finessing.
</p>
<p>
Arguably the most significant addition in 1.5, though, comes in the form of a Ranger and Fighter refresh, with both classes getting new abilities and passives on their skill trees. This, Obsidian says, should "round out the classes compared to the Wizard tree". The full list is pretty extensive, but Fighter upgrades include the powerful block-breaking Driving Kick and pulverising Barbaric Smash, while Rangers can deploy the sneaky Shadow Step, as well as Deadly Poison. The latter, as you might imagine, makes poison more deadly.
</p>
<p>
Elsewhere, 1.5 adds more unique gear across a number of regions, meaning you'll now find (among other things) a new unique two-handed hammer and wand in Dawnshore, and a new unique one-handed axe in Shatterscarp. "We found that players were not able to play specific builds that they wanted to early on in the game," explained Obsidian, and this is the solution.
</p>
<p>
Beyond all that, there are tweaks to enemies that introduce two new types of barriers they can use - one blocking melee attacks and the other blocking magic attacks. They can also now access a number of player abilities, including Clear Out, Blizzard, and Tanglefoot. If you're looking for more granular detail, however, you'll find <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2457220/view/510711823303967381?l=english">full patch notes over on Steam</a>.
</p>
<p>
Avowed's 1.5 update - which is available now on all platforms - arrives as the second planned update in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/avoweds-2025-roadmap-promises-new-game-plus-and-more-with-an-arachnophobia-mode-out-now">Obsidian's previously announced post-launch roadmap</a>. A third update, scheduled for this autumn, is set to include New Game Plus, a photo mode, a new weapon type, new character presets, and more.
</p>
<p>
"What Avowed lacks in gloss it makes up for with charm, depth and a playful heart," Eurogamer's Robert Purchese wrote in his <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/avowed-review">four star Avowed review</a> earlier this year.
</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/with-avoweds-15-update-it-finally-gets-steam-deck-verified-as-well-as-some-fancy-new-ranger-and-fighter-moves]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Donkey Kong Bananza's destruction gameplay all started as a goomba with giant arms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/donkey-kong-bananzas-destruction-gameplay-all-started-as-a-goomba-with-giant-arms</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/donkey-kong-bananzas-destruction-gameplay-all-started-as-a-goomba-with-giant-arms.1245105/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Destruction is the core focus of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a>'s gameplay, but that all started as a goomba with giant arms.</p>
<p>Ahead of the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-nintendo-switch-2-the-digital-foundry-hardware-review">Switch 2</a> platformer's release this week, Nintendo published an <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/ask-the-developer-vol-19-donkey-kong-bananza-part-1/">interview with the development team</a> where they detailed the decision to have destructible environments at the game's core, built using voxel technology.</p>
<p>It turns out the programming team had been experimenting with destruction shortly after the release of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/super-mario-odyssey">Super Mario Odyssey</a>. They were inspired by that game's Knucklotec boss who attacks Mario with giant hands.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Donkey Kong Bananza Review - Delightful, Inventive and One of DK's Best" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nzcumZDEJTo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Donkey Kong Bananza Review - Delightful, Inventive and One of DK's Best</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nzcumZDEJTo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nzcumZDEJTo?autoplay=1" title="Donkey Kong Bananza Review - Delightful, Inventive and One of DK's Best">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Donkey Kong Bananza Review - Delightful, Inventive and One of DK's Best<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nzcumZDEJTo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>As one of Bananza's game directors, Wataru Tanaka, explained, "The programmer who created [Knucklotec] tried attaching those arms to a Goomba as an experiment. The Goomba could smash terrain, tear off pieces to use as weapons, and throw them.</p>
<p>"Those actions felt surprisingly satisfying, and we got a sense that this destruction-based gameplay could be a compelling core mechanic."</p>
<p>Nintendo even <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/ask-the-developer-vol-19-donkey-kong-bananza-part-2/">shared a video of the goomba in action</a> as part of the interview. Below is a screenshot.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As a result, the team's desire to define a new Donkey Kong aligned with the destruction-focused gameplay they were testing.</p>
<p>Indeed, Bonanza's producer Kenta Motokura noted how in a long-running series "novelty and continuity are both important" but the team wanted to "fully convey the appeal of Donkey Kong as a character".</p>
<p>As such, they wanted to split between 2D and 3D Donkey Kong games and bring the gorilla's "strengths and new actions to the forefront". The concept of destruction was seen as a good fit.</p>
<p>This also led to the use of voxel technology to create detailed destructible environments. However this proved difficult on the original Switch console with the detail the team aspired to, as this sort of technology uses a lot of system memory. Nintendo even shared comparison screenshots to show how differently the game looked across the two machines.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"With the move to Switch 2, we gained not only more memory but also greater processing capacity," said Tanaka. "That gave us the freedom to incorporate gameplay ideas we'd previously abandoned because they were too demanding. When we got down to trying it, we discovered that not only could it handle the heavy processing requirements, but it also ran at 60 fps. Things we'd given up on, like explosions flinging large objects or causing them to collapse, were now possible. Designers could also place as many objects as they wanted. There were so many moments when we thought to ourselves, 'Now we can really do this.'"</p>
<p>Donkey Kong Bananza will release on Switch 2 later this week. "A brilliant core mechanic and clever design twists make Bananza a delightfully sticky 3D platform adventure topped off with a sweet central character relationship," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/donkey-kong-bananza-review">Donkey Kong Bananza review</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/donkey-kong-bananzas-destruction-gameplay-all-started-as-a-goomba-with-giant-arms]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>