<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 13:21:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt nearly had a very different name]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt-nearly-had-very-different-name</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt-nearly-had-a-very-different-name.1202466/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt-nearly-had-very-different-name<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>It was a bit of a mouthful.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer / CD Projekt Red</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>There was a time when <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt">The Witcher 3</a> wasn't called Wild Hunt and CD Projekt Red was trying out various names for its new game - and we've just unearthed a couple we'd never heard before.</p>
<p>"I liked Northern Lights," Michal Platkow-Gilewski, vice president of communication and PR, told Eurogamer. "For a moment there was The Witcher 3: Northern Lights. It never made it into even a logo design but on the whiteboard, for a while, it was there."</p>
<p>There was also, he revealed, A Time of Axe and Sword, and he said that for a while, this name was going to be 'the one'. However, it's a bit of a mouthful to say.</p>
<p>"Yes!" Platkow-Gilewski said, speaking as part of an interview for a larger article looking back on 10 years of The Witcher 3, which we'll publish tomorrow. "That's why it died pretty fast. But I remember I created a doc with the final name and that was the final name, and with some colleagues we were betting how long it would last.</p>
<p>"It didn't last long," he added. "So we were toying with the name but the moment we found Wild Hunt..."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Witcher 4 Ciri Explained: Lore Nerd Breaks Down the White Frost, Story, and More" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EHuw6gZxqcg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Witcher 4 Ciri Explained: Lore Nerd Breaks Down the White Frost, Story, and More</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EHuw6gZxqcg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EHuw6gZxqcg?autoplay=1" title="The Witcher 4 Ciri Explained: Lore Nerd Breaks Down the White Frost, Story, and More">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>It's the lore. Of The Witcher.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EHuw6gZxqcg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The moment the studio tried "Wild Hunt", the name fit. It not only directly referenced the titular threat of the Wild Hunt in the game - the phantasmal group of riders which relentlessly pursues Ciri - but it, regardless of whether you knew the lore or not, left a strong impression of what the game might be about.</p>
<p>That was a big concern for CD Projekt Red at the time: bringing new players in. Remember back in 2013, far fewer people knew about The Witcher games, the studio making them, or the The Witcher lore - those books written by Andrzej Sapkowski. The two released Witcher games only had a cumulative 5 million sales at that point, which is an order of magnitude less than the 60 million copies The Witcher 3 has now sold. There was no Netflix Witcher TV show, either.</p>
<p>That number 3 in the game's title was a potentially off-putting thing for a prospective audience, then. Would people who hadn't played the other two games feel like they needed to in order to enjoy this? It's for precisely this reason the game's logo changed mid-campaign, switching from displaying an actual number 3 to displaying three claw-like slash marks instead. "We decided, in the middle of the campaign, with all the questions of like, 'Should I play? Do I have to play?' that we should turn the three into these marks from Eredin's helmet in the centre of the logo," Platkow-Gilewski said.</p>
<p>Today, 10 years later, The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt is the name in our heads. The question is, would a different name have had any effect on the legacy it left?</p>
<p>We also now look forward to a new Witcher game, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-dev-cd-projekt-red-talks-ciri-fan-reaction-playable-geralt-coyness-and-if-the-game-will-honour-your-previous-choices">The Witcher 4, which is in full development although not likely to be released until after 2026</a>. The new game will star Ciri as its protagonist, moving her into a central role after being the co-protagonist, of sorts, in The Witcher 3. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-dev-cd-projekt-red-talks-ciri-fan-reaction-playable-geralt-coyness-and-if-the-game-will-honour-your-previous-choices">It's a decision that's met some resistance</a> but one the game's makers, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/geralt-actor-celebrates-witcher-4-protagonist-ciri-following-woke-criticism">and people such as Geralt's English language voice actor Doug Cockle</a>, have openly and vocally stood behind.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here're this week's free Epic Games Store games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/herere-this-weeks-free-epic-games-store-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/herere-this-weeks-free-epic-games-store-games.1202433/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/herere-this-weeks-free-epic-games-store-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Tiny Tina's Wonderlands! More!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Another week is here, meaning another opportunity to expand your already dangerously swollen games library with yet more titles you won't have time to play. And this week's Epic Games Store refresh means users can currently grab two new freebies on PC, including Gearbox's well-received Borderlands spin-off <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/tiny-tinas-wonderlands">Tiny Tina's Wonderlands</a>.
</p>
<p>
Epic's latest free games - which replace <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/herere-this-weeks-free-epic-store-games">Sifu, Deliver At All Costs, and Gigapocalypse from last week</a> - are available to download now in PC and mobile flavours. You'll need to be in the EU to access Epic's mobile store on iOS, of course, but it's available via Android devices worldwide. Here's what free right now:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Tiny Tina's Wonderlands (PC)</li>
<li>Limbo (PC/mobile)</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Tiny Tina's Wonderlands: 20 Minute Official Gameplay Walkthrough" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4gg4hepQcmw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Tiny Tina's Wonderlands: 20 Minute Official Gameplay Walkthrough</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4gg4hepQcmw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4gg4hepQcmw?autoplay=1" title="Tiny Tina's Wonderlands: 20 Minute Official Gameplay Walkthrough">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's a lengthy look at Tiny Tina's Borderlands.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4gg4hepQcmw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
That, then, gives you one surprisingly decent recent-ish release and a stone-cold classic from the ancient days of gaming yore. Tiny Tina's Wonderlands is the former, taking the tabletop-inspired action of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/borderlands-2">Borderlands 2</a>'s much-loved DLC episode Tiny Tina's Assault on Dragon Keep and building it out into a full-length game of first-person fantasy adventuring. We called it "endearing" despite its "hodgepodge design" in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tiny-tinas-wonderlands-review-happy-vibes-and-hodgepodge-design">our 2022 review</a>.
</p>
<p>
As for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/limbo">Limbo</a>, it's developer PlayDead's hugely influential and deeply atmospheric side-scrolling puzzler in which a nameless boy traverses the titular black-and-white void in search of his sister. It's packed with physics-based platforming, gruesome demises, arachnid horror, and forlorn vibes - not to mention one of gaming's most memorable opening acts - and Eurogamer <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/limbo-review">called it</a> "a game that has very few humans, but a surplus of humanity" back in the day.
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/tiny-tinas-wonderlands">Tiny Tina's Wonderlands</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/limbo">Limbo</a> are available to download and keep via the Epic Games Store right now and will remain so until next Thursday, 5th June. After that, a fresh batch of (still mysterious) freebies will take their place.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft's Xbox handheld reportedly "sidelined" as it focuses on third-party portable devices]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/microsofts-xbox-handheld-reportedly-sidelined-as-it-focuses-on-third-party-portable-devices</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsofts-xbox-handheld-reportedly-sidelined-as-it-focuses-on-third-party-portable-devices.1202409/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/microsofts-xbox-handheld-reportedly-sidelined-as-it-focuses-on-third-party-portable-devices<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>ASUS partnership still targeting this year.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Microsoft has reportedly "sidelined" the development of its long-teased first-party handheld gaming device as it focuses its attention on third-party portable opportunities, including ASUS' Project Kennan, which is supposedly still due this year.
</p>
<p>
Xbox boss <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/phil-spencer">Phil Spencer</a> first discussed an Xbox handheld back in 2017, when he revealed Microsoft had "roughly designed" one in the past, and it's a subject he's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/phil-spencer-discusses-potential-xbox-handheld-plans">repeatedly returned to in recent years</a>, fuelling speculation the project had been revived. Then, this March, Windows Central reported <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-next-gen-console-reportedly-targeting-2027-with-handheld-device-due-this-year">Microsoft had settled on a multi-pronged handheld strategy</a>, and would be teaming up with a third-party to release an Xbox-branded portable gaming PC this year under the codename Kennan while it worked on its own internally developed device to release alongside an Xbox Series X/S successor in 2027.
</p>
<p>
Now, though, Windows Central <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/exclusive-xboxs-handheld-pembrooke-has-been-sidelined-for-now-as-microsoft-doubles-down-on-windows-11-pc-gaming-handheld-optimization">claims</a> Microsoft has had a bit of a strategic rethink, and development of its own handheld device has been "sidelined". According to the publication's source, the company has internally announced it'll instead "prioritise its teams to improve Windows 11 gaming performance, specifically for devices like the ASUS partner device Project Kennan" (NB. the site originally reported this under the name "Keenan" back in March, but has since updated its original story). It doesn't sound like Microsoft is completely abandoning its own handheld plans, however; Windows Central says the company "still has big ambitions and is investing heavily to deliver a native Xbox handheld", but third-party devices and Windows 11 improvements will be where it focuses its resources for now.
</p>
<p>
As for Project Kennan specifically, the website claims it's "essentially finished" on the hardware side, but that there's currently a "significantly boosted effort" between Microsoft's Xbox and Windows teams to "improve the experience on the software side". The plan, however, is that the Xbox-branded ASUS device will still launch "later this year".
</p>
<p>
Microsoft's decision to refocus on providing adequate infrastructure for Windows 11-powered third-party devices is perhaps not entirely surprising given increasing competition elsewhere; back in January, Valve announced it's been working to bring SteamOS, which powers Steam Deck, to third-party handheld gaming, and the operating system is now available on a variety of devices, including <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lenovo-unveils-legion-go-2-and-go-s-handheld-gaming-pcs-including-steamos-model">recently released official partner machine, the Lenovo Legion Go S</a>.
</p>
<p>
Beyond its handheld plans, Microsoft <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-says-next-xbox-will-deliver-largest-technical-leap-seen-in-a-hardware-generation">continues to developed its Xbox Series X/S successor</a>, which Xbox president Sarah Bond previously claimed would deliver "the largest technical leap that you will have ever seen in a hardware generation." According to Windows Central, there are currently "three prototype devices in development for Microsoft's Gen-10 effort", and the company is also said to be working on "next-gen Xbox cloud systems" to bring latency more in line with NVIDIA's GeForce Now service.
</p>
<p>
As for games, we'll know more about Xbox's future slate once <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-announces-june-showcase-event-reveals-game-getting-this-years-big-spotlight">this year's Xbox Games Showcase</a> airs on Sunday, 8th June at 6pm UK time. Eurogamer will, of course, have news from that and more as the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/summer-game-fest-2025-conference-schedule-all-dates-times-streams">Summer Game Fest season</a> gets underway next week. 
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>