<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 13:09:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims 1 and 2 patch fixes numerous issues, following "farcical" re-release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-1-and-2-patch-fixes-numerous-issues-following-farcical-re-release</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-1-and-2-patch-fixes-numerous-issues-following-farcical-re-release.1100694/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-1-and-2-patch-fixes-numerous-issues-following-farcical-re-release<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article">
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-Sims-1-cover-art.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>EA</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>EA and Maxis have issued a patch for the recently released Legacy editions of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims">The Sims 1</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-2">The Sims 2</a>.</p>
<p>These games <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-1-2-re-releases-are-out-now-and-you-can-get-both-for-25">launched on Friday</a>, after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-1-2-reportedly-getting-pc-re-releases-this-week">earlier rumours suggested the classic life-sim series was making a trip back to its roots</a>. However, when they launched, many players were met with a number of rather glitchy issues and game crashes. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3314060/The_Sims_Legacy_Collection/#app_reviews_hash">Reviews</a> on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3314070/The_Sims_2_Legacy_Collection/#app_reviews_hash">Steam</a> called the debut "farcical", "broken" and even a "waste of money", which has to sting. The games currently sit with a Mixed review average.</p>
<p>The team acknowledged the games had issues at the time, stating it would hop to it and sort out some fixes. And, true to its word, it has, sharing a generous set of patch notes for both The Sims 1 and 2 last night.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Why the Switch 2 Needed the Steam Deck. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WBzuCVIuOtM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Those who are enjoying the classic Sims game again (or, perhaps even for the first time, she writes suddenly realising there are people out there quite a bit younger than her who may not have been around when these games first came out) should now notice less crashes.</p>
<p>Additionally, players should now be able to click on parts of the neighbourhood they were initially not able to, despite it clearly intended to be doable. The travel screen should also not be quite to "garbled or glitched" now.</p>
<p>You can check out the full patch notes for The Sims Legacy and The Sims 2 Legacy below:</p>
<p><strong>The Sims Fixed Issues: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Alt+Tab or Alt+Enter can sometimes cause a crash</li>
<li>Alt+Enter can sometimes cause the Windows title bar to be hidden</li>
<li>Alt+Enter can sometimes not toggle between full screen and windowed modes</li>
<li>On some systems, The Sims can appear to launch and then immediately exit (no splash screen displayed)</li>
<li>The Sims should now launch in most situations</li>
<li>In some cases where there is an underlying graphics issue, The Sims will display a message</li>
<li>Some players are unable to click on various parts of the neighbourhood map</li>
<li>The travel screen, when traveling between neighbourhoods/worlds, can sometimes appear garbled or glitched</li>
<li>The Sims might crash if you are not on the default neighbourhood, interact with another Sim, and then save</li>
<li>When using Alt+Enter to cycle window and zoom sizes, the HUD could be clipped. At this zoom level, The Sims will now instead clip from the top of the screen.</li>
<li>In some situations in windowed mode the title bar might not be visible</li>
<li>The Family friends counter could sometimes not be visible</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The Sims General Notes: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Several players have had problems (e.g. walls, floors, objects not showing up; game not launching; other oddities) that are addressed by updating graphics drivers to the latest versions. Please make sure your drivers are up to date.</li>
<li>The Sims game window is of a fixed size that can't have its basic properties changed after it has launched. Moving the window from a monitor to another with a different, lesser resolution can lead to unexpected results, possibly even crashes. If you want to run The Sims on that second monitor please use the option "-monitor: [open pointy brackets] num [close pointy brackets]" to force it to launch on the other monitor. "0" is your primary monitor, a second monitor is "1" and so on. We are investigating adding this as a menu option in the future.</li>
<li>In some situations, players have noted that music only plays in Live mode. Please check your computer sound options and make sure that everything is properly configured (e.g. on a 5.1 surround system make sure that your center speaker is functioning).</li>
<li>You might be prompted to "Enable the help system" every time you return to a house. This is the game trying to have you complete the tutorial. This will continue to happen until you complete the tutorial.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The Sims 2 Fixed Issues:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Alt-Tab or Alt+Enter can sometimes cause a crash</li>
<li>Some players on EA App received an error message indicating that certain needed files were corrupt</li>
<li>The game would sometimes crash after creating a family</li>
<li>The game sometimes launched at a small resolution (800x600) and then scaled that small format to fill the entire monitor</li>
<li>In certain situations the game will launch and then immediately show a "DirectX" error, requiring use of the "-w" option to work around the problem</li>
<li>Sometimes a Sim (or multiple Sims) would disappear after the player moves to another lot or neighbourhood, or after leaving and rejoining the game despite saving</li>
<li>Sometimes non-adult Sims (children, pets) would disappear</li>
<li>Some interactions that result in a transferable reward (e.g. a dog returns from work) can cause the game to crash</li>
<li>Addressed some infinite loading screen issues</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The Sims 2 General Notes: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Several players have had problems that are addressed by updating graphics drivers to the latest versions. Please make sure your drivers are up to date.</li>
<li>Remember that the "boolProp testingCheatsEnabled" cheat will cause the game to periodically show various dialogue boxes with debugging information in them. The cheat is working as expected.</li>
<li>We are investigating an issue where during certain cinematic events (such as Alien Abduction), the Sim can be reset and the event fails. While we are investigating this, you can work around the issue by making certain there are no other Sims on the lot to observe the event.</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-Sims-1-couple-kissing-at-a-wedding-with-the-famale's-eyes-wide-open.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Why are her eyes open??  | <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The Sims team is still working on some remaining issues. "Some topics can require an extended investigation on our end, so even though these fixes may be in active review, it's not a guarantee that we'll have an immediate fix for it in the upcoming patch," it wrote in a <a href="https://forums.ea.com/blog/the-sims-game-info-hub-en/the-sims%E2%84%A2-legacy-and-the-sims%E2%84%A2-2-legacy-patch-notes/11861248">post regarding the latest patch</a>.</p>
<p>"Thank you for playing these games that are such a storied part of our history - starting 25 years ago!"</p>
<p>Please excuse me while I go and put in my dentures. </p></div>



        </article>

  
    </div><div data-component="article-footer">
      <div>
      <p><span><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/authors/victoria-kennedy">Victoria Kennedy</a></span>: Joining Eurogamer in 2022, Victoria is a baby-faced old soul with a penchant for Pimm's, pancakes and pirates, but not all at the same time 🥞 actually, maybe all at the same time...
      </p>
    </div>







  



  <section>
    <p>In this article</p>

    <div>
        <div>
      <p>
        <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims">The Sims</a>
      </p>

      <p>
            <span>Nintendo GameCube</span>, 
            <span>PS2</span>, 
            <span>Xbox</span>, 
            <span>PC</span>
      </p>





</div>
        <div>
      <p>
        <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-2">The Sims 2</a>
      </p>

      <p>
            <span>Nintendo GBA</span>, 
            <span>Nintendo GameCube</span>, 
            <span>PS2</span>, 
            <span>Xbox</span>, 
            <span>PSP</span>, 
            <span>PC</span>, 
            <span>Nintendo DS</span>
      </p>





</div>
    </div>

  </section>

  <section>
    <p>Related topics</p>

    
  </section>

  <div data-mode="signup" data-component="smart slot">
      <p>
        Eurogamer is better when you sign in
      </p>

      <p>
        Join our community of gamers and get access to personalised reading recommendations and much more!
      </p>

      
    </div>
  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA eyeing Nintendo Switch 2 for several key franchises]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-eyeing-nintendo-switch-2-for-several-key-franchises</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-eyeing-nintendo-switch-2-for-several-key-franchises.1100658/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-eyeing-nintendo-switch-2-for-several-key-franchises<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_EE1u8ne.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>EA / Nintendo / Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
EA has become one of the first publishers to discuss - in broad terms - its plans for Switch 2, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/its-official-nintendo-switch-2-revealed-after-months-of-waiting">now Nintendo has finally lifted the lid on its next console</a>.
</p>
<p>
Speaking to investors last night following the release of its latest financial results, EA boss Andrew Wilson namechecked major franchises the company expected to find a home on Switch 2.
</p>
<p>
"Certainly, our expectation is that products like [EA Sports] FC and Madden and others might find real energy on the platform as they have done in the past," Wilson said. 
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Nintendo Switch 2 and Mario Kart 9 have been revealed - but questions remain.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UyPgPcxLlIk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"When you think about something like The Sims and MySims: Cozy Bundle, which performed well ahead of our expectations, 50 percent of all players were new to EA," he continued. "That represents a great opportunity for us."
</p>
<p>
Switch 2 still lacks a release date, but with public hands-on events running in April and May, a summer launch seems likely. 
</p>
<p>
Could Switch 2 launch with the current <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/ea-sports-fc-25">EA Sports FC 25</a>? Or might EA decide to hold off until this autumn's next installment?
</p>
<p>
It's easy to see EA releasing existing titles in The Sims series on the new console - perhaps <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-1-2-re-releases-are-out-now-and-you-can-get-both-for-25">the new Sims 1+2 Bundle</a>? Could EA also make use of the Switch 2's mysterious mouse pointer functionality also?
</p>
<p>
And how about <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-walkthrough-tips-and-tricks-guide">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a>? EA could try and launch that on Switch 2 as a way to boost sales, after previously saying <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-suggests-dragon-age-the-veilguard-might-have-sold-better-if-it-was-live-service-so-what-does-this-mean-for-mass-effect-5">the game had not met its own expectations</a>.
</p>
<p>
Lastly, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/next-battlefield-game-glimpsed-as-ea-announces-big-community-playtest-plans">there's the next Battlefield</a>. EA <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-says-next-battlefield-expected-to-release-before-april-2026">still seems unsure exactly when it will land</a> (we may know more after Rockstar decides on a date for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-everything-we-know-so-far-9357">GTA 6</a>), but could Switch 2 have the horsepower to run that? It'll be intriguing to find out. 
</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-direct-confirmed-for-april-with-more-info-following-todays-brief-reveal">Nintendo is next set to discuss Switch 2 in April</a>, via a special Nintendo Direct laying out more detail on the upcoming console. We're expecting to hear a launch date and price then - as well as more information on the games we'll all be playing, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-announcement-reveals-new-mario-kart-game">other than the next Mario Kart</a>.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds players can test their machines ahead of release with PC benchmarking tool]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-players-can-test-their-machines-ahead-of-release-with-pc-benchmarking-tool</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-players-can-test-their-machines-ahead-of-release-with-pc-benchmarking-tool.1100625/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-players-can-test-their-machines-ahead-of-release-with-pc-benchmarking-tool<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Capcom has released a PC benchmarking tool for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> so players can test out their machines ahead of release.</p>
<p>Performance has been a big concern for players since the game's last beta, with erratic framerates and visual glitches across both PC and console. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-specs-revealed">Capcom released the PC specs</a> last September, but has since stated it plans to lower GPU requirements.</p>
<p>Now, following last night's Capcom Spotlight, the company has released a benchmark tool on PC you can download <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/">via Steam</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Monster Hunter Wilds: 6th Trailer | Into the Iceshard Cliffs" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OFoueW07mxQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Monster Hunter Wilds: 6th Trailer | Into the Iceshard Cliffs</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OFoueW07mxQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OFoueW07mxQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Monster Hunter Wilds: 6th Trailer | Into the Iceshard Cliffs<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OFoueW07mxQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-uk/benchmark/">free tool</a> provides a score of your computer's performance, from Excellent down to Difficulty Playing, along with an average frame rate.</p>
<p>The benchmark comes ahead of a second beta, <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-uk/obt/">operating across two weekends in February</a> before the game's launch on 28th February.</p>
<p>However, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-second-open-beta-ahead-of-february-release">various improvements made to the game won't be included in this beta</a>, including performance, weapon changes, Hitstop, and quality of life tweaks. As such, the benchmark tool is the best way for PC players to truly see if their machine is up to scratch.</p>
<p>Last night, Capcom confirmed this beta will give players a chance to go up against <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-next-open-betas-will-let-players-fight-flagship-monster-arkveld-for-the-first-time">flagship monster Arkveld for the first time</a>. A new trailer (above) provides a look at the Iceshard Cliffs biome and new monster Hirabami.</p>
<p>For console players, director Yuya Tokuda previously confirmed performance targets across PS5 and Xbox Series X/S. There will also be a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-director-confirms-ps5-pro-patch-coming-day-one">day one PS5 Pro patch</a>, for which further details have been revealed.</p>
<p>On <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/topics/ps5-pro">PS5 Pro</a>, PSSR will be used to upscale the resolution with added ray-tracing effects. Unlike on base consoles where two settings will be available to prioritise resolution or framerate, the PS5 Pro will have an additional Balanced mode for a 40fps frame rate with ray-tracing enabled.</p>
<p>The three modes are as follows:</p>
<table data-mobile-mode="scroll">
<tbody><tr>
<th>Performance Settings</th>
<th>Ray Tracing</th>
<th>Output Resolution (Rendering Resolution)</th>
<th>Frame Rate</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Prioritise Resolution</td>
<td>Enabled</td>
<td>3840 x 2160 (3072 x 1728)</td>
<td>30fps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Balanced</td>
<td>Enabled</td>
<td>3840 x 2160 (1920 x 1404)</td>
<td>40 fps</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Prioritise Frame rate</td>
<td>Disabled</td>
<td>3840 x 2160 (1920 x 1080)</td>
<td>60fps</td>
</tr>
</tbody></table>
<p>Monster Hunter Wilds will release across PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC on 28th February. I went <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-cuts-out-the-clunk-and-plays-like-the-most-streamlined-beginner-friendly-entry-yet">hands-on at Gamescom last year</a> and was impressed by its more streamlined approach.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Another Bloodborne fan-project gets the legal takedown treatment, sparking speculation an official remake is coming]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/another-bloodborne-fan-project-gets-the-legal-takedown-treatment-sparking-speculation-an-official-remake-is-coming</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/another-bloodborne-fan-project-gets-the-legal-takedown-treatment-sparking-speculation-an-official-remake-is-coming.1100619/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/another-bloodborne-fan-project-gets-the-legal-takedown-treatment-sparking-speculation-an-official-remake-is-coming<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Bloodborne-PS1-Demake-Father-Gascoigne.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Lilith Walther</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The Bloodborne PSX demake fan-project from tech artist and engineer Lilith Walther has become the latest legal takedown victim.</p>
<p>The Bloodborne PSX demake, you may recall, took the PS4 classic back to its roots, with a PS1 makeover that yielded some rather excellent results. Our Ian gave it a go on release, delighting in the demake's ability to combine two of his favourite things - retro games and spanking werewolves (see below).</p>
<p>But, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bloodborne-demake-out-today">three years after it made its pixel perfect debut</a>, the Bloodborne PSX demake project has been hit by a copyright claim by MarkScan Entertainment. This claim comes soon after a fellow Bloodborne fan project from modder Lance McDonald, which enabled Bloodborne to run at 60fps, was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-takes-aim-at-bloodborne-60fps-mod-released-in-2021">also hit with the legal take down notice hammer</a>. Eurogamer has contacted Sony for comment, but is yet to receive a response.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Let's Play Bloodborne PSX Gameplay - THE PS4 CLASSIC, REBUILT WITH PS1 AESTHETICS!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3n3OQuSDkq0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Let's Play Bloodborne PSX Gameplay - THE PS4 CLASSIC, REBUILT WITH PS1 AESTHETICS!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3n3OQuSDkq0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/3n3OQuSDkq0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Let's Play Bloodborne PSX Gameplay. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3n3OQuSDkq0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>But, why is Sony suddenly so interested in Bloodborne-related fan projects that have been around for, let's be honest, quite some time now? Well, McDonald has a "copium" theory that Sony could well be working on an official 60fps Bloodborne remake of its own, and the company doesn't want any fan-related projects getting in the way of Google searches and such when the time comes for an announcement.</p>
<p>"Like if they plan on trademarking 'Bloodborne 60fps' and 'Bloodborne remake' they need to actually clean up in order to actually file a trademark request. Right??" the noted modder mused on social media platform X.</p>
<p>Gosh, I may now have my hopes up again...</p>
<div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>My copium theory is that Sony DMCAed the 60fps patch and the video about the Bloodborne demake so that when they announce a 60fps remake, google searching for “bloodborne 60fps” and “Bloodborne remake” won’t have collisions with our fan projects.</p><p>Let me cope.</p></div>— Lance McDonald (@manfightdragon) <a href="https://twitter.com/manfightdragon/status/1886240572660457506?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 3, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>Bloodborne will celebrate its 10th anniversary next month, which suddenly makes me feel old. In the time since, many have shared their hopes that Sony may give the game a remake, remaster, PC port or sequel of some description. After all, Sony has done all this for many of its other IPs, such as The Last of Us, Uncharted and God of War to name just three. However, Bloodborne has remained untouched.</p>
<p>Last month, former Sony Interactive Entertainment exec and PlayStation legend Shuhei Yoshida shared his thoughts on why Bloodborne hasn't had the same attention as other PlayStation releases. Speaking following his <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-legend-shuhei-yoshida-announces-retirement">retirement from Sony after more than 30 years at the company</a>, Yoshida said he thinks a key factor in Bloodborne's lack of a remaster or similar comes down to one quite simple thing - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/why-hasnt-playstation-done-anything-new-with-bloodborne-shuhei-yoshida-has-a-theory">the game's creator Hidetaka Miyazaki is "so busy"</a>, it has just not been possible.</p>
<p>"Miyazaki-san really, really loved Bloodborne, what he created. So I think he is interested but he's so successful and he's so busy, so he cannot do it himself, and he doesn't want anyone else to touch it," Yoshida reasoned.</p>
<p>As for the demake's creator, Walther released a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bloodborne-kart-back-without-bloodborne-and-with-a-new-release-date">Bloodborne-inspired racer known as Nightmare Kart last year</a>. This project initially had Bloodborne in its branding, but this was changed following a request from Sony.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA says next Battlefield "expected" to release before April 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-says-next-battlefield-expected-to-release-before-april-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-says-next-battlefield-expected-to-release-before-april-2026.1100547/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-says-next-battlefield-expected-to-release-before-april-2026<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Following playtest initiative launch.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bf-ca-1726271105698.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>EA/IGN</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
We might not have seen a whole lot of EA's next Battlefield game beyond the few seconds of pre-alpha footage shared this week, but it turns out it's probably not all that far away. The publisher has confirmed it expect the series' latest instalment to arrive before April next year.
</p>
<p>
EA shared the news as part of its third-quarter financial earnings report, saying its new Battlefield is "expected fiscal year 2026 release". That means the game should - all being well - arrive sometime between 1st April this year and 31st of March 2026.
</p>
<p>
Specifics remain limited, but EA last year confirmed the long-running multiplayer shooter series would be <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-says-next-battlefield-is-modern-day-brings-back-classes-and-more-focused-maps">returning to the modern era</a> for its next outing, and that it'd feature traditional classes and more focused maps - a clear indication it would be revisiting a tried-and-tested formula after shaking things up in 2021's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-2042-is-now-one-of-steams-worst-reviewed-games-of-all-time">poorly received Battlefield 2042</a>.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Introducing Battlefield Labs | Battlefield Studios" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_fGteYuaNxA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Introducing Battlefield Labs | Battlefield Studios</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_fGteYuaNxA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_fGteYuaNxA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>EA launches Battlefield Labs.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_fGteYuaNxA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Last year's announcement also revealed EA was planning a series of playtests for Battlefield's next instalment, in order to "get the community back on [its] side" - and that initiative, now known as Battlefield Labs, was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/next-battlefield-game-glimpsed-as-ea-announces-big-community-playtest-plans">officially unveiled this week</a> alongside brief early gameplay.
</p>
<p>
The next Battlefield game is being developed by a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-amassing-largest-battlefield-team-in-franchise-history-to-double-down-on-live-service-multiplayer">huge group spread across four major EA teams</a>, now working under the umbrella name of Battlefield Studios. That includes series creator DICE, splinter studio Ripple Effect, Dead Space Remake developer Motive, and Criterion - the veteran UK studio, which, as Eurogamer reported earlier this week, has now <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/next-battlefield-game-glimpsed-as-ea-announces-big-community-playtest-plans">paused work on its next Need for Speed game</a> in order to pitch in with the new Battlefield.
</p>
<p>
EA will be wanting to hit the ground running with the next Battlefield entry after it was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-admits-battlefield-2042-flopped-but-would-have-been-less-than-10-percent-of-annual-revenue-anyway">forced to admit 2042 "did not meet expectations"</a>. The publisher also had a difficult 2024, and last month said <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-says-ea-sports-fc-25-and-dragon-age-the-veilguard-underperformed-as-it-lowers-financial-forecast">EA Sports FC 25 and Dragon Age: The Veilguard "underperformed"</a> as it lowered its financial forecast for the year.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>