<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:40:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD and Nvidia will reportedly raise GPU prices "significantly" in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/amd-and-nvidia-will-reportedly-raise-gpu-prices-significantly-in-2026</link>
            <guid>1395859</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>According to a new report, both AMD and Nvidia will raise the prices of their consumer GPUs "significantly" this year. If this report is true, both companies will have pushed these price hikes by next month.</p>
<p><a href="https://mobile.newsis.com/view/NISX20251229_0003458273#_endPass">This information comes from Newsis</a>, which claims these price hikes will come as a result of the high cost of memory in the computer hardware market right now. This increased cost has been caused by construction of widespread AI data centres, which has resulted in a huge demand for such components.</p>
<p>This price hike will continue to get worse too, according to Newsis industry sources. While an initial price increase will reportedly go into place in January for AMD and February for Nvidia, both companies will continue gradually increasing the price throughout the year.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Here's why Blue Prince is why Eurogamer's game of 2025!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YzksL5Az7ro" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Expectations are that these price increases will impact certain GPUs, including Nvidia's GeForce RTX 50 series and AMD's Radeon RX 9000 series which are already expensive. According to Newsis, the Nvidia RTX 5090 which was released at a price point of $1,999 could eventually increase to $5,000 this year.</p><p>The reasons why these price hikes are coming are clear. Not only are GPus getting more expensive to make due to the increased cost of construction, but AI companies such as OpenAI are hardware guzzling behemoths. <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/02/26/nvidia-ceo-huang-says-next-generation-ai-will-need-more-compute.html">Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang stated that next generation AI will need "100 times more compute" than older models</a>, and <a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/artificial-intelligence/microsoft-ceo-says-the-company-doesnt-have-enough-electricity-to-install-all-the-ai-gpus-in-its-inventory-you-may-actually-have-a-bunch-of-chips-sitting-in-inventory-that-i-cant-plug-in">Microsoft's CEO mused that they don't have the electricity to install the GPUs sitting in their inventory</a>.</p>
<p>Whether or not you buy into the hype regarding Generative AI and LLMs, the reality is these companies are buying GPUs (<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ram-prices-are-soaring-what-does-it-mean-for-gaming">and RAM</a>) with the expectation that they'll need an absurd amount of hardware for future models, and the consumer demand for those models. Thus, we have a massive demand for GPUs, thus the price increase. Nvidia and AMD know they can charge AI companies more too, as these companies rely on such hardware for continued growth.</p>
<p>What this means for the average consumer of PC parts for gaming purposes is that your PC parts are going to get drastically more expensive over the coming months if this report is accurate, and they'll likely get more expensive due to basic supply / demand problems in the hardware market.</p>
<p>All the while video game companies state their intention to embrace AI through development. Take <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/after-chasing-nfts-and-the-metaverse-square-enix-wants-generative-ai-to-do-70-of-its-qa-by-2027">which intends to replace 70% of its QA wit hAI by 2027</a>, and Ubisoft <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-boss-believes-generative-ai-is-as-big-a-revolution-for-games-as-the-shift-to-3d-as-tech-is-embraced-company-wide">whose CEO believes AI will be as big a revolution as the shift to 3D</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  




  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/amd-and-nvidia-will-reportedly-raise-gpu-prices-significantly-in-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Underrated 'slow life RPG' Fantasy Life i gets a free roguelike mode in surprise new year update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/rpg-fantasy-life-i-gets-roguelike-mode-in-free-new-year-update</link>
            <guid>1395817</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Snoozaland sounds like a place for me.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fantasy-life-i-snoozaland.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fantasy-life-i-snoozaland.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fantasy-life-i-snoozaland.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fantasy-life-i-snoozaland.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fantasy-life-i-snoozaland.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fantasy-life-i-snoozaland.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fantasy-life-i-snoozaland.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fantasy-life-i-snoozaland.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fantasy-life-i-snoozaland.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Level 5</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Underrated 'slow life' role-playing game Fantasy Life i: The Girl Who Steals Time - which stole a lot of my time last year on <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platforms/switch-2">Switch 2</a> - has just received an exciting new year content drop.</p>
<p>The update, free and available now on all platforms (PC, Xbox, PlayStation and Switch), is called Sinister Broker Bazario's Schemes, and it adds a new location to the game called Snoozaland, where Fantasy Life i becomes a roguelike experience - one life, one attempt, see how far you get.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fantasy Life – Free Major Update &quot;The Sinister Broker Bazario's Schemes&quot; Trailer2" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3zUiaq36_xk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fantasy Life – Free Major Update "The Sinister Broker Bazario's Schemes" Trailer2</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3zUiaq36_xk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/3zUiaq36_xk?autoplay=1" title="Fantasy Life – Free Major Update &quot;The Sinister Broker Bazario's Schemes&quot; Trailer2">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3zUiaq36_xk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>There, in Snoozaland, you'll always start as an unequipped level one character, and the world will rearrange itself every time you reattempt it. You'll learn new lives - the game's job/class/role system - on the job, and gather equipment as you explore. </p>
<p>A powerful end-boss and powerful rewards await, and there are alchemy robots you'll find that will potentially spit out powerful items, providing you fill them up with various unwanted materials and equipment first.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.fantasylife.jp/fli/en/dlc1/">The game's website</a> makes it sound like a self-contained experience, which presumably means the character you build while adventuring in Snoozaland only lasts for as long as your run does, and that there's no actual permanence there.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fantasy-life-i-might-be-the-star-of-the-switch-2-launch-providing-both-the-animal-crossing-and-rpg-experience-it-needs">I found Fantasy Life i to be one of the Switch 2's most alluring launch titles</a>. It's a sort of cross between Animal Crossing and Dragon Quest - a game that's part town building and resource harvesting and crafting, and part role-playing adventure. It's bright and colourful and uplifting.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/rpg-fantasy-life-i-gets-roguelike-mode-in-free-new-year-update]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is there really going to be a new Witcher 3 expansion this year?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/is-there-really-going-to-be-a-2026-witcher-3-expansion</link>
            <guid>1395781</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/witcher-3-geralt_uS0zYOX.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/witcher-3-geralt_uS0zYOX.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/witcher-3-geralt_uS0zYOX.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/witcher-3-geralt_uS0zYOX.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/witcher-3-geralt_uS0zYOX.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/witcher-3-geralt_uS0zYOX.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/witcher-3-geralt_uS0zYOX.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/witcher-3-geralt_uS0zYOX.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/witcher-3-geralt_uS0zYOX.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>CD Projekt Red</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><strong>UPDATE 1.30PM BST:</strong> I exchanged emails with Borys Nieśpielak today, the original source for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt">The Witcher 3</a> expansion rumours, who told me his information was verified by "several" independent sources. He didn't have any further information to share beyond what was <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j5G22X8V9IA&amp;t=1821s">in his original podcast</a> but he did direct me to a potentially supporting piece of information from <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/wp-content/uploads-en/2025/11/transcript-q3-2025-earnings-3.pdf">an earnings call transcript attached to CD Projekt Red's recent financial report</a>. It's a piece of information he said he's been surprised to see people miss.</p>
<p>In the earnings call, CD Projekt chief financial officer Piotr Nielubowicz said: "Given our current progress, there is a chance that new content hinted upon in recent calls and reports may see release in the coming year, having an impact on our results and increasing the likelihood of achieving the earnings condition for the first stage of the incentive program."</p>
<p>It's a vague statement but it does mention new content that may be released in the coming year. Could this really be true?</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>

</figure><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EHuw6gZxqcg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></p><p><strong>ORIGINAL STORY 11.30AM BST:</strong> Is there really going to be a new paid expansion released for The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt in 2026? Because that's the suggestion I've seen. That's the rumour that's been ricocheting around the internet while I've been trying to enjoy a leftover sandwich this holiday.</p><p>The rumour stemmed originally from someone called Borys Nieśpielak, a trusted source of Polish games industry information - a leaker of sorts. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/polish-indie-lichtspeer-documentary-we-are-alright">He made a documentary a few years back about Polish indie game development, called We are alright</a>, which is a good watch, and it shows that he has industry connections.</p>
<p>Nieśpielak said in the summer last year that Fool's Theory, the studio remaking The Witcher 1 for CD Projekt Red, was making a new Witcher 3 expansion, and he reiterated this ahead of The Game Awards in December where he expected the announcement to be made, according to <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt/dlc-game-awards">PCGamesN</a>. But such an announcement never came.</p>
<p>Rumour quashed? No, because a separate voice has added strength to it. <a href="https://x.com/MtChrzanowski">Polish Noble Securities analyst Mateusz Chrzanowski</a> wrote a report on 16th December - after The Game Awards - which said, "We expect the next paid add-on (DLC) for The Witcher 3 to be released in May 2026." That's according to a Google translation of <a href="https://strefainwestorow.pl/analizy/noblesecurities-cdprojekt-wiedzmin-dlc-orion-cyberpunk">a Polish website report</a> via <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1ptxa4g/the_witcher_3_dlc_to_release_in_may_2026_other/">Reddit</a>.</p>
<p>"We assume sales of 11 million copies at $30 each next year. We estimate the production budget at PLN 52 million. The release should kick off the proper marketing campaign for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a>," Chrzanowski added. Later, he predicted The Witcher 4 would be released in Q4 2027.</p>
<p>I wonder: could this rumoured Witcher 3 expansion be <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-whole-new-witcher-trilogy-of-games-released-within-six-years-of-each-other-is-that-even-possible-cd-projekt-red-thinks-so">the unannounced project referenced in a recent CD Projekt Red financial report</a>?</p>
<p>Partially, it makes sense. From a marketing point of view, beginning The Witcher 4 marketing campaign with a surprise content-drop for The Witcher 3 would certainly cause a stir. And storywise, an expansion could help bridge the gap between leaving Geralt as the main character and Ciri taking over. A paid expansion would obviously bridge a financial gap between now and The Witcher 4 being released, too - The Witcher 4 being the next big thing on the company's to-do list.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>But there are reasons to doubt it too. One big one is Unreal Engine 5. The studio has wholesale moved development from its proprietary Red Engine to Unreal Engine 5 - that's what The Witcher 4 is being built on and what the Witcher 1 remake, which Fool's Theory is also tasked with, is being made with too. That Witcher 1 remake has been slightly backbenched while Fool's Theory helps CDPR make The Witcher 4 - that information was revealed during the recent financial call too. Why, then, give an already very busy developer another project to make and one made using the company's old Red Engine, which The Witcher 3 uses?</p><p>It's worth remembering how much effort CD Projekt Red puts into expansions as well. You need only look at <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/phantom-liberty-is-a-remarkable-expansion-and-a-bittersweet-end-for-cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077's Phantom Liberty</a> or <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-3-blood-and-wine-review">The Witcher 3's Blood and Wine</a> as examples of this. They are big, usually overly generous things. They provide a smaller game's worth of content. They are important enough, then, to be handled internally, and the best time to make them is while you have a still-warm development after a main game has been released.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-worked-in-the-witcher-3-and-what-didnt-looking-back-on-a-landmark-rpg-with-cd-projekt-red">It's been 10 years since The Witcher 3 came out</a>. The people who made and led that game have moved on, or are elsewhere in the company. Trying to reassemble some of that team and magic, and muscle memory, would be incredibly hard. And why would you pull people from arguably more important projects, such as The Witcher 4 and Cyberpunk 2, in order to do it?</p>
<p>What's more, who would the expansion be centered on - Geralt again? Why bring that character back to the fore if you're trying so hard to get people on board with Ciri as the series' new protagonist? Blood and Wine was a perfectly fitting swansong for him, for Geralt, and Ciri's story will be covered by the new game. I don't see where a new story would fit in - or where it would be needed.</p>
<p>I've contacted Nieśpielak and Chrzanowski and CD Projekt Red to see if I can get any more information. But in the meantime, what do you think?</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/is-there-really-going-to-be-a-2026-witcher-3-expansion]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prices of an obscure PS4 game are skyrocketing thanks to the latest PS5 jailbreak efforts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ps5-jail-break-star-wars-racer-revenge</link>
            <guid>1395778</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-wars-racer-revenge.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-wars-racer-revenge.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-wars-racer-revenge.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-wars-racer-revenge.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-wars-racer-revenge.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-wars-racer-revenge.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-wars-racer-revenge.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-wars-racer-revenge.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-wars-racer-revenge.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Limited Run Games / Lucasarts</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The price of an obscure PS4 game is skyrocketing on the second-hand market, thanks to its necessity in a new PS5 jailbreak. This game, of which 1,000 or less physical copies were produced, has suddenly become a hot commodity among jailbreak enthusiasts and resellers alike.</p>
<p>The game in question is Star Wars Racer Revenge, specifically the Limited Run Games physical special re-release for the PS4. This collectors item was first sold in 2019 by Limited Run as a collectors item, the companies' business model focusing on taking older titles and repackaging them in special physical versions for enthusiasts.</p>
<p>Why is this game noteworthy? According to one of the developers behind the upcoming version 12.0 PS5 jailbreak, this physical version of Star Wars Racer Revenge is needed. The reason is interesting, as the game has a decade's old bug that allows players to inject code via its Hall of Fame menu. So in order to jailbreak the PS5, you'll need to snatch yourself a copy of the game.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Star Wars Racer Revenge PS2 Gameplay HD (PCSX2)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wvJPCsXat9s?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Star Wars Racer Revenge PS2 Gameplay HD (PCSX2)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wvJPCsXat9s?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wvJPCsXat9s?autoplay=1" title="Star Wars Racer Revenge PS2 Gameplay HD (PCSX2)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's some gameplay footage of Star Wars Racer Revenge!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wvJPCsXat9s" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>As for how hard this is, you may be shocked to learn that these Limited Run games were part of a… limited run. As such, you can't buy them from the Limited Run Games website anymore, you can only buy them second-hand. <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1ko7iYqZDcr5Leq6I_1byupsVcyFjFZDYItTK5qhOwxk/edit?usp=sharing">According to official Limited Run Games sales data</a>, only 8,500 copies were produced. Your only bet is to luck out in a store out in the real world, or the treacherous world of online markets.</p><p>Taking a look at Ebay as of writing presents one with a shocking list of absurdly expensive copies of Star Wars Racer Revenge. Prices range from £70 to upwards of £300 as people attempt to profit off the game's newfound value to PS5 jailbreakers.</p>
<p>So if you've got a taste for diving deep into your console's guts and unlocking a world of interesting possibilities via niche means, or happen to have an old copy of Limited Run Games' Star Wars Racer Revenge release lying around, 2026 might be off to an explosive start.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/ps5-jail-break-star-wars-racer-revenge]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The first announcement for Persona's 30th anniversary isn't that thrilling, but don't worry: there's more to come]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/persona-30th-anniversary-boxing-fitness-more-announcements</link>
            <guid>1395775</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/persona-30th.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/persona-30th.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/persona-30th.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/persona-30th.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/persona-30th.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/persona-30th.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/persona-30th.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/persona-30th.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/persona-30th.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>It's a big year for gaming anniversaries. There are five massive series that turn 40 years old in 2026 - The Legend of Zelda, Metroid, Dragon Quest, Kid Icarus, and Castlevania - whilst Sonic the Hedgehog turns 35, and Persona and Pokémon both turn 30. There's probably a lot of celebratory stuff coming over the next 12 months, but let's start with a franchise we know is getting some attention this year before anything else: Persona.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, Japanese developer Atlus unveiled <a href="https://asia.sega.com/p30th/en/">an official website</a> dedicated to the 30th anniversary of the Persona series. Whilst there's not too much over there at the moment, clicking through to the website will show you some fantastic new art from Persona character designer Shigenori Soejima (the most surprising aspect of this being that the team actually acknowledges Persona 1 and 2 - it's been a hot minute!)</p>
<p>The first announcement to tie in with this anniversary promotion is <a href="https://twitter.com/FitBoxingInfo/status/2006561021620584708">the reveal of Fitness Boxing Persona 5</a>. Not exactly Persona 6, is it? But if you're a fan of the series - which has previously done collabs with Japanese series like Fist of the North Star and Hatsune Miku - you'll probably enjoy a fitness gauntlet run by Joker or Ryuji or something… (let's just hope Kamoshida isn't taking on any new students). The Fitness Boxing series is developed by Japanese devs, Imagineer, and has been exclusive to the Nintendo Switch for the last few entries. You can probably expect the same, here.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>The biggest news on the site, though, for those that want something a little bit more Persona-related and a little bit less 'new year, new me', is that we're getting some sort of announcement on January 8th, or next Thursday if you're reading this article on the day of publication. Whilst I wouldn't get my hopes up too much for this (it could just be merch, or discounts, or news about <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/individual-diablo-hades-and-persona-orchestral-musical-concerts-are-coming-to-london-and-if-last-years-baldurs-gate-3-concert-was-anything-to-go-by-you-wont-want-to-miss-them">the series' upcoming concert dates</a>), there's a chance we could hear something about <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/persona-4-revival-will-be-enjoyable-in-a-new-and-different-way-says-series-boss">Persona 4 Revival </a>or even the next full title in the franchise, assumedly titled Persona 6.</p><p>I expect we'll also get a console port of gacha title <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/persona-5-x-players-are-obsessed-with-the-subway-slammer-but-whats-his-deal-anyway">Persona 5: The Phantom X</a> at some point, too, and we may hear about that as part of the 30th anniversary celebrations. So keep your eyes peeled next week for the next entry in this announcement saga, and let's just hope the next reveal is something big.</p>
<p>Now, excuse me as I start singing "You'll never see it coming" to myself in an eternal loop.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/persona-30th-anniversary-boxing-fitness-more-announcements]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new Deux Ex isn't coming in 2026 as people in charge are "psychopaths", jokes series voice lead]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/deus-ex-no-2026-people-in-charge-psychopaths</link>
            <guid>1395760</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/deus-ex-mankind-divided-crop.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/deus-ex-mankind-divided-crop.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/deus-ex-mankind-divided-crop.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/deus-ex-mankind-divided-crop.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/deus-ex-mankind-divided-crop.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/deus-ex-mankind-divided-crop.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/deus-ex-mankind-divided-crop.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/deus-ex-mankind-divided-crop.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/deus-ex-mankind-divided-crop.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Square Enix</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Elias Toufexis, the voice actor behind robotic employee of the year and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/deus-ex">Deus Ex</a> main character Adam Jensen, has assured fans that a new entry in the sci-fi series will not be coming in 2026, as the people in charge are "psychopaths".</p>
<p>This sad news and witty remark comes via Toufexis's <a href="https://x.com/EliasToufexis/status/2006498544270856318">Twitter</a>, where he celebrated the new year by sharing a cheeky snapshot of his upcoming work in 2026. Cheeky because, while one of the four featured projects is clearly Bungie's upcoming extraction shooter Marathon, the remaining three projects are NDA symbols and cannot be discussed by the voice actor.</p>
<p>This post indicating three mysterious projects feature Toufexis' voice talents led some Deus Ex fans to feel hope once again that a new game in the franchise would be on the way. Aside from the original games Deus Ex and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/deus-ex-invisible-war">Deus Ex: Invisible War</a> in the early 2000's, we got <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/deus-ex-human-revolution">Deus Ex: Human Revolution</a> in 2011 and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/deus-ex-mankind-divided">Deus Ex: Mankind Divided</a> in 2016. Since then, one of gaming's most beloved sci-fi series has remained dormant.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Deus Ex: Mankind Divided Trailer - Jensen talks through a mission" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wiehfhUgsRc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Deus Ex: Mankind Divided Trailer - Jensen talks through a mission</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wiehfhUgsRc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wiehfhUgsRc?autoplay=1" title="Deus Ex: Mankind Divided Trailer - Jensen talks through a mission">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>You can hear Toufexis' fantastic voice work here.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wiehfhUgsRc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>With this context in mind, Toufexis came forward to break the bad news to Deus Ex faithfuls, writing: "no Deus Ex because the people in charge are psychopaths." The frustration is understandable, especially given the Mankind Divided ended on a narrative stinger which has gone without payoff ever since.</p><p>So who is in charge these days? Well, Mankind Divided was developed by Eidos Montreal and published by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> back in 2016. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-sells-off-western-studios-and-ip-including-tomb-raider-and-deus-ex">Square Enix would later sell the IP to Embracer group in 2022</a>, alongside Tomb Raider and Thief, plus the entire studio of Eidos Montreal. Embracer Group would later cancel a Deus Ex game in 2024,<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/embracer-has-reduced-its-workforce-by-over-1800-people-in-the-past-year"> laying off a sizable chunk of staff while doing so</a>. Embracer still retains control of the franchise and studio as of writing.</p>
<p>Whether we'll ever see another Deus Ex game remains a mystery, though there's perhaps some hope. Crystal Dynamics, another studio sold to Embracer by Square Enix,<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/next-tomb-raider-game-known-as-catalyst-finally-revealed-at-the-game-awards"> has only recently revealed a new Tomb Raider game</a>. If Lara Croft can come back, why can't Adam Jensen? Fingers crossed.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/deus-ex-no-2026-people-in-charge-psychopaths]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>