<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 20:55:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mastercard insists it has not "required restrictions of any" game on Steam or itch.io, but Valve claims otherwise]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/mastercard-insists-it-has-not-required-restrictions-of-any-game-on-steam-or-itchio-but-valve-claims-otherwise</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mastercard-insists-it-has-not-required-restrictions-of-any-game-on-steam-or-itch-io-but-valve-claims-otherwise.1261839/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>As NSFW games controversy continues.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
As Steam and Itch.io continued to grapple with recent pressure by payment processors to withdraw NSFW games from their platforms, Mastercard has moved to distance itself from the ensuing censorship controversy, insisting it has not "required restrictions of any" game. But Valve says otherwise, pointing to a Mastercard rule saying the company can refuse to process anything it believes 'reflects negatively' on its brand.
</p>
<p>
Last month, Valve <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/steam-introduces-vague-new-rules-banning-certain-kinds-of-adult-content-to-appease-credit-card-companies">introduced vague new guidelines</a> preventing "certain types of adult content" from being distributed on Steam, later confirming it had begun "retiring" certain adult games that "may violate the rules and standards set forth by our payment processors and their related card networks and banks". Shortly after, indie-focused digital distribution platform Itch.io <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/itchio-deindexes-all-nsfw-games-blames-same-anti-porn-group-that-campaigned-against-steam">began 'deindexing' all NSFW games</a>, blaming the same anti-porn group - Australia-based Collective Shout - that had pressured Visa, Mastercard, and PayPal into targeting Steam. In both cases, Itch.io and Valve noted the support of payment processors was essential to the ongoing operation of their platforms.
</p>
<p>
Plenty has happened since then; Itch.io has <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/itch-begins-re-indexing-free-adult-nsfw-content-as-it-seeks-alternative-payment-processors">begun reindexing free NSFW games</a> and confirmed it's looking to partner with a payment processor comfortable with adult material, while other parts of the games industry - including <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gog-offers-13-free-nsfw-games-as-it-launches-anti-censorship-campaign-freedomtobuygames">rival storefront GOG with its FreedomToBuy campaign</a> - have spoken out against game censorship. But amid all this, Mastercard is now attempting to distance itself from recent events, denying it put pressure on Itch.io and Valve to remove games from their platforms. In a <a href="https://www.mastercard.com/us/en/news-and-trends/press/2025/august/clarifying-recent-headlines-on-gaming-content.html">statement shared on its website,</a> the credit card company insisted it had "not evaluated any game or required restrictions of any activity on game creator sites and platforms, contrary to media reports and allegations."
</p>
<p>
"Our payment network follows standards based on the rule of law," it continued. "Put simply, we allow all lawful purchases on our network. At the same time, we require merchants to have appropriate controls to ensure Mastercard cards cannot be used for unlawful purchases, including illegal adult content."
</p>
<p>
However, Valve claims otherwise, saying that while Mastercard didn't directly pressure it to remove adult content from Steam, the credit card company instead "communicated with payment processors and their acquiring banks", and these, in turn, contacted Valve.
</p>
<p>
"Mastercard did not communicate with Valve directly, despite our request to do so," the Steam operator wrote in a <a href="https://kotaku.com/mastercard-denies-pressuring-steam-to-censor-nsfw-games-2000614393">statement shared with Kotaku over the weekend</a>. "Mastercard communicated with payment processors and their acquiring banks. Payment processors communicated this with Valve, and we replied by outlining <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/valve-backs-away-from-content-policing-says-it-will-allow-everything-on-steam">Steam's policy since 2018</a> of attempting to distribute games that are legal for distribution. Payment processors rejected this, and specifically cited Mastercard's Rule 5.12.7 and risk to the Mastercard brand."
</p>
<p>
Mastercard's <a href="https://www.mastercard.us/content/dam/public/mastercardcom/na/global-site/documents/mastercard-rules.pdf">Rule 5.12.7</a> prohibits transactions that are illegal or that "in the sole discretion of the Corporation, may damage the goodwill of the Corporation or reflect negatively on the Marks." The first part is easy to define - Mastercard says the sale of "products or services other than [those] in full compliance with law" violates its terms - but the second is more open-ended, giving the company potentially limitless freedom to define what is and isn't acceptable. It can then either fine, audit, or withdraw services for violations.
</p>
<p>
This latter clause prohibits "the sale of a product or service, including an image, which is patently offensive and lacks serious artistic value (such as, by way of example and not limitation, images of nonconsensual sexual behavior, sexual exploitation of a minor, nonconsensual mutilation of a person or body part, and bestiality)", but also "any other material that the Corporation deems unacceptable to sell in connection with a Mark."
</p>
<p>
As the events at Steam and Itch.io have continued to unfold, industry figures and representative bodies have spoken out against payment processor overreach. The International Game Developer Association <a href="https://igda.org/news-archive/press-release-statement-on-game-delistings/">recently showed its support</a> for games depicting "consensual adult content", pushing back against "financial institutions... influencing which stories can be told and sold in games, with minimal transparency or public accountability". But with adult content increasingly under fire - as more countries begin drafting legislation such as the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/uk-online-safety-act-explainer">UK's controversial Online Safety Act</a> - the adult games industry may have a difficult road ahead.
</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/mastercard-insists-it-has-not-required-restrictions-of-any-game-on-steam-or-itchio-but-valve-claims-otherwise]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's everything else Microsoft is doing to celebrate Rare's 40th birthday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-everything-else-microsoft-is-doing-to-celebrate-rares-40th-birthday</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-everything-else-microsoft-is-doing-to-celebrate-rares-40th-birthday.1261809/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Evercade! Vinyl! Plushies! More!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Microsoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
It turns out there's more to Microsoft's 40th birthday celebrations for beloved UK studio Rare than just an ugly controller. Xbox has now <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/08/04/rare-40th-anniversary-rewards-sea-of-thieves/">outlined its full anniversary plans</a>, which include an Evercade cartridge collection, a four-disc vinyl soundtrack, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sea-of-thieves">Sea of Thieves</a> bits, and more.
</p>
<p>
These days, Rare is best known for Sea of Thieves, but before that it gave us the wonderful <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/viva-piata">Viva Piñata</a> among other delights. And fans of a certain age will fondly recall the studio's legendary Nintendo output, which included the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/donkey-kong-country">Donkey Kong Country</a> series on SNES, and a stellar run of N64 titles, such as Banjo-Kazooie, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/goldeneye-007-review">GoldenEye 007</a>, Blast Corps, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/jet-force-gemini">Jet Force Gemini</a>, Diddy Kong Racing, Perfect Dark, and Conker's Bad Fur Day. But go back even further, to the days of rubber-keyed Spectrums and tangled tape cassettes, and the studio - then known as Ultimate Play the Game - was already pumping out bangers like Sabre Wolf, Jetpack, Atic Atac, and Knight Lore.
</p>
<p>
All of which is to say there's a lot to celebrate as the studio turns 40, and current Rare owner Microsoft has now detailed its birthday plans. Long-time fans will, for instance, have the opportunity to purchase iam8bit's Rare 40th Anniversary Box Set, which features 39 tracks across four-discs. It costs $100 USD (pre-orders <a href="https://www.iam8bit.com/products/rare-40th-anniversary-box-set-4xlp">go live on 7th August</a>) and includes two and a half hours of music, spanning the likes of Sea of Thieves, Viva Piñata, Battletoads, Banjo-Kazooie, Kinect Sports, Perfect Dark, Killer Instinct, Conker's Bad Fur Day, Jet Force Gemini, Grabbed by the Ghoulies, Blast Corps, and Kameo: Elements of Power. 
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Evercade - Rare Collection 1 - Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iWq8EOwLFrk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Evercade - Rare Collection 1 - Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iWq8EOwLFrk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/iWq8EOwLFrk?autoplay=1" title="Evercade - Rare Collection 1 - Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's a look at that Evercade collection.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iWq8EOwLFrk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Microsoft has also <a href="https://evercade.co.uk/cartridges/rare-collection-1/">teamed up with Evercade to release a new cartridge collection</a> featuring twelve "vintage" Rare titles. Specifically, it includes Jetpac, Lunar Jetman, Atic Atac, Sabre Wulf, Underwurlde, Knight Lore, Gunfright, RC Pro-Am, Cobra Triangle, Battletoads, Battletoads Arcade, and Conker's Pocket Tales, with pre-orders going live on 30th September. Elsewhere, Fangamer has a wide-ranging (but disappointingly Viva Piñata-averse) <a href="https://www.fangamer.com/collections/rare">merchandise collection</a>, which runs from t-shirts and vinyl soundtracks to key rings and a King Conker plushie I'm struggling to resist. As for that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/its-been-a-rough-year-for-rare-but-at-least-xbox-is-celebrating-its-40th-anniversary-with-a-licensed-controller">previously leaked 8bitdo Rare 40th Anniversary Edition controller</a>, it costs $89.99 USD and still seems to be a US exclusive.
</p>
<p>
And inevitably, Sea of Thieves is also getting in on the birthday action. Starting tomorrow, Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscribers can grab the in-game Rare Ruby Emote as a Perk, and a Pirate Emporium sale begins on 6th August, discounting various cosmetics inspired by classic Rare games. There's more happening from 14th August, when the multiplayer pirate adventure's next season, Smugglers' Tide, begins. Players that log in before the end of the month, for instance, get the Rare Ruby Eyepatch; various ruby-themed items will be available to purchase from Outposts, and the Ruby Legend Figurehead can be unlocked as a goal during the next Community Weekend on 30th August. On top of that, there's a 40th Anniversary Sea of Thieves cosmetics bundle coming to digital storefronts when the new season starts, as well as a ruby ship set in the Pirate Emporium and ruby items in the Seasonal Plunder Pass.
</p>
<figure>

<figcaption>A blue heritage plaque marking the birthplace of Rare. | <span>Image credit: <cite>Microsoft</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
But if you're in need of more immediate celebrations, Microsoft has just launched new Xbox gamerpics and a dynamic background featuring a "who's-who of Rare characters old and new". Furthermore, Rare fans able to make the pilgrimage to the English town of Ashby-de-la-Zouch, Leicestershire, can gaze upon a blue heritage plaque, which has been unveiled on the building where Tim and Chris Stamper co-founded the studio in 1985.
</p>
<p>
It's just a shame all this follows a difficult year for Rare, which saw its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/rares-everwild-reportedly-cancelled-following-xbox-job-cuts">long-in-the-works fantasy game Everwild cancelled</a> in July with some employees facing redundancy amid devastating Xbox restructuring that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-begins-substantial-layoff-process-across-gaming-division-king-and-zenimax-impacted">resulted in substantial job cuts across Microsoft's games division</a>. Additionally, Rare veteran Gregg Mayles, who directed the likes of Banjo-Kazooie and Sea of Thieves, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sea-of-thieves-and-banjo-kazooie-director-gregg-mayles-reportedly-leaving-rare-after-35-years">departed the studio after more than 35 years</a>.
</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-everything-else-microsoft-is-doing-to-celebrate-rares-40th-birthday]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>