<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 10:51:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion Remastered off to a good start on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-off-to-a-good-start-on-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-off-to-a-good-start-on-steam.1171086/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-off-to-a-good-start-on-steam<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Who would have suspected Bethesda to shadow drop Oblivion yesterday! Well, quite a lot of us, in fact. 
</p>
<p>
But regardless of whether fans had already prepped themselves for The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion Remastered or not, they turned up in huge numbers.
</p>
<p>
Over on Steam, which <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2623190/charts/">publicly reveals its player data</a>, Oblivion Remastered has an 182,298 concurrent player peak so far - placing it ahead of anything else on Steam except stalwarts <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/counter-strike-two">Counter-Strike 2</a>, PUBG and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dota-2">Dota 2</a>.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Elder Scrolls 4 Oblivion Remastered Live Reaction - WAIT, IT'S REAL?!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yBrWEPgDrI0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Elder Scrolls 4 Oblivion Remastered Live Reaction - WAIT, IT'S REAL?!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yBrWEPgDrI0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/yBrWEPgDrI0?autoplay=1" title="Elder Scrolls 4 Oblivion Remastered Live Reaction - WAIT, IT'S REAL?!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Eurogamer's video team reacts to The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion Remastered reveal.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yBrWEPgDrI0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Oblivion Remastered is, perhaps unsurprisingly, the best-selling game on Steam right now, and has launched with a Very Positive user review rating from those who have played.
</p>
<p>
Of course, Steam's numbers only count for a fraction of those who have jumped in so far. Oblivion Remastered is also available via the Microsoft Store on PC, and via the PC Game Pass subscription, as well as on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S, including via Game Pass Ultimate.
</p>
<p>
We'll be keeping an eye out for combined player numbers from Bethesda when they're available.
</p>
<p>
As announced - and launched - yesterday, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesda-reveals-the-elder-scrolls-4-obivion-remake-gameplay">the Oblivion Remaster is really more of a ground-up remake</a> using Unreal Engine 5 from talented co-developer Virtuos. 
</p>
<p>
The new version of Bethesda's classic role-player includes the game's previous expansion content and boasts various gameplay tweaks such as a refreshed levelling system inspired by Skyrim, additional dialogue, modern controls including sprinting. It now also runs at 4K 60fps.
</p>
<p>
Last night, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesda-say-no-official-mod-support-for-its-oblivion-remaster">Bethesda said it had no plans for Oblivion Remastered official mod support</a>, though plenty of unofficial mods have popped up now anyway. Bethesda also made the welcome gesture of gifting access to the Oblivion Remaster to the team of fans currently remaking Oblivion in the Skyrim engine. 
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Part 2 Abby actress reflects on "intense" reaction, TV series story changes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-part-2-abby-actress-reflects-on-intense-reaction-tv-series-story-changes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-part-2-abby-actress-reflects-on-intense-reaction-tv-series-story-changes.1171065/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-part-2-abby-actress-reflects-on-intense-reaction-tv-series-story-changes<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"A very rough period of time."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Kaitlyn-Dever-as-Abby-in-The-Last-of-Us-series-two-next-to-an-image-of-Abby-from-The-Last-of-Us-Part-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>HBO/Naughty Dog/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Laura Bailey, who played Abby Anderson in The Last of Us Part 2, believes HBO made the right call changing several key points in the TV adaptation.</p>
<p><strong>Please note, there will be spoilers for The Last of Us below.</strong></p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UtaSpf-70nc?autoplay=1" title="9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>9 Exciting 2025 Open-World Games We Can't Wait to Play. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtaSpf-70nc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Earlier this week, the second episode of The Last of Us' second season aired. While much of the episode's run time was made up of the infected's attack on Jackson, there was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-internet-reacts-to-the-last-of-us-season-twos-latest-episode">one particular moment that left fans of the series in shock</a>: Joel's death.</p>
<p>As in the video game it is based on, in HBO's adaptation Joel - played by Pedro Pascal - is killed by new character Abby with a golf club, following a harrowing and bloody beating. While Abby's reasons for killing Joel are not explained until much later in the game's narrative, resulting in a surprising twist for players, HBO's showrunners decided to change this, laying out Abby's intentions from the beginning.</p>
<p>The second series begins with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-2-episode-one-makes-a-big-change-to-the-chronology-of-abbys-revelation-and-im-not-sure-about-it">Kaitlyn Dever's Abby mourning the loss of her fellow Fireflies following Joel's rampage at the end of season one</a>, vowing to kill him for what he has done. Now, Bailey has spoken about the changes in the script, stating she believes them to be a wise choice by the showrunners.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2025-02-14-at-12.41.40.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>When it first leaked that Abby kills Joel in The Last of Us Part 2, Bailey received online abuse and death threats aimed at herself and her son. "Every time I went online, that's all I saw. Death threats and threats of violence," she said in the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-part-2s-abby-actor-reveals-online-abuse-didnt-just-threaten-her-life-but-her-baby-son-too">behind-the-scenes documentary, Grounded 2: Making The Last of Us Part 2</a>, which was released in February last year.</p>
<p>Now speaking with <a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/the-last-of-us-abby-voice-actress-interview-backlash.html">Vulture</a>, Bailey says she feels it was a good decision by the showrunners to brace viewers for Joel's fate ahead of the event itself. "I think that's why HBO is doing what they're doing," she said. "You're prepared for it."</p>
<p>Bailey called her own experiences with the online abuse "a very rough period of time" for her. "I knew it was going to be intense. I knew it was going to be controversial," the Abby actress said.</p>
<p>"But I was still so excited to share it with the world, because I poured so much into that performance, and I was really proud of it. So to get <em>that </em>reaction right away was really tough. I don't think anybody predicted what the fallout would be from it. I was not prepared. But I don't think anybody on the team was."</p>
<p>Bailey admitted there is still a part of her that is anxious Joel's TV death will stir things up again, and while things have "definitely calmed down" in the five years since The Last of Us Part 2's first release, "there's definitely still a contingent of people that have not calmed down" from the events of the game.</p>
<p>"You know, anytime anything gets posted about [The Last of Us Part 2], or anytime I post anything random, there's going to be at least one comment from somebody," Bailey revealed.</p>
<p>"And I honestly don't know: Is it just the same hundred people that keep commenting? And they just won't let go? It's one of the reasons I don't really post on social media anymore. I don't want to say I was scared away from it, because I don't think that's what it was. It just kind of made me more guarded, you know?"</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Kaitlyn-Dever-as-Abby-in-TLOU-season-two.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>HBO</cite></span></figcaption></figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/abby-the-last-of-us.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Naughty Dog</cite></span></figcaption></figure>
</figure>
<p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/naughty-dog">Naughty Dog</a> and HBO have already confirmed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-tv-show-renewed-for-season-three-and-the-second-hasnt-even-aired-yet">The Last of Us will be back for a third season</a>, with showrunner Craig Mazin stating:</p>
<p>"We approached season two with the goal of creating something we could be proud of. The end results have exceeded even our most ambitious goals."</p>
<p>For more, you can check out my feature on the show's latest episode: <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/joel-dominates-headlines-but-its-tommy-who-shines-in-the-last-of-us-season-2-episode-two">Joel dominates headlines, but it's Tommy who shines in The Last of Us season 2 episode two</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>