<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:55:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Missing shots in Battlefield 6? Well, you might not be bad, a bug might be throwing your shots off]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/missing-shots-in-battlefield-6-well-you-might-not-be-bad-a-bug-might-be-throwing-your-shots-off</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/missing-shots-in-battlefield-6-well-you-might-not-be-bad-a-bug-might-be-throwing-your-shots-off.1325089/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Have you been struggling to hit other players in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/battlefield-2025">Battlefield 6</a>, especially when shooting for extended periods of time? Well, it turns out it may not be a skill issue, as a bug related to bullet dispersion is causing shots to go wide.</p>
<p>It's meant to work is like this. When you shoot an automatic weapon in Battlefield 6 for an extended period of time, the bullets will start to shift away from where your aiming reticle is pointed. This is due to a combination of recoil and random, intended deviations, and is there to prevent people being able to maintain near-perfect accuracy while unloading an entire magazine. It also promotes firing in bursts, which is more realistic and Battlefield-y.</p>
<p>The problem is, even when you do fire in bursts, stopping to allow this weapon bloom to reset, right now that doesn't always happen. As shown in the clip below, the bullet spread you had at the end of your previous burst can remain even after you stop and start firing again, leading to greater inaccuracy. In laymen's terms, your guns may not be as accurate as they should be during persistent firefights.</p>
<div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>This was a problem during the Battlefield 6 beta too, and some have speculated this is the same problem from that early version of the game alive and well during Battlefield 6's full launch. However, it turns out this problem is thanks to entirely new bugs.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Watch our Battlefield 6 video review!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N5TCS-pDmqk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Principle game designer on Battlefield 6 Florian Le Bihan stated on X: "The Beta bug was actually fixed but we've identified another issue (two in fact) that impacts dispersion/bloom in an unintended way and will cause you to have more dispersion at times," Bihan stated on X. "The team is working on this and we're looking at general balance/tuning of dispersion too."</p><p>Such small problems do have a wider impact on the gameplay experience, especially for more competitive players. However it's worth noting that the Battlefield 6 team has proven especially keen to fix bugs and other issues. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-ladder-launching-one-of-the-games-funnest-bugs-will-soon-be-gone">It was only recently they announced that Ladder Launching will soon be gone</a>, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-issues-fix-for-jump-momentum-bug-and-is-monitoring-breakthrough-player-counts">various movement techniques that proved unpalatable for the intended Battlefield experience were removed too</a>.</p>
<p>These come as Battlefield 6 remains a powerhouse in terms of player numbers, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-has-only-been-out-a-day-and-its-already-one-of-steams-biggest-games-ever">quickly becoming one of the biggest Steam launches of all time</a> with nearly 750,000 concurrent players on its launch day last weekend.</p>



        </div>
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/missing-shots-in-battlefield-6-well-you-might-not-be-bad-a-bug-might-be-throwing-your-shots-off]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 "ladder launching" - one of the game's funnest bugs - will soon be gone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-ladder-launching-one-of-the-games-funnest-bugs-will-soon-be-gone</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-ladder-launching-one-of-the-games-funnest-bugs-will-soon-be-gone.1325086/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-multiplayer-reveal-screen-9_csTNWaO.jpeg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-multiplayer-reveal-screen-9_csTNWaO.jpeg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-multiplayer-reveal-screen-9_csTNWaO.jpeg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-multiplayer-reveal-screen-9_csTNWaO.jpeg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-multiplayer-reveal-screen-9_csTNWaO.jpeg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-multiplayer-reveal-screen-9_csTNWaO.jpeg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-multiplayer-reveal-screen-9_csTNWaO.jpeg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-multiplayer-reveal-screen-9_csTNWaO.jpeg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-6-multiplayer-reveal-screen-9_csTNWaO.jpeg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Ladder launching will soon be removed in an upcoming <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/battlefield-2025">Battlefield 6</a> patch, according to lead producer David Sirland.</p>
<p>The act of ladder launching allows players to essentially bounce off Assault Ladders to get a sudden boost of speed up into the air, allowing for unintentional mobility options and alternative angles of attack. It is absolutely a bug and needs to be removed, but on the other hand, it is really fun to do! So you should probably give it a go while you can.</p>
<p>Sirland, asking for general feedback on X following the initial launch of Battlefield 6, outright confirmed this bug in particular will be removed in an upcoming patch. He wrote: "Please keep the feedback coming! With the first weekend for BF6 in the wild, we are bound to have found issues, problems, stuff you like to see change - perhaps even praise? It's still all good, I want to know. And the team is eager to show you how much we care!"</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Battlefield 6 is one of the best entries in the series... When it's being Battlefield.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N5TCS-pDmqk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Other suggestions Sirland publicly acknowledged include names for objective points, as well as problems with helicopter spawns. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-issues-fix-for-jump-momentum-bug-and-is-monitoring-breakthrough-player-counts">Quick hotfixes have already been pushed out to fix movement bugs</a>, so it looks as though Battlefield 6 will certainly continue to get improvements in the coming weeks, as the game marches towards its major season one update on the 28th October.</p><p>Assault Ladders it seems are a source of a few headaches, at least as far as bugs are concerned. Not only do they currently let you do some cheeky ladder launching, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/despite-eas-best-efforts-battlefield-6-players-are-finding-themselves-out-of-bounds-and-on-top-of-rooftops">players have been using them to reach otherwise unintentional high ground</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-has-only-been-out-a-day-and-its-already-one-of-steams-biggest-games-ever">Battlefield 6 has proven exceptionally popular </a>since its full launch last weekend, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-players-face-extensive-queues-this-weekend-as-servers-immediately-reach-capacity">so slammed full of players that extensive server queues kept many from jumping into the game</a>. It even broke the EA app, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-issues-free-premium-battlefield-6-season-passes-to-ea-app-pre-orderers-frozen-out-of-the-game">forcing the company to hand out free premium battle passes to frozen-out users</a>.</p>



        </div>
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-ladder-launching-one-of-the-games-funnest-bugs-will-soon-be-gone]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>