<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 01:01:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark Souls now has seamless co-op thanks to modder who did the same for Elden Ring]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dark-souls-now-has-seamless-co-op-thanks-to-modder-who-did-the-same-for-elden-ring</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-souls-now-has-seamless-co-op-thanks-to-modder-who-did-the-same-for-elden-ring.1164282/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/dark-souls-now-has-seamless-co-op-thanks-to-modder-who-did-the-same-for-elden-ring<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Dark-Souls-bonfire.webp?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
FromSoftware's seminal action-RPG Dark Souls now has seamless co-op, courtesy of the modder behind similar co-op overhauls for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-walkthrough-8042">Elden Ring</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dark-souls-iii">Dark Souls 3</a>.
</p>
<p>
Modder Yui initially <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/eldenring/mods/510">made headlines through their work on Elden Ring</a>, stripping away some of its co-operative faff so players could adventure and battle bosses together seamlessly. A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ahead-of-elden-ring-nightreign-dark-souls-3-modder-adds-seamless-co-op-overhaul-nine-years-after-release">similar mod arrived for Dark Souls 3</a> earlier this year, and now it's the turn of FromSoftware's stone cold classic Dark Souls, which gets seamless co-op some 14 years after its original release.
</p>
<p>
Dark Souls' Seamless Co-op mod is <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/darksoulsremastered/mods/899">available to download now on NexusMods</a> and works very much like Yui's earlier mods, introducing a special custom item used to summon up to five additional players into a game. Once in a multiplayer session participants will notice some major differences compared to how things work in the base game.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dark Souls Remastered Seamless Co-op: Release" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wqdZ1-uk9h8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dark Souls Remastered Seamless Co-op: Release</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wqdZ1-uk9h8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wqdZ1-uk9h8?autoplay=1" title="Dark Souls Remastered Seamless Co-op: Release">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's a look at the Dark Souls Seamless Co-op mod in action.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wqdZ1-uk9h8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
If a players dies, for instance, they'll spawn at the last bonfire they visited rather than being booted from the session, and clearing areas or defeating bosses won't disband play either. Additionally, when one player rests at a bonfire, the world will reset for everyone; NPC dialogue and events are synchronised for all players; all fog walls and barriers designed to restrict multiplayer zones are removed, and game progression made during a multiplayer session will also progress the game in your own world.
</p>
<p>
Yui has also implemented configurable multiplayer difficulty scaling for all enemies, and says that while seamless co-op makes Dark Souls "significantly easier", the mod's default scaling settings should be enjoyable while 'somewhat preserving the game's challenge'. Notably, players can't immediately spawn back into a boss fight on death - they'll instead be turned into a spectator until either everyone in the party is defeated or a player rests at a bonfire.
</p>
<p>
Dark Souls' seamless co-op mod - which also supports Invasions - is currently at the alpha stage, meaning it's "very likely" to contain bugs. Using it won't, however, result in a ban, given it utilises an overhauled peer-to-peer connection system rather than FromSoftware's servers. The mod even creates a different save file to keep things separate in case you want to play the vanilla game at the same time - although Yui warns that attempting to revert a mod saved file to a vanilla save <em>will</em> likely result in a ban.
</p>
<p>
Yui's Dark Souls mod comes ahead of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/after-eight-hours-with-elden-ring-nightreign-im-convinced-multiplayer-souls-is-an-exhilarating-rush">FromSoftware's multiplayer-focused Nightreign</a>, in which up to three players can work together to defeat <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-nightreign-will-feature-enemies-from-dark-souls-director-confirms">new and familiar challenges from Elden Ring and other From games</a> - including The Nameless King from Dark Souls 3. <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Nightreign</a> launches for PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC on 30th May - and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2</a> is also getting its own bit of FromSoftware multiplayer in the form of the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fromsoftwares-the-duskbloods-is-bloodborne-meets-sekiro-meets-dark-souls-with-jetpacks-and-dinos-thrown-in">recently revealed The Duskbloods</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>