<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:28:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["You've just made my day" live reactions to the Silksong release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/youve-just-made-my-day-live-reactions-to-the-silksong-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/youve-just-made-my-day-live-reactions-to-the-silksong-release-date.1277223/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Team Cherry</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>In case you hadn't heard the many summon circle participants crying out in joy that their prayers had finally been answered, or the klaxons sounding far and wide, let me tell you the good news - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksong-finally-gets-release-date-out-next-month">Silksong has a release date</a>!</p>
<p>The much anticipated <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hollow-knight">Hollow Knight</a> follow up is set to release across Switch consoles, PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S, including on Xbox Game Pass in just two weeks time, on 4th September.</p>
<p>On the ground here at <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-at-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024">Gamescom</a>, applause could be heard as the date was announced, so of course I headed out into the fray to get some first hand reactions from those waiting in line for the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hollow-knight-silksong">Silksong</a> demo. What I got was a mix of relief, giddy anticipation and, for one person, a little bit of stress.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>First up, there was the lovely young gentleman who had somehow missed the news until I asked his thoughts about Silksong's release date.</p>
<p>"Wait, what?! It's coming out? Okay, I am pretty freaking excited. This is crazy, because everybody was waiting for it, and now it's so soon! Two weeks? Ahhh, I am very happy," he beamed. "I played the first Hollow Knight a few years back, and it was the first metroidvania I played, and it made me fall in love with the genre, and since then I have played many more metroidvanias and it's all because of Hollow Knight. I loved it - I hope this is going to be even better!</p>
<p>"You've just made my day."</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Team Cherry</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"I am quite surprised it is so soon," another Gamescom attendee told me. "I've been waiting just as impatiently as everyone else."</p>
<p>"I played the original in 2017, and since then - I've been waiting!!" another added. "It's two weeks, that's wild!! When [Team Cherry] said it's this year, I thought maybe at Christmas, but… two weeks!"</p>
<p>"I am sooo, so so so surprised it is coming out so soon," I was again told. "Ahh, I can't wait!!"</p>
<p>A very eloquent chap of 12 years old told me he had been waiting for this moment for four years. "I loved the first one," he said. "It's super nice." He will "definitely" be getting Silksong day one, he informed me, with this being the game he is most excited about.</p><p>Another chap waiting in the queue for Silksong's demo told me that while he was both "surprised" and "excited", but also already feeling pretty stressed about managing to play all the games he wants to. "It's coming out right between <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a> and before <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-f">Silent Hill f</a>. I want to play all of those games! But, I will play Silksong day one," he laughed.</p>
<p>"I have been waiting for years [he gestured to his shirt which shows Hornet looking back at me]. It's absolutely great news, I have been waiting for so long."</p>
<p>Are you just as excited as this lot?</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Team Cherry</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Elsewhere in Silksong news, it has not, in fact, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/no-silksong-hasnt-been-in-development-hell-hype-skyrocketed-sales-of-the-original-game-to-give-team-cherry-financial-freedom">taken so long to release due to being stuck in development hell</a>. Rather, hype skyrocketed sales of the original game to give Team Cherry financial freedom.</p>
<p>Our Dom also braved the Gamescom queues to go hands-on with Silksong, and came away impressed with its high challenge and how Hornet's movement differs from the original game's Knight. You can check out their thoughts in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/with-gamescom-queues-over-an-hour-and-reddit-in-overdrive-hollow-knight-silksong-hype-has-outpaced-everything-from-opening-night-live">Eurogamer's Silksong preview here</a>.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/youve-just-made-my-day-live-reactions-to-the-silksong-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No, Silksong hasn't been in development hell, hype skyrocketed sales of the original game to give Team Cherry financial freedom]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/no-silksong-hasnt-been-in-development-hell-hype-skyrocketed-sales-of-the-original-game-to-give-team-cherry-financial-freedom</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-silksong-hasnt-been-in-development-hell-hype-skyrocketed-sales-of-the-original-game-to-give-team-cherry-financial-freedom.1277154/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"It's nice to make fun things."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Team Cherry</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Earlier today, Team Cherry finally <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksong-finally-gets-release-date-out-next-month">announced a release date for its long-awaited Hollow Knight sequel Silksong</a>. After seven years, it will finally be out next month.</p>
<p>Yet contrary to what you may believe, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hollow-knight-silksong">Silksong</a> hasn't been in development hell for that time. Instead, Team Cherry's developers were just having too much fun making it.</p>
<p>In fact, sales of the original game have skyrocketed from 2.8m copies to 15m copies since Silksong's announcement in 2019, giving the studio the financial freedom to take their time.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Hollow Knight: Silksong - Release Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6XGeJwsUP9c?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Hollow Knight: Silksong - Release Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6XGeJwsUP9c?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6XGeJwsUP9c?autoplay=1" title="Hollow Knight: Silksong - Release Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Hollow Knight: Silksong - Special Announcement<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6XGeJwsUP9c" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>What was originally intended as an expansion to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hollow-knight">Hollow Knight</a> soon ballooned into its own game, with the studio announcing in February 2019 it would be a full sequel.</p>
<p>"Even at that point we were recognising that it was going to become another giant thing to rival the scale of Hollow Knight or probably exceed it," Team Cherry co-founder Ari Gibson told <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-08-21/why-silksong-team-cherry-s-sequel-to-hollow-knight-took-so-long-to-make?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc1NTc4NjYzOSwiZXhwIjoxNzU2MzkxNDM5LCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJUMUNMTUpHUFdDUFcwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.oTN8q1m9pNWFv7oW-n3vzq-hRWAxrDx9B7iF80RdTzk&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall">Bloomberg</a>. "And then because of how we work, obviously the world ended up being just as big or bigger. And the quest system existed. And the multiple towns existed. Suddenly you end up six, seven years later."</p>
<p>"It was never stuck or anything," Gibson added. "It was always progressing. It's just the case that we're a small team, and games take a lot of time. There wasn't any big controversial moment behind it."</p>
<p>That 12m rise in sales of the original Hollow Knight is extraordinary. Somehow, Team Cherry inadvertently created the ultimate hype machine: hype for the sequel led to sales for the original, which meant it could take longer to develop, which fed the hype even more due to silence, which became a meme, which meant it could take even longer.</p>
<p>"We're very lucky in that regard," said Gibson. "I don't ever really think about it that much. Maybe that's the privilege of it."</p>
<p>No strict deadline and a flood of financial income meant Team Cherry could take its time. It's in stark contrast to so many other studios at the moment hell-bent on chasing trends and generating cash in the face of rising development costs, which has inevitably resulted in the mass layoffs across the industry in the last couple of years.</p>
<p>By contrast, Team Cherry has remained lean. What's more, it's spent the past seven years enjoying development.</p>
<p>"We've been having fun," said Gibson said. "This whole thing is just a vehicle for our creativity anyway. It's nice to make fun things.</p>
<p>"We're very fortunate that we have a development method that is so enjoyable," Gibson continued. "Not exactly sure how we stumbled into that. Everything comes together quickly. You can see results fast. Ideas turn into something that exist in the game almost immediately before your eyes, and that's very satisfying. And that allows you to go off on those tangents and meet weird characters because someone's off-handedly mentioned a weird character as an idea and the other person's laughed, and that's enough."</p>
<figure>

<figcaption>Will Silksong push the Metroidvania genre to new heights? | <span>Image credit: <cite>Team Cherry</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"You're always working on a new idea, new item, new area, new boss," added co-founder William Pellen. "That stuff's so nice. It's for the sake of just completing the game that we're stopping. We could have kept going."</p>
<p>Add to that a desire for exceptional polish, and it's easy to see how development could have continued even longer.</p>
<p>"I think we're always underestimating the amount of time and effort it'll take us to achieve things," said Gibson. "It's also that problem where, because we're having fun doing it, it's not like, 'It's taking longer, this is awful, we really need to get past this phase.' It's, 'This is a very enjoyable space to be in. Let's perpetuate this with some new ideas.'"</p><p>"There's a level of finish that has to be met throughout the entire game," added Pellen. "All the way the systems interact, all the hidden work that pops up later on. It's multiplicative. As you add stuff, the process of tying it all back together just increases."</p>
<p>Of course, it remains to be seen whether Silksong will fully live up to the hype, but with its release date of 4th September it won't be long until we find out. At the least, it follows games like <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> as a project with a relatively small team and a huge amount of passion finding big success, where so many AAA studios and publishers have stumbled.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/no-silksong-hasnt-been-in-development-hell-hype-skyrocketed-sales-of-the-original-game-to-give-team-cherry-financial-freedom]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>