<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 14:45:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite OG will rotate Chapter 1 seasons every couple of months]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-og-will-rotate-chapter-1-seasons-every-couple-of-months</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-og-will-rotate-chapter-1-seasons-every-couple-of-months.1052532/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-og-will-rotate-chapter-1-seasons-every-couple-of-months<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Original map relaunches tomorrow, with Ranked mode to follow.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-12-04-173144.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Epic Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Epic Games has detailed a few more details on its much-anticipated <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> OG mode, which brings back the game's beloved original battle royale Island as a newly-permanent addition. 
</p>
<p>
As previously suspected, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-reviving-original-map-as-permanent-addition-featuring-multiple-classic-seasons">Fortnite OG will rotate through the game's original Chapter 1 seasons</a>. Today, we learned that these will begin with a season lasting until 31st January - so roughly two months. 
</p>
<p>
This means, of course, shorter seasons than the original Fortnite Chapter 1 featured - and shorter than the game's main Chapter 6 version. But we're all waiting for the meteor impact and the volcano anyway, right? So this is good news.
</p>
<p>
Fortnite OG will feature solos and squads modes at launch, with both classic building enabled and Zero Build options. 
</p>
<p>
Other improvements from the original Chapter 1 will include modern building mechanics and traversal options to sprint, slide, mantle, door bash and move while healing. Epic Games does not make mention of the very latest mechanics added in Chapter 6, such as wall jumping.
</p><p>
As previously announced, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnites-permanent-og-mode-will-have-its-own-battle-pass">Fortnite OG will also feature its own distinct battle pass</a>, which will feature 45 tiers of rewards. This is one of the four in-game passes now included in the £10 a month Fortnite Crew subscription, and offers three skins plus other bits and pieces. 
</p>
<p>
Epic Games previously revealed brought back its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-smashes-concurrent-user-records-as-over-6m-players-log-on-this-weekend">hugely-popular original Fortnite map 12 months ago</a> for a limited time, the launch of which saw the game hit 44.7 million players in 24 hours. Last weekend, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-remix-finale-event-smashes-14m-all-time-player-record">Fortnite broke its own player record for a live concert event</a>, with 14 million concurrent players tuning in to watch Eminem, Snoop Dogg, Ice Spice and Juice WRLD.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hitman's next Elusive Target is Jean-Claude 'The Splitter' Van Damme]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/hitmans-next-elusive-target-is-jean-claude-the-splitter-van-damme</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hitmans-next-elusive-target-is-jean-claude-the-splitter-van-damme.1052493/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/hitmans-next-elusive-target-is-jean-claude-the-splitter-van-damme<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Players will soon be able to have Agent 47 take a few pot shots (other methods are available) at none other than Jean-Claude Van Damme, with the actor lending his likeness to Hitman's next Elusive Target: Max Valliant aka The Splitter.</p>
<p>Max Valliant is described as one of the ICA's "most formidable operatives", and one whom everyone assumed to be dead and gone. But, of course, that isn't actually the case, and now he is back and causing trouble. Agent 47 needs to put a stop to that, and will head to Chongqing for the occasion.</p>
<p>The Splitter will both be available as part of the Free Starter Pack for new players (although, not on Switch) and as a regular Elusive Target for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hitman-world-of-assassination">Hitman World of Assassination</a> players. Interested in giving it a shot? Well, you will be able to take down Valliant from 12th December, until 12th January. Here's a trailer:</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="HITMAN: World of Assassination - The Splitter  (featuring @JCVDWorld ) Mission Reveal" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9xS2zKlpYVM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>HITMAN: World of Assassination - The Splitter  (featuring @JCVDWorld ) Mission Reveal</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9xS2zKlpYVM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9xS2zKlpYVM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Well, I'll be Jean-Claude Van Dammed! <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9xS2zKlpYVM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Max Valliant is quite the entertaining character, bringing a lot of action movie villain energy, he is ruthless, and of course, he can do the split!" shared Jean-Claude Van Damme. "The Splitter is a thrilling mission and like in any good action flick, Hitman players will have a few surprises, but I'll let them find out by themselves."</p><p>Van Damme is known for his love of doing the splits, as you can see in the header image above. In fact, when developer IOI first teased The Splitter, <a href="https://www.hitmanforum.com/t/new-elusive-target-the-splitter-winter-2024/22258/20">many guessed</a> the actor would be one of Agent 47's upcoming targets.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Jean-Claude-Van-Damme-in-Hitman.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>IOI</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In addition, IOI has also announced The Splitter Pack DLC, which will retail for £3.99 when it goes live on 12th December. The Splitter Pack includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Permanent Access to the Replication - a two-level Arcade contract featuring The Splitter Elusive Target</li>
<li>The Splitter SMG</li>
<li>The Splitter Kukri Knife</li>
<li>The "Good Quar Vol. 3" VHS Tape</li>
<li>A set of six cosmetics for the Freelancer Safehouse inspired by the Elusive Target</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Volvo Trucks - The Epic Split feat. Van Damme" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M7FIvfx5J10?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Volvo Trucks - The Epic Split feat. Van Damme</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M7FIvfx5J10?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/M7FIvfx5J10?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Of course I had to reshare this Volvo advert. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M7FIvfx5J10" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Season of The Splitter is also coming for Hitman World of Assassination players. This will be free, and launching on 12th December. The season will feature new challenges, featured contracts, returning targets and some <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/twitch">Twitch</a>-related perks.</p>
<p>Last but not least, when all of this Jean-Claude Van Damme flavoured goodness goes live on 12th December, Hitman World of Assassination will be patched up to support <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/topics/ps5-pro">PS5 Pro</a> features. This means assassinating at a locked 60fps, with a resolution of 3840 x 2160.</p>
<p>You can check out <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/every-ps5-pro-enhanced-games-listed">all of the PS5 Pro Enhanced games with our guide here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google has developed an AI tool that generates fully playable 3D worlds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/google-has-developed-an-ai-tool-that-generates-fully-playable-3d-worlds</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/google-has-developed-an-ai-tool-that-generates-fully-playable-3d-worlds.1052424/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/google-has-developed-an-ai-tool-that-generates-fully-playable-3d-worlds<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Genie is out of the bottle.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/google-genie2.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Google</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Google has developed a new AI tool that can generate a fully playable 3D game world from a single image prompt.</p>
<p>Genie 2, as the tool is known, is described as a "world model". So where Genie 1 generated 2D worlds, this subsequent tool can create 3D worlds in a variety of perspectives and includes the consequences of taking actions like jumping or swimming.</p>
<p>Google stresses the tool can be used for "rapid prototyping" as it "enables artists and designers to prototype quickly, which can bootstrap the creative process for environment design, further accelerating research".</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Is Sony buying FromSoftware's parent company the next big games industry acquisition?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qvqusIyhV2M" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>It works using a single image prompt, with Google of course using examples from its own text-to-image AI tool Imagen 3, though real world images can be used too.</p>
<p>From there users can jump in and interact with the world, with the AI overcoming challenges like understanding control inputs and remembering the world it's created as the camera pans elements in and out of view. It then generates new plausible content on the fly for up to a minute of gameplay.</p>
<p>It can further generate NPCs and interactions with them; the physics of water or gravity; lighting models and reflections; and multiple animations.</p>
<p>"While this research is still in its early stage with substantial room for improvement on both agent and environment generation capabilities, we believe Genie 2 is the path to solving a structural problem of training embodied agents safely while achieving the breadth and generality required to progress towards AGI [Artificial General Intelligence]," reads a <a href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/genie-2-a-large-scale-foundation-world-model/">blog post on the tool from Google</a>.</p>
<p>So while the tool can be used for prototyping, it's also being used to train further AI models.</p>
<p>Discussing how Google developed the technology responsibly, the blog post reads: "Genie 2 shows the potential of foundational world models for creating diverse 3D environments and accelerating agent research. This research direction is in its early stages and we look forward to continuing to improve Genie's world generation capabilities in terms of generality and consistency.</p><p>"As with SIMA [Scalable Instructable Multiworld Agent], our research is building towards more general AI systems and agents that can understand and safely carry out a wide range of tasks in a way that is helpful to people online and in the real world."</p>
<p>As such it's purpose as of yet doesn't seem to be directly in video game development, though the potential is clear.</p>
<p>Indeed, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/how-ai-is-changing-video-game-development-forever">AI is changing video game development</a> with its use in multiple areas, from NPCs to scriptwriting and voice acting.</p>
<p>Multiple studios have already stated their interest in AI technology, both for and against it. Most recently, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-boss-says-ai-will-revolutionise-gaming-but-must-be-balanced-with-human-touch">PlayStation co-CEO Hermen Hulst</a> stated AI technology has the capacity to "revolutionise" the games industry, but it won't replace the "human touch".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>