<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 11:01:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team Cherry confirms Hollow Knight: Silksong is coming this year following Xbox Games Showcase]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/team-cherry-confirms-hollow-knight-silksong-is-coming-this-year-following-xbox-games-showcase</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/team-cherry-confirms-hollow-knight-silksong-is-coming-this-year-following-xbox-games-showcase.1213080/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/team-cherry-confirms-hollow-knight-silksong-is-coming-this-year-following-xbox-games-showcase<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Team Cherry</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Team Cherry has confirmed that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hollow-knight-silksong">Hollow Knight Silksong</a> will be coming out before the holiday season this year, following the game's appearance at last night's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-game-showcase-2025-round-up-everything-announced">Xbox Games Showcase</a>.</p>
<p>Writing on the official Silksong Discord, Team Cherry's Matthew Griffon wrote: "I confirmed BEFORE holiday - we are not tied to a console release." This indicates that Silksong's release is not tied to that of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsofts-xbox-branded-asus-handheld-finally-gets-an-official-reveal">Xbox's new Xbox ROG Ally handheld</a>.</p>
<p>The reason for the confusion is due to the game's sudden appearance at the tail-end of the Xbox ROG Ally reveal at the Xbox Games Showcase. Xbox's Sarah Bond stated that people will be able to play Silksong on this new handheld, leading some to interpret the two sharing a release date.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Seriously, What Is Hollow Knight Silksong's Release Date?" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V2nAnDLgHBM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Seriously, What Is Hollow Knight Silksong's Release Date?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V2nAnDLgHBM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/V2nAnDLgHBM?autoplay=1" title="Seriously, What Is Hollow Knight Silksong's Release Date?">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Check out Eurogamer's video on the Silksong release date situation here!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V2nAnDLgHBM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The gaggle of people who have been fiending for anything and everything Silksong related have been desperate for anything concrete about the game and its release. Prior to the event-heavy weekend, interest was piqued <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksong-steam-update-ignites-perfectly-reasonable-shadow-drop-hopes">due to an update to the game's Steam page</a>.</p>
<p>Before that, the game was confirmed as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silksong-is-playable-in-a-museum-this-september-but-that-probably-doesnt-help-narrow-down-its-release-date">playable at an Australian museum this September</a>. Earlier still, Nintendo included the game in a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksong-confirmed-for-both-switch-consoles">Nintendo Direct and locked in the game's presence on both the Switch 1 and Switch 2</a>.</p>
<p>There was also the cake fiasco, in which the eagle-eyed Silksong lovers went all in on a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silksong-fans-believe-creators-switch-2-hint-points-to-april-announcement-and-its-all-thanks-to-a-slice-of-cake">cake recipe as the core of a release date tease</a>, a theory Team Chery had to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hollow-knight-silksong-is-real-progressing-and-will-release-says-team-cherry">come out and put to rest</a>. With last night's news, those down bad for the smallest crumb of Silksong info may be able to rest, at last.</p>
<p>As you can imagine, the concrete confirmation last night has folks very excited. A peak at the Silksong Reddit <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/comments/1l6k3vt/thank_you_leth/">provides a window into the joys of happy gamers far and wide</a>. However the scars of hopium still ache in the hearts of some battle-hardened Silksong-minded folks. One user, Breadbowl004 wrote in response to Griffon's post: "Notice how he didn't say Holiday 2025".</p>
<p>That being said, it's still unknown when <em>exactly</em> the game will be released. Also consider this, it would be incredibly funny if the game was pushed back to 2026. Something to think on.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persona-inspired Demonschool gets release window following last year's delay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/persona-inspired-demonschool-gets-release-window-following-last-years-delay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/persona-inspired-demonschool-gets-release-window-following-last-years-delay.1213050/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/persona-inspired-demonschool-gets-release-window-following-last-years-delay<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Necrosoft Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The Persona-inspired horror game Demonschool has a new release window, following a delay last year.</p>
<p>As revealed at the PC Gaming Show, the RPG will be released this summer. It was originally intended to launch last September, but in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/persona-and-italian-horror-inspired-tactical-rpg-demonschool-gets-last-minute-delay">August was delayed to allow the studio to "manifest our bigger dreams into reality"</a>.</p>
<p>The new trailer, below, provides a gameplay summary of Demonschool and its parallel social activities and tactical battles, all with a cartoon horror aesthetic.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Demonschool release window trailer - PC Gaming Show 2025" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0pEkSsgvcJk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Demonschool release window trailer - PC Gaming Show 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0pEkSsgvcJk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0pEkSsgvcJk?autoplay=1" title="Demonschool release window trailer - PC Gaming Show 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Demonschool release window trailer - PC Gaming Show 2025<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0pEkSsgvcJk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Demonschool will be released across PS4, PS5, Xbox Series X/S, Switch, and PC (Steam, Epic), with Steam Deck support too.</p>
<p>Set in a haunted university, Demonschool includes both Persona-esque social activities and romance, with tactical battles inspired by Into the Breach. There will be 15 playable characters, each with special combat skills.</p>
<p>"Our team took great pride in fleshing out the world of Demonschool as much as possible," said Brandon Sheffield, creative director of developer Necrosoft Games. "With plenty of class and demon assignments to complete, characters to hang out with, and minigames to play, students won't run out of things to do on Jabberwock Island."</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/demonschool-is-persona-meets-buffy-and-i-love-its-90s-vibes">demo of the game was released last year</a>, which I described as "Persona meets Buffy" with its 90s vibes. "Added to the bold artwork, a dark yet funky soundtrack, and an over-the-top cartoonish aesthetic (I love the bouncy run animation), and Demonschool is yet another brilliant example of silly adults bested by a plucky gang of pesky kids."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Rogue Prince of Persia finally leaving early access]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-finally-leaving-early-access</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-finally-leaving-early-access.1213023/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-finally-leaving-early-access<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Evil Empire</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The Rogue Prince of Persia is finally leaving early access with a full 1.0 release set for August.</p>
<p>A fresh trailer for the game was shown at the PC Gaming Show over the weekend, showing plenty of its 2D roguelike gameplay, parkour abilities, and stylish combat.</p>
<p>Published by Ubisoft, The Rogue Prince of Persia is being developed by <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dead-cells">Dead Cells</a> studio Evil Empire. It released into early access last May.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PC Gaming Show Trailer - The Rogue Prince of Persia" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9c1QFum8GXY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PC Gaming Show Trailer - The Rogue Prince of Persia</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9c1QFum8GXY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9c1QFum8GXY?autoplay=1" title="PC Gaming Show Trailer - The Rogue Prince of Persia">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>PC Gaming Show Trailer - The Rogue Prince of Persia<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9c1QFum8GXY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The game <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-rogue-prince-of-persia-the-second-act-update-effectively-relaunches-the-game-makes-prince-no-longer-purple">received a huge update back in November</a>, revamping the art style and doubling the game's size.</p>
<p>The full version will finish the story, add extra biomes with a proper final boss, and include more enemies and weapons. The developer has also promised news of an exact release date as well as console releases on the way.</p>
<p>It's heavily inspired by Dead Cells too, as you'd expect from the same studio.</p>
<p>"What it definitely gets from Dead Cells is an enviable forward momentum," wrote <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/theres-a-lot-of-dead-cells-in-the-rogue-prince-of-persia">Christian Donlan for Eurogamer last year</a>. "The Prince is all leanness and athleticism, decked out like a modern Olympian but with a bright red sash that flows out behind him and highlights his swiftness, his elegance."</p>
<p>Evil Empire is a subsidiary of original Dead Cells developer Motion Twin, which was spun off to work on updates and DLC. It <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dead-cells-developer-ends-support-focusing-on-new-projects">ended support for Dead Cells last year</a> to work on a "secret project", which turned out to be The Rogue Prince of Persia.</p>
<p>Motion Twin, meanwhile, has <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/motion-twins-windblown-releases-in-early-access-even-sooner-than-you-think">its own game in early access: Windblown</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Trek Beyond co-writer joins Mass Effect TV series as a showrunner]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/star-trek-beyond-co-writer-joins-mass-effect-tv-series-as-a-showrunner</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-trek-beyond-co-writer-joins-mass-effect-tv-series-as-a-showrunner.1213002/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/star-trek-beyond-co-writer-joins-mass-effect-tv-series-as-a-showrunner<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Things are picking up on the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mass-effect">Mass Effect</a> TV series. Over the weekend, it was announced that Doug Jung - known for his work on the upcoming Chief of War and as a co-writer for Star Trek Beyond - has joined Amazon's Mass Effect TV series as a showrunner.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://deadline.com/2025/06/mass-effect-doug-jung-tv-series-showrunner-1236423704/">Deadline</a>, Jung will executive produce the upcoming show with writer Dan Casey. They will be working alongside Michael Gamble from EA, Karim Zreik of Cedar Tree Productions via its overall deal at Amazon, as well as Ari Arad (<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/borderlands-film-benefited-game-sales-despite-being-disappointing-flop-take-two-boss-says">Uncharted, Borderlands</a>) and Emmy Yu of Arad Productions.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Let's Play Mass Effect Legendary Edition PS5 Gameplay - CHECKING OUT THE FIRST HOUR OF EACH GAME!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lVU4QsuxGWU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Let's Play Mass Effect Legendary Edition PS5 Gameplay - CHECKING OUT THE FIRST HOUR OF EACH GAME!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lVU4QsuxGWU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/lVU4QsuxGWU?autoplay=1" title="Let's Play Mass Effect Legendary Edition PS5 Gameplay - CHECKING OUT THE FIRST HOUR OF EACH GAME!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Let's Play Mass Effect Legendary Edition PS5 Gameplay - CHECKING OUT THE FIRST HOUR OF EACH GAME! <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lVU4QsuxGWU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Casey has been writing the Mass Effect TV show for "almost a year", the publication noted. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effect-is-officially-getting-a-tv-adaptation-at-amazon">Amazon officially announced a Mass Effect TV show</a> was in development in November last year, when Casey's involvement was initially confirmed.</p>
<p>While we don't know any casting details at the present time, fem Shep actress <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effects-original-cast-should-return-for-the-tv-series-shepard-voice-actor-jennifer-hale-says">Jennifer Hale previously told Eurogamer she would love to be part of the Mass Effect series</a>, and believes the original cast should be involved as well. Meanwhile, once upon a time <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/henry-cavill-would-love-to-discuss-being-in-the-mass-effect-tv-series">Henry Cavill said he would "love" to be a part of a Mass Effect TV adaptation</a>, however <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/liam-hemsworth-was-almost-cast-as-the-witchers-geralt-in-2018">following his time in The Witcher</a> the actor has now been <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/henry-cavill-reportedly-set-to-star-in-a-warhammer-40k-series-at-amazon">snapped up for Amazon's Warhammer shenanigans</a>.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>BioWare</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for the world of video games themselves, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/new-mass-effect-teaser-shows-series-will-return-to-milky-way">Mass Effect 5 has been announced</a>, but lacks a release date and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effect-5-isnt-ready-to-suddenly-have-a-team-of-250-300-people-working-on-it-now-dragon-age-the-veilguard-is-done">appears to still be several years away</a>.</p>
<p>In October, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effect-5-wont-dabble-with-stylised-visuals-like-dragon-age-the-veilguard-director-says">project director Michael Gamble said Mass Effect 5 will not seek to tweak the sci-fi franchise's established visual style</a>. This is something developer BioWare did with its recent release, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-walkthrough-tips-and-tricks-guide">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>