<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 15:20:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft's "Vibrant Visuals" update finally has a release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/minecrafts-vibrant-visuals-update-finally-has-a-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecrafts-vibrant-visuals-update-finally-has-a-release-date.1218903/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/minecrafts-vibrant-visuals-update-finally-has-a-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Minecraft's Vibrant Visuals update finally has a release date: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zPWdMDZWM4Y">17th June</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/minecraft-wont-go-free-to-play-because-it-simply-wasnt-built-that-way">We've known for some time</a> that Mojang was planning on a visual overhaul for Minecraft, and yesterday (14th June), the studio released a new video not only reminding us just what Vibrant Visuals brings to the game, improving "visual elements such as directional lighting, volumetric fog, and more", but also how the team achieved it.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="MINECRAFT’S VISUAL REFRESH!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NTOLOErWN4w?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>MINECRAFT’S VISUAL REFRESH!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NTOLOErWN4w?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NTOLOErWN4w?autoplay=1" title="MINECRAFT’S VISUAL REFRESH!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>MINECRAFT’S VISUAL REFRESH!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NTOLOErWN4w" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>And the new feature really does elevate the world of Minecraft. As the developer explains, "every biome has their own atmosphere", so warmer biomes will look more orange and yellowish, while cooler ones will take on a crisper blue appearance.</p>
<p>"This is a visual enhancement - there are no changes to Minecraft's gameplay," Mojang said. "For example, visual shadows will not impact light levels in a game-mechanics sense, or affect where hostile mobs spawn. Vibrant Visuals will be easy to access and approachable for many more Minecraft players, as it will be available on many platforms as a simple menu toggle."</p>
<p>"This is a start on this journey of modernising the look and feel of Minecraft," explained Vibrant Visuals Lead, Dejan Dimic. "So we look forward to hearing more feedback from the players."</p>
<p>Vibrant Visuals is coming to supported devices for those running Minecraft Bedrock Edition, and if your device can run it, you can expect the new feature to be on by default once it updates. It still isn't yet available for Java, but Mojang insists it's "actively working" on it.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Mojang</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Did you catch the news that the roster of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hatsune-miku-personas-joker-and-minecrafts-steve-join-the-roster-for-sonic-crossworlds">Sonic Racing CrossWorlds is expanding outside of the Sonic universe to include other Sega characters and beyond</a>? As announced at last week's Summer Game Fest, joining the likes of Sonic, Tails and Knuckles, will be Joker from <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/persona-5">Persona 5</a>, Ichiban from the Like A Dragon games, Vocaloid artist Hatsune Miku, and - the reason why I'm making this seemingly nonsensical tangent - Steve from Minecraft, too.</p>
<p>It is, of course, a flagship year for Minecraft, thanks to the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/minecraft-movie-jockeys-past-550m-at-the-box-office">unbridled popularity</a> of its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-minecraft-movie-now-shows-warning-following-disruptive-chicken-jockey-trend">cinema-trashing</a> <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-minecraft-movie-review">live-action movie adaptation</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red Dead Redemption star teases he "cannot wait" for us to know about a big announcement that's coming "before Friday"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/red-dead-redemption-star-teases-he-cannot-wait-for-us-to-know-about-a-big-announcement-thats-coming-before-friday</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/red-dead-redemption-star-teases-he-cannot-wait-for-us-to-know-about-a-big-announcement-thats-coming-before-friday.1218879/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/red-dead-redemption-star-teases-he-cannot-wait-for-us-to-know-about-a-big-announcement-thats-coming-before-friday<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"I am so excited, but I truly cannot think about anything else."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rockstar Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Another day, another Red Dead rumour, but this one comes from John Marston himself - or, at least, the actor who brings him to life, Rob Wiethoff.</p>
<p>In his latest Red Dead Redemption livestream, as spotted by F4D3broboi on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/reddeadredemption/comments/1lbextu/i_wonder_what_this_could_mean/">Reddit</a>, Wiethoff was very excited indeed about an upcoming announcement. And while he was coy about the details, he did stress that he was particularly excited playing "<em>this</em> game" - the original Red Dead Redemption - and even suggested we'll know by this time next week.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="9 Things You Can Do When You Aren't Being a Cowboy in Red Dead Redemption 2" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bEDRJu_18mI?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>9 Things You Can Do When You Aren't Being a Cowboy in Red Dead Redemption 2</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bEDRJu_18mI?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bEDRJu_18mI?autoplay=1" title="9 Things You Can Do When You Aren't Being a Cowboy in Red Dead Redemption 2">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's a blast from the past with one of our Red Dead Redemption 2 videos!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bEDRJu_18mI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"I've got such exciting news," he teased. "I can't share it with you right now, and it's absolutely <em>killing</em> me. By the end of this week, hopefully sooner, you're going to - not this week, I guess; probably not as soon as tomorrow, but definitely before Friday… Oh my goodness, the news that I have to share, and I won't be the only one sharing it.</p>
<p>"I cannot wait for you to know what's going on," he added. "And that's all I can say. And I'm not trying to be… I'm just telling, that's the only thing I can think about right now. And you will know soon enough. I can't wait for you to know, I am <em>so</em> excited, but I truly cannot think about anything else, especially playing <em>this</em> game, I can't think of anything else. Oh, then what I want to tell you <em>so</em> bad."</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="546"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/reddeadredemption/comments/1lbextu/i_wonder_what_this_could_mean/">i wonder what this could mean?</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/F4D3broboi/">u/F4D3broboi</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/reddeadredemption/">reddeadredemption</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p>
<p>This latest tease comes just days after we heard another rumour that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/red-dead-redemption-2-next-gen-update-switch-2-port-reports-suggest">Red Dead Redemption 2 may be getting a next-gen update alongside a Nintendo Switch 2 port</a>. YouTuber Nate the Hate stated the cowboy classic will receive the update and a port to Nintendo's latest console release later this year.</p>
<p>The original Red Dead Redemption released way back in May 2010. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/red-dead-redemption-review?page=3">We awarded it 8/10</a>, calling it "an exceptional Rockstar game, one that successfully re-clothes the Grand Theft Auto framework in an exciting, distinct and expertly realised scenario".
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nier: Automata creators deny characters "were problematic overseas" and blame mistranslated subtitle for censorship rumours]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nier-automata-creators-deny-characters-were-problematic-overseas-and-blame-mistranslated-subtitle-for-censorship-rumours</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nier-automata-creators-deny-characters-were-problematic-overseas-and-blame-mistranslated-subtitle-for-censorship-rumours.1218594/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nier-automata-creators-deny-characters-were-problematic-overseas-and-blame-mistranslated-subtitle-for-censorship-rumours<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Square Enix</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Nier: Automata producer Yosuke Saito and director <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/yoko-taro">Yoko Taro</a> have denied that any of their character designs were restricted for Western audiences.</p>
<p>As spotted by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/nier-automata-creators-deny-rumors-of-square-enix-imposing-character-design-restrictions-on-them-its-a-huge-mistranslation/">Automaton</a>, the developers were compelled to comment after a mistranslated Japanese-to-English subtitle intimated Nier: Automata had been subjected to censorship from <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> to meet global standards.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="GODDESS OF VICTORY: NIKKE | Producers' Creative Dialogue Special Livestream" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EezDZURfSfk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>GODDESS OF VICTORY: NIKKE | Producers' Creative Dialogue Special Livestream</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EezDZURfSfk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EezDZURfSfk?autoplay=1" title="GODDESS OF VICTORY: NIKKE | Producers' Creative Dialogue Special Livestream">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>GODDESS OF VICTORY: NIKKE | Producers' Creative Dialogue Special Livestream.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EezDZURfSfk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In the interview above (skip to 28:12 for the segment concerned), Sony executive Yoshida Shuhei asked the developers about their design process.</p>
<p>"Our concept is always to do something that's 'not like anything else'. What I mean is, if Nier: Replicant had a boy as the main character, Nier: Automata would have a girl protagonist. If Western sci-fi is filled with Marine-like soldiers, we might go in the opposite direction and use Gothic Lolita outfits, for example," Taro said. "We tend to take the contrarian route."</p>
<p>"There are, of course, certain things that are ethically or morally inappropriate – even if they're just aspects of a character," Saito added, according to the subtitles. "We try to draw a line by establishing rules about what’s acceptable and what’s not.</p>
<p>"While certain things might be acceptable in Japan, they could become problematic in certain overseas regions, and even characters could become problematic as well. These are the kind of situation[s] we usually try to avoid creating. As a result, there are actually countries where we couldn't officially release Nier: Automata."</p>
<p>This immediately caused consternation with fans but as Automaton points out, this "could be a little tricky to translate, even for an advanced Japanese speaker".</p>
<p>When asked directly about the claim, Taro denied it, <a href="https://x.com/yokotaro/status/1933044002095575201">saying on X/Twitter:</a> "I've never heard of such a thing happening". Saito simply said he thought the things he'd mentioned had been mistranslated, and would clarify this in a future livestream.</p>
<p>In the same interview, former PlayStation exec Shuhei Yoshida called <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nier-automata-revived-the-japanese-games-industry-says-former-sony-exec-shuhei-yoshida">Nier: Automata the "game that changed everything", as it was responsible for reviving the Japanese games industry</a> on its release. In a recent interview, Yoshida discussed how during the PS3 era, sales of Japanese games had declined, and increasingly studios there were chasing "overseas tastes".</p>
<p>That changed with NieR: Automata in 2017, released for the PS4. "I think Yoko Taro created it without paying any mind at all to making it sell overseas, but it was a tremendous success," Yoshida said.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout Shelter has been downloaded over 230 million times in 10 years]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-shelter-has-been-downloaded-over-230-million-times-in-10-years</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-shelter-has-been-downloaded-over-230-million-times-in-10-years.1218570/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-shelter-has-been-downloaded-over-230-million-times-in-10-years<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bethesda Softworks</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>On the tenth anniversary of the release of free-to-play <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout-shelter">Fallout Shelter</a>, Bethesda has revealed the management sim game has been downloaded 230 million times across all platforms.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, Bethesda reckons it's time to "celebrate a decade of adventure, excitement, and Vault-building fun with Fallout Shelter" by launching a new in-game event that offers "party favours" for everyone who logs in from 16th–21st June, including bonus lunchboxes, Nuka, and more.</p>
<p>"Tons of content has been added to the game since 2015. You've built Vaults, made lives (or chaos) for your dwellers, and embarked on thrilling quests, all while keeping the spirit of the wasteland alive and well," the developer <a href="https://bethesda.net/en/article/6zT9anWe9yLVqi1F6gGPms/fallout-shelter-10th-anniversary">said</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fallout Season 2 Teaser" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tu5EN8V35JM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fallout Season 2 Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tu5EN8V35JM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tu5EN8V35JM?autoplay=1" title="Fallout Season 2 Teaser">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Fallout Season 2 Teaser.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tu5EN8V35JM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Whether you've been with us all along or you're new to the party, now is a great time to head into the wasteland and start building. To celebrate this huge milestone, we’re offering up to 70 percent off lunchboxes in the in-game store from now through 17th June.</p>
<p>"So, dust off your Pip-Boy, tune in to the celebration, and keep those Vaults thriving. Here's to another 10 years of Fallout Shelter!"</p>
<p>As for those aforementioned party favours?</p>
<ul>
<li>16-17th June: Lunchbox x2, Pet Carrier x1, Nuka x10</li>
<li>18-19th June: Lunchbox x3, Mr. Handy x1, Nuka x15</li>
<li>20-21st June: Lunchbox x5, Pet Carrier x1, Nuka x20</li>
</ul>
<p>ICYMI, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/amazon-renews-fallout-for-third-season-six-months-before-second-arrives">Fallout TV series has already been renewed for a third season on Amazon Prime</a>. That's despite the show's second season still being months away, debuting in December 2025.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony quietly removes PC sale restrictions in dozens of countries for four huge PlayStation games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-quietly-removes-pc-sale-restrictions-in-dozens-of-countries-for-four-huge-playstation-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-quietly-removes-pc-sale-restrictions-in-dozens-of-countries-for-four-huge-playstation-games.1218540/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-quietly-removes-pc-sale-restrictions-in-dozens-of-countries-for-four-huge-playstation-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Games returned to sale include God of War Ragnarök, The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered, Marvel's Spider-Man 2, and yes... Helldivers 2.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>PlayStation</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sony has seemingly loosened regional restrictions on a number of its PC games, including <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/god-of-war-ragnarok">God of War Ragnarök</a>, The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/spider-man-2-walkthrough-9356">Marvel's Spider-Man 2</a>, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a>.</p>
<p>As spotted by Wario64, the changelogs for all aforementioned games listed on SteamDB show that a number of sale restrictions were quietly lifted yesterday, 13th June.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered's Roguelike No Return Mode Explained: TLOU2 No Return Gameplay PS5" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n3XuB8ZBHX4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered's Roguelike No Return Mode Explained: TLOU2 No Return Gameplay PS5</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n3XuB8ZBHX4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/n3XuB8ZBHX4?autoplay=1" title="The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered's Roguelike No Return Mode Explained: TLOU2 No Return Gameplay PS5">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n3XuB8ZBHX4">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered's Roguelike No Return Mode Explained: TLOU2 No Return Gameplay PS5</a>.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n3XuB8ZBHX4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Although Sony made no public comment concerning the furore about sales restrictions invoked in countries where PSN isn't available or shared any plans to address it, check SteamDB and you'll see that the games <a href="https://steamdb.info/sub/833972/history/?changeid=29554938">have indeed trimmed down the number of countries where they're unavailable</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/sony-removes-regional-restrictions-on-four-of-its-biggest-games-on-steam/">PC Gamer</a>). Just one region was added to the restricted sale list: Russian Federation.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreia24z2us5mamqq7fuzivp5cmyswoghpufymdjvsktqboo7fvh62nq" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637/app.bsky.feed.post/3lrj3gsdkr22v"><div lang="en"><p>Sony appears to be removing regional restrictions on their Steam/PC games

God of War Ragnarok steamdb.info/sub/833972/h...

The Last of Us Part II Remastered steamdb.info/sub/1219787/...

Spider-Man 2 steamdb.info/sub/1219797/...

Helldivers 2 steamdb.info/sub/137730/h...</p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637/post/3lrj3gsdkr22v?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p></div>— Wario64 (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637?ref_src=embed">@wario64.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637/post/3lrj3gsdkr22v?ref_src=embed">June 13, 2025 at 7:38 PM</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>This all started, of course, when Helldivers 2 was review-bombed last year following a PSN requirement which led to the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-has-been-pulled-from-sale-in-177-countries-as-its-psn-linking-requirement-rolls-out">game being pulled from sale in 177 countries</a>. The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-overturns-helldivers-2-psn-requirement-following-backlash">company quickly u-turned its decision</a> following the backlash but not before several Sony-published games were caught up in the controversy. Most recently <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blade-pc-release-blocked-on-steam-in-over-120-countries-surprising-even-its-developer">Stellar Blade found itself at the centre of the backlash</a> even though developer Shift Up had stated a PSN account was only optional and not a formal requirement.</p>
<p>On the subject of Sony, president Hideaki Nishino recently stated the company is open to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-will-continue-to-add-more-value-to-ps-plus-says-company-president-but-it-may-come-with-price-changes-too">adjusting the price of PlayStation Plus in the future, as the company aims to "maximise profitability</a>".</p>
<p>The comments came as part of a discussion between Sony CEO Hermen Hulst and president Hideaki Nishino on PS Plus and the company's future. Discussing Sony's subscription service, Nishino stated: "We will continue to add more value and adjust our pricing strategy in a dynamic way to maximise profitability."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>