<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 17:20:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infinity Nikki hacked with abusive message to players shortly after launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/infinity-nikki-hacked-with-abusive-message-to-players-shortly-after-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/infinity-nikki-hacked-with-abusive-message-to-players-shortly-after-launch.1052697/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/infinity-nikki-hacked-with-abusive-message-to-players-shortly-after-launch<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/infinity-nikki">Infinity Nikki</a> - the cute and colourful dress up game with gacha elements - released earlier today, but was quickly hacked, with reports of players being met with a distressing and distasteful message.</p>
<p>Please note, there may be some upsetting content below. <strong>Please read on at your own discretion.</strong></p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Infinity Nikki Review. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2WmtKWOJzeo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As shared on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gachagaming/comments/1h73ssp/infinity_nikki_site_got_hacked/">reddit</a> and social media platform X, the Infinity Nikki website briefly displayed an abusive message earlier this morning, which was being used to promote fellow gacha game <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/genshin-impact">Genshin Impact</a> (there is no evidence this message was posted by a member of the Genshin Impact community). </p><p>A QR was also displayed under the message, but for obvious reasons, Eurogamer has not tested to see where it leads. However, it appears the hacked page was for the official celebration event, which asks players to use a QR code to open a page on their phone.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/IMG_20241205_152825.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A reddit moderator suggested the Infinity Nikki website was "compromised for roughly 30-40 minutes", but advises players proceed with caution until developer Infold makes an announcement regarding the site's status.</p>
<p>In the meantime, it appears that the Infinity Nikki servers are down for some. Our Zoe was looking to stream the game this afternoon, however she has been met with a maintenance notice.</p>
<p>"The server is not open yet," the message on Zoe's screen reads, stating maintenance will conclude in 2029 (which we hope is an error). Additionally, Infinity Nikki's announcement page isn't working for Zoe.</p>
<p>It is unclear if these server issues are related to this morning's hack. Eurogamer has reached out to the Infinity Nikki team for comment.</p>
<p>We recently awarded Infinity Nikki four out of five stars, with our Jessica saying it has the potential to give Genshin Impact a run for its money.</p>
<p>"It sure is nice see miHoYo have some proper competition for once, and I know I'll still be returning to Miraland whenever I'm in need of a mood boost, whether that be in the form of humming along to catchy tunes while Whimcycling my way towards hot air balloons, or laughing at the melodrama in future story updates," she wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/infinity-nikki-review">Eurogamer's Infinity Nikki review</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foamstars season pass ends with ironically titled Party Goes On]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/foamstars-season-pass-ends-with-ironically-titled-party-goes-on</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/foamstars-season-pass-ends-with-ironically-titled-party-goes-on.1052622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/foamstars-season-pass-ends-with-ironically-titled-party-goes-on<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/image-(267).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Square Enix</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> is pulling the metaphorical season plug on its soapy shooter Foamstars next month, less than a year after its release.</p>
<p>In a blog post, the company announced its next season - known somewhat ironically as Party Goes On - will be its last, though it will remain online and isn't shutting down completely.</p>
<p>Foamstars' Party Goes On season will kick off on 13th December, and run until 17th January. After that, season updates for Foamstars will come to an end, and no new content will be added to the game.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="FOAMSTARS | “PARTY GOES ON” Season Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_JvM01exsU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>FOAMSTARS | “PARTY GOES ON” Season Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_JvM01exsU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/7_JvM01exsU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>FOAMSTARS | PARTY GOES ON Season Trailer. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7_JvM01exsU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"In this concluding update, expansions will be introduced to enhance gameplay, such as the ability to customise shots of each character, and new enhancement elements, such as Prism Gems, all aimed at ensuring players can continue to enjoy the game for the foreseeable future," Square Enix wrote.</p><p>Foamstars' previous season passes will be made available once again, for those players who may have missed them previously. Square Enix noted there will be the option for players to switch between passes and choose the season pass track of their choice. "This will make it possible for players to obtain all the items from each season," it explained.</p>
<p>Those who want to go for the Premium Pass will need to pay, as before. The basic pass is free.</p>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>In a letter from producer <a href="https://www.square-enix-games.com/en_GB/news/foamstars-letter-producer-5-dec-2024">Kosuke Okatani</a>, the developer thanked those who have played and will continue to play Foamstars.</p>
<p>"I don't want this to sound like a final message since you will be able to continue playing the game. However I wanted to take this opportunity to express my gratitude to you all once again, so I've taken up my pen to write this producer's letter," Okatani wrote.</p>
<p>"Since the game's release on February 6, 2024, the development team has been working tirelessly to add new content and features, striving to bring the game as close as possible to that goal.</p>
<p>"Throughout both the development and operational phases, we have faced many challenges. However, the support of all of you who play the game, along with the incredible fan art, has been a constant source of encouragement for the team. It's because of this support that we've been able to overcome these difficulties, always with the goal of responding to your feedback.</p>
<p>"If Foamstars has become a game that you can enjoy with others, then we couldn't be happier."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/FOAMSTARS_Launch_Soa_png_jpgcopy-0he98yvgw.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Square Enix</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Foamstars initially started life as a paid for release, before <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/splatoon-a-like-foamstars-is-going-free-to-play-in-october-eight-months-after-release">becoming free-to-play a few short months ago</a>.</p>
<p>Eurogamer contributor Kaan Serin called Foamstars a "serviceable paintballer... lathered with some wild lore and underwhelming hero shooter elements" in his <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/foamstars-review">review</a>, asking: "What does it say about this shooter if the... character details are more entertaining than the 10-minute shooting galleries that precede them?"</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>