<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 04:10:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embracer Group's Eidos-Montréal studio lays off "up to 75" employees]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/embracer-groups-eidos-montreal-studio-lays-off-up-to-75-employees</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/embracer-groups-eidos-montr%C3%A9al-studio-lays-off-up-to-75-employees.1150443/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/embracer-groups-eidos-montreal-studio-lays-off-up-to-75-employees<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"We don't have the capacity to entirely reallocate them."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/eidos-montreal-logo-guardians.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer/Embracer Group</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Eidos-Montréal, the Embracer-owned studio currently providing support on Microsoft's Fable reboot, is laying off "up to" 75 members of staff, saying it doesn't "have the capacity to entirely reallocate them to our other ongoing projects and services."
</p>
<p>
News of the layoffs - which follows 97 job cuts at Eidos-Montréal last year - was confirmed in a <a href="https://x.com/EidosMontreal/status/1906728993061020142">statement shared on social media</a>. "Today, we informed our studio staff that we are going to let go up to 75 valuable members," the studio wrote, "as one of our mandates is coming to an end. It is not a reflection of their dedication or skills, but unfortunately, we don't have the capacity to entirely reallocate them to our other ongoing projects and services.
</p>
<p>
"These very talented, highly experienced experts are going to enter the employment market," the statement continued, "and we are working to support them through this transition. Eidos-Montréal stays committed to deliver its other projects currently in development."
</p>
<p>
Eidos-Montréal's most recent game, Marvel's Guardians of the Galaxy, released in 2021 when the studio was still owned by publisher <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>. Following its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-sells-off-western-studios-and-ip-including-tomb-raider-and-deus-ex">purchase by Embracer Group in 2022</a>, however, it was reportedly set to work creating a new game in the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/deus-ex">Deus Ex</a> series - a project that was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/embracer-cancels-deus-ex-game-in-development-for-two-years">canned last year amid a devastating programme of "restructuring" and cost cutting at Embracer Group</a> that resulted in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-the-human-cost-of-embracers-restructuring-programme">over 4500 job losses across the company</a>.
</p>
<p>
Since then, it's been confirmed Eidos-Montréal is assisting Microsoft's Playground Games as the Xbox studio attempts to get its long-awaited - and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xboxs-fable-reboot-delayed-into-next-year">recently delayed</a> - Fable reboot over the finish line. Today's statement suggests Fable isn't Eidos-Montréal's only project, but it's unclear what else the studio may be working on at present.
</p>
<p>
Layoffs have continued to blight the games industry in 2025 following an already devastating few years which have seen over 25,000 employees lose their jobs since the start of 2023. So far this year, <a href="https://publish.obsidian.md/vg-layoffs/Archive/2025">1200 layoffs have been recorded</a>, affecting workers across the likes of Unity, PlayStation, Ubisoft, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/warner-bros-games">Warner Bros. Games</a>, Sumo Digital, Splash Damage, Bossa Studios, Night School, and Cyan, Inc. Results of a GDC State of the Games Industry survey shared earlier this year <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gdcs-state-of-the-games-industry-survey-says-one-in-ten-respondents-laid-off-in-2024">revealed one in 10 of the 3000 developers canvassed were laid off in 2024</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox's 2025 gaming handheld teased in new trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/xboxs-2025-gaming-handheld-teased-in-new-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xboxs-2025-gaming-handheld-teased-in-new-trailer.1150404/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/xboxs-2025-gaming-handheld-teased-in-new-trailer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Phil it coming in the air tonight.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/asus-rog-ally-xbox-handheld-teaser.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>ASUS</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Following recent claims Microsoft's much-rumoured handheld Xbox will arrive later this year in collaboration with an unspecified "PC gaming OEM", hardware manufacturer ASUS has shared a teaser trailer suggesting the machine is real and set to be revealed soon.
</p>
<p>
Word that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-next-gen-console-reportedly-targeting-2027-with-handheld-device-due-this-year">Microsoft was partnering with a third-party company to release an Xbox-branded handheld this year</a> first surfaced via Windows Central, which reported the device was being developed under the codename Keenan and would look "unmistakably 'Xbox'", sporting familiar design sensibilities and even an Xbox guide button.
</p>
<p>
Skip ahead a couple of weeks and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VXzXhezpSF4">ASUS has now shared a teaser</a> for what appears to be its next-generation ASUS ROG Ally gaming handheld - a video that doesn't perhaps <em>immediately</em> scream Xbox with its magenta hues and weird dabbing robot. However, at one point during its brisk runtime, a ROG Ally and Xbox-style controller are seen hurtling through the air before disappearing into a machine where some sort of fusing process unfolds.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Run Omni_Upgrades.exe" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VXzXhezpSF4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Run Omni_Upgrades.exe</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VXzXhezpSF4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VXzXhezpSF4?autoplay=1" title="Run Omni_Upgrades.exe">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>ASUS' Run Omni_Upgrades.exe teaser trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VXzXhezpSF4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
The inference is clear enough, but Microsoft's involvement in the project was seemingly all but confirmed when Xbox's official social media account <a href="https://x.com/Xbox/status/1906769447341510708">replied to ASUS' teaser post</a> with the side-eye monkey meme. Obviously, all this stays in the 'speculation' bucket until either party is ready to go beyond memes and teases, but the pieces are undoubtedly starting to fall into place.
</p>
<p>
According to Windows Central's previous report, this year's Xbox-branded handheld will be something of a stop gap while <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/phil-spencer-says-no-red-lines-over-any-xbox-game-coming-to-nintendo-or-playstation">Microsoft continues developing its own Xbox gaming handheld</a> internally. The company's said to be targeting a 2027 launch for this other machine, which will reportedly arrive alongside an Xbox Series X/S successor and "several new controller options".
</p>
<p>
However things pan out, it's a pretty exciting time in the world of handheld gaming - not least because <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-reportedly-prepping-playstation-5-portable-plans-to-battle-nintendos-handheld-dominance">Sony is reportedly also working on its own handheld device</a> in the form of portable PS5, while <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-everything-we-know">Nintendo's hugely anticipated Switch 2 is just days away from its big reveal</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds performance-related PC improvements coming this week, says Capcom]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-performance-related-pc-improvements-coming-this-week-says-capcom</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-performance-related-pc-improvements-coming-this-week-says-capcom.1150314/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-performance-related-pc-improvements-coming-this-week-says-capcom<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>As future plans detailed.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/mhw-ss-06.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer/Capcom</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> has been an massive success for publisher Capcom, but not everybody's happy on PC, where the game has been repeatedly lambasted for its poor performance. Finally, however, a month after its release, Capcom has revealed a first round of performance-related PC improvements is coming later this week.
</p>
<p>
Capcom shared the news in a <a href="https://www.monsterhunter.com/wilds/en-uk/topics/director-letter/">lengthy post from Monster Hunter Wilds game director Yuya Tokuda</a> over on the official Monster Hunter website. After thanking players for their support amid <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-rises-beyond-another-impressive-milestone-in-first-month">Wilds' impressive 10m sales milestone</a>, Tokuda began detailing some of the improvements the developer is targeting in response to player feedback.
</p>
<p>
The big one, for PC players at least, is the promise of improved game stability. "The team is continuing to identify stability issues and make improvements where possible," Tokuda wrote, "especially on the Steam version. This will be an ongoing process, where we'll aim to make continual steps forward in this area and respond to critical issues."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Monster Hunter Wilds PC - Profound Perf Problems Must Be Addressed" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0yhacyXcizA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Monster Hunter Wilds PC - Profound Perf Problems Must Be Addressed</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0yhacyXcizA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0yhacyXcizA?autoplay=1" title="Monster Hunter Wilds PC - Profound Perf Problems Must Be Addressed">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's Alex with the full lowdown on Monster Hunter Wilds' PC release.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0yhacyXcizA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
The good news is Capcom's first round of performance-related PC improvements is set to arrive very soon - as part of Monster Hunter Wilds' Title Update 1 this Thursday, 3rd April. This'll include a promised reduction in VRAM usage, as well as an upgrade to the DirectStorage version on Steam - both of which "should result in an overall improvement in stability for our PC players", according to Capcom.
</p>
<p>
Notably, VRAM usage and DirectStorage issues were both highlighted in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-monster-hunter-wilds-pc-weve-got-issues">Digital Foundry's review of Monster Hunter Wilds on PC</a>, in which Alex Battaglia detailed the games "profound performance problems" and "substantial" technical issues. At the time, Alex advised "caution" for higher-end GPU owners, but flat-out recommended anyone with lower-end graphics cards "avoid" Wilds until Capcom could improve the situation - so hopefully this week's update will bring meaningful changes ahead of promised "continued improvements" in future patches.
</p>
<p>
Away from PC performance, Tokuda highlighted some other areas the team is targeting. There's talk of weapon balance adjustments, for instance, which are set to be implemented "gradually" with each new title update. As for quality of life changes, Capcom says it's currently looking to make it easier for players to access information they require through UI/UX improvements, alongside "additional adjustments... to further enhance the overall feel of the game to curate an even smoother gameplay experience."
</p>
<p>
Capcom says to expect changes making it easier to restock items, check skill information, participate in multiplayer quests, and use the Seikret. Additionally, improved camera behaviour during hunts is also on the developer's to-do list. More generally, the team is planning to "take a wider look at overall gameplay flow, which encompasses a range of things, such as the in-game economy, balance and other areas." This, it says, will "require more time for preparation".
</p>
<p>
Alongside the aforementioned PC performance improvements, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-first-major-content-update-detailed-ahead-of-next-weeks-release">this week's Monster Hunter Wilds title update</a> introduces a new social hub and a range of new monsters, including bubble dragon Mizutsune, a High Rank version of Zoh Shia, and the arch-tempered Rey Dau. Notably, Tokuda's blog stresses additional tough monsters are on the way, following criticism of Wilds' low difficulty at launch. May's update, for instance - which previously appeared to be relatively small in scope - will bring tempered variants of Gore Magala, Rey Dau, Uth Duna, Nu Udra, and Jin Dahaad. Additionally, more "challenging monsters will also appear in future updates".
</p>
<p>
"We will continue to add new elements and content to make Monster Hunter Wilds even more enjoyable for all hunters through our free content updates," Tokuda concluded, "while at the same time making further improvements and adjustments to the game."
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>