<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 13:54:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision "AI slop" Guitar Hero advert is market research for a fake game that doesn't exist and maybe never will]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/activision-ai-slop-guitar-hero-advert-is-market-research-for-a-fake-game-that-doesnt-exist-and-maybe-never-will</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-ai-slop-guitar-hero-advert-is-market-research-for-a-fake-game-that-doesnt-exist-and-maybe-never-will.1124631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/activision-ai-slop-guitar-hero-advert-is-market-research-for-a-fake-game-that-doesnt-exist-and-maybe-never-will<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Call of Duty and Crash Bandicoot titles also touted.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_4fb725a530ea35d130a9db5eabf81b215869378b.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Activision</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Activision's social media post advertising a new entry in the Guitar Hero series is market research for a game that doesn't exist, and is not meant to be an actual announcement, Eurogamer understands.
</p>
<p>
The fake advert - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/activision-accused-of-ai-slop-yet-again-this-time-for-new-guitar-hero">which has been dubbed "AI slop" for its use of poorly-generated imagery</a> - is one of several tests currently being run across the publisher's social media profiles. 
</p>
<p>
These adverts also include new smartphone games in other Activision franchises such as Call of Duty and Crash Bandicoot that also don't exist (yet) either. 
</p>
<p>
Clicking on some of the adverts will take you through to a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GuitarHero/comments/1j0jbh3/instagram_ad_for_a_new_guitar_hero_mobile_game/">mocked up mobile store page</a> organised by marketing service Geeklab, and then onto a survey that reveals "this isn't a real game, but could be some day!"
</p>
<p>
Market research questions then include queries asking users what made them click on the advert and what gameplay features they expected the game to include, based on the fake advert.
</p>
<p>
Activision posts on Instagram and Facebook have similarly advertised "Call of Duty: Zombie Defender", "Call of Duty: Sniper" and "Crash Bandicoot: Brawl".
</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Activision plans to develop two new Call of Duty titles for mobile platform:</p><p>🔸 Call of Duty: Zombie Defender<br>🔸 Call of Duty: Sniper</p><p>AI-generated advertisements are being used to gauge player interests. If there is enough interest, the project will go into development. These… <a href="https://t.co/PWA1KjLd4h">pic.twitter.com/PWA1KjLd4h</a></p></div>— Leakers On Duty (@LeakersOnDuty) <a href="https://twitter.com/LeakersOnDuty/status/1896536223478403382?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 3, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
Artwork for the latter game, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Activision/videos/569180362817791/">hosted on Facebook</a>, again shows obvious use of AI image generation. One squirrel-like character appears to be missing half a face.
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2025-03-04-125736.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Activision</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Will any of these Guitar Hero, Crash Bandicoot or Call of Duty smartphone games ever see the light of day? That remains to be seen. If and when they do, however, here's hoping Activision hires some actual humans to work on their artwork.
</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/activision-admits-call-of-duty-includes-generative-ai">Activision recently added a warning label to the Steam page for Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> confirming the game "uses generative AI tools to help develop some in-game assets", after players spotted various in-game examples - including a zombie Santa Claus with six fingers.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's how realistic The Sims-like Inzoi handles WooHoo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/want-to-know-what-inzois-woohoo-equivalent-will-be-like</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-how-realistic-the-sims-like-inzoi-handles-woohoo.1124592/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/want-to-know-what-inzois-woohoo-equivalent-will-be-like<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/monster-hunter-wilds-alle-monster-gp_6292889_N7tPqJd.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Krafton / Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Inzoi - the upcoming and rather realistic looking Sims-like - is set to launch in early access later this month, and ahead of that people want to know one very important thing: what's the sex situation?</p>
<p>Sex is, of course, a pretty common feature in Maxis and EA's The Sims series, where it is known as WooHoo. And Inzoi players want to have a deeper understanding of what will be the WooHoo equivalent in Krafton's own life-sim.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="8 Wholesome 2025 Cosy Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cnh2QCkzw90?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>8 Wholesome 2025 Cosy Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cnh2QCkzw90?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cnh2QCkzw90?autoplay=1" title="8 Wholesome 2025 Cosy Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>8 Wholesome 2025 Cosy Games. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cnh2QCkzw90" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The Inzoi team recently hosted a Q&amp;A session <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1162040845181124618/1162040845181124621/1345026317103534131">via the game's Discord</a>, where it was asked: "In Inzoi will you be able to have interactions for the purpose of creating babies?" (thanks, <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/life-sim/theres-sort-of-sex-in-inzoi-its-developers-explain-as-terminally-horny-life-sim-players-ask-about-getting-freaky-and-watching-their-zois-shower/">PC Gamer</a>). So, essentially, let's talk about sex, baby, but without actually using that word.</p>
<p>Here's what assistant director Joel Lee had to say about sex in Izoi: "There is a feature in the game that you obviously know what's happening, the male Zoi and the female Zoi are together, likely in bed, with the intention of creating babies. How visually apparent is that? That's where you have to go to your imagination. </p>
<p>"What you're seeing is not what you're seeing; you have to assume that's what's happening. Is that clear enough for everyone? It's there. Sort of. Maybe not to the level that everyone would have been expecting."
</p>
<p>Reading this, I assume this means Inzoi won't feature the same over-the-top interactions such as shaking bushes, love hearts popping out of rocket ships and a bombastic firework finale like we see in <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-sims-4">The Sims 4</a>. That is perhaps understandable, given Inzoi is going for a more realistic tone (even if the characters do wear towels in the shower).</p>
<p>I am still not sure exactly what sex in Inzoi will look like, though. Also, given the game will feature same-sex relationships, I presume sex won't only be limited to - in Lee's words - the intention of creating babies.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gorgeous-sims-like-inzoi-delayed-into-next-year-to-give-it-a-stronger-foundation">Izoi is set to release in early access on 28th March</a>, via Steam. Our Ian along with Outside Xbox's Jane went hands on with Inzoi last year. You can check out their thoughts on the game - including its toilet animations - below.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="inZOI: Like The Sims But With Drivable Cars, Cat Gods, and AI Chat | gamescom 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_TReJFbhyWY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>inZOI: Like The Sims But With Drivable Cars, Cat Gods, and AI Chat | gamescom 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_TReJFbhyWY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_TReJFbhyWY?autoplay=1" title="inZOI: Like The Sims But With Drivable Cars, Cat Gods, and AI Chat | gamescom 2024">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Ian-Zoi... <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_TReJFbhyWY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In the meantime, and if you want to have some life-sim-WooHoo-related-fun, last year <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-sims-4-is-turning-up-the-heat-with-its-super-sexy-lovestruck-expansion-pack">EA released the Lovestruck Expansion Pack for The Sims 4</a>. This pack added new romantic interactions, which include a new kiss, a sultry dance and three new WooHoo spots.</p>
<p>It also added a sexy aubergine costume, because of course.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo's latest legal win against piracy "significant" for "the entire games industry"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendos-latest-legal-win-against-piracy-significant-for-the-entire-games-industry</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendos-latest-legal-win-against-piracy-significant-for-the-entire-games-industry.1124568/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendos-latest-legal-win-against-piracy-significant-for-the-entire-games-industry<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>File-sharing site beaten after long-running battle.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/monster-hunter-wilds-alle-monster-gp_6292889_gTkglup.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nintendo</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Nintendo has trumpeted its latest legal success in the company's ongoing fight against pirated games as "significant" not only for itself, "but for the entire games industry".
</p>
<p>
The Mario maker today confirmed it had won a final victory over French file-sharing company Dstorage, which operates the website 1fichier.com, following years of legal wrangling and repeated appeals.
</p>
<p>
Nintendo's victory means European file-sharing companies must now remove illegal copies of games when asked to do so, or be held accountable and cough up potentially sizable fines as punishment.
</p>
<p>
In 2021, the Judicial Court of Paris ordered Dstorage pay Nintendo €935k (£773k) in damages after it was found to be hosting pirate games. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-wins-case-against-french-filesharing-service-hosting-pirated-games">Dstorage launched an appeal, which then failed in 2023, and was ordered to pay Nintendo further costs</a>. But the case didn't end there. 
</p>
<p>
Dstorage finally took the matter to the highest French judiciary court, where it argued that a specific court order was required before it needed to remove content from its hosting services. This bid has also now failed, ending the long-running matter for good.
</p>
<p>
"Nintendo is pleased with the court's finding of liability against Dstorage," reads a statement from the Mario maker shared with Eurogamer this morning. 
</p>
<p>
"Together with its recent decision of 15th January 2025, confirming that a major French Bank had rightfully terminated a payment processing agreement with 1fichier.com due to lacking anti-piracy measures, the French Supreme Court leaves no doubt that sharehosting providers like 1fichier.com are not a safe haven for storing and sharing illegal content.
</p>
<p>
"Nintendo promotes and fosters development and creativity, and strongly supports developers who legitimately create new and innovative software. Nintendo's message to consumers is not to download pirate copies of Nintendo games as this increases the risk that this will interfere with the functionality and experience that playing legitimate Nintendo games on authentic Nintendo hardware provides."
</p>
<p>
Nintendo's campaign against game piracy has regularly hit the headlines over the past year, perhaps most notably with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-emulator-yuzu-shuts-down-as-creator-agrees-to-pay-nintendo-24m">the shutdown of Switch emulator Yuzu - whose creator agreed to pay Nintendo $2.4m</a> (£1.89m). 
</p>
<p>
Last summer, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-war-against-switch-piracy-ramps-up-with-two-fresh-cases">Nintendo tracked down the moderator behind the infamous SwitchPirates reddit</a> and claimed the individual ran "several pirate shops" that sold "massive libraries of pirated Nintendo Switch games". Nintendo is seeking damages in the millions of dollars.
</p>
<p>
In November 2024, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-sues-streamer-who-said-he-could-broadcast-its-pirated-games-all-day">Nintendo filed a lawsuit against a streamer who regularly played pirated copies of Nintendo games ahead of release</a>, including <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom">The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mario-and-luigi-brothership">Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership</a>. The streamer had previously boasted he "could do all this all day" as he had "1000 burner accounts".
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds patch notes warn of network error when firing SOS flares]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-patch-notes-warn-of-network-error-when-firing-sos-flares</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-patch-notes-warn-of-network-error-when-firing-sos-flares.1124556/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-patch-notes-warn-of-network-error-when-firing-sos-flares<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Chapter 5-2 progress-blocking bug fixed.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/monster-hunter-wilds-alle-monster-gp_6292889.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Capcom / Adobe</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Capcom has released details of today's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> patch, which fixes <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-has-a-progress-breaking-npc-bug">the game's progression-blocking bug in the main mission Chapter 5-2 "A World Turned Upside Down"</a>.
</p>
<p>
The update, numbered as version 1.000.04.00, is available to download now on all platforms. You must download the patch to continue playing online, and restart the game to make sure it is applied.
</p>
<p>
Alongside a list of fixes, Capcom also warns of several other issues it is currently aware of, but is yet to resolve. This includes an issue where a network error occurs after someone fires an SOS flare right after a quest begins - so, for now, don't do that.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Monster Hunter Wilds Review" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3b7tXGXPBeQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Monster Hunter Wilds Review</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3b7tXGXPBeQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/3b7tXGXPBeQ?autoplay=1" title="Monster Hunter Wilds Review">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Eurogamer's Monster Hunter Wilds review, in video form.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3b7tXGXPBeQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Other problems still to be addressed include a bug where Palico attacks with blunt weapons don't inflict stun and exhaust damages, and an issue where "Link Members are not prioritised over other players and may not appear in some places including Base Camps".
</p>
<p>
The full list of fixes added in today's patch lie just below.
</p>
<p>
<strong>Monster Hunter Wilds version 1.000.04.00 patch notes</strong>
</p>
<ul>
<li>The "Grill a Meal" and "Ingredient Center" features cannot be unlocked even after meeting the progress criteria.</li>
<li>When heading to Azuz during Main Mission: Chapter 2-1 "Toward Fervent Fields," players keep falling through the map.</li>
<li>The Monster Field Guide cannot be accessed.</li>
<li>During Main Mission: Chapter 5-2 "A World Turned Upside Down," an NPC may not appear, preventing further progression.</li>
<li>At the Smithy, an issue may occur where tutorials are repeatedly shown, disabling certain options in the menu.</li>
<li>When guarding a monster's attack with a lance using Power Guard under certain conditions, the weapon flashes in red but the effect is not activated</li>
<li>When using a mantle, a Weapon Equipment Skill may mistakenly be activated.</li>
<li>Some effects may be displayed continuously when using certain skills, such as Peak Performance and Self-Improvement.</li>
<li>When successfully preforming an Offset Attack with the Insect Glaive's Descending Slash under certain conditions, the hunter freezes and becomes unresponsive to any controls.</li>
<li>Addressed issues that occurred under certain conditions with screen rendering and causing force quits.</li>
</ul>

<p>
Earlier today, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/monster-hunter-wilds-is-capcoms-fastest-selling-game-ever">Capcom confirmed the sales success of Monster Hunter Wilds</a> with the announcement that the game had now sold 8m copies across PC, PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S in just three days. The game is now Capcom's fastest-selling title ever, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/capcom-responds-after-monster-hunter-wilds-steam-success-is-marred-by-performance-complaints">though its user rating on Steam still sits at Mixed</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty season delayed, Verdansk return now expected next month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-season-delayed-verdansk-return-now-expected-next-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-season-delayed-verdansk-return-now-expected-next-month.1124517/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-season-delayed-verdansk-return-now-expected-next-month<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Activision has delayed the rollout of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/call-of-duty-2024">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> and Warzone Season 3, including the anticipated return of the latter's classic Verdansk map. 
</p>
<p>
Season 3 was previously due to arrive around 20th March. Now, it'll hit two weeks later on 3rd April.
</p>
<p>
"Season 3 is a big moment for Call of Duty: Warzone and Black Ops 6, and we're taking the time to deliver a great experience starting on 3rd April," Activision wrote in a <a href="https://x.com/CallofDuty/status/1896636715143704641">post on social media</a>. 
</p>
<p>
"More to come following Call of Duty: Warzone's fifth anniversary next week..."
</p>
<p>
Verdansk was Call of Duty: Warzone's original map, available when the battle royale's first iteration arrived back in 2020. Now, it's widely-expected to return in time for the game's fifth anniversary.
</p>
<p>
Call of Duty is the latest battle royale to lean on nostalgia and bring back a classic map in the hopes of boosting player numbers, following the likes of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/apex-legends">Apex Legends</a>.
</p>
<p>
The move to return to a fan-favourite map follows a patchy start to this year's Call of Duty content, with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-bans-another-136000-cheaters">Activision having to focus time to address player concerns over rampant in-game cheating</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-block-ops-6-players-accuse-activision-of-using-ai-slop">admitting to the use of in-game AI imagery</a>, and selling a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-players-lament-battle-passes-in-between-battle-passes-with-squid-game-event">separate expensive Squid Game battle pass</a>
</p><p><span data-fixed="false" data-hashid="" data-init="false" data-poll-position="1"></span>

"For a series built on high-octane thrills and explosive gratification, Call of Duty: Black Ops 6's withdrawal to the well-trodden formula echoes the wider industry's continued allergy to risk," our Chris Tapsell wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-review">Eurogamer's Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 review</a>.



        </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>