<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 13:22:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stellar Blade's runaway success on PC proves South Korea is positioning itself to become a major force in global gaming, and experts agree]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blades-runaway-success-on-pc-proves-south-korea-is-positioning-itself-to-become-a-major-force-in-global-gaming-and-experts-agree</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stellar-blades-runaway-success-on-pc-proves-south-korea-is-positioning-itself-to-become-a-major-force-in-global-gaming-and-experts-agree.1270953/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Gonna be, gonna be golden.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Shift Up / Neowiz / Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The PC release of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blade-guides-tips-tricks-9430">Stellar Blade</a> has proven exceptionally popular, with developer Shift Up revealing impressive sales earlier this week in its latest financial report. But it's not only a huge win for the studio and publisher Sony, it's also exemplary of a booming games industry in South Korea seeking global expansion.</p>
<p>As announced by Shift Up, the PC version of Stellar Blade sold a million copies in its first three days on Steam, and now boasts over 3m sales on PC and console combined. Further, its peak concurrent player count on Steam sits at almost 200k - as per Shift Up's latest financial report, that's 2-5x higher than Sony's other flagship triple-A games (<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/ghost-of-tsushima">Ghost of Tsushima</a>, God of War, Spider-Man, to name three), making it the best-ever PC performance for a PS-exclusive IP launch. These are single-player games only, not including the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-now-playstations-fastest-selling-game-ever">multiplayer and multi-platform success of Helldivers 2</a>.</p>
<p>"Following the PS5 success of Stellar Blade as a triple-A IP, Shift Up leveraged its unique strengths in optimisation, user experience, content enhancements, and market specific marketing to continue its success in the PC market - becoming a developer with proven hits across mobile, PC, and console," wrote the studio in its report. And that success is set to continue throughout the rest of the year.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Stellar Blade - PC Features Trailer | PC Games" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pex7jW3Tqwo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Stellar Blade - PC Features Trailer | PC Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pex7jW3Tqwo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Pex7jW3Tqwo?autoplay=1" title="Stellar Blade - PC Features Trailer | PC Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Stellar Blade - PC Features Trailer | PC Games<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pex7jW3Tqwo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>The popularity of Stellar Blade parallels an explosion of Korean culture in general. K-pop bands are global phenomenons; K-dramas and reality shows are all over Netflix; Korean films are winning Oscars; and Sony Pictures Animation's KPop Demon Hunters film is <em>the </em>thing that's dominating everything right now. And it's happening in games, too.</p><p>Just this week alone there's been plenty of news about Korean games. On top of those Stellar Blade sales, there was the announcement of Woochi the Wayfarer from publisher Nexon, a single-player triple-A action game based on Korean mythology that's set for release on PC and consoles. With its basis in Korean culture, it could follow the sort of nationalistic success <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/black-myth-wukong">Black Myth: Wukong</a> received in China.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Woochi the Wayfarer - Teaser Trailer | PS5 Games" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/15AZ6rqXw-Y?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Woochi the Wayfarer - Teaser Trailer | PS5 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/15AZ6rqXw-Y?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/15AZ6rqXw-Y?autoplay=1" title="Woochi the Wayfarer - Teaser Trailer | PS5 Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Woochi the Wayfarer - Teaser Trailer | PS5 Games<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=15AZ6rqXw-Y" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Then, along with those Stellar Blade figures, there's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/inzoi-is-releasing-on-ps5-in-the-first-half-of-2026-xbox-version-is-being-considered">Krafton's Sims-like Inzoi heading to PS5</a>, as well as the delay of Pearl Abyss' open-world adventure Crimson Desert that will now be released early next year "due to longer than expected timelines arising from schedule coordination and collaborations with multiple partners for offline distribution, voice-overs, console certification, and other launch preparations", according to the company's latest financial report (thanks <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/08/crimson-desert-delayed-to-q1-2026">Gematsu</a>).</p>
<p>This all follows the likes of Soulslike <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lies-of-p-overture-difficulty-options">Lies of P celebrating the release of its DLC</a> earlier this summer; Nexon <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dave-the-diver-director-finally-ends-indie-debate-after-controversial-the-game-awards-2023-nomination">debating what indie means with its popular Dave the Diver</a> game, as well as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-first-descendant-developer-responds-to-claims-its-icons-are-too-similar-to-those-in-destiny-2">courting plagiarism concerns with its Destiny-esque shooter The First Descendent</a>; and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/playerunknowns-battlegrounds">PUBG</a> developer <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tango-gameworks-and-hi-fi-rush-acquired-by-pubgs-krafton-following-microsofts-studio-closure-in-may">Krafton acquiring Hi-Fi Rush developer Tango Gameworks</a> to boost its action game output, while more recently <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/krafton-defends-itself-amidst-subnautica-2-fiasco-says-milestone-process-is-being-rigorously-managed">defending itself amid a Subnautica 2 lawsuit fiasco</a>.</p><p>In short, the Korean games industry appears to be thriving. Of course, the country has long had a history with games, but it's previously focused predominantly on mobile games and online games, not to mention its exceptional esports scene. Now, though, we're seeing a shift towards PC and console gaming, and single-player games too. Pearl Abyss following its MMORPG Black Desert with the single-player Crimson Desert is just one example.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/lies-of-p">Lies of P</a> director Choi Ji-won told Eurogamer back at the Game Developer Conference the studio's "primary focus from the concept of this game was to deliver a high quality, premium action game that is single-player," though he admitted he'd be <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/lies-of-p-to-remain-single-player-despite-refreshing-elden-ring-nightreign-says-director">open to a Nightreign-esque multiplayer game in future</a>.</p>
<p>"In the future, instead of pegging us into a certain genre, we want the fans to look at us and actually know what sort of unique components that we deliver that they look forward to," he added. "So they see our next work as a sort of projection of our trust and characters that we are building moving forward."</p>
<p>Speaking on the wider industry, Choi Ji-won said: "There are many talented and remarkable developers in Korea, and we are grateful for the opportunity that in, especially the action game [genre], our game perhaps provided a little more motivation to the already talented developers in Korea to craft their own experience in the genre."</p>
<figure>

<figcaption>Lies of P has challenged the dominance of FromSoftware's Souls games | <span>Image credit: <cite>Neowiz</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Why is it that action games in particular are proving popular? "I think action in general is very intuitive, it's primal," Choi Ji-won suggested. "It's pretty natural that the action genre is big and there are many games actually in it. Also East Asia has a long tradition of action related materials, so because of that I think it comes very naturally."</p><p>Now, the Korean industry is looking to go global. Speaking to Game Informer (via <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/korean-devs-report-a-burst-of-interest-in-single-player-console-and-pc-games">Game Developer</a>), Round8 Studio CEO Jason Park said there are a "fixed number of people" playing single-player games on console and PC in South Korea, a number that "won't change". That's why Lies of P was made with a global market in mind.</p>
<p>Shift Up CEO Kim Hyung-tae said only five percent of Stellar Blade's PS5 sales came from Korea, and console share isn't growing - that's why the PC release was so important. He added that mobile games are designed around monetisation so appeal to an older demographic. "That's continued for the past 20 years, and players have become older, so it's harder to acquire new and younger users," he said.</p>
<p>Niko Partners analyst Daniel Ahmad echoed these comments to Eurogamer. "The Korean video game market remained flat in 2024 with narrowed growth prospects," he said. "This has led Korean video game companies, who have typically excelled at developing live service MMORPGs at home, to explore new geographies, genres and business models including premium single player games for the global market."</p>
<p>What's more, Ahmad explained, the Korean government has doubled its investment from 2024 into domestic console game development, now allocated 15.5 billion won. "The success of titles such as Stellar Blade and Lies of P show this strategy is delivering results for Shift Up and Neowiz, respectively," he said.</p><p>"While the goal is primarily growth outside of Korea, the industry is also looking to fill gaps at home with titles in genres that can challenge the dominance of long standing MMO, MOBA and shooter games in the country. Korean video game companies have also stepped up investment efforts in global studios and developing markets, with the aim of building a publishing portfolio with global appeal."</p>
<p>Growth in Korea mirrors a similar surge in China, where the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/how-black-myth-wukong-has-changed-the-game-for-chinese-developers">success of Black Myth: Wukong has paved the way for other action-RPGs</a>, from Phantom Blade Zero, to Lost Soul Aside, Wuchang: Fallen Feathers, and Tides of Annihilation. Developers here have similarly moved from mobile to PC and console development, seeking global appeal. Phantom Blade Zero director "Soulframe" Liang described this shift to Eurogamer as akin to the "golden age of PlayStation 1 and 2".</p>
<p>Shift Up will <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blade-2-is-official-and-seemingly-not-too-far-away">follow up the success of Stellar Blade with a sequel</a>, set to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blade-2-better-story-than-stellar-blade">address issues with the lack of story in the first game</a>. Its next original game, currently known as Project Spirit, is in development for a release some time from 2027 onwards. Whether it can match Stellar Blade's success with increased competition from other Korean developers remains to be seen.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blades-runaway-success-on-pc-proves-south-korea-is-positioning-itself-to-become-a-major-force-in-global-gaming-and-experts-agree]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get another taste of the Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds official soundtrack]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/get-another-taste-of-the-sonic-racing-crossworlds-official-soundtrack</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-another-taste-of-the-sonic-racing-crossworlds-official-soundtrack.1270884/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>A new video highlights music inspired by Sonic Unleashed, Sonic Colours, and Sonic Adventure 2.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer / SEGA</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sonic the Hedgehog isn't loved by everyone, but most people can agree that the music in his games is generally top-tier stuff. We expect the soundtrack to the upcoming Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds will be stellar, and Sega has released a brand new video that highlights six of the tunes in the game.</p>
<p>The video below, which runs for almost eight minutes, features a mix of six remixed tracks from CrossWorlds put together by Kanon Oguni!. These tracks from the official soundtrack are said to be inspired by courses in the game based on Sonic Unleashed, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sonic-colours">Sonic Colors</a>, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/r-sa2-dc">Sonic Adventure 2</a>.</p>
<figure><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lycWyLXqduE">
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lycWyLXqduE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" height="113" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" title="Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds OST | DJ Mix" width="200"></iframe><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</a></figure>
<blockquote><p>About the music:</p>
<p><strong>Apotos</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Composed by Tomoya Ohtani</li>
<li>Arranged by @GigaVideos</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dragon Road</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Composed by Kenichi Tokoi</li>
<li>Arranged by @Cametek.CamelliaOfficial</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Galactic Parade</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Composed by Tomoya Ohtani</li>
<li>Arranged by @torienaofficial</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Market Street</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Composed by Tomoya Ohtani</li>
<li>Arranged by @TeeLopes</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sweet Mountain</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Composed by Kenichi Tokoi</li>
<li>Arranged by @nanobii</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Radical Highway</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Composed by Jun Senoue</li>
<li>Arranged by @djzardonic &amp; Jun Senoue</li>
</ul>
<p>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds will release digitally and physically on September 25, 2025, and is available for pre-order now for PlayStation 5 (PS5), PlayStation 4 (PS4), Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, and PC starting at £64.99.</p>
<p>Physical and digital pre-orders for Nintendo Switch, Nintendo Switch- OLED Model, and Nintendo Switch Lite are available now starting at £54.99. The Nintendo Switch 2 system version will be available for pre-order at a later date starting at £64.99 for the Standard Edition and £79.99 for the Digital Deluxe Edition. There will be a paid upgrade path available for owners of Nintendo Switch, Nintendo Switch- OLED Model, and Nintendo Switch Lite, with content and progress able to carry over through the upgrade. The Nintendo Switch 2 system version will launch digitally this holiday 2025 and physically early 2026.</p></blockquote>
<p><em>This is a news-in-brief story. This is part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-is-changing-to-give-you-more-of-what-you-want">our vision</a> to bring you all the big news as part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-in-video-games-15th-august-battlefield-6-beta-continues-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-is-out-and-early-shouts-for-game-of-the-year">daily live report</a>.</em></p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/get-another-taste-of-the-sonic-racing-crossworlds-official-soundtrack]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Emergency Call 112 - The Firefighting Simulation 3 revealed for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/emergency-call-112-the-firefighting-simulation-3-revealed-for-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-consoles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/emergency-call-112-the-firefighting-simulation-3-revealed-for-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-consoles.1270866/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>The new game aims to be even more authentic, developed in cooperation with the Mülheim an der Ruhr fire department.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Aerosoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>If you simply can't get enough authentic firefighting video games, publisher Aerosoft has got some great news: Emergency Call 112 - The Firefighting Simulation 3 is coming to PC, PS5, and Xbox Series consoles, and is in development at crenetic.</p>
<p>The PC version is set to arrive first, initially in Early Access, with Aerosoft saying that the full release will be moulded by "community driven development." Versions of The Firefighting Simulation 3 will land on PS5 and Xbox after the game's full PC release.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>About Emergency Call 112 - The Firefighting Simulation 3</strong></p>
<p><em>"With Emergency Call 3, we’re building a new emergency simulation that reflects the daily rhythm of life at a fire station, every drill, every task, and every operation is part of a larger, continuous system where preparation is as important as the emergency itself. As we continue to work hard on development, we hope that fans of the series and new budding firefighters alike will find the game enjoyable and educational!"</em> - said the team at crenetic.</p>
<p><strong>Key Features:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Developed alongside Real Fire Fighters: Developed with the Mülheim an der Ruhr Fire Department to ensure accurate procedures and operations.</li>
<li>Interactive Character Progression: Track and improve physical and professional attributes through training and mission experience.</li>
<li>Specialized Roles &amp; Qualifications: Earn operational roles like attack squad, hose team, or driver/operator through targeted courses and drills.</li>
<li>Open Game World: Multiple urban districts with varied missions, from firefighting to traffic accidents.</li>
<li>Dynamic Shifts: Full day-night cycle, changing weather conditions, and a rotating duty schedule.</li>
<li>Detailed Fire Station Simulation: Perform daily tasks and interact with an explorable fire station environment.</li>
<li>Missions with Real Stakes: Plan and execute operations to protect lives and property, with performance evaluations after each shift.</li>
<li>Powered by Unreal Engine 5: Delivering high-fidelity visuals, lighting, and environmental realism.</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p><em>This is a news-in-brief story. This is part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-is-changing-to-give-you-more-of-what-you-want">our vision</a> to bring you all the big news as part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-in-video-games-15th-august-battlefield-6-beta-continues-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-is-out-and-early-shouts-for-game-of-the-year">daily live report</a>.</em></p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/emergency-call-112-the-firefighting-simulation-3-revealed-for-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-consoles]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neo Berlin 2087 - Gamescom 2025 Gameplay Trailer shows off impressive visuals]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/title-neo-berlin-2087-gamescom-2025-gameplay-trailer-shows-off-impressive-visuals</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/neo-berlin-2087-gamescom-2025-gameplay-trailer-shows-off-impressive-visuals.1270839/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Futuristic action-RPG is coming to PS5, Xbox Series consoles, and PC.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Elysium Game Studio</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Elysium Game Studio has released a brand-new gameplay trailer for its third- and first-person action RPG, Neo Berlin 2087. According to the developer's official website, the game is coming to PS5, Xbox Series consoles, and PC.</p>
<p>The game first appeared in a pre-alpha footage gameplay trailer two years ago, and also made an appearance at <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-at-gamescom-opening-night-live-2024">Gamescom</a> last year. Elias Toufexis, known as the voice of Adam Jensen in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/deus-ex-human-revolution">Deus Ex: Human Revolution</a>, and as Seraphim in Netflix's Blood of Zeus, announced last year that he'd signed on to play the main character.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Neo Berlin 2087 - Gamescom 2025 Gameplay Trailer | PS5 Games" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i8B89MssneU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Neo Berlin 2087 - Gamescom 2025 Gameplay Trailer | PS5 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i8B89MssneU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/i8B89MssneU?autoplay=1" title="Neo Berlin 2087 - Gamescom 2025 Gameplay Trailer | PS5 Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i8B89MssneU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>As the name suggests, this is a futuristic world, and the trailer looks pretty impressive.</p>
<p>From the trailer blurb:</p>
<blockquote><p>Dive into the dystopian cyberpunk world of Neo Berlin 2087 – a unique third- and first-person action RPG crafted for fans of immersive single-player experiences. Uncover a deep, narrative-driven story through never-before-seen gameplay, new levels, cinematic cutscenes, and intense combat. Meet new characters Bryan and Phoenix in this action-packed Gamescom 2025 reveal.</p></blockquote>
<p><em>This is a news-in-brief story. This is part of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eurogamer-is-changing-to-give-you-more-of-what-you-want">our vision</a> to bring you all the big news as part of a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-in-video-games-15th-august-battlefield-6-beta-continues-dawn-of-war-definitive-edition-is-out-and-early-shouts-for-game-of-the-year">daily live report</a>.</em></p>

        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/title-neo-berlin-2087-gamescom-2025-gameplay-trailer-shows-off-impressive-visuals]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>