<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - eurogamer_net</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/eurogamer_net.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for eurogamer_net</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 16:59:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's what's coming to Xbox Game Pass in July]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-whats-coming-to-game-pass-in-july</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-whats-coming-to-xbox-game-pass-in-july.1232955/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Tony Hawk 3 + 4! Tomb Raider! More!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer/Xbox</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
July and the sizzle of summer are finally upon us. And as ever, a new calendar month means a fresh batch of Xbox Game Pass titles, which this time include the likes of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/rise-of-the-tomb-raider">Rise of the Tomb Raider</a>, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/little-nightmares-ii">Little Nightmares 2</a>.
</p>
<p>
Microsoft has so far announced a grand total of nine titles joining the various tiers of its subscription service this month, with the first of those arriving today, 1st July. You can see everything coming - plus when, on what platform, and to what Game Pass tier - below:
</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Little Nightmares 2</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) - available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard from 1st July</li>
<li><strong>Rise of the Tomb Raider</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) - available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard from 1st July</li>
<li><strong>Legend of Mana</strong> (Console) – available with Game Pass Standard from 2nd July</li>
<li><strong>Trials of Mana</strong> (Console) – available with Game Pass Standard from 2nd July</li>
<li><strong>Ultimate Chicken Horse</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) – available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard from 3rd July</li>
<li><strong>The Ascent</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) – available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard from 8th July</li>
<li><strong>Minami Lane</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) – available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass from 9th July</li>
<li><strong>Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) – available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass from 11th July</li>
<li><strong>High On Life</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC) – available with Game Pass Ultimate, PC Game Pass, Game Pass Standard from 15th July</li>
</ul>
<p>
It's a decent line-up, then, although Activision's long-awaited Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4 remake will undoubtedly be the headline act for many people. But adorably sinister horror sequel Little Nightmares 2 is well worth your time if you're in the mood for some macabre chills, and that double-whammy of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>'s Mana series should keep fantasy RPG fans occupied. Beyond that, there's a spot of tomb raiding, some wholesome street-management action in Miami Lane, visually striking cyberpunk action in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-ascent">The Ascent</a>, and more.
</p>
<p>
As for departures, six games are leaving Xbox Game Pass on 15th July, so if you've been meaning to check out any of the following, you've only got a couple of weeks to do so:
</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Flock</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li><strong>Mafia Definitive Edition</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li><strong>Magical Delicacy</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li><strong>Tchia</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li><strong>The Callisto Protocol</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
<li><strong>The Case of the Golden Idol</strong> (Cloud, Console, and PC)</li>
</ul>
<p>
To keep playing the above titles after they leave Game Pass, you'll need to buy them - but subscribers do at least get a 20 percent discount. And for everything else in Microsoft's subscription service, check out <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-game-pass-games-list-this-month-price-6400">Eurogamer's handy Xbox Game Pass guide</a>.
</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-whats-coming-to-game-pass-in-july]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>