<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 13:52:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Can Play Tony Hawk 3 + 4 Early Right Now On Game Pass, If You Pay Extra]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/you-can-play-tony-hawk-3-4-early-right-now-on-game-pass-if-you-pay-extra/1100-6533049/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-play-tony-hawk-3-4-early-right-now-on-game-pass-if-you-pay-extra.1239165/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533049">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Later this week, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-review/1900-6418379/" data-ref-id="1900-6418379">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4</a> will officially launch on consoles and PC. But if you're willing to pay for early access, you can play Pro Skater 3 + 4 right now.</p><p>Activision Blizzard has released Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4 - Deluxe Edition Upgrade on <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0002-PPSA18010_00-TH34RDLXBUNDL001" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PSN</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-deluxe-edition-upgrade/9NF55CV839VJ/0010" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox and PC</a>. For an extra $20, players can join the three-day early access ahead of the game's official launch on July 11. If you're a Game Pass Ultimate or PC Game Pass subscriber, that's all you'll need to start playing right now. Those on PlayStation (and those on Xbox/PC without a Game Pass subscription) will need to outright buy the $70 Digital Deluxe Edition.</p><p>The Digital Deluxe Edition also includes the Doom Slayer and the Revenant as playable skaters, each with their own secret moves and skate decks. Doom Slayer also has two unique outfits as well as the Unmaykr Hoverboard skate deck. Additionally, the in-game soundtrack has songs that aren't included in the standard edition as well as exclusive Create-a-Skater items.</p><p>You can read our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-review/1900-6418379/" data-ref-id="1900-6418379">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4 review</a> for more on what to expect.</p><p>While it was originally believed that content from Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 4 would be excluded from the remake, developer Iron Galaxy recently confirmed that many of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-remake-actually-does-include-most-of-thps-4s-original-activities/1100-6532324/" data-ref-id="1100-6532324">the fourth game's activities will be playable as post-game content</a>. Jack Black is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/jack-black-returns-for-tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-and-plays-two-characters-this-time/1100-6532730/" data-ref-id="1100-6532730">reprising his role as Officer Dick</a> from Pro Skater 1 + 2, and also playing his UK counterpart, Constable Richard in Pro Skater 3 + 4.</p><p>Taco Bell-themed DLC <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/taco-bell-themed-tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-dlc-is-coming-and-we-hope-youre-hungry/1100-6532708/" data-ref-id="1100-6532708">is also on the way to Pro Skater 3 + 4</a> for hungry fans who purchase the Build Your Own Luxe Cravings Box starting on July 11. Each week, different Taco Bell skating apparel will available with the purchase of a BYOLCB.</p><p>As for Tony Hawk himself, the famous skater <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tony-hawk-is-auctioning-his-gear-and-board-he-used-when-he-did-an-iconic-trick/1100-6532828/" data-ref-id="1100-6532828">is auctioning off the board</a> he used to successfully execute the 900 flip--a two-and-a-half-revolution aerial spin.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/you-can-play-tony-hawk-3-4-early-right-now-on-game-pass-if-you-pay-extra/1100-6533049/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>