<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 15:56:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former PlayStation boss says 'stupid money' crippled the game industry]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/former-playstation-boss-says-stupid-money-crippled-the-game-industry</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-playstation-boss-says-stupid-money-crippled-the-game-industry.1193031/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/former-playstation-boss-says-stupid-money-crippled-the-game-industry<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Former PlayStation boss Shuhei Yoshida, who spent over three decades at the company before </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/playstation-veteran-shuhei-yoshida-is-departing-the-company">departing earlier this year</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, feels "stupid money" is responsible for the wave of studio closures and layoffs that have dominated the video game industry following the COVID-19 pandemic.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">During a wide-ranging chat at Gamescom LATAM, Yoshida said it remains "totally possible" for the industry to become truly sustainable, but claimed that would require the biggest players and investors to stop treating the market like a fabled golden goose.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"What we've been seeing for the last two years is just the adjustment to the misjudged [spending] by so many companies during the COVID days," he explained, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/embracer-s-m-a-era-is-ending-with-job-cuts-and-game-cancellations">pointing to the ill-fated M&amp;A spree</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> undertaken by Embracer Group as an example of a growth tactic that seemed incredibly short-sighted.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Many companies and even the analysts believed the crazy growth [during the pandemic] would continue. So they over-invested and over-hired and they started too many projects, but after COVID there were a lot more ways for people to entertain themselves so the growth slowed down."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Yoshida described the situation that has left thousands of developers out of work (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sony-reevaluating-playstation-studios-and-cutting-900-jobs">including many at his former employer Sony</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) as "very sad," but claimed the "stupid money" that helped spark that age of over-investment&nbsp;has departed the video game industry in search of the next big thing.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/activision-is-delisting-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-after-one-year" target="_self" data-discover="true">Activision is delisting Call of Duty: Warzone Mobile after one year</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Yoshida feels diverse portfolios and smaller projects can deliver stability">Yoshida feels diverse portfolios and smaller projects can deliver stability</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Does that mean there's cause for quiet optimism? Yoshida believes so, but feels the largest companies need to begin (sensibly) investing in portfolio rather than pinning all of their financial hopes on a handful of gargantuan projects with no margin for error.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Each product is different, right? Some live service games are successful—like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Helldivers 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. So you cannot just take one product [or model] and say they're all wrong. Especially with entertainment products, nobody can predict sales, especially when new IPs are tried," he continued.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I've worked with marketers in the past and they always miss the numbers. So, what big companies should do is invest in a portfolio of titles—because if they just invest in a small number of titles it's a huge risk. Even when you invest in existing successful franchises, because people's tastes will change."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's also important, says Yoshida, to moderate the amount invested across that portfolio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He explains that because big companies have to compete with rivals of similar size and stature, budgets can quickly balloon as competitors attempt to outdo each other. The antidote to that budgetary arms race, he suggests, is to realize that "sometimes limitation is really helpful" for studios and developers looking to push themselves creatively.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/take-two-projects-annual-growth-despite-gta-vi-delay" target="_self" data-discover="true">Take-Two projects annual growth despite GTA VI delay</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a sentiment that chimes with the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/-it-s-okay-to-make-a-small-game-astro-bot-director-nicolas-doucet-says-tiny-ideas-contain-huge-potential">advice handed out by </a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/-it-s-okay-to-make-a-small-game-astro-bot-director-nicolas-doucet-says-tiny-ideas-contain-huge-potential">Astro Bot</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/-it-s-okay-to-make-a-small-game-astro-bot-director-nicolas-doucet-says-tiny-ideas-contain-huge-potential"> director Nicolas Doucet at GDC 2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, where he reminded attendees that "it's okay to make a small game."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"A lot of the choices we made with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astro Bot</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> could be labelled double-A or maybe lacking in ambition—like the size of the team, the size of the game, the fact there's no text, no voice, and its not an open world," added Doucet. "But that doesn't really matter. We still made a game that made people really happy, and in fact it was probably the simplicity that a lot of players made time for."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>