<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 14:06:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2 Guardian Games 2025 Adds New Boss Rush Mode, Rushdown]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-guardian-games-2025-adds-new-boss-rush-mode-rushdown/1100-6529969/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destiny-2-guardian-games-2025-adds-new-boss-rush-mode-rushdown.1127991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-guardian-games-2025-adds-new-boss-rush-mode-rushdown/1100-6529969/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529969">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Since 2020, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/destiny-2-review/1900-6416758/" data-ref-id="1900-6416758">Destiny 2</a> has pit the three Guardian classes against each other in the Guardian Games to determine whether the Titans, the Warlocks, or the Hunters will reign supreme for a year. On March 11, the 2025 Guardian Games will begin with a few changes. Guardian Games Nightfalls and Focused Activities have been dropped from this year's event. In their place is a new boss rush mode called Rushdown, which looks like it will test even the most seasoned Destiny 2 players.</p><p>Bungie has shared <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/News/Article/twid_03_06_2025" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the details for this year's Guardian Games</a>, including the way that Rushdown will work. Rushdown will assemble bosses from the campaigns, the seasonal story missions, and the exotic missions in battles that will get exponentially more difficult for players. Each run through Rushdown will feature five boss encounters, all of which must be completed before time expires. Time gets added to the clock with each boss that goes down, and teams that finish more quickly have a better chance of earning higher quality rewards.</p><p>Rushdown includes warm-up, standard, and expert modes, but only the last two will include combatants with modifiers while also letting players receive revive tokens. However, players will get a higher score if they use fewer revive tokens. All three modes will be open for standard matchmaking, class-based matchmaking, and private fireteam matches. Players will be judged by how many bosses they defeated and by their overall score.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4455148-destiny2guardiangamestraceriffle.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4455148" data-ratio="0.56230769230769" data-width="1300" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4455148-destiny2guardiangamestraceriffle.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4455148"></a><figcaption>The new Arc Trace riffle from this year's Guardian Games.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4455148-destiny2guardiangamestraceriffle.jpg"></figure><p>It just wouldn't be a Guardian Games without a new weapon. This year's addition to the armory is called Keraunios. It's a powerful new Arc Trace rifle that features jolting impact, recycled energy, and rolling storm. Last year's addition, the Allstar Vector Skimmer, will be available again during this year's Guardian Games. Players will receive a temporary version of the weapon for the duration of the event. But if players want to permanently add it to their collection, they will need to complete a drop-in quest. </p><p>Players who finish three encounters in any of the Rushdown modes will be guaranteed to receive a Guardians Games weapon during that run. The five scoring thresholds are bronze, silver, gold, platinum, and diamond. Naturally, players who reach the higher tiers in standard or expert will get better rewards. And players who achieve high scores in expert mode will also get the chance to pick up fully Masterworked Guardian Games weapons.</p><p>In order for players to help their preferred faction to win the overall Guardian Games, they have to team up with members of the same class and fight in PvP and other activities to earn medallions. Once the medallions are in hand, players need to bring them to the podium to count them among the total points for their class. There will be winning classes on every day of the event, but only one faction will be named the victor when the Guardian Games close after three weeks of competition. </p><p>Outside of this event, Bungie recently announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-destiny-2-pvp-mode-heavy-metal-lets-you-finally-pilot-a-brig/1100-6529865/" data-ref-id="1100-6529865">a brand-new, limited-time PvP mode</a> called Heavy Metal that will arrive during Heresy Act 3. This will finally give players their chance to pilot a Brig. There's also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2s-new-rite-of-the-nine-event-is-for-dungeon-newcomers-and-veterans-alike/1100-6529863/" data-ref-id="1100-6529863">a Rite of the Nine event</a> that's geared for both Destiny 2 veterans and newcomers.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>