<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 18:15:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ninja Gaiden 4 Will Finally Be Released This October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ninja-gaiden-4-will-finally-be-released-this-october/1100-6532247/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ninja-gaiden-4-will-finally-be-released-this-october.1212138/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ninja-gaiden-4-will-finally-be-released-this-october/1100-6532247/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532247">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>During the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/xbox-games-showcase-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-6656/" data-ref-id="2900-6656">Xbox Games Showcase</a>, we got another look at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/xbox-games-showcase-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-6656/" data-ref-id="2900-6656">Ninja Gaiden 4</a>. Most importantly, it received an October 21 release date.</p><p>The trailer gave us another look at its brutal action, which looks on par with what Platinum Games usually delivers, as well as some of the fantastical enemies and bosses that players will be going up against throughout the game. An <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/06/08/ninja-gaiden-4-prevew-interview-xbox-games-showcase/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox Wire preview post</a> provided even more details on the game.</p><p>It revealed that mechanical Dark Nest Terminals will be scattered throughout the levels, and players can restock items and take on optional missions to earn Ninja Coins. Players can use those Ninja Coins when they meet a character named Tyran throughout each level, who will teach them new and returning action skills.</p><p>When Ninja Gaiden 4 comes out on October 21, it will be available across PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. Like all games published by Xbox, it will be available as part of the Xbox Game Pass Catalog. A new 2D Ninja Gaiden, titled <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/ninja-gaiden-ragebound/" data-ref-id="5000-654954">Ninja Gaiden: Ragebound</a>, is also in the works and launches on July 21.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox ROG Ally Windows Handheld Revealed, Releases Holiday 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-rog-ally-windows-handheld-revealed-releases-holiday-2025/1100-6532245/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-rog-ally-windows-handheld-revealed-releases-holiday-2025.1212135/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-rog-ally-windows-handheld-revealed-releases-holiday-2025/1100-6532245/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532245">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Xbox is partnering with Asus on a Windows-based handheld with support for your Game Pass library, Steam, GOG, and other PC gaming clients. The long-rumored handheld was officially revealed during the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/xbox-games-showcase-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-6656/" data-ref-id="2900-6656">Xbox Games Showcase</a>. The ROG Xbox Ally is slated to launch Holiday 2025. No pricing details were provided, but two configurations were revealed.</p><p>Like the regular Asus ROG Ally handhelds, the "X" version is the premium model. The ROG Xbox Ally X has a black color scheme and is fitted with an AMD Ryzen Z2 Extreme chipset, 24GB RAM, and a 1TB SSD.</p><p>The base model ROG Xbox Ally is white like the Xbox Series S and has an AMD Ryzen Z2A chipset, 16GB RAM, and a 512GB SSD.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4508932-xboxrogally.png" data-ref-id="1300-4508932" data-ratio="0.56230769230769" data-width="1300" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4508932-xboxrogally.png" data-ref-id="1300-4508932"></a><figcaption>ROG Xbox Ally</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4508932-xboxrogally.png"></figure><p>Both models share the same design and form factor, which is a departure from the lineup of ROG Ally handhelds made solely by Asus. Current ROG Ally handhelds have rounded handhelds and generally look more Switch-like, whereas the ROG Xbox Ally has traditional controller grips like the PlayStation Portal.</p><p>Xbox said both editions can natively play the full Game Pass library, which means you can download any of the hundreds of titles in the PC Game Pass catalog. The ROG Xbox Ally also supports cloud streaming and remote play, so Game Pass Ultimate subscribers can stream all of the games in the Xbox Cloud Gaming service over Wi-Fi. You can also play your full Xbox Series X|S library via remote play with a Wi-Fi connection.</p><p>Since the ROG Xbox Ally is, in practice, a Windows PC with additional Xbox integration, you won't be limited to the Xbox ecosystem. All PC game clients for Windows will work on both devices, so that means you'll be able to download games from Steam, GOG, Epic Games Store, and more. And since Windows supports PS Remote Play and cloud streaming, you should be able to stream your PS5 games library, too.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Studio Announces Post-Apocalypse Game Set In Japan, Beast Of Reincarnation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-studio-announces-post-apocalypse-game-set-in-japan-beast-of-reincarnation/1100-6532249/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-studio-announces-post-apocalypse-game-set-in-japan-beast-of-reincarnation.1212129/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-studio-announces-post-apocalypse-game-set-in-japan-beast-of-reincarnation/1100-6532249/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532249">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A new title from Pokemon studio Game Freak was revealed at the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/xbox-games-showcase-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-6656/" data-ref-id="2900-6656">Xbox Games Showcase</a>--titled Beast of Reincarnation, the upcoming game is a new action RPG set in a post-apocalyptic Japan. The game, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-dev-game-freak-reveals-project-bloom-a-new-action-adventure-game/1100-6513954/" data-ref-id="1100-6513954">originally announced as "Project Bloom,"</a> is set for a 2026 release on Xbox Series X/S and PC as a day one Game Pass title.</p><p>The brief announcement trailer shows a version of Japan, in the year 4026, corrupted by blight, which was brought on by a giant monstrous creature. Beast of Reincarnation's protagonist is named Emma, an outcast marked as a "Blighted One. Gameplay footage showcases parts of her journey, punctuated with shots of samurai action, vine swinging, and epic boss battles.</p><p>In the trailer, Emma fights a variety of enemies, from massive tree-like behemoths to what appear to be robots. She is accompanied by her dog Koo, who will presumably be part of the action. Despite her outcast status, a character in the trailer states that Emma is the "blade" that will destroy the eponymous Beast of Reincarnation.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L-qZiMPsNz0" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/L-qZiMPsNz0" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The trailer's YouTube description describes the combat as "demanding" and "technical," and live commentators during the Xbox Showcase noted similarities to games like Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice and the Nioh series.</p><p>While Game Freak is, of course, best known for the mainline Pokemon games on Nintendo platforms, the Tokyo-based studio has developed several other IPs, including Tembo the Badass Elephant, Giga Wrecker, and Little Town Hero. The title was originally announced as being published by Private Division, but according to the trailer, Beast of Reincarnation is published by Fictions Inc.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight Silksong Is Launching This Year According To Microsoft]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-is-launching-this-year-according-to-microsoft/1100-6522715/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksong-is-launching-this-year-according-to-microsoft.1212126/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-is-launching-this-year-according-to-microsoft/1100-6522715/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6522715">

            
            
    


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-everything-we-know-about-team-cherrys-metroidvania/1100-6520282/" data-ref-id="1100-6520282">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> has finally made a reappearance, featuring during the announcement of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-rog-ally-windows-handheld-revealed-releases-holiday-2025/1100-6532245/" data-ref-id="1100-6532245">ROG Xbox Ally</a> handheld. Speaking after the reveal, Xbox's Sarah Bond confirmed that Silksong will be out soon, stating that it will be "available at launch and in Game Pass" when the handheld launches later this year.</p><p>This isn't the first time Microsoft has confirmed Silksong's release window. Back in 2022, Silksong featured during the Xbox Games Showcase then, with each game at the show supposedly releasing within 12 months. It was later <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-has-been-delayed/1100-6513963/" data-ref-id="1100-6513963">indefinitely delayed</a>, only surfacing again during the Nintendo Switch 2 reveal earlier this year.</p><p>First revealed more than five years ago, details on Silksong have been very hard to come by since 2019. While Team Cherry has teased <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-gets-more-enemies-in-brief-/1100-6472220/" data-ref-id="1100-6472220">enemy designs</a> and gameplay updates over the years, everything else has remained a mystery.</p><p>After appearing in the original Hollow Knight as a powerful enemy first and an ally later, Silksong stars Hornet, a princess who is both the daughter of the god-like ruler of Hallownest, the Pale King, and the spider queen of Deepnest, Herrah the Beast. The expansion-turned-sequel will allow players to wield Hornet's needle and thread across a wide variety of stages in an action-packed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-metroidvania-games/2900-4005/" data-ref-id="2900-4005">metroidvania</a>.</p><p>Silksong has currently been announced for Xbox Series X|S, PC, and Nintendo Switch 2. On Xbox and PC, Silksong will be available through Xbox Game Pass on day one.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          

                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>