<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 11:59:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega, Netflix and others will let Roblox creators monetize their major franchises]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sega-netflix-and-others-will-let-roblox-creators-monetize-their-major-franchises</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sega-netflix-and-others-will-let-roblox-creators-monetize-their-major-franchises.1244709/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">July 16, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">User generated content platform Roblox has launched a new licensing initiative to let creators build experiences based on popular franchises like Stranger Things, Squid Game, Like a Dragon, Saw, Divergent, Now You See Me, and Twilight.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Platform owner Roblox Corp said the move is part of its plan to have 10 percent of all global gaming content revenue flow through the Roblox ecosystem.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It has so far partnered with Lionsgate, Netflix, Sega, and Kodansha to make seven major franchises available for licensed use (by eligible creators) but has promised that more partners will be announced in the coming months.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Until now, licensing IP was a complex and time-consuming process. Potential licensees had to negotiate with a variety of stakeholders and submit to regular reviews, and the process could take months," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://corp.roblox.com/newsroom/2025/07/roblox-launches-new-licensing-platform-for-experiences">said the company in a statement</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Not only did rights holders struggle to discover interested creators, but the nature of the process meant that only a select group of larger studios were able to benefit. To keep pace with the iterative nature of development on Roblox, full of user-generated experiences that creators are continually evolving and updating, we recognized the need to provide creators with a flexible, simple-to-use licensing solution."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/santa-ragione-says-apple-is-delisting-wheels-of-aurelia-without-justification-" target="_self" data-discover="true">Update: Santa Ragione says Apple is delisting Wheels of Aurelia 'without justification'</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Roblox Corp explained a new License Manager enables IP holders to register and create IP licenses with their own specific usage terms. It also permits them to "proactively scan experiences for IP usage, offer licensed uses directly to creators, and automatically collect the revenue share." Creators interested in gaining access to a franchise can request a license via the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://create.roblox.com/explore/licenses">Licenses Catalog</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in the Creator Hub.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Sega offers to split revenue with Roblox creators—but others haven't been as generous">Sega offers to split revenue with Roblox creators—but others haven't been as generous</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Roblox said it intends to open the License Manager to all IP holders.&nbsp;Creators will be prohibited from accessing a license based on terms set by IP holders.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For instance, Sega claims it will only allow Roblox creators to make use of its Like a Dragon license if they have crafted experiences that attract over 1,000 daily active users (DAUs). Sega also recommends that all fan-created content based on Like a Dragon should "primarily reference the story, characters, and settings as depicted in the official Like A Dragon mainline video game series."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This includes plotlines, character arcs, and locations established within these titles. While we encourage creative expression, please make sure your works stay true to the world and lore as portrayed in these canonical entries."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/untitled" target="_self" data-discover="true">Report: Nearly 8,000 games on Steam disclose GenAI use</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Japanese publisher is offering Roblox creators who use the license a 50 percent revenue share (after platform fees) from all Robux earned through those experiences.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a generous offering compared to other license holders, with Netflix only granting creators a 15 percent revenue share on Stranger Things and Squid Game experiences—although, by contrast, the streaming giant isn't locking access to those franchises behind a minimum DAU requirement.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Roblox says creators on its platform earned $923 million in 2024 and are on track to receive over $1 billion in 2025.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sega-netflix-and-others-will-let-roblox-creators-monetize-their-major-franchises]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>