<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 03:28:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive Riftbound Spiritforged Card Reveal - Jax, Unrelenting]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/11/24/exclusive-riftbound-spiritforged-card-reveal-jax-unrelenting</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-riftbound-spiritforged-card-reveal-jax-unrelenting.1363420/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Riftbound, the League of Legends physical trading card game, has had its Origins set go live worldwide. Now, Riot Games is looking towards its second set, Spiritforged; and <em>Game Informer</em> was offered the opportunity to reveal one of its upcoming Champion cards.</p><p>Surprisingly, our chosen card wound up being one familiar to both myself and fellow Video Editor Alex Van Aken. Jax is, in League of Legends, a potential menace in the top lane. As the last weaponmaster of Icathia, he wields a lamp as his chosen implement, leaping around the battlefield and smacking foes left and right. His Champion card Jax, Unrelenting reflects his particular proclivity for weaponry.</p><p>Jax, Unrelenting is Jax's Body (aka Orange) Champion Unit, standing at 3 Might for 4 and one Body Rune. The real eye-catching text is in the bonus text, however. Jax's Weaponmaster ability allows you to Equip an existing piece of Equipment on the field to Jax for one Rune less, even if it's already attached. This makes upcoming Equipment pieces like the Long Sword a free Equip-on-entry for Jax, The Unrelenting.</p><p>The second slice of text says that when you attach an Equipment to Jax, Unrelenting, you may pay 1 to draw 1. Card draw can be a very powerful advantage in card games. This version of Jax means you're drawing deeper into your deck, finding more options, and making use of those odd bits of floating, untapped Rune power.</p><p>Jax's associated Legend, <a href="https://riftbound.leagueoflegends.com/en-us/card-gallery/#card-gallery--sfd-193-221">Grandmaster at Arms</a>, makes it easy to attach and detach Equipment as well. It seems like Jax is the Legend to go after if you want to lean into Spiritforged's introduction of Equipment. Get some early pieces on the board, fight and tussle, and then play Jax, Unrelenting to vacuum up some equipment for card draw and a giant push. I don't think anyone will want a piece of the champ after that.</p><p>The next Riftbound set Spiritforged is currently set for February 2026 in English, and December 2025 for China. Go check out the other cards being announced and revealed during this preview season <a href="https://riftbound.leagueoflegends.com/en-us/news/announcements/spiritforged-preview-season/">over here</a>.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/11/24/exclusive-riftbound-spiritforged-card-reveal-jax-unrelenting]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>