<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 13:44:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo lowers sales forecast with Switch performing 'below expectations']]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-lowers-sales-forecast-with-switch-performing-below-expectations-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-lowers-sales-forecast-with-switch-performing-below-expectations.1099497/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-lowers-sales-forecast-with-switch-performing-below-expectations-<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-template="layout" data-theme="theme2"><nav data-module="navigation" aria-label="navigation"></nav><div data-testid="article-base-body" data-template="article"><div data-component="summary"><h2>At a Glance</h2><ul><li><span data-component="icon" data-name="Circle"></span><span data-testid="summary-item-content">The Nintendo Switch has now sold 150.86 million units worldwide to close in on the all-time record held by the Nintendo DS.</span></li><li><span data-component="icon" data-name="Circle"></span><span data-testid="summary-item-content">Hardware sales fell by 30.6 percent year-over-year with the launch of the Switch 2 on the horizon. </span></li><li><span data-component="icon" data-name="Circle"></span><span data-testid="summary-item-content">Super Mario Party Jamoboree has sold 6.17 million copies since launching in October 2024.</span></li></ul></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Switch has topped 150.8 million lifetime sales but Nintendo has conceded the aging platform is performing 'below expectations.'</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2025/250204_3e.pdf">fiscal report</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for the nine months ended December 31, 2024, Nintendo explained Switch hardware sales declined by 30.6 percent year-on-year to 9.54 million units. Software sales dipped by 24.4 percent year-on-year to 123.98 million units over the same period.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That downturn resulted in consolidated net sales tumbling by 31.4 percent to 956.2 billion yen ($6.15 billion) over the past nine months. Profits fell by 41.9 percent to 237.2 billion yen ($1.5 billion).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Digging into those numbers, Nintendo said titles released during the current fiscal year delivered "steady" sales. That includes </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Super Mario Party Jamboree</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which sold 3.91 million copies and 6.17 million copies respectively.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It also benefitted from the longevity of catalog releases like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which sold 5.38 million units over the past nine months. The kart racer </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/en/finance/software/index.html">remains the best-selling Switch title of all time</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> with over 67 million lifetime sales.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Switch, however, is a console in decline after eight years on shelves and Nintendo has acknowledged that by downwardly revising its sales forecast. The company now expects the Switch to sell 11 million units by the end of the current fiscal year–down on the 12.5 million units it previously forecasted.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It has also lowered its full-year software sales forecast by 6.3 percent to 150 million units.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Nintendo highlights Switch player count with hardware and software in decline">Nintendo highlights Switch player count with hardware and software in decline</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Despite that revision, Nintendo said the Switch is "still being purchased by many people" and now boasts 129 million annual playing users. The Nintendo Switch OLED Model is currently the most popular console in the family in terms of hardware sales.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Elsewhere, Nintendo noted that digital sales fell by 29 percent year-on-year to 245.8 billion yen ($1.58 billion)–largely due to a decrease in sales of downloadable Switch software.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sales also fell by 33.9 percent year-on-year within the company's mobile and IP related business, but that decline accounts for a substantial decrease in revenue related to The Super Mario Bros. Movie.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Looking ahead, Nintendo reminded investors (as if they needed telling) </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/-shell-nintendo-finally-unveils-the-tktk-its-successor-to-the-nintendo-switch">the newly-unveiled Switch 2 is slated for launch in 2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It also confirmed it will release a number of notable first-party titles this year including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and Xenoblade</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> Chronicles X: Definitive Edition</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company now downwardly revised its consolidated forecast and expects to deliver net sales of 1.2 trillion yen ($7.7 billion) and profits of 270 billion yen ($1.73 billion) by the end of the fiscal year on March 31, 2025.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div><p>You May Also Like</p><hr></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>