<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 23:09:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Looks Like Fortnite Blitz Royale Is Sticking Around]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-looks-like-fortnite-blitz-royale-is-sticking-around/1100-6532735/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it-looks-like-fortnite-blitz-royale-is-sticking-around.1228554/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532735">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>When Epic first revealed and launched <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fortnite/" data-ref-id="5000-125765">Fortnite</a>'s popular new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnites-new-blitz-royale-mode-comes-with-a-free-skin/1100-6532511/" data-ref-id="1100-6532511">Blitz Royale mode</a> on June 17, it came with an expiration date of July 15. But it didn't take long for the company to deliver an extension.. Blitz Royale has consistently been Fortnite's most popular mode in the week since it launched, and on Wednesday, Epic updated the Fortnite API with <a href="https://x.com/FN_Assist/status/1937960260406296938" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">four additional weeks of Blitz Royale</a>. The new end date is apparently August 12.</p><p><a href="https://x.com/ShiinaBR/status/1937963962600939740" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Leakers believe</a> they already know the themes Epic will give to each of the additional weeks: Jujutsu Kaisen, Mortal Kombat, and Dragon Ball. Blitz Royale is currently having Avatar Week, which will be followed by Boss Week next Tuesday, and then TMNT Week after that. Each of these weeks will feature weapons and items related to the theme--for the current Avatar week, for example, the loot pool is full of the bending scrolls that were in standard Battle Royale during Chapter 5 Season 2, and TMNT week will bring back each of the turtles' melee weapons from Chapter 5 Season 1. </p><p>Blitz Royale is a quicker and smaller version of Fortnite's battle royale, with 32 players on a tiny map, and rounds that last under five minutes. It's a faster and furiouser version of Fortnite, and it caught on immediately. If Blitz Royale continues pulling in tons of players, it's very likely that Epic will make it a permanent mode eventually. This initial launch period may be about seeing how Blitz Royale affects the overall Fortnite ecosystem. Since all seems to be going well on that front, we expect it won't stay away long if it actually does leave on August 12.</p><p>As it is, Blitz Royale will definitely need some overhauls. For one thing, the initial storm circle is the same in every round, always cutting off the northern part of the island. Secondly, Blitz Royale deserves its own fresh map, because the current Blitz map is just a smaller version of the Reload Venture island, and that in turn was just a smaller version of the Chapter 1 OG island. We've already wasted enough of our lives fighting over Pleasant Park and Retail Row, thank you very much.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-looks-like-fortnite-blitz-royale-is-sticking-around/1100-6532735/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Museum Will Open A New Art Gallery This Fall]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-museum-will-open-a-new-art-gallery-this-fall/1100-6532734/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-museum-will-open-a-new-art-gallery-this-fall.1228503/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532734">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>This fall, visitors at the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-our-first-look-at-the-nintendo-museum/1100-6526006/" data-ref-id="1100-6526006">Nintendo Museum</a> in Japan are going to get an opportunity to catch a glimpse of history from Nintendo's five decades in the video game industry. Nintendo Museum has announced that an art gallery will be opening on September 3 featuring "a wide range of game artwork, including character illustrations and concept art."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/Museum_Nintendo/status/1937405684179693786" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">The Art Gallery will open on Wednesday, September 3rd on the 2nd floor of the Nintendo Museum Exhibition Building. Visitors can explore a wide range of game artwork, including character illustrations and concept art.</p>  — ニンテンドーミュージアム (@Museum_Nintendo) <a href="https://twitter.com/Museum_Nintendo/status/1937405684179693786?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 24, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>The announcement was light on details about what kind of artwork will be presented in the gallery, or how far back it will go. Although Nintendo became widely known in the early '80s for arcade hits like Donkey Kong, the company's first foray into gaming came in the early '70s with lightgun games. Since the launch of the Nintendo Entertainment System in North America in 1985, Nintendo has remained a major player in gaming.</p><p>The Nintendo Museum already has exhibits that celebrate the history of Nintendo's video games, as well as a selection of minigames that visitors are allowed to play. During <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/my-visit-to-the-nintendo-museum-made-my-life-flash-before-my-eyes/1100-6526764/" data-ref-id="1100-6526764">GameSpot's two-day visit to the museum in 2024</a>, Dan Ryckert noted that it "is light on text, descriptions, placards, and other traditional elements of a museum." He added that the room with fully-functional giant controllers from the Famicom, SNES, N64, and Wii Remotes was his favorite.</p><p>Nintendo Museum also has a large selection of exclusive merchandise. In response to demand from around the world, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-museum-puts-limits-on-gift-store-merch-to-discourage-scalpers/1100-6526911/" data-ref-id="1100-6526911">Nintendo Museum added limits to the merch that visitors can buy</a> in order to discourage scalpers. The museum still requires visitors to register for tickets, and <a href="https://x.com/Museum_Nintendo/status/1937405685819670914" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Nintendo also noted</a> that anyone who wishes to change their reservation for September should cancel their old reservation and reapply by the end of June.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-museum-will-open-a-new-art-gallery-this-fall/1100-6532734/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty Mobile Season 6 Is A Gundam Crossover]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-mobile-season-6-release-date-gundam/1100-6532732/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-mobile-season-6-is-a-gundam-crossover.1228485/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532732">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-mobile-2/" data-ref-id="5000-501123">Call of Duty Mobile</a> Season 6: Gundams Arrive launches next month. This new season of mobile Call of Duty features Gundam-themed operators, weapons, and rewards. A new multiplayer mode also lets players battle in Gundam mech suits.</p><div data-embed-type="toc"><p><span><strong>Table of Contents</strong> [<a data-toggle="collapse" href="#toc_list">hide</a>]</span></p><ul id="toc_list"><li><a href="#Season_6_start_date_details">Season 6 start date details</a></li><li><a href="#Battle_pass_details">Battle pass details</a></li><li><a href="#New_events">New events</a><ul><li><a href="#Gundam_events">Gundam events</a></li><li><a href="#U_S__Independence_Day">U.S. Independence Day</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#Gundam_multiplayer_LTM">Gundam multiplayer LTM</a></li><li><a href="#Gundam_bundles">Gundam bundles</a></li></ul></div><h2 dir="ltr" id="Season_6_start_date_details">Season 6 start date details</h2><p dir="ltr">Season 6: Gundams Arrive starts on July 2 at 5 PM PT / 8 PM ET. This new season includes a brand-new battle pass with both free and premium items. The Season 6 battle pass features sci-fi themed operators and weapon blueprints.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Battle_pass_details">Battle pass details</h2><p dir="ltr">The main highlight of the free battle-pass tiers is Season 6's new 3-Line Rifle, which is a new bolt-action marksman rifle. For the premium tiers, players can unlock futuristic operator skins for Misty, Atlas, and Rock Hound. Weapon blueprints are included for the PDW-57 submachine gun, BY15 shotgun, and the new 3-Line Rifle marksman rifle.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="New_events">New events</h2><h3 dir="ltr" id="Gundam_events">Gundam events</h3><p dir="ltr">Activision teases there will be several Gundam-themed events offering free seasonal rewards, including login events and check-ins. These rewards include camos, legendary blueprints, emotes, and more.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="U_S__Independence_Day">U.S. Independence Day</h3><p dir="ltr">Call of Duty will be celebrating July 4 with an event running from July 4-9, and this awards Independence Day-themed calling cards, charms, and weapon blueprints. These are available to earn for players who login and play multiplayer and battle royale matches throughout the event duration.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4521741-codm-s6-announce-007.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4521741" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4521741-codm-s6-announce-007.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4521741"></a><figcaption>4v4 Gundam duels</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4521741-codm-s6-announce-007.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Gundam_multiplayer_LTM">Gundam multiplayer LTM</h2><p dir="ltr">Season 6 adds the Gundam Team Deathmatch limited-time multiplayer mode. This is a variant of team deathmatch where players spawn in as operators themed around Gundam suits. Gundam Team Deathmatch is played in third-person as a 4v4 mode with mech vs mech Gundam duels. Operators can use the mech suits to dodge, sprint, and activate vertical jets. Instead of normal loadout weapons, each Gundam comes with its own special abilities and weapons.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Gundam_bundles">Gundam bundles</h2><p dir="ltr">Additionally, the in-game shop will feature Gundam-themed operators and weapon blueprints in the series draws. Each Gundam operator skin comes with its own finishing move plus a unique lobby screen and animation. Gundams can also be displayed in a player's personal safe house.</p><p dir="ltr">In other news, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-4-reloaded-start-date-and-details/1100-6532532/">Call of Duty Season 4 Reloaded</a> is arriving soon to Black Ops 6 and Warzone. The big update will include more DLC weapons, multiplayer maps, and Resurgence Ranked Play for Warzone.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-mobile-season-6-release-date-gundam/1100-6532732/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jack Black Returns For Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4 And Plays Two Characters This Time]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/jack-black-returns-for-tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-and-plays-two-characters-this-time/1100-6532730/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jack-black-returns-for-tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-and-plays-two-characters-this-time.1228392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532730">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Actor Jack Black had a role in 2020's Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 1 + 2, and he's coming back in Pro Skater 3 + 4 to reprise that character and pull double duty by voicing another one as well.</p><p>Black will play Officer "Dick <em>and </em>Dick's UK-born twin, Constable Richard. Both characters are villains, of sorts, meant to represent "the man" trying to ruin everyone's fun by enforcing rules.</p><p>Richard Ennvee (see what they did there?) was mocked in his childhood for being a "poser," so he vowed to get revenge by becoming "the long arm of the law," according to Activision.</p><p>Game director Kurt Tillmanns told <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/jack-black-tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-officer-dick-1236440201/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Variety</a> that Activision wanted to carry the character forward to Pro Skater 3 + 4 and "tell a little bit more" of his story, while also expanding things to tell the story of his UK twin. For Constable Richard, Black does a British accent and appears in the London level. Check out the trailer below to get a closer look at Black's two characters.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l181WSin3g4" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/l181WSin3g4" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>In other news, Tony Hawk himself has partnered with Taco Bell to create his own special luxe box that includes <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/taco-bell-themed-tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-dlc-is-coming-and-we-hope-youre-hungry/1100-6532708/" data-ref-id="1100-6532708">DLC codes for Pro Skater 3 + 4 in-game items. </a></p><p>Pro Skater 3 + 4 releases on July 11, and as an Activision game, it's coming to Xbox Game Pass at launch. The game can also be purchased outright on Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, PS4, PS5, PC, Switch, and Switch 2.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/jack-black-returns-for-tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-and-plays-two-characters-this-time/1100-6532730/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE 2K25 DLC Adds Shaq, Tyrese Haliburton, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wwe-2k25-dlc-adds-shaq-tyrese-haliburton-and-more/1100-6532729/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wwe-2k25-dlc-adds-shaq-tyrese-haliburton-and-more.1228359/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532729">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The second DLC for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/wwe-2k25-review/1900-6418343/" data-ref-id="1900-6418343">WWE 2K25</a>, the Dunk &amp; Destruction Pack, is out today, and it's bringing three NBA superstars into the game: Shaquille O'Neal, the Indiana Pacers' Tyrese Haliburton, and New York Knicks player Jalen Brunson.</p><p>O'Neal's connection to wrestling goes back three decades to a handful of guest appearances in WCW, as well as a one-time appearance backstage at TNA. Shaq also participated in the André the Giant Memorial Battle Royal at WrestleMania 32 and he had a tag-team match against Cody Rhodes during the latter's stint in AEW.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UkFPNjSgW1k" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="30">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UkFPNjSgW1k?start=30" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Neither Haliburton nor Brunson have had wrestling matches in WWE, but they did have a confrontation with each other on WWE Smackdown. Haliburton also had a breakout performance in this year's NBA playoffs before he suffered an Achilles rupture in game seven of the NBA Finals.</p><p>The other two additions in the Dunk &amp; Destruction Pack are TNA legend Abyss--who is currently working backstage as a producer for WWE--and WWE hall of fame member The Great Khali. WWE 2K25 is also adding new MyFACTION content including the Amethyst Token Market and a new Bloodline card pack that will debut on June 26. A robotic version of Cody Rhodes, Firefly Funhouse Alexa Bliss, Alexa's Lily Doll, and Nikki Cross '23 will be added for players who bought either the WrestleMania 41 Pack or The Bloodline Edition.</p><p>According to the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wwe-2k25-season-pass-will-add-80s-legends-ex-aew-stars-and-nba-players/1100-6529931/" data-ref-id="1100-6529931">WWE 2K25 season pass roadmap</a>, there are three more DLC packs to be released. The Fearless pack will arrive next month with ECW legend New Jack, NXT's Jordynne Grace, Penta, Bull Nakano, and an unannounced celebrity guest. An Attitude Era Superstars pack will follow in September with D’Lo Brown, Billy Gunn, Road Dogg, Victoria, and Mark Henry. The final WWE 2K25 release will be the Saturday Night's Main Event pack in November, with '80s legends Jesse Ventura, Mr. Wonderful, Tito Santana, Junk Yard Dog, and Sid Justice.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wwe-2k25-dlc-adds-shaq-tyrese-haliburton-and-more/1100-6532729/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>