<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.gamedeveloper.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.gamedeveloper.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:17:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Scopely confirms it used generative AI to advertise Star Trek Fleet Command]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/scopely-confirms-it-used-generative-ai-to-advertise-star-trek-fleet-command</link>
            <guid>1427923</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">February 6, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>1 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Screenshot via Game Developer</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Mobile publisher Scopely has been using generative AI assets to advertise </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Star Trek Fleet Command</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company, which is owned by Saudi state-backed investor Savvy Games Group and last year </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/pokemon-go-and-niantic-s-game-business-is-being-sold-to-the-saudi-state">spent $3.5 billion to acquire Pokemon Go</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, has confirmed it created at least one advertising asset&nbsp;for Instagram using an unnamed generative AI tool.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer spotted the advertisement last week and approached Scopely for comment. In response, the company said its marketing teams have been experimenting with AI tools and confirmed the ad was AI-generated.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our dedicated creative studio delivers hundreds of assets each month as we continuously explore new ways to engage players and fans of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Star Trek Fleet Command</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">," said a company spokesperson. "As is common across modern marketing teams, we regularly test and experiment with AI-enabled tools. This specific asset is no longer running, as we routinely refresh creative in market."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/gdc-festival-of-gaming-unveils-featured-speakers-for-new-luminaries-speaker-series" target="_self" data-discover="true">GDC Festival of Gaming unveils featured speakers for new Luminaries Speaker Series</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Star Trek Fleet Command</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is an officially licensed free-to-play title currently available on PC, Mac, and mobile.&nbsp;The advertisement showed what is quite obviously an AI-generated person wandering through a futuristic vessel. As shown in the featured image above, the assets used in the advertisement lack quality and cohesion.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There was no disclosure informing users the advert had been AI-generated. Despite that, many people seemed to clock on, with a number of Instagram users deriding the advertisement in the comments section.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Generative AI tools remain divisive within the game industry. The latest State of the Game Industry survey found that while </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/one-third-of-game-workers-use-generative-ai-but-half-think-it-s-bad-for-the-industry">36 percent of game workers are using the tools</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, including many within marketing departments, over half believe the technology is having a negative impact on the industry.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/scopely-confirms-it-used-generative-ai-to-advertise-star-trek-fleet-command]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard workers ratify union contract, Ghost of Yotei soars, and has Yves Guillemot outstayed his welcome at Ubisoft? - Patch Notes #39]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blizzard-workers-ratify-union-contract-ghost-of-yotei-soars-and-has-yves-guillemot-outstayed-his-welcome-at-ubisoft-patch-notes-39</link>
            <guid>1427905</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">February 6, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>5 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Artwork via Blizzard / Logo via Patch Notes</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Wouldn't you know it? There is a maelstrom of news to sift through this week, but before we plunge into the headlines I wanted to take a moment to GUSH about </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cairn</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, a new video game from indie studio The Game Bakers (of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Furi</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Haven</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> fame) that might be one of this year's very best.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a bold statement to make this early on, but I'm going to stand by it. I sat down with the survival climber at 8pm on Saturday thinking I'd stick with it for an hour or two before slapping on a movie and munching my way through a bag of delectable crisps (chips, for our American readers) I had saved for such an occasion.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Hard cut to 2am and there I am still glued to the screen. Palms sweaty. Eyes blurring. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cairn's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">protagonist, Aava, straining every sinew in her body as she clings to a sheer face on the side of Mount Kami. It has been minutes since I secured my last piton—the only thing standing between Aava and oblivion.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/four-tips-for-pitching-your-game-to-investors-and-publishers" target="_self" data-discover="true">Four tips for pitching your game to investors and publishers</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It might as well have been a lifetime. Any false move now would almost certainly result in death, sending Aava crashing into the mountain below at breakneck pace. The only way is up. This struggle is my salvation.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The higher you climb, the more </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cairn</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> turns into a brilliantly tense battle of wills. The question 'why am I doing this?' might cross your mind on more than one occasion, but therein lies the magic. There is victory in conquering even the smallest peak. Imagine what awaits at the summit.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Okay, okay. I'll rein myself in before this becomes a full-blown review. Did I mention we have some news to get through?</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="MachineGames asking more staff to move to full-time office work"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/machinegames-asking-more-staff-to-move-to-full-time-office-work">MachineGames asking more staff to move to full-time office work</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via GamesIndustry.biz // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">MachineGames, the Microsoft subsidiary behind Wolfenstein and Indiana Jones, is pulling employees back into the office. According to studio director Jerk Gustafsson, leadership is now required to be on-site five days per week to drive efficiency and collaboration. The hope is that will set a precedent for others to follow. "We are moving more and more towards five days a week," added Gustafsson. Given Ubisoft's recently-announced RTO mandate has seemingly gone down like a lead balloon internally, you have to wonder what MachineGames staffers make of the shift.&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Ghost of Yotei outperforms Ghost of Tsushima to bolster Sony financials"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ghost-of-yotei-outperforms-ghost-of-tsushima-to-bolster-sony-financials">Ghost of Yotei outperforms Ghost of Tsushima to bolster Sony financials</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via Game Developer // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Sucker Punch's soaring sequel </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ghost of Yotei</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> exceeded the expectations of Sony after outperforming its predecessor </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ghost of Tsushuma</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> during its first three months on shelves. The PlayStation maker shared the news in its latest fiscal report, where it also confirmed the PlayStation 5 has now sold-in over 92 million units worldwide.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-probablymonsters-lays-off-devs-while-unveiling-nazi-hunting-game" target="_self" data-discover="true">Report: ProbablyMonsters lays off devs while unveiling Nazi hunting game</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="No, NetEase isn't suddenly ditching generative AI"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/kerrblimey.bsky.social/post/3mdzzmptmy22c">No, NetEase isn't suddenly ditching generative AI</a></h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via NetEase //</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> File this one under 'news that didn't really happen.' Earlier this week, NetEase described widespread reports that it had shuttered a generative AI research division and told staff to abandon the tech as "false." The rumor spread after veteran designer Goichi Suda told Eurogamer the company was ditching generative AI altogether. Suda's studio, Grasshopper Manufacture, is currently owned by Netease. That claim was quickly quashed by multiple Netease representatives. "The situation described did not occur, and we have not published any related policies," said one spokesperson.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Steam Machine pricing and shipping details delayed due to RAM shortage"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/valve-delays-steam-machine-and-steam-frame-due-to-ram-shortage">Steam Machine pricing and shipping details delayed due to RAM shortage</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via Game Developer // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Do you remember what life was like before the RAM wars? That's a sentence our descendants might one day utter as they scamper through the apocalypse. Until then, we have to contend with the fact that the ongoing memory and storage shortage—driven by rampant investments into generative AI—might force us to pay more and wait longer for Valve's upcoming hardware slate. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://aftermath.site/steam-machine-frame-delayed-ai-data/">Oh, and shout out to Aftermath for this whopper of a headline when covering the news</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/us-based-tariffs-impact-38-of-business-leaders" target="_self" data-discover="true">38 percent of game industry leaders are feeling the impact of U.S. tariffs</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Games for Change is coming to London"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.videogamesindustrymemo.com/p/games-for-change-is-coming-to-london">Games for Change is coming to London</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via VGIM // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Games for Change is heading to the Big Smoke for a one-day event on April 15, 2026, dedicated to interrogating how video games can be a powerful force for good. The London event will unite 150 people from the world of video games, business, and politics. There'll be talks, panels, roundtables, workshops, and more. Could be worth a look if that sounds like your cup of tea.&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Ubisoft union representatives call for resignation of CEO Yves Guillemot"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-union-representatives-call-for-resignation-of-ceo-yves-guillemot">Ubisoft union representatives call for resignation of CEO Yves Guillemot</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via Game Developer // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Ubisoft is (still) in revolt. Ahead of an impending international strike called by five unions across France, two union representatives have implored long-serving CEO Yves Guillemot to head for the exit in order to restore an ounce of trust between workers and management. They feel it might be impossible for Ubisoft, which recently announced more layoffs and studio closures, to regain the trust of its employees without a change in personnel at the very top.&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="UK co-development house Sumo Digital announces redundancies"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/uk-co-development-house-sumo-digital-announces-redundancies">UK co-development house Sumo Digital announces redundancies</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via GamesIndustry.biz //</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> UK co-development specialist Sumo Digital has confirmed yet another round of redundancies. The Tencent-owned company said it must adapt its business to remain "resilient" amid ongoing instability across the video game industry. The news came around 18 months after the company laid off 15 percent of its workforce.&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="QA workers at Blizzard ratify union contract with Microsoft"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/qa-workers-at-blizzard-ratify-union-contract-with-microsoft">QA workers at Blizzard ratify union contract with Microsoft</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via Game Developer //</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> After years of negotiations, a group of QA workers at Blizzard Albany and Austin rated a union contract with Microsoft that delivers wage increases, generative AI protections, crediting provisions, disability accommodations, and much more. One union member said the contract makes it easier to see a "real, long-term career" at the company.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blizzard-workers-ratify-union-contract-ghost-of-yotei-soars-and-has-yves-guillemot-outstayed-his-welcome-at-ubisoft-patch-notes-39]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>