<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 19:38:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk: Edgerunners 2 Is A Standalone Sequel Series Coming To Netflix]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/07/cyberpunk-edgerunners-2-is-a-standalone-sequel-series-coming-to-netflix</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-edgerunners-2-is-a-standalone-sequel-series-coming-to-netflix.1237491/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>A standalone follow-up to Netflix’s 2022 acclaimed animated series<a href="https://gameinformer.com/2020/06/25/anime-cyberpunk-edgerunners-headed-to-netflix"><em> Cyberpunk: Edgerunners</em></a><em> </em>has been confirmed. Dubbed simply <em>Cyberpunk: Edgerunners 2</em>, the upcoming anime features a fresh story and a new director.&nbsp;</p><p>Announced during a behind-the-scenes panel with <em>Edgerunners’</em> creators and cast during Anime Expo in Los Angeles over the weekend, <em>Cyberpunk: Edgerunners 2</em> sees CD Projekt Red and Studio Trigger rekindle their partnership to bring the sequel series to Netflix. The original <em>Edgerunners</em> serves as a prequel to <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/cyberpunk-2077/cyberpunk-2077-review-a-wild-time-in-night-city">Cyberpunk 2077</a>, though it is unclear when this follow-up will occur and if it will feature any returning characters. Check out the teaser trailer for <em>Edgerunners 2</em> below (<strong>but beware of spoilers for the first series</strong>).</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HdwAiyfrMO8"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HdwAiyfrMO8" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>The panel also revealed prolific animator Kai Ikarashi as <em>Edgerunners 2</em>’s director, taking the mantle from the previous series’ director, Hiroyuki Imaishi. The show is currently in production but does not have a release window.</p><p>“David’s story might be over, but there’s plenty more to discover in Night City," said Bartosz Sztybor, <em>Cyberpunk: Edgerunners 2 </em>showrunner, story writer, and producer, in a press release. "And to again have the legendary animation studio Trigger along for the ride makes us at CD Projekt Red so excited to introduce a raw, real chronicle of redemption and revenge, something unlike what we’ve done before."</p><p>In addition to Sztybor, the returning production crew includes lead character designer Kanno Ichigo and screenplay writer Masahiko Otsuka. The voice cast has not been revealed.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/07/cyberpunk-edgerunners-2-is-a-standalone-sequel-series-coming-to-netflix]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>