<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:06:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK union IWGB Game Workers launches manifesto after topping 1,500 members]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/uk-union-iwgb-game-workers-launches-manifesto-after-topping-1-500-members</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/uk-union-iwgb-game-workers-launches-manifesto-after-topping-1-500-members.1025160/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/uk-union-iwgb-game-workers-launches-manifesto-after-topping-1-500-members<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via IWGB Game Workers</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">UK trade union IWGB Game Workers has expanded to over 1,500 members. Co-founder Austin Kelmore </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/austinkelmore.com/post/3l7sfff5r462j">shared the news on Bluesky</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and explained the worker-led organization has "grown an incredible amount" over the past year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The union has marked the occasion by </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gameworkers.co.uk/manifesto/">launching a new manifesto</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to outline its vision for a better video game industry, and explained it will continue fighting for worker rights.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We envision a future where job insecurity, long unpaid hours, and inadequate compensation are a thing of the past," reads the manifesto.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">IWGB said it intends to fight for a future in which all workers across the game industry have the power to transform their workplace and impact the decision-making process; feel safe and secure in their role; have the tools and knowledge to push back against harmful practices; and are able to work free from harassment and discrimination.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Its newly-launched manifesto claims that vision will be realised by leaning on five core pillars: democracy, solidarity and care, taking action, education, and equality and justice.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"IWGB Game Workers is a union for all workers in the UK games industry and our members come from a huge variety of backgrounds. In order to achieve our mission, we must find common ground and take action on similar issues, although the details of our campaigns and direct action may differ from workplace to workplace," it continues.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For IWGB, finding common ground means collectively working towards achievable goals such as ending reliance on overtime, widespread union recognition, improved baseline pay and an end to the gender pay gap, and contractual protections that shield workers against "firing without cause or careless redundancy measures."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Developers across the industry continue to join unions like IWGB Game Workers or form their own cohorts with the help of organizations like the CWA to find ways of securing their future in the face of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/keyword/layoffs">rampant layoffs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and other harmful practices.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Earlier this year, we </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/corporate-kryptonite-developers-and-reps-discuss-the-power-of-game-industry-unions">spoke with a group of union representatives and members</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to learn more about the value of collective action in a titanic industry that's crumbling under its own weight.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>