<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 19:44:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Legends: Z-A's Mega Dimension DLC Adds Another Mega Evolution For Lucario]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-legends-z-as-mega-dimension-dlc-adds-another-mega-evolution-for-lucario/1100-6536641/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1370752</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536641">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A handful of new Mega-Evolved Pokemon are making their debut in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/pokemon-legends-z-a/" data-ref-id="5000-619901">Pokemon Legends: Z-A</a>'s upcoming <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-legends-z-a-dlc-is-coming-really-soon-brings-new-mega-evolutions-and-donuts/1100-6535993/" data-ref-id="1100-6535993">Mega Dimension DLC</a>, and ahead of the expansion's launch, The Pokemon Company has revealed another new one: a second Mega Evolution for Lucario.</p><p>Mega Lucario Z marks the game's first Z Mega Evolution--a new kind of Mega-Evolved form that has a shorter cooldown period, but depletes Mega Energy much more quickly. According to the official <a href="https://www.pokemon.com/us/pokemon-news/mega-lucario-z-debuts-in-pokemon-legends-z-a-mega-dimension" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Pokemon website</a>, "Pokemon that undergo Z Mega Evolution require less time to fire off moves after receiving the orders from their Trainer, but they also burn through their Mega Power very quickly, making them less suited for long battles."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V_UkrLROjkA" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/V_UkrLROjkA" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Like the original Mega Lucario, Mega Lucario Z is a steel and fighting type. Where this form differs, however, is in its defense and speed stats. As the official Pokemon website explains, "While Mega Lucario concentrates its aura into a destructive force, Mega Lucario Z uses it to surround its entire body, cloaking itself to increase its defense, flexibility, and agility."</p><p>It's unclear how many other Pokemon will be able to undergo Z Mega Evolution, but we've already gotten a look at several new Mega-Evolved forms coming in the Mega Dimension DLC. In addition to Mega Raichu X and Mega Raichu Y, the DLC will introduce Mega Evolutions for Baxcalibur, Chimecho, and the mythical Pokemon Zeraora.</p><p>Pokemon Legends: Z-A's Mega Dimension DLC launches on December 10 and costs $30. The expansion takes players to an alternate dimension known as Hyperspace Lumiose, where they'll encounter Pokemon not normally available in the base game, including wild Pokemon that are over level 100.</p><p>In the meantime, Pokemon Legends: Z-A's third Ranked Battle season is underway until December 17. Players who hit Rank S before the season ends will receive a Mega Stone for Chestnaught. A new Mystery Gift is also now available. All players can claim a free Mewtwonite X and Mewtwonite Y, which will unlock a new side quest that leads to an encounter with the legendary Pokemon Mewtwo.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-legends-z-as-mega-dimension-dlc-adds-another-mega-evolution-for-lucario/1100-6536641/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney's Possible New CEO Wants To Do More With Gaming - Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disneys-possible-new-ceo-wants-to-do-more-with-gaming-report/1100-6536640/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1370746</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536640">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A new report has shed more light on the CEO succession plans at Disney, with a story from <a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/media/disney-bob-iger-next-ceo-f571257c?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=AWEtsqcAnvO9HkSwOq6dtHvI9PgJs3zhb49bj_LauaFJs14tv8lhB61GX4WPPBJja20%3D&amp;gaa_ts=692f2221&amp;gaa_sig=5rTkrqo_jsKcEoMTYLBST2cadphurZq06o0aS9vWQa9F-lFkDGUUH5KOtfmQmf5ojqy4aIYuQjsxv9Dmruz0-g%3D%3D" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Wall Street Journal</a> saying leading candidate Josh D'Amaro wants to focus more on gaming. The same report also suggested that Electronic Arts CEO Andrew Wilson is not going to get the job.</p><p>It was previously reported that Disney's board considered external candidates to take over for Bob Iger, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-ceo-reportedly-in-the-mix-to-be-the-next-disney-boss/1100-6527707/" data-ref-id="1100-6527707">including Wilson</a>. But the new report said Disney is likely to choose an internal candidate. Wilson, for his part, is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/unpacking-eas-55-billion-sale-to-go-private-what-does-it-all-mean/1100-6535168/" data-ref-id="1100-6535168">staying on with EA amidst the company's $55 billion sale. </a></p><p>The new Disney CEO could be D'Amaro, who is currently the current head of Disney Experiences--a sprawling unit that covers theme parks, consumer products, cruise ships, and video games. The WSJ report said D'Amaro--who is "widely considered" to be named the next CEO--wants to give video games "a bigger role at the company." The report said D'Amaro is also looking to integrate "gaming technology" into Disney's creative processes. No further details were divulged, however.</p><p>Disney already uses Epic's Unreal technology for filmmaking, with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/see-how-star-wars-the-mandalorian-used-fortnite-en/1100-6473958/" data-ref-id="1100-6473958">The Mandalorian employing the Fortnite tech</a> to project scenes onto LED screens surrounding the physical set.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gUnxzVOs3rk" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/gUnxzVOs3rk" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>D'Amaro is already making moves at Disney in regards to gaming. He spearheaded Disney's $1.5 billion investment into Epic Games for a future Fortnite collaboration and has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-explains-why-its-fortnite-deal-is-so-important-we-have-to-adapt/1100-6526831/" data-ref-id="1100-6526831">previously discussed why gaming is so important to Disney.</a></p><p>D'Amaro said Walt Disney himself was an "adventurer" and a "risk-taker," going on to say what Disney is now trying to achieve through Fortnite is an extension of that spirit.</p><p>"We should never rest on past success. We should always look for the next big idea, the next big challenge," he said. "If we'd always relied on what worked in the past, the Walt Disney Company might not exist today. As consumer preferences continue to shift, we have to adapt, or we are going to be left behind."</p><p>Characters and content from Disney's Pixar, Marvel, Star Wars, and Avatar brands, among others, will be represented in Fortnite. Disney and Epic have yet to officially unveil any specific projects in Fortnite tied to Disney, but many are hoping to see some kind of "virtual Disney World."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yf2bRcSIUsE" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Yf2bRcSIUsE" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>For more, be sure read GameSpot's rundown of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-fortnite-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6534455/" data-ref-id="1100-6534455">everything we know about the Disney x Fortnite project.</a></p><p>Disney was at one time a bigger player in the world of video games, as the company had its own dedicated internal gaming division with Disney Interactive Studios. Disney also operated the once-popular Disney Infinity "toys-to-life" brand, but it also shuttered. Today, Disney's efforts in gaming mainly involve licensing its brands to other companies. In 2019, <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/general-news/bob-iger-disney-isnt-particularly-good-at-publishing-games-1183088/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Iger spoke candidly about Disney's struggles</a> making and publishing games internally, admitting, "We haven't been particularly good..."</p><p>Disney does, however, do some internal game production and development within the Disney Experiences team. Right now, the company has <a href="https://www.disneycareers.com/en/category/gaming-and-interactive-jobs/391/8221696/1" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">four open positions for video games</a>, including multiple producer roles and a pair of engineering jobs.</p><p>As for Iger, he has said he plans to leave Disney at the end of 2026, and many are speculating his replacement could be named early next year. As many may recall, Iger retired at the end of 2021, but came back in November 2022 after his replacement, Bob Chapek, was dismissed amid multiple controversies.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disneys-possible-new-ceo-wants-to-do-more-with-gaming-report/1100-6536640/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 PC Install Size Is Now 85% Smaller, But Not Automatically--Here's How To Free Up Space]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-pc-install-size-is-now-85-smaller-but-not-automatically-heres-how-to-free-up-space/1100-6536644/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1370743</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536644">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2025-12-02T10:20:49-0800">December 2, 2025 at 10:20AM PST</time></p></section>
    


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container" data-in-content-placements="[{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-incontent-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:1,&quot;minElements&quot;:2},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:4,&quot;minElements&quot;:5}]},{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-banner-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:7,&quot;minElements&quot;:8},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:10,&quot;minElements&quot;:11},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:13,&quot;minElements&quot;:14}]}]">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/helldivers-2/" data-ref-id="5000-589428">Helldivers 2</a> on PC just got a whole lot smaller, with developer Arrowhead Studios announcing a new, "slim" version of the game that reduces the game's install size by 131GB.</p><p dir="ltr">Fans on PC have long complained about the PC version's huge install size (and other <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-prioritizing-patches-every-two-weeks-to-reduce-critical-bug-count/1100-6535835/" data-ref-id="1100-6535835">technichal issues</a>), which since the game's launch in 2024 has ballooned to 154GB. That's much larger than the close-to-22GB size of the console versions.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QQPp9ZCgrP8" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QQPp9ZCgrP8" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Arrowhead stated in a new <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/553850/announcements/detail/491583942944621372" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog post</a> its long-term goal has always been to reduce the PC install size, but that now, with help from Nixxes Software, that goal has become a reality "much sooner than expected." Helldivers 2 on PC now only takes up 23GB--an 85% size reduction.</p><p dir="ltr">Users on PC who play Helldivers 2 on an HDD may experience slightly increased load times of a few seconds with this change, according to Arrowhead. The studio previously said it believed removing duplicate data on PC (which contributed to the game's huge install size) could potentially greatly increase load times for HDD players. Arrowhead said it now has data to prove that's not the case, as the majority of Helldivers 2's load times are due to level generation rather than asset loading.</p><p dir="ltr">There is, however, one catch to Helldivers 2's new, much smaller size. Players who want to free up space on their drive will need to opt in to a new "beta" version of Helldivers 2 on Steam, after which the game will update and its file size will be reduced. Below is a step-by-step guide on how to enable it.</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Find Helldivers 2 in your Steam library and right click</li><li dir="ltr">Select Properties from the drop down menu</li><li dir="ltr">Select the Betas tab</li><li dir="ltr">In the Beta Participation drop down list, select "prod_slim"</li><li dir="ltr">Close the dialog box and Helldivers 2 will update to the new version</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Arrowhead stated that once players using the beta version confirm there are no issues present, the slim version will become the default. For a limited time after that, players will be able to opt in to the legacy version if need be. However, given that there are only "very minor differences in loading times" between each version, Arrowhead will not continue to support the legacy version long term, as it would add "extra burden" to the development team.</p><p dir="ltr">Alongside the file-size reduction on PC, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/helldivers-2-python-commandos-warbond-all-skins-guns-and-rewards/2900-7282/" data-ref-id="2900-7282">Helldivers 2's new Python Commando Warbond is also live</a>, adding a flame-spewing drone, minigun, chainsword, and more for Super Earth's defenders to add to their arsenal. The Warbond was delayed in order for Arrowhead to better start addressing various bugs and technical concerns players have had with Helldivers 2, including the game's file size.</p><p dir="ltr">In other Helldivers news, Sony's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-movie-lands-fast-furious-director/1100-6536624/" data-ref-id="1100-6536624">Helldivers film just found a director in Justin Lin</a>, known for his work on the Fast and Furious film franchise.</p>
  
                        
        
    
    
                                  </div>


          
  
        <div data-merchant-service-api-link="https://www.gamespot.com/merchantapi/offer/?gameid=589428"><div><p>
      There are currently no available deals
    </p></div><p>GameSpot may get a commission from retail offers.</p></div>  
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-pc-install-size-is-now-85-smaller-but-not-automatically-heres-how-to-free-up-space/1100-6536644/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shovel Knight Dev's Next Game Is "Make Or Break," Needs To Sell 200,000 Copies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/shovel-knight-devs-next-game-is-make-or-break-needs-to-sell-200000-copies/1100-6536639/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1370740</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536639">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/mina-the-hollower/" data-ref-id="5000-556845">Mina the Hollower</a>, the next game from the creators of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/shovel-knight/" data-ref-id="5000-175270">Shovel Knight</a>, is "make-or-break" for indie developer Yacht Club Games, according to studio head and co-founder Sean Velasco.</p><p dir="ltr">In a new <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-02/creator-of-hit-game-shovel-knight-is-at-make-or-break-moment?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc2NDY4MDU4MywiZXhwIjoxNzY1Mjg1MzgzLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJUNk41RDBLR0NURlkwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.tTCDzLvXeRacM9mzJfRv3juJV7WGiMAKvYS8DWRQBFs&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloomberg</a> interview, Velasco said in order for Yacht Club Games to remain independent, Mina the Hollower needs to be a success, and if it could sell 200,000 copies, "that would be really, really great." The studio recently underwent layoffs and put a second in-the-works project on hold until Mina the Hollower releases.</p><p dir="ltr">"It's make-or-break for sure," Velasco said. "If we sold 500,000 copies, then we would be golden. If we sold even 200,000, that would be really, really great. If we sold, like, 100,000, that's not so good."</p><p dir="ltr">Originally slated to release in October, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/shovel-knight-devs-next-game-mina-the-hollower-delayed-but-not-for-long/1100-6535260/" data-ref-id="1100-6535260">Mina the Hollower underwent an indefinite last-minute delay</a> just a few weeks prior to launch and currently does not have a new release date.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ns7FkgskFGw" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Ns7FkgskFGw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Velasco told Bloomberg the delay happened in order for Yacht Club to improve on various elements within the game that were only recently identified. At the time of the delay, the studio said it "wasn't a major delay" and was to done in order to "apply some final polish and balancing to make the game truly shine." The studio said it didn't want to announce a new release date until the game was submitted to platform holders.</p><p dir="ltr">It was only in 2024 that the entire studio shifted to work on Mina the Hollower, a top-down Zelda-like with Game Boy-era visuals, with the studio having previously been split into two teams. One team worked on Mina while the other worked on an unannounced 3D Shovel Knight sequel, according to Bloomberg.</p><p dir="ltr">Yacht Club released its debut Shovel Knight, a throwback platformer starring a knight that wielded a shovel, to great success in 2014. The character struck a chord with players, and Shovel Knight even received an official Amiibo from Nintendo and was included in Super Smash Bros. Ultimate as an assist trophy.</p><p dir="ltr">The studio spent the years after Shovel Knight's release crafting various expansions and spin-offs. Yacht Club's most recent release was 2022's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/shovel-knight-dig/" data-ref-id="5000-501664">Shovel Knight Dig</a>, developed in collaboration with Nitrome.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/shovel-knight-devs-next-game-is-make-or-break-needs-to-sell-200000-copies/1100-6536639/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>