<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 16:22:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Acknowledge WWE 2K25 On Switch 2 Later This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/01/acknowledge-wwe-2k25-on-switch-2-later-this-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/acknowledge-wwe-2k25-on-switch-2-later-this-month.1232994/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>WWE 2K25 is heading to Switch 2 later this month. This marks the series' first appearance on a Nintendo platform since WWE 2K18 in 2017.</p><p>2K states the Switch 2 version of WWE’s latest wrestling sim will feature all the same game modes as its PlayStation, Xbox, and PC brethren. WWE 2K25 centers on The Bloodline and features a new Showcase mode highlighting the prominent members of the Anoaʻi/Maivia wrestling dynasty, including The Rock, Roman Reigns, Yokozuna, and more.&nbsp;</p><p>The game features a new mode called The Island, a new hub filled with quests and mini-games as players compete to earn a WWE contract. WWE 2K25 features new stipulations, including Bloodline Rules and the Underground Match, as well as the introduction of intergender gameplay across all match types. You can see the Switch 2 version in action in the trailer below, and check out some screenshots in the gallery underneath.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q0KlzGD9qz4"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q0KlzGD9qz4" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Like the other versions, WWE 2K25 comes in three editions: A Standard version for $69.99, the special Deadman Edition for $99.99, and the Bloodline Edition for $129.99. You can read what each edition has to offer on the game’s <a href="https://wwe.2k.com/2k25/buy/?release=wwe-2k25-the-bloodline-edition&amp;platform=nintendo-switch-2&amp;medium=digital">website</a>.</p><p>In my review of WWE 2K25, I scored the game an 8.25 out of 10, saying, “Although it’s the only real game in town, WWE 2K25 retains its title as the best and most substantial pro wrestling sim fans can buy.” You can read the full review <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/wwe-2k25/banger-after-banger">here</a>. &nbsp;You can also keep up with every Switch 2 game launching in 2025 with our complete <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/05/29/2025-nintendo-switch-2-game-release-schedule">release calendar</a>.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/01/acknowledge-wwe-2k25-on-switch-2-later-this-month]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Timmy Turner And The Fairly Odd Parents Join The Nicktoons & The Dice Of Destiny Roster]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/07/01/timmy-turner-and-the-fairly-odd-parents-join-the-nicktoons-the-dice-of-destiny</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/timmy-turner-and-the-fairly-odd-parents-join-the-nicktoons-the-dice-of-destiny-roster.1232958/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><em>Game Informer </em>can exclusively reveal the latest Nickelodeon character joining the roster of <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/nicktoons-the-dice-of-destiny">Nicktoons &amp; The Dice of Destiny</a>, and it's none other than Timmy Turner and his fairly odd (god)parents! Entering the fantasy fray as a Wizard-class character, Timmy (finally) has his own wand and will be slinging spells alongside Wanda and Cosmo in this real-time action-RPG that can be played solo or with up to three other players.&nbsp;</p><p>Alongside the reveal of Timmy, <em>Game Informer </em>also has your first look at how he plays in Nicktoons &amp; The Dice of Destiny, with a new gameplay trailer that showcases his various abilities and more.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Check out the Timmy Turner reveal trailer for yourself below:&nbsp;</strong></p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bqhGtMBEw0c"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bqhGtMBEw0c" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>"One kid, two fairies, and a lot of chaos," a description of Timmy Turner reads. "Timmy Turner casts himself into the quest with Cosmo and Wanda at his side."&nbsp;</p><p>As you can see in the trailer above, Timmy Turner is a Wizard, and his gameplay is all about casting spells, some of which utilize his fairy godparents.&nbsp;</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="a09f9539-309b-422d-ab2e-2e003f0e02f9" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	






</article>
<p><strong>Here's a look at all of Timmy Turner's abilities in Nicktoons &amp; The Dice of Destiny:&nbsp;</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Elemental Wall </strong>– Summons a random elemental wall of Fire, Lightning, or Ice that deals damage and knocks enemies backward with a satisfying poof.</li><li><strong>Mushroom Rain</strong> – Opens a sparkly portal that drops enchanted mushrooms from the sky. Each one smacks enemies for damage and randomly applies poison, burn, or freeze them.</li><li><strong>Vacuum Ball </strong>– A vacuum that slowly siphons energy from enemies as it pulls them inward, dealing damage with each tick. Enemies below 20% HP are instantly absorbed into the swirling core, forming the Vacuum Ball. Once charged, it can be hurled at enemies, dealing attack damage.</li><li><strong>Piñata’s Revenge</strong> – A totally cursed piñata taunts nearby enemies into attacking it. While it’s up, your hits grant random buffs, and enemy hits cause random debuffs. After a few seconds… KABOOM. Candy and damage for everyone in range.</li><li><strong>A Really Dangerous Weapon</strong> – Drops a magical cannon that fires a barrage of magical cannonballs. Hits enemies with rapid-fire blasts of damage. Nobody's quite sure where Timmy got it. Definitely not approved by Da Rules.</li><li><strong>Scepter Beam</strong> – Unleashes a crackling elemental ray that cycles between Fire, Lightning, and Ice. Each second brings a new element and a fresh debuff. Zapping enemies restores mana.</li><li><strong>Spiky Ball</strong> – Summons a giant, glittery spiked ball that bounces three times before exploding. Or press skill button again to blow it up early. Each bounce deals damage. Each explosion? Spectacular. Just don’t ask who tested it.</li></ul><p>Nicktoons &amp; The Dice of Destiny is set to launch on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, Switch, and PC via Steam and the Epic Games Store sometime this Fall.</p><hr><p><em>What character do you want to see revealed for Nicktoons &amp; The Dice of Destiny? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/07/01/timmy-turner-and-the-fairly-odd-parents-join-the-nicktoons-the-dice-of-destiny]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>