<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 10:45:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You now need a credit card to access mature content on Steam in the UK]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/you-now-need-a-credit-card-to-access-mature-content-on-steam-in-the-uk</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-now-need-a-credit-card-to-access-mature-content-on-steam-in-the-uk.1285479/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">September 1, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Logo via Steam / Flag via Pixabay</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Valve is requiring Steam users based in the UK to verify their age using a credit card in order to access "mature content."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company said its new age assurance policy is designed to comply with the UK Online Safety Act (OSA), which is billed by the UK government as a new set of laws that will protect both children and adults online by pushing social media platforms and other internet businesses to take more responsibility for their users' safety.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The OSA has resulted in some online platforms such as Reddit and Bluesky locking certain features behind age verification checks that require selfies, but Valve said it has chosen to rely on credit card checks to preserve the "maximum degree of user privacy."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The data processed in the verification process is identical to that of the millions of other Steam users who make purchases or store their payment details for convenience. The verification process therefore provides no information about a user's content preferences to payment providers or other third parties," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://help.steampowered.com/en/faqs/view/292B-3DA3-CFC8-97F6">wrote Valve in a blog post</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Valve handles the verification process using its own internal payment processing system, which is independently certified under the PCI-DSS standard."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Valve claims its new age assurance policy is &quot;highly effective&quot;&nbsp;">Valve claims its new age assurance policy is "highly effective"&nbsp;</h2><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/netease-shuts-down-rich-vogel-led-t-minus-zero-entertainment" target="_self" data-discover="true">NetEase shuts down Rich Vogel-led T-Minus Zero Entertainment</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company explained that UK users who do not verify their age will be unable to access Steam store pages for "mature content games" or their associated community hubs.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"You need to be logged into an active user account and explicitly opt-in through the account settings page [to access that content]," added Valve. "For UK users, this opt-in process requires age verification. Your UK Steam user account is considered age verified for as long as a valid credit card is stored on the account."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Valve noted that Ofcom—the UK's independent regulator for online safety—has positioned credit card checks as one "highly effective age assurance measure." That's because UK residents must be at least 18 years of age obtain a credit card.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Having the credit card stored as a payment method acts as an additional deterrent against circumventing age verification by sharing a single Steam user account among multiple person," Valve continued.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Valve has instructed customers who encounter issues when attempting to register their credit card on Steam to contact their local bank for assistance before filing a Steam Support ticket. "Our data minimal approach means that we typically do not have insight into reasons why a given credit card use fails," the company added.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-s-stinginess-on-switch-2-dev-kits-layoffs-at-crystal-dynamics-and-diablo-developers-unionize-patch-notes-20" target="_self" data-discover="true">Nintendo's stinginess on Switch 2 dev kits, layoffs at Crystal Dynamics, and Diablo developers unionize - Patch Notes #20</a></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/you-now-need-a-credit-card-to-access-mature-content-on-steam-in-the-uk]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>