<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 17:54:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mortal Kombat: Legacy Kollection’s Full Roster Includes Mythologies Sub-Zero And Special Forces]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/08/21/mortal-kombat-legacy-kollections-full-roster-includes-mythologies-sub-zero-and-special</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mortal-kombat-legacy-kollection%E2%80%99s-full-roster-includes-mythologies-sub-zero-and-special-forces.1277352/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Digital Eclipse has revealed the full roster of games for its retrospective compilation/interactive documentary, Mortal Kombat: Legacy Kollection. This update reveals that the infamously terrible single-player spin-off titles Mortal Kombat Mythologies: Sub-Zero and Mortal Kombat: Special Forces will be part of the bundle.</p><p>Mortal Kombat Mythologies: Sub-Zero launched for the original PlayStation in 1997 and is a side-scrolling action game starring the titular ice ninja (specifically Bi-Han, the first Sub-Zero and eventual Noob Saibot). Spoiler: It’s a very bad game, but it is notable for featuring the series debuts for staple fighters Quan Chi and Shinnok. You can watch former GI editors (including <em>Giant Bomb'</em>s Dan Ryckert) suffer through this game in this classic 2010 episode of Replay, posted below.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_wFljLP_1-4"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_wFljLP_1-4" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Mortal Kombat: Special Forces was released in 2000, also for PlayStation 1, and is a 3D action game starring Jax. The game sees him taking on Kano and his crew of baddies, including the debuting Tremor, who would later resurface as a <a href="https://gameinformer.com/b/news/archive/2015/07/19/see-mortal-kombat-x-39-s-next-dlc-character-tremor-crush-opponents-with-rocks.aspx">DLC fighter in Mortal Kombat X</a>. Special Forces didn’t exactly light the world on fire; that’s a nice way of saying it’s also terrible. It does have a very funny and strange <a href="https://youtu.be/8T1EeAHIFMU?si=kn0qWzQKEWURaO4H">‘70s spy-themed intro cinematic</a> going for it, though.</p><p>Digital Eclipse also announced that the extremely rare WaveNet Arcade version of Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3 is part of the Kollection. This version was originally made to support Midway’s WaveNet online matchmaking service for arcades, and has not been available on any platform since 1997. It’s also the only arcade release to feature Noob Saibot as a playable fighter.&nbsp;</p><p>Check out the Kollection's new trailer from Gamescom below.&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O89KZUGXbqY"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O89KZUGXbqY" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Here is the full list of titles in the Kollection:</p><ul><li><strong>Mortal Kombat</strong> – 1992 (Arcade, SNES, Genesis, Game Boy, Game Gear)</li><li><strong>Mortal Kombat II</strong> – 1993 (Arcade, SNES, Genesis, Game Boy, 32X)</li><li><strong>Mortal Kombat 3</strong> – 1995 (Arcade, SNES, Genesis)</li><li><strong>Ultimate Mortal Kombat 3</strong> – 1995 (Arcade, WaveNet Arcade, SNES)</li><li><strong>Mortal Kombat Trilogy</strong> – 1996 (PlayStation)</li><li><strong>Mortal Kombat 4</strong> – 1997 (Arcade)</li><li><strong>Mortal Kombat Mythologies: Sub-Zero</strong> – 1997 (PlayStation)</li><li><strong>Mortal Kombat Special Forces</strong> – 2000 (PlayStation)</li><li><strong>Mortal Kombat Advance</strong> – 2001 (Game Boy Advance)</li><li><strong>Mortal Kombat: Deadly Alliance</strong> – 2002 (Game Boy Advance)</li><li><strong>Mortal Kombat: Tournament Edition</strong> – 2003 (Game Boy Advance)</li></ul><p>Mortal Kombat: Legacy Kollection launches later this year for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, Switch 2, PlayStation 4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/08/21/mortal-kombat-legacy-kollections-full-roster-includes-mythologies-sub-zero-and-special]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>