<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 14:16:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathon Alpha Update Allows Players To Talk About The Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marathon-alpha-update-allows-players-to-talk-about-the-game/1100-6530975/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marathon-alpha-update-allows-players-to-talk-about-the-game.1169331/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marathon-alpha-update-allows-players-to-talk-about-the-game/1100-6530975/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530975">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Bungie has <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/News/Article/alpha_update" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that it has updated one of the guidelines for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marathon-everything-we-know-about-bungies-extraction-shooter/1100-6514617/" data-ref-id="1100-6514617">Marathon</a>'s upcoming closed alpha test. Bungie is removing the NDA from the alpha and players will be able to talk about their experiences with it when it begins on April 23 to when it ends on May 4.</p><p>"As developers we believe community feedback and dialog is essential to make the best version of Marathon. Up until now, this feedback has come from closed playtest sessions," Bungie said in a statement. "In the spirit of building towards that future, we've decided to remove the NDA from our Closed Alpha Test. Everyone can share their thoughts, feedback, and footage, including streaming starting on April 23."</p><p>Bungie added that the studio is most interested in hearing feedback surrounding Marathon's gunplay, weapons, maps, runners, early-game progression, PvP engagements against other players, and PvE engagements against AI. As this isn't the full game, Bungie also clarified that the alpha will not include aspects such as final visuals, a polished user interface, a complete narrative, and ranked play.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marathon-alpha-requirements-and-minimum-pc-specs-revealed/1100-6530908/" data-ref-id="1100-6530908">alpha test requires all players</a> to have a Bungie.net account, but not a PlayStation Plus or Xbox Live account. However, they will be when Marathon officially launches. Marathon will not have a single-player mode like the Destiny franchise does, due to the PvP experience being the foundation of it, according to its former game director.</p><p>Marathon launches on September 23 for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. It'll support both cross-play and cross-save, as well <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marathon-wont-be-full-price-though-bungie-says-it-will-be-a-premium-title/1100-6530835/" data-ref-id="1100-6530835">be a premium paid title</a>, with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bungies-marathon-will-be-40-report/1100-6526561/" data-ref-id="1100-6526561">reports stating that it costs $40</a>. In GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bungies-marathon-is-a-polished-extraction-shooter-but-that-might-not-be-enough/1100-6530826/" data-ref-id="1100-6530826">Marathon preview</a>, we said, "Marathon feels like it'll deliver satisfying gameplay, but the experience around it could leave a lot to be desired."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[See Battlefield 6's New Destruction Elements In Action In This Video]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/see-battlefield-6s-new-destruction-elements-in-action-in-this-video/1100-6530977/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/see-battlefield-6s-new-destruction-elements-in-action-in-this-video.1169304/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/see-battlefield-6s-new-destruction-elements-in-action-in-this-video/1100-6530977/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530977">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>There's still a lot we don't know about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/" data-ref-id="1100-6526583">the next Battlefield game</a>, but it looks like old-school destructible environments are making a comeback. Developer DICE shared an early look at the upcoming game's destructive capabilities with a brief video from a pre-alpha build in which a player brings down the side of a building. That allows the player to quickly enter the now wide-open structure.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/Battlefield/status/1913249264488296827" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">We’re back with another Battlefield Labs Community Update focused on destruction! Check out an early pre-alpha example of destruction that showcases the ability to destroy a wall to quickly traverse through the building. Read the full article now! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Battlefield?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Battlefield</a> <a href="https://t.co/bgDcPgZRbg" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/bgDcPgZRbg</a></p>  — Battlefield (@Battlefield) <a href="https://twitter.com/Battlefield/status/1913249264488296827?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 18, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>DICE also shared <a href="https://x.com/Battlefield/status/1913250029126787494" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a lengthy explanation</a> about how it plans to implement destructive elements into the game. The team's stated goal is to give players the ability to "reshape the environment and transform your surroundings toward a tactical advantage." The article notes that there will be visual and audio cues that let players know which environments can be destroyed. And while the demonstration only took down part of a building, it will be possible to "[take] down a building to take out an attacking squad."</p><p>Buildings and objects won't necessarily break immediately. Instead, they will "visually degrade" while taking persistent damage before starting to break down. Rubble from the destruction won't disappear from the battlefield, and players can even use it for cover during firefights.</p><p>For the current test, DICE is focused on how to let players differentiate between non-destructible and destructible environments. It's also examining how the destructible elements and collateral damage will affect the gameplay.</p><p>Despite players signing NDAs <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-play-the-new-battlefield-early-sign-up-for-a-chance-to-get-into-test-program/1100-6529190/" data-ref-id="1100-6529190">to participate in the Battlefield tests</a>, there have been a lot of leaks. The dev team <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-dev-reacts-to-games-many-leaks-i-am-not-ok-with-leaks/1100-6530040/" data-ref-id="1100-6530040">has voiced its displeasure</a> over those in part because these tests aren't necessarily representative of what the final game will be like. Earlier this month, Battlefield's lead producer David Sirland addressed the rumors about the game's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-dev-clarifies-use-of-sbmm-in-playtest/1100-6530889/" data-ref-id="1100-6530889">potential use of skill-based matchmaking</a> that likely originated from the play tests.</p><p>A previous report suggested that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-battlefield-game-will-have-a-free-to-play-battle-royale-report/1100-6521440/" data-ref-id="1100-6521440">the next Battlefield game will arrive in October 2025</a>. However, EA has yet to formally set a release window for the upcoming title.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>