<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 21:06:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tales Of The Shire: A Lord Of The Rings Game Has Been Delayed Again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tales-of-the-shire-a-lord-of-the-rings-game-has-been-delayed-again/1100-6529631/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tales-of-the-shire-a-lord-of-the-rings-game-has-been-delayed-again.1114890/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tales-of-the-shire-a-lord-of-the-rings-game-has-been-delayed-again/1100-6529631/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529631">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>There's a famous line in J.R.R. Tolkien's The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Rings where Gandalf the Grey explains that a wizard is never late or early. Instead, "he arrives precisely when he means to." Video games, on the other hand, are another matter. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/tales-of-the-shire-a-lord-of-the-rings-game/" data-ref-id="5000-604117">Tales of the Shire: A Lord of the Rings Game</a> has been delayed again.</p><p>The game's developers, Private Division and Wētā Workshop, jointly announced that Tales of the Shire will now be released on July 29. Prior to that, Tales of the Shire was delayed from its 2024 release window and was scheduled to land on March 25. Now, fans will just have to wait until summer to move into the virtual Shire.</p><p>In the statement below, the given reason for the delay is that the devs want to ensure "the same cozy experience" is available on all platforms. The note also states that the developers want the game "to feel like a warm hug from Middle-earth."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4447318-talesoftheshirenote.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4447318" data-ratio="1" data-width="1300" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4447318-talesoftheshirenote.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4447318"></a><figcaption>The complete message from Tales of the Shire developers Private Division and Wētā Workshop.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4447318-talesoftheshirenote.jpg"></figure><p>There will be no epic quests or ring-tossing into Mount Doom in this game. Tales of the Shire is all about the tranquil lives of Hobbits when they aren't out saving the world or having adventures. Truthfully, Bilbo and Frodo Baggins--as well Sam, Pippin, and Merry--were always outliers among their people. Most of the Hobbits prefer to stay at home in the Shire.</p><p>This game will allow players to create their own Hobbit character, and put together a beautiful home for them. Players can also enjoy simple Hobbit tasks like farming, gardening, decorating, and trading for rare items with fellow residents of the Shire.</p><p>Tales of the Shire will be available on Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch, and PC . GameSpot had <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tales-of-the-shire-has-a-long-ways-to-go-if-it-wants-to-be-precious/1100-6526616/" data-ref-id="1100-6526616">a hands-on preview for Tales of the Shire</a> last year, which called it "charming" and praised its "good fundamentals," while also stressing the need for several quality-of-life improvements and more compelling gameplay. Hopefully the final version of the game will deliver those adjustments.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Patch Lets Players Keep Pouring The Wine]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-patch-lets-players-keep-pouring-the-wine/1100-6529629/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-patch-lets-players-keep-pouring-the-wine.1114818/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-patch-lets-players-keep-pouring-the-wine/1100-6529629/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529629">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-review-whats-old-is-new-again/1900-6418333/" data-ref-id="1900-6418333">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a> hasn't even been out for a month yet, but the wildly successful game already has another patch ready to go from Warhorse Studios. Although there are a handful of crash fixes, there aren't many major issues at all in this patch, which Warhorse is calling Hotfix 1.1.2. Instead, the most exciting revision comes in The King's Gambit, where players can now keep the wine flowing for the king.</p><p>As related on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/kingdomcome/comments/1imfa12/kcd2_cant_pick_up_white_wine_during_the_kings/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Reddit</a>, some players ran into an issue in The King's Gambit where the option to pour wine for the king disappears. When the king asks to switch from red wine to white, players failed the task when they couldn't fulfil that simple request.</p><p>Warhorse shared the Hotfix 1.1.2 breakdown on <a href="https://kingdomcomerpg.com/en/news/hotfix-1-1-2" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the official site for Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a>. According to the developers, the primary adjustments include stability improvements and quest fixes. There's also a specific fix for the game on the Epic Games Store. Taken together, these changes may not seem very significant, but they're meant to help players have a more refined experience.</p><p>So far, Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 has been a massive hit for Warhorse Studios. It sold <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-tops-1-million-copies-sold-in-a-single-day/1100-6529264/" data-ref-id="1100-6529264">1 million copies in its first 24 hours</a>, and recently passed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-studio-reports-its-approaching-2-million-sales/1100-6529486/" data-ref-id="1100-6529486">the 2 million mark</a> as well. It also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-had-a-huge-weekend-on-steam-and-it-may-get-even-bigger/1100-6529355/" data-ref-id="1100-6529355">peaked at 250,000 concurrent users</a> on Steam. Additionally, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kingdom-come-2-mods-are-coming-get-a-first-peek-with-henry-holding-a-fish/1100-6529434/" data-ref-id="1100-6529434">official mod support is coming</a> to the PC version of the game as well.</p><p>Players have also found entertaining details in Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-has-a-secret-ending-you-only-see-if-youre-the-worst-person-ever/1100-6529439/" data-ref-id="1100-6529439">a hidden ending</a> that can only be achieved by letting the main character embrace all of his worst instincts. The complete patch notes for Hotfix 1.1.2 are reproduced below.</p><h3><strong>Fortuna </strong></h3><ul><li>Bozhena and Pavlena will no longer report the player for crimes during the quest.</li></ul><h3><strong>The King's Gambit </strong></h3><ul><li>The quest interactor for wine will no longer disappear, allowing players to continue pouring wine for the guests.</li></ul><h3><strong>Combat</strong></h3><ul><li>Fixed the crossbow aiming zoom on ultrawide resolutions.</li></ul><h3><strong>Platform-specific fixes</strong></h3><ul><li>Epic Games Store: Fixed the issue with achievements not being completed after longer than one hour of play.</li></ul><h3><strong>PROS</strong></h3><ul><li>Improved the issue with rewards sometimes requiring game restart to be awarded.</li></ul><h3><strong>Stability</strong></h3><ul><li>Fixed a crash when looking at certain locked doors and chests.</li><li>Fixed a crash sometimes occurring loading the game after finishing the dice mini-game.</li><li>Fixed a crash related to opening the horse inventory.</li><li>Fixed a crash related to interacting with a cart.</li><li>Fixed a crash when spamming keys on the EULA screen.</li><li>Fixed a crash when having conflicting versions of the Bink library.</li><li>A few dozen additional stability fixes and improvements.</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Split Fiction Cross-Play And Friend's Pass Free Access Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/split-fiction-cross-play-and-friends-pass-free-access-explained/1100-6529627/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/split-fiction-cross-play-and-friends-pass-free-access-explained.1114815/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/split-fiction-cross-play-and-friends-pass-free-access-explained/1100-6529627/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529627">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>EA and Hazelight Studios have <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/it-takes-two/about/friends-pass" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">revealed information</a> about how Split Fiction's Friend's Pass and cross-play between different platforms work. There's even a free trial for players who don't own the game.</p><p>Similar to Hazelight's previous co-op games like It Takes Two and A Way Out, Split Fiction also offers a Friend's Pass. This allows players who bought the game to connect with someone who doesn't have a copy, and play through the game in its entirety. But this time, Split Fiction's version has some expanded features that weren't in those previous games, such as cross-platform play.</p><h2>How does Split Fiction's work?</h2><p>The first step is that one person has to own the game, whether it'd be a physical or digital copy. The next step is to have a buddy download Split Fiction's Friend's Pass on their chosen platform, whether it'd be PC, PlayStation, or Xbox through their respective digital storefronts. Just be aware that if you and your friend are playing on different platforms, for example PC and PlayStation, both of you need an EA account.</p><p>Next, the person who owns Split Fiction should send an in-game invite to their friend, whom then accepts the invite. Once that step is completed, both players can play through the entire game together.</p><p>What happens if neither of you own the game? No problem. The Friend's Pass offers a free trial for both players which includes the opening stages of Split Fiction. Both players will need to download the Friend's Pass version of the game, and once either of you purchase the full game, progresses can be continued.</p><p>Another aspect to note is that in It Takes Two and A Way Out, the player who was on the Friend's Pass version did not unlock trophies or achievements on their platform, while the one who owned the game did. At least in A Way Out, if the player on the Friend's Pass decides to purchase the full game later on, <a href="https://help.ea.com/en/help/a-way-out/a-way-out/play-a-way-out-with-the-friends-pass/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">they will retroactively earn the trophies and achievements</a> they would have unlocked while on the pass. It's unknown whether this is the same case for Split Fiction.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4AAzbMPitPI" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4AAzbMPitPI" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2>How does cross-play in Split Fiction work?</h2><p>It Takes Two and A Way Out didn't have cross-play, meaning that both players had to be on the same platform in order to play with each other. However, It Takes Two had cross-gen play, meaning that PS4 and PS5 players and Xbox One and Xbox Series X|S players could play with each other as long as they were on the same platform family.</p><p>Split Fiction is only on current-gen consoles, so cross-gen play doesn't exist. However, Split Fiction now offers cross-play, meaning that PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S players can all play together. Cross-play requires both players to sign up for separate EA accounts each, which you can <a href="https://help.ea.com/en/help-home/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">make for free</a>.</p><p>Hazelight also has a <a href="https://discord.com/invite/hazelight" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Discord server</a> with a channel called "Looking for Player" for those who want to play Split Fiction with but don't have anyone available to arrange game sessions.</p><p>Split Fiction launches on March 6 for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. In other related news, director Josef Fares recently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-takes-two-and-split-fiction-director-shares-his-thoughts-on-ai/1100-6529493/" data-ref-id="1100-6529493">shared his thoughts on AI</a>, and also said that Hazelight Studios <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-takes-two-boss-says-studio-will-never-make-a-live-service-game/1100-6529501/" data-ref-id="1100-6529501">will never make a live-service game</a>.</p><p>For more Split Fiction coverage, be sure to check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/split-fiction-is-shaping-up-to-be-another-great-co-op-adventure-hands-on-impressions/2300-6465704/" data-ref-id="2300-6465704">Split Fiction preview</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lost Soul Aside Preorders Are Finally Live On PS5 And PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lost-soul-aside-preorders-are-finally-live-on-ps5-and-pc/1100-6529617/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lost-soul-aside-preorders-are-finally-live-on-ps5-and-pc.1114761/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lost-soul-aside-preorders-are-finally-live-on-ps5-and-pc/1100-6529617/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529617">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>First revealed in 2016, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DX42RXMS?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lost Soul Aside</a> is finally heading to PS5 and PC later this year on May 30. Originally started as a one-person project, the action RPG has grown into something much larger, boasting flashy graphics and fast-paced combat. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DX42RXMS?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Preorders</a> are now open ahead of its release. Reserving in advance will unlock a few nice in-game bonuses, and dedicated fans will also find a Digital Deluxe Edition packed with even more goodies.</p><h2>Lost Soul Aside Preorder Bonus</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4447136-54324021208_4f6f135466_4k.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4447136" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4447136-54324021208_4f6f135466_4k.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4447136"></a><figcaption>Lost Soul Aside preorder bonuses</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4447136-54324021208_4f6f135466_4k.jpg"></figure><p>Preorder Lost Soul Aside ahead of its release on May 30, and you’ll get the following in-game items:</p><ul><li>Kaser’s original reveal outfit (The Origin)</li><li>500 Divinity’s Gold</li><li>10x High Potion</li></ul><p>If you’ve been following the game for some time, The Origin cosmetic is the same one worn by the protagonist during Lost Soul Aside’s first reveal. The other two bonuses should help kickstart your adventure.</p><div title="6529617 - Lost Soul Aside Preorder Guide" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="3175" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6529617 - Lost Soul Aside Preorder Guide" data-collection="">                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DX42RXMS?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DX42RXMS?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DX42RXMS?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">Lost Soul Aside</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DX42RXMS?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DX42RXMS?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DX42RXMS?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">$60</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>The standard version of Lost Soul Aside includes the base game and all preorder bonuses. Physical formats are available at most major retailers, including <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgo.skimresources.com%3Fid%3D225336X1707200%26xs%3D1%26xcust%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fdirect.playstation.com%2Fen-us%2Fbuy-games%2Flost-soul-aside-ps5&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Flost-soul-aside-preorders-are-finally-live-on-ps5-and-pc%2F1100-6529617%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS Direct</a>. Digital preorders are also available on PC and PS5.</p>                      </div>                                                                     <div>             <h2>                    <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/HP9000-PPSA26358_00-LOSTSOULASIDEDDE" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/store.playstation.com\/en-us\/product\/HP9000-PPSA26358_00-LOSTSOULASIDEDDE&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/HP9000-PPSA26358_00-LOSTSOULASIDEDDE">Lost Soul Aside Digital Deluxe</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/HP9000-PPSA26358_00-LOSTSOULASIDEDDE" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/store.playstation.com\/en-us\/product\/HP9000-PPSA26358_00-LOSTSOULASIDEDDE&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/HP9000-PPSA26358_00-LOSTSOULASIDEDDE">$70</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>Along with the base game and preorder bonuses, the Digital Deluxe Edition comes with a bunch of additional goodies. Here’s a closer look at everything you’ll get for an extra $10:</p><ul><li>Digital Soundtrack</li><li>Digital Art Book</li><li>Ruby Necklace Health Booster</li><li>Gemstone Badge XP Booster</li><li>Three Weapon Fragment Cosmetics</li><li>Arena Skin: Golden Blaze</li></ul></div>                      </div>   </div><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4447137-54323798191_539fdb5946_4k.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4447137" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4447137-54323798191_539fdb5946_4k.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4447137"></a><figcaption>Lost Soul Aside Deluxe Edition bonuses</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1702/17023653/4447137-54323798191_539fdb5946_4k.jpg"></figure><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/final-fantasy-x-magic-the-gathering-set-is-up-for-preorder/2900-6271/">Final Fantasy X Magic: The Gathering Set Is Up For Preorder</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-festival-nintendo-switch-controller-with-fret-attachment-gets-first-discount/1100-6528188/">Fortnite Festival Nintendo Switch Controller With Fret Attachment Gets First Discount</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-entry-level-3d-printer-is-over-100-off-thanks-to-amazon-lightning-deal/1100-6529550/">This Entry-Level 3D Printer Is Over $100 Off Thanks To Amazon Lightning Deal</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (3)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/asus-rog-ally-extreme-with-free-travel-case-gets-massive-discount/1100-6524126/">Asus ROG Ally Extreme With Free Travel Case Gets Massive Discount</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-up-to-20-on-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-preorders-for-pc/1100-6529515/">Save Up To $20 On Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater Preorders For PC</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-preorder-deals-collectors-edition-amazon/1100-6526606/">Like A Dragon: Pirate Yakuza In Hawaii Collector's Edition In Stock At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/105566936584242225941?rel=author">Jon Bitner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528461&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dragon-ball-blu-ray-collectors-box-sets-are-steeply-discounted-at-amazon\/1100-6528461\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529566&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/looks-like-were-getting-gta-in-fortnite-before-gta-6\/1100-6529566\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529560&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hollow-knight-silksong-page-removed-from-nintendo-store-remains-elsewhere\/1100-6529560\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529594&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-pc-game-sale-includes-hundreds-of-aaa-hits-for-low-prices\/1100-6529594\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529572&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-69-capcom-retro-games-for-only-20-for-a-limited-time\/1100-6529572\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529559&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvel-rivals-devs-laid-off-despite-the-games-huge-success\/1100-6529559\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529573&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mass-effect-veteran-who-didnt-come-back-for-mass-effect-3-says-director-was-not-particularly-happy-with-me\/1100-6529573\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529531&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/avowed-forged-of-star-stuff-quest-guide\/1100-6529531\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529587&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/japan-studio-closed-because-the-double-a-market-has-disappeared-ex-playstation-boss-says\/1100-6529587\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529468&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-long-is-like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii\/1100-6529468\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529376&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-remastered-physical-edition-preorder-at-amazon-release-date-june-2025\/1100-6529376\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529557&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/call-of-duty-recon-squad-announced-but-its-not-a-new-game\/1100-6529557\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529577&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sony-didnt-pass-on-dark-souls-from-software-just-passed-on-sony\/1100-6529577\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529546&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/save-up-40-on-nintendo-switch-first-party-games-at-best-buy\/1100-6529546\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529507&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-4-release-date-trailer-story\/1100-6529507\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529584&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dozen-of-ps5-xbox-series-x-and-switch-games-are-discounted-at-best-buy\/1100-6529584\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529532&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/xbox-boss-says-hes-no-longer-trying-to-move-ps5-players-to-xbox\/1100-6529532\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529575&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/next-tony-hawks-pro-skater-game-to-launch-this-summer-report\/1100-6529575\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>