<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 15:58:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Delay Had This Major Effect On Rockstar's Parent Company]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-delay-had-this-major-effect-on-rockstars-parent-company/1100-6531286/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-delay-had-this-major-effect-on-rockstars-parent-company.1179669/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-delay-had-this-major-effect-on-rockstars-parent-company/1100-6531286/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531286">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Rockstar's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> has been <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-delayed-to-2026/1100-6531282/" data-ref-id="1100-6531282">delayed to 2026</a>, and parent company Take-Two's stock price is tanking today following the announcement. Shares of Take-Two have slid by about 8% so far today to around $219, wiping out billions of market cap for the video game publisher.</p><p>Take-Two anticipated investors having questions about the delay and its impact on the company's financial outlook, so it released a statement reiterating that the company still expects "sequential increases in, and record levels of" net bookings (i.e. revenue) for Fiscal 2026 and Fiscal 2027.</p><p>GTA 6's new release date of May 26, 2026 falls in Take-Two's Fiscal Year 2027 (April 1 2026-March 31 2027). Previously, the game was scheduled to release in Fall 2025, which fell in Take-Two's Fiscal Year 2026 (April 1, 2025-March 31, 2026).</p><p>While GTA 6 is no longer coming this year, Take-Two's labels still have Mafia: The Old Country and Borderlands 4 coming this year, in addition to its roster of sports titles.</p><p>Take-Two will release its next earnings report on May 15, and it's expected the company will face numerous questions about the impact of GTA 6's delay on Take-Two's earnings outlook.</p><p>While Take-Two's share price fell today, it's still up around 80% in the past five years. In February 2025, Take-Two's share price <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-parent-companys-stock-reaches-all-time-high-and-this-could-be-why/1100-6529336/" data-ref-id="1100-6529336">reached a record high</a> following Take-Two's announcement that GTA 6 remained on track for release in 2025 and that the company had exceeded earnings expectations. Now that GTA 6 has been delayed, the stock price is moving in the other direction, at least for now. Stock prices tend to fluctuate significantly during a major news event and then moderate soon after.</p><p>For its part, Take-Two boss Strauss Zelnick said Take-Two "fully" supports Rockstar's decision to take additional time to "realize their creative vision for GTA 6." Reporter Jason Schreier said the delay was in part to help Rockstar's developers <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jasonschreier.bsky.social/post/3lo6qieb3wc2x" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">avoid a "brutal crunch" period</a>. Rockstar <a href="https://kotaku.com/inside-rockstar-games-culture-of-crunch-1829936466" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">previously came under fire for its working conditions</a>, and the company later spoke out to say it had <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/red-dead-redemption-2-exec-responds-to-crunch-cont/1100-6463106/" data-ref-id="1100-6463106">addressed some workplace concerns</a> pertaining to lengthy work days and weeks.</p><p>GTA 6 is expected to sell <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-5-could-make-3-billion-in-first-year-alone/1100-6528605/" data-ref-id="1100-6528605">40 million copies and drive $3 billion in revenue in the first year alone</a>, and workers at Rockstar are likely to share in the game's success. Rockstar has an employee bonus program that can lead to big payouts. In addition to an annual bonus, developers are paid performance-based bonuses in the years of game launches. For the original Red Dead Redemption, for example, Rockstar workers earned five-figure bonuses, <a href="https://kotaku.com/inside-rockstar-games-culture-of-crunch-1829936466" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">according to Kotaku.</a></p><p>For Take-Two's latest reporting period, running October-December 2024, <a href="https://ir.take2games.com/static-files/4d81f3f6-cf24-44fa-892b-8ace44767349" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Take-Two paid out more than $100 million in bonuses to developers</a>, referred to as "internal royalties" by the company's accounting.</p><p>Keep checking back with GameSpot for the latest on GTA 6.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Minecraft Game Modes And Difficulty Settings Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-minecraft-game-modes-and-difficulty-settings-explained/1100-6531283/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-minecraft-game-modes-and-difficulty-settings-explained.1179630/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-minecraft-game-modes-and-difficulty-settings-explained/1100-6531283/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531283">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>When you think of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/minecraft/" data-ref-id="5000-73990">Minecraft</a>'s game modes, you might automatically go to the game's classic Survival mode, or the peaceful Creative mode. However, there are five game modes in the vanilla version, not all of them resembling a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-survival-games/2900-5289/" data-ref-id="2900-5289">survival game</a>, and many more made possible by Minecraft mods. Here are all of the game modes in Minecraft, as well as the difficulty options that go alongside them, and which to choose.</p><h2 id="Survival">Survival</h2><p>Minecraft's traditional experience is nestled within Survival. Here, you'll have to work to collect the resources you need, craft upgrades and new items, and build your structures. You'll have to face deadly mobs and enemies, and your hunger bar will decay. While Survival can be challenging for new players, it's easily the best way to become acquainted with the game as you'll be forced to learn the mechanics and recipes quickly if you want to survive.</p><p>You'll be dropped into the world at a random spawn point at dawn, giving you a full day to get your bearings and craft something resembling a safe house. From there, you can continue to gather resources and upgrade your surroundings before setting off on the hunt for iron and diamond to make more powerful armor and tools. Don't forget to find a good food source so you don't succumb to hunger.</p><p>Eventually, you'll have to build a Nether portal to seek out a Stronghold for Blaze Rods which are required to reach The End. Heading to The End, you'll meet the Ender Dragon. Defeating the Ender Dragon means you've technically beaten the game, but with so many Minecraft biomes to explore, there are endless hours of enjoyment in this mode.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486449-minecraft-modes%285%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486449" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486449-minecraft-modes%285%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486449"></a><figcaption>Death is possible in Survival</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486449-minecraft-modes%285%29.jpg"></figure><h2 id="Hardcore">Hardcore</h2><p>Hardcore is Survival with a malicious twist. You only get one life in Hardcore mode, and when you die you'll have to reset your world. The only exception to this is if you're playing with friends who don't meet the same fate, where you have the option to spectate the world. It's not possible for some players to be in Survival and some in Hardcore in the same world; everyone will need to face the perils of Hardcore.</p><p>Once you've entered Hardcore mode you cannot change the difficulty level, so make sure it's something you're willing to commit to and grind through. The difficulty itself will also be much harder than normal Survival mode, with enemies dealing more damage, and cheats and bonus chest options are automatically turned off. While there are many <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/minecraft-java-vs-bedrock-differences-and-which-to-play/1100-6531281/" data-ref-id="1100-6531281">Minecraft Java vs Bedrock </a>differences, a large one is that Hardcore was not added to Bedrock until September 2024, while it was in the Java version of the game from the beta stage.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486448-minecraft-modes%284%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486448" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486448-minecraft-modes%284%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486448"></a><figcaption>Be very wary of mobs in Hardcore</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486448-minecraft-modes%284%29.jpg"></figure><h2 id="Creative">Creative</h2><p>While Hardcore is the ultimate test of a Minecraft player's skill, Creative is the absolute opposite. There's no hunger bar, resources are unlimited, and you won't get hurt by enemies, fall damage, or even falling into a lava pit. This is the best option if you want to build something truly monumental, like a massive castle, or some of the most lavish Minecraft houses you can think of.</p><p>In Creative mode you can fly, meaning structures that are extremely tall are much easier to build. Resources can be selected from the menu and you'll have unlimited amounts of any of them. Similarly, you can access every tool, weapon, and book in the game.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486447-minecraft-modes%283%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486447" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486447-minecraft-modes%283%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486447"></a><figcaption>You can't interact with blocks in Spectator mode</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486447-minecraft-modes%283%29.jpg"></figure><h2 id="Adventure">Adventure</h2><p>Adventure mode is one of the lesser-known Minecraft features. Visitors to your world won't be able to break or place blocks unless they own special items that allow them to. These player-created adventure worlds allow for things such as Skyblock and RPG servers to exist, as they change permissions to add or remove challenge if needed. You can create custom maps and puzzles, making parkour a popular Adventure mode creation.</p><p>Similarly to Survival, you will receive damage from the environment and can die, and keeping an eye on your hunger bar is essential. However, you can respawn so it's not as challenging as Hardcore. Players often make use of Minecraft Redstone builds to create interactive and engaging environments.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486445-minecraft-modes%282%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486445" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486445-minecraft-modes%282%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486445"></a><figcaption>Mobs won't hurt you in Creative mode</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486445-minecraft-modes%282%29.jpg"></figure><h2 id="Spectator">Spectator</h2><p>Spectator mode is the mode you'll enter if you die in Hardcore but want to continue to experience your friends' playthrough. It can also be entered from the main world creation screen, or by using '/gamemode spectator' in the command bar on PC. You won't be able to interact with anything, meaning you can't assist with construction or help your friends take down a difficult enemy, but it comes in handy for tracking down foes such as the Warden without alerting him.</p><p>You can fly through blocks and easily traverse the world, meaning Spectator mode could be useful for anyone wanting to give their friends a helping hand without the risk of death. It's a good way to view a world you've been working on from another perspective though, and switching to this mode in the middle of a huge build will allow you to soar above it to check whether it's symmetrical, or just look for expansion potential.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486442-minecraft-modes.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486442" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486442-minecraft-modes.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486442"></a><figcaption>Game modes allow for custom games</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486442-minecraft-modes.jpg"></figure><h2 id="Difficulty_Levels">Difficulty Levels</h2><p>There are four difficulty levels in Minecraft as follows:</p><ul><li><strong>Peaceful</strong> - This is the easiest game difficulty. There are no hostile mobs, and your hunger bar will not deplete. It's an alternative to Creative mode if you still want the challenge of having to mine and craft for the items and resources you want.</li><li><strong>Easy</strong> - This sticks pretty closely to the standard Minecraft game rules, but mobs don't deal as much damage and you can't die from hunger. Spiders also can't poison you. If you're a younger player, or new to the game, this might be a good option to choose.</li><li><strong>Normal</strong> - The standard game rules, where hunger can kill you and mobs deal the usual amount of damage.</li><li><strong>Hard </strong>- This is more challenging than the normal mode, but not quite as brutal as Hardcore as you can still respawn. Zombies can break through doors and call for reinforcements, so your safe house needs to be as protected as possible.</li></ul><p>Now that you know all of the game modes and difficulty levels in Minecraft, as well as what they do, check out our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/minecraft-guides-hub/1100-6526408/" data-ref-id="1100-6526408">Minecraft guides hub </a>for more helpful information. We've also got everything to know about how to<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-show-your-minecraft-coordinates/1100-6531264/" data-ref-id="1100-6531264"> show Minecraft coordinates </a>if you're feeling a bit lost.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/100905401902076465889?rel=author">Cheri Faulkner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft Java Vs. Bedrock - Differences And Which To Play]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/minecraft-java-vs-bedrock-differences-and-which-to-play/1100-6531281/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecraft-java-vs-bedrock-differences-and-which-to-play.1179627/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/minecraft-java-vs-bedrock-differences-and-which-to-play/1100-6531281/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531281">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>While you may be limited to which version of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/minecraft/" data-ref-id="5000-73990">Minecraft </a>you can play based on the device you're using, there are some important differences between Minecraft Java and Bedrock to be aware of. In Mojang's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-survival-games/2900-5289/" data-ref-id="2900-5289">survival game</a>, it's more common for PC users to play on Java, while console and mobile users are on Bedrock. Here's our full breakdown of the differences between Java and Bedrock so you can decide which version is right for you.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486433-minecraft-java-bedrock.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486433" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486433-minecraft-java-bedrock.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486433"></a><figcaption>Minecraft</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486433-minecraft-java-bedrock.jpg"></figure><h2>Minecraft Java Edition</h2><p>The Java edition of Minecraft supports cross-play, so you can jump in with friends on other platforms or operating systems who are also using Java. It also allows for the customization of Minecraft skins, meaning you can completely personalize your in-game look by downloading one of the many skins online. You could even try your hand at creating your own and uploading it to the game.</p><p>The most important difference is that Minecraft Java allows for the installation of mods, meaning you can access more of the best Minecraft servers and their custom packs. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-minecraft-mods/2900-5234/" data-ref-id="2900-5234">Minecraft mods</a> can do anything from adding small quality-of-life updates, to completely overhauling the way chests and loot work. They even make playing dedicated questlines possible, or introducing new Minecraft mobs.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486434-minecraft-java-bedrock%281%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486434" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486434-minecraft-java-bedrock%281%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4486434"></a><figcaption>Petting a dog in Minecraft</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4486434-minecraft-java-bedrock%281%29.jpg"></figure><h2>Minecraft Bedrock Edition</h2><p>While Bedrock is a named entity, it actually refers to any version of Minecraft that isn't Java. For this reason, console and mobile users primarily play the Bedrock version of the game. Bedrock does support <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-cross-platform-games/2900-5425/" data-ref-id="2900-5425">cross-play</a>, so most people on consoles wanting to team up with PC players will use it if you're both on the Bedrock version. Bedrock has controller support, or touch control support for mobile.</p><p>You'll also have access to the <a href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/marketplace" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Minecraft marketplace</a>, which sells packs that can be downloaded to completely overhaul the gameplay experience. Some recent examples include the Hello Kitty pack, which added a beautifully cute village alongside all of the Sanrio characters, and the Star Wars pack. This is the closest thing to mods that Bedrock users can use to customize the game, as the marketplace sells add-ons that transform the look or behavior of mobs, in-game items, and other environmental factors.</p><p>Bedrock also allows for parental controls, family sharing support, and moderation via the Xbox Family Settings and Family Share apps, making it the more child-friendly option for concerned parents.</p><p>While each version does have exclusive features, both Minecraft Java and Bedrock can use Minecraft servers, and they can both join or host Minecraft Realms. Realms are servers hosted by Minecraft that create a private space for you and up to ten friends to play together, for a small monthly fee.</p><p>Now that you've decided which version of the game is best for you, check out our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/minecraft-guides-hub/1100-6526408/" data-ref-id="1100-6526408">Minecraft guides hub</a> for more helpful information. We've also got all you need to know on how to show <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-show-your-minecraft-coordinates/1100-6531264/" data-ref-id="1100-6531264">Minecraft coordinates </a>if you're feeling a little lost.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/100905401902076465889?rel=author">Cheri Faulkner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>