<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:16:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Legends: Z-A Trailer Reveals Mega Lucario Z, Mewtwo Side Mission Now Available]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/02/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-reveals-mega-lucario-z-mewtwo-side-mission-now-available</link>
            <guid>1370284</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/pokemon-legends-z-a">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> might have launched on the Nintendo Switch and Switch 2 back in October, but developer Game Freak is apparently nowhere near done with adding content to the game. Ahead of the upcoming&nbsp;<a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/11/06/pokemon-legends-z-a-mega-dimension-dlc-launches-next-month-with-pokemon-over-level-100" target="_blank">Mega Dimension DLC's launch next week on December 10</a>, Game Freak has revealed Mega Lucario Z, a new Mega-Evolved form of the fan-favorite Pokémon, alongside word that a new Mewtwo side mission and Mystery Gift are now available in the base game.&nbsp;</p><p>Before beginning this new side mission, head to Mystery Gift starting today to obtain Mewtwonite X and Mewtwonite Y, which will allow you to evolve a Mewtwo into Mega Mewtwo X and Mega Mewtwo Y. Once you have those stones, a new side mission will appear in Lumiose – head there to begin the mission that eventually leads to an encounter with Mewtwo where you can catch the legendary Pokémon and add it to your party.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Here's a look at the trailer highlighting this new mission:&nbsp;</strong></p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DRt5h-Yrp_0"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DRt5h-Yrp_0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Game Freak also released a new trailer today highlighting Mega Lucario Z, which will be obtainable exclusively in the upcoming Mega Dimension DLC, which goes live on December 10. Mega Lucario is already pretty great – Mega Lucario Z looks even better, and we can't wait to see how it performs in combat.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Check out the Mega Lucario Z trailer below:&nbsp;</strong></p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V_UkrLROjkA"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V_UkrLROjkA" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Pokémon Legends: Z-A is available on Switch 2 and Switch. The Mega Dimension DLC launches next week, on December 10, for $29.99.&nbsp;</p><p>In the meantime, check out this reveal trailer for <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/11/19/mega-zeraora-revealed-for-pokemon-legends-z-as-mega-dimension-dlc">Mega Zeraora</a>, and then read <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/pokemon-legends-z-a/maintaining-rank"><em>Game Informer's </em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A review</a>.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>What do you think of Mega Lucario Z's design? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/02/pokemon-legends-z-a-trailer-reveals-mega-lucario-z-mewtwo-side-mission-now-available]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>