<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 13:57:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Nintendo Is Losing Their Identity" With Switch 2, Former PlayStation Boss Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-is-losing-their-identity-with-switch-2-former-playstation-boss-says/1100-6530863/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-is-losing-their-identity-with-switch-2-former-playstation-boss-says.1164597/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-is-losing-their-identity-with-switch-2-former-playstation-boss-says/1100-6530863/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530863">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Former PlayStation executive Shuhei Yoshida has shared his thoughts on the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Nintendo Switch 2</a>, saying Nintendo is "losing their identity" with the console due to its lack of new and exciting features. Appearing on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iWTzHlC_vrE&amp;ab_channel=EasyAllies">Easy Allies podcast</a>, Yoshida said, "I have to be polite," adding, "To me it was a bit [of a] mixed message from Nintendo. In a sense I think Nintendo is losing their identity, in my opinion."</p><p>Yoshida, in his decades of experience working in the video game industry, said he observed over the years that Nintendo always stood out by creating some kind of "new experience" that no one saw coming.</p><p>"But Switch 2, as we all anticipated, is a better Switch, right? It's a larger screen, more powerful processor, higher resolution, 4K 120fps. They even had their hardware person starting the stream as other platforms do," he said. "And because it's a better Switch, the core premise of the whole Switch 2 is, 'We made things better.' And that's something other companies have been doing all the time."</p><p>Yoshida did, however, praise Nintendo for the Switch 2's new mouse controls, saying the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/drag-x-drive/" data-ref-id="5000-671279">Drag X Drive</a> game is "very Nintendo." But overall, Yoshida said he was "a bit disappointed" with the Switch 2 and the response from fans. People were not generally disappointed, Yoshida observed, and this suggests that all people really wanted was a "better Switch."</p><p>The Switch is the No. 2 best-selling console ever, with more than 150 million units sold. </p><p>When the Switch 2 was unveiled in January, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-reveal-was-surprising-due-to-lack-of-surprises-says-former-playstation-boss/1100-6529203/" data-ref-id="1100-6529203">Yoshida said he was surprised by the console's lack of surprises</a>, so hearing him double down on that line of thinking makes sense.</p><p>For what it's worth, Nintendo has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-reveals-what-the-switch-2-could-have-been-called/1100-6530565/" data-ref-id="1100-6530565">maintained from the onset</a> that the Switch 2 is "a new system with improved performance." The company said the aim is that it becomes "the new standard for Nintendo Switch," which is why the company named it Nintendo Switch 2.</p><p>The Switch 2's development director, Takuhiro Dohta, went on to say that the Switch 2 is not aimed at people who prefer "high-performance hardware," but instead its ambition is to be a product that can appeal to the widest possible audience. "So, we wanted a name that would communicate simply to potential customers that, if you're considering buying a Switch, Nintendo Switch 2 is the newest system," Dohta said.</p><p>Another Switch 2 designer, Tetsuya Sasaki, said the name "Switch 2" is "simple and easy to understand." Sasaki added that it was always the plan for the system to be a "proper successor to Switch," so keeping the same name made sense.</p><p>Yoshida left PlayStation in early 2025 after 30 years with the company. Since leaving Sony he's been very outspoken in interviews, freely speaking his mind on a range of topics.</p><p>Yoshida also made headlines recently for saying he would have <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ex-playstation-exec-says-he-would-have-resisted-sonys-live-service-push/1100-6528881/" data-ref-id="1100-6528881">"resisted" Sony's push into live-service games</a> and that he was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/former-sony-exec-on-the-one-playstation-game-he-was-surprised-didnt-sell-like-he-thought-it-would/1100-6528860/" data-ref-id="1100-6528860">surprised Horizon Forbidden West didn't sell as well as expected.</a> Yoshida also talked about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/former-playstation-exec-theorizes-bloodborne-director-is-too-busy-for-remaster/1100-6528852/" data-ref-id="1100-6528852">why there hasn't been a Bloodborne remaster yet.</a></p><p>The Switch 2 launches on June 5. Nintendo announced a $450 price point for the console, but some fear Nintendo may <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">raise the price due to Trump's tariffs</a>. Other experts believe <a href="https://nikopartners.com/nikos-opinion-on-tariffs-video-games-and-us-china-trade/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Nintendo will not.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Give Marathon A Chance, Former Concord Developer Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/give-marathon-a-chance-former-concord-developer-says/1100-6530862/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/give-marathon-a-chance-former-concord-developer-says.1164570/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/give-marathon-a-chance-former-concord-developer-says/1100-6530862/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530862">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Bungie finally lifted the lid on its extraction shooter <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marathon-everything-we-know-about-bungies-extraction-shooter/1100-6514617/">Marathon</a> this week, and while the game looks like a vibrant entry in the genre, it has been negatively compared to Sony's live-service flop Concord. Both games share similar elements, being live-service sci-fi shooters with a colorful art direction, but one former Concord developer wants people to not only give Bungie's project a chance when it launches later this year, but to also show some compassion for the people working on it.</p><p>"After reading the comments about Marathon being Concord 2.0 on Reddit, YouTube, and Twitch, I just wanted to share a little insight into what a 40-year-old man is feeling after dedicating a large portion of his life to making videogames," former Firewalk Studios senior VFX artist Stephan Williams wrote on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Marathon/comments/1jyr8dm/former_firewalkconcord_dev_talks_marathon/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Marathon subreddit</a> (via <a href="https://www.vg247.com/marathon-concord-comparisons-ex-firewalk-dev-weighs-in" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">VG247</a>). "Seeing the faces of the developers on the Bungie stream gave me hope and excitement for what is to come for Marathon," Williams added. "I commend them for taking a chance, trying something foreign to them, that isn't proven, nor guaranteed to succeed. It takes a lot of courage."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e8eLy_C5lOM" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/e8eLy_C5lOM" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Williams explained that while Concord "failed to inspire players," there were lessons to be learned from that "gut-wrenching" failure. Now a senior VFX artist at Warframe studio Digital Extremes, Williams stressed that video games are meant to be fun and that people need to be kinder to the developers working on them behind the scenes.</p><p>After its big livestream, Bungie revealed quite a few details on Marathon, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bungies-marathon-releases-in-september-on-same-day-as-another-big-game/1100-6530810/">from its September 23 release date</a> to a closer look at the maps players will battle each other on as they hunt down some loot. The big question surrounding the game for now is its price, as while <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marathon-wont-be-full-price-though-bungie-says-it-will-be-a-premium-title/1100-6530835/">Bungie says that Marathon won't be a full-priced game</a>, it is promising a "premium" experience. If you're one of the people who'd like to give it a chance, you can try your luck at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marathon-closed-alpha-begins-in-april-heres-how-to-sign-up/1100-6530808/">snagging a key to join the game's closed alpha playtest</a> later this month.</p><p>"Marathon could launch as a solid multiplayer shooter that is brimming with potential but thin on content. And in the dog-eat-dog world of multiplayer games, that could be a major issue," Tamoor Hussain wrote in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bungies-marathon-is-a-polished-extraction-shooter-but-that-might-not-be-enough/1100-6530826/">GameSpot's hands-on preview of Marathon</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Opens Up Colorblind Simulation Tool To The Public]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-opens-up-colorblind-simulation-tool-to-the-public/1100-6530861/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-opens-up-colorblind-simulation-tool-to-the-public.1164549/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-opens-up-colorblind-simulation-tool-to-the-public/1100-6530861/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530861">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Ubisoft has <a href="https://news.ubisoft.com/en-gb/article/72j7U131efodyDK64WTJua" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">released its colorblind simulation tool</a>, Chroma, to the general public after several years in development. It's available to check out over on <a href="https://github.com/ubisoft/UbiChroma" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Github</a>.</p><p>In the announcement, Ubisoft explained that there are an estimated 300 million people across the globe who are impacted by colorblindness. Chroma's purpose is to simulate the three major colorblindness types: Protanopia, Deuteranopia, and Tritanopia.</p><p>Ubisoft also said that its quality-control team in India started developing Chroma in 2021. The team wanted to create a tool that could provide real-time feedback so developers could simultaneously control the game and simulate colorblindness.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1646/16465123/4476672-image_2025-04-14_234124656.png" data-ref-id="1300-4476672" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="960" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1646/16465123/4476672-image_2025-04-14_234124656.png" data-ref-id="1300-4476672"></a><figcaption>Chroma in action</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1646/16465123/4476672-image_2025-04-14_234124656.png"></figure><p>Now that it's open-source, developers simply have to apply a filter over the game screen  and it can simulate live gameplay up to 60fps. Chroma utilizes the Color Oracle algorithm and is compatible with single and dual screens. It also works with hotkeys and has a customizable overlay.</p><p>"Chroma is a testament to the team's innovation and dedication; their work is already making a difference in how we design games with accessibility in mind," said Ubisoft QC product manager Jawad Shakil. "Open-sourcing Chroma is a proud step forward, allowing everyone to benefit from this innovation."</p><p>Ubisoft isn't the only large developer aiming to make accessibility available to the general public. Last year, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-just-made-two-accessibility-patents-open-source/1100-6528289/" data-ref-id="1100-6528289">Electronic Arts made two of its patents open-source</a>. One of them was a speech-based patent that made it easier for players' speech to be recognized and reflected in-game. The other was an Unreal Engine 5 plugin called IRIS, which automatically alerts developers to moments in their games that could cause seizures in players with photosensitive epilepsy.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>