<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:43:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['CEOs need to take a backseat:' MindsEye devs accuse studio execs of fumbling layoffs and mandating crunch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mindseye-devs-accuse-studio-leaders-of-mishandling-layoffs-and-mandating-crunch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ceos-need-to-take-a-backseat-mindseye-devs-accuse-studio-execs-of-fumbling-layoffs-and-mandating-crunch.1321879/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">October 10, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>3 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Build A Rocket Boy</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A group of almost 100 former and current Build a Rocket Boy (BARB) developers have </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gameworkers.co.uk/barb-open-letter/">published an open letter</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> containing allegations of calamitous mismanagement that purportedly led to the "disastrous handling of redundancies" and "unbearable levels of overtime."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The letter was published with assistance from the Game Workers Branch of the Independent Workers of Great Britain union and claims that between 250 to 300 studio workers have lost their livelihoods because BARB leaders, Mark Gerhard and Leslie Benzies, refused to support and listen to their employees.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">An additional statement from the union </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/gameworkers.co.uk/post/3m2tnj54mfk2q">posted on Bluesky</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> states that multiple BARB employees are now filing legal claims against the studio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The studio </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mindseye-developer-build-a-rocket-boy-confirms-layoffs">confirmed it was making layoffs In June</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">—just weeks after the bungled launch of its debut title </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>MindsEye</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">—but didn't specify how many people would be made redundant. BARB's chief legal officer Riley Graebner and chief financial officer Paul Bland also </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/build-a-rocket-boy-execs-depart-one-week-before-mindseye-launches">departed ahead of MindsEye's launch</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the newly-published open letter, 93 current and former BARB staffers claim Gerhard and Benzies implemented a mandatory overtime policy that required every single employee to work an extra eight hours per week in the four months leading up to launch.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/fantastic-pixel-castle-at-risk-of-closure-after-being-ousted-by-netease" target="_self" data-discover="true">Fantastic Pixel Castle at risk of closure after being ousted by NetEase</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Time Off In Lieu (TOIL) was given at a rate of 7 hours back for every 8 hours worked, but many have still not been able to take this time off due to your continued requests for extra “high-priority” work, even after launch," states the letter.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Signatories also claim Gerhard and Benzies completely mishandled the redundancy process, causing "distress and confusion" across the board.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Employees have received misinformation, been handed dismissal notices with the wrong notice periods, and been put in the wrong teams so that their performances were scored by the wrong people," the letter continues. "These and other errors have potentially resulted in the wrongful dismissal of dozens of staff members."&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="&quot;CEOs need to take a backseat and allow the skilled people who remain at the company to forge the path ahead&quot;">"CEOs need to take a backseat and allow the skilled people who remain at the company to forge the path ahead"</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">All 93 signees say both executives consistently failed to effectively communicate with the very employees whose expertise the company relied upon. "Information has been sparse and vague, with you often making radical changes to the way we worked with little or no input from those affected," the letter adds.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Gerhard and Benzies are ultimately accused of inflicting pain and stress on BARB employees by failing to adequately take responsibly for the company and its workforce.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-panders-to-america-heart-machine-in-trouble-and-what-next-for-ea-patch-notes-26" target="_self" data-discover="true">Ubisoft reportedly panders to America, Heart Machine in trouble, and what next for EA? - Patch Notes #26</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our experience at the company has been one of burnout, job insecurity, health issues, and the failure of a game that many of us have put years of our lives into," the letter continues. "BARB needs to change. CEOs need to take a backseat and allow the skilled people who remain at the company to forge the path ahead."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">All signatories are demanding a public apology for the mistreatment they experienced and proper compensation for laid-off employees. They are want to be granted an option that will enable remaining employees on redundancy notice to either work their notice period to take Payment in Lieu of Notice (PILON).&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In addition, they want Gerhard and Benzies to make a concerted, meaningful, and documented effort to improve workplace conditions—including the acknowledgement of IWGB as a trade union—and commit to using official external partners to action any future redundancies and prevent unfair treatment.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Mark Gerhard and Leslie Benzies, you often refer to your employees as 'family,'" concludes the letter. "But we ask you to consider; is this really how you treat your own?"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to BARB for comment.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mindseye-devs-accuse-studio-leaders-of-mishandling-layoffs-and-mandating-crunch]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>