<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 19:30:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atreus Has Been Cast In Amazon’s Live-Action God Of War Series]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2026/02/09/atreus-has-been-cast-in-amazons-live-action-god-of-war-series</link>
            <guid>1430281</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><a href="https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/14/thor-actor-from-god-of-war-ragnarok-cast-as-kratos-in-live-action-series">After casting Kratos last month</a>, Amazon has filled the role of Atreus for its upcoming God of War live-action series. As reported by <a href="https://variety.com/2026/tv/news/god-of-war-live-action-series-cast-callum-vinson-atreus-1236656985/"><em>Variety</em></a>, Callum Vinson will play the role of Kratos’ young son from the Norse series of games.</p><p>Vinson will play opposite Ryan Hurst’s Kratos in the upcoming series. The young actor has previously appeared in series such as <em>Chucky, Long Bright River, Poker Face, </em>and<em> Dead Ringers.</em>&nbsp;He also voices Piglet in the animated series&nbsp;<em>Me &amp; Winnie the Pooh</em>/<em>Playdate with Winnie the Pooh.</em> In addition to God of War, Vinson’s upcoming appearances include roles in Netflix’s <em>The Night Agent,</em> and he<em> </em>will portray a young Jason Voorhees in Peacock’s <em>Crystal Lake</em>, a prequel to <em>Friday the 13th</em> slated to premiere this year.</p>



<article alt="Callum Vinson" title="Callum Vinson" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="3119da42-957e-43cd-b553-9ccb4e134399" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="image:responsive_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;responsive_image_style&quot;:&quot;content_body&quot;,&quot;image_loading&quot;:{&quot;attribute&quot;:&quot;lazy&quot;},&quot;image_link&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;Callum Vinson&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

  
          <picture>
                  <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/body_default/public/2026/02/09/752dd0d7/callum_vinson.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 851px)" type="image/webp" width="408" height="600">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2026/02/09/752dd0d7/callum_vinson.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 315px) and (max-width: 450px)" type="image/webp" width="272" height="400">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2026/02/09/752dd0d7/callum_vinson.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (max-width: 314px)" type="image/webp" width="272" height="400">
                  

  </picture>


  
  
      <p>Callum Vinson</p>
  
</article>

<p>Amazon’s <em>God of War</em> adapts the storyline of 2018’s God of War, which features Kratos and Atreus on a journey to lay Faye, Kratos’ wife and Atreus’ mother, to rest. <em>Deadline</em> shares Atreus’ official show description as:</p><p>"The ten-year old son of Kratos, who grew up in a remote forest cabin, isolated from the rest of the world and raised almost entirely by his mother Faye. He is an accomplished archer, has an affinity for animals and is intensely curious about what lies beyond the confines of his forest home. After his mother’s death, Atreus is left with a cold, distant father who he barely knows and who knows little about him in return. Nonetheless, Atreus yearns for his father’s approval and is desperate to prove he is strong enough to survive in a harsh and dangerous world."</p><p>So far, the announced cast is as follows:</p><p>Ryan Hurst - Kratos<br>Callum Vinson - Atreus<br>Max Parker - Heimdall<br>Ólafur Darri Ólafsson - Thor<br>Mandy Patinkin - Odin<br>Alastair Duncan - Mimir<br>Danny Woodburn - Brok<br>Jeff Gulka - Sindri</p><p>Amazon’s <em>God of War</em> currently has a two-season order and is now in pre-production in Vancouver. The series is led by showrunner, writer, and executive producer Ronald D. Moore (<em>Outlander, Battlestar Galactica</em>). It will be co-produced by Sony Pictures Television, Amazon MGM Studios, PlayStation Productions, and Tall Boy Productions.</p><p>[<em>Source: </em><a href="https://variety.com/2026/tv/news/god-of-war-live-action-series-cast-callum-vinson-atreus-1236656985/"><em>Variety</em></a>]</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2026/02/09/atreus-has-been-cast-in-amazons-live-action-god-of-war-series]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>