<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:32:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Federal Judge casts doubt on Epic v. Google settlement terms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/california-court-postpones-approval-of-proposed-settlement-between-epic-games-and-google</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/federal-judge-casts-doubt-on-epic-v-google-settlement-terms.1351363/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">November 12, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A California federal court has postponed the approval of last week's proposed settlement between Epic Games and Google following concerns from judge James Donato, who has been overseeing the case.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Via </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://80.lv/articles/epic-games-google-settlement-under-review-as-us-judge-raises-concerns">80 Level</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, this presents yet another roadblock for the lawsuit filed back in 2020. The settlement was proposed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/_fortnite_-maker-epic-wins-antitrust-lawsuit-against-google">two years after a federal judge</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> ruled that Google Play constituted an illegal monopoly on Android devices.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The settlement proposed introducing a new tiered service fee to allow developers to retain a larger cut of each transaction for their apps, capping fees at nine or 20 percent depending on the type of transaction and the date on which the app was installed. This was joined by the ability to include alternative payment options and for developers to be free to set different prices for transactions on alternative platforms, as well as Google removing "scare screens" and allow easy installation of approved alternative app stores.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Said agreement was pending approval, which judge James Donato has not granted. The judge said the proposal may not meet the legal threshold required to modify the existing court ruling, which could include shifts in market conditions, company policy, or legislation, to justify the revisions.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The only changed circumstance that I can see right now is Epic and Google—two mortal enemies who pounded each other relentlessly in this courtroom for many years—are suddenly BFFs," Donato said.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/rockstart-hit-with-legal-claims-by-iwgb-over-firing-of-unionizing-workers" target="_self" data-discover="true">Rockstar hit with legal claims by IWGB over firing of unionizing workers</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="A new hearing is slated sometime in the next couple of months">A new hearing is slated sometime in the next couple of months</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The judge on the case has scheduled another hearing, which is taking place in either December or January, to further review the agreement.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Both Epic and Google wanted to keep the full details of the settlement confidential, which Donato rejected, saying he doesn't "want to do this in the dark."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As of October 29, Google is already prohibited from forcing developers in the United States to use Google Play Billing, or from restricting alternative payment systems.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When talking about the proposed changes on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/ssamat/status/1985920218602918343">X (formerly Twitter)</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Android president Sameer Samat said these would "focus on expanding developer choice and flexibility, lowering fees, and encouraging more competition all while keeping users safe." He added that, if these changes were approved, that would resolve the litigations between the companies.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Meanwhile, Epic Games CEO Tim Sweeney </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1985920786545123613">called the settlement "awesome,"</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> adding that "it genuinely doubles down on Android's original vision as an open platform to streamline competing store installs globally, reduce service fees for developers on Google Play, and enable third-party in-app and web payments."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sony-unveils-japanese-language-only-playstation-5-at-350" target="_self" data-discover="true">Sony unveils Japanese-language-only PlayStation 5 at $350</a></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/california-court-postpones-approval-of-proposed-settlement-between-epic-games-and-google]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>