<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:30:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tekken boss Katsuhiro Harada is leaving Bandai Namco]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/tekken-boss-katsuhiro-harada-is-leaving-bandai-namco</link>
            <guid>1375945</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">December 8, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Tekken boss Katsuhiro Harada is departing Bandai Namco at the end of 2025. The veteran developer has worked on the fighting series for around three decades at Bandai Namco, eventually taking charge of the franchise as executive game director and chief producer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/Harada_TEKKEN/status/1997952347709034747">In a post on X</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Harada reflected on his time at the studio and the legacy of a franchise that shaped "the core of who I am as a developer and game creator."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"My roots lie in the days when I supported small local tournaments in Japanese arcades and in small halls and community centers overseas. I still remember carrying arcade cabinets by myself, encouraging people to 'Please try Tekken,' and directly facing the players right in front of me. The conversations and atmosphere we shared in those places became the core of who I am as a developer and game creator," he wrote.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Even as the times changed, those experiences have remained at the center of my identity. And even after the tournament scene grew much larger, many of you continued to treat me like an old friend—challenging me at venues, inviting me out for drinks at bars. Those memories are also deeply precious to me."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Harada prepared for his departure in recent years by slowly handing over his responsibilities to his colleagues. He explained that, with the Tekken franchise approaching its 30th anniversary, it now feels right to move on.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-iam8bit-sues-skybound-alleging-fraud" target="_self" data-discover="true">Report: iam8bit sues Skybound, alleging fraud</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He also spoke highly of his time spent working on other projects such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Pokken Tournament</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, SoulCalibur, and VR title </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Summer Lesson</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Each project was full of new discoveries and learning, and every one of them became an irreplaceable experience for me. To everyone who has supported me, to communities around the world, and to all the colleagues who have walked alongside me for so many years, I offer my deepest gratitude," he finished. "I'll share more about my next steps at a later date. Thank you very much for everything."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Harada will make a guest appearance at the Tekken World Tour Finals in January 2026 to bid farewell to the Tekken community in person.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/tekken-boss-katsuhiro-harada-is-leaving-bandai-namco]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>