<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:33:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Players Are Making Larger Maps Because The Game Doesn't Have Them Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-players-are-making-larger-maps-because-the-game-doesnt-have-them-yet/1100-6536010/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-players-are-making-larger-maps-because-the-game-doesnt-have-them-yet.1346167/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536010">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/battlefield-6/" data-ref-id="5000-687940">Battlefield 6</a> has largely been well-received by players, but it's not as if it can't be improved. In particular, Battlefield 6 fans have been requesting bigger maps in Conquest, and they didn't wait around for Battlefield Studios to do it. Instead, a handful of fans have created their own big maps with Battlefield Portal and REDSEC.</p><p>Reddit users andy_6170 and kurtinthegrind have joined forces to create Club House, a Conquest play area that has plenty of space for large scale battles to break out. There are options for bots or botless versions of Club House, as well as servers that can support 64 real players. The Conquest and Tech Center options open up most of the map, while Operation Tech Center offers a smaller-scale experience in and around a single building. As described by the creators, Conquest mode features "vehicles, semi-urban areas ideal for infantry fights, and hills perfect for snipers. It's also a great map for helicopter combat!"</p><p>Separately, Battlefield lead producer David Sirland wrote on <a href="https://x.com/tiggr_/status/1985980359436083539" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">X</a> that the game needs "more of the large sandbox types for sure though!" Sirland indicated that maps and weapons will be added continuously over time. He also noted that the dev team will be "looking at fixing issues on the existing maps, and changing things up when necessary to make it better too, of course."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/tiggr_/status/1985980837293408370" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Maps and weapons is of course the biggest area we'll just keep adding to over time, so this will move in that direction for sure.<br>We are also looking at fixing issues on the existing maps, and changing things up when necessary to make it better too of course.</p>  — David Sirland (@tiggr_) <a href="https://twitter.com/tiggr_/status/1985980837293408370?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Earlier this week, Battlefield Studios made adjustments to Battlefield 6 to make some of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6s-challenges-have-become-signiciantly-easier-to-complete/1100-6535960/" data-ref-id="1100-6535960">the achievements easier to complete</a>. Sirland also explained <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/without-battlefield-6-bots-youd-be-waiting-a-lot-longer-producer-says/1100-6535956/" data-ref-id="1100-6535956">why the bots are necessary</a> to fill up the servers in order to get matches started more quickly.</p><p>So far, Battlefield 6 has sold over <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-reaches-10-million-copies-sold-but-wont-be-enough-to-topple-call-of-duty-analyst-says/1100-6535920/" data-ref-id="1100-6535920">10 million copies</a>. However, its momentum may suffer when Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 launches on November 14 for Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-players-are-making-larger-maps-because-the-game-doesnt-have-them-yet/1100-6536010/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Might Be Getting KPop Demon Hunters Jam Tracks After All]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-might-be-getting-kpop-demon-hunters-jam-tracks-after-all/1100-6536009/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-might-be-getting-kpop-demon-hunters-jam-tracks-after-all.1346137/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536009">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fortnite/" data-ref-id="5000-125765">Fortnite</a>'s collaboration with KPop Demon Hunters is not done yet, if new leaks are to be believed. The first wave of the collab saw a bundle of skins based on the HUNTR/X trio hit the item shop, while the seasonal Horde Rush mode got a KPop Demon Hunters-themed makeover. Now, <a href="https://x.com/SamLeakss/status/1986484452563034475" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">word is</a> that KPop Demon Hunters will return to Fortnite with a jam track for the song "Golden."</p><p>The KPop Demon Hunters collab was noticeably missing any jam tracks or dance emotes with music from the Netflix film. That absence was likely the result of how quickly the collab was put together. Since the movie wasn't expected to be such a massive hit, the deal might have gone from conception to fruition in just a couple months--that's lightning speed for something like this.</p><p>Right now, the only leak about further KPop Demon Hunters content in Fortnite is about the jam track for "Golden." It's possible that other HUNTR/X jam tracks could be added, or that a new wave of skins could come with the tracks, but there's no info about that just yet. The members of HUNTR/X are also prime candidates for the next music pass in December, but there haven't been any leaks about future Festival-season headliners.</p><p>Fortnite has followed up the packed Halloween event that introduced the KPop Demon Hunters to Epic's metaverse with a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/everything-new-in-fortnite-simpsons-season/2900-7202/" data-ref-id="2900-7202">Simpsons takeover over of the main Battle Royale mode</a>, which has boosted Battle Royale and Zero Build to their highest player counts of the year so far.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-might-be-getting-kpop-demon-hunters-jam-tracks-after-all/1100-6536009/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix Reportedly Conducting Mass Layoffs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/square-enix-reportedly-conducting-mass-layoffs/1100-6536007/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-reportedly-conducting-mass-layoffs.1346134/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536007">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Square Enix is enacting a round of mass layoffs, according to multiple reports. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-undergoes-mass-layoffs-as-it-reorganizes-to-consolidate-development-in-japan" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IGN </a>and <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/square-enix-announces-more-layoffs-as-part-of-us-and-europe-restructuring/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">VGC</a> reported that Square Enix informed affected staff today that cuts are being made as part of a "fundamental restructuring of the overseas publishing organization," referring to the company's Western business.</p><p>Cuts are beng made in Europe and America to help Square Enix become more "lean" and "agile," president Takashi Kiryu told staff. The extent of the cuts was not confirmed, but VGC reported that at almost 140 people at the London office alone were "at risk" of being laid off. </p><p>The cuts are affecting various departments, including IT, marketing, publishing, sales, QA, and business planning, the report said.</p><p>In 2024, Square Enix also made cuts to its Western teams. Square Enix also sold assets as part of its reorganization effort, selling developers like Crystal Dynamics, Eidos-Montreal, and Square Enix Montreal to Embracer. </p><p>Square Enix's latest earnings briefing included <a href="https://www.hd.square-enix.com/eng/news/pdf/20251106_01_en.pdf" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a slide</a> detailing how the company would conduct a "fundamental restructuring of the overseas publishing organization" with the aim of "further strengthening global publishing capabilities and improving operational efficiency."</p><p>Square Enix is projecting an annual cost savings of more than 3 billion yen ($19.6 million) as part of the restructuring. Another effort Square Enix is undertaking is further adoption of AI, with the company recently announcing it wants to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/square-enix-wants-genai-to-automate-70-of-game-qa-by-2027/1100-6535996/" data-ref-id="1100-6535996">use genAI to automate 70% of game QA by 2027.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/square-enix-reportedly-conducting-mass-layoffs/1100-6536007/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Screwed Up Apu's Look In The New Simpsons Season, And Epic Is Fixing It]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-screwed-up-apus-look-in-the-new-simpsons-season-and-epic-is-fixing-it/1100-6536006/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-screwed-up-apus-look-in-the-new-simpsons-season-and-epic-is-fixing-it.1346101/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536006">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2025-11-06T10:55:34-0800">November 6, 2025 at 10:55AM PST</time></p></section>
        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Epic Games has acknowledged a mistake with its new Simpsons update in Fortnite pertaining to the character Apu Nahasapeemapetilon.</p><p>After the new season began, people quickly noticed that an image of Apu shows the character with the <a href="https://x.com/MemeManTweets/status/1985126383396274588" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">same yellow skin tone</a> as his fellow <a href="https://simpsons.fandom.com/wiki/The_Be_Sharps" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Be Sharps</a> quartet members Homer, Barney, and Principal Skinner.</p><p>This was a mistake and Epic will fix it. "This wasn't intentional. It's being adjusted in our next release," <a href="https://x.com/fortnitestatus/status/1986245741820743979" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Epic said</a>.</p><p>The picture can be found in Moe's Tavern, and the venue also hosts a picture of Homer, Moe, Otto, and Apu, and in that photo, Apu has the <a href="https://x.com/nescartridges/status/1985572143141126357" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">screen-accurate skin tone from the TV show</a>. Given that, many assumed this was an oversight on Epic's part, and that does indeed seem to be true.</p><p>Apu has been sidelined in some ways on The Simpsons TV series, as the character has not spoken a word on the show for years after actor Hank Azaria announced that he would stop voicing him. This came after the documentary The Problem with Apu brought up a discussion about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-simpsons-responds-to-apu-controversy-and-some-/1100-6458105/" data-ref-id="1100-6458105">negative racial stereotypes.</a></p><p>The Fortnite x Simpsons season has been a big hit, propelling Fortnite to the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnites-simpsons-update-led-to-a-huge-surge-in-players-the-most-in-a-long-time/1100-6535919/" data-ref-id="1100-6535919">biggest player numbers since 2024.</a></p><p>The new Fortnite season, which runs through November 29, brings a new Springfield map to Fortnite featuring locations like Moe's Tavern, the Kwik-E-Mart, and the Springfield nuclear plant. There is also a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/fortnite-battle-pass-for-simpsons-season-all-skins-and-other-rewards/2900-7205/" data-ref-id="2900-7205">new Simpsons battle pass</a>, which includes skins for characters like Homer and Marge, along with variants like Stupid Sexy Flanders. Epic is also offering up a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/free-fortnite-glider-how-to-unlock-the-simpsons-dlc-right-now-before-it-costs-money/1100-6535889/" data-ref-id="1100-6535889">free Kang and Kodos glider for people who link their Epic and MyDisney accounts.</a></p><p dir="ltr">Looking ahead, Fortnite dataminers believe they've found evidence pointing to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-dataminers-suggest-harry-potter-and-spongebob-collabs-could-be-next/1100-6535870/">future collaborations with SpongeBob SquarePants and Harry Potter</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-screwed-up-apus-look-in-the-new-simpsons-season-and-epic-is-fixing-it/1100-6536006/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders' Store Now Features A Very Odd Diving Suit]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-store-now-features-a-very-odd-diving-suit/1100-6536008/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-store-now-features-a-very-odd-diving-suit.1346098/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536008">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/arc-raiders/" data-ref-id="5000-546105">Arc Raiders</a>' in-game store has just received a fresh update for any players looking to brave the mech-ridden wasteland in some stylish new gear. Even Scrappy, everyone's favorite rooster, is getting in on the fun.</p><p>Alongside a new patch, Arc Raiders has some new looks for the fashion-forward players by way of the new Wilderness Scout and Leviathan sets. The former is the more affordable of the two and will cost players 1,150 raider tokens, which translates to $10. The latter, which is a bit more extravagant, will run folks 1,600 tokens, or roughly $15.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/ARCRaidersGame/status/1986478734539452567" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">📡Store update<br>Whether you're cutting new paths topside or wading through the muck for buried treasure, gear up like a true survivor.<br>The Leviathan Set and Wilderness Scout Set are out now; built for those who know the world still has wonders left to find. <a href="https://t.co/ZsCIe8H3A2" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/ZsCIe8H3A2</a></p>  — ARC Raiders (@ARCRaidersGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/ARCRaidersGame/status/1986478734539452567?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 6, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>The Wilderness Scout set is more toned-down than its companion and most resembles common hiking gear. The player is outfitted in a long coat (whose colorways can be changed), tights and ice cleats, as well as a sort of aviation helmet. The helmet's visor can be kept up or down, and the whole headpiece can be toggled off, revealing the set's soot-covered skin, recalling the defining look of Furiosa from George Miller's recent Mad Max movies.</p><p>The Leviathan set, as the name might suggest, is far more nautical. The whole thing resembles a kind of old-fashioned diving suit, complete with a lavish fishbowl helmet that'll definitely raise an eyebrow or two in the heat of battle. I'm burning up just thinking of wearing that thing in the desert.</p><p>The Leviathan skin comes with an oxygen tank, and a backpack covered in netting, as well as what appears to be some barnacles. I wouldn't loot that thing with a 10-foot (and deeply sterilized) pole.</p><p>Additionally, Scrappy, the rooster who frequents players' home base and scavenges for materials, can be equipped with a miniaturized version of the Leviathan diving helmet as part of the Deep Sea Bird set, which is going for another $10.</p><p>That isn't all players should expect though. A new update that just released will be rolling out new map conditions for folks to experience, and a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-roadmap-reveals-new-map-in-november-quests-and-more-in-the-months-ahead/1100-6535859/" data-ref-id="1100-6535859">pair of exciting updates</a> are coming to Arc Raiders over the next few months, introducing new quests, gear, maps, and more.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-store-now-features-a-very-odd-diving-suit/1100-6536008/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Members Get These 13 Free Games In November]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-members-get-these-13-free-games-in-november/1100-6535872/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-prime-members-get-these-13-free-games-in-november.1346047/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535872">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Amazon has revealed the next batch of PC games that'll be coming to <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/prime/pipeline/signup?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Prime Gaming</a> in November, and this month, you can explore the Borderlands, cook up a scrumptious meal, and explore dungeons that might contain dragons.</p><p>As a reminder, all of the free games that you claim through Prime Gaming are yours to keep forever, even if your subscription expires. If you aren't a member, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/prime/pipeline/signup?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">you can sign up for Amazon Prime</a> for as little as one month to take advantage of the subscription and the freebies offered through it.</p><h2>Prime Gaming free games for November 2025</h2><h2>Now available</h2><ul><li>New Tales from the Borderlands [Epic Games Store]</li><li>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Dark Sun Series [GOG Code]</li><li>Gas Station Simulator [Epic Games Store]</li><li>Lovecraft's Untold Stories [Epic Games Store]</li></ul><h2>November 13</h2><ul><li>Another World: 20th Anniversary Edition [GOG Code]</li><li>Fallout 76 [PC via Microsoft Games Store]</li><li>Fort Solis [GOG Code]</li><li>Dark City: Kyiv Collector's Edition [Amazon Games App]</li><li>PlateUp! [Epic Games Store]</li></ul><h2>November 20</h2><ul><li>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Krynn Series [GOG Code]</li><li>Dream Tactics [GOG Code]</li></ul><h2>November 26</h2><ul><li>Big Adventure: Trip to Europe 6 Collector's Edition [Legacy Games Code]</li><li>Gunslugs [GOG Code]</li></ul><p>Prime subscribers will also be able to play the following games in October via the Prime Gaming Luna channel:</p><ul><li>Courtroom Chaos: Starring Snoop Dogg</li><li>Angry Birds Flock party</li><li>Taboo</li><li>Clue</li><li>Hogwarts Legacy</li><li>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</li><li>Dave the Diver</li><li>Farming Simulator 22</li><li>SpongeBob SquarePants: Battle for Bikini Bottom - Rehydrated</li><li>Rise of the Tomb Raider</li><li>Two-Point Hospital</li><li>Bus Simulator 21: Next Stop</li><li>World War Z</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

    
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-members-get-these-13-free-games-in-november/1100-6535872/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Company Of Heroes 3 Will Get New Battlegroup DLC This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/company-of-heroes-3-will-get-new-battlegroup-dlc-this-month/1100-6535973/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/company-of-heroes-3-will-get-new-battlegroup-dlc-this-month.1346011/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535973">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In 2023, Relic Entertainment's real-time strategy game, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/company-of-heroes-3/" data-ref-id="5000-534671">Company of Heroes 3</a>, dived into rarely explored corners of World War 2 by letting players control Allied Forces during the invasion of Italy as well as Axis soldiers during their attempt to conquer North Africa. Later this month, Relic is adding a new Battlegroup DLC, Endure &amp; Defy, which may shake up the war during multiplayer and co-op/skirmish vs, A.I. fights.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1Ryr8UF4SX4" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1Ryr8UF4SX4" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Each of the four factions is getting their own battlegroup. The U.S. forces will have access to the Italian Partisans, a resistance group that aids their efforts behind enemy lines through sabotage, hidden tunnels, and fighters who will go into battle alongside your troops.</p><p>Germany's Wehrmacht will receive a Last Stand battlegroup that exists to slow down the Allied advance with imposing new vehicles including the Borgward Wanze and Pantherturm. The Last Stand group can also demoralize their enemy through propaganda towers, Panzerfaust rollouts, and improvised barrages.</p><p>British forces will be given backup from the Polish cavalry battlegroup, which thrives against veteran soldiers with a deep desire for revenge against the Nazis. The cavalry is equipped with heavy weaponry, Polish-crewed Sherman Fireflies, and Land Mattresses.</p><p>Deutsches Afrikakorps--aka Germany's Africa expedition force--is getting support from the German navy, the Kriegsmarine. This battlegroup can fortify positions with "catastrophic fire support" while opening up supply chains for troops. The Kriegsmarine can provide supply drops, engineering know-how, and "combat flexibility."</p><p>Company of Heroes 3 Battlegroup DLC - Endure &amp; Defy will drop November 27 on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1677280/Company_of_Heroes_3/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam</a>. It's regular price is $25, but it will be offered at 10% off that price for the first two weeks. During that time, new players can also purchase the core Company of Heroes 3 game for 60% off its normal $60 price.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/company-of-heroes-3-will-get-new-battlegroup-dlc-this-month/1100-6535973/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>