<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:44:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Narrative Superhero Game Dispatch Launches Next Month With First Two Playable Episodes]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/16/narrative-superhero-game-dispatch-launches-next-month-with-first-two-playable-episodes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/narrative-superhero-game-dispatch-launches-next-month-with-first-two-playable-episodes.1299225/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Dispatch, the narrative adventure game that puts you in charge of dispatching various superheroes and reformed villains to those in need in a city, launches next month. More specifically, Dispatch will launch on PlayStation 5 and PC on October 22, marking the beginning of its four-week release.&nbsp;</p><p>Developed by AdHoc Studio, a team comprised of Telltale alumni, Dispatch consists of eight playable episodes, with the first two scheduled for release on October 22. Two episodes will be released each week for four consecutive weeks. The full season will cost $30, or you can purchase the Deluxe Version, which includes a digital artbook and four digital comics, for $40.&nbsp;</p><p>Check out the Dispatch PS5 and PC release date trailer, courtesy of <em>IGN</em>, below:&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rrWos4NShT8"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rrWos4NShT8" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Dispatch launches on October 22 on PS5 and PC.&nbsp;</p><p>We've enjoyed what we played of <a href="https://gameinformer.com/round-up/2025/06/13/the-25-best-steam-next-fest-demos-you-need-to-try">Dispatch during the June Steam Next Fest</a>, and we learned a lot from AdHoc in our exclusive behind-the-scenes feature you can read <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/08/26/suiting-back-up">here</a>. For more, check out <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/03/28/the-league-of-upcoming-superhero-games"><em>Game Informer's </em>list of upcoming superhero games</a>.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Are you starting Dispatch next month? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/16/narrative-superhero-game-dispatch-launches-next-month-with-first-two-playable-episodes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hit Viking Survival Game Valheim Is Finally Coming To PS5 Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/16/hit-viking-survival-game-valheim-is-finally-coming-to-ps5-next-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hit-viking-survival-game-valheim-is-finally-coming-to-ps5-next-year.1299174/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/valheim">Valheim</a>, the hit indie Viking survival game from developer Iron Gate AB and Coffee Stain Publishing, is finally coming to PlayStation 5 in 2026. It's currently unclear, though, if this version of the game will be 1.0 or Early Access.&nbsp;</p><p>Valheim launched into Early Access on PC back in 2021, quickly <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2021/02/08/valheim-dominates-best-seller-list-on-steam">climbing up the Steam charts</a> to become one of the most popular survival games of the year. That excitement continued well into 2022, with the audience growing in 2023 when <a href="https://gameinformer.com/psa/2023/03/14/valheim-is-now-available-on-xbox-and-game-pass">Valheim launched into Game Preview on Xbox Series X/S and Xbox One</a>, featuring cross-play as well. Now, Valheim is finally coming to PS5, and you can check out a new trailer celebrating the news below.&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lRSy1vtQxqg"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lRSy1vtQxqg" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Since Valheim's Early Access debut in 2021, it has garnered a 94 percent "Very Positive" rating on Steam, based on over 477,000 reviews and 12 million copies sold. Since that launch, Iron Gate AB has released various updates, including the following:&nbsp;</p><ul><li><strong>Hearth and Home:</strong> enhanced survival and base-building mechanics</li><li><strong>Mistlands: </strong>introduced a new fog-shrouded biome filled with dangerous creatures and magic to master</li><li><strong>Ashlands:</strong> introduced treacherous cliffs, boiling waters, and new threats</li><li><strong>Call To Arms: </strong>the latest update, which updated combat and added new enemies, weapons, armor sets, and crafting materials&nbsp;</li></ul><p>Valheim launches on PS5 in 2026. It is currently available on Xbox Series X/S and Xbox One (including Xbox Game Pass), PC via Steam Early Access, the Microsoft Store, PC Game Pass, and the Mac App Store.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Are you still playing Valheim? Let us know why we should be playing it in 2025 below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/16/hit-viking-survival-game-valheim-is-finally-coming-to-ps5-next-year]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>