<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 14:49:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Off The Grid, The Cyberpunk Battle Royale From District 9 Director Neill Blomkamp, Hits Steam Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/21/off-the-grid-the-cyberpunk-battle-royale-from-district-9-director-neill-blomkamp-hits</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/off-the-grid-the-cyberpunk-battle-royale-from-district-9-director-neill-blomkamp-hits-steam-next-month.1195038/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/05/21/off-the-grid-the-cyberpunk-battle-royale-from-district-9-director-neill-blomkamp-hits<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Gunzilla Games has announced that <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/off-the-grid">Off The Grid</a>, its cyberpunk battle royale <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2022/05/05/district-9-director-neill-blomkamp-is-working-on-off-the-grid-a-cyberpunk-battle-royale">featuring a narrative by <em>District 9</em> director Neill Blomkamp</a>, is coming to Steam in June. It launched into Early Access on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC via the Epic Games Store last October, and now, it’s coming to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3659280/Off_The_Grid/">Steam</a> via Early Access as well.</p><hr><p><em><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> Gunzilla Games is the parent company of Game Informer Inc.. All editorial coverage is selected and completed by our content team, without influence from owners or other outside parties.</em></p><hr><p>As part of the Steam launch, Off The Grid will support full crossplay across PlayStation, Xbox, and PC, allowing players to link up regardless of where they’re playing the game. Gunzilla says it has been actively evolving the game in line with community feedback with “improved performance, refined balancing, and introduced new cybernetic limbs, weapons, locations, and game modes.”</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sZ1iA9LgQPY"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sZ1iA9LgQPY" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>“Bringing Off The Grid to Steam is a major milestone for us, not just because of the platform’s reach, but because it allows us to welcome an entirely new wave of players into a game that’s been built hand-in-hand with the community,” CEO and co-founder of Gunzilla Games Vlad Korolov said in a press release. “From new limbs and weapons to map expansions and performance upgrades, every major step forward has been shaped by player feedback. This launch is a celebration of that collaboration, and it’s only the beginning.”</p><p>You can wishlist Off The Grid on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3659280/Off_The_Grid/">Steam</a> starting today. It launches there next month, though Gunzilla did not announce the exact date. &nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Are you going to check out Off The Grid on Steam next month? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>