<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 19:51:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's Why Your Nintendo Switch 2 Display Looks So Blurry]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-why-your-nintendo-switch-2-display-looks-so-blurry/1100-6532692/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-why-your-nintendo-switch-2-display-looks-so-blurry.1227342/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532692">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The Nintendo Switch 2 makes some big improvements over the first console, especially when comparing it to the first iteration that came out in 2017. A lot of that has to do with the significantly more powerful APU, but the larger, crisper screen is certainly the upgrade you'll notice first. It could also be the area where you might notice where the Switch 2 falls short of its predecessor.</p><p>Shortly after release, some discussions regarding how blurry the on-board display seemed to be started surfacing, prompting some hardware publications to take a closer look. Hardware Unboxed, known for detailed reviews of PC hardware and monitors, conducted a few tests on the Nintendo Switch 2 display, taking a closer look at the screen's response time. Running the display through 20 gray-to-gray transitions to measure response times, Hardware Unboxed determined that the Switch 2's LCD was one of the slowest it's ever tested, coming in at 33.3ms.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AB67B8LCorI" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/AB67B8LCorI" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>To put that into context, Hardware Unboxed compared this to an average LCD panel you'll find in entry-level displays today. These were tested in the same manner and averaged out to a response time of 6.3ms. Perhaps the most damning was the comparison to the original Switch's LCD, a display that is more than eight years old, that presented a response time nearly twice as fast a 21.3ms. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-nintendo-switch-2-the-digital-foundry-hardware-review" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Digital Foundry</a> noted the same issues with the display in its extensive Nintendo Switch 2 review earlier this week, noting that, "The Switch 2 LCD has blurring characteristics that are easily worse than the 2017 Switch's display"</p><p>Why does a fast response time matter? With slower response times, it takes longer for the image on-screen to transition between new frames, which can lead to noticeable blurring with objects in motion. This is particularly bad when the Switch 2 is running games at 60fps, which thus far is the preferred frame rate of most first-party titles. To put it into perspective, it takes 16.67ms for a new frame to be rendered when running at 60Hz, but it takes the display twice as long to transition from one frame to the next, causing a significant bottleneck that reduces the impact of improved motion clarity that higher refresh rates provide. This would be just as bad, if not worse, in games making use of the full 120Hz the new display has to offer.</p><p>It's unclear why this is happening, but Hardware Unboxed offers a suggestion that Nintendo has decided to reduce an overdrive support for the display (which uses higher voltages to drive faster transitions) in the pursuit of better battery life. With a display that is brighter and larger, Nintendo might have potentially reduced its ability to transition faster as a tradeoff. Given that the Nintendo Switch 2 ships with a 19Wh battery, less than half of that found in Valve's Steam Deck, it's understandable why this concession might have been made. But considering how noticeable it can be once you've seen it, it could make portable play significantly less desirable until addressed, if it ever is.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-why-your-nintendo-switch-2-display-looks-so-blurry/1100-6532692/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4 Season 9 Will Bring Big, Permanent Changes To Nightmare Dungeons]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-9-will-bring-big-permanent-changes-to-nightmare-dungeons/1100-6532690/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4-season-9-will-bring-big-permanent-changes-to-nightmare-dungeons.1227303/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532690">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>One of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-iv/" data-ref-id="5000-504255">Diablo 4</a>'s main endgame activities, Nightmare dungeons, will be permanently changed come Season 9, as Blizzard looks to make them both more challenging and surprising going forward.</p><p dir="ltr">As detailed in a new <a href="https://news.blizzard.com/en-us/article/24215863/purge-the-sins-of-the-horadrim" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">blog post</a>, when Season 9 launches July 1, Nightmare dungeons will receive some major updates. Most notably, there will be a new activity within them called Horadric Strongrooms. Described as a "potent micro-dungeon," strongrooms will be found more frequently on higher Torment difficulties and can also be reliably found by using a Nightmare dungeon sigil that guarantees the appearance of a strongroom.</p><p dir="ltr">Once players are inside the dungeon, players can discover a portal that will take them to the strongroom. In a system somewhat similar to Diablo 4's Infernal Hordes activity, players will be able to select from a number of statues that add modifiers to the strongroom, increasing the challenge but also the rewards.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6W5UkhQVtMQ" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6W5UkhQVtMQ" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Players will then need to attune themselves with the strongroom by slaying enemies within the vicinity of Horadric Pillars within a time limit. Those who complete the attunement process will be transported to the micro-dungeon's final boss that when defeated will reward a Grand Horadric cache that scales its rewards based on the amount of attunement players earned. These caches will include Obducite as a reward, an endgame material needed to Masterwork weapons and armor. Completing the strongroom will also grant a buff that lasts for the remainder of the Nightmare dungeon, which a chance to receive more XP from monsters, increased reputation gains, increased Obducite drops, 25% more gold, or Horadric Phial drops (a seasonal item that is used to make Horadric Jewels).</p><p dir="ltr">There will, however, be another new way to experience Nightmare dungeons--Escalating Nightmares. This new endgame activity is a sequence of three Nightmare dungeons that see dungeon affixes stack from one to the next, with monster difficulty additionally increasing for each subsequent dungeon.</p><p dir="ltr">To access an Escalating Nightmare, players will need to find Escalation Sigils from completing Horadric Strongrooms. In pre-Torment difficulties, completing all three dungeons will finish the Escalating Nightmare. However, those playing on Torment difficulties will instead be transported to a boss fight, where players will take on a new version of Astaroth from the Diablo 4 main campaign. Players will need to defeat both Astaroth and his steed, which will become separate bosses over the course of the fight. Defeating Astaroth's mount first will see it go into a resurrection state, after which it will rejoin the fight if players can't defeat Astaroth in time. Astaroth can also be modified by Nightmare dungeon affixes, making the boss fight even more challenging.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4520164-diablo4season9infographic.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4520164" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4520164-diablo4season9infographic.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4520164"></a><figcaption>A look at everything coming as part of Diablo 4 Season 9.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4520164-diablo4season9infographic.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Last but not least, Nightmare dungeons will receive new affixes. Each Nightmare sigil will sport both a positive and negative affix. New positive affixes include the guaranteed appearance of specific shrines, increased XP gains, the appearance of Treasure Goblins, a guaranteed strongroom, equipment rewards, and currency drops.</p><p dir="ltr">While the Nightmare dungeon changes will be permanent additions to Diablo 4, Season 9 will additionally introduce new seasonal mechanics for a limited-time. Players will be able to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-9-will-let-players-build-their-own-spells/1100-6531782/" data-ref-id="1100-6531782">create and modify Horadric Spells</a> to compliment their builds, and can further augment them using new Horadric Jewels that can be slotted into amulets and rings. One Horadric teleport spell in particular might be</p><p dir="ltr">Updates to Nightmare dungeons are just the latest permanent changes to come as part of a Diablo 4 season. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-diablo-4-season-8-is-making-endgame-bosses-stronger-simpler-to-access-and-more-rewarding/1100-6530970/" data-ref-id="1100-6530970">Season 8 overhauled the game's endgame boss ladder</a>, while previous seasons, like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-diablo-4-loot-reborn-update-will-make-its-items-and-players-more-powerful-than-ever/1100-6523061/" data-ref-id="1100-6523061">Loot Reborn</a>, reworked Diablo 4's entire gear progression system. Diablo 4 Season 9 is not, however, bringing changes to the game's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-new-reliquary-battle-pass-system-is-even-worse-than-players-originally-thought/1100-6532514/" data-ref-id="1100-6532514">new (and unpopular) Reliquary battle pass system</a>, though Blizzard has stated it is listening to player feedback.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-9-will-bring-big-permanent-changes-to-nightmare-dungeons/1100-6532690/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light Gets A "Retouched" Update Soon With All These Improvements, But It's Not A Remaster]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dying-light-gets-a-retouched-update-soon-with-all-these-improvements-but-its-not-a-remaster/1100-6532687/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dying-light-gets-a-retouched-update-soon-with-all-these-improvements-but-its-not-a-remaster.1227297/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532687">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A decade after <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/dying-light/" data-ref-id="5000-182057">Dying Light</a> came out in 2015, developer Techland is revisiting the zombie game with a major new update to refresh the game's visuals and other elements--just don't call it a remaster.</p><p><a href="https://pilgrimoutpost.techlandgg.com/news/ten-years-later-still-going-strong-dying-light-retouched-update-releasing-june-26" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The "Retouched" update</a>, as it's called, launches on June 26. This update is focused on "squeezing out even more" from Dying Light, the studio said. "It's not a complete overhaul or remaster," the developer clarified, adding that the team has found new ways to "squeeze more from the tech we already have."</p><p>"One day, someone just started applying those learnings to some old assets--and it just clicked that we could do that across the whole game," technical game director Grzegorz Świstowski said.</p><p>In the Retouched update, players can expect increased texture quality and upscaling for textures to help them look "sharper" and better overall.</p><p>Additionally, the "maximum level of detail range" in Dying Light has been increased from 260% to 340% in the view distance menu from the game's settings. The studio is also adding new "8K Ultra shadow quality" and improved lighting for many surfaces. Surfaces that might have previously looked "flat" should not "really pop out and get depth."</p><p>Check out some of the images in the gallery below to see the improvements.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4520148-screenshot2025-06-24at1.51.07pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4520148" data-ratio="0.55555555555556" data-width="738" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4520148-screenshot2025-06-24at1.51.07pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4520148"></a><figcaption>The wood now looks more like wood.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4520148-screenshot2025-06-24at1.51.07pm.png"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4520149-screenshot2025-06-24at1.51.12pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4520150-screenshot2025-06-24at1.51.22pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4520149,1300-4520150" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4520149-screenshot2025-06-24at1.51.12pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4520150-screenshot2025-06-24at1.51.22pm.png"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4520149-screenshot2025-06-24at1.51.12pm.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4520150-screenshot2025-06-24at1.51.22pm.png"></figure><p>Beyond visuals, Techland said composer Paweł Blaszczak came back to "give the soundtrack a complete remaster" with a unique twist.</p><p>"He even recreated that retro-tape sound by actually recording on tape! Talk about dedication. It’s authentic, nostalgic, and absolutely fantastic," Techland said, adding that the Retouched update will have new tracks and ambient sounds. Audio in combat has been "juiced up," too.</p><p>"Every swing, every crunch, every zombie takedown will sound more satisfying, more impactful. You'll feel those hits," the developer said.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abQYwONaKgk" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/abQYwONaKgk" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>This Retouched update was first hinted at in January, and Techland said it took so long to realize because of the manual effort required.</p><p>"I basically walked through the entire map, looking for assets to be improved. And all of those had to be changed manually by our artists," lead 3D artist Krzysztof Knefel said.</p><p>The Retouched update doesn't require players to invest in new PC hardware, however, as Techland said it was important to keep the system requirements the same. The Retouched update is also available on PS4 and Xbox One, requiring Techland to test the game "endlessly" to ensure "we didn't run out of memory" for those older consoles.</p><p>The Retouched patch launches June 26 and it's free for everyone across PC, PS4, PS5, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X|S. While the Retouched update promises improvements on all systems, Techland said, "the level of changes may vary by platform," but it didn't dig into specifics.</p><p>June 26 is also the date that CD Projekt Red planned to release Cyberpunk 2077's big new 2.3 update, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077s-big-new-update-delayed/1100-6532620/" data-ref-id="1100-6532620">it's been delayed</a>. Techland and CD Projekt are two of Poland's biggest developers, and fans of their games no longer have to decide what to play first on June 26.</p><p>Dying Light was followed up by 2022's Dying Light 2. The next entry in the series is Dying Light: The Beast, which launches in August for console and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dying-light-gets-a-retouched-update-soon-with-all-these-improvements-but-its-not-a-remaster/1100-6532687/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dune: Awakening Class Tier List - Best Classes To Use]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dune-awakening-class-tier-list-best-classes-to-use/1100-6532561/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dune-awakening-class-tier-list-best-classes-to-use.1227294/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532561">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>At the beginning of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/dune-awakening/" data-ref-id="5000-570883">Dune: Awakening</a>, you're able to select one of four classes for your character, with another being available later on in the game. Your class determines the ability trees you have access to, your stats, and certain playstyles that mesh better with specific classes. While you can make any class into what you want, it's most beneficial to choose a class that you can scale properly and efficiently as you advance in Dune: Awakening.</p><p>There are some classes that are best for beginners, but these classes won't benefit most players in the long run. If you're just looking for the best overall classes in Dune: Awakening, then you can check out the guide below to see a full class tier list and explanations for why each class is ranked where it is.</p><h2>Dune: Awakening class tier list</h2><p>One of the most important aspects of the class system to remember is that you're not locked to your class's ability trees for the entire game. You can eventually interact with "trainers" in Dune: Awakening that allow you to unlock other classes' ability trees, giving you the chance to create a new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dune-awakening-best-starting-class-and-build/1100-6532573/" data-ref-id="1100-6532573">build </a>entirely or add some abilities you previously didn't have access to.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4517702-duneawakeningscreenshot2025.06.05-13.07.30.88.png" data-ref-id="1300-4517702" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4517702-duneawakeningscreenshot2025.06.05-13.07.30.88.png" data-ref-id="1300-4517702"></a><figcaption>Selecting a starting class in Dune: Awakening</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4517702-duneawakeningscreenshot2025.06.05-13.07.30.88.png"></figure><p>However, not all trainers are accessible at the same time in Dune: Awakening. You can find some trainers early on in your journey, while others can't be found until much later. So, if you're looking for the optimal class route, you want to select a class that has a late-game trainer unlock, as this gives you that class's ability trees right away.</p><p>Of course, this doesn't always apply when it comes to picking a class, as one or two classes in Dune: Awakening are strong enough on their own that they don't necessarily need abilities from other trees.</p><p>With all of that in mind, here's our current class tier list for Dune: Awakening:</p><table data-max-width="true"><thead><tr><th scope="col">Tier</th><th scope="col">Class</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>S</td><td>Swordmaster, Bene Gesserit</td></tr><tr><td>A</td><td>Mentat, Planetologist</td></tr><tr><td>B</td><td>Trooper</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Naturally, there is quite a lot of room for debate with this tier list, as the classes in Dune: Awakening are all varied and can appeal to different players. However, we have a few concrete reasons for our rankings, which we'll outline below.</p><h3>S Tier</h3><p>In S tier, we have Swordmaster and Bene Gesserit. Starting with Swordmaster, this is arguably the best class in all of Dune: Awakening, regardless of your skill level, experience, etc.</p><p>Swordmaster begins with the Knee Charge ability, which can absolutely shred through enemies at close range in the early game and maintains its value in the late game as well. Knee Charge makes going through camps and other enemy spots an absolute breeze, allowing you to save ammunition and healing items when they're most crucial to have.</p><p>As for Bene Gesserit, this is one class you'll want to use if you're an experienced survival player or you've gone through Dune: Awakening a time or two already. The Bene Gesserit begins with the Voice: Compel ability, and the class emphasizes a psychological approach to combat rather than a physical one. This can make the early game a bit challenging, as you need to utilize your wits and avoid relying on abilities for every situation. However, if you can master the Bene Gesserit class, it's incredibly powerful as you progress.</p><h3>A Tier</h3><p>Moving on to the A tier, we have selected Mentat and Planetologist. The Mentat class could make an argument for the S tier, while Planetologist is just an all-around solid class that's good, not great,t for the duration of Dune: Awakening.</p><p>Mentat begins with The Sentinel ability, which is a terrific way to fight enemies without your character having to do much. The ability places a turret down and allows you to deal damage and get out of sticky situations with ease. One of the more intriguing parts of the Mentat, though, is its access to poison damage, which scales particularly well with ranged weapons.</p><p>As for the Planetologist, this technically isn't a starting class, but it's still a class you can unlock as you approach the late game. The Planetologist is arguably the best late-game class, but it's only in A tier, seeing as you can't use it for a majority of your playthrough. The class excels at base building, resource management, and other survival aspects of the game. It's seen as a utility class that doesn't have a major focus on combat, but you'll still have loads of combat abilities to access in the late game in addition to your new abilities from the Planetologist's trees.</p><h3>B Tier</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4517701-duneawakeningscreenshot2025.06.05-13.44.48.82.png" data-ref-id="1300-4517701" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4517701-duneawakeningscreenshot2025.06.05-13.44.48.82.png" data-ref-id="1300-4517701"></a><figcaption>The opening ability tree for the Trooper in Dune: Awakening</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1745/17457013/4517701-duneawakeningscreenshot2025.06.05-13.44.48.82.png"></figure><p>Finally, in the B tier is the Trooper. This ranking is slightly unfair, as the Trooper is actually a highly enjoyable class with a ton of use, especially in the early game. The only reason we put it in B tier is because you can access the Trooper's trainer early on in Dune: Awakening, allowing you to access its ability trees. So, you can essentially get the best of both worlds if you select another class at the start.</p><p>Nevertheless, the Trooper has some of the best mobility out of any class in Dune: Awakening, primarily thanks to its starting Shigawire Claw ability that acts as a grappling hook. The Trooper also has some terrific early combat abilities, making it a solid beginner class as well as a decent class for all skill levels.</p><p>And that wraps up our class tier list for Dune: Awakening. Of course, as time goes on, developer Funcom might make some updates to the classes and even add new ones, so this tier list may change over time. </p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dune-awakening-class-tier-list-best-classes-to-use/1100-6532561/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fan-Made Ultimate Sonic Smackdown Has Big Marvel Vs. Capcom Energy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fan-made-ultimate-sonic-smackdown-has-big-marvel-vs-capcom-energy/1100-6532689/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fan-made-ultimate-sonic-smackdown-has-big-marvel-vs-capcom-energy.1227288/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532689">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In 2020, the ArcForged team of fan developers released Sonic Smackdown, a fighting game featuring several characters from Sega's Sonic the Hedgehog franchise. Now, ArcForged has returned with an upgraded version of that game, Ultimate Sonic Smackdown. And as seen in the announcement video below, it's clearly inspired by Capcom's Marvel vs. Capcom games.</p><p>This project is not affiliated or endorsed by Sega itself. But it does look pretty polished for a fan-made creation.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4dn7uq5g6iM" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4dn7uq5g6iM" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Unlike its 1-vs-1 predecessor, Ultimate Sonic Smackdown has 3-vs-3 tag battles on tap. The roster isn't as deep as the 17 characters in the original Sonic Smackdown, but the primary characters are back including Sonic, Shadow, Knuckles, Mecha Sonic, and Doctor Eggman.</p><p>Players will be able to choose between having one, two, or three characters on their team, and the game has rollback netcode. Since this is an unofficial fan project, Ultimate Sonic Smackdown is available for free on <a href="https://arcforged.itch.io/ultimatesonicsmackdown" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">ArcForged's itch.io site</a>.</p><p>The next official Sonic game from Sega, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/preview?isSlp=1&amp;isPreview=1&amp;asins=B0F8R7QS54,B0F8RBYYNM,B0F8RCDNH5&amp;tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</a>, is an arcade racing title that's set to hit PS5, PS4, Switch, Xbox, and PC on September 25. However, Sega <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sonic-rumble-delayed-yet-again-this-news-may-be-disappointing-sega-says/1100-6531227/" data-ref-id="1100-6531227">indefinitely delayed its upcoming mobile title, Sonic Rumble</a>. That game doesn't currently have a revised release date, but it is available in a pre-launch testing mode. Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sonic-x-shadow-generations-getting-a-nintendo-switch-2-version-preorders-are-now-live/1100-6531130/" data-ref-id="1100-6531130">Sonic X Shadow Generation was released on Nintendo Switch 2</a> earlier this month.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fan-made-ultimate-sonic-smackdown-has-big-marvel-vs-capcom-energy/1100-6532689/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition Is A Great Showcase For The Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition-is-a-great-showcase-for-the-switch-2/1100-6532688/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition-is-a-great-showcase-for-the-switch-2.1227270/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532688">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Few games pack the technical punch of Cyberpunk 2077, making it an interesting proposition for Nintendo's shiny new handheld. While the Switch 2 is a significant upgrade to the original, Cyberpunk 2077 is considered one of the most hardware-intensive games in recent years. Despite this, CD Projekt Red's ambitious Switch 2 port is a commendable one that makes the most of the console's power, but with some noticeable drawbacks.</p><p dir="ltr">Cyberpunk 2077 for the Switch 2 offers a performance mode and quality mode for both docked and handheld play, with the key difference between the two play styles being resolution. While docked, Cyberpunk 2077's resolution ranges between 540p and 1080p. In quality mode, it shouldn't fall below 720p. Handheld play, depending on the graphics mode, scales between 360p and 810p. This sounds rough, but given the screen size and DLSS, Cyberpunk 2077 looks pretty palatable on the Nintendo Switch 2. Post-processing effects help offset this low resolution and the Switch 2 screen boasts a clean image, especially at a standstill. The quality can vary depending on what's happening on screen, though. If you're speeding through Night City or in the heat of combat, the resolution may plummet, but most players probably won't be able to tell.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4520143-01_cp2077_mousecontrols.mov.00_28_23_18.still003.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4520143" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4520143-01_cp2077_mousecontrols.mov.00_28_23_18.still003.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4520143"></a><figcaption>Johnny Silverhand looking at V with Night City in the background captured on the Nintendo Switch 2</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4520143-01_cp2077_mousecontrols.mov.00_28_23_18.still003.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Quality mode targets 30 frames per second and performance mode targets 40. The caveat is that performance mode while docked only works with 120Hz TVs and monitors, meaning that not every display can utilize the frame rate boost. However, in my testing, the frame rate boost seemed pretty negligible when compared to quality mode. This is largely due to the fact that the Nintendo Switch 2 does not support variable refresh rate while docked, meaning the frame rate dips are noticeable. Fortunately, the quality setting appears to be more consistent. The frame rate can fluctuate depending on where you are in the world and what's happening. Thanks to the Switch 2's built-in VRR screen, performance mode feels pretty solid while playing handheld. That said, Dog Town--the new district added in the Phantom Liberty DLC--appears to be particularly taxing on the Switch 2. It's far from unplayable, but it does run slightly worse than other parts of the city. This shouldn't come as a surprise considering Phantom Liberty never made it to PlayStation 4 and Xbox One due to technical limitations. That makes its inclusion on the Switch 2 all the more noteworthy.</p><p dir="ltr">In order to get Cyberpunk 2077 running on the Switch 2, the visuals have noticeably been pared back. While it doesn't feel as extreme of a downgrade as The Witcher 3's 2019 Switch port, those who played Cyberpunk 2077 on a high-end PC, Xbox Series X, or PS5 will definitely see the difference. Draw distances are reined in, textures aren't as detailed, and the lighting isn't as crisp. That said, it does appear to outpace last-gen consoles--perhaps not in every way, but I'd much rather play Cyberpunk 2077 on my Switch 2 than my creaky old Xbox One. For me, the most notable differences are the smaller crowd sizes and emptier roads. At times, especially in the downtown areas, Night City feels a bit empty. Concessions had to be made, and I understand why this was chief among them, but wandering around a quiet city center can take me out of the experience.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4520144-04_cp2077_frameratemode.mov.00_18_25_088.still002.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4520144" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4520144-04_cp2077_frameratemode.mov.00_18_25_088.still002.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4520144"></a><figcaption>The hacking menu on the Nintendo Switch 2</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4520144-04_cp2077_frameratemode.mov.00_18_25_088.still002.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Cyberpunk 2077 isn't just a straightforward port to the Nintendo Switch 2. CD Projekt Red has leveraged the console's hardware to add in some new ways to play. The most interesting of the bunch are <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-nintendo-switch-2-game-that-supports-joy-con-mouse-controls/2900-6517/">mouse controls</a>. This lets you use a Joy-Con as a mouse in order to aim, and it works well. Once I tweaked the sensitivity, I had no trouble lining up headshots and gunning down enemies from afar. It's a little awkward maneuvering with mouse controls outside of combat, and the default button layout took some getting used to, but it feels like more than just a gimmick. I could see myself playing for dozens of hours with mouse controls turned on. However, the gyro controls <em>do</em> feel like a gimmick. Using a Pro Controller or Joy-Con, you can aim using motion; it's not quite as imprecise as it sounds, but it's certainly not the ideal way to play Cyberpunk 2077. The more approachable, middle ground is to use the gyro controls for subtle adjustments while aiming. You can control your camera with the right stick, but when you need to make a slight adjustment you can use the motion controls.</p><p dir="ltr">Additionally, CD Projekt Red has added touch controls to the experience. This primarily lets you navigate menus with your finger. As someone who has put in over 250 hours into Cyberpunk, navigating the menu with analog sticks is muscle memory at this point, so I've largely ignored this feature (I also don't like getting fingerprints on my screens). However, the touch screen controls are intuitive and could alleviate some of the inventory management issues that newer players might experience.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4520145-02_cp2077_gyrocontrols.mov.00_06_48_15.still003.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4520145" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4520145-02_cp2077_gyrocontrols.mov.00_06_48_15.still003.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4520145"></a><figcaption>V holding a pistol outside of Night City captured on the Nintendo Switch 2</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1512/15120939/4520145-02_cp2077_gyrocontrols.mov.00_06_48_15.still003.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Quite possibly the coolest feature in the Switch 2 version is cross-progression, letting you transfer your saves between PC and console. This isn't new for Cyberpunk or CD Projekt Red, but it makes this package considerably more inviting. After I completed Phantom Liberty for the first time in 2023, I've been slowly chipping away at a 100% playthrough, and cross-progression makes that even more attainable. The Witcher 3 for Switch eventually got cross-play, but for that functionality to work on day one with Cyberpunk 2077 is commendable.</p><p dir="ltr">If you've never played Cyberpunk 2077 and the Switch 2 is your only means to do so, then it's an easy recommendation. The base game is excellent and the Phantom Liberty expansion is phenomenal. However, if you've already played Cyberpunk 2077 and don't feel an itch to return to Night City, then this may not be worth your time. The Switch 2-specific features are a nice touch--and it's great to see CD Projekt Red embracing the hardware--but they don't elevate Cyberpunk 2077 beyond its already impressive pedestal.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition-is-a-great-showcase-for-the-switch-2/1100-6532688/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get The Best 2D Platformer Since Celeste And 5 More Games For $5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-the-best-2d-platformer-since-celeste-and-5-more-games-for-5/1100-6532663/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-the-best-2d-platformer-since-celeste-and-5-more-games-for-5.1227264/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532663">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nothing beats the thrill of completing a challenging platformer, and while we've been spoiled for choice lately, you can put your skills to the test <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Get+The+Best+2D+Platformer+Since+Celeste+And+5+More+Games+For+%245&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A07&amp;fnarticle_id=6532663&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fbundle%2Fnemesis-bundle&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-the-best-2d-platformer-since-celeste-and-5-more-games-for-5%2F1100-6532663%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">with a real gem in this genre</a>. Better yet, it's on sale for $5 <em>and </em>you'll get some other PC games included as well. As usual, each game here is provided as a key that can be redeemed on a Steam account.</p><p>Available through Fanatical's Nemesis Bundle, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/bzzzt/">Bzzzt</a> is the kind of game that platforming fans and speedrunners will get a kick out of. If you enjoyed games like the all-time classics Celeste and Super Meat Boy, then Bzzzt is very easy to recommend.</p><p>It has delightfully charming pixel art, each level is a masterpiece of design, and the controls are designed to keep the momentum going once you hit your stride. Overall, it's a showcase of precision-platforming and it's also Steam Deck Verified, so you can take it on the go with you.</p><p>The other games in this bundle aren't too bad either, as you experience an homage to the original Grand Theft Auto--but with a medieval twist--in Rustler, face off against knaves in the fantasy-themed StormEdge, and experience some mind-bending horror in Ad Infinitum. Nova Lands is another noteworthy game here, as it mixes ideas from Factorio, Forager, and Satisfactory with open-world influences to build a fun automation adventure.</p><h2>Fanatical Nemesis Bundle</h2><ul><li>Bzzzt (Steam Deck Verified)</li><li>Nova Lands (Steam Deck Verified)</li><li>Ad Infinitum (Steam Deck Playable)</li><li>Rustler (Steam Deck Verified)</li><li>Fargone (Steam Deck Playable)</li><li>StormEdge (Steam Deck Verified)</li></ul><p>For more bundle deals, you can also fill up your Steam library with some great options right now. <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Get+The+Best+2D+Platformer+Since+Celeste+And+5+More+Games+For+%245&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A07&amp;fnarticle_id=6532663&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fpick-and-mix%2Ffanatical-favorites-build-your-own-bundle&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-the-best-2d-platformer-since-celeste-and-5-more-games-for-5%2F1100-6532663%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Fanatical Favorites Bundle</a> offers games like Warhammer 40,000: Mechanicus and Stasis: Bone Totem for just a few bucks, and the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Get+The+Best+2D+Platformer+Since+Celeste+And+5+More+Games+For+%245&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A07&amp;fnarticle_id=6532663&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fpick-and-mix%2Fbuild-your-own-brutal-bundle&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-the-best-2d-platformer-since-celeste-and-5-more-games-for-5%2F1100-6532663%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Build Your Own Brutal Bundle</a> has a curated list that includes Doom Eternal. <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Get+The+Best+2D+Platformer+Since+Celeste+And+5+More+Games+For+%245&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A07&amp;fnarticle_id=6532663&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fpick-and-mix%2Fplatinum-collection-build-your-own-bundle&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-the-best-2d-platformer-since-celeste-and-5-more-games-for-5%2F1100-6532663%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">June's Platinum Collection Bundle</a> starts at just $10 for three games, and it has a nice selection of nostalgic favorites and recent releases.</p><h2>More Fanatical Bundle Deals</h2><ul><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Get+The+Best+2D+Platformer+Since+Celeste+And+5+More+Games+For+%245&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A07&amp;fnarticle_id=6532663&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fpick-and-mix%2Ffanatical-favorites-build-your-own-bundle&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-the-best-2d-platformer-since-celeste-and-5-more-games-for-5%2F1100-6532663%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fanatical Favorites: Build Your Own Bundle</a></li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Get+The+Best+2D+Platformer+Since+Celeste+And+5+More+Games+For+%245&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A07&amp;fnarticle_id=6532663&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fpick-and-mix%2Fbuild-your-own-brutal-bundle&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-the-best-2d-platformer-since-celeste-and-5-more-games-for-5%2F1100-6532663%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Build Your Own Brutal Bundle</a></li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Get+The+Best+2D+Platformer+Since+Celeste+And+5+More+Games+For+%245&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A07&amp;fnarticle_id=6532663&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fpick-and-mix%2Fbuild-your-own-tabletop-and-deckbuilder-bundle&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-the-best-2d-platformer-since-celeste-and-5-more-games-for-5%2F1100-6532663%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Build Your Own Tabletop and Deckbuilder Bundle</a></li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Get+The+Best+2D+Platformer+Since+Celeste+And+5+More+Games+For+%245&amp;fnauthor=darranged&amp;fndate=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-06-24+10%3A51%3A07&amp;fnarticle_id=6532663&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Deals&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dpbolvw.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fpick-and-mix%2Fplatinum-collection-build-your-own-bundle&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fget-the-best-2d-platformer-since-celeste-and-5-more-games-for-5%2F1100-6532663%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">June: Platinum Collection Bundle</a></li></ul><p><em>Disclosure: GameSpot and Fanatical are both owned by Fandom.</em></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-the-best-2d-platformer-since-celeste-and-5-more-games-for-5/1100-6532663/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This New Motorcycle Roadtrip Game Is Becoming A Movie In An Unusual Way]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-new-motorcycle-roadtrip-game-is-becoming-a-movie-in-an-unusual-way/1100-6532681/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-new-motorcycle-roadtrip-game-is-becoming-a-movie-in-an-unusual-way.1227189/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532681">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The production company Tandem Pictures is expanding beyond film into video games with a new hybrid game-and-movie project.</p><p>The project is called Great Northern (not to be confused with the popular Australian beer), and <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/great-northern-video-game-movie-megan-suri-1236437048/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Variety reported</a> that it's being produced as a "live-action video game" starring Never Have I Ever's Megan Suri <em>and </em>an independent movie that uses "the same footage." Great Northern tells the story of a young woman who rides a motorcycle across the US to Alaska on a journey to scatter her father's ashes.</p><p>"With danger around every corner, players will make impactful decisions as a modern-day lone ranger facing the open road on the adventure of a lifetime," the game's description said.</p><p>The report added that Great Northern--the game--is a choose-your-own-adventure game, with the movie then adapting "the characters and plotlines that are most beloved by the community of people who play the game."</p><p>The developer Little Wooden Toys is making the Great Northern video game, and it's set to debut in the first half of 2027 for PC, console, and mobile phones. Production hasn't yet begun, however.</p><p>Tandem Pictures is also behind the show Warehouse Phase and the upcoming movie Nuked, which follows a group of friends who <a href="https://tribecafilm.com/films/nuked-2024" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">take a trip to get stoned and relax only to learn a nuclear bomb is headed for them.</a></p><p>Little Wooden Toys, meanwhile, is a production company that makes "stories that blend film and video games."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-new-motorcycle-roadtrip-game-is-becoming-a-movie-in-an-unusual-way/1100-6532681/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>