<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 14:29:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Game Hellblade 2 Coming To PS5 Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-hellblade-2-coming-to-ps5-soon/1100-6531706/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-game-hellblade-2-coming-to-ps5-soon.1195101/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-hellblade-2-coming-to-ps5-soon/1100-6531706/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531706">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Microsoft has announced the next Xbox game headed to PlayStation, and it's Senua's Saga: Hellblade 2. The game will come to PS5 at some point this summer.</p><p>Microsoft said the game will be optimized for PS5 and PS5 Pro, while a free update for all systems (PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC) will arrive alongside the game's PS5 debut, adding new features. Developer Ninja Theory didn't say what these new features are, however.</p><p>The original Hellblade game launched on PS4 in 2017, and it was exclusive on console to Sony's system until it came to Xbox in 2018 and then Switch in 2019.</p><p>Ninja Theory said, "The team are excited to bring Senua back to where her journey began and for PlayStation players to be able to experience the next chapter in her brutal saga of survival."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sh4QQyM1KP0" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/sh4QQyM1KP0" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Microsoft's releases on PS5 have been <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lpoo4bysme2e" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">successful so far</a>, as four of the top five--and five of the top seven--of the best-selling games for April 2025 on PlayStation in the US were published by Microsoft.</p><p>Two high-profile releases for April, Forza Horizon 5 and Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, surged up the US sales charts following their debut on PS5 that month. Forza Horizon 5 jumped from No. 42 best-selling overall in March to No. 2 in April, while The Great Circle jumped from 118th in March to No. 6 in April, according to Circana.</p><p>Microsoft will release more Xbox games on PlayStation in the future, including Gears of War Reloaded, which <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gears-of-war-reloaded-remaster-coming-this-august-to-xbox-playstation-and-pc/1100-6531314/" data-ref-id="1100-6531314">launches on PS5 in August.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Sequel Will Feature A Second City]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-will-feature-a-second-city/1100-6531705/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-will-feature-a-second-city.1195041/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-will-feature-a-second-city/1100-6531705/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531705">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/cyberpunk-2077-review/1900-6417622/" data-ref-id="1900-6417622">Cyberpunk 2077</a> will celebrate its fifth anniversary later this year, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-sequel-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6526333/" data-ref-id="1100-6526333">the currently untitled sequel</a> may still be years away. While fans will eventually get to revisit Night City, Mike Pondsmith--the creator of the Cyberpunk franchise--has hinted that the Cyberpunk 2077 sequel will include a second city.</p><p>Pondsmith appeared at Digital Dragons 2025 (Via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/cyberpunk-2077s-sequel-features-a-second-city-that-feels-like-chicago-gone-wrong-reveals-creator/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">VGC</a>) and indicated that he's not heavily involved with the Cyberpunk 2077 follow-up. But he has been shown the scripts and he's been kept in the loop about some fresh additions to the game's universe, including a new city.</p><p>"I spent a lot of time talking to one of the environment guys, and he was explaining how the new place… because there's another city that we visit," said Pondsmith. "And I'm not telling you anymore than that. But there's another city that we visit. Night City is still there."</p><p>"I remember looking at it and going, 'I understand the feel that you’re going for, and this really does work,'" added Pondsmith. "'It doesn't feel like Blade Runner, it feels more like Chicago gone wrong.' And I said, 'Yeah, I can see this working.'"</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-witcher-4/" data-ref-id="5000-561041">The Witcher 4</a> may be getting the majority of CD Projekt Red's attention, but the Cyberpunk 2077 sequel is currently in development at the publisher's Boston studio ostensibly to give the game a more authentic American experience than the first one. A recent job posting for the game suggested that the devs want to create "<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cd-projekt-red-wants-cyberpunk-2077-sequel-to-have-most-realistic-crowds-ever/1100-6529613/" data-ref-id="1100-6529613">the most-realistic crowds ever</a>."</p><p>In the meantime, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-on-switch-2-cd-projekt-acknowledges-development-challenges/1100-6531129/" data-ref-id="1100-6531129">Cyberpunk 2077 Ultimate Edition</a> will be <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-nintendo-switch-2-launch-game/2900-6401/" data-ref-id="2900-6401">a launch title for Nintendo Switch 2</a>. It will arrive roughly a month after Switch 2's debut on June 5.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>