<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:57:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Crew 2 Finally Gets Its Offline Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-crew-2-finally-gets-its-offline-mode/1100-6535499/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-crew-2-finally-gets-its-offline-mode.1326913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535499">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>When Ubisoft launched <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-crew-2/" data-ref-id="5000-464876">The Crew 2</a> in 2018, there weren't any options to bring this online racing game offline. Now, seven years later, The Crew 2 has finally received its much-requested offline mode.</p><p>Starting today, PC players can download an update from Ubisoft and enjoy The Crew 2 without an internet connection with Hybrid Mode. The console update for PlayStation 4 and Xbox One will be released later today.</p><p>Players now have the option of picking either online or offline when starting up the game. If players aren't connected to the internet, then The Crew 2 will automatically switch to offline. Ubisoft notes that saves for the two modes are completely separate, and progress made offline will not carry over to online. However, players can export a copy of their online save to their computer or console for the offline mode.</p><p>The exported saves will include the Season Pass content, vehicles, and rewards as long as players claim them before they export their online save. However, <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/the-crew/the-crew-2/news-updates/zs6ZFyLEQvKbFskEJZolR/the-crew-2-hybrid-mode-is-now-available" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">there are a handful of features</a> that won't carry over to offline mode:</p><ul><li>Crew Credits purchases (vehicle bundles, vanity items) and the Far &amp; Beyond shop in all 4 Hubs.</li><li>LIVE Summits.</li><li>All multiplayer content, including PvP, Crews, crew features, news feed, leaderboards, ghosts, and statistics menus. Only your own best times will be recorded per race.</li><li>UGC features, including the Race Creator and Livery Editor. Custom liveries will not transfer to offline saves.</li><li>Some Hobbies and Achievements (Xbox, PlayStation, PC, and Ubisoft Connect) that require online-only actions.</li></ul><p>Last year, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-crew-is-delisted-servers-shutting-down-at-the-end-of-march-2024/1100-6519967/" data-ref-id="1100-6519967">The Crew was delisted</a> without giving players an offline mode, effectively making the game unplayable. A few players even <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-is-facing-lawsuit-after-the-crew-was-removed-from-platforms/1100-6527713/" data-ref-id="1100-6527713">filed a lawsuit against Ubisoft</a> over its removal. To appease its angry fans, Ubisoft promised that both <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/after-the-crew-was-rendered-unplayable-its-sequels-will-be-preserved/1100-6526400/" data-ref-id="1100-6526400">The Crew 2 and The Crew Motorfest would get offline modes</a>. While the former has now received it, there isn't currently a date for the latter to get an offline mode of its own.</p><p>Earlier this year, a fan-made recreation of the first game called <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-crew-is-coming-back-online-this-month-thanks-to-fan-made-mod/1100-6534438/" data-ref-id="1100-6534438">The Crew Unlimited</a> went online.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-crew-2-finally-gets-its-offline-mode/1100-6535499/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-Call Of Duty Boss "Immensely" Worried About The Series Under Microsoft's Ownership]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ex-call-of-duty-boss-immensely-worried-about-the-series-under-microsofts-ownership/1100-6535500/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ex-call-of-duty-boss-immensely-worried-about-the-series-under-microsofts-ownership.1326907/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535500">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Glen Schofield, a former Call of Duty boss at Sledgehammer Games, has said he is "immensely" worried about the future of the series under Microsoft. He also stated that the quality of most Call of Duty releases since he left has fallen.</p><p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/features/interviews/interview-glen-schofields-plan-to-save-the-games-industry/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">VGC</a>, Schofield said of Microsoft's ownership of Call of Duty, "I worry about it immensely, I really do. Because what's happening here is a war."</p><p>"Unfortunately, once you're assimilated by one of these companies, I think you take on some of their traits," he added.</p><p>Schofield also said he imagines that Activision has eliminated the bonus program paid to Call of Duty developers based on the success of a game, and that might negatively impact the company's ability to attract and retain top talent.</p><p>Also in the interview, Schofield said that the Call of Duty series has sunk below its previous highs, creatively at least, since he left in February 2018 after Call of Duty: WWII. "I hate doing this, but since I left Sledgehammer, none of the games have been very good. I mean, the last one [Sledgehammer's Modern Warfare 3 in 2023] was a 50. They still sell well," he said.</p><p>"They just aren't as good. They aren't the same. Treyarch's still really good but you know … I got lucky," he added.</p><p>Finally, Schofield said he has a theory as to why the Call of Duty series has remained an annual franchise, and it's all about money. "First of all if they go to not every year, they lose a billion dollars every year, so that's why Call of Duty never did that," he said.</p><p>It was recently reported that Activision <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-lost-300-million-in-sales-due-to-game-pass-report/1100-6535256/" data-ref-id="1100-6535256">missed out on $300 million in revenue from putting Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 on Xbox Game Pass</a>. The subscription service <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-nearly-hit-5-billion-in-revenue-says-microsoft/1100-6533574/" data-ref-id="1100-6533574">recently approached $5 billion in annual for the first time ever.</a> The next entry in the series, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-start-time-how-to-get-in-and-everything-else-to-know/1100-6534073/" data-ref-id="1100-6534073">Black Ops 7</a>, launches this November and will be on Game Pass.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ex-call-of-duty-boss-immensely-worried-about-the-series-under-microsofts-ownership/1100-6535500/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4 Season 11 Might Be Its Biggest Rework Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-11-might-be-its-biggest-rework-yet/1100-6535476/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4-season-11-might-be-its-biggest-rework-yet.1326868/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535476">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-iv/" data-ref-id="5000-504255">Diablo 4</a> Season 11 is poised to bring huge changes to Blizzard's ARPG, and will overhaul item progression, see the return of leaderboards, rework the Renown system, and even dramatically change how the game's potions work. And that's not even everything.</p><p dir="ltr">While noticeable changes to the core of Diablo 4 come alongside nearly every season, most notably with Season 4's Loot Reborn, Season 11 still stands out. None of these changes were detailed in the game's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-2025-roadmap-highlights-new-crossovers-endgame-updates/1100-6530666/" data-ref-id="1100-6530666">2025 content roadmap</a>, and Blizzard has teased for months that many of players' biggest gripes with the game would be addressed in a coming update. Now we finally know what Blizzard has been cooking.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586075-diablo4masterworkingchanges.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4586075" data-ratio="0.56267217630854" data-width="1452" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586075-diablo4masterworkingchanges.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4586075"></a><figcaption>Masterworking and Tempering are becoming less random in Season 11.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586075-diablo4masterworkingchanges.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">Tempering And Masterworking Overhaul</h2><p dir="ltr">Perhaps the biggest complaint players have had since Season 4 regards the act of Tempering and Masterworking items. In the current live version of Diablo 4, Tempering allows players to add affixes to items but with a catch.</p><p dir="ltr">The act of Tempering has an element of randomness, as each Tempering recipe usually contains up to three possible affixes. Which affix gets applied is random, and players often end up "bricking" an item by being unable to get their desired affix. Masterworking, too, has an element of luck, with bonus affix upgrades every few levels applied at random. Players trying to optimize their gear to the fullest often have to reset the item when the bonus affix upgrade doesn't land on a desired roll and start the entire Masterworking process over again from scratch.</p><p dir="ltr">That's all changing with Season 11. As detailed in a new blog outlined what all is coming to Diablo 4's public test realm, Tempering will finally no longer be random, with players able to apply the affix of their choice to gear. That affix can also be changed as many times as a player likes (as long as they have the necessary resources). The catch is that gear can now only have one Tempered affix. To compensate, non-Unique items are having their base number of affixes raised from three to four.</p><p dir="ltr">Going hand-in-hand with the Tempering changes is an update to Masterworking. Instead of improving the value of affixes, Masterworking instead improves an item's overall quality, up to a quality level of 20. Higher-quality items have increased base damage, armor, or resistances, and Masterworking an item has a chance to increase its quality by two to five levels.</p><p dir="ltr">Once an item hits Masterwork level 20, players can roll for a Capstone bonus, which upgrades a random non-greater affix on the item and turns it into a greater one. These Capstone bonuses can be re-rolled an unlimited amount of times without resetting an item's quality, allowing players to hone in on specific affixes necessary for their build (though it will cost some upgrade currencies).</p><p dir="ltr">More than just changing how Tempering and Masterworking works, Blizzard has additionally added a final step for an item's upgrade journey--Sanctification. This new system lets players use a fraction of Heaven's power to sanctify an item. Sanctifying an item has a random chance to apply one of the following benefits:</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Bonus Legendary power</li><li dir="ltr">Turn an affix into a Greater Affix</li><li dir="ltr">Add a bonus Sanctification Affix</li><li dir="ltr">Replace an existing affix with a Sanctification Affix</li><li dir="ltr">Make an item indestructible</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Sanctifying an item makes the item unmodifiable. Blizzard warns that Sanctification should always be the very last upgrade made to an item.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586084-diablo4season11sanctification.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4586084" data-ratio="0.56215083798883" data-width="1432" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586084-diablo4season11sanctification.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4586084"></a><figcaption>Diablo 4 Season 11 is introducing a final step in an item's upgrade path called Sanctification.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586084-diablo4season11sanctification.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">Healing And Defense Changes</h2><p dir="ltr">Diablo 4 Season 11's major rework for item progression isn't the only big change. It's also completely changing how defenses work, and scrapping the game's entire existing potion system in the process. Armor and Resistances are becoming a rating system, and one with diminishing returns at higher levels. Armor will reduce all damage taken, rather than just physical, and the armor and resistance penalties associated with each Torment difficulty will be removed. A new character-stat page that aggregates all of a character's defensive stats into one number, Toughness, will help give players a better idea of how durable they overall are.</p><p dir="ltr">As for healing, Blizzard is ripping out the existing potion system. Instead of needing to upgrade potions every few levels, potions in Diablo 4 Season 11 will instead always immediately heal 35% of a player's total health. Base potion capacity is being reduced to four as a result, but potions will recharge over 30 seconds. To aid with healing, values for all life-gaining affixes like life on kill, life on hit, and life regeneration have all had their values increased.</p><p dir="ltr">Fortify, a unique Diablo 4 mechanic that grants additional defenses when overhealing, is being changed into what is essentially an extra life bar that's slowly drained to heal over time. When Fortified, players will heal a percentage of their max life every second, draining the Fortified health pool.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Renown Reborn</h2><p dir="ltr">Potions aren't the only idea from the launch version of Diablo 4 that is being scrapped. Renown, a zone-specific reputation system that has various rewards like additional potion slots, skill points, and gold tied to it, is going away, at least for the game's Seasonal realm. It will still exist permanently in the Eternal realm, effectively making for noticeably different versions of Diablo 4 to choose from.</p><p dir="ltr">On the game's seasonal server, Renown is being replaced and combined with the game's current Season Journey system to form a new system called Season Rank. Players will earn rewards like additional skill and paragon points, Smoldering Ashes, and cosmetics by completing various objectives and advancing their Season Rank. Altars of Lilith will grant experience and minor rewards, but will no longer grant permanent stats as they have since the game launched.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586086-diablo4season11leaderboards.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4586086" data-ratio="0.56215083798883" data-width="1432" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586086-diablo4season11leaderboards.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4586086"></a><figcaption>Leaderboards are finally returning in Diablo 4 Season 11.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586086-diablo4season11leaderboards.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">The Tower</h2><p dir="ltr">Leaderboards are returning to Diablo 4 after having previously been deactivated alongside the game's Vessel of Hatred expansion. This time, however, they are taking a new form--The Tower. A new multi-floor dungeon, The Tower works similarly to The Pit, where players will need to battle through monsters and fill a meter within a 10-minute time limit.</p><p dir="ltr">Once enough monsters (or progress orbs that drop from them) have been slain, a random Tower boss will spawn. Defeating them concludes the dungeon and stops the timer, registering the run on the new leaderboard. There will be solo leaderboards for each class, as well as leaderboards for parties of two, three, and four. There will additionally be separate leaderboards for Hardcore characters. Blizzard said the version of The Tower and leaderboard appearing in Season 11 will be considered a beta, and that it hopes to update The Tower in future seasons.</p><p dir="ltr">There's more too, with Season 11 set to add a new world boss for the first time since launch, make enemy monsters tougher, and introduce a whole new set of seasonal powers and mechanics. Testing for Diablo 4 Season 11 will begin on the game's PTR October 21, with the season proper set to debut on December 9. Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4s-second-expansion-isnt-coming-until-2026/1100-6529452/" data-ref-id="1100-6529452">Diablo 4's second expansion</a> is slated to arrive sometime next year.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-11-might-be-its-biggest-rework-yet/1100-6535476/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4's Monsters Are Getting Deadlier, And Smarter, In Season 11]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4s-monsters-are-getting-deadlier-and-smarter-in-season-11/1100-6535477/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4s-monsters-are-getting-deadlier-and-smarter-in-season-11.1326865/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535477">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-iv/" data-ref-id="5000-504255">Diablo 4</a> may be far more challenging come Season 11, with a slew of updates set to address monster behavior and difficulty.</p><p dir="ltr">As detailed by Blizzard, the goal is to have monsters starting with Season 11 more regularly test players' defenses and force players to interact with them in new ways. Enemy monsters will see changes to make their behavior less predictable, while at the same time making it so each type of monster will have their own clear role and identity in combat. Monsters packs will also group up less, making it more difficult for players to wipe out large groups of multiple packs in a single go.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586093-diablo4season11azmodanworldboss.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4586093" data-ratio="0.56215083798883" data-width="1432" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586093-diablo4season11azmodanworldboss.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4586093"></a><figcaption>Azmodan will be a new world boss coming in Diablo 4 Season 11.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4586093-diablo4season11azmodanworldboss.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">A big part of the update to monsters will be new affixes, with more than 20 additional affixes for players to deal with. Elites will spawn minions that inherit some of their affixes, and affixes will in general be more powerful, requiring players to deal with them before taking out less-dangerous foes. Blizzard said that overall, monster affixes should overlap less in their design, be more visually clear, and be more engaging.</p><p dir="ltr">Those changes, in conjunction with other Season 11 updates like fewer potion charges and item progression changes, should make Diablo 4 overall more challenging than before. But deadlier monsters aren't the only thing players have to be afraid of. Season 11 is also adding a new world boss, as well as ways to encounter endgame Lesser Evil bosses like Duriel, Andariel, and Belial while doing endgame activities like Helltide, The Pit, and Kurast Undercity. The new world boss, the first added since Diablo 4's launch over two years ago, will be a familiar face to Diablo 3 players. Azmodan, the Lord of Sin, has a chance to appear as a world boss in the game's open world but can also be summoned at will using a special altar south of Zarbinzet.</p><p dir="ltr">It's currently unclear if the ability to summon the Lesser Evils is an evergreen mechanic or strictly seasonal one, but defeating bosses in this way will reward Divine Favor, used to level up a seasonal Divine Gifts mechanic and increase players' Season Rank (a new system for the game's seasonal server that combines the game's current Renown and Season Journey systems).</p><p dir="ltr">More powerful monsters and the inclusion of Azmodan aren't the only big changes coming next season, with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-11-might-be-its-biggest-rework-yet/1100-6535476/" data-ref-id="1100-6535476">Diablo 4 Season 11 poised to be the game's biggest rework yet</a>. Season 11 will additionally overhaul item progression with sweeping changes to Masterworking and Tempering, reintroduce leaderboards, and more. Diablo 4 Season 11 is slated to begin on December 9, with PTR testing for the season beginning October 21. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4s-second-expansion-isnt-coming-until-2026/1100-6529452/" data-ref-id="1100-6529452">Diablo 4's second expansion</a> is expected to release in 2026.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4s-monsters-are-getting-deadlier-and-smarter-in-season-11/1100-6535477/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire Survivors Crosses Over With A Very Unexpected Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-survivors-crosses-over-with-a-very-unexpected-game/1100-6535496/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-survivors-crosses-over-with-a-very-unexpected-game.1326829/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535496">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://vampire-survivors.fandom.com/wiki/Poe_Ratcho" rel="nofollow ">Poe Ratcho</a> can now pop up in Two Point Museum, thanks to a very unexpected collaboration between the simulation game and Vampire Survivors. The elderly protagonist isn't the only part of the free crossover, either, as Two Point Museum players can now put garlic on display and send experts out to three locations from the roguelike title.</p><p dir="ltr">A trailer for the Two Point Museum and Vampire Survivors crossover can be seen below, showcasing how discoveries can also be equipped to staff members in the simulation game. The three new locations from Vampire Survivors are the Mad Forest, Inlaid Library, and Capella Magna.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="2118179367" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466447,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Two%20Point%20Museum%20x%20Vampire%20Survivors%20Trailer%20%7C%20Free%20Update%20OUT%20NOW%21&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:47,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/two-point-museum-x-vampire-survivors-trailer-free-update-out-now\/2300-6466447\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466447\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466447\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466447\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466447&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4586268-2.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/5RGiSuh8.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1760624580,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="5RGiSuh8" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Two Point Museum x Vampire Survivors Trailer | Free Update OUT NOW!</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">This isn't the first crossover for Two Point Museum. In August, the simulation game got a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2185060/view/545618256387375629" rel="nofollow ">collaboration with Dredge</a>. Meanwhile, looking ahead, Two Point Museum is set to launch October 28 on Switch 2. The title is already available on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p><p dir="ltr">As for Vampire Survivors, developer Poncle revealed earlier this month that the game is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-survivors-is-getting-online-co-op-for-up-to-four-players/1100-6535275/">getting online co-op for up to four players</a>. It also has had crossovers previously, such as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/free-vampire-survivors-update-is-out-now-adds-several-saga-frontier-characters/1100-6530763/">introducing characters from the Square Enix fantasy-RPG series SaGa</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Two Point Museum is one of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/two-point-museum-will-let-you-make-indiana-jones-proud/1100-6525791/">the best simulation games to play in 2025</a>, while Vampire Survivors is one of<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-best-steam-deck-games-to-play-right-now/2900-4083/"> the best Steam Deck games to play</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        <div>
	<p>
		Latest in
		Two Point Museum
	</p>

	
</div>
  
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535440&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/bleach-returns-in-2026-with-a-new-action-rpg-adventure\/1100-6535440\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535473&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/last-of-us-director-reveals-his-favorite-moment-in-a-game\/1100-6535473\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535472&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/breaking-bads-aaron-paul-explains-why-he-finally-did-a-video-game\/1100-6535472\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535354&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/zack-snyders-dawn-of-the-dead-rises-again-with-a-new-steelbook-4k-blu-ray\/1100-6535354\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535376&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/learn-how-quentin-tarantinos-once-upon-a-time-in-hollywood-was-made-with-this-new-book\/1100-6535376\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535487&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sony-accuses-tencent-of-playing-a-shell-game-to-avoid-liability-in-horizon-lawsuit\/1100-6535487\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535214&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/splinter-cell-deathwatch-is-a-sad-reminder-that-ubisoft-has-no-idea-what-to-do-with-sam-fisher\/1100-6535214\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535356&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/genai-is-very-seducing-battlefield-6-boss-says\/1100-6535356\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535359&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ubisoft-adds-two-classic-rpgs-to-game-pass\/1100-6535359\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535363&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-guardians-of-the-galaxy-ship-gets-massive-discount-at-amazon\/1100-6535363\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535365&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/this-mario-game-just-released-in-the-us-for-the-first-time-ever\/1100-6535365\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535358&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/assassins-creed-actor-has-blunt-message-about-that-reportedly-canceled-game\/1100-6535358\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535361&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battlefield-6-generated-100-million-on-steam-from-pre-sales-report\/1100-6535361\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535360&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mindseye-devs-speak-out-build-a-rocket-boy-leadership-slammed-in-open-letter\/1100-6535360\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535355&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/after-11-years-of-development-this-game-is-finally-ready-for-early-access-business\/1100-6535355\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535357&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-makes-progression-wipes-optional-as-studio-puts-players-time-first\/1100-6535357\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535293&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-save-space-when-installing-battlefield-6-on-pc-or-console\/1100-6535293\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535305&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hearthstone-across-the-timeways-fabled-card-reveal-druid\/1100-6535305\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535371&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/madden-leagues-are-vanishing-again-and-no-one-knows-why\/1100-6535371\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535368&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battlefield-6-player-made-this-popular-call-of-duty-map-before-game-even-launched\/1100-6535368\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-survivors-crosses-over-with-a-very-unexpected-game/1100-6535496/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>