<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 13:22:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Is Now Easier Than Ever To Refund PS5 Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-is-now-easier-than-ever-to-refund-ps5-games/1100-6534286/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it-is-now-easier-than-ever-to-refund-ps5-games.1281675/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534286">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It should now be easier to refund PlayStation games, as Sony has scrapped its chatbot in favor of a more streamlined process.</p><p dir="ltr">If you want to refund a game, you can't do it from your console. Instead you'll need to log in to the PlayStation website or open the PlayStation app and follow these instructions, but the process is still quite simple. </p><h3 dir="ltr">How To Refund A Game On the PlayStation Store Or App</h3><ol><li dir="ltr" value="1">Go to the PlayStation store.</li><li dir="ltr" value="2">Click on the three dots in the top right corner.</li><li dir="ltr" value="3">Select the option that reads "Transaction History"</li><li dir="ltr" value="4">Select one of your purchases and choose the "request refund" option.</li></ol><p dir="ltr">There are restrictions on what games you can refund. Generally speaking, you can only refund games purchased in the last 14 days and those you haven't played or downloaded. Special circumstances or a faulty product might get you an exception, but you'll have to explain your case to PlayStation's customer service.</p><p dir="ltr">In the past, you had to request a refund for a PlayStation game via a support chatbot, which could be cumbersome or confusing. The change to a simple menu option was part of a general summer wave of changes on the PlayStation Store, which also included new accessibility options and Apple Pay support.</p><p dir="ltr">In other PlayStation news, a Sony exec recently claimed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/concords-failure-led-to-increased-oversight-says-sony-exec/1100-6534243/" data-ref-id="1100-6534243">Concord's failure has lead to increased oversight</a>. Sony has also revealed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nba-2k26-ps5-slim-bundle-preorder-guide/1100-6534210/" data-ref-id="1100-6534210">a new PS5 slim bundle featuring NBA 2K26</a>, just after the price of the console was hiked.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-is-now-easier-than-ever-to-refund-ps5-games/1100-6534286/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halo, Sonic React To Taylor Swift's Engagement To Travis Kelce]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/halo-sonic-react-to-taylor-swifts-engagement-to-travis-kelce/1100-6534295/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halo-sonic-react-to-taylor-swifts-engagement-to-travis-kelce.1281612/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534295">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Taylor Swift and Travis Kelce announced their engagement on August 26, and it was one of the biggest stories on the internet that day. Many big brands hopped on the train to try to drive engagement and awareness for their own franchises, and this included some video game companies.</p><p>The Halo account posted an image of Halo's Buck and Veronica Dare, with the same caption that Swift used in her announcement, "Your English teacher and your gym teacher are getting married."</p><p>The official Sonic the Hedgehog account, meanwhile, re-shared the engagement announcement to its story on Instagram with the caption, "I think I found the fourth Chaos Emerald..."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4557745-screenshot2025-08-27at8.08.57am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4557745" data-ratio="1.7441441441441" data-width="555" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4557745-screenshot2025-08-27at8.08.57am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4557745"></a><figcaption>Sonic reacts to the Swift/Kelce engagement</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4557745-screenshot2025-08-27at8.08.57am.png"></figure><p>Swift and Kelce got engaged some time ago but only just jointly shared the news with the world this week. It became a top-trending story all over the world, which is no surprise given Swift's popularity. A <a href="https://www.instagram.com/utksocialmedia/reel/DN1BmVdXN9I/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">college professor in Tennessee canceled class</a> upon learning the news.</p><p>Swift and Kelce have not detailed their wedding plans as of yet, but their engagement is sure to be an ongoing popular story. Swift's newest album, The Life of a Showgirl, releases on October 3, while Kelce's first game with the Kansas City Chiefs this season is September 5 in Brazil.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/halo-sonic-react-to-taylor-swifts-engagement-to-travis-kelce/1100-6534295/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>