<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 20:07:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed Was Originally Pitched With Multiplayer Like Destiny Mixed With Skyrim]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-was-originally-pitched-with-multiplayer-like-destiny-mixed-with-skyrim/1100-6529651/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-was-originally-pitched-with-multiplayer-like-destiny-mixed-with-skyrim.1115838/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-was-originally-pitched-with-multiplayer-like-destiny-mixed-with-skyrim/1100-6529651/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529651">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Avowed was originally going to have multiplayer components, similar to that of Destiny where players could walk around in a massive world.</p><p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-02-21/new-xbox-game-avowed-took-six-years-two-reboots?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc0MDE2MDg3MiwiZXhwIjoxNzQwNzY1NjcyLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTUzFPT0xUMVVNMFcwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.FhUrXseBBb83k69Ovuo9PgY3sOuBdW-owuWeanAYc5o&amp;leadSource=uverify%20wall" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloomberg</a>, director Carrie Patel said that Obsidian Entertainment pitched Avowed as a cross between Destiny and Skyrim to prospective buyers, which ended with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-acquires-fallout-new-vegas-star-wars-knights-/1100-6463175/" data-ref-id="1100-6463175">Microsoft purchasing the studio</a>. Avowed's development started in 2018 but went through two reboots, which led Obsidian to scrap its multiplayer component.</p><p>The second reboot occurred in January 2021, when Obsidian replaced Avowed's leadership as they were about to enter production. Patel initiated two major pivots to Avowed, the first of which was to focus on its story and lore from the Pillars of Eternity universe. The second was to replace Avowed's original open world with open-zone ones, similar to that of Obsidian's The Outer Worlds. The latter decision was made so that the development team could create more distinct and denser spaces.</p><p>As a result, the development team had to scale back in creating large and sprawling maps like Skyrim. "We knew from The Outer Worlds that we could build a really great game with 'open zones' and that also adds some advantages in terms of letting you really theme your areas more distinctly and intentionally, and provide a sense of progression as the player’s going from one environment to the next," Patel explained.</p><p>Patel also said that the team is happy with Avowed's sales numbers so far. Although Patel wouldn't reveal what her team's next project is, we do know that Obsidian Entertainment is currently working on The Outer Worlds 2. Initially announced in 2021, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-outer-worlds-2s-first-gameplay-trailer-debuts-during-the-game-awards/1100-6528439/" data-ref-id="1100-6528439">Obsidian released its first gameplay trailer at The Game Awards 2024</a>. The game is set for release sometime this year for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p><p>Avowed is now available on PC and Xbox Series X|S, as well as Game Pass. In GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/avowed-review/2300-6465692/" data-ref-id="2300-6465692">Avowed review</a>, we said, "Avowed's impactful and satisfying combat is undone by a widely unbalanced upgrade system and an uninteresting story that wastes its potential."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shotgun Cop Man Is My Friend Pedro Dev's New Game About Arresting Satan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/shotgun-cop-man-is-my-friend-pedro-devs-new-game-about-arresting-satan/1100-6529644/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shotgun-cop-man-is-my-friend-pedro-devs-new-game-about-arresting-satan.1115676/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/shotgun-cop-man-is-my-friend-pedro-devs-new-game-about-arresting-satan/1100-6529644/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529644">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The developer behind <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/my-friend-pedro-review-vote-for-pedro/1900-6417173/" data-ref-id="1900-6417173">My Friend Pedro</a> has revealed its new game, Shotgun Cop Man, for PC and Nintendo Switch. In this game, Shotgun Cop Man must travel to hell and arrest Satan.</p><p>Shotgun Cop Man's main mechanic revolves around propelling the titular character using firearms across levels and platforms. Its simplistic and minimalist art style complements its chaotic gameplay, allowing players to keep track of incoming bullets while also leaving room for players to make last-minute decisions on how to evade them. Solo dev DeadToast Entertainment said that adding on extra visual flair only increased "cognitive load," leading to a decrease in gameplay flow.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cWSNEN2mZH8" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cWSNEN2mZH8" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>"I mentioned earlier the simplicity of the shotgun-propelling being something that spoke to me. And I wanted to stick with that word, simplicity, and try to make a game where I could strip away or minimize anything that wasn’t contributing to that core flowy feel and experience," DeadToast explained. "Hence the minimalist look and straightforward nature of the game."</p><p>Shotgun Cop Man also includes a level editor, which was one of My Friend Pedro's most-requested features. All of Shotgun Cop Man's levels are built with the same level-editor tools that players will have access to in the full release through Steam Workshop. There will also be No Damage and Speedrun modes for hardcore players.</p><p>The game will cost $10 when it launches on PC and Switch later this year, but a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2966850/Shotgun_Cop_Man/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">demo is now available on Steam</a>. It contains 17 levels for players to go through. It wasn't revealed whether Shotgun Cop Man would get PlayStation and Xbox releases, but My Friend Pedro eventually came <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/my-friend-pedro-comes-to-ps4-next-week/1100-6475317/" data-ref-id="1100-6475317">to all platforms</a>, so it's possible that Shotgun Cop Man will too.</p><p>It's also possible that Shotgun Cop Man will be playable on Switch 2, but it's currently unclear what the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/is-the-nintendo-switch-2-backwards-compatible/1100-6527615/" data-ref-id="1100-6527615">upcoming system's backwards compatibility limitations are</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>