<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 15:44:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NFL's Best Wide Receiver Is Aware Of Madden Curse, Doesn't Want To Be Cover Star]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nfls-best-wide-receiver-is-aware-of-madden-curse-doesnt-want-to-be-cover-star/1100-6528594/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nfls-best-wide-receiver-is-aware-of-madden-curse-doesnt-want-to-be-cover-star.1066302/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nfls-best-wide-receiver-is-aware-of-madden-curse-doesnt-want-to-be-cover-star/1100-6528594/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528594">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Electronic Arts can go ahead and mark one potential star player off its list for cover athlete on next year's edition of the Madden NFL franchise. Cincinnati Bengals wide receiver Ja'Marr Chase revealed during a press conference this week that he doesn't want to appear on the game's cover, seemingly aware of the Madden curse.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://x.com/Trags/status/1869846693451280690" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">On X</a>, Bengals columnist Mike Petraglia shared a video clip of Chase where the star wide receiver discusses video games. While he does play Madden, Chase clearly doesn't want to be the game's cover athlete. When asked about the possibility, the NFL's wide receiver leader in catches, yards, and touchdowns replied: "No, I don't want that [knocks on wood]. No."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/Trags/status/1869846693451280690" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Ja’Marr Chase was all fun and games talking old school video football games and Madden until the subject of a possible cover came up. “No! I don’t want that.” <a href="https://t.co/jfo1P46hgD" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/jfo1P46hgD</a></p>  — Mike Petraglia (@Trags) <a href="https://twitter.com/Trags/status/1869846693451280690?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 19, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">Chase offered a "no comment" when directly questioned about the Madden curse. However, the Bengals wide receiver was open to appearing on the cover of a NFL Street revival game. <a href="https://www.cbssports.com/nfl/news/does-madden-nfl-cover-curse-still-exist-a-look-back-at-25-years-of-covers-after-christian-mccaffrey-nod/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CBS Sports</a> recently ran through the data of Madden cover stars for this century (2000-24), finding that 58% of the players were "cursed"--meaning they dealt with an injury or decline in performance. However, the report states that only 25% in the past decade have been "cursed."</p><p dir="ltr">This all comes after <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-25-cover-athlete-christian-mccaffrey-injured-will-miss-4-games/1100-6526490/" data-ref-id="1100-6526490">Madden NFL 25 star Christian McCaffrey was injured</a> earlier this season. After appearing in only four games, the San Francisco 49ers running back is most likely out for the rest of the season, too. However, McCaffrey also has a history of injuries throughout his career, with multiple seasons where he's missed over half of the season.</p><p dir="ltr">In 2020, GameSpot looked into <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/super-bowl-2020-patrick-mahomes-and-the-madden-cur/1100-6473047/" data-ref-id="1100-6473047">the curse as Kansas City Chiefs quarterback Patrick Mahomes was preparing for the Super Bowl</a>. Mahomes, who appeared on Madden NFL 20's cover, ending up winning the championship, poking a big hole in the curse.</p><p dir="ltr">For more, check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/madden-nfl-25-review-gridiron-grates/1900-6418271/" data-ref-id="1900-6418271">Madden NFL 25 review</a>. In addition, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/peacocks-madden-nfl-cast-will-blend-video-games-with-reality/1100-6528588/" data-ref-id="1100-6528588">Peacock will have a Madden NFL cast this weekend</a>, December 21, for the NFL game between the Kansas City Chiefs and Houston Texans.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Peacock's Madden NFL Cast Will Blend Video Games With Reality]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/peacocks-madden-nfl-cast-will-blend-video-games-with-reality/1100-6528588/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/peacocks-madden-nfl-cast-will-blend-video-games-with-reality.1066173/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/peacocks-madden-nfl-cast-will-blend-video-games-with-reality/1100-6528588/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528588">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>This weekend, the NFL game between the Kansas City Chiefs and the Houston Texans may play a role in determining the No. 1 seed in the AFC. It also has the distinction of being the first-ever EA Sports Madden NFL Cast, an alternate broadcast that will stream exclusively on Peacock.</p><p>The traditional broadcast of the game will remain on NBC, but Peacock's stream will incorporate elements from the Madden NFL video games. For example, Madden's signature passing routes and player ratings will be overlaid on the live-action footage, and the game may incorporate animations from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/madden-nfl-25-review-gridiron-grates/1900-6418271/" data-ref-id="1900-6418271">Madden NFL 25</a> as well. This altcast is being produced specifically with Madden gamers in mind, some of whom may not be traditional football fans.</p><p>"There are millions and millions of Madden fans, and I think we have to really serve them in this game and try to find that perfect blend between the video game and the real game and merge them together," said NBC Sports executive producer Fred Gaudelli in a statement.</p><p>The EA Sports Madden NFL Cast will begin on Saturday, December 21 at 10 AM PT / 1 PM ET on Peacock. Paul Burmeister will provide the play-by-play commentary for the altcast, with former NFL quarterback Kurt Benkert placing the Madden graphic overlays to breakdown potential plays. Former wide receiver Chad Johnson will also contribute as he makes adjustments to players' Madden ratings in real-time. Ultimate Madden Bowl champion player Henry Leverette will take part in the production as well.</p><p>Madden's namesake, John Madden, was a former NFL coach-turned-broadcaster who announced games for all of the major broadcast networks, including NBC. The video game franchise that is synonymous with his name carries so much weight that a report this week suggested that New York Jets owner Woody Johnson vetoed a trade for Denver Broncos wide receiver Jerry Jeudy <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-york-jets-owner-torpedoed-trade-because-of-a-players-madden-rating-report/1100-6528565/" data-ref-id="1100-6528565">because he didn't like Jeudy's Madden player ratting</a>.</p><p>EA recently updated Madden NFL 25 with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/saquon-barkleys-no-look-hurdle-has-been-added-to-madden-nfl-25/1100-6527917/" data-ref-id="1100-6527917">Saquon Barkley's unique no-look spin hurdle into the game</a>, although it can only be performed under specific circumstances. Last month, Amazon's Prime Video debuted <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/first-trailer-for-its-in-the-game-shares-the-history-of-madden-nfl/1100-6527695/" data-ref-id="1100-6527695">It's in the Game</a>, a four-part documentary series about the history and development of the Madden NFL games. Additionally, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nicolas-cage-will-star-as-john-madden-in-biopic-about-the-nfl-legend/1100-6525859/" data-ref-id="1100-6525859">Nicolas Cage will play John Madden</a> in a new biopic from writer and director <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-studded-movie-amsterdam-flops-could-lose-100-million-report/1100-6508153/" data-ref-id="1100-6508153">David O. Russell</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>