<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 17:53:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Leak Points To Toe-Tally Weird New Kicks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-leak-points-to-toe-tally-weird-new-kicks/1100-6530350/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-leak-points-to-toe-tally-weird-new-kicks.1144371/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-leak-points-to-toe-tally-weird-new-kicks/1100-6530350/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530350">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Developer Epic Games is apparently putting its best foot forward with a pair of toe-tally new shoes for the game. To say they're a bit odd is probably an understatement, since the cosmetics feature a humongous big toe bursting through a blue sneaker.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://x.com/HYPEX/status/1904448166121918747" rel="nofollow ">On X</a>, well-known Fortnite leaker HypeX shared the new Kicks--seen below--for the battle-royale title. It's unknown if the cosmetics might just be called "Toe" or a different name. Regardless, they definitely are eye-catching and probably appeal to Once Upon a Time in Hollywood filmmaker Quentin Tarantino.</p><p dir="ltr">If released soon, they'll arrive hot on the heels of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/crocs-are-coming-to-fortnite-so-you-can-ensure-foot-comfort-for-optimus-prime/1100-6530045/">Crocs coming to Fortnite</a>. The addition of the popular brand of clogs and sandals meant you could dress up characters like Batman and Optimus Prime with the comfy footwear.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/your-fortnite-skins-can-finally-wear-jordans-starting-thursday/1100-6527888/">Fortnite Kicks were formally introduced in November</a>, with Nike sneakers, Air Jordans, and unique footwear to the game like Chomp Stomp slippers. Epic has updated <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/help/en-US/c-Category_Fortnite/c-Fortnite_Gameplay/what-are-kicks-and-which-outfits-can-i-use-with-kicks-in-fortnite-a000092738">a list on its website</a> showing the ridiculously long list of skins that are compatible with Kicks.</p><p dir="ltr">Today marks the start of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-og-season-3-release-date-battle-pass-and-everything-else-to-know/1100-6530296/">Fortnite OG Season 3</a>, which is based on a season that originally occurred in February 2018. Additionally, we've compiled all of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/fortnite-og-pass-season-3-all-skins-and-other-rewards/2900-6362/#1">the OG Season 3 battle-pass skins and rewards</a>. Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/negan-is-coming-to-fortnite-alongside-a-major-walking-dead-update/1100-6530326/">The Walking Dead has come to Fortnite Creative</a>, with Negan set to land in the item shop on April 4.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard Makes Unprecedented Move To Restore WoW Classic Hardcore Characters Slain In DDoS Attacks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-makes-unprecedented-move-to-restore-wow-classic-hardcore-characters-slain-in-ddos-attacks/1100-6530351/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blizzard-makes-unprecedented-move-to-restore-wow-classic-hardcore-characters-slain-in-ddos-attacks.1144368/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/blizzard-makes-unprecedented-move-to-restore-wow-classic-hardcore-characters-slain-in-ddos-attacks/1100-6530351/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530351">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a> Classic Hardcore characters who permanently died during recent DDoS attacks will be restored, Blizzard says, citing the disruption as "a cut above anything we've faced before."</p><p dir="ltr">The attacks happened multiple times over the weekend and affected a large number of players, but in particular seemed targeted at the WoW Classic Hardcore streamer guild <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/world-of-warcraft-onlyfangs-twitch-roleplay-1235222436/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">OnlyFangs</a>, a group that has made a name for itself on Twitch playing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-hardcore-servers-will-combat-griefing-but-leave-the-rest-up-to-players/1100-6515547/" data-ref-id="1100-6515547">WoW Classic's high-stakes permadeath mode</a>. During a boss fight against Ebonroc in Blackwing Lair, many Onlyfangs players were disconnected as a result of the denial-of-service attack, resulting in a large number of guild members <a href="https://clips.twitch.tv/ImpartialAdventurousAsteriskPraiseIt-ENr-xvTV29UraV3Z" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">dying</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">The guild leader, a player by the name Sodapoppin, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/1ji81ms/sodapoppin_declares_the_end_of_onlyfangs/?utm_source=embedv2&amp;utm_medium=post_embed&amp;utm_content=whitespace&amp;embed_host_url=https://www.icy-veins.com/wow/news/blizzard-revives-hardcore-characters-affected-by-ddos-attacks/&amp;rdt=35392" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">announced</a> what amounted to the end of the guild shortly after. He cited the targeted attacks as making the continuation of the guild difficult unless Blizzard decided to restore killed characters, something he said he believed was "highly unlikely."</p><p dir="ltr">But that is, in fact, what Blizzard is doing. In a post on the <a href="https://us.forums.blizzard.com/en/wow/t/in-response-to-the-ddos-attacks/2082423" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">WoW Classic forums</a>, associate production director Clay Stone said Blizzard would resurrect characters that died as a result of the attack, which goes against the developer's broader stance on how it treats WoW's Hardcore realms.</p><p dir="ltr">"Unlike the many other ways characters can die in Hardcore, DDoS attacks are an intentionally malicious effort made by third-party bad actors, and we believe the severity and results of the DDoS attacks specifically warrant a different response," Stone said.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard's overall stance on character deaths in WoW Classic Hardcore hasn't changed, Stone continued, stating that characters who die due to random lag spikes, bugs, or occasional server disconnects will not be restored. Stone said in the future, Blizzard may elect at its sole discretion to revive characters that die in a mass event it deems "inconsistent with the integrity of the game," including future DDoS attacks.</p><p dir="ltr">In a post on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/aggrend.bsky.social/post/3ll6byzbyvs2v" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bluesky</a>, WoW Classic senior game producer Josh Greenfield said it had been a "gut wrenching few days" and called the scale and scope of the DDoS attacks "a cut above anything we've faced before."</p><p dir="ltr">"It's a tough call, but the only alternative is letting the losers behind these DDoS attacks win, and honestly, f*** that," Greenfield said.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Could Prompt Major Studios To Delay Games - Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-could-prompt-major-studios-to-delay-games-report/1100-6530346/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-could-prompt-major-studios-to-delay-games-report.1144272/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-could-prompt-major-studios-to-delay-games-report/1100-6530346/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530346">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">Grand Theft Auto VI</a> is coming this year, and it's expected to be a huge success with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-5-could-make-3-billion-in-first-year-alone/1100-6528605/" data-ref-id="1100-6528605">40 million sales and $3 billion in revenue in its first year</a>. Its release looms so large that some publishers are apparently considering delaying their games to avoid a clash.</p><p>Three anonymous "major" video game publishers told <a href="https://www.thegamebusiness.com/p/major-publishers-plan-to-delay-games" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Game Business</a> that they are "ready" to delay upcoming projects due to GTA 6. The report didn't say what these companies are, but an anonymous boss of "one of the world's biggest game publishers" told TGB that Rockstar's releases "always suck a lot of money, and more importantly, time out of the market."</p><p>"We don't want to be anywhere near that. We are working up multiple different plans for our titles," the anonymous executive said. Another unnamed senior executive at a publisher said even without GTA 6 coming to market, it's become "immensely difficult to find free time for new games to shine. Time is the real scarcity for us, not money. It's tough out there."</p><p>Two anonymous developers of "top 10 live-service games" told TBG that they are not planning any major updates to their titles around the time of GTA 6's launch.</p><p>One unnamed studio boss told TGB that GTA 6 is "basically a huge meteor and we will just stay clear of the blast zone." A different developer said there is "no point" in trying to compete with GTA 6 and it might be smarter to "prepare to win players back once the excitement has started to die down."</p><p>GTA 6 is officially set for release in Fall 2025 on PS5 and Xbox Series X|S, but every Rockstar Games release going back a decade has been delayed, so it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-is-scheduled-for-2025-but-rockstar-has-a-history-of-delays/1100-6519700/" data-ref-id="1100-6519700">would be notable if GTA 6 is <em>not </em>delayed.</a> Take-Two boss Strauss Zelnick has acknowledged that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-still-on-track-for-release-in-fall-2025/1100-6529307/" data-ref-id="1100-6529307">GTA 6 could be delayed</a>.</p><p>Publishers being wary of launching near GTA 6 is not a new concern. At the end of 2024, it was reported that many publishers were <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/publishers-reportedly-waiting-for-gta-6-release-date-before-setting-their-own-2025-dates/1100-6528325/" data-ref-id="1100-6528325">waiting to assign release dates to their own titles until Rockstar confirmed a date for GTA 6</a>. More recently, an analyst said <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-release-date-not-being-revealed-yet-could-be-disastrous-for-some-analyst-says/1100-6530312/" data-ref-id="1100-6530312">some companies might not survive if they don't properly plan their launch timings around GTA 6</a>.</p><p>GTA 6 coming to market could also help lift the overall video game industry, as a game of that magnitude is expected to draw in new or lapsed players. Ubisoft, for its part, said <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-does-not-scare-ubisoft-ceo-says/1100-6520931/" data-ref-id="1100-6520931">it sees its own game sales grow when a big game like a new entry in the GTA series comes out</a>.</p><p>In related news, Greg Rice of Day of the Devs and PlayStation recently said there is a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-is-not-in-competition-with-indie-games-playstation-boss-says/1100-6530259/" data-ref-id="1100-6530259">fear that GTA 6 is "sucking all the space out" of the industry</a>, but this might not tell the whole story.</p><p>GTA 6 is the first new entry in main series since 2013's GTA V. That game has enjoyed enormous success, selling more than 200 million copies and generating countless additional revenue from GTA Online.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>