<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 23:20:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Players Can Check Out These Games For Free This Weekend]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-players-can-check-out-these-games-for-free-this-weekend/1100-6529957/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-players-can-check-out-these-games-for-free-this-weekend.1127511/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-players-can-check-out-these-games-for-free-this-weekend/1100-6529957/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529957">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Microsoft has <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/03/06/free-play-days-03-06-2025/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">announced</a> a new edition of Free Play Days, offering free access to four games starting today, March 6 and ending on March 10.</p><p>The biggest game on the list is Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six Siege. Ubisoft's popular shooter has entered its 10th year and Xbox Game Pass subscribers can check it out for free. It's especially good timing as the franchise is preparing for its biggest transformation yet with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rainbow-six-sieges-biggest-transformation-yet-teased/1100-6529518/" data-ref-id="1100-6529518">Siege X later this month</a>. This game is also getting a bonus day, so it's available until Monday, March 10 at 11:59 AM PT / 2:59 PM ET.</p><p>AEW: Fight Forever and Test Drive Unlimited Crown are available until Sunday, March 9 at 11:59 PM PT / 2:59 AM ET. They also both require Xbox Game Pass subscriptions.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/aew-fight-forever-review-a-midcard-debut/1900-6418082/" data-ref-id="1900-6418082">AEW: Fight Forever</a> is an arcade wrestling game featuring AEW talent such as Jon Moxley and Toni Storm. There are multiple match types to play in, including four-way and tag-team, as well as other customizations options. It's a great game for AEW fans as it also has a career mode with over 40 weapons to choose from.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-launch-trailer/2300-6465066/" data-ref-id="2300-6465066">Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown</a> is the latest entry in the series and features a 1:1 recreation of Hong Kong Island as its main backdrop. If you're looking for an alternative to Forza or The Crew, be sure to check out Test Drive Unlimited Solar Crown.</p><p>Finally, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/born-of-bread-gameplay-trailer/2300-6461020/" data-ref-id="2300-6461020">Born of Bread</a> is free for all Xbox players until March 9 at 11:59 PM PT / 2:59 AM ET, meaning that you don't need a Game Pass subscription. This game is a turn-based RPG that follows a flour golem named Loaf as he explores the world with his friends.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bethesda Knows Fans Are Eager For Starfield Updates, Promises "Exciting" Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bethesda-knows-fans-are-eager-for-starfield-updates-promises-exciting-year/1100-6529956/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bethesda-knows-fans-are-eager-for-starfield-updates-promises-exciting-year.1127481/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bethesda-knows-fans-are-eager-for-starfield-updates-promises-exciting-year/1100-6529956/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529956">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Fans waiting for news regarding updates or additional DLC for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/starfield/" data-ref-id="5000-483376">Starfield</a> will have to wait a while longer, as developer Bethesda Softworks has acknowledged the lack of updates but promises "exciting things" are in the works for later this year.</p><p dir="ltr">In response to a fan on <a href="https://x.com/StarfieldGame/status/1897709518013997493" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">X</a> asking Bethesda to more clearly communicate what's happening with the game's next update or DLC, the official Starfield account responded by saying it knows fans are eager for news and that the development team has been "hard at work."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/StarfieldGame/status/1897709518013997493" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">We know you're eager for an update, and we truly appreciate your passion for Starfield. The team has been hard at work, and while we're not ready to share specific details just yet, we have a lot of exciting things planned for the game this year that we can't wait to talk about… <a href="https://t.co/XJDGkAEv8m" rel="nofollow ">https://t.co/XJDGkAEv8m</a></p>  — Starfield (@StarfieldGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/StarfieldGame/status/1897709518013997493?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 6, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">"We know you're eager for an update, and we truly appreciate your passion for Starfield," the post reads. "The team has been hard at work, and while we're not ready to share specific details just yet, we have a lot of exciting things planned for the game this year that we can't wait to talk about when the time is right."</p><p dir="ltr">Starfield's latest update came on November 19, 2024, improving performance, fixing bugs, and adding a few quality-of-life changes, like improvements to bounties. Bethesda added its first drivable land vehicle, the REV-8, to better explore alien worlds in August 2024. Alongside the update, Bethesda announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/starfield-passes-15-million-players-as-game-adds-new-vehicle-and-quest/1100-6527873/" data-ref-id="1100-6527873">Starfield had been played by more than 15 million players</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">So far, Starfield only has one DLC expansion, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-long-is-starfield-shattered-space-full-quest-list/1100-6526899/" data-ref-id="1100-6526899">Shattered Space</a>. It was released in September 2024 and added new story content centered around the mysterious House Va'ruun. Similarly to what it previously did for Skyrim and Fallout 4, Bethesda additionally added official mod support, allowing players to create and share user-created content in Starfield.</p><p dir="ltr">In GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/starfield-review-to-infinity-but-not-beyond/1900-6418110/" data-ref-id="1900-6418110">Starfield review</a>, we called Bethesda's latest open-world RPG "a mile wide, but an inch deep," praising its first-person shooting combat and interesting side quests while finding its main story, space exploration, and RPG elements underwhelming.</p><p dir="ltr">Rumors continue to circulate that Starfield, currently only available on Xbox and PC, may release on PlayStation 5, with head of Microsoft Gaming CEO<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/starfield-on-ps5-isnt-ruled-out-xboxs-phil-spencer-says/1100-6529031/" data-ref-id="1100-6529031"> Phil Spencer recently saying he wouldn't commit to Starfield remaining an Xbox exclusive</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>