<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 15:24:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Are 'unreasonable investor expectations' the cause of poor video game market conditions?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/are-unreasonable-investor-expectations-the-cause-of-poor-video-game-market-conditions-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/are-unreasonable-investor-expectations-the-cause-of-poor-video-game-market-conditions.1244079/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image By Brian Jackson via Adobe Stock</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Who is to blame for the brutal video game industry downturn that's driven </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-xbox-begins-latest-round-of-mass-layoffs-with-cuts-at-king-and-zenimax">mass layoffs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-ea-obliterates-black-panther-developer-cliffhanger-games">studio closures</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and (modest) </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/five-takeaways-for-game-developers-from-matthew-ball-s-state-of-gaming-data">declining revenue</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> since 2022? According to new data from The Game Developer Collective (a survey program run jointly with our partners at </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://omdia.tech.informa.com/advance-your-business/media-and-entertainment/games-tech-intelligence-service">Omdia</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">), developers say investors—specifically investors with mismanaged expectations—are the number one party to blame.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This month's Collective surveyed a panel of developers about the economic state of the game industry. When asked what the "main cause" of bad market conditions in the video game business, 64 percent of respondents stated "unreasonable investor expectations" were the number one cause of the downturn.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">60 percent of respondents ranked "mismanagement" as a close second. The next-highest variable was "too-high development costs," according to 43 percent of survey takers.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's certainly a spicy statistic—but is it a fair sentiment? Some Studio founders and investors (who may be a bit biased here) disagree.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I'm not sure that's fair," said Midsummer founder and CEO Jake Solomon. "The venture capital model is built upon significant return on the VC investment."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"When a VC funds our studio, they don't have any expectation of sharing in revenue, they don't set milestones, they don't dictate day to day operations, and they even pay the entirety of the agreed upon funding upfront, it's a great deal for developers. But any company funded by VC knows the deal, you are expected to not just make a great game, but a transformational one." VC investors can only make money through an "exit event" like an acquisition or IPO. "Exit events for game studios are rare," he noted.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/santa-ragione-says-apple-is-delisting-wheels-of-aurelia-without-justification-" target="_self" data-discover="true">Santa Ragione says Apple is delisting Wheels of Aurelia 'without justification'</a></p><p>Image via Game Developer Collective.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Griffin Gaming Partner Jason Della Rocca also disagreed, saying it's really "the complete reverse" "It is the market conditions that are driving investor expectations," he wrote in a comment to Game Developer. "Developers need to wake up and adapt to the new reality that they can no longer just be in the game making business. They need to embrace being in the fan building business, and understand that studio value and sustainability comes from identifying a specific audience/player base and feeding them great games."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">AstroBeam founder and CEO Devin Reimer (who also co-founded and was Chief Executive Owl of VR powerhouse Owlchemy Labs) rounded out the dissent, stating that investors have been "propping up some of the game industry given the withdrawal of platform funding and the collapse of game publishers."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"People are often looking for a simple villain to pin things on, while reality is not as simple or exciting to talk about," Reimer said, saying that "the increase in competition, rising development costs, lack of long-term studio funding, and [overestimates] of game growth during Covid" played a greater role.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-they-tried-to-choke-us-from-the-start-secret-6-madrid-workers-slam-owner-testronic-ahead-of-impending-closure" target="_self" data-discover="true">'They tried to choke us from the start:' Secret 6 Madrid workers slam owner Testronic ahead of impending closure</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Reimer was the only one we spoke with who called out what he referred to as a "mismatch" between investors and the way game studios work. "Successful game studios generally need to launch many games before they get a hit. For example, at my previous studio, Owlchemy Labs, it took 4 original IP games before we had our breakout hit."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Game publishers and platform funding works for this model, because they are focused on individual games. So a studio could get funding for many games without giving up equity in the company and each deal was judged on the odds of success of the title being funded. Meanwhile investors buy a stake in the whole company, and traditionally it is focused around a singular product."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Is it easier to find funding in 2025?">Is it easier to find funding in 2025?</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">While developers have plenty of reason to find fault with investors, there's some hope that funding for new games and studios may be thawing out in 2025.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's not a dramatic thaw, to be clear. The number of developers who reported receiving fundraising in the past 12 months is "virtually unchanged," according to the Collective report, with 30 percent of respondents saying their company received funding.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-star-wars-battlefront-2-player-surge-exposes-a-major-flaw-in-ea-s-business-model" target="_self" data-discover="true">The Star Wars Battlefront II player surge exposes the flaws in EA's business model</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But when asked if it was "harder, easier, or about the same" to get funding this year over the prior year, fewer number of developers reported that it was "harder" than the year before. 50 percent of respondents declared it was more difficult, a 23 percent decrease down from 2024.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There's a chance this may just be developers adjusting to the new reality, as the number of developers saying there was "no change" increased from seven percent to 27 percent, a correlating increase. Fewer developers reported that it was "easier" to find funding this year, dropping from 9 percent to 6 percent.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Della Rocca said this is part of a trend toward what he called "evidence-based investing." This follows a pattern of investors responding well to developers who can prove "audience validation" early in the process. "The real market failure is that there are very limited sources of funding for prototypes and audience validation," said the veteran investor.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Anecdotally, it does seem like 2025 is better than 2024," said Reimer when quizzed about the topic. "But that isn’t saying a lot because 2024 was so bad."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Solomon warned that an improved investing environment may be true at the seed stage, as it still "makes sense" for investors to chip in at that level in exchange for relatively large amounts of equity. But he argued that 2025 is "the worst year" for Series A funding and beyond. "Valuations probably feel too high, exit events are few, and examples of good investment bets in games are not plentiful. It's rough sailing out there, and it's a shame, because many ideas being shopped are extremely low-cost and innovative, which is exactly what our industry needs right now."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One way or another, the game industry does need a way out of this mess that isn't just cashing in on trends and buzzwords. For all the investors out there looking to win over developer sentiment, Reimer might have a solution worth looking into: investing in at least the first two games from a studio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Then you could at least see growth potential and your odds of a hit would go up significantly," he explained. "The problem is due to current high development costs, that means a very large investment out of the gate at a time where it is harder to get investment at all."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game Developer and Omdia are sibling organizations under Informa</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div data-testid="contributor-summary-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Follow Bryant Francis, Senior Editor, on </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/bryantfrancis.me">Bluesky</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> or </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bryant-francis-99898b29">LinkedIn</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>.</span></span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/are-unreasonable-investor-expectations-the-cause-of-poor-video-game-market-conditions-]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Secret 6 Madrid will strike against owner Testronic to secure fair severance]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/secret-6-madrid-will-strike-against-owner-testronic-to-secure-fair-severance</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/secret-6-madrid-will-strike-against-owner-testronic-to-secure-fair-severance.1244022/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">July 15, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>3 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Secret 6 Madrid</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Workers at Secret 6 Madrid intend to strike unless parent company Testronic commits to adequately compensating employees it plans to make redundant.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This morning, we </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-they-tried-to-choke-us-from-the-start-secret-6-madrid-workers-slam-owner-testronic-ahead-of-impending-closure">published an extensive report</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in which four members of the Secret 6 Madrid team accused parent company Testronic of "wildly violating" their labor rights and essentially leaving the art outsourcing studio "to die." The studio is fighting back with assistance from Spanish labor union Confederación General del Trabajo (CGT).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Testronic purchased Secret 6, which also has offices in Manila, around three years ago but staff at the studio </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-testronic-preparing-to-shutter-outsourcing-studio-secret-6-madrid">claim the Spanish location will be effectively shuttered</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on July 31, 2025.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Those based in Madrid say Testronic has failed to provide the studio with business support or work contracts since completing its acquisition in 2023, and believe they have been intentionally sabotaged so the global service provider can prioritize operations in Manila where they say working conditions are "much more precarious and wages much lower."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Now, Secret 6 Madrid studio leaders have told Game Developer the entire team will strike for five days—across July 17, 21, 22, 23, and 24—unless they receive a final offer from Testronic's legal team that meets their demands.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Although the majority of the studio could be laid off at the end of July, leadership confirmed that eight people will remain under contract with clients until November and December 2025. Those staffers have not ruled out the possibility of striking again.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/-a-future-has-been-stolen-zenimax-union-workers-respond-to-microsoft-layoffs" target="_self" data-discover="true">'Our lives were upended:' ZeniMax union workers respond to Microsoft layoffs</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"These eight colleagues are not replaceable, as the clients they work with have specifically requested them (or, at most, someone from the Madrid team who we consider capable of matching their level)," said Secret 6 Madrid leadership in a statement. "Under no circumstances do these clients want to work with the Manila team, as they have mentioned multiple times."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Secret 6 Madrid is demanding Testronic provides fair severance compensation and claims the company has so far tabled offers "far below" their expectations.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our intention was always to continue our professional activity, as we are capable of generating value and benefits if given the opportunity to work on new projects. As the company has decided to shut us down, that possibility has been taken away from us entirely, so we only claim a fair compensation," continues the statement.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Throughout the negotiation process, we have always been open to dialogue and shown flexibility. We have even been willing to consider offers far below our original expectations, while the company has maintained a completely inflexible stance from the start."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/how-co-op-climbing-hit-peak-achieved-2-million-sales-for-less-than-200-000-" target="_self" data-discover="true">How co-op climbing hit Peak achieved 2 million sales for less than $200,000</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In addition, Secret 6 Madrid wants Testronic to recognize the seniority and status of team members who have been employed for a year under an "irregular internship contract," which they explain held them to the same standards, hours, and performance expectations of permanent employees.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>"</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">This period was recognized as valid seniority for the colleagues who were laid off in 2023, just before the Secret 6 studio head resigned. That moment was, in hindsight, the first sign that Testronic had stopped actively seeking new projects, as those team members came from a very specialised field that had already been left without projects for some time," added the studio.&nbsp;"This recognition is entirely legal, according to both union lawyers and the private legal advisors who are supporting us."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Testronic has yet to reply to repeated requests for comment.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/secret-6-madrid-will-strike-against-owner-testronic-to-secure-fair-severance]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>