<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 20:41:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pacific Drive Whispers In The Woods Expansion Is Out Now, And It's Coming To Xbox Too]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pacific-drive-whispers-in-the-woods-expansion-is-out-now-and-its-coming-to-xbox-too/1100-6535659/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pacific-drive-whispers-in-the-woods-expansion-is-out-now-and-its-coming-to-xbox-too.1333432/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535659">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Anyone looking to return to the Olympic Exclusion Zone in the first <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/pacific-drive/">Pacific Drive</a> story DLC, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-of-2024s-best-games-is-getting-a-huge-horror-expansion/1100-6534553/">Whispers in the Woods</a>, are in for a surprise, as the expansion is out right now. In a surprise announcement, developer Ironwood Studios and publisher Kepler Interactive revealed that Whispers in the Woods is now available, and the game has also been ported over to Xbox Series X|S consoles.</p><p>The expansion features a brand-new story and content that Ironwood Studios says is roughly a third of the size of the base game, and it includes new anomalies and horrors to discover.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cXRk1pFRgOc" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/cXRk1pFRgOc" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Players can also experiment with several new gameplay systems, such as the Whispering Tide. This is described as a "mysterious force that grows more perilous" the longer you linger in the Whispering Woods, and to survive, you'll need to equip specially attuned parts to your station wagon that can keep it at bay. Artifacts from Altars will also be found in the expansion, and these offer reality-warping powers that affect both the environment and you.</p><p>Pacific Drive made a lasting impression when it debuted last year, as the Indie survival game blended a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-pacific-drive-pulls-off-being-unnervingly-spooky-and-relaxingly-chill-all-at-once/1100-6523113/">well-crafted layer of suspense with a surprisingly chill vibe</a> as you explored a creepy patch of the Pacific Northwest from the relative safety of your station wagon.</p><p>"With its wonderful depth in both story and gameplay, Pacific Drive is an early hit in 2024," Mark Delaney wrote in GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/pacific-drive-review-road-trippy/1900-6418183/">Pacific Drive review</a>. "It sets out to create a world that fits comfortably in the New Weird genre but brings its own style and substance to it. Though the game can be especially hard to decipher, difficulty options help to counter some of its more overwhelming aspects. I'll stick to bikes in my day-to-day life through the actual northwest, but in Pacific Drive, I'm up for another joy ride through one hell of a winding road."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pacific-drive-whispers-in-the-woods-expansion-is-out-now-and-its-coming-to-xbox-too/1100-6535659/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eating Poop Is No Longer A Solid Strategy In Viral Steam Game Duckov]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/eating-poop-is-no-longer-a-solid-strategy-in-viral-steam-game-duckov/1100-6535668/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eating-poop-is-no-longer-a-solid-strategy-in-viral-steam-game-duckov.1333351/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535668">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The newest update for the viral Steam game Escape from Duckov is out now, and it discourages players from eating poop.</p><p>Up until now, players of the game <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/escape-from-duckov-a-parody-of-tarkov-featuring-ducks-is-putting-up-huge-numbers-on-steam/1100-6535556/" data-ref-id="1100-6535556">made by five people that has sold more than 1 million copies</a> could eat poop to restore energy and hydration values. Players can still do that after the new update, but it's less effective to do so. The patch notes state:</p><p>"Reduced the Energy and Hydration values provided by Poop."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ewmV79zP5XQ" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ewmV79zP5XQ" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/third-person-shooter/after-making-1-million-sales-escape-from-duckov-makes-eating-s-worse/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">As PC Gamer points out</a>, some players resorted to downing dookie to revitalize their character. The fecal matter is found on the map and can be eaten to restore some energy and hydration levels, at the cost of somewhat poisoning yourself. Apparently this proved to be too successful a tactic, and developer Team Soda made some changes. Players can still craft poop to create a throwable weapon called, wait for it, a Poop Ball.</p><p>You can see the full patch notes for the Duckov October 23 update below, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3167020/view/503965668093200561?l=english" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">as Team Soda shared on Steam. </a></p><h2><strong>Escape from Duckov October 23 patch notes</strong></h2><p><b>Updates</b></p><ul><li>Orange Headphones can now be dismantled.</li><li>Added indicator display when the player is injured.</li><li>Removed the footstep sound of dogs.</li><li>Reduced the Energy and Hydration values provided by Poop.</li><li>Added another construction site in the base to prevent players from getting stuck inside rooms.</li><li>Slightly reduced the damage of Storm Creatures.</li><li>In Motion Sickness-Friendly Mode, removed the camera movement when leaving the base.</li><li>Mad Bombers now have a chance to drop other cellar keys.</li><li>Reduced the durability consumption of Small Energy Bullets, Enhanced Small Energy Bullets, and Large Energy Bullets.</li><li>Monster: Storm? now inflicts a “Shatter” effect.</li></ul><p><b>Fixes</b></p><ul><li>Fixed lag issues caused by mining machines.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Sniper Trial quest requirements do not match its description after the last update.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the MCXspear blueprint incorrectly appeared in the Recipe Collection even when it was locked.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Standard Bullet (MAG) crafting recipe used a deprecated item.</li><li>Fixed an abnormal amount of ornaments appearing in the sewers.</li><li>Fixed an issue where weapon attachments were lost when disassembling guns.</li><li>Guns with Armor Penetration will now display their Penetration Level.</li><li>We're trying to fix the issue where reloading caused ammo to become “-1.”</li></ul><p><a href="https://x.com/ZhugeEX/status/1979966966447177783" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Analyst Daniel Ahmad reminded people</a> that Duckov was made by a team of five people, which makes the game's success even more impressive. The game is a parody of Escape from Tarkov and published by BiliBili, a Chinese giant also behind titles like Magicraft, Core Keeper, and Warm Snow.</p><p>Duckov is available now for $15.83 USD, but the price will go up 12% to $18 USD on October 30. It's putting up massive numbers on Steam, where it's reached <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/mostplayed" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">more than 250,000 concurrent players.</a> The game is also available on the Epic Games Store, but not console.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/eating-poop-is-no-longer-a-solid-strategy-in-viral-steam-game-duckov/1100-6535668/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill F's Reception Proves Why Its Feminist Messages Are So Important]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/silent-hill-fs-reception-proves-why-its-feminist-messages-are-so-important/1100-6535638/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-fs-reception-proves-why-its-feminist-messages-are-so-important.1333303/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="">

            
          
  

<section><p>Hinako's hypersexualization is a betrayal to the Silent Hill franchise as a whole and its longstanding theme of exploring violence against women through horror.</p></section>
        
        
                    
              <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><strong><em>Silent Hill f spoilers to follow--read at your own discretion.</em></strong></p><p dir="ltr">Set in the fictional village of Ebisugaoka in 1960s Japan, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/silent-hill-f-review/2300-6466366/">Silent Hill f</a> follows Hinako, a high school-aged girl who is navigating her transition from girlhood to womanhood, defying gender roles and resisting an arranged marriage. As she grapples subconsciously with these struggles, it is revealed in both subtle and overt ways how Hinako has endured psychological and physical abuse in a patriarchal society.</p><p dir="ltr">Hinako’s first journal entry discloses her father’s abuse, as she writes “he yells at Mom, throws things around, and even hits us.” On the first run of the game, it takes under five minutes to discover a magazine suggesting women are happiest when submitting to men. For Japanese-speaking people and players familiar with Japanese culture and folklore, there are considerably more clues that enrich the story. As an English-speaking woman living in 2025, I still found myself wholly resonating with Hinako’s experiences and Silent Hill f’s themes of exploring the various manifestations of sexism and abuse.</p><p dir="ltr">In the simplest of terms, Silent Hill f is a game about the horrors faced as a woman merely existing in a patriarchal society. Distressingly, these horrors are spilling over into the real life reactions to the game.</p><p dir="ltr">The new installment in the Silent Hill franchise has been met with a wave of criticism from (mostly male) content creators referring to it as “woke feminist slop" and “feminist propaganda." This is disappointing, but not surprising. There seem to be gamers who still cannot cope with playing a protagonist who isn’t a white, heterosexual man. Of course, some who typically engage in this gender bias will make an exception for female protagonists that have oversexualization or unrealistic beauty standards baked into their character design.</p><p dir="ltr">In 2024, one Twitter user shared an “anti-woke” gaming list, which has categorized over 1,400 video games into categories, offering a brief explanation as to why you should skip or play. While Silent Hill f has yet to be added, it’s worth noting that Silent Hill 2 is listed as “Not Recommended" for its "overtly anti-family, overtly anti-male, overtly anti-patriarchy, overtly pro-DEI, and subtly pro-LGBTQ+ messaging.”</p><p dir="ltr">General misogyny to the side, players began to drop mods that sexualized a teenage Hinako as soon as Silent Hill f was released. Modding character and game design is not a new practice, and considered a cornerstone of PC gaming. For instance, in September, PC users released a <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/silenthillf/mods/16" rel="nofollow ">“no fog” mod</a> that transforms Ebisugaoka into a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/silent-hill-f-modders-have-already-removed-the-games-signature-fog/1100-6534984/">serene village unstricken by the Silent Hill sickness</a>, and additional mods <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/silenthillf/mods/9" rel="nofollow ">optimize the game’s performance</a>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4589512-mv5bnwi3odk3mgqtmme1zi00nwi0lwi2nzitywu1mwvmmwfkzmnixkeyxkfqcgc%40._v1_.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4589512" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4589512-mv5bnwi3odk3mgqtmme1zi00nwi0lwi2nzitywu1mwvmmwfkzmnixkeyxkfqcgc%40._v1_.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4589512"></a><figcaption>Hinako stands in a dimly lit room.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4589512-mv5bnwi3odk3mgqtmme1zi00nwi0lwi2nzitywu1mwvmmwfkzmnixkeyxkfqcgc%40._v1_.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">However, popular mods for Silent Hill f--with thousands of unique downloads--include those that purposefully make Hinako look “more kawaii” with childlike facial features, and a “girl next door” mod that reenvisions Hinako with a younger-looking character design. While the game endings suggest Hinako is actually in her twenties, that does not negate the fact that she is canonically depicted as being high school age throughout the story.</p><p dir="ltr">On a Steam community thread where the original poster criticizes people complaining about “upskirt censorship,” another Steam user responded with “put me on a list because I got so pissed I installed a straight nude mod.” A self-described “gooner” mod for Hinako that shreds her clothing until she is nude has already been downloaded over 3,200 times.</p><p dir="ltr">To be clear, there are <em>real</em> threats of online censorship that are looming over gamers in the U.S., like the <a href="https://www.projectcensored.org/kids-online-safety-act-first-amendment/" rel="nofollow ">Kids Online Safety Act</a>; the passage of this law would require strict “duty of care” requirements to “protect” children on gaming platforms, which could ultimately result in the removal of a good deal of content. Further, censorship and anti-porn organizations such as Collective Shout have <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/itch-and-steams-new-policies-reflect-a-larger-battle-on-free-speech/1100-6533750/">pressured platforms like Steam to remove or ban any “not safe for work” content</a> under the guise of protecting children and women. In response to the recent campaign by Collective Shout, major payment processors also temporarily halted handling purchases for some “adult” titles. Notably, many of the <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/radio/day6/steam-itch-takedowns-credit-cards-1.7597563" rel="nofollow ">games targeted by ongoing anti-porn campaigns feature LGBTQ+ characters</a> and have no sexual component at all. Game developers choosing not to include upskirt shots of a female protagonist who is a minor is not a form of censorship.</p><p dir="ltr">Hinako is not the only character in Silent Hill f who has been the center of viral streamer clips and mods. In one section of the game, players must figure out a puzzle that takes place in the rice fields of Fog Town that involves pulling pins out of scarecrows, of whom the majority are monstrous figures that resemble girls dressed in ripped school uniforms. As their bodies contort in inhuman positions, and their forced expressions make them look like they are in perpetual pain. While the sexualization of the scarecrows may be an intentional choice on the part of the developers as another representation of misogyny and the male gaze, the reaction from some players demonstrates a lack of understanding. Content creators have joked that they have wives as they position themselves behind the schoolgirl mannequins. They've also made jokes that Konami developers knew what they were doing by making the mannequins bend over to reveal the parts where their plastic legs connect to their doll-like torsos.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4589513-ff%2810%29.png" data-ref-id="1300-4589513" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4589513-ff%2810%29.png" data-ref-id="1300-4589513"></a><figcaption>Scarecrows dressed in school uniforms are posed in disturbing, unnatural positions.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4589513-ff%2810%29.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">On another Steam community thread where a user asked for nude mods of Hinako, a commenter wrote, “I'm proud to see you being a warrior of justice for the fictional characters,” in response to a Steam user asking for the IP address of the original poster.</p><p dir="ltr">To write off the hypersexualization of Hinako as “not deep” because she is a fictional character shows a lack of media literacy at best. I meticulously went through each section of the map to discover key documents and journal entries that expand upon what life is like for women and girls living in Ebisugaoka. With minimal exploration of the map, you’ll inevitably stumble upon dozens of collectibles that reveal the patriarchal oppression of women introduced in Silent Hill f, including those who remain unnamed. For example, there are items like a detailed letter written by an unnamed woman who describes the physical abuse she experiences at the hands of an alcoholic husband. That said, even if you quickly complete the game and focus on combat, the dialogue and cutscenes alone are enough to reveal the throughline of the violence against women as the theme of Silent Hill f.</p><p dir="ltr">It’s important to note that this isn’t about morality or a general takedown of modding female characters. There are <em>plenty </em>of "not safe for work" mods that aren’t inherently toxic. Just this past summer, mod sites were flooded with clothing and non-clothing options for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-stellar-blade-mods/2900-6696/#10">Eve</a>, the (adult) protagonist of Stellar Blade. Rather, it’s about the context, and why these mods are troubling when it comes to Silent Hill f. Many of these mods are in direct contradiction with the games’ overarching theme, which reinforces the hypersexualization present in the story.</p><p dir="ltr">At a surface level, it’s easy to just call these widespread sexist reactions and Hinako mods creepy because, well, they are. Upon greater reflection, there is something disturbingly poignant about the objectification of Hinako and other characters in Silent Hill f. In a way, the hypersexualization is a betrayal to the Silent Hill franchise as a whole and its longstanding theme of exploring violence against women through horror.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4589514-ff%2811%29.png" data-ref-id="1300-4589514" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4589514-ff%2811%29.png" data-ref-id="1300-4589514"></a><figcaption>Hinako stands outside her friend's home.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4589514-ff%2811%29.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Just as Hinako felt isolated playing Space Wars, I felt like I was on a different planet as I played through Silent Hill f while simultaneously watching streamers and viral clips of the game. There is an important cutscene in which Hinako confronts her father for his abuse, as well as her mother for enabling it, before he transforms into a grotesque monster. As Hinako explains in her journal, this version of her father “acts the same way he did when he let his anger get the best of him,” and this is “his true form.” As I entered this boss fight against the man who is supposed to be a source of unconditional love and support, a pit of sadness grew in my stomach imagining Hinako being exposed and sexualized during this devastating moment.</p><p dir="ltr">I felt similarly as I sat through the gory moments of the marriage-like ritual that takes place in the spirit realm with Fox Mask, especially when Hinako’s face is sliced off and replaced with a mask. Hinako is slowly stripped of her autonomy and identity throughout the story, and stripped down physically by some players.</p><p dir="ltr">There is a sense of vulnerability I experienced playing Hinako--and that I’m sure many women experienced--battling monsters that served as a generalized representation of how she is treated by men in her village. For example, there is the Fog Town monster that acts disgustingly “chummy” with her, yet ignores guys. Unlike the other monsters in Silent Hill f that beat, stab, or burn Hinako during grab animations, this “chummy” <a href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/-r1ZTEL_ba0">creature licks her face as a means to drain her sanity and health</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Every woman recognizes and has encountered different versions of these monsters: It may be the cat-caller on the street, the “nice guy” who turns violent if romantically rejected, or an anonymous gamer who hurls misogynistic insults and threats of sexual assault over the mic during a multiplayer game. Sadly, global statistics suggest <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/violence-against-women" rel="nofollow ">one in three women experience gender-based violence</a>, and specifically a <a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/29-07-2024-adolescent-girls-face-alarming-rates-of-intimate-partner-violence" rel="nofollow ">quarter of 15- to 19-year-old girls</a> report they’ve experienced intimate partner violence.</p><p>The fictional world of Silent Hill f is very real in many ways, and the response to the game also demonstrates just how relatable Hinako’s story is regardless of the fictional, horrifying monsters she must battle. It is <em>that deep</em>.</p>
  
                                                              </div>
    

              <div>
  <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>
  
    </div>
      
        
        
  
              


  

    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/silent-hill-fs-reception-proves-why-its-feminist-messages-are-so-important/1100-6535638/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>