<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 17:34:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Must-have tools and libraries for indie game developers in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/must-have-tools-and-libraries-for-indie-game-developers-in-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/must-have-tools-and-libraries-for-indie-game-developers-in-2024.1032723/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/must-have-tools-and-libraries-for-indie-game-developers-in-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Thanks to the constant development of technology and an ever-growing set of powerful tools, indie developers can create games that rival those made by big studios. Indie devs have always matched the big players in creativity and innovation, but now the tech is right there for the taking too.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Along with that, the tools for making games are changing and improving. So if you're an indie developer looking to take your project to the next level, here's your essential toolkit for 2024.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I have divided all the tools into main groups according to their purpose:</span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li></li><li></li><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Programming tools and IDEs,</span></p></div></li><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Libraries and middleware.</span></p></div></li></ul></div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Let’s have a detailed look at each one.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Game Engines">Game Engines</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.valuecoders.com/blog/technology-and-apps/unreal-engine-vs-unity-3d-games-development/">2023 survey</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, among developers working in indie studios, 48% use </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Unity </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">as their primary game engine and 20% use </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Unreal Engine</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">So I won't be original if I say that when choosing a game engine you should pay attention to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://unity.com/">Unity</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>.</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> It is still one of the most popular game engines for indie developers. Why Unity? It’s incredibly versatile: you can create both 2D and 3D games for a variety of platforms, including PCs, consoles, and mobile devices. With a robust repository of assets and a large community, it offers extensive resources and support – an invaluable aspect when in-house resources are limited. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>User-friendly interface, extensive documentation, and strong community support</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> are also among the huge advantages. Unity is ideal for</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> developers who want flexibility and cross-platform capabilities.</span></span></p><p>Screenshot from the game. Image credit: unity.com</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Now let's take a look at why 20% still seem to be a fan of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US">Unreal Engine</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It is renowned for its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>high-fidelity graphics </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and is a go-to choice for developers aiming for AAA-quality visuals. Many of those </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>with minimal coding experience</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> also prefer this engine, as thanks to Blueprints, a visual scripting system, they can quickly create prototypes without having to be a coder with decades of experience. Plus, another advantage is that until the game earns a certain income, it can be</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> used for free</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p>Screenshot from the game. Image credit: unrealengine.com</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A slightly less popular engine is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://godotengine.org/">Godot</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>.</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> It has gained considerable popularity due to its open-source nature and lack of royalties or subscription fees, making it a very lucrative choice for indie developer teams. It can do both 2D and 3D development and offers a node-based architecture, so it is quite intuitive for beginners. Community support is also a key factor. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>If you are looking for a free and open-source engine – Godot is your friend.</span></span></p><p>&nbsp;Screenshot from the game. Image credit: godotengine.org</p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Audio Tools">Audio Tools</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Quality audio - one of the most important aspects of creating a successful game, especially for the audiophiles out there. With the abundance of tools and resources available, choosing the best ones for game development can be a lot. Let me streamline it for you.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One of the most popular tools is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.fmod.com/">FMOD Studio</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>.</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> It is an audio middleware solution that simplifies the process of introducing complex audio into games. It supports adaptive audio, allowing sounds to change depending on game events. It has </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>powerful features, and cross-platform support</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>free</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for indie developers with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>some</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> income.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.audacityteam.org/">Audacity</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>free</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>open-source</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> audio editor for recording and editing sounds. It is a great tool for basic audio manipulation and sound effects creation.</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> It is easy to use, supports many formats and is free.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Melodrive</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is an artificial intelligence-driven music engine designed to create real-time adaptive music for interactive applications such as video games and virtual reality. It creates music that dynamically responds to gameplay, adjusting to the player's actions and environment to enhance immersion. One of the advantages is the creation of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>adaptive music in real-time</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It is also widely appreciated for its support for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>multiple genres and emotional tones, seamless integration with game engines such as Unity and Unreal Engine, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and the ability to adjust to the narrative and pace of the game.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Graphics and art tools">Graphics and art tools</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.blender.org/">Blender</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (does it even need an introduction?) is a free, open-source 3D creation package that does it all — modelling, rigging, animation, rendering, you name it. Its features rival those of pricey, proprietary software, making it a favourite among game developers. Game developers appreciate Blender for its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>extensive toolset, active development and large community. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">It is ideal for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>3D modelling, animation and game asset creation.</span></span></p><p>Screenshots of an image created in Blender. Image credit: blender.org</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For the connoisseurs of the retro feel and those who specialise in pixel art, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.aseprite.org/">Aseprite</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is a perfect tool dedicated for creating animated sprites and graphics. Its user-friendly interface makes creating pixel art accessible and efficient. Among the pros: </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>specialisation for pixel art, animation support, and affordable price. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Naturally – most suitable for 2D games with pixel-art aesthetics.</span></p><p>Screenshots of image creation in Aseprite. Image credit: aseprite.org</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Some developers have successfully integrated </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Blender</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Aseprite </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">into their workflow, using Blender for 3D modelling and texturing, and then importing the results into Aseprite to refine pixel art and animation.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Another fun tool is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://krita.org/">Krita</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">It's a free, open-source drawing software for digital artists. It's great for creating concept art, textures and illustrations. The pros are simple: </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>extensive brush engine, customisable interface and no cost.</span></span></p><p>Screenshots of image creation in Krita. Image credit: instagram.com/krita_foundation</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.deepmotion.com/">DeepMotion</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> offers artificial intelligence-based tools for real-time motion capture and 3D animation. By analysing the video signal, it generates motion data that can be applied to 3D characters, eliminating the need for traditional motion capture suits. Animators, game developers and directors who need</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> motion data without the need for expensive equipment </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">will get the most use out of it.</span></p><p>Screenshot of the work process in DeepMotion. Image credit: deepmotion.com</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Graphics tools are, of course, chosen based on the developer's needs. For example, Blender offers comprehensive 3D modelling tools, including advanced sculpting and UV mapping, which Krita lacks. Krita excels with multiple brush types and stabilisers tailored for digital painting, which Blender doesn't offer. I might be saying an obvious thing, but identifying your needs and choosing software accordingly will save you time and resources in the long run.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Programming tools and IDEs">Programming tools and IDEs</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The most popular tool among developers is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">Visual Studio</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It is a powerful integrated development environment (IDE) developed by Microsoft. It has a complete set of tools for developing applications on various platforms, including desktop, web, mobile and cloud. With features such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>intelligent code editing, advanced debugging, and seamless integration with Microsoft services, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Visual Studio increases productivity and simplifies the development process. Ideal for: Coding in languages such as C++, C#, JavaScript and Python. Most professionals choose to use VS even though it is paid, unlike VS Code. VS Code has fewer features, but it is</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> less resource-intensive and free to use.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For developers working with .NET and Unity, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.jetbrains.com/rider/">JetBrains Rider</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> offers a fast and responsive IDE. It provides intelligent code completion and many features to improve productivity. JetBrains Rider has a very rich feature set, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Unity integration and cross-platform support</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It is best suited </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>for developers who need an advanced IDE for working with C#.</span></span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Version control systems">Version control systems</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://git-scm.com/">Git</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is designed to handle everything from small to very large projects with speed and efficiency. With Git, multiple developers can work on the same project simultaneously without overwriting each other's changes. Enjoy </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>a seamless collaborative environment!</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> So, it is an essential tool for collaboration and also</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> has extensive community support.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To use Git you can choose from a variety of providers, the best-known ones are </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>GitHub</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (offers features such as pull requests, code reviews, issue tracking, and GitHub Actions for CI/CD workflows), </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>GitLab</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (hosting repositories along with integrated CI/CD, project management tools) and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Bitbucket </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">(Atlassian's Git-based code hosting and collaboration tool).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://subversion.apache.org/">Subversion (SVN)</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is a centralised version control system that helps developers manage changes to source code and files over time. It allows multiple contributors to work on a project by tracking each modification in a central repository. Moreover, it keeps a complete history of changes, allowing users to revert to earlier versions if necessary. Benefits – </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>robust centralised control, easy to use, great for managing large binary files, mature and stable, with extensive documentation and community support.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When comparing Git and SVN, it is worth noting that Git is decentralised and therefore more flexible, while SVN is centralised, which limits its flexibility. But, SVN is much easier to learn and understand.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Libraries and middleware">Libraries and middleware</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.photonengine.com/pun">Photon Unity Networking (PUN)</a></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For indie developers venturing into multiplayer games, Photon is a reliable, tried-and-true networking solution. It's integrated with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Unity</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and offers features like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>matchmaking and real-time communication. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">It is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>easy to implement,</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> scalable and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>has good documentation.</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> It is especially suitable for those who </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>implement multi-user functionality.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If you are planning to release your game on Steam, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/sdk">Steamworks SDK</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will be indispensable. It allows you to integrate Steam features such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>achievements, leaderboards and cloud saves. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Another plus is the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>DRM support.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://box2d.org/">Box2D</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is an open-source 2D physics engine for modelling realistic physics for game development and interactive applications. It’s written in C++ and provides a framework for modelling rigid body dynamics including collision detection, friction, restitution and joint constraints. Due to the fact that it is widely used in the industry, Box2D has been ported to various programming languages and platforms, making it accessible to developers working in a variety of environments. Benefits</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>: </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Realistic and efficient physics modelling, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>easy integration with game engines and frameworks, well-documented community support, cross-platform compatibility and the ability to be customised for specific project needs.</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> Ideal for: game developers who want to implement accurate 2D physics in their projects, educational tools for teaching physics, and developers of simulators, platformers and puzzle games that require complex physics interactions.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Successful game development is nothing without the right tools and libraries. Even the brightest, most creative minds need robust tech to make their ideas come to life. Thankfully, we’ve reached a point of abundance, where for any task – there is a tool. The listed in the article are some of the most trusted and widely adopted in the indie game development community as of 2024. They strike a balance of functionality, community support, and affordability that can help bring your creative visions to life. Now, you can pick and choose from this range of options, and perhaps, become the next sensation in the indie game development industry.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>