<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 16:54:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA employees and UVW-CWA slam Saudi-led EA buyout, call for regulatory scrutiny]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-employees-and-cwa-slam-saudi-led-ea-buyout-call-for-regulatory-scrutiny</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-employees-and-uvw-cwa-slam-saudi-led-ea-buyout-call-for-regulatory-scrutiny.1326781/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Screenshot via Electronic Arts, logo via UVW-CWA.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Electronic Arts workers, in conjunction with the video game union United Videogame Workers-CWA Local 9433, have released a public statement criticizing the Saudi Arabia-led buyout of the company and calling for regulatory scrutiny.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The statement—crafted in part by the CWA and EA employees who have signed up for membership with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/industry-wide-union-uvw-cwa-has-already-welcomed-over-100-new-members">the industry-wide union UVW-CWA</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">— argues that the deal jeopardizes workers at the company who have already spent two years enduring </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-allegedly-lays-off-hundreds-of-workers-after-canceling-more-games-at-respawn-entertainment">layoffs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-ea-obliterates-black-panther-developer-cliffhanger-games">studio closures</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. EA has informed workers that "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-says-55-billion-take-private-won-t-result-in-immediate-layoffs">no immediate layoffs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" will take place upon the completion of the buyout, but those assurances come from a company that said it was primed for "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-says-business-primed-for-accelerated-growth-following-layoffs">accelerated growth</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" after gutting hundreds of jobs.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"EA is not a struggling company," the unnamed workers said in their statement. "EA’s success has been entirely driven by tens of thousands of EA workers whose creativity, skill, and innovation made EA worth buying in the first place. Yet we, the very people who will be jeopardized as a result of this deal, were not represented at all when this buyout was negotiated or discussed."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The statement lays out concerns that studios deemed "less profitable," but whose work defines EA's reputation, could be on the chopping block. Citing </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-gaming-is-the-new-oil-how-the-ea-buyout-diverges-from-the-traditional-playbook-">reporting from our own Nicole Carpenter</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, they asked what will be done to pay off the $20 billion in debt secured for the transaction by the Saudi Public Investment Fund and Affinity Partners, the firm owned by Jared Kushner, son-in-law of President Donald Trump.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/us-senators-concerned-about-foreign-influence-in-ea-buyout" target="_self" data-discover="true">US senators concerned about 'foreign influence' in EA buyout</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"If jobs are lost or studios are closed due to this deal, that would be a choice, not a necessity, made to pad investors' pockets—not to strengthen the company," they said.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="EA buyout stakeholder Jared Kushner already advises key regulator Scott Bessent">EA buyout stakeholder Jared Kushner already advises key regulator Scott Bessent</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The statement lands a day after US senators Elizabeth Warren and Richard Blumenthal </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/us-senators-concerned-about-foreign-influence-in-ea-buyout">sent strongly-worded letters</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to U.S. treasury secretary and Committee of Foreign Investment chair Scott Bessent and Electronic Arts CEO Andrew Wilson expressing concern for "foreign influence" as a result of the deal. That influence could include "surveillance of Americans, covert Saudi propaganda, and selective retaliation and censorship of persons disfavored by the Saudi government."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The pair urged Bessent and other regulators to conduct a "thorough investigation" of the transaction EA workers and the CWA echoed this message in a call for elected officials and regulators to exert similar scrutiny and "ensure that any path forward protects jobs, preserves creative freedom, and keeps decision-making accountable to the workers who make EA successful."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blizzard-entertainment-platform-and-technology-workers-unionize-under-cwa" target="_self" data-discover="true">Blizzard Entertainment Platform and Technology workers unionize under CWA</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">They followed this with comment that regulators and elected officials "won't save" the video game industry. This comment is particularly relevant given Kushner's close relationship with Bessent. According to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.wsj.com/world/middle-east/jared-kushner-trump-second-term-5738956b">the Wall Street Journal</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Kushner advised Bessent during ongoing trade negotiations with China.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The union argued that game developers—particularly those at EA—will be the only ones who can save the industry. "Organizing is the only thing that guarantees workers a real voice when ownership changes hands, and it’s the only way to ensure that the people who make video games have a say in how they’re run," they wrote.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The value of video games is in their workers. As a unified voice, we, the members of the industry-wide video game workers’ union UVW-CWA, are standing together and refusing to let corporate greed decide the future of our industry."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has reached out to EA for comment and will update this story when a response is issued.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-employees-and-cwa-slam-saudi-led-ea-buyout-call-for-regulatory-scrutiny]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>