<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 13:16:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is generative AI really 'just a tool'?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/programming/is-generative-ai-really-just-a-tool</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-generative-ai-really-just-a-tool.1203132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/programming/is-generative-ai-really-just-a-tool<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"AI is inevitable."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That's a phrase that's rattled around my head for a month. Not willingly mind you. It's taken up lodging in my grey matter after hearing it in meetings, reading it in emails, and seeing it buffeted back and forth across Bluesky, LinkedIn, and Discord.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's not a convincing phrase. If you hear it from AI boosters it's easy to brush off as raw hype, and if you hear it from doomsayers it can lull you into a sense of fatalism. But as the philosopher Natasha Bedingfield </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://youtu.be/b7k0a5hYnSI?si=wpIbqOH5OM9T3WeS">told us in 2004</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, today is where the book begins, the rest is still unwritten. Nothing, for better or worse, is inevitable.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But in those various calls another phrase—one you may have heard at your studio—has slipped past more unnoticed: "AI is just a tool. It can be used for good or evil, like any other tool."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">After all this is a business where we use tools for good or evil, right and wrong, correctly and incorrectly. We debate the effectiveness of Unity, Unreal, or Godot. We agonize over whether to use procedural versus hand-crafted content. We debate and discuss the topic so much that Game Developers Conference has a whole </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://gdconf.com/tools-summit">Tools Summit</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> dedicated to craft of making game development software.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Viewing generative AI through the neutral lens of tool assessment is natural—and I'll go so far as to say admirable—for our community. It's a method we use to get past hype and bombast, to try and take technology on its own terms and see how it fits our purposes. And as the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gdc-2025-state-of-the-game-industry-devs-weigh-in-on-layoffs-ai-and-more">2025 GDC State of the Industry</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> report tells us, some developers are adopting generative AI, plenty of them not bought in on the hype but through the act of seeking the right tool for the job.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/is-nvidia-s-ai-driven-npc-tech-just-really-expensive-improv-" target="_self" data-discover="true">Is NVIDIA's AI-driven NPC tech just really expensive improv?</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But looking at generative AI as 'just a tool' is a deeply flawed lens. That phrase betrays a quiet cynicism (one we hear often from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://youtu.be/RYa-_lrG3H8?si=GTDXPf9__8MOWGZg">opponents of firearm regulation</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in the United Stats). Because nothing—not generative AI, not a firearm, not even a hammer—is "just a tool."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The function of tools is influenced by their form">The function of tools is influenced by their form</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Consider two tools found in many American households: the claw hammer and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3887145">the handgun</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Normally Game Developer restricts itself to the craft of making video games but I promise this is relevant. Guns are another tool where neutralizing rhetoric is deployed to downplay a tool's negative effects. I grew up in a gun-owning house in a gun-owning neighborhood in suburban Maryland. There were probably four handguns sitting in lockboxes across two rooms, a few rifles and shotguns in a vault in the basement, and one questionably legal World War I firearm tucked away in a closet. The NRA's mantra of "guns don't kill people, people kill people" was commonplace. A neighbor of mine laughed when I advocated for stronger regulations on gun ownership on the basis of "guns are meant to kill." "Guns aren't meant to kill," I recall him saying. "Cars can kill people. Does that mean cars are meant for killing?"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">His point boils down to this: The </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>outcome </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">of the tool's use is not worth considering when discussing regulation, only its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>potential </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">use. A gun is a tool and the user has control over a tool is used.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Cars are already tightly regulated and cost thousands of dollars, making his point moot, so we'll break down the construction of the claw hammer instead. We generally refer to hammers as being used to pound nails into wood, but I mainly use mine for hammering anchors into drywall because I'm a theater kid and was taught in crew to trust screws.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In either case, the physical shape of the claw hammer dictates its most common purpose. The handle extends into a metal object that is blunt at one end, and clawed on the other. The design follows the swing of the human arm, transferring kinetic energy generated by the bicep, down the elbow, through the wrist, and into the blunt end.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We also know that claw hammers are not useful for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>every</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> form of transferring this energy. Variations on hammer design like the ball-peen hammer show how this basic purpose needs to be altered for different tasks. The shape and the material changes depending on the purpose. To sell more hammers, companies invest in better materials and affordances like rubber grips to make their use more comfortable.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Like a firearm, hammers can be used as weapons. That same transference of force can be used to harm another living being. Video games sometimes place hammers in a players' loadout alongside guns, grenades, and weapons of war.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Neither the hammer nor the firearm is "just" a tool. They are tools that are </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>optimized</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for a purpose. We can study that purpose, and cast judgements about a tool's safety, merits, and need to be regulated based on that.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>But</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The shape of the hammer is not an efficient way to inflict harm. This is supported by data from the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://cde.ucr.cjis.gov/LATEST/webapp/#/pages/explorer/crime/shr">FBI Crime Statistics survey</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which gathers data filed by police departments that participate in assembling data. "Handgun" is the most common weapon used in homicides, and "knife/cutting instrument" ranks higher than "blunt objects." That's because handguns are an incredibly efficient means of wounding living beings.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Let's break down the handgun the way we did the hammer. Handguns are assembled from an assortment of components that transfer the squeeze of a trigger into the strike of a hammer against a firing pin, which strikes the primer of a bullet's cartridge and sends it propelling out of the tube. Though some bullets seen in larger firearms are meant to penetrate metal, a handgun's bullet is envisioned and designed to cut through flesh.</span></p><p>Image via Adobe Stock.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These constraints make handguns efficient at few other tasks. In a pinch you could use the butt of a handgun as a hammer. I can't find any data about them being used for that purpose. I can only wander onto a construction site and count the number of firearms in toolboxes as a general sample size.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Neither the hammer nor the firearm is "just" a tool. They are tools that are </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>optimized</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for a purpose. We can study that purpose, and cast judgements about a tool's safety, merits, and need to be regulated based on that. Firearm advocates oppose this process through neutralizing language because it's difficult to dispute the correlation between the number of guns versus the number of murders and assaults with guns in a geographic area.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Generative AI proponents sometimes regurgitate that language when defending this new technology. Because like the gun lobby, they don't want the purpose of generative AI decided by its outcomes, only its potential.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">What is that purpose? It may be the death of truth itself.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Generative AI is broadly used to deceive through mimicry">Generative AI is broadly used to deceive through mimicry</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Generative AI is a tool for deception.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That's not what its biggest backers will tell you. It's broadly pitched as a tool for efficiency. But efficiency is hard to measure and easy to game. Deception is loud and obvious. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/openai-chatgpt-ai-cheating-education-college-students-school.html">Students are using it to cheat on papers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/frankmckenna/2024/12/16/5-ai-scams-set-to-surge-in-2025-what-you-need-to-know/">Scam calls with AI-generated voices are on the rise</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The Department Human Health and Services </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.notus.org/health-science/make-america-healthy-again-report-citation-errors">published a study</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> citing secretary Kennedy's unfounded health views that cites nonexistent studies, likely generated through AI. There was that cadre of YouTubers </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://deadline.com/2025/03/inside-youtube-fake-movie-trailers-1236352406/">creating AI-generated fake movie trailers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to attract clicks and make money off people who don't follow entertainment use. Apple marketed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91218041/apple-intelligence-ad-total-idiots">Apple Intelligence</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> with advertisements showing people deceiving their neighbors, family, and coworkers. Activision Blizzard </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/activision-blizzard-is-using-generative-ai-to-hawk-games-that-don-t-exist">used generative AI to advertise games</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that don't exist.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Now here's the rub: games—and all of entertainment—are also a form of deception. We use the phrase "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/programming/making-immersive-games-1-1-maintaining-the-magic-circle">magic circle</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" to describe how we attract players into our worlds. We use </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/deep-dive-the-movement-of-echo-point-nova">camera tricks</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/programming/the-technical-magic-behind-doctor-strange-s-portals-in-marvel-rivals">rendering technology</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and even </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/programming/deep-dive-the-narrative-octopus-of-i-was-a-teenage-exocolonist">VO barks</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to simulate digital worlds. People engage with games, film, TV, books, and especially magic shows because on some level they want to be not just deceived, but lied to. AI has also been sold as technology that will let every player make their own perfect experience tailored for them by generating worlds, visual assets, and audio on the fly. But the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://venturebeat.com/games/liminal-experiences-raises-5-8m-for-ugc-and-ai-gaming/">best pitches</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> I've </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bitpart.ai/">heard for AI</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> tend to "hide" the presence of the LLM, only mildly asking the player for prompts in order to accomplish behind-the-scenes computing tasks. These lies can make shared realities, not wholly distinct ones.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That is the difference between telling lies to make virtual worlds and and telling lies to shape the real one. Lies in virtual worlds create shared realities. Lies in the real world tear them down.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">How appropriate that one such "shared reality," the Star Wars show Andor, recently warned us about the price we pay with treating AI as "just a tool." "The loss of an objective reality is perhaps the most dangerous," said the character Mon Mothma in a climactic speech decrying the whitewashing of a carefully executed genocide.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"When truth leaves us, when we let it slip away, when it is ripped from our hands, we become vulnerable to the appetite of whatever monster screams the loudest."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game Developers Conference and Game Developer are sibling organizations under Informa</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div data-testid="contributor-summary-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Follow Bryant Francis, Senior Editor, on </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/bryantfrancis.me">Bluesky</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> or </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bryant-francis-99898b29">LinkedIn</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>.</span></span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>