<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 23:19:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Relaxing Baby Steps Nature Stream Sees A Guy Violently Fall Into Frame Every 15 Minutes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/relaxing-baby-steps-nature-stream-sees-a-guy-violently-fall-into-frame-every-15-minutes/1100-6534963/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/relaxing-baby-steps-nature-stream-sees-a-guy-violently-fall-into-frame-every-15-minutes.1305849/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534963">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/baby-steps/" data-ref-id="5000-590662">Baby Steps</a>, the literal walking simulator from the minds behind games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/qwop/" data-ref-id="5000-93182">QWOP</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/getting-over-it-with-bennett-foddy/" data-ref-id="5000-473119">Getting Over It</a>, is out now, and publisher Devolver Digital is celebrating with a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xjgjDYppxbA" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">relaxing "naturescape" stream</a> where the game's protagonist Nate violently falls into frame every 15 minutes.</p><p dir="ltr">It's all as weird, jarring, and hilarious as it sounds. In Baby Steps, "unemployed failson" Nate must traverse a "mountain-sized mountain" using the power of putting one foot in front of the other using the game's unique (and by the look of it, frustrating) physics-based control scheme. The stream highlights various landscapes from the game that Nate must overcome and presents them as serene, idyllic vistas.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xjgjDYppxbA" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/xjgjDYppxbA" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Every few minutes, however, the stream takes a sharp turn as Nate comes tumbling down some rocks or faceplants into the dirt, mimicking the experience more than a few Baby Steps players are having themselves. It's never not funny, in large part because it's easy to forget it's going to happen while the stream runs in the background on a second monitor, only for the peaceful sounds of nature to be suddenly interrupted by a bumbling oaf crashing through the landscape.</p><p dir="ltr">Those who pay close attention to the stream will notice there's more than just Nate occasionally bursting into view in a physics-based cacophony. Product keys for free copies of Baby Steps occasionally flash across the screen as well, rewarding those who have become entrapped by the meditative experience of waiting for a comically proportioned man-baby to flail onto the screen.</p><p dir="ltr">Baby Steps isn't quite like anything else out there, as is evident by its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/well-this-esrb-description-sure-is-a-wild-ride/1100-6534659/" data-ref-id="1100-6534659">truly wild ESRB rating description</a> that includes the phrase "human/donkey hybrids with exposed male genitalia." Originally scheduled to release earlier, Devolver wisely chose to delay Baby Steps to September 23 in order to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-latest-silksong-induced-game-delay-doesnt-hide-its-reasoning-in-new-trailer/1100-6534273/" data-ref-id="1100-6534273">avoid the debut of Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>, which it announced with a video of Nate comically failing to climb a statue of Silksong's heroine Hornet.</p><p dir="ltr">Baby Steps is available now on PC and PlayStation 5, and is also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baby-steps-is-steam-deck-verified-meaning-you-can-just-throw-the-whole-system-when-frustrated/1100-6534828/" data-ref-id="1100-6534828">Steam Deck verified</a>, in case you wanted the ability to throw your whole console in frustration.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/relaxing-baby-steps-nature-stream-sees-a-guy-violently-fall-into-frame-every-15-minutes/1100-6534963/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty: Black Ops 7 Lets You Pet The DAWG]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-lets-you-pet-the-dawg/1100-6534961/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-lets-you-pet-the-dawg.1305807/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534961">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Activision has confirmed that you can indeed pet the dog in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel/1100-6529073/" data-ref-id="1100-6529073">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a>, but it's not exactly what you think. Black Ops 7 is a futuristic game set in 2035, and it features the Deployable Armored Weaponized Groundcraft, or <a href="https://callofduty.fandom.com/wiki/DAWG" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">D.A.W.G.</a> In a newly released video, the developers from Treyarch said a small team put in the work to add the ability to pet the killer robot machine. </p><p>"This is a fun one. It started as a small, little Easter egg and, inevitably, somebody asked the question, <a href="https://imgur.com/gallery/can-i-pet-that-dawg-GK5crqi" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">'Can I pet that dog?'</a> And a very small group of people made it happen," design director Matt Scronce said.</p><p>You can see the character petting the D.A.W.G. in the video below, but Scronce said Treyarch is not going to reveal exactly <em>how </em>players achieve petting the D.A.W.G. You'll have to figure that out for yourself, he said.</p><p>Players will get to try to figure it out for themselves when the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-start-time-how-to-get-in-and-everything-else-to-know/1100-6534073/" data-ref-id="1100-6534073">Black Ops 7 multiplayer beta</a> kicks off in early October. </p><p>Earlier this week, Activision opened the floodgates on information about Black Ops 7's multiplayer, including revealing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-trailer-shows-off-all-18-maps-coming-at-launch/1100-6534905/" data-ref-id="1100-6534905">all the maps</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-all-modes/2900-7059/" data-ref-id="2900-7059">modes available at launch.</a></p><p>Activision will share lots more details on Black Ops 7's multiplayer mode during the Call of Duty: Next event, which is scheduled for September 30. </p><p>Black Ops 7 is a direct sequel to 2024's Black Ops 6, which was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/2024s-best-selling-games-in-the-us/2900-5106/" data-ref-id="2900-5106">the year's best-selling game in the US.</a> The same two co-lead developers, Raven Software and Treyarch, made both games.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-lets-you-pet-the-dawg/1100-6534961/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Pokemon Legal Chief "Wouldn't Touch" Homeland Security Video That Used Ash Ketchum]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/former-pokemon-legal-chief-wouldnt-touch-homeland-security-video-that-used-ash-ketchum/1100-6534960/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-pokemon-legal-chief-wouldnt-touch-homeland-security-video-that-used-ash-ketchum.1305783/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534960">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2025-09-23T11:10:45-0800">September 23, 2025 at 11:10AM PDT</time></p></section>
        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In response to the Department of Homeland Security's video using Ash Ketchum to promote ICE, The Pokemon Company's ex-legal chief said he "wouldn't touch" it, suggesting some possible reasons why the company might not pursue legal action.</p><p>This week, Homeland Security <a href="https://x.com/DHSgov/status/1970251208322621530" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">posted a video to X</a> of an arrest compilation. In between footage of ICE agents handcuffing people at their homes and in their cars are clips from the OG Pokemon TV series, with the famed "Gotta catch 'em all" theme playing in the background. When Ash Ketchum looks up at the sky, the text "The Department of Homeland Security" populates the screen in Pokemon's iconic yellow-and-blue font. As a Poke Ball closes, the camera zooms in on wrists in cuffs. And at the very end of the video, those arrested appear as Pokemon cards with their "crime" described under their picture.</p><p>Fans were understandably upset about this, with many in the comments begging for The Pokemon Company to sue the DHS. However, the company's former legal chief, Don McGowan, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fans-want-pokmon-to-sue-after-department-of-homeland-security-video-uses-ash-ketchum-to-promote-ice-but-the-companys-former-legal-boss-says-he-wouldnt-touch-this" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">explained to IGN</a> why The Pokemon Company likely won't do anything about the video.</p><p>"I don't see them doing anything about this for a few reasons," McGowan started. "First, think of how little you see [The Pokémon Company International]'s name in the press. They are insanely publicity-shy and prefer to let the brand be the brand. Second, many of their execs in the USA are on green cards. Even if I was still at the company I wouldn't touch this, and I'm the most trigger-happy CLO [Chief Legal Officer] I've ever met. This will blow over in a couple of days and they'll be happy to let it."</p><p>It's unclear what The Pokemon Company proper will do or say in response to the DHS's co-opting of Pokemon and Ash Ketchum. The video is still up and has been reposted by the government body's official account, so it appears as though DHS is happy to continue using Ash and the "Gotta catch 'em all" theme as ICE promotional material.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/former-pokemon-legal-chief-wouldnt-touch-homeland-security-video-that-used-ash-ketchum/1100-6534960/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>