<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 09:17:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Sports NHL Celebrates Alexander Ovechkin's Record-Breaking Goal]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/07/ea-sports-nhl-celebrates-alexander-ovechkins-record-breaking-goal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-sports-nhl-celebrates-alexander-ovechkins-record-breaking-goal.1157925/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/07/ea-sports-nhl-celebrates-alexander-ovechkins-record-breaking-goal<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Over the weekend, Washington Capitals forward Alexander Ovechkin scored his 895th goal, surpassing the legendary Wayne Gretzky to become the NHL’s all-time leading goal scorer. To celebrate this feat, EA Sports released a video congratulating Ovechkin and offering in-game rewards in NHL 25.</p>

<p>Starting today, players can log into Hockey Ultimate Team to receive a Milestones Ovechkin item. Ovechkin HUT Moments challenges will grant tokens to upgrade the item. Additionally, EA Sports is adding an "895 Ovechkin" HUT item that features special art and a 99 overall rating. Finally, NHL 25 is adding a commemorative "895" jersey in World of Chel and making it available to all players.</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="425f68dd-d863-400f-acfd-be6ba24c10c8" data-langcode="en" data-entity-embed-display-settings="[]">





</article><p>Alexander Ovechkin first appeared in an EA Sports NHL game in 2006 with NHL 07, where he also served as the cover athlete. Since then, he has appeared in every entry and was the cover athlete of NHL 21 and NHL 94 Rewind, making him one of only three players to be featured on the cover of EA Sports' NHL franchise multiple times. He was also the cover athlete of NHL 2K10 in the now-defunct NHL 2K series.</p>



<p>Alexander Ovechkin was selected first overall by the Washington Capitals in 2004. However, due to the 2004/2005 NHL lockout, Ovechkin didn't make his NHL debut until 2005. In the time since, Ovechkin has been elected to 13 All-Star teams, was named an All-Decade First-Team member for both the 2000s and 2010s, and won the Calder Memorial Trophy for Rookie of the Year in 2006, as well as three Hart Memorial Trophies for Most Valuable Player. In 2018, Ovechkin led the Capitals to the franchise's first and only Stanley Cup, where he also took home the Conn Smythe Trophy for the Stanley Cup Final's Most Valuable Player.</p>

<p>NHL 25 arrived on October 4, 2024, on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[La Quimera, A New Futuristic Shooter By Former Metro And Stalker Devs, Arrives This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/07/la-quimera-a-new-futuristic-shooter-by-former-metro-and-stalker-devs-arrives-this-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/la-quimera-a-new-futuristic-shooter-by-former-metro-and-stalker-devs-arrives-this-month.1157916/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/07/la-quimera-a-new-futuristic-shooter-by-former-metro-and-stalker-devs-arrives-this-month<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>La Quimera is an upcoming story-driven futuristic shooter and the debut title by Reburn, a young developer founded by former developers of the Metro series. The impressive-looking action game arrives later this month, but players can access a closed beta even sooner.</p>

<p>The game is set in 2064 in a futuristic, dystopian Latin American city. Players control a private military operative outfitted in a powerful exosuit boasting features such as a scanner to pinpoint hidden enemies, an electric shock weapon to stun multiple targets, and enhanced agility for evasion. Wielding an arsenal of advanced weaponry, players will take on hostile foes, including robotic enemies. La Quimera can be played solo or with up to two other friends in three-player co-op. Check out the gameplay trailer and a batch of new screenshots below.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JVCU_hdG3Iw" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>The Ukranine-based Reburn is an indie studio founded in 2006, formerly under the name 4A Games Ukraine. It consists of over 100 developers whose credits include the Metro series and the original S.T.A.L.K.E.R.</p>



<p>Reburn is hosting a 24-hour closed beta for La Quimera on April 12, but space is limited. You can sign up for the beta on the game’s Steam page and play the full version when it launches on April 25 on PC for $29.99.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie’s Marathon Gets Gameplay Reveal This Weekend]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/07/bungies-marathon-gets-gameplay-reveal-this-weekend</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bungie%E2%80%99s-marathon-gets-gameplay-reveal-this-weekend.1157913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/07/bungies-marathon-gets-gameplay-reveal-this-weekend<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Marathon, Bungie’s upcoming multiplayer extraction shooter, is getting its first gameplay reveal this weekend. The date was revealed via a community ARG campaign that saw thousands of fans decipher a series of fragmented codes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The gameplay reveal presentation airs this Saturday, April 12, starting at 10 a.m. PT/1 p.m. ET. It will be broadcast on Bungie’s Twitch, YouTube, and TikTok accounts.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PZUv1-qR1Aw" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p><span><span>First </span></span><a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/playstation-showcase/2023/05/24/bungie-is-revitalizing-its-old-shooter-series-marathon"><span><span><span><span>announced</span></span></span></span></a><span><span> in 2023, this reimagining of the original Marathon series, one of Bungie’s earliest shooter franchises from the ‘90s, puts players in the roles of cybernetic mercenaries called Runners. The game unfolds in a lost colony on the dangerous planet Tau Ceti IV, and Runners are specially designed to survive the world’s harsh conditions and search for lost artifacts and other treasures.&nbsp;</span></span></p>

<p><span><span>That premise translates to team-based matches where players must work together to salvage and extract the most loot (such as weapons and gear) while preventing the opposing team from doing so. Bungie hasn’t divulged many more details up to this point, so we expect Saturday’s showcase to provide a deeper dive into everything Marathon offers.</span></span></p>

<p><span><span>Marathon has no release window but will be available on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC at launch.&nbsp;</span></span></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>