<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:17:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After 11 Years Of Development, This Game Is Finally Ready For Early Access Business]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/after-11-years-of-development-this-game-is-finally-ready-for-early-access-business/1100-6535355/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-11-years-of-development-this-game-is-finally-ready-for-early-access-business.1321756/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535355">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/tavern-keeper/">Tavern Keeper</a> developer Greenheart Games has officially announced that its fantasy-themed business simulator will be launching in Steam Early Access on November 3. A follow-up to Game Dev Tycoon, Greenheart Games is celebrating the development milestone with a new trailer for the game <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/436780/Tavern_Keeper/" rel="nofollow ">and an updated demo</a> that has gone live ahead of the October edition of Steam Next Fest.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IjqNMKF13q4" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IjqNMKF13q4" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Similar to management games like Two-Point Hospital, Tavern Keeper is all about running your very own inn and dealing with the challenges of the service industry within its fantasy setting. The game mixes light humor with an in-depth simulation mode that allows you to tweak your establishment's design to a high degree, as well as detailed decorative elements in its sandbox mode that allow you to create everything from bustling taprooms to relaxing reading corners.</p><p>Tavern Keeper also offers a campaign narrated by English actor Steven Pacey, and this part of the game will see players build taverns across several varied challenges. Each region will offer its own challenges, fantasy cultures, and stories.</p><p>As mentioned above, Steam Next Fest kicks off on October 13. This new edition of the week-long event will once again offer demos for unreleased games. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/when-is-the-next-steam-sale-date/1100-6532422/" data-ref-id="1100-6532422">Other big Steam promotions</a> scheduled for this year include Steam Scream (October 27 - November 3), Animal Fest (November 10-17), Sports Fest (December 8-15), and the Steam Winter Sale will start on December 18.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/after-11-years-of-development-this-game-is-finally-ready-for-early-access-business/1100-6535355/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GenAI Is "Very Seducing," Battlefield 6 Boss Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/genai-is-very-seducing-battlefield-6-boss-says/1100-6535356/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genai-is-very-seducing-battlefield-6-boss-says.1321753/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535356">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Electronic Arts has been implementing AI technologies in its development cycles for years, and while EA says there is no content in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-battle-royale-release-date-trailer-details/1100-6533631/" data-ref-id="1100-6533631">Battlefield 6</a> made using generative AI, the technology is "very seducing," according to DICE GM Rebecka Coutaz.</p><p>She told <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8xrkxdkkrno" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">BBC Newsbeat</a> that EA's teams use genAI in the early stages of development "to allow more time and more space to be creative." But Battlefield 6 has no genAI-created content. She is optimistic about the technology overall, though. "If we can break the magic with AI it will help us be more innovative and more creative," she said.</p><p>Another Battlefield 6 developer, Fasahat "Fas" Salim, told the site that genAI is "not anything to be scared of" in the video game industry and that teams are now working on figuring out how to best implement the technology into future development pipelines.</p><p>"It's just a matter of how we can incorporate that productively into our workflows; how can we leverage that to take our games to the next level," he said.</p><p>To hear EA developers speak enthusiastically about AI is no big surprise, as the company's other key executives, including CEO Andrew Wilson, have said the tools will help EA in the long run. Wilson has said further adoption of AI technologies <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-says-ai-will-help-its-teams-get-to-holy-grail-of-game-development/1100-6523265/" data-ref-id="1100-6523265">will lead to job losses, but it will ultimately create more jobs than it displaces over time.</a></p><p>Before this, EA Sports said <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-says-cfb-25-would-not-have-been-as-good-without-the-developers-using-ai/1100-6525428/" data-ref-id="1100-6525428">CFB 25 might not have turned out as good without the developers using machine-learning and AI.</a> Outside of EA, Sony has been using AI tools for game development for years, crediting machine-learning systems for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstations-plan-to-use-ai-to-speed-up-development-started-with-spider-man-2/1100-6526809/" data-ref-id="1100-6526809">helping speed up development on Marvel's Spider-Man 2.</a></p><p>Meanwhile, Candy Crush developers who got laid off by Activision Blizzard said they are <a href="https://mobilegamer.biz/laid-off-king-staff-set-to-be-replaced-by-the-ai-tools-they-helped-build-say-sources/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">being replaced by AI tools they helped create.</a> A recent report from <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/61cef75e-ceba-43ee-80e3-040756c6154f" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Financial Times</a> said EA might look to further implement AI systems to help ramp up development amid its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/unpacking-eas-55-billion-sale-to-go-private-what-does-it-all-mean/1100-6535168/" data-ref-id="1100-6535168">private sale to an investor consortium.</a></p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-times-seemingly-revealed-and-there-is-no-early-access/1100-6535079/" data-ref-id="1100-6535079">Battlefield 6 launches today, October 10</a>, for PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC. It comes to market with a huge amount of hype behind it, and it's coming out a few weeks before rival <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel/1100-6529073/" data-ref-id="1100-6529073">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 in November.</a> For more, check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/battlefield-6-review-good-company/1900-6418420/" data-ref-id="1900-6418420">Battlefield 6 review</a> and our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-guides-hub/1100-6533950/" data-ref-id="1100-6533950">roundup of tips to help you hit the ground running.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/genai-is-very-seducing-battlefield-6-boss-says/1100-6535356/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>