<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 19:23:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World Of Tanks Studio Seized By Russia, Accused Of Supporting Ukraine]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/world-of-tanks-studio-seized-by-russia-accused-of-supporting-ukraine/1100-6532140/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world-of-tanks-studio-seized-by-russia-accused-of-supporting-ukraine.1208679/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/world-of-tanks-studio-seized-by-russia-accused-of-supporting-ukraine/1100-6532140/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532140">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/world-of-tanks-review/1900-6342098/" data-ref-id="1900-6342098">World of Tanks</a> lets players engage in simulated war battles, but the real war between Russia and Ukraine has led to Lesta Games--the Russian studio behind the game--facing charges that it illegally funneled money from its title to Ukraine.</p><p>The original developer of World of Tanks is WargamingUnited, a company that withdrew from Russia and Belarus directly because of Russia's 2022 invasion of Ukraine. Wargaming <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/world-of-tanks-dev-calls-on-fans-to-help-buy-ambulances-for-ukraine-with-new-charity-bundles/1100-6518517/" data-ref-id="1100-6518517">has also raised money in support of Ukraine</a>, which would be a crime under current Russian law. Lesta Games--which took over the local Russian rights for World of Tanks--has repeatedly stressed that it has no relationship with Wargaming. That wasn't enough to prevent Russia from seizing control of Lesta Games.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/mmo/russia-assures-world-of-tanks-players-they-wont-end-up-in-prison-as-it-takes-full-control-of-the-studio-in-charge-of-it-domestically-accusing-it-of-funnelling-funds-to-ukraine/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PC Gamer</a>, Moscow has frozen all assets that belong to Lesta Games, and accused the company's co-founder, Malik Khatazhaev, of being part of an "extremist group" under the control of Wargaming CEO Viktor Kisly. The evidence cited in court reportedly drew upon footage of Wargaming's support for Ukraine.</p><p>Russian media is reportedly telling World of Tanks players in the country that they won't be arrested for spending money on the game that might have gone to Ukraine. Duma's Information Technology Committee's deputy chairman, Anton Gorelkin, also told players that Lesta Games' assets will likely be handed over to "a specialized Russian company."</p><p>It bears repeating that the World of Tanks game rights in Russia are only limited to that country. Wargaming still has its World of Tanks assets and rights in other countries. Lesta Games isn't the only video game developer to be affected by the ongoing conflict in Ukraine. Developer GSC Game World continued to develop <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl/" data-ref-id="5000-82469">Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl</a> even as some of the devs either fled the country or remained to fight. The story of those developers was told in GameSpot's documentary, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/watch-gamespots-stalker-2-documentary-about-how-russian-war-impacted-the-studio/1100-6529929/" data-ref-id="1100-6529929">How Stalker 2 Survived a War</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch This Guy Smash His Brand-New Switch 2 With A Hammer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/watch-this-guy-smash-his-brand-new-switch-2-with-a-hammer/1100-6532139/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/watch-this-guy-smash-his-brand-new-switch-2-with-a-hammer.1208622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/watch-this-guy-smash-his-brand-new-switch-2-with-a-hammer/1100-6532139/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532139">

            
            
  


    


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container" data-in-content-placements="[{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-incontent-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:1,&quot;minElements&quot;:2},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:4,&quot;minElements&quot;:5}]},{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-banner-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:7,&quot;minElements&quot;:8},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:10,&quot;minElements&quot;:11},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:13,&quot;minElements&quot;:14}]}]">
                <p>The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Switch 2</a> is out today, and immediately someone has smashed it with a hammer. In the video below from YouTube account TechRex, we see the host perform an extreme durability test on the console, culminating in a test that the Switch 2 was never going to survive.</p><p>The test begins with a simple drop test, where the Switch 2 is dropped from a tabletop height. As you can see in the video, the Switch 2 survives multiple five-foot drops with no issues, at least in this specific test environment. The video also has the host slashing the Switch 2's screen with a box cutter trying to snap off the Joy-Cons improperly, and attempting to apply force to break the kickstand.</p><p>Finally, the host drops a hammer on the screen and then smashes it with a lot more force. It's painful to type these words and even more painful to watch the video, but alas, here it is for your own enjoyment or punishment.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p33K1uuOk-A" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/p33K1uuOk-A" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>No mass-market technology product is designed to withstand the kind of abuse that TechRex subjected the Switch 2 in this video. But it's good to know the Switch 2 has a fighting chance to survive a drop from a day-to-day height like a coffee table or dining table. </p><p>For what it's worth, Nintendo <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dont-remove-switch-2s-protective-film-nintendo-says/1100-6531977/" data-ref-id="1100-6531977">officially recommends that you keep the Switch 2's film screen on</a>, but that likely would not protect it from scratches with a box cutter. For that, you might want to invest in a tempered screen protector, or make changes to your personal life.</p><p>If you're unlucky enough to need a repair for your Switch 2 (<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/some-switch-2-owners-have-holes-in-their-screen-thanks-to-gamestop/1100-6532136/" data-ref-id="1100-6532136">or if GameStop stapled your Switch 2 screen</a>), you can <a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68227" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">pay Nintendo for an official repair</a>. Also worth mentioning is how the Switch 2 packaging itself does not contain much in the way of protection for the console.</p><p>The Switch 2 launched today, June 5, with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-9-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6528874/" data-ref-id="1100-6528874">Mario Kart World</a> as its marquee <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-nintendo-switch-2-launch-game/2900-6401/" data-ref-id="2900-6401">launch title</a>. The game is enjoying a positive critical response, though it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-world-is-missing-one-feature-people-really-wanted/1100-6532133/" data-ref-id="1100-6532133">does not include one feature many wanted to see.</a></p>
  
                        
        
    
    
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zelda Upgrade Process Is Mildly Confusing For NSO Members]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/zelda-upgrade-process-is-mildly-confusing-for-nso-members/1100-6532137/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zelda-upgrade-process-is-mildly-confusing-for-nso-members.1208580/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/zelda-upgrade-process-is-mildly-confusing-for-nso-members/1100-6532137/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532137">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>If you're a member of Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack, the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/zelda-breath-of-the-wild-and-tears-of-the-kingdom-every-switch-2-upgrade/2900-6612/" data-ref-id="2900-6612">Switch 2 upgrades for The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom</a> come included with your subscription. But how exactly you access those upgrades can be mildly confusing, so be warned.</p><p>When you transfer your data from a Switch to Switch 2, it will start downloading various software from your old system. Once it's done downloading one of the Zelda games, you might think the rest happens automatically--but no. Instead, starting up Tears of the Kingdom starts the Switch version, with a menu option at the bottom to upgrade to the Switch 2 version. Selecting that menu item forwards you to the Nintendo eShop store page, or you can find the store pages manually.</p><p>But here's where the process may trip up unsuspecting Hyrulians. The store page displays two different buttons. On the left side, next to the "Online + Expansion Pack" label, is "Download." On the right side is "Continue." The Continue button is noticeably much bigger and brighter, and located where you'd usually go to complete a transaction. But the free option for subscribers is the "Download" button.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4507548-switchzeldaupgrade.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4507548" data-ratio="0.55186509964231" data-width="1957" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4507548-switchzeldaupgrade.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4507548"></a><figcaption>Tears of the Kingdom's eShop page</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4507548-switchzeldaupgrade.jpg"></figure><p>You can still hit Continue to buy the content, which means you would continue to have access to it even if you let your Switch Online subscription lapse. But if that won't be a problem for you, there's no reason to pay the $10 premium. Purchasing the upgrade will prompt a second download, after which you'll need to restart the software if you had it running.</p><p>The Nintendo Switch 2 has just launched, which means lots of fans are getting their first hands-on with the games, including the launch lineup like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/love-weird-lil-guys-mario-kart-world-is-the-game-for-you/1100-6532028/" data-ref-id="1100-6532028">Mario Kart World</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour-is-a-surprising-stem-showpiece-but-it-should-still-be-free/1100-6532015/" data-ref-id="1100-6532015">Nintendo Switch 2 Welcome Tour</a>. Be sure to reference our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-restock-launch-week-buying-guide-major-retailers-walmart-target-best-buy/1100-6531967/" data-ref-id="1100-6531967">restock guide</a> if you still need a hand finding the system. If you are an Expansion Pack subscriber, you also now get access to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-gamecube-game-coming-to-switch-2s-switch-online-library/2900-6400/" data-ref-id="2900-6400">GameCube games on Switch 2</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>