<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 07:38:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision Is Pulling Call Of Duty: Warzone Mobile From iOS And Google Play Stores]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/activision-is-pulling-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-from-ios-and-google-play-stores/1100-6531616/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-is-pulling-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-from-ios-and-google-play-stores.1191693/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/activision-is-pulling-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-from-ios-and-google-play-stores/1100-6531616/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531616">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Just a little more than a year after releasing <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone-mobile/" data-ref-id="5000-572199">Call of Duty: Warzone Mobile</a>, Activision is ending its support for the game, which includes removing it from the Apple App Store and Google Play stores.</p><p dir="ltr">Activision made the announcement with a written statement on <a href="https://x.com/WarzoneMobile/status/1923468603959259556" rel="nofollow ">X (formerly Twitter)</a>. "Going forward, we will be streamlining the scope of the game," Activision wrote. May 18 is the last day the game will be available for download from Apple and Google's stores, and Activision has ended the ability of players to purchase Call of Duty points or Black Cell in the game "effective immediately." Social features are also being retired.</p><p dir="ltr">However, Activision said servers will still be available for players who have already downloaded the game--in essence, while you can't download Warzone Mobile after this weekend or buy anything in it, you'll still be able to play. Activision didn't say if or when servers for Warzone Mobile would be shut down.</p><p dir="ltr">"Players who have the game installed before Monday, May 19, 2025 will still have access to the game with continued cross-progression of shared inventories using existing content, and servers with matchmaking for online play," Activision wrote. "Any unspent COD Points can also be redeemed in-game toward available content in the Store."</p><p dir="ltr">However, according to <a href="https://support.activision.com/warzone-mobile/articles/warzone-mobile-service-changes" rel="nofollow ">Activision's support website for Warzone Mobile</a>, future Warzone content will not be available in Warzone Mobile. Activision also won't be offering refunds to players who purchased CoD Points or Black Cell in Warzone Mobile.</p><p dir="ltr">"This decision was made after careful consideration of various factors and while we're proud of the accomplishment in bringing Call of Duty: Warzone to mobile in an authentic way, it unfortunately has not met our expectations with mobile-first players like it has with PC and console audiences," the statement says.</p><p dir="ltr">While that effectively means that support for Warzone Mobile seems to be coming to an end, GameSpot understands that Activision's Warzone Mobile teams are moving forward on other projects.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Will Help You Find Your Joy-Con If It Falls Into The Couch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-will-help-you-find-your-joy-con-if-it-falls-into-the-couch/1100-6531613/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-will-help-you-find-your-joy-con-if-it-falls-into-the-couch.1191561/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-will-help-you-find-your-joy-con-if-it-falls-into-the-couch/1100-6531613/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531613">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">While the launch of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/">Nintendo Switch 2</a> inches closer by the day, the Nintendo Today app has been providing useful updates on a few of the upcoming console's new features. Today, the app revealed that hidden within the options menu is a feature that will help you find a lost Joy-Con should it get separated from the console.</p><p dir="ltr">As spotted by X user Stealth40K, by tapping the Controllers icon on the main menu, you can select "Search For Controllers" from the list. Once there, select which Joy-Con you've misplaced, and the device will vibrate and make a ringing sound until you've retrieved it.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/Stealth40k/status/1923394783642280221" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Switch 2 has a ‘Search for Controllers’ feature to locate Joy-Con 2 controllers.<br>The controller you are looking for will vibrate and make a sound. <a href="https://t.co/FLNF1XoXL6" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/FLNF1XoXL6</a></p>  — Stealth (@Stealth40k) <a href="https://twitter.com/Stealth40k/status/1923394783642280221?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 16, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Nintendo Today has provided numerous updates about the Nintendo Switch 2 since the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/switch-2-nintendo-direct-april-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-6391/">Switch 2 Direct</a> in early April, including more information on the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-controllers-gl-gr-buttons-are-more-customizable-than-we-thought/1100-6531549/">customizable GL and GR buttons</a> for the Switch 2's Pro Controller, as well as the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-worlds-new-unexpected-feature-binoculars/1100-6531580/">binoculars found around the map</a> in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-9-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6528874/">Mario Kart World</a>. The app's first-ever announcement was the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-live-action-movie-lands-a-release-date-but-still-no-word-on-the-cast/1100-6530461/">March 2027 release date for the upcoming live-action The Legend of Zelda movie</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Nintendo's next console will feature a<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-nintendo-switch-2-launch-game/2900-6401/"> robust launch lineup</a> of games, including Mario Kart World, Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition, and updated Nintendo Switch 2 editions of both The Legend Of Zelda: Breath Of The Wild and Tears Of The Kingdom. The console will also see <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-gamecube-game-coming-to-switch-2s-switch-online-library/2900-6400/">Nintendo GameCube games</a> come to the Nintendo Switch Online service exclusively on Switch 2, with The Legend of Zelda: Wind Waker and Soul Calibur 2 among the first games to be playable.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/">Nintendo Switch 2</a> is set to launch in North America on June 5.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2's Bravely Default Remaster Rings In The 3DS Nostalgia Era With A Great Version Of A Great RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2s-bravely-default-remaster-rings-in-the-3ds-nostalgia-era-with-a-great-version-of-a-great-rpg/1100-6531611/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2s-bravely-default-remaster-rings-in-the-3ds-nostalgia-era-with-a-great-version-of-a-great-rpg.1191528/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2s-bravely-default-remaster-rings-in-the-3ds-nostalgia-era-with-a-great-version-of-a-great-rpg/1100-6531611/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531611">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-nintendo-switch-2-launch-game/2900-6401/">Switch 2 launch lineup</a> is not exactly bursting at the seams. While <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-9-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6528874/">Mario Kart World</a> is the banner game, the handful of others coming on June 5 are mostly ports of existing games. Among those, Bravely Default is an oddball, as it's an HD remaster of a game that's more than a decade old rather than a modern game like Street Fighter 6 or Cyberpunk 2077 that can finally run on Nintendo hardware. But for my money, Bravely Default is also an all-time RPG classic, and as strange as it feels to be nostalgic for the 3DS era of games, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/">Switch 2</a>'s Bravely Default: Flying Fairy HD Remaster looks to be a great way to play it.</p><p dir="ltr">For those unfamiliar, Bravely Default was a riff on the classic Final Fantasy formula, making it FF in all but name. Four warriors of light, holy crystals, the whole enchilada. It sported a robust class system that encouraged players to find game-breaking combinations, and it was one of the first to sport the ability to speed up encounters and auto-battle--both now mainstays in classic RPG remakes--or even turn them off entirely. The title referred to one of its battle mechanics, the ability to "Default" (defend and store an extra Brave Point aka BP) or "Brave" (spend extra BP, or even go into BP debt, to take extra actions). So for level-grinding, you could Brave every time to burn through low-level enemies, and against tougher enemies and bosses you would need to take a more considered approach.</p><p dir="ltr">It was followed by the semi-sequel, Bravely Second: End Layer, and a full sequel, Bravely Second. Notably unlike the Final Fantasy series, the Bravely games take place in one consistent canonical world, so the sequels build on the stories and continuity that came before them.</p><p dir="ltr">But like much of the 3DS library, Bravely Default is not exactly easy to play anymore. You need working 3DS hardware and a game cartridge, and unlike Bravely Default 2, it was never released on another platform like Steam. That makes it a prime candidate for the HD remaster treatment, allowing fans to own it in a format that continues well into the future. After a brief hands-on, I'm convinced that Bravely Default will be my most-played Switch 2 game outside of Mario Kart at launch.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496384-01_battle_brave_en.png" data-ref-id="1300-4496384" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496384-01_battle_brave_en.png" data-ref-id="1300-4496384"></a><figcaption>The Battle menu in Bravely Default: Flying Fairy HD</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496384-01_battle_brave_en.png"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496385-01_battle_brave_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496386-01_character_tiz01.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496387-01_character_tiz02_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496389-01_concept02_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496390-01_concept03_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496392-01_concept04_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496393-01_job_freelancer_abi01_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496395-01_job_freelancer_abi02_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496396-01_system_graphic_new_en.png" data-ref-id="1300-4496385,1300-4496386,1300-4496387,1300-4496389,1300-4496390,1300-4496392,1300-4496393,1300-4496395,1300-4496396" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1585/15855271/4496385-01_battle_brave_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1585/15855271/4496386-01_character_tiz01.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1585/15855271/4496387-01_character_tiz02_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1585/15855271/4496389-01_concept02_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1585/15855271/4496390-01_concept03_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1585/15855271/4496392-01_concept04_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1585/15855271/4496393-01_job_freelancer_abi01_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1585/15855271/4496395-01_job_freelancer_abi02_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1585/15855271/4496396-01_system_graphic_new_en.png"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496385-01_battle_brave_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496386-01_character_tiz01.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496387-01_character_tiz02_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496389-01_concept02_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496390-01_concept03_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496392-01_concept04_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496393-01_job_freelancer_abi01_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496395-01_job_freelancer_abi02_en.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4496396-01_system_graphic_new_en.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">To start, the game looks fantastic. The prerendered painterly backgrounds look incredible and vibrant on the big screen, which is all the more impressive when you consider they were originally made to appear on a 3DS. This visual style--your polygonal characters running against a painted backdrop--was itself a throwback to early 3D RPGs like Final Fantasy 7, but it looks especially wonderful here. Meanwhile, the style of the character models themselves largely holds up. It's a testament to the strength of the art style that these characters--squat chibi characters rendered in the unmistakable style of Akihiko Yoshida--still look so elegant in their simplicity. I wasn't able to tinker with the job classes to see the lovely way these models look when donning their various outfits, but I'm looking forward to it.</p><p dir="ltr">The battle system remains untouched as far as I can tell, which is fine by me because it's already perfectly balanced. I only played a little bit of an early area but I know from experience that the combination of the Brave/Default and job-class systems creates some engaging combat puzzles, especially once the game starts challenging you to split its systems wide open. This is a game that absolutely wants to make you feel like you've outsmarted it.</p><p dir="ltr">The newest element is a pair of minigames, which seem well designed even if they're temporary diversions at best. Both use the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-nintendo-switch-2-game-that-supports-joy-con-mouse-controls/2900-6517/">Switch 2 mouse functionality</a>, challenging you to use both at once in different ways. The first is a rhythm game that has a glowing tether between your two cursors, and so matching the rhythm means lining up the tether to intersect with the music prompts, or hitting exact notes with the cursors themselves. The second is an airship-piloting game set in the first-person perspective of a pilot, so you have to manage steering the ship's wheel while also tending to other tasks. Imagine Steel Battalion but cute, with its massive controller being virtualized on screen. Neither game feeds back into the main game, but you can use the job-class costumes in the minigames as you unlock them for a bit of personalization.</p><p dir="ltr">I doubt I'll play much of the minigames. They're neat little showpieces for the Switch 2 mouse functionality, but they aren't the draw. The real prize is Bravely Default, one of my favorite modern(ish) RPGs, getting a beautiful restoration and being released from 3DS jail. If you haven't played it before, or even if you have, this looks to be the way to experience it.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>