<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 04:45:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SAG-AFTRA members ratify new interactive media contract]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/sag-aftra-members-ratify-new-interactive-media-contract-conclude-year-long-strike</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sag-aftra-members-ratify-new-interactive-media-contract.1240011/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Actor's union SAG-AFTRA is celebrating the end of a three-year negotiating process over the terms of the Interactive Media Agreement (IMA), its wide-ranging contract with major video game development studios like Warner Bros. Interactive, Take-Two, and Electronic Arts. Union members officially </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.sagaftra.org/member-message-sag-aftra-members-approve-2025-interactive-media-agreement">ratified the contract's terms</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> after a month-long voting process, cementing protections for voice actors and performance capture artists around the use of generative AI, pay raises, and new safety standards for on-set stunts and auditions.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This deal achieves important progress around A.I. protections, and progress is the name of the game," said SAG-AFTRA president Fran Drescher in a statement accompany the announcement the results of the vote. "My sincere respect goes out to the entire video game performer community and their allies for their solidarity during the strike which provided the necessary leverage to secure this deal’s many essential gains."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">95 percent of participating union members voted in favor of the contract, with 5 percent opposed.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Members of the game development production bargaining group praised the conclusion of negotiations, with spokesperson Audrey Cooling saying the producers are "pleased" that the deal was ratified. "We look forward to building on our industry's decades-long partnership with the union and continuing to create groundbreaking entertainment experiences for billions of players worldwide."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/sag-aftra-urges-more-non-struck-game-studios-to-sign-interim-agreement" target="_self" data-discover="true">SAG-AFTRA urges more non-struck game studios to sign interim agreement</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Going forward, union members will benefit from minimum payments for the use of "Digital Replicas" created with their performances, as well as higher payments for the creation of chatbots based on their work. They'll also receive payments when performances are reused in future projects.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Actors will also receive a modest pay raise for future gigs, starting with a 15 percent increase in new projects signed under the new IMA, with compounded 3 percent increases starting in November 2025. Overtime pay will also increase for "overscale" performers based on "double scale."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A lesser-discussed portion of the contract also mandates the presence of qualified medical professionals at rehearsals and performances during which "hazardous actions or working conditions" are planned. On-camera "principal performers" will also now have mandated rest periods, and employers will not be able to request performers execute stunts or "other dangerous activity" in virtual or self-taped auditions.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A SAG-AFTRA spokesperson confirmed that these terms will apply to developers who signed on to the interim </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/sag-aftra-calls-huge-win-as-80-games-agree-to-the-union-s-ai-terms">IMA over the last year</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (which allowed them to hire SAG-AFTRA members on new projects), but not those operating under the tiered budget independent agreements.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/how-ninja-theory-created-hellblade-ii-s-unsettling-soundscape" target="_self" data-discover="true">How Ninja Theory created Hellblade II's unsettling soundscape</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Negotiations over the Interactive Media agreement lasted over two years">Negotiations over the Interactive Media agreement lasted over two years</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Though the SAG-AFTRA strike against companies in the collective bargaining group lasted for just under a year, SAG-AFTRA negotiators have been battling for today's contract for three years. The union first called for actors to vote on strike authorization in September 2023 after months of negotiation between the two parties. Members overwhelmingly agreed to authorize the bargaining committee to call for a strike, which it only did after holding its powder for another 10 months.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In that time, the union made aggressive plays to show it was compromising with the wants and needs of game developers in regards to pay and generative AI. It signed an agreement with AI audio company </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/sag-aftra-signs-agreement-with-ai-powered-voice-company-ethovox">Ethovox</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/sag-aftra-calls-huge-win-as-80-games-agree-to-the-union-s-ai-terms">struck deals with game studios</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> not part of the core bargaining group, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sag-aftra-ups-indie-dev-contract-tiers-to-include-30m-game-projects">created new contracts</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for independent devs and developers making games at game jams or as students.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Video game voice actors accomplished these wins without the same work stoppage pressure of their peers in TV, film, and streaming who went on a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.sagaftrastrike.org/home">3-month strike</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in 2023 for better pay and protections against exploiting their image with generative AI. Interactive Media union members had to wrangle with the terms of "side letter six," a section of the Interactive Media Agreement that allows work to continue on games already in production like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Grand Theft Auto VI</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Some bargaining developers like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/black-ops-6-zombies-characters-recast-after-original-actors-withdrew-during-strike">Activision</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/riot-games-league-of-legends-vo-formosa-interactive">Riot Games</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/destiny-2-is-the-latest-game-impacted-by-sag-aftra-strike">Bungie</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> found themselves impacted by the strike, as actors were allowed to turn down offers to "re-up" short-term contracts on exempt production to show solidarity with their striking peers.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/supergiant-denies-recasting-hades-ii-actor-over-interim-sag-aftra-contract-request" target="_self" data-discover="true">Supergiant denies recasting Hades II actor over interim SAG-AFTRA contract request</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Drescher and National Executive Director &amp; Chief Negotiator Duncan Crabtree-Ireland lauded the work of Interactive Media Agreement Negotiating Chair Sarah Elmaleh for enduring the three-year ordeal, along with the negotiating staff and lead negotiator Ray Rodriguez. . "Now that the agreement is ratified, video game performers will be able to enjoy meaningful gains and important A.I. protections, which we will continue to build on as uses of this technology settle and evolve," Crabtree-Ireland said.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The fight for voice actors' working rights may now head overseas. In France, the French dubbing cast of Respawn Entertainment's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Apex Legends</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> quit after being </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://gamerant.com/apex-legends-french-voice-actors-quit/">asked to sign away their voices</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> by an unnamed publisher, and actor's guild Equity </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/actors-union-protests-outside-baftas-for-better-working-conditions-in-the-uk">protested the BAFTA awards</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> earlier this year to advocate for video game union contracts in the UK.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div data-testid="contributor-summary-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Follow Bryant Francis, Senior Editor, on </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/bryantfrancis.me">Bluesky</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> or </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bryant-francis-99898b29">LinkedIn</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>.</span></span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/sag-aftra-members-ratify-new-interactive-media-contract-conclude-year-long-strike]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>