<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:06:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls Online Developers Have Unionized]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-online-developers-have-unionized/1100-6528457/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-elder-scrolls-online-developers-have-unionized.1060716/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-elder-scrolls-online-developers-have-unionized/1100-6528457/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528457">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Following in the footsteps of earlier union action by <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bethesda-game-studios-is-now-unionized-across-the-board-recognized-by-microsoft/1100-6525206/" data-ref-id="1100-6525206">Bethesda workers</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/qa-workers-at-zenimax-studios-have-become-the-gaming-industrys-largest-union/1100-6510268/" data-ref-id="1100-6510268">ZeniMax QA</a> workers, 461 developers at ZeniMax Online Studios have launched their union. The union has been recognized by parent company Microsoft, which acquired ZeniMax and it subsidiaries in 2021.</p><p>The union is called ZOS United-CWA, and like the previous unionization efforts within ZeniMax Media, has been formed with the Communications Workers of America (CWA). The new union consists of web developers, designers, engineers, and graphic artists, with an announcement on Bluesky identifying union members as "a majority of video game workers at ZeniMax Online Studios and the workers behind ESO."</p><p>"We are thrilled to be joining thousands of other tech and video game workers in building solidarity across the industry with CODE-CWA," the new union said in an announcement on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/zosunited.bsky.social/post/3ld5jhqijg226" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bluesky</a>, tagging the CWA's campaign for unionization within the tech, gaming, and digital industries. "With a union, we are looking forward to collectively pushing for improvements to the workplace, including job security, protections against AI, better pay and benefits--in an industry that we’re so deeply passionate about."</p><p>In June this year, Microsoft signed a labor-neutrality agreement with the CWA, agreeing not to interfere with any unionization efforts within ZeniMax Media, and making it easier for workers within ZeniMax to unionize. Shortly after, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bethesda-game-studios-is-now-unionized-across-the-board-recognized-by-microsoft/1100-6525206/" data-ref-id="1100-6525206">Bethesda workers</a> announced the formation of their own union, making it the first Microsoft game studio to be unionized across the board. Prior to that, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/qa-workers-at-zenimax-studios-have-become-the-gaming-industrys-largest-union/1100-6510268/" data-ref-id="1100-6510268">QA workers across ZeniMax studios and Bethesda</a> formed the largest certified video game union in the US in January 2023.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Major Palworld Update Feybreak Is Arriving On December 23]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/major-palworld-update-feybreak-is-arriving-on-december-23/1100-6528456/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/major-palworld-update-feybreak-is-arriving-on-december-23.1060713/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/major-palworld-update-feybreak-is-arriving-on-december-23/1100-6528456/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528456">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/palworld/" data-ref-id="5000-532768">Palworld</a>'s next major update is arriving on December 23, bringing with it a brand-new island to explore. The update will also add new Pals, a new faction leader, weapons, buildings, new mechanics, and more.</p><p>Pocketpair has said that the new island explorable in Feybreak is "the largest and harshest" yet, at six times the size of Sakurajima, which was added in June. In a trailer that debuted at The Game Awards, the developer gave a look at the upcoming Palworld update, featuring a character who may be the new faction leader, as well as some of the new Pals and other new content coming to the game.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mI_0U7-7hRA" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mI_0U7-7hRA" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Despite teasing a bunch of new content in the update, Pocketpair hasn't been forthcoming about what that new content is, leaving it to fans to analyze what's been shown in the trailer. As well as some unfamiliar Pals, the trailer appears to showcase a new base in a traditional Japanese building style, and it hints at some new mechanics that may include Pal-cloning vats.</p><p>Palworld has found itself in legal trouble over its similarity to Nintendo's long-running Pokemon franchise, with the two companies currently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/palworld-developer-shares-more-details-about-nintendos-lawsuit-against-the-game/1100-6527664/" data-ref-id="1100-6527664">embroiled in a lawsuit</a> over Pocketpair's alleged infringement of some of Nintendo's patents. Despite the legal challenge, the studio is continuing to release new content for the game, and has also teased a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/palworld-x-terraria-collaboration-is-coming-in-2025/1100-6528087/" data-ref-id="1100-6528087">Terraria collab</a> due out sometime next year</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>