<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 19:31:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact Is Being Delisted On PS4 As Hoyoverse Plans To Cease Support]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/08/06/genshin-impact-is-being-delisted-on-ps4-as-hoyoverse-plans-to-cease-support</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-is-being-delisted-on-ps4-as-hoyoverse-plans-to-cease-support.1263723/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>MiHoYo has announced plans to cease support for <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/genshin-impact/genshin-impact-review-into-the-great-wide-open">Genshin Impact</a> on PlayStation 4. Furthermore, the game is being delisted from the platform.</p><p>In a <a href="https://www.hoyolab.com/article/40408849">blog post</a>, the developer states it is ending support for the popular free-to-play action RPG on PS4 due to “limitations related to hardware performance and platform application size." In layman's terms, it sounds like the game has simply become too big and demanding for Sony's last-generation console to handle anymore. This means that in the near future, Genshin Impact on PS4 will no longer receive any updates, and MiHoYo is beginning the process of sunsetting that version of the game.</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="da55e62c-c578-4b78-b510-1a5286e2aabd" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	






</article>
<p>MiHoYo details a three-step plan that begins with the game’s removal on PS4, which takes place on September 10. The game will be unavailable to download after this date, but those who have previously downloaded the game will still be able to reinstall it, as it will not disappear from their library. You’ll also still be able to log in and receive update patches until the game is taken completely offline.</p><p>Next, in-game PS4 purchases on the PlayStation Store and the in-game shop will be disabled on February 25, 2026. Items purchased on PSN before this date but not yet claimed in-game can still be obtained, however.&nbsp;</p><p>Lastly, on April 8, 2026, MiHoYo will cease all support for Genshin Impact on PS4. Players will be unable to log into the game, it won’t receive any more updates, and unclaimed items purchased on the PlayStation Store will only be obtainable by logging into the PS5 version.&nbsp;</p><p>The PS5 version of Genshin Impact will be unaffected by this development, and the game supports cross-progression, making it easy to transition to the other platforms the game remains playable on. &nbsp;In addition to PS5, Genshin Impact is available on Xbox Series X/S, PC, iOS, and Android.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/08/06/genshin-impact-is-being-delisted-on-ps4-as-hoyoverse-plans-to-cease-support]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>