<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:29:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mass Effect Boss Understands You Are "Thirsty For News" About Next Game, But You Can't Have It Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mass-effect-boss-understands-you-are-thirsty-for-news-about-next-game-but-you-cant-have-it-yet/1100-6536043/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mass-effect-boss-understands-you-are-thirsty-for-news-about-next-game-but-you-cant-have-it-yet.1347133/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536043">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Today is N7 Day, which is BioWare's annual celebration of the Mass Effect series, and to mark the occasion, the developer gave an update on the next game and the TV show. Do not get too excited, though, as BioWare wants people to know it can't reveal very much.</p><p>Executive producer Michael Gamble <a href="https://blog.bioware.com/2025/11/07/n7-day-2025/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">said</a> the next entry in the Mass Effect series remains in development and that "EA and BioWare remain committed to telling more stories in this universe." Gamble also addressed the rumors of BioWare getting shut down or sold off as part of EA's $55 billion sale to an investor consortium led by Saudi Arabi.</p><p>"Like you, we've heard the rumors lately. You've made it clear you care deeply about what's next," he said.</p><p>There has been speculation that if EA's $55 billion sale goes through, the new owners <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-may-sell-bioware-and-dice-or-close-other-studios-says-analyst/1100-6535312/" data-ref-id="1100-6535312">might close or sell BioWare</a>. The studio's latest game, Dragon Age: The Veilguard, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-had-far-fewer-players-than-ea-expected/1100-6528964/" data-ref-id="1100-6528964">failed to meet EA's sales expectations</a>. It remains to be seen what the new owners might do, or how EA might look to come up with the money to pay off its $20 billion in debt for the deal, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-acknowledges-risk-of-selling-to-saudi-arabia-claims-it-will-retain-creative-control/1100-6535894/" data-ref-id="1100-6535894">this uncertainty is a business risk for EA.</a></p><p>Gamble did not address these rumors specifically but said the team at BioWare is "heads-down and focused exclusively on Mass Effect."</p><p>He added: "We have a lot of universe to cover, lots of features to build, and lots of romances to figure out. We're excited by what we're building, and we promise you: when we're ready, it'll be a lot of fun to show."</p><p>Gamble said he knows people are "thirsty for news" and thanked them for being patient until the studio can share more.</p><h2><strong>Update on Mass Effect TV show</strong></h2><p>Outside of the Mass Effect game series, Gamble gave an update on the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mass-effect-tv-shows-latest-update-reveals-a-key-detail/1100-6534272/" data-ref-id="1100-6534272">Mass Effect TV series at Amazon</a>. He said the writers room is "going strong," and the writers have already come up with "a lot" about how the show will connect to the wider Mass Effect canon and "where it sits in respect to the new game."</p><p>"The show will explore a brand-new story within the universe's timeline, and will be set after the original trilogy. It won't be a retread of Commander Shepard's story--because after all--that's YOUR story, isn’t it?" he said.</p><p>The Mass Effect show was <a href="https://deadline.com/2021/11/the-wheel-of-time-premiere-ratings-amazon-prime-video-mass-effect-lort-of-the-rings-jennifer-salke-qa-1234879517/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">first revealed back in 2021</a>, so it's been in the works for a long time already. In November 2024, the TV series <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mass-effect-tv-series-first-revealed-in-2021-is-apparently-back-on-with-a-key-update/1100-6527637/" data-ref-id="1100-6527637">got a key update</a>, when a report said the show was actually in development. The report said Daniel Casey (Fast &amp; Furious 9) is writing and executive producing the show, while Gamble is an executive producer as well.</p><p>Ari Arad (Iron Man, Uncharted, upcoming Zelda movie) is an executive producer, too. There are no plot details available as of yet for the Mass Effect show, but the main series follows the spacefaring events of Commander Shepard. A movie version of Mass Effect was planned at one point, but it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bioware-on-why-the-mass-effect-movie-stalled-and-how-a-tv-show-might-be-better/1100-6493310/" data-ref-id="1100-6493310">never got off the ground.</a></p><p>Filming for the Mass Effect TV show <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mass-effect-tv-shows-latest-update-reveals-a-key-detail/1100-6534272/" data-ref-id="1100-6534272">could begin in 2026.</a></p><h2>"I want you to see stuff"</h2><p>In a <a href="https://x.com/GambleMike/status/1986833146873024598" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">social media post</a>, Gamble said he's aware that BioWare's N7 Day post for this year didn't actually include much meat. However, the time is not right for more disclosure about the next Mass Effect game.</p><p>"For everyone yelling at me because we didn't use N7 Day to provide a whole bunch of info… I mean, I get it. I'm a fan too. I want you to see stuff. But it's not the time…yet. Has it been years since announce? Yes. Have we been busy? Yes. Are we NOW 100% on mass effect? Also yes," he said.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mass-effect-boss-understands-you-are-thirsty-for-news-about-next-game-but-you-cant-have-it-yet/1100-6536043/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WoW's New Premium Currency Is "Player Friendly" And More "Efficient," Blizzard Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-new-premium-currency-is-player-friendly-and-more-efficient-blizzard-says/1100-6536042/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wows-new-premium-currency-is-player-friendly-and-more-efficient-blizzard-says.1347076/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536042">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a> is officially getting a premium currency just for player-housing items, and Blizzard is now looking to explain its reasoning to a concerned and upset playerbase.</p><p dir="ltr">Following a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-looks-to-be-getting-a-new-premium-currency-for-housing/1100-6535888/" data-ref-id="1100-6535888">datamine earlier this week</a> that hinted at a new premium currency called Hearthsteel, Blizzard has confirmed the currency is real and how it plans to implement it in a <a href="https://worldofwarcraft.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24242736" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">blog post</a>. Once WoW's Midnight expansion releases, Hearthsteel will be available for purchase with real money and will only be used for housing items in the in-game shop. Items and Hearthsteel amounts available for purchase should align in a "player-friendly way," Blizzard states.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WmG98apVwKw" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="2">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WmG98apVwKw?start=2" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">The big question many players have is why introduce a virtual currency at all? Microtransactions have existed in WoW for a long time now. Blizzard confirmed earlier this year it would sell premium housing items, something that was expected. But buying a fancy store mount or transmog set has always been done with real money as opposed to having to first buy a currency. According to Blizzard, using real money when purchasing multiple items can be "inefficient, inconvenient, and often tedious."</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard then seems to confirm that players who buy housing items on the shop will need to buy multiples of the same item if they want, for example, a full set of chairs, as opposed to making a single purchase and then being able to put down as many chairs as one wants.</p><p dir="ltr">"Using an in-game currency can help make the process of obtaining many of these types of inexpensive items more efficient," Blizzard states.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard notes that as is the case with store mounts, the vast majority of housing items will be earnable in-game by playing, with only a small selection of housing items available on the shop. Housing items tied to a core class or race fantasy, or "thematically important decor," won't be sold in the shop either. A housing catalog will be visible in the house-decorating UI that will let players preview decor items (including ones from the shop), so players can decide if they wish to purchase or work towards earning a specific piece of decor.</p><p dir="ltr">The end of Blizzard's Hearthsteel blog post tells players to keep the feedback coming, and judging from places like the WoW subreddit, there is plenty of (negative) feedback to go around. Some players aren't finding Blizzard's justification for the virtual currency convincing.</p><p dir="ltr">"The only reason for a virtual currency is to do the exact opposite and nudge people into buying more shit because they have leftover balance," user <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/1oq65xb/comment/nnh43m0/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Pariah</a> writes. "As if that's a secret to anyone these days."</p><p dir="ltr">As another user, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/wow/comments/1oq65xb/comment/nnghh4b/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lord0fHats</a>, puts it: "Selling housing decor and such was a no brainer, but they had to adopt a particularly toxic method of doing it. Very disappointing."</p><p dir="ltr">Whether or not player concerns and feedback will cause Blizzard to reconsider its approach remains to be seen, but for many players who have been waiting for player housing for decades, the pivot into a virtual currency looks like nothing more than a cash grab.</p><p dir="ltr">In other WoW microtransaction news, the game's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-infamous-90-dinosaur-mount-may-be-coming-back/1100-6535911/" data-ref-id="1100-6535911">infamous $90 dinosaur mount</a> may be returning to the shop. Housing early access, meanwhile, is set to arrive with the game's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-player-housing-will-launch-with-patch-11-2-7-but-not-in-full/1100-6534018/" data-ref-id="1100-6534018">11.2.7 patch</a> before the end of the year, with Midnight proper set to release early in 2026. Those waiting for WoW to arrive on console will keep waiting, as the game's director said a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-isnt-coming-to-consoles-game-director-says-no-reason-for-us-to-hide-anything-about-this/1100-6535952/" data-ref-id="1100-6535952">console version of WoW isn't in the works</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-new-premium-currency-is-player-friendly-and-more-efficient-blizzard-says/1100-6536042/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockstar Delays GTA 6 And The Internet Responds Exactly As You'd Expect]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rockstar-delays-gta-6-and-the-internet-responds-exactly-as-youd-expect/1100-6536039/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rockstar-delays-gta-6-and-the-internet-responds-exactly-as-youd-expect.1347022/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536039">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It's official: <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-delayed-to-november-2026/1100-6536012/" data-mce-href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-delayed-to-november-2026/1100-6536012/">Grand Theft Auto 6 has been delayed</a>. The highly anticipated <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-open-world-games/2900-6388/" data-ref-id="2900-6388" data-mce-href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-open-world-games/2900-6388/">open-world game</a> from Rockstar was originally scheduled for a May 2026 release, but it will now be out on November 19 instead. A game delay is never good news, but for Take-Two Interactive, the news saw its stock price temporarily drop while the industry calibrated itself for the later launch.</p><p>GTA 6 is regarded as something truly special, a once-in-a-generation release that is being fueled by an absurd amount of hype. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-gets-a-new-trailer/1100-6531329/" data-mce-href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-gets-a-new-trailer/1100-6531329/">Even a simple YouTube trailer dominates discussions for days</a> after it's released--and reignites interest in Tom Petty and the Heartbreakers--and the delay has gotten a lot of responses from just about everyone with their finger on the pulse of the gaming community.</p><p>Big brands like Dominos Pizza and KFC haven't missed with their responses, and someone at Red Bull Gaming needs to stop drinking a dangerous amount of overly caffeinated energy drinks. Some of the responses have been brutally honest, others have taken the news in their stride with cheeky responses, and some people have overreacted really badly to the delay.</p><p>Fortunately, there are a lot of games scheduled to launch next year, and if you want to plan around GTA 6, you can check out our list of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2026-upcoming-games-release-schedule/1100-6534941/" data-ref-id="1100-6534941" data-mce-href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2026-upcoming-games-release-schedule/1100-6534941/">2026 game releases</a>.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/redbullgaming/status/1986546697355600227" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">IT WILL BE WORTH THE WAIT<br>IT WILL BE WORTH THE WAIT<br>IT WILL BE WORTH THE WAIT<br>IT WILL BE WORTH THE WAIT<br>IT WILL BE WORTH THE WAIT <a href="https://t.co/fsrDbPtHv1" rel="nofollow " data-mce-href="https://t.co/fsrDbPtHv1">https://t.co/fsrDbPtHv1</a></p>— Red Bull Gaming (@redbullgaming) <a href="https://twitter.com/redbullgaming/status/1986546697355600227?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-mce-href="https://twitter.com/redbullgaming/status/1986546697355600227?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 6, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Several analysts believe <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-is-most-important-game-release-in-industrys-history-analyst-says/1100-6521839/" data-mce-href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-is-most-important-game-release-in-industrys-history-analyst-says/1100-6521839/">GTA 6 is the single most important game release of all time</a>, and its predicted to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-5-could-make-3-billion-in-first-year-alone/1100-6528605/" data-mce-href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-5-could-make-3-billion-in-first-year-alone/1100-6528605/">sell 40 million units within its first year of release</a>. At the same time, Rockstar has been criticized for firing dozens of employees <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-dev-says-it-fired-workers-for-leaking-secrets-not-for-trying-to-unionize/1100-6535987/" data-mce-href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-dev-says-it-fired-workers-for-leaking-secrets-not-for-trying-to-unionize/1100-6535987/">allegedly leaking company secrets</a>, but a labor union claims that the layoffs were part of a union-busting effort.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        <div>
	<p>
		Latest in
		Grand Theft Auto VI
	</p>

	
</div>
  
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535976&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-plus-collector-edition-4k-blu-ray-star-wars-and-marvel-original-series\/1100-6535976\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536012&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gta-6-delayed-to-november-2026\/1100-6536012\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535928&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-straight-record-quest-guide\/1100-6535928\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535971&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-echoes-of-victory-ridge-quest-guide\/1100-6535971\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535925&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-market-correction-quest-guide\/1100-6535925\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536003&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-4-has-a-legendary-bee-shooting-gun-you-can-farm-for-this-week\/1100-6536003\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535965&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-keeping-the-memory-quest-guide\/1100-6535965\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535872&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-prime-members-get-these-13-free-games-in-november\/1100-6535872\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534941&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2026-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6534941\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/all-arc-raiders-quests-full-mission-list\/1100-6535922\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535932&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-industrial-espionage-quest-guide\/1100-6535932\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535867&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/all-fortnite-simpsons-season-quests-and-how-to-complete-them\/1100-6535867\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535961&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-broken-monument-quest-guide\/1100-6535961\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536006&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fortnite-screwed-up-apus-look-in-the-new-simpsons-season-and-epic-is-fixing-it\/1100-6536006\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535944&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ps-portal-update-adds-full-cloud-streaming-two-years-after-launch\/1100-6535944\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6524536&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/audible-premium-plus-sign-up-deal-harry-potter-full-cast-audio-editions\/1100-6524536\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535962&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-the-majors-footlocker-quest-guide\/1100-6535962\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rockstar-delays-gta-6-and-the-internet-responds-exactly-as-youd-expect/1100-6536039/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RDR2 For Switch 2, PS5, And Xbox Series X|S - Everything We Know About Rumored Ports]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/red-dead-redemption-2-ps5-xbox-switch-2-port-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6536035/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rdr2-for-switch-2-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s-everything-we-know-about-rumored-ports.1347019/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536035">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Rockstar's 2018 open-world Western Red Dead Redemption 2 is a huge success with more than 79 million copies sold, making it one of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/top-10-best-selling-video-games-of-all-time/2900-4814/" data-ref-id="2900-4814">top five best-selling games in history</a>. The game is expected to continue to make a mark on the gaming industry with rumored ports for PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and Switch 2. The ports have not been officially announced, but there have been some developments, and in this post, we're rounding up everything we've heard about the rumored ports.</p><h2 id="What_do_we_know_"><strong>What do we know?</strong></h2><p>Earlier this year, reliable leaker <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/red-dead-redemption-2-may-be-heading-to-switch-2-report/1100-6532372/" data-ref-id="1100-6532372">Nate the Hate said</a> a port of Red Dead Redemption 2 was headed to Nintendo Switch 2 in 2025, alongside an update that improves the game on Xbox Series X|S and PlayStation 5.</p><p>Red Dead Redemption 2 has been playable on PS5 and Xbox Series X|S already through backwards compatibility. That was also true for GTA 5, which was playable on the latest consoles prior to Rockstar releasing new versions of GTA 5 for PS5 and Xbox Series X|S in March 2022 with significant upgrades.</p><p>Then in October 2025, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/red-dead-redemption-2-still-planned-for-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-and-switch-2-report/1100-6535240/" data-ref-id="1100-6535240">Nate the Hate said the ports are still in the works</a>, but had no information to share regarding when they could be released.</p><p>There is no word on what the rumored PS5 and Xbox Series X|S upgrades could be, but improved graphics and performance are two possibilities.</p><p>The original Red Dead Redemption, meanwhile, came to Switch in 2023 after it originally launched in 2010.</p><h2 id="What_has_Rockstar_Take_Two_said_"><strong>What has Rockstar/Take-Two said?</strong></h2><p>Officially, Rockstar and Take-Two have not said a peep about new ports of Red Dead Redemption 2. However, the <a href="https://ir.take2games.com/static-files/a8a1ef24-f159-4c6e-98df-f33c34a1dd3e" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">company's latest earnings briefing</a> included a slide that said Take-Two has eight new iterations of previously released titles in the works that will be released by the end of its 2028 fiscal year, meaning by March 31, 2028.</p><p>This includes remasters and ports, and only four have been confirmed as of yet: these are Civilization 7 for Meta Quest VR (released April 10, 2025), Civilization 7 for Switch 2 (released June 5, 2025), WWE 2K25 for Switch 2 (released July 22, 2025), and Borderlands 4 for Switch 2 (TBA).</p><p>It's possible ports of Red Dead Redemption 2 could be among those ports/remasters that have yet to be announced. The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-4-remaster-may-be-in-the-works/1100-6531466/" data-ref-id="1100-6531466">rumored GTA 4 remaster</a> could be another. The previously announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/max-payne-1-and-2-remakes/">Max Payne remakes</a> could be counted here as well.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4598588-screenshot2025-11-07at10.39.53%E2%80%AFam.png" data-ref-id="1300-4598588" data-ratio="0.55621805792164" data-width="1174" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4598588-screenshot2025-11-07at10.39.53%E2%80%AFam.png" data-ref-id="1300-4598588"></a><figcaption>Red Dead Redemption 2 may be headed to more platforms.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4598588-screenshot2025-11-07at10.39.53%E2%80%AFam.png"></figure><h2 id="When_will_the_RDR_2_ports_be_released_">When will the RDR 2 ports be released?</h2><p>If the rumors are true, Red Dead Redemption 2 for PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and Switch 2 could launch before the end of 2025.</p><h2 id="Preorder_the_RDR_2_ports">Preorder the RDR 2 ports</h2><p>Given that Red Dead Redemption 2 ports for PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and Switch 2 have not been announced, there is no word on preorder availability.</p><h2 id="RDR_2_ports_trailer">RDR 2 ports trailer</h2><p>There are no trailers yet for the possible Red Dead Redemption 2 ports, nor have there been any trailer leaks that have been posted publicly online.</p><h2 id="Rockstar_s_next_release">Rockstar's next release</h2><p>Rockstar's next big release is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">GTA 6</a>, which was recently delayed from May 2026 to November 2026. It remains to be seen if Rockstar itself would develop the possible new versions of RDR 2 or if the company might hire an outside studio to do the work.</p><h2 id="Take_Two_s_stance_on_ports">Take-Two's stance on ports</h2><p>Rockstar owner Take-Two is a big believer in ports, and CEO Strauss Zelnick said the company takes time and care to ensure the company does "the very best job we can making the title different for the new release."</p><p>"We improve the technology, we upgrade the visuals, and we make performance enhancements. And that's why I think our remastered titles typically do so well," <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/rockstar-owner-discusses-remasters-strategy-says-its-not-interested-in-simple-ports/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">he said.</a> "We don't just port titles over."</p><p>Grand Theft Auto: The Trilogy – The Definitive Edition, which included updated versions of three GTA games from developer Grove Street, launched in 2021 and was beset by numerous technical issues. Despite this, the game was apparently a massive success, selling an <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gta-remastered-trilogy-10-million-units-technical-issues" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">estimated 10 million copies.</a></p><hr><p>Keep checking back with GameSpot for more as new information comes to light.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/red-dead-redemption-2-ps5-xbox-switch-2-port-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6536035/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>