<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 10:50:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PUBG April Fool's Dating Sim Available Now For A Limited Time]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/01/pubg-april-fools-dating-sim-available-now-for-a-limited-time</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pubg-april-fools-dating-sim-available-now-for-a-limited-time.1151631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://gameinformer.com/2025/04/01/pubg-april-fools-dating-sim-available-now-for-a-limited-time<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>It’s April Fool’s Day, which means the next several hours will consist of scrutinizing every announcement to avoid being hoodwinked, bamboozled, and otherwise duped. However, this particular joke is legit. In the tradition of creating weird dating sims based on mature franchises, you can now find love in PUBG: Battlegrounds thanks to Winner Winner Romantic Dinner.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pRIzm0f7cLQ" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>Winner Winner Romantic Dinner is a free visual novel set in a high school in the PUBG world. Players control a student preparing a school festival who can court pretty girls who are actually human personifications of iconic PUBG weapons. The Molotov cocktail, for example, transforms into a fiery red-headed girl, while the AKM takes the form of a stoic silver-haired love interest. The wacky adventure features branching storylines and multiple endings, with each conclusion unlocking a themed nameplate and Contraband Coupons, alongside other PUBG rewards. The game can even be played using voice recognition for those with microphones.</p>

<p>This is a good time to reiterate that this is a real thing.</p>

<p>However, it won’t be a permanent thing. Winner Winner Romantic Dinner will only be available until April 29. To play it, you’ll have to visit <a href="https://pubg.com/en/events/wwrdevent">Krafton’s website</a> and have a registered Krafton ID. The game can be played on PC and mobile.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This is an example of the best kind of April Fool’s joke, in that it’s a real thing people can engage with. It’s reminiscent of April Fool’s 2023 when Sega released <a href="https://gameinformer.com/video-feature/2023/08/28/how-sega-murdered-sonic-the-hedgehog-exclusive-interview">The Murder of Sonic the Hedgehog</a>, a humorous (and quite good) visual novel mystery game that’s still available to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2324650/The_Murder_of_Sonic_the_Hedgehog/">play for free</a>. Winner Winner Romantic Dinner seems like a cute way to celebrate April Fools, if for no other reason than knowing it’s a funny novelty that won’t be around forever.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>