<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:40:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape Simulator 2 Will Take Players Into A Derelict Starship, Dracula's Castle, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/escape-simulator-2-will-take-players-into-a-derelict-starship-draculas-castle-and-more/1100-6528286/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/escape-simulator-2-will-take-players-into-a-derelict-starship-draculas-castle-and-more.1054095/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/escape-simulator-2-will-take-players-into-a-derelict-starship-draculas-castle-and-more/1100-6528286/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528286">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Experiencing escape rooms is the closest thing many fans will have to being in a real video-game world. Three years ago, Pine Studio's Escape Simulator brought that experience home. Now, Pine Studio is doing it again with Escape Simulator 2. The accompanying announcement trailer includes a glimpse at three of the upcoming escape rooms, none of which are confined to a single environment.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gsl4DvPyJs4" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Gsl4DvPyJs4" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Escape Simulator 2 will allow 1-8 players to step into intricately designed escape rooms that were created with help from real-life escape-room builders. The three rooms seen in the trailer are set in a pirate ship linked to a cursed treasure, an enigmatically empty starship stranded in space, and Count Dracula's castle in Transylvania. Before players can get out, they will be tasked to solve smaller mysteries in each room that add to the lore behind the experience.</p><p>Pine Studio co-founder Boris Barbir released a statement that touted the sequel's technical upgrades, including improved physics and animations. And despite the ominous tone of the trailer, Barbir insisted that "it's not a horror game--there are no jump scares or gore." He also pledged that Pine Studio will continue to support the original Escape Simulator while offering expansions for Escape Simulator 2 post-launch.</p><p>Escape Simulator 2 is now available to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2879840/Escape_Simulator_2" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">wishlist on Steam</a>, but a release date was not included in the announcement. The original Escape Simulator <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1435790/Escape_Simulator/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">is currently on Steam</a> at a big discount, and it has a new Mayan DLC expansion that offers four additional escape room adventures to explore in the jungle.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Just Made Two Accessibility Patents Open-Source]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-just-made-two-accessibility-patents-open-source/1100-6528289/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-just-made-two-accessibility-patents-open-source.1054092/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-just-made-two-accessibility-patents-open-source/1100-6528289/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528289">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">EA has made two of its patents accessible to the public, declaring them open-source, allowing non-EA developers to access technology the AAA publisher previously owned. Even better, this decision also means players who experience photosensitive seizures or need help with speech when gaming now have unfettered access to these patents as well.</p><p dir="ltr">Accessibility features in gaming have <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/access-ability-announces-june-2024-summer-showcase/1100-6523281/">gained steam in recent years</a> as developers and software engineers work to ensure players with disabilities can access their games. In 2021, EA pledged to loosen restrictions on its patents, especially patents regarding hardware or software that's meant to improve a player's quality of life. Now, <a href="https://www.ea.com/commitments/positive-play/accessibility-patent-pledge" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the 2021 pledge has been updated</a> to announce the two patents that have been made available for free.</p><p dir="ltr">EA says that the ultimate goal of its speech-based patent is to "make it possible for those players’ speech to be more effectively recognized and reflected in-game in a way that is representative of their age, emotion, language, and speaking style." The second patent is an Unreal Engine 5 plugin called IRIS. IRIS automatically alerts developers to moments in their games that may trigger seizures in individuals with photosensitive epilepsy.</p><p dir="ltr">"The sooner you start testing, the sooner you find potential issues," IRIS engineer Blanca Macazaga Zuaz said of the patented tech.</p><p>EA is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-playstation-access-controller-is-setting-up-an-accessibility-revolution/1100-6518347/">far from the only corporation</a> to lean in to accessibility features, but its decision to provide the public free access to the aforementioned patents is certainly an encouraging sign.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones And The Great Circle Wows On Consoles With Ray Tracing And 60FPS - Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-wows-on-consoles-with-ray-tracing-and-60fps-report/1100-6528285/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-wows-on-consoles-with-ray-tracing-and-60fps-report.1054017/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-wows-on-consoles-with-ray-tracing-and-60fps-report/1100-6528285/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528285">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">It's beautiful, and no, Digital Foundry isn't talking about the Lost Ark. The tech-analysis outfit examined Indiana Jones and the Great Circle on console--comparing Series X and Series S versions--coming away impressed with what developer MachineGames has done on the platforms.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-tech-review" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Digital Foundry's tech review</a> by John Linneman states that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-platforms-release-date-and-everything-we-know/1100-6520456/" data-ref-id="1100-6520456">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> maintains 60fps on both consoles (for the most part) while utilizing ray tracing. Linneman explains that it's rare for a console title to offer open-ended levels, ray tracing, and 60fps together and still perform well.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b8I4SsQTqaY" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/b8I4SsQTqaY" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">However, there are odd frame-rate dips during cutscenes for Indiana Jones and the Great Circle. Linneman writes that unlike the developer's Wolfenstein series, all cutscenes in this title are rendered in real time. But, other than this quirk, the action-adventure game runs "perfect[ly] on console" from a performance perspective. In fact, loading times are so fast they're barely noticeable, noted Linneman.</p><p dir="ltr">The Xbox Series X version of the game is better looking, offering 1800p most of the time from a visual perspective. Meanwhile, Series S sits around 1080p or lower. This leads to a blurrier presentation, even a bit blotchy at times. In addition, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle has more of a glow and worse shadows on Xbox Series S.</p><p dir="ltr">Earlier this week, we learned that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-will-let-you-shoot-puzzles-with-your-camera-to-solve-them/1100-6528192/" data-ref-id="1100-6528192">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle will let you shoot puzzles (with your camera) to solve them</a>. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-unlock-times-and-how-to-play-early/1100-6528168/" data-ref-id="1100-6528168">The game is already unlocked</a> for people who purchased the Premium or Collector's editions of the title. However, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/game-pass-for-december-includes-indiana-jones-and-lots-more/2900-6009/#1" data-ref-id="2900-6009">Game Pass subscribers will have to wait until next week</a> to take a crack at the timed Xbox console exclusive (it's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/will-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-run-on-your-pc-check-out-the-requirements/1100-6528208/" data-ref-id="1100-6528208">also available at launch on PC</a>).</p><p dir="ltr">For more, check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review-im-making-this-up-as-i-go/1900-6418322/" data-ref-id="1900-6418322">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle review</a>. Additionally, be prepared to don the hat and whip with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/indiana-jones-great-circle-tips-to-know-before-you-play-beginners-guide/2900-6016/#1" data-ref-id="2900-6016">15 things to know before playing the action-adventure game</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>