<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 18:27:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead Take, The Psychological Horror FMV From Surgent Studios, Gets July Release Date, Full Cast Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/16/dead-take-the-psychological-horror-fmv-from-surgent-studios-gets-july-release-date-full</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dead-take-the-psychological-horror-fmv-from-surgent-studios-gets-july-release-date-full-cast-revealed.1245423/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Last month, we learned that the next game from Surgent Studios, the team behind 2024's <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/tales-of-kenzera-zau/spirit-over-substance">Tales of Kenzera: Zau</a>, will be <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/dead-take">Dead Take</a>, a psychological horror FMV game set to release this year. Now, the team has revealed it launches later this month on July 31, alongside the full cast players can expect to hear (and see) the game.&nbsp;</p><p>In Dead Take, you play as an actor, voiced by Neil Newbon (Astarion in Baldur's Gate 3), searching for his missing friend, who is played Ben Starr (Verso in Clair Obscur: Expedition 33). Set in a beautiful but seemingly abandoned Hollywood mansion, you must explore the house to figure out what exactly has transpired within its walls. There are puzzles to solve, videos to splice together, and more.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Check out gameplay in the latest Dead Take trailer below:&nbsp;</strong></p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aXhJB9ICvfc"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aXhJB9ICvfc" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>As you can see in the trailer above, Newbon and Starr will be joined by Jane Perry, Matt Mercer, Laura Bailey, Sam Lake, Travis Willingham, Alanah Pearce, and Connor Cdawg Colquhoun, with music by Ross Tregenza.&nbsp;</p><p>Dead Take launches on PC later this month on July 31.&nbsp;</p><p>In the meantime, <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/2025/06/03/dead-take-is-a-psychological-horror-game-from-the-studio-behind-tales-of-kenzera-and-it">check out the Dead Take reveal trailer</a> from June.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Are you going to check out Dead Take? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/07/16/dead-take-the-psychological-horror-fmv-from-surgent-studios-gets-july-release-date-full]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>