<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 18:50:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RoboCop: Rogue City Expansion Will Let You Play As The Fleshy Version Of The Ultimate Cop]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/robocop-rogue-city-expansion-will-let-you-play-as-the-fleshy-version-of-the-ultimate-cop/1100-6529938/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robocop-rogue-city-expansion-will-let-you-play-as-the-fleshy-version-of-the-ultimate-cop.1127289/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/robocop-rogue-city-expansion-will-let-you-play-as-the-fleshy-version-of-the-ultimate-cop/1100-6529938/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529938">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>During Nacon Connect 2025, developer Teyon announced that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/robocop-rogue-city/" data-ref-id="5000-534157">RoboCop: Rogue City</a> will be getting a standalone expansion. Called Unfinished Business, the new content sees RoboCop return to Omni Tower after an army of skilled mercenaries have taken over the building, and it'll be launching in the summer for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. Here's the first trailer for it:</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HZxqWFQI7GY" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/HZxqWFQI7GY" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>While it looks like you'll have plenty of targets and challenging opponents in the expansion, it does add an interesting wrinkle in the form of flashback missions. These levels will let players step into the boots of Alex Murphy long before he had his fatal encounter with Clarence J. Boddicker and his gang in the 1987 film. Additionally, the levels featuring RoboCop will also give players access to new weapons, brutal finishers, and special missions.</p><p>RoboCop: Rogue City is admittedly a flawed game, but if you can overlook its rougher parts, you'll find that it's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/robocop-rogue-city-captures-the-vibe-of-the-movies-and-benefits-from-rpg-inspired-gameplay/1100-6514775/" data-ref-id="1100-6514775">incredibly faithful to the source material</a> and a fun blast of '80s action. Teyon had several post-launch updates for the game, including a New Game Plus mode that fans had been requesting.</p><p>In GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/robocop-rogue-city-review-id-buy-that-for-a-dollar/1900-6418149/">RoboCop: Rogue City review</a>, reviewer Richard Wakeling called the game a solid--if sometimes poorly paced--shooter full of fun references that RoboCop fans will appreciate. "If you're a fan of RoboCop, then you'll find a lot to love in Rogue City. It's chock full of Easter eggs and manages to capture the look and feel of the first two RoboCop movies with excellent attention to detail, even getting Peter Weller to reprise his role as the eponymous hero."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Members Get These 20 Free Games In March]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-members-get-these-20-free-games-in-march/1100-6529925/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-prime-members-get-these-20-free-games-in-march.1127208/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-members-get-these-20-free-games-in-march/1100-6529925/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529925">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Amazon has revealed all of the free PC games that'll be coming to Prime Gaming in March, and there's a pretty solid lineup of classic open-world, fantasy, and puzzle games to grab. In total, there'll be 20 games offered this month, with four games available right now. As a reminder, all of the free games that you claim through Prime Gaming are yours to keep forever, even if your subscription expires. If you aren't a member, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/prime/pipeline/signup?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">you can sign up for Amazon Prime</a> for as little as one month to take advantage of the subscription and the freebies offered through it.</p><p>The month kicks off with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/saints-row-the-third/" data-ref-id="5000-40483">Saints Row: The Third Remastered</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/mafia-ii/" data-ref-id="5000-32858">Mafia 2: Definitive Edition</a>. Considered to be the best in the Saints Row series, the threequel is a goofy sandbox of crime and dubstep-powered weapons, and this remastered edition features enhanced graphics and all of the post-launch DLC. Mafia 2: Definitive Edition is a story-driven open-world game set in the 1940s, as war hero Vito Scaletta becomes entangled with the mob.</p><p>You can also redeem <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/crime-boss-rockay-city/" data-ref-id="5000-577630">Crime Boss: Rockay City</a> if you feel like gawking at bad gameplay and want to see Chuck Norris as the bad guy, and there's also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/naheulbeuks-dungeon-master/" data-ref-id="5000-590955">Naheulbeuk's Dungeon Master</a> to round out the first batch of games. March 13 will give you five more games to choose from, with the highlight here being <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/endling-extinction-is-forever/" data-ref-id="5000-484683">Endling: Extinction is Forever</a>. It's not a game for the faint-hearted, as Endling lets you take control of the last mother fox on Earth. Driven to protect all of her cubs in a merciless world that is on the brink of destruction, Endling is a stressful and emotional survival-adventure game.</p><p>Moving ahead to March 20, the Prime Gaming library will expand with five more games. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/mortal-shell/" data-ref-id="5000-510197">Mortal Shell</a> is a flawed but interesting souls-like, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/wolfenstein-the-old-blood/" data-ref-id="5000-403573">Wolfenstein: the Old Blood</a> is a spooky spin-off from the first Wolfenstein adventure developed by MachineGames, and you can jump into 2003's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/legacy-of-kain-defiance/" data-ref-id="5000-18258">Legacy of Kain: Defiance</a> to check out the final game in the classic series.</p><p>Finally, March 27 will see six more games arrive to cap the month off with games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/deus-ex-invisible-war/" data-ref-id="5000-3789">Deus Ex: Invisible War</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-forgotten-city/" data-ref-id="5000-483405">The Forgotten City</a>, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/session-skate-sim/" data-ref-id="5000-483355">Session: Skate Sim</a>.</p><h2>Prime Gaming free games for March 2025</h2><h3>Available now</h3><ul><li>Saints Row: The Third Remastered (GOG Code)</li><li>Mafia 2: Definitive Edition (GOG Code)</li><li>Crime Boss: Rockay City (Epic Games Store)</li><li>Naheulbeuk's Dungeon Master (Amazon Games App)</li></ul><h3>March 13</h3><ul><li>Wall World (Amazon Games App)</li><li>Syberia: The World Before (GOG Code)</li><li>Endling: Extinction is Forever (Amazon Games App)</li><li>Dark Deity: Complete Edition (GOG Code)</li><li>Beholder 3 (Amazon Games App)</li></ul><h3>March 20</h3><ul><li>Wolfenstein: The Old Blood (Xbox and PC via Microsoft Store Code)</li><li>Mutazione (GOG Code)</li><li>Figment 2: Creed Valley (Amazon Games App)</li><li>Legacy of Kain: Defiance (GOG Code)</li><li>Mortal Shell (Epic Games Store)</li></ul><h3>March 27</h3><ul><li>The Forgotten City (Amazon Games App)</li><li>Deus Ex: Invisible War (GOG Code)</li><li>Session: Skate Sim (Epic Games Store)</li><li>Let's Build A Zoo (Epic Games Store)</li><li>Gamedec - Definitive Edition (GOG Code)</li><li>The Wisbey Mystery (Legacy Games Code)</li></ul><p>Prime subscribers will also be able to the following games in January via the Prime Gaming Luna channel:</p><ul><li>WRC Generations: Fully Loaded Edition</li><li>Overcooked 2</li><li>Spitlings</li><li>The Jackbox Party Pack 3</li><li>Strange Horticulture</li><li>Fortnite</li><li>Fortnite Ballistic</li><li>Lego Fortnite Brick Life</li><li>Fortnite Battle Royale</li><li>Fortnite Festival</li><li>Lego Fortnite Odyssey</li><li>Rocket Racing</li><li>Fortnite</li><li>Trackmania</li><li>Fallout New Vegas: Ultimate Edition</li><li>Fallout 3: Game of the Year Edition</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>