<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 23:49:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Chapter 6 Finale Live Event: Everything You Need To Know About Zero Hour]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-6-finale-live-event-everything-you-need-to-know-about-zero-hour/1100-6536400/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-chapter-6-finale-live-event-everything-you-need-to-know-about-zero-hour.1361377/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536400">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">We are fast approaching the end to another <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fortnite/" data-ref-id="5000-125765">Fortnite</a> chapter, and that means it's nearly time for a huge live event that will introduce a new era for Epic Games' metaverse. It's Fortnite's biggest party, typically drawing its biggest concurrent player numbers by a wide margin each year. In 2023 it drew more than 11 million players, and 2024's event pulled more than 14 million.</p><p dir="ltr">And with this year's chapter finale, titled Zero Hour, looking like it's going to rope in every collab Fortnite had over the past 365 days <em>while also</em> picking up old storylines that Fortnite abandoned years ago, this one's looking like quite a doozie.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4609075-g6tarewx0aalrhx.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4609075" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4609075-g6tarewx0aalrhx.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4609075"></a><figcaption>The Fortnite Chapter 6 finale event looks like it'll be quite a spectacle.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1757/17577455/4609075-g6tarewx0aalrhx.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">When is Fortnite's Chapter 6 finale event going down?</h2><p dir="ltr">The live finale event, which will only take place one time, will begin at 11 AM PT / 2 PM ET on Saturday, November 29.</p><p dir="ltr">You'll be able to join the mode 40 minutes prior to start time, which likely means there will be some sort of pre-show entertainment. Prior to the event at the end of Star Wars season back in June, there was an X-Wing vs TIE Fighter PvP space flight sim for players to enjoy before the main event, so these things can get pretty elaborate.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Will Fortnite go offline afterward?</h2><p dir="ltr">Yes. You can expect that Fortnite's servers will go offline for the Chapter 7 update once the event ends. But if all goes well, Fortnite should only be down for about 4-7 hours. Expect Chapter 7 to start in the evening on November 29.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Fortnite Chapter 6: Zero Hour live event teaser</h2><p dir="ltr">Epic has offered a cinematic teaser for the event, and it looks like<em> a lot. </em>Check it out.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mwh7WFCW3f8" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Mwh7WFCW3f8" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2 dir="ltr">What can we expect to happen during the Zero Hour event?</h2><p dir="ltr">Based on the teaser, we're going to get some kind of Avengers: Endgame-level confrontation with Chapter 6's ultimate big bad, whose tentacles have made sporadic appearances throughout the chapter. All the past year's Fortnite collabs will team up like it's the end of Ready Player One, and then whatever happens will usher in the Chapter 7 island.</p><p dir="ltr">We're expecting characters from tons of different IPs that collabed with Fortnite in the past year to show up, with Godzilla x Kong, Star Wars, Halo, K-Pop Demon Hunters, Hatsune Miku, Power Rangers, TMNT, and Superman already being teased. Likewise, at least two upcoming Chapter 7 collabs--Kill Bill and Back to the Future--will also have parts to play.</p><p dir="ltr">But Zero Hour won't just be about the collabs. The Fortnite original superhero group known as the Seven are almost guaranteed to make their return during this event. None of the members of the Seven have been seen since the end of Chapter 3, so it's been a while.</p><p dir="ltr">The big question is whether they'll be the same versions of the characters as before. We've already had two different versions of The Paradigm, who were entirely different characters from alternate realities, so we might get to meet a new version of The Foundation not played by Dwayne Johnson. But there have been no rumors either way on that front just yet, so we'll have to wait and see.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-6-finale-live-event-everything-you-need-to-know-about-zero-hour/1100-6536400/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 4 Gets New Update Following Anniversary Edition Backlash]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-4-gets-new-update-following-anniversary-edition-backlash/1100-6536446/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-4-gets-new-update-following-anniversary-edition-backlash.1361344/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536446">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In October, Bethesda announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-4-and-fallout-new-vegas-are-getting-anniversary-editions/1100-6535649/" data-ref-id="1100-6535649">Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition</a>, an updated version of the game that was released 10 years ago this month. What was meant to be the definitive version of the game launched with numerous bugs and other issues that sparked a backlash against Fallout 4. Now, Bethesda is releasing an update for November and looking ahead to a December update as well.</p><p>Bethesda shared the patch notes on social media. The message didn't directly address the negative response to Fallout 4 Anniversary Edition, but it did thank players for their "continued communication with us on your current Fallout 4 experience." The dev team notes that it's focused on DLC installation issues, occasional crashing, and general user experience in the patch.</p><p>The team added that it still plans to add a mod storage expansion on Fallout 4's console versions. However, the devs state that more time is needed before that feature is ready to be released. Beyond that, the team promised to share details about the December patch in a few weeks.</p><p>Additionally, the devs promised "several free Fallout 4 Creations coming to players," including the first one, The Varmint Rifle. To get that one when it arrives next week, players will have to fall down a manhole before they discover the unique rifle, solve a series of puzzles, and fight their way out of enemy territory.</p><p>The release date for Fallout 4's November patch hasn't been announced yet. You can find the full patch notes below.</p><h2>Upcoming Fallout 4 November Patch - Patch Notes</h2><h3>Crash and Stability Fixes</h3><ul><li>Fixed crash when starting a new game with Creations installed on PS4.</li><li>Fixed crash when quitting after exiting an interior with Pip-Boy open (PS4/PS5).</li><li>Guest/local users can no longer access the Creations menu, which resulted in an inoperable state</li><li>Addressed rare crashes when choosing to use the save data load order, especially when loading saves with missing Creations.</li><li>Fixed a crash that could occur when selecting 'Purchase Credits' on PC</li><li>Fixed a crash when selecting "Download all owned Creation Club Creations"</li></ul><h3>Save/Load &amp; Profile</h3><ul><li>Exit saves are now correctly created when exiting to the main menu</li><li>Fixed infinite loading when downloading missing Creation Club content from a save made on a different platform.</li><li>Switching Xbox user profiles no longer causes softlocks or loss of controls.</li><li>Fixed an issue where loading a save file with different creations enabled did not prompt a load order warning</li><li>Downloading a creation and disabling it immediately, will no longer cause content that relies on it to become permanently disabled</li></ul><h3>UI &amp; User Experience</h3><ul><li>Performance improvements in the Creations menu across platforms.</li><li>Fixed softlocking when entering/exiting the Creations menu repeatedly.</li><li>Fixed infinite loading/hang when loading a save file that requires creations.</li><li>Bundle prices now update immediately after purchasing individual items in the bundle.</li><li>Bundles now show correct file sizes for included creations.</li></ul><h3>Localization improvements.</h3><ul><li>In-game Creations menu now respects the load order set by the player, not alphabetical order.</li><li>Players can now like/unlike creations in the Load Order menu as intended.</li><li>Guest/local users can no longer access the Creations menu; option is now greyed out as on PS4.</li><li>Downloaded Creations will now remain visible in your Load Order after deletion from BethesdaNet.</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fallout-4-gets-new-update-following-anniversary-edition-backlash/1100-6536446/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox CEO Responds To Child Predator Concerns Poorly]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/roblox-ceo-responds-to-child-predator-concerns-poorly/1100-6536445/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roblox-ceo-responds-to-child-predator-concerns-poorly.1361317/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536445">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Developer Roblox Corporation recently introduced a new face-scanning feature as a way to increase child safety protection on its game creation platform, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/roblox-game-client/" data-ref-id="5000-451936">Roblox</a>. CEO David Baszucki is very excited about this initiative, giving some rather intense and questionable answers during a new podcast episode about the age-gating technology.</p><p>Baszucki sat down with The New York Times journalists Casey Newton and Kevin Roose for an episode of their Hard Fork podcast. Posted on November 21, the three engaged in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/11/21/podcasts/hardfork-roblox-child-safety.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a wide-ranging conversation</a> that started with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/roblox-will-try-harder-to-keep-kids-from-talking-to-strangers/1100-6536311/" data-ref-id="1100-6536311">the face-scanning feature</a>, moved to misnomers about data, and peaked at disgreements regarding the use of AI for moderation. Newtown opened with an inquiry about the problem with predators on Roblox, which Baszucki said is a good and bad dilemma.</p><p>"We think of it not necessarily just as a problem, but an opportunity as well," he said. "How do we allow young people to build, communicate and hang out together? How do we build the future of communication at the same time? So we, you know, we’ve been, I think in a good way, working on this ever since we started. And when we were--this was almost 18 or 19 years ago--when we first launched the company and we had just four of us sitting in a room, we were literally the moderators, like we would rotate all the time."</p><p>Baszucki continued, saying that with the scale Roblox has grown to, the company decided that "the latest tech" (that is, "using facial age estimation with A.I.") is what it's looking toward to complement its moderation tools with. He mentioned text filters as one example, particularly since chatters tend to use "hashtag, hashtag, hashtag" and other keyword tricks to bypass the system.</p><p>"With A.I., these filters have gotten better and better," Baszucki said. "The state of where we are now is primarily getting into the blocking of adversarial attempts to broach the filter, and adversarial attempts to try to share PII [personally identifying information], which we're getting better and better at as well. On the age estimation, it's just--I would say--recently come of age to the point where we would complement it. But I would say our strategy is always [to] complement with whatever technology is out there to put that together."</p><p>Before long, the three were interrupting each other, interjecting statements and questions to get a leg up. Baszucki "categorically rejected" the assertion in recent lawsuits claiming predators use Roblox to find kids. He said the platform is doing "an incredible job at innovating" when compared to other online social platforms, repeating that the company is "constantly getting better" at protecting kids' ability to chat in-game.</p><p>"There's enormous benefits for having people be able to communicate, and we think we see those benefits," Baszucki explained. "There's a lot of kids who find their peeps on Roblox. There are a lot of kids when they're lonely or isolated actually--I'm not going to use it as an excuse or anything--but I get a lot of calls from famous parents who said, 'Look, my kid would be dead if it were not for finding a community on a platform like Roblox to stay connected with.' And I would also say we do take it as an enormous responsibility to design for not the sophisticated parent who goes in and says, 'Look, I'm going to turn off who you can chat to and all of that.' We have to design for all parents and think through that. But we do believe we have enormously great technology up and down the stack. We think it's part of building an experience like this. You know, if you go out there in the gaming space, I think it is very common to support communication. I'm not going to list any other games. And typically, we are way beyond in, I'd say, our innovation level, responsibility level, on both the filtering, on the image sharing, on all of these things."</p><p>After more tense exchanges around the 150 million daily active users--which Baszucki claimed is now "self-reported [to be] almost two-thirds over 13"--Roose asked about <a href="https://hindenburgresearch.com/roblox/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hindenburg Research's October 2024 findings</a> on the company allegedly disregarding child safety in the name of profits. He deflected, instead opting to focus on the fact that the activist fund "went out of business for some reason" and asked the hosts if they've researched that information themselves. He then responded by saying that AI is making everything better.</p><p>"So it's really interesting, because I think we're diving into a situation where we're getting better, better, better," Baszucki said. "But would you ask the same situation of someone who converted from maybe hypermanual labor making cars by hand to an assembly line? The assembly line might be infinitely better and at the same time not have so many people. So, I think what they're referring to is moving more and more and more and more to A.I. Arguably, is it better to have A.I. systems reviewing every image, every piece of text, all of that, or to keep doing that manually? So I think that was a misnomer. And I think if you interview anyone in our safety team or safety systems, that would be just part of making our systems better."</p><p>It's at this point that Baszucki's mood became a little flustered--though not "frustrated," as he said on multiple occasions--as he apparently went around high-fiving Newton and Roose for "aligning" with the company's decision to use AI tools for content moderation and "supporting our Roblox decision matrix."</p><p>"Is this a stealth interview where actually you love everything we’re doing and you’re here to stealthily support it?" He asked the hosts, later adding that he's "excited to talk." </p><p>"I thought we were going to be talking about fun, funny things in the industry and all of that," Baszucki said. "So I'm not frustrated, I’m just kind of figuring out how much fun time I have with you guys and how much fun time we have versus kind of this superfocus. But I'm happy to talk about whatever you guys want."</p><p>Something fun that Baszucki started talking about was a hypothetical "prediction market inside Roblox" that Roose tossed out. A "terrible idea," Roose thought, he wondered if the company would ever consider letting children place bets with the Robux in-game currency." Baszucki called it a "brilliant idea" he loves.</p><p>"I actually think it's a brilliant idea if it can be done in an educational way that's legal," he said. "And so, imagine no free Robux, no free prizes, just a game called the Dress to Impress Predictor, where it's not like trying to get kids' money or anything like that. I would be a big fan of it."</p><p>In the end, Baszucki seemed adamant in defending the fact that Roblox's content moderation tools are ever-evolving, pointing to text filtering in the past and face-scanning in the present as ways the company cares for the safety of its user base.</p><p>Roblox Corporation has come under intense scrutiny in recent months following a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2024-roblox-pedophile-problem/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">June 2024 Bloomberg investigation</a> that revealed the platform is rampant with predators. States like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/florida-ag-alleges-roblox-is-a-predator-breeding-ground-opens-investigation/1100-6535594/" data-ref-id="1100-6535594">Florida</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/texas-sues-roblox-over-child-exploitation-and-grooming-concerns/1100-6536037/" data-ref-id="1100-6536037">Texas</a> have sued for what lawmakers say is the company <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/roblox-is-not-doing-enough-to-protect-kids-lawmaker-says/1100-6533929/" data-ref-id="1100-6533929">not doing enough to protect kids</a> from child exploitation and grooming.</p><p>Whether or Roblox or not, the problem with child predators is beginning to reach a fever pitch. According to the European law enforcement agency Europol, European society is seeing a sharp rise in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/children-are-weaponized-through-online-games-to-commit-murder-europol-claims/1100-6536430/" data-ref-id="1100-6536430">criminal networks weaponizing children</a> to commit violent crimes.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/roblox-ceo-responds-to-child-predator-concerns-poorly/1100-6536445/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Really Good Multiplayer Game Is Free On Steam For A Limited Time]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-really-good-multiplayer-game-is-free-on-steam-for-a-limited-time/1100-6536443/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-really-good-multiplayer-game-is-free-on-steam-for-a-limited-time.1361269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536443">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Steam users can pick up the beloved Warhammer: Vermintide 2 at no cost this weekend, as part of a celebration thrown by developer Fatshark.</p><p>From now until November 23 at 9:59 PM ET / 6:59 PM PT, you can go to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/552500/Warhammer_Vermintide_2/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the game's Steam page</a> and add Vermintide 2 to your library.</p><p>The title usually costs $30, but Fatshark is offering the game for free to mark 10 years of "Tide" games from the studio, beginning with Warhammer: End Times - Vermintide in 2015. The event also includes new content for both Vermintide 2 and its spiritual successor, Warhammer 40K: Darktide.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/VermintideGame/status/1991944743769481661" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">The 10 years of Tide celebration is far from over!<br>Seize the opportunity to get new friends into the rat-slaying hobby.<br>That's right, anyone who downloads Vermintide 2 on Steam this weekend gets to keep it forever, in perpetuity, until the end times! <a href="https://t.co/JUyMzaEsA4" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/JUyMzaEsA4</a></p>  — Warhammer Vermintide (@VermintideGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/VermintideGame/status/1991944743769481661?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 21, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>For the uninitiated, Vermintide 2 is a cooperative multiplayer game in which teams of four players clash against the Chaos army and hordes of rat men called Skaven. Think of it as a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/what-made-left-4-dead-special-according-to-the-devs-making-games-like-it/1100-6503996/" data-ref-id="1100-6503996">Left 4 Dead-like experience</a>, but you bash giant rats with melee weapons instead of mowing down zombies with assault rifles.</p><p>Releasing in 2018, Vermintide 2 still enjoys plenty of new content and support from Fatshark, receiving a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/warhammer-vermintide-2-versus-mode-open-beta-trailer-gamescom-2024/2300-6464930/" data-ref-id="2300-6464930">new Versus mode last year</a> and getting tons of quality-of-life updates and free DLC over the years. Just this week, Vermintide 2 added the Return to the Reik level, which recreates a fan-favorite location from Vermintide 1.</p><p>This actually isn't the first time Vermintide 2 has been temporarily offered for free on Steam--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grab-this-warhammer-game-for-free-on-steam-right-now/1100-6508881/" data-ref-id="1100-6508881">Fatshark made the same move in 2022</a>. The game is also available for full price on PlayStation 4, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X|S, though it's part of the Xbox Game Pass Ultimate and Standard libraries and the PlayStation Plus Extra catalog.</p><p>There are plenty of fun games that will always remain <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-free-steam-games/2900-5335/" data-ref-id="2900-5335">free-to-play on Steam</a>, but nabbing Vermintide 2 this coming weekend would be an absolute steal.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-really-good-multiplayer-game-is-free-on-steam-for-a-limited-time/1100-6536443/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Shows Off Generative AI Game Demo Called Teammates]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-shows-off-generative-ai-game-demo-called-teammates/1100-6536444/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-shows-off-generative-ai-game-demo-called-teammates.1361242/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536444">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>During an investor presentation earlier today, Ubisoft showed off Teammates, a new R&amp;D game experience that utilizes generative AI. Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot also described the advent of generative AI in games as "a revolution."</p><p>"Generative AI is as big a revolution for games as the shift to 3D," said Guillemot (via <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/ubisoft-delayed-results%20%20as%20the%20tech%20is%20embraced%20company%20wide" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Game File</a>). "We are making great strides in applying Gen AI to high-value use cases that bring tangible benefits to our players and teams... It's as big [of] a revolution for our industry as the shift to 3D. And we have everything to lead on this front."</p><p>Teammates was developed by the team behind Neo NPC. The company also said that the demo is meant to prove that "generative AI-driven gameplay can shape a new generation of more interactive and engaging games."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4608845-teammatessofiaandpablo.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4608845" data-ratio="0.56230769230769" data-width="1300" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4608845-teammatessofiaandpablo.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4608845"></a><figcaption>A screencap from Teammates.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4608845-teammatessofiaandpablo.jpg"></figure><p>The game's prototype is currently being tested by a small number of players. Teammates is a first-person shooter, but its AI tools will supposedly let it adapt to voice commands from the player, allowing NPCs to dynamically respond in real-time.</p><p>"It's really about experimenting with entirely new ways of creating interactive stories," said the game's narrative director, Virginie Mosser. "Our role is to give AI meaning, to narrativize it, ensuring logic doesn’t replace soul. We designed Teammates to leave space for player creativity, finding that balance between emotion and unpredictability."</p><p>Teammates includes a companion character called Jaspar who is said to be able to help the player overcome obstacles and provide hints or strategies. In concept, that's not very different from other NPCs in numerous games. What supposedly makes Jaspar stand out is his ability to interact and respond directly to the player.</p><p>The Teammates devs note that it has a specially made Application Programming Interface (API) that can utilize guardrails that shield players from AI-powered hallucinations and "helps control its power to put it at the service of human creativity and play." The company also characterized Teammates as an experiment that "serves both as a playable prototype and a testbed for the underlying technology."</p><p>Ubisoft has stated that its new "Creative Houses" operating model will be <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-posts-strong-first-half-growth-and-teases-major-creative-shake-up-coming-in-2026/1100-6536414/" data-ref-id="1100-6536414">unveiled in January 2026</a>. Earlier this week, Ubisoft apologized to players for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-promises-to-replace-ai-art-found-in-anno-117-pax-romana/1100-6536293/" data-ref-id="1100-6536293">including AI artwork in Anno 117: Pax Romana</a>. The replacement image looks like the AI version, minus a few people with extra fingers or distorted faces.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-shows-off-generative-ai-game-demo-called-teammates/1100-6536444/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 7's Nuketown Map Doesn't Have The Mannequin Easter Egg Yet, But That's No Surprise]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-7s-nuketown-map-doesnt-have-the-mannequin-easter-egg-yet-but-thats-no-surprise/1100-6536441/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-7s-nuketown-map-doesnt-have-the-mannequin-easter-egg-yet-but-thats-no-surprise.1361203/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536441">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-7s-nuketown-2025-map-goes-live-tomorrow-see-it-in-action-now/1100-6536356/" data-ref-id="1100-6536356">new version of Nuketown arrived on November 20</a>, and one of the first things people tried on it was shooting off all the mannequin heads to unlock the long-running Nuketown Easter egg. Unfortunately, it doesn't work in Black Ops 7, at least not yet. This isn't a huge shock, though, as Black Ops 6's version of Nuketown didn't unlock the Easter egg right away, either.</p><p>A popular video from the Detonated account shows that the mannequin heads on Nuketown 2025 cannot be shot off, thereby not allowing the Easter egg to unlock once they're all blasted away. People are theorizing that the new version of Nuketown does indeed carry forward the Easter egg that's been in every version of Nuketown since 2010, but it's just not active yet.</p><p>In Black Ops 6, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-easter-egg-breathes-new-life-into-nuketown-in-the-creepiest-way-possible/1100-6527796/" data-ref-id="1100-6527796">zombified mannequins sprung forth from the ground</a> for the Easter egg. And <a href="https://screenrant.com/call-duty-black-ops-nuketown-easter-eggs-ranked/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">as ScreenRant reminds us</a>, when Black Ops 6's version of Nuketown launched, it also didn't have the Easter egg unlocked, but it arrived around a week later. If the same pattern holds for Black Ops 7, fans can expect the latest version of the Easter egg to be here soon. Season 1 is expected to launch in early December, and this could be when the Easter egg gets unlocked for Black Ops 7, but that's just a guess.</p><p>The Nuketown Easter egg debuted with the first Black Ops game in 2010 and has showed up, in different forms, for every version of the map since. For the first game, shooting all the mannequin heads would trigger the game to start playing the Rolling Stones song "Sympathy for the Devil." In Black Ops 2, the Easter egg makes classic Activision games playable on an in-game sign.</p><p>In other Call of Duty news, Treyarch made <a href="https://x.com/Treyarch/status/1991220426618597519" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Black Ops 7's Endgame available to everyone</a> today, November 21. Before, players had to complete the campaign to unlock it. A new update just arrived, too, and it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-patch-notes-detail-aim-assist-change-drone-pod-nerf-and-smg-buffs/1100-6536440/" data-ref-id="1100-6536440">makes some aim-assist changes. </a></p><p>Black Ops 7 launched on November 14, and, in a break from tradition, Activision's first-weekend social media post about the game <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/activision-isnt-sharing-any-black-ops-7-launch-weekend-game-stats/1100-6536299/" data-ref-id="1100-6536299">did not include any mention of how the game is performing compared to past releases.</a></p><p>For more, check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-review/1900-6418441/" data-ref-id="1900-6418441">GameSpot's Black Ops 7 review</a>. You can also catch up on why <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/us-congressman-calls-for-ai-regulations-after-call-of-duty-black-ops-7-debate/1100-6536263/" data-ref-id="1100-6536263">one US lawmaker is calling for AI regulations</a> after it came to light that Black Ops 7 developers used AI.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-7s-nuketown-map-doesnt-have-the-mannequin-easter-egg-yet-but-thats-no-surprise/1100-6536441/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>