<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 23:20:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naughty Dog's Debated Going Straight Into The Last Of Us Part III After Part II]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/11/naughty-dogs-debated-going-straight-into-the-last-of-us-part-iii-after-part-ii</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/naughty-dogs-debated-going-straight-into-the-last-of-us-part-iii-after-part-ii.1295241/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Naughty Dog president and The Last of Us director Neil Druckmann has seemingly revealed that The Last of Us Part III is, at the very least, an idea that's been floated at the studio. In a new interview with <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/neil-druckmann-last-of-us-exit-intergalactic-video-game-1236514453/"><em>Variety</em></a>, Druckmann says Naughty Dog debated going straight into Part III after completing <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/the-last-of-us-part-ii/the-last-of-us-part-ii-review-a-perfect-circle">Part II</a>, but that ultimately, the team decided to move forward on what we now know as <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>While a Part III to The Last of Us seems like a no-brainer, considering how well this franchise does for Naughty Dog and PlayStation, Druckmann has given mixed signals over the years. When <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered">The Last of Us Part II Remastered</a> dropped last year, it eventually included <a href="https://gameinformer.com/news/2024/01/25/grounded-ii-the-making-of-documentary-for-the-last-of-us-part-ii-will-be-released"><em>Grounded II</em>, a documentary about the making of the game</a>.&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7HJZJTMP9gw"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7HJZJTMP9gw" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Near the end of it, Druckmann said, "For years now, I haven't been able to find that concept [for Part III], but recently, that's changed, and I don't have a story, but I do have a conept that to me is as exciting as 1, as exciting as 2, is its own thing, and yet has this throughline for all three. So it does feel like there's probably one more chapter to this story."&nbsp;</p><p>But then, in a March 2025 <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/the-last-of-us-season-2-abby-video-game-changes-backlash-1236327786/"><em>Variety</em></a><em> </em>interview, Druckmann, when asked about a potential Part III, said, "I guess the only thing I would say is don't be on there being more of The Last of Us. This could be it."&nbsp;</p><p>Now, in a new interview with <em>Variety</em>, Druckmann has seemingly revealed that Naughty Dog, at one point, had plans regarding a Part III game in its Last of Us franchise.&nbsp;</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="1dd06917-68b1-4ebc-a0ed-645bbdc86da0" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	






</article>
<p>When asked about potential Intergalactic sequels, Druckmann said, "We don't tend to plan too much in the future, because we find – and this is something I inherited, it's just the Naughty Dog culture – that we do our best work when it's something we're really excited about, really passionate about.</p><p>"Just to give you an example, when we finished The Last of Us Part II, and that was highly successful for us, we were debating whether we should just go straight into The Last of Us 3, and we had a really long period where we looked at ideas for maybe what could be in that game."&nbsp;</p><p>The team looked at Uncharted, Jak and Daxter, and its "sci-fi thing," though, and Druckmann said what is now Intergalactic is where the team's passion led it.&nbsp;</p><p>So for now, it sounds like a third Last of Us game is on the theoretical or potential table as Naughty Dog continues work on Intergalactic.&nbsp;</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="b3906ef8-1431-4bbf-bdf5-93c2d24a2d06" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	






</article>
<p>For more, read <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/11/naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-discusses-intergalactic-gameplay-and-casting-in-new">Druckmann's thoughts on the casting and gameplay of Intergalactic</a>, and then check out <a href="https://gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/03/26/naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-on-the-creative-process-behind-season-2-of-the"><em>Game Informer's </em>interview with Druckmann on the set of <em>The Last of Us </em>Season 2</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>[Source: <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/neil-druckmann-last-of-us-exit-intergalactic-video-game-1236514453/">Variety</a>]</p><hr><p><em>Do you want Naughty Dog to make a third Last of Us game or something else? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/11/naughty-dogs-debated-going-straight-into-the-last-of-us-part-iii-after-part-ii]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naughty Dog's Neil Druckmann Discusses Intergalactic Gameplay And Casting In New Interview]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/11/naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-discusses-intergalactic-gameplay-and-casting-in-new</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-discusses-intergalactic-gameplay-and-casting-in-new-interview.1295208/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><em>Game Informer </em>spoke with Naughty Dog president and The Last of Us director Neil Druckmann last year on the set of <em>The Last of Us </em>Season 2. Since then, he's revealed he is stepping back from Season 3 of the show to focus on developing the studio's next game, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</a>, which Naughty Dog <a href="https://www.naughtydog.com/blog/intergalactic_the_heretic_prophet_announcement">revealed at The Game Awards 2024</a> last December.&nbsp;</p><p>In a new interview with <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/neil-druckmann-last-of-us-exit-intergalactic-video-game-1236514453/"><em>Variety</em></a><em>, </em>Druckmann discussed a number of things about Intergalactic, including casting Tati Gabrielle as the game's lead, Jordan A. Mun, working with Joel actor Troy Baker again, casting <em>The Last of Us </em>Season 2 actor Tony Dalton (who played Joel's dad), and more.&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VLGy63pt9vA"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VLGy63pt9vA" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Perhaps the most revealing statement from Druckmann came when <em>Variety </em>asked him about his description of Intergalactic as having "the deepest gameplay" in Naughty Dog history.&nbsp;</p><p>"You can look at our previous titles and see the evolution going from 'Uncharted,' where we're really cutting our teeth on a realistic character-action game, third-person shooter, combined with emotional storytelling," Druckmann said. "With 'The Last of Us,' we added some RPG elements, we started playing with wide linear layouts. Continue that trajectory forward, add sci-fi, and you start to get the sense of what we're doing, and then we've gotten even more ambitious than that."</p><p>My money's on a deep, third-person, character-driven RPG with multiple open hubs to explore, and I hope I'm right.&nbsp;</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="f7393528-b494-418e-8cf0-d57045a99e67" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	






</article>
<p>When asked about Gabrielle's casting, Druckmann explains Naughty Dog had an idea of who protagonist Jordan is as a character, but via documents and backstories – scripts and gameplay come much later as the team wants the space to "run experiments and prototypes and then see what works, what doesn't work," and so on.&nbsp;</p><p>"We were kind of at that stage when we started talking to [Gabrielle]," Druckmann told <em>Variety</em>. "That came about because we had just cast her in Season 2 [of <em>The Last of Us</em>], and just got the idea that she might be perfect for this role. Then she showed up, she came by Naughty Dog, I pitched her the story as it was at the time, and we kind of walked through it beginning, middle, end, and explained what her role would be.</p><p>"I asked her if she'd be willing to audition, and she was. We had her on stage, and I asked Troy to come in and read with her, so she read against Troy Baker. We were just very confident that is our Jordan A. Mun."&nbsp;</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="73033c67-f366-4f8a-b7a2-64ef630f67a5" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	






</article>
<p>Druckmann says since then, he's been writing with Gabriella, something he did with Ellie actor Ashley Johnson and Baker when making The Last of Us. "[Gabrielle's] been just as influential in the writing and the thinking of this character, her arc, and I believe she's gonna be very iconic and complex and interesting in the Naughty Dog tradition.&nbsp;</p><p>Speaking of Baker, Druckmann says, "Troy is in the game, and it's been five years since I've worked with Troy, and I've got to do it again, and it was a lot of fun to be on stage with him again."</p>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="dceb4a97-5a6d-42d9-931b-5849e0b5cb19" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	






</article>
<p>The final piece of casting information from this interview is about Dalton. Druckmann says after working with him on Episode 206 of <em>The Last of Us </em>where he played Joel's dad, he DM'd him on Instagram to ask if he'd jump into a Zoom call to check out Intergalactic. "We jumped on a Zoom call, and I showed him parts of the game, and I talked to him about it," Druckmann said. "He's like, 'Yeah, I'm in. I'd love to do it.' So Tony Dalton is there, and maybe there's a few more [of actors from Season 1 or Season 2 of <em>The Last of Us</em>]."</p><p>Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet is due out on PlayStation 5, though there's no word on when to expect the game.&nbsp;</p><p>In the meantime, read <a href="https://gameinformer.com/exclusive/2025/03/26/naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-on-the-creative-process-behind-season-2-of-the"><em>Game Informer's </em>interview with Druckmann about creating Season 2 of <em>The Last of Us</em></a>.&nbsp;</p><p>[Source: <a href="https://variety.com/2025/gaming/news/neil-druckmann-last-of-us-exit-intergalactic-video-game-1236514453/"><em>Variety</em></a>]</p><hr><p><em>When do you think Intergalactic will launch? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/09/11/naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-discusses-intergalactic-gameplay-and-casting-in-new]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>