<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:59:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft reworks Xbox Game Pass and hikes price of Ultimate tier by 50 percent]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-reworks-xbox-game-pass-and-hikes-price-of-ultimate-tier-by-50-percent</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-reworks-xbox-game-pass-and-hikes-price-of-ultimate-tier-by-50-percent.1313827/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Microsoft is overhauling its Xbox Game Pass subscription service with the introduction of new tiers and pricing options.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Xbox Game Pass Essential, Premium, and Ultimate will replace&nbsp;Game Pass Core, Standard, and Ultimate, respectively.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Essential and Premium will remain the same price, but the cost of Ultimate will increase by 50 percent to $29.99/month from $19.99/month.&nbsp;Microsoft last increased the price for its Ultimate tier in 2024, when it raised the price to $19.99/month from $16.99/month.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">People who are already subscribed to Core and Standard subscriptions will be transferred over to Essential and Premium plans.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ultimate members will remain put, assuming they're happy with the price increase.&nbsp;Similarly, Microsoft's PC Game Pass subscription, which is designed for people who don’t play on consoles, will increase from $11.99 to $16.49,&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.theverge.com/news/789424/xbox-game-pass-premium-essentials-ultimate-price-increase-changes">according to The Verge</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Each reworked subscription tier will offer varying degrees of access to first and&nbsp;third-party titles. For instance, Essential subscribers will be granted access to more than 50 games playable on PC, console, and via the cloud. Premium users will be able to instantly access over 200 games and will be offered Xbox-published titles within one year of release.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ultimate members will be able to access over 75 "day one" games a year, including all Xbox-published titles. Their Xbox Game Pass catalog will comprise over 400 releases and will also include access to Ubisoft+ Classics and EA Play. Online console multiplayer is included in every tier.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/hasbro-opens-new-wizards-of-the-coast-development-hub-in-montreal" target="_self" data-discover="true">Hasbro opens new Wizards of the Coast development hub in Montreal</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Xbox Game Pass’ annual revenue&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-becomes-playstation-s-top-publisher-and-game-pass-revenue-nears-5-billion">totalled more than $5 billion during the 2024 fiscal year</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Microsoft’s Xbox hardware sales decreased by 25 percent year-over-year during that period.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In September,&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/console/xbox-series-x-to-cost-650-after-microsoft-raises-prices">Microsoft announced it was increasing the price of its Xbox Series X console</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;to $650 in the United States, up from $600. It's the second time the U.S. tech giant raised the price of console hardware in 2025.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Here's a full breakdown of the new Xbox Game Pass tiers:</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Xbox Game Pass Ultimate //&nbsp;</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Microsoft's biggest change to Xbox Game Pass is with its Ultimate tier, which got a 50 percent price increase to $29.99 per month. The company said it's the "most expansive upgrade yet," offering more than 400 games on PC, console, and via the cloud.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Microsoft said it guarantees 75 or more games coming to the service on release date. 45 new games were added on Wednesday. Likewise, Microsoft has rolled a&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fortnite</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;Crew subscription into Ultimate, which unlocks the&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fortnite</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;Battle Pass for no extra fee.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-and-tencent-launch-vantage-studios-to-expand-key-franchises" target="_self" data-discover="true">Ubisoft and Tencent officially launch new subsidiary Vantage Studios</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ubisoft+ Classics, which is roughly $16 a month on its own, is also part of the Ultimate subscription. Microsoft said its cloud gaming service will operate the best for Ultimate subscribers, with "best quality streaming and shortest wait times." Finally, Ultimate subscribers can earn points by playing games—up to $100 in points per year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Xbox Game Pass Premium //</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;Xbox Game Pass Premium is the new Xbox Game Pass Standard, and it's the same price. But Microsoft said subscribers will now have access to more games than before—with the plan bundling together over 200 games across console and PC. Premium subscribers will also&nbsp;receive&nbsp;"unlimited cloud gaming" and the ability to earn up to $50 per year with the rewards program.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Xbox Game Pass Essential //</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;What once was Xbox Game Pass Core is now Xbox Game Pass Essential. This tier includes "unlimited cloud gaming, online multiplayer, in-game benefits, and Rewards with Xbox, plus a curated catalog of 50+ games playable on both console and PC." With the rewards program, players can earn up to $25 worth of points per year. It's an increase from the advertised more than 25 games it previously offered.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>PC Game Pass //&nbsp;</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Microsoft didn't outline any changes to its PC Game Pass subscription in its blog post, but told The Verge subscribers will no longer be able to access Ubisoft+ Classic. Instead, they will granted access to "about 50 additional Ubisoft titles." The price is increasing from $11.99 to $16.49.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/teen-who-threatened-to-kill-epic-games-employees-pleads-guilty" target="_self" data-discover="true">Teen who threatened to kill Epic Games employees pleads guilty</a></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Columnist, Game Developer</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nicole Carpenter is a veteran reporter who has been covering the video game industry for over a decade.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-reworks-xbox-game-pass-and-hikes-price-of-ultimate-tier-by-50-percent]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>