<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 21:30:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Premium Metroid Prime Trilogy Art Book Is Launching Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-new-premium-metroid-prime-trilogy-art-book-is-launching-next-year/1100-6528042/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-new-premium-metroid-prime-trilogy-art-book-is-launching-next-year.1045056/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-new-premium-metroid-prime-trilogy-art-book-is-launching-next-year/1100-6528042/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528042">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">2025 is going to be a massive year for Metroid Prime. Not only is the long-awaited Metroid Prime 4: Beyond finally launching on Nintendo Switch, but now fans can look forward to a new, official art book covering the original trilogy from premium game-guide publisher Piggyback. Metroid Prime 1-3: A Visual Retrospective is a 212-page hardcover edition launching in Summer 2025.</p><p dir="ltr">According to <a href="https://www.piggyback.com/us/guide/metroid-prime-1-3-a-visual-retrospective" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Piggbyback's official announcement</a>, the publisher worked directly with Nintendo and Retro Studios to create Metroid Prime 1-3: A Visual Retrospective. The book will feature "concept drawings, sketches, and assorted illustrations" from the original Metroid Prime, Prime 2: Echoes, Prime 3: Corruption, and the recent Metroid Prime Remastered on Switch. The art is presented alongside "exclusive commentary from Nintendo producer Kensuke Tanabe, as well as the esteemed Retro Studios." Tanabe also contributed a foreword to the book and each section features written intros from Retro Studios staff. The hardcover book is printed on premium, sheet-fed art paper with stitch binding and etched metallic foil cover art featuring Samus Aran's iconic Varia suit.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4405390-mptrilogyartbook.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4405390" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4405390-mptrilogyartbook.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4405390"></a><figcaption>Metroid Prime 1-3: A Visual Retrospective</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1701/17013431/4405390-mptrilogyartbook.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The Official Art and Making of Metroid Prime 1-3 will launch for $50 sometime in Summer 2025. No preorders are available yet, but judging by Piggypack's previous book launches, we expect The Official Art and Making of Metroid Prime 1-3 will be on Amazon soon.</p><p dir="ltr">If Piggyback's other books are any indication, Metroid fans are in for a treat. Not only is it rare for Nintendo games to get this sort of behind-the-scenes examination, but Piggyback is behind some of the coolest game guides of the last several years, including the official guides for <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Complete-Official-Expanded/dp/1911015486?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1913330001?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tears of the Kingdom</a>--both of which are some of the coolest Zelda collector's items currently available. Other highlights include Piggyback's guides for <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Cyberpunk-2077-Complete-Official-Guide-Collectors/dp/1911015761?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Cyberpunk 2077</a> and the upcoming <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-getting-an-official-collectors-edition-strategy-guide/1100-6527284/" data-ref-id="1100-6527284">official Assassin's Creed Shadows</a>.</p><hr><h2 dir="ltr">More Video Game Book Deals</h2><p dir="ltr">For anyone curious about Piggyback's other work, several of the company's books are discounted at Amazon right now, including both Zelda guides. The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Complete-Official-Expanded/dp/1911015486?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Breath of the Wild Expanded Guide</a> is just $22.85 (was $45) and the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1913330001?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tears of the Kingdom Collector's Edition Guide</a> is $26.85 (was $45). Both include unique cover art and lots of collectible materials. The Zelda guides are also part of <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/promotion/psp/A26JXL22CUZ9JT?ref=psp_pc_cart_collapse&amp;tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon's Buy Two Get One promotion on books</a></strong>, and if you're looking for more Zelda material to round out the B2G1 deal, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Encyclopedia-Nintendo/dp/150670638X?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda Encyclopedia</a> is eligible for the deal and available for $20.60 (was $40). Piggyback's <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Cyberpunk-2077-Complete-Official-Guide-Collectors/dp/1911015761?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Cyberpunk 2077 Collector's Edition Guide</a> is also part of the B2G1 sale and discounted to $22 (was $40).</p><p dir="ltr">There are several more <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/black-friday/">Black Friday deals</a> on gaming books available at Amazon. While they're not part of the B2G1 deal, the Dark Horse-published Zelda lore books are all roughly 50% off right now, including <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Hyrule-Historia/dp/1616550414?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hyrule Historia</a> for $23.60 (was $40) and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Breath-Wild-Creating-Champion/dp/1506710115?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Creating a Champion Hero's Edition</a> for $59.50 (was $110). You can also grab Nintendo's official <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Encyclopedia-Deluxe/dp/1506707408?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda Encyclopedia Deluxe Edition</a> for $48 (was $90). You'll find a list of more Zelda book deals below.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Cyberpunk-2077-Complete-Official-Guide-Collectors/dp/1911015761?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Cyberpunk 2077 Collector's Edition Guide</a> -- $20.60 (<del>$40</del>) <strong>B2G1</strong></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1913330001?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom Collector's Edition Guide</a> -- $26.85 (<del>$45</del>) <strong>B2G1</strong></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Complete-Official-Expanded/dp/1911015486?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Zelda: Breath of the Wild Expanded Guide</a> -- $22.26 (<del>$40</del>) <strong>B2G1</strong></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Encyclopedia-Nintendo/dp/150670638X?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda Encyclopedia</a> -- $20.60 (<del>$40</del>) <strong>B2G1</strong></li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Art-Artifacts/dp/1506703356?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda: Arts &amp; Artifacts</a> -- $18.31 (<del>$50</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Breath-Wild-Creating-Champion/dp/1506710115?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda: Creating A Champion Hero's Edition</a> -- $59.50 (<del>$110</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Hyrule-Historia/dp/1616550414?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda: Hyrule Historia</a> -- $23.60 (<del>$40</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Legend-Zelda-Encyclopedia-Deluxe/dp/1506707408?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Legend of Zelda Encyclopedia Deluxe Edition</a> -- $48 (<del>$90</del>)</li></ul><hr><h2>More Metroid Deals</h2><p>Lastly, for anyone who wants to check out Samus' most recent adventure, you can pick up <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FMetroid-Dread-Nintendo-Switch-Standard-Edition%2F805085338%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fa-new-premium-metroid-prime-trilogy-art-book-is-launching-next-year%2F1100-6528042%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Metroid Dread</a> for $47 (was $60) in Walmart's big Black Friday Nintendo sale. You can pair that with a deal on the<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Nintendo-Metroid-Dread-amiibo-2-Pack-Switch/dp/B0979ZHC5B?tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"> Metroid Dread Amiibo Two-Pack</a> that includes Samus and the E.M.M.I. Amiibo figures at Amazon. Amazon also has a bunch of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?k=metroid&amp;i=black-friday&amp;crid=1PS3LQF6TC1QH&amp;sprefix=metroid%2Cblack-friday%2C96&amp;ref=nb_sb_noss_1&amp;tag=gamespot-bfcm-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">awesome Metroid apparel on sale</a>, too.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-dark-souls-board-game-for-only-51-and-roleplaying-sourcebook-for-30/1100-6527696/">Get Dark Souls Board Game For Only $51 And Roleplaying Sourcebook For $30</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-disc-drive-is-sold-out-at-most-retailers-but-walmart-has-it-for-now/1100-6526391/">PS5 Pro Disc Drive Is Sold Out At Most Retailers, But Walmart Has It (For Now)</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-preorders-live-at-amazon-walmart-and-best-buy/1100-6526406/">The PS5 Pro Is Available Now And Eligible For One-Day Delivery At Amazon</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-is-on-sale-for-a-great-price/1100-6527148/">Zelda: Echoes Of Wisdom Is Already On Sale For 25% Off</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-collectors-edition-preorders-available-ahead-of-this-weeks-launch/1100-6525830/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard Collector's Edition In Stock On Launch Day For PS5 And Xbox</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/special-edition-lord-of-the-rings-trilogy-4k-gift-set-releases-this-holiday-preorders-live-at-amazon/1100-6527414/">Lord Of The Rings 4K Gift Set Releases This Holiday, Comes With One Ring Collectible</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/build-shadow-the-hedgehogs-head-out-of-720-lego-bricks-for-only-56/1100-6525229/">Target's Exclusive Shadow The Hedgehog Lego Set Is Discounted Just Weeks After Its Release</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/king-boos-haunted-mansion-lego-mario-set-gets-first-price-cut-at-amazon/1100-6525381/">King Boo's Haunted Mansion Lego Mario Set Gets First Price Cut At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/104300651635509044736?rel=author">Brendan Hesse</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sniper Elite: Resistance Is Like A Welcome Serving Of Comfort Food]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sniper-elite-resistance-is-like-a-welcome-serving-of-comfort-food/1100-6528045/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sniper-elite-resistance-is-like-a-welcome-serving-of-comfort-food.1045011/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sniper-elite-resistance-is-like-a-welcome-serving-of-comfort-food/1100-6528045/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528045">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">I often think about the era when Grand Theft Auto games were coming out almost every year rather than once a decade or so. In those off years, there were a lot of games that tried to fill the void for players wanting an open-world crime-drama game: True Crime, Saints Row, Mafia, Scarface, Crackdown--the list goes on. Presumably, no one making these games thought they would dethrone Rockstar. Still, they understood they could capitalize on the genre's popularity by giving players a new lookalike while Rockstar was busy cooking up the next GTA. Since 2017's Sniper Elite 4, I've viewed the Sniper Elite series as something similar, only in this case, the series it's filling in for is Hitman. Rebellion's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/sniper-elite-resistance/" data-ref-id="5000-640579">Sniper Elite: Resistance</a> won't outdo IO Interactive's incredible Hitman series, and it doesn't even seem to do much differently compared to the last few games in its own series, but if you've enjoyed this sort of game before and are eager for another one, Sniper Elite: Resistance looks to be a reliable proxy.</p><p dir="ltr">I recently played about 90 minutes of the game's third mission before its debut in January on PC, PlayStation, and Xbox Series X|S, when it will also be a day-one Game Pass launch. Even as I strained to find much in the way of new experiences, I had a fun time. That suggests that this sixth game in the series, and the first since 2022, is roughly as enjoyable as the last couple of entries--at least from what I've seen so far.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4405385-ser_announcement_09_fort_c_sights.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4405385" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4405385-ser_announcement_09_fort_c_sights.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4405385"></a><figcaption>Pictured: politics in games</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4405385-ser_announcement_09_fort_c_sights.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Like Hitman, levels are huge and open-ended regarding where you can go and how you can complete your objectives when you get there. In recent sequels, Rebellion has built in more creative kills reminiscent of Agent 47's handiwork, such as hiding a grenade in wrapping paper for a target to unwrap, or killing Hitler with a bowling pin. Each mission includes a main objective and several optional objectives of a few different kinds. There are intel collectibles you can gather, ally hideouts to locate, things like enemy weapons depots to blow up, and usually a high-value target to snuff out, too.</p><p dir="ltr">The sandbox-style fun of it all is deciding how you do that, whether it's by sneaking past everyone and exfiltrating before anyone knew you were there, or going loud and aiming for the groins of every Nazi who comes into view of your scope. Some players will prefer to mainline the campaign, but I've long found Sniper Elite to be one of the better series at enticing me to clear each map of all its different mission markers, and as a stealth experience especially, I've always enjoyed the challenges they put in front of me.</p><p dir="ltr">Even with just 90 minutes to play the preview build of the game, I couldn't help but investigate every optional objective I came across. Once, when I was nearing the end of a main objective, I'd suddenly realized what I'd overlooked when seeking a secret ally hideout about an hour earlier in the level, so I ditched the elaborate Nazi mansion I was sneaking through, trekked all the way back to an earlier section past the dead fascists I'd left in my wake, to climb the side of a building using the drain pipe and some ledges so I could finally check that side quest off my list. Sniper Elite gives you a vast playground to explore, offers many viable routes through it, and doesn't punish you for handling it all in the order and manner of your choosing. In a world without Agent 47 for the foreseeable future, I'll gladly accept this Historical Hitman in his absence.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4405386-ser_screenshots_releasedate_prologuealps_21b-%281%29.png" data-ref-id="1300-4405386" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4405386-ser_screenshots_releasedate_prologuealps_21b-%281%29.png" data-ref-id="1300-4405386"></a><figcaption>Sniper Elite's sharpshooting gameplay run deep, but its best attribute is its sprawling levels.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4405386-ser_screenshots_releasedate_prologuealps_21b-%281%29.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">I've played all of these games, and though the next one to really blow me away would also be the first one, none have been bad. The studio seems to think better of its signature X-ray bullet cam than I do--in Sniper Elite 5, I eventually turned it off so it wouldn't keep slowing down my missions--but I'm still otherwise very much into the format of these games. Both level to level and game to game, they become a kind of even-keeled comfort-food experience.</p><p dir="ltr">Like cooking your favorite meal for the fourth time in a week, you know what you're getting with Sniper Elite. It may not dazzle you with new flavors that have never graced your tongue, but it's a reliable go-to when you don't know what to make for dinner that night. I don't mean to damn the game with faint praise; I sincerely enjoy these games and gladly try a new one every few years at their current pace.</p><p dir="ltr">That's not to say this sequel is totally void of new experiences. The broad strokes are certainly very familiar, but one aspect Rebellion is adding--which I didn't get to see in my time with the game so far--are Propaganda missions, which cast players as "resistance fighters," giving the game's massive levels more replayability in the form of new objectives on subsequent playthroughs.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4405389-ser_screenshots_releasedate_prologuealps_16.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4405389" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="7680" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4405389-ser_screenshots_releasedate_prologuealps_16.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4405389"></a><figcaption>The slow-motion X-ray camera isn't a selling point for me after so many entries, but the mechanics around it remain satisfying.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1632/16320660/4405389-ser_screenshots_releasedate_prologuealps_16.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">This will also be the first game in the series to cast a hero other than Karl Fairburne, the square-jawed alpha American, as the playable protagonist. Instead, it turns to Harry Hawker, a British soldier who has been in past games, but usually as the backup character for those playing the campaign in co-op. That will give this chapter in the story a different voice, but the lack of a number in this game's title and the fact that Hawker's story takes place at the same time as Fairburne's in Sniper Elite 5 also suggest this is overtly a continuation of what worked well before. Rebellion is keeping things in France for now rather than moving the series to a new country like sequels in this series have tended to. If Sniper Elite is the comfort food series, Resistance is like enjoying a second plate of what you scarfed down earlier. If you're still hungry, eat up.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Now Has Wallrunning, Thanks To A Fan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-now-has-wallrunning-thanks-to-a-fan/1100-6528038/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-now-has-wallrunning-thanks-to-a-fan.1045008/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-now-has-wallrunning-thanks-to-a-fan/1100-6528038/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528038">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The biggest goal Epic Games has with Fortnite Creative is to transform Fortnite into a platform for games that share little to no resemblance with its core battle royale mode. Independent creators--while perhaps still a long ways off from making Creative's breakout game--have started to do just that.</p><p>Creator duuk has built a 10-player free-for-all <a href="https://fortnite.gg/island?code=9756-5951-6748" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fortnite Creative map</a> that replicates the beloved wallrunning mechanic of other first-person shooters such as the Titanfall series. The 19-year-old, Netherlands-based creator is one of the first to implement this type of mechanic in Fortnite Creative.</p><p>You can find the map by searching in the Discover tab with the following code: 9756-5951-6748.</p><p>Players are immediately shifted to a first-person point of view once they load into the map. They have the ability to practice the wallrunning mechanic in a small training area before loading into the full map, which resembles a warehouse lot.</p><p>The mechanic feels nowhere near as smooth or responsive as it does in games like Titanfall 2 and Call of Duty: Black Ops 3, although it's still an interesting experience to combine the wallrunning with other Fortnite mechanics like mantling and items like shockwave grenades.</p><p>Wallrunning has been rumored as an upcoming mechanic for Fortnite's battle royale mode for at least a year, as YouTube and TikTok videos have hinted that future chapters and seasons would include it to complement the mantling and climbing system. Despite the rumors, no wallrunning feature has ever been officially mentioned by Epic Games.</p><p>Movement has been one of Fortnite's most-enjoyable features as the battle royale development team has continued to iterate and build on the game's traversal mechanics with special items that give players incredible abilities. Players have been bounced off the ground with the Shockwave Hammer, dashed through the sky with the Kinetic Blade, and soared above the clouds Iron-Man gauntlets over previous seasons.</p><p>The base movement system within Fortnite's third-person mode has evolved over the course of the game's five chapters (<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/fortnite-chapter-6-start-date-battle-pass-skins-and-everything-else-to-know/2900-5955/" data-ref-id="2900-5955">Fortnite Chapter 6</a> launches soon). Previous updates have added and refined sprinting, mantling, climbing, and sliding mechanics that have transformed the shooter into something that looks nothing like the survival game that Fortnite originally launched as in 2017.</p><p>Many of the features found in the battle royale mode can be used by players in Creative, although copyright restrictions prevent things like the Spider-Man gauntlets from making the crossover without receiving a generic rebranding.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15957481/4405376-img_6014.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4405376" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15957481/4405376-img_6014.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4405376"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15957481/4405376-img_6014.jpg"></figure><p>We haven't seen many fluid movement mechanics in Creative, but players are beginning to push that boundary as well. This map is duuk's first full release, as they put it, within the Fortnite Creative ecosystem. Mechanics and game types tend to spread like wildfire in Creative if a map featuring them gets popular. It's too early to tell now, but both duuk and other creators could continue to refine wallrunning in future maps and updates.</p><p>Although wallrunning is the signature feature of duuk's map, it also distinguishes itself from the standard Fortnite experience through the aforementioned first-person perspective. While a first-person mode has been teased for battle royale in the past, an experimental mode only came to Creative users in <a href="https://create.fortnite.com/news/fortnite-first-person-now-available-as-an-experimental-feature-in-uefn-and-creative?team=personal" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">October 2024</a>. The feature, as the experimental tag would suggest, is still in its early stages and does not include all weapons, use cases, and player features that Fortnite' standard third-person mode includes.</p><p>Fortnite Creative has been slowly evolving since Epic Games announced a new way to create with Unreal Editor for Fortnite, which expands creator tools through further integration with Unreal Engine. The ability to use different camera angles, including a top-down view, give creators an opportunity to build experiences that feel completely different from the battle royale mode. Wallrunning is a beloved game mechanic thanks to many shooters that have come before--these creators are adding to a short chapter to its history with this Creative map.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Studio Went From Losing Money To A Huge Profit In One Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-studio-went-from-losing-money-to-a-huge-profit-in-one-year/1100-6528040/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-studio-went-from-losing-money-to-a-huge-profit-in-one-year.1045002/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-studio-went-from-losing-money-to-a-huge-profit-in-one-year/1100-6528040/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528040">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">It's no secret that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/baldurs-gate-3/">Baldur's Gate 3</a> has been a massive success for Larian Studios. It won Game Of The Year at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-game-awards-2023-winners-revealed/2900-4977/">2023's The Game Awards</a>, and over a year after its initial launch, Larian is still pushing out game updates and gaining fans all over the globe (<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-mods-help-player-numbers-grow-and-someone-in-the-vatican-just-bought-a-copy/1100-6527834/">including in the Vatican</a>). But a recent report from the <a href="https://www.independent.ie/business/irish/dublin-firm-behind-baldurs-gate-game-posts-249m-profit-after-runaway-success/a2033961431.html" rel="nofollow ">Irish Independent</a> has revealed that the game wasn't just a hit with players--it was also a massive financial success, raking in roughly $260 million in profits in 2023.</p><p dir="ltr">According to the figures shared by the Independent, Larian earned a total of $466 million in revenue in 2023, nearly 20 times what the studio earned in 2022. The massive success of Baldur's Gate 3 clearly had a major hand in the studio's financial success, and although Larian has yet to release the game's sales numbers, the Independent cites 15 million copies sold. 2023 marked a major change for the studio, which was operating at a $223,000 loss in 2022.</p><p dir="ltr">Part of the game's success is likely due to its sheer level of replayability. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-players-have-collectively-downloaded-over-50-million-mods/1100-6527513/" data-ref-id="1100-6527513">Players can mod the game</a> to their heart's content (<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/larian-rolls-out-baldurs-gate-3-mod-limitations-for-console-players/1100-6528031/" data-ref-id="1100-6528031">even on console</a>) and play through the story as their own original player-character, or step into the shoes of the game's companions and play as one of them. For those looking to wreak havoc on Faerûn, there's the Dark Urge character origin option, and players who wish to bring others into their adventures can make use of the game's robust online multiplayer mode or split-screen couch co-op, all for a single $70 purchase. No microtransactions, no DLC, and seemingly infinite content might explain why the game now sees <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/baldurs-gate/baldurs-gate-3-defies-the-laws-of-physics-by-being-a-single-player-rpg-with-more-daily-users-in-2024-than-its-release-year/" rel="nofollow ">more daily users in 2024 than it did in 2023</a>--an <em>extremely</em> rare occurrence when it comes to single-player RPGs.</p><p dir="ltr">As for the future, Larian CEO Swen Vincke says the studio has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/larian-isnt-making-baldurs-gate-4-next-thats-not-what-we-were-made-for/1100-6522049/">no current plans to start work on Baldur's Gate 4</a> (for now), but the team behind the best RPG of 2023 is currently laying the groundwork for a new that Vincke says he hopes will take players by surprise <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-is-working-toward-an-rpg-that-dwarfs-it/1100-6522051/">and "dwarf" Baldur's Gate 3</a> by comparison.</p><p>"Hopefully nobody's going to leak it for us, but it's different than what you think it is," Vincke <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-teases-next-game-and-discusses-decision-to-not-make-baldurs-gate-4/1100-6522165/">said of the untitled RPG</a>. "But it is still familiar enough for you to recognize that it's something that we are making."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mass Effect Veteran's New Studio, Which Was Making AAA Sci-Fi Game, Is Shutting Down]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mass-effect-veterans-new-studio-which-was-making-aaa-sci-fi-game-is-shutting-down/1100-6528039/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mass-effect-veterans-new-studio-which-was-making-aaa-sci-fi-game-is-shutting-down.1044999/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mass-effect-veterans-new-studio-which-was-making-aaa-sci-fi-game-is-shutting-down/1100-6528039/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528039">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Humanoid Origin, a new studio founded by Mass Effect veteran Casey Hudson, is closing up shop. The studio <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/humanoid-origin_earlier-today-we-informed-our-staff-that-activity-7266889657370447874-9uwE/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">announced on LinkedIn</a> that it is closing down due to an "unexpected shortfall of funding."</p><p>The statement said the studio is "heartbroken" that it won't be able to launch its new sci-fi game, but its main concern is supporting staffers as they find new jobs. "In our time together, the team achieved incredible progress, and demonstrated that it's possible to do amazing work while fostering a culture of fun and creativity," the statement said. "We thank them for their talent, courage, and friendship. Thank you to everyone who supported us throughout our journey."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4405383-screenshot2024-11-25at2.24.15pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4405383" data-ratio="0.61475409836066" data-width="976" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4405383-screenshot2024-11-25at2.24.15pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4405383"></a><figcaption>A piece of concept art for Humanoid's sci-fi game.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4405383-screenshot2024-11-25at2.24.15pm.png"></figure><p>Humanoid Origin was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bioware-veteran-casey-hudson-launches-studio-working-on-new-ip/1100-6493385/" data-ref-id="1100-6493385">announced in 2021</a> and had been working on the previously described sci-fi game that was labeled as <a href="https://x.com/HumanoidOrigin/status/1757155294860243383" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">"an incredible AAA IP unlike anything else."</a> The studio was based in Canada and had offices in Edmonton, Alberta, and Kelowna, in addition to working with remote staff.</p><p>Hudson worked at BioWare for 16 years from 1998-2014, and was best known for his work on the Mass Effect series. He joined Xbox in 2015 and worked on the company's mixed-reality devices before returning to BioWare in 2017 to become its general manager. He left BioWare again in 2020 before starting Humanoid in 2021. It remains to be seen what he could do next.</p><p>As for BioWare, the team just launched Dragon Age: The Veilguard in October. The team is not making any DLC or expansions and is now <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-not-getting-expansions-team-shifts-to-next-mass-effect/1100-6527554/" data-ref-id="1100-6527554">shifting to the next Mass Effect game</a>, which is being made by a group of series veterans (but not Hudson).</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>