<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 16:08:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flashbulb Games confirms layoffs after scrapping unannounced project]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/flashbulb-games-confirms-layoffs-after-scrapping-unannounced-project</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/flashbulb-games-confirms-layoffs-after-scrapping-unannounced-project.1062510/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/flashbulb-games-confirms-layoffs-after-scrapping-unannounced-project<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Trailmakers</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Flashbulb Games has laid off seven employees.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Danish studio confirmed the news in a statement to Game Developer and said the job cuts were made after it halted development on an unannounced project.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"While this was a tough decision, the majority of the team previously working on that project has been reassigned to Trailmakers, our flagship game," said studio CEO Christopher Håkonsson. "We see great potential in Trailmakers and are excited to accelerate its development and deliver even more for our players and community."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Flashbulb was formed in 2016 by developers from CCP, Rare, IO Interactive, and Press Play. It launched vehicle-building sandbox </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Trailmakers</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in September 2019 and continues to support the title. The studio's sophomore title, multiplayer party brawler </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Rubber Bandits</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, launched in 2021.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The deluge of layoffs and studio closures that has defined 2024 looks set to continue until the bitter end.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Major players like EA, Sony, Microsoft, Take-Two, Embracer, Unity, and more have </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/keyword/layoffs">collectively laid off thousands of people</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> since the turn of the year, leaving workers scrambling for security and certainty in an industry that looks more unstable than ever.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>