<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:54:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Invincible VS Roster Adds Viltrumites Anissa And Lucan]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/26/invincible-vs-roster-adds-viltrumites-anissa-and-lucan</link>
            <guid>1416868</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><a href="https://gameinformer.com/2025/06/08/invincible-vs-is-a-3v3-fighting-game-based-on-the-popular-series">Invincible VS</a>’ roster of playable Viltrumites has expanded with the additions of Anissa and Lucan. Acting as the game's 12th and 13th characters, the pair bring even more brutality to an already hyperviolent tag team fighter.</p><p>Like fellow Viltrumites Omni-Man and Thula, Anissa and Lucan are powerhouses whose immense strength is matched only by their ferocity. Both pummel opponents in their own unique and referential ways, from Anissa “educating” adversaries by slapping them senseless or Lucan breaking spines over his knee like an extraterrestrial Bane. Check them out in action in the trailer below.&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yZbexxHip4w"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yZbexxHip4w" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Anissa and Lucan join an announced roster of Invincible, Omni-Man, Atom Eve, Rex Splode, Monster Girl, Robot, Battle Beast, Thula, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/preview/2025/10/09/cecil-joins-the-roster-new-story-details-and-an-original-character-arrives">Cecil Stedman</a>, Bulletproof, and original character <a href="https://gameinformer.com/the-game-awards-2025/2025/12/15/invincible-vs-gets-april-release-date-alongside-ella-mental">Ella Mental</a>. With a confirmed roster of 18 characters, only five slots remain open; who do you think will fill them?</p><p>Invincible VS will launch on April 30 for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC. You can learn more about the game by reading&nbsp;our first preview of the game from last June <a href="https://gameinformer.com/preview/2025/06/10/a-faithfully-bloody-adaptation">here</a>.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/26/invincible-vs-roster-adds-viltrumites-anissa-and-lucan]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>