<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 22:45:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows Will "Dramatically" Alter How It Plays Based On Your Character And Weapons]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-will-dramatically-alter-how-it-plays-based-on-your-character-and-weapons/1100-6528362/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-will-dramatically-alter-how-it-plays-based-on-your-character-and-weapons.1057380/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-will-dramatically-alter-how-it-plays-based-on-your-character-and-weapons/1100-6528362/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528362">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-release-date-gameplay-and-everything-we-know/1100-6523576/" data-ref-id="1100-6523576">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a> will bring players to feudal Japan when the game arrives early next year. As you might expect, swords and knives will be a big part of the arsenal for Shadows' two main characters, Naoe and Yasuke. However, neither character will be solely reliant on their primary weapons to dish out death.</p><p>Ubisoft has shared <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/assassins-creed/news/1zutGco21KjZ5PUe6EYnpf" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a lengthy overview of combat</a> in Assassin's Creed Shadows, which also reveals the tools that the lead characters will use in battle. According to Ubisoft, players' choice of weapons and characters "dramatically alters combat" in this game. The first character, Naoe, is a shinobi/ninja, and she'll have a katana, a ball-and-chain weapon known as a kusarigama, and a tanto dagger that allows her to make quick strikes and double assassinations.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CaUaOUUQ8JM" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CaUaOUUQ8JM" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The samurai Yasuke has a larger arsenal to work with, including a long katana, a naginata [a staff with a blade attached to the end], a kanabo (a spiked war club), a yumi bow, and a teppo flint rifle. Unlike Naoe, Yasuke can also switch between weapons mid-combo for some devastating attacks.</p><p>Yasuke's weapons and strength make him well-suited for head-on combat, while Naoe's speed and stealth make her ideal for more subtle assassinations or missions. Each character has their own light or heavy attacks, in addition to the ability to charge their offensive moves which the game calls posture attacks. Defense is also a key component of the combat, as certain techniques by Naoe and Yasuke can wear down an enemy's guard and leave them vulnerable to a counterstrike.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dfHbUiwF958" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dfHbUiwF958" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Ubisoft also listed some of the most common enemies in the game:</p><ul><li>Outlaws</li><li>Ashigaru soldiers</li><li>Ronin</li><li>Samurai</li><li>Samurai Daisho</li><li>Guardians</li></ul><p>Each of those enemies has their own strengths and weaknesses, and some are going to be easier to defeat than others. The notes indicate that the Samurai Daisho are among the deadliest enemies in the game, but the rewards for their defeat are said to be worth it.</p><p>Assassin's Creed Shadows was delayed to February 14, 2025 <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-until-early-2025/1100-6526703/" data-ref-id="1100-6526703">earlier this fall</a>. It will <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-will-introduce-a-new-direction-for-its-modern-day-story/1100-6527555/">introduce a new direction</a> for the storyline set in modern times. Details about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-battle-pass-allegedly-leaks-showing-off-futuristic-and-mythological-cosmetics/1100-6527789/" data-ref-id="1100-6527789">the game's battle pass</a> recently leaked online, and Ubisoft has stated that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-clarifies-rumors-about-animus-hub-the-new-name-of-assassins-creed-infinity/1100-6527804/" data-ref-id="1100-6527804">the rewards in the Animus Hub are free</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Can Now Check Out Your PlayStation 2024 Wrap-Up]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/you-can-now-check-out-your-playstation-2024-wrap-up/1100-6528359/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-now-check-out-your-playstation-2024-wrap-up.1057287/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/you-can-now-check-out-your-playstation-2024-wrap-up/1100-6528359/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528359">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>PlayStation has revealed the <a href="https://wrapup.playstation.com/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PlayStation 2024 Wrap-Up</a>, a tool that provides a summary of your year on PS4 and PS5. This year, the Wrap-Up features a retro aesthetic to celebrate <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/12/10/celebrate-30-years-of-playstation-with-playstation-2024-wrap-up-launching-today/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PlayStation's 30th anniversary</a>.</p><p>PlayStation 2024 Wrap-Up will continue to update and track your profile through the end of December, until it goes away on January 10. The Wrap-Up will show your various stats such as most games played, monthly gaming stats, habits, and more.</p><p>It'll also show you what year your profile was made, as well as other historical statistics. These include the total number of games you've played since the creation of your PSN account and the number of trophies you've earned.</p><p>Those who complete the PlayStation 2024 Wrap-Up experience can redeem a 30th anniversary-inspired avatar and PlayStation Stars digital collectible. </p><p>PlayStation also released a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OPnsdExnfEM" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">trailer to show off upcoming PS5 games in 2025</a>, which include ones like Death Stranding 2: On the Beach and Ghost of Yotei. At the beginning of 2024, PlayStation <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/no-major-sony-franchise-game-releases-are-coming-until-april-2025-at-earliest/1100-6521071/" data-ref-id="1100-6521071">confirmed that no major AAA first-party games</a> would be released until April 2025 at the earliest.</p><p>You can also check out your <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-year-in-review-2024-unlocked-shows-your-most-played-game-and-busiest-month/1100-6528235/" data-ref-id="1100-6528235">Xbox Year in review 2024 as well</a>. Nintendo <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/see-whether-you-played-zelda-or-mario-more-with-nintendos-switch-year-in-review-website/1100-6519927/" data-ref-id="1100-6519927">had its own in 2023</a>, and it's possible that there will be one for this year too.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA Online's Agents Of Sabotage Update Is Free, Full Of New Features, And Available Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-onlines-agents-of-sabotage-update-is-free-full-of-new-features-and-available-now/1100-6528361/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-onlines-agents-of-sabotage-update-is-free-full-of-new-features-and-available-now.1057284/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-onlines-agents-of-sabotage-update-is-free-full-of-new-features-and-available-now/1100-6528361/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528361">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/grand-theft-auto-online/">GTA Online</a>'s enormous new Agents of Sabotage expansion is now live, and is available to play for free. First <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-online-debuts-trailer-and-release-date-for-next-expansion/1100-6528201/">unveiled in early December</a>, Agents of Sabotage brings loads of content to the table, including a new property for purchase called The Darnell Bros Garment Factory, new missions, and of course, new wheels.</p><p dir="ltr">"After purchasing the legendary Darnell Bros Garment Factory, players will head underground to take on Los Santos’ super-rich and the military-industrial complex in a series of multi-part high-stakes scores employing the latest clandestine technology," Rockstar said of the expansion's plotline.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1752/17528202/4413279-gtaonline.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4413279" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1752/17528202/4413279-gtaonline.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4413279"></a><figcaption>This update is sure to bring out your inner sneak-thief.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1752/17528202/4413279-gtaonline.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">In addition to the new factory, the Agents of Sabotage expansion also includes the following features:</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Brand-new property:</strong> Players can purchase The Darnell Bros Garment Factory, but what's in the factory is the real treat. It's equipped with a Mk. 2 Weapon Workshop, Personal Quarters, a safe for passive income, 10 storage slots for player vehicles, and a garage with a basement that provides access to the Los Santos' underground tunnels, allowing players who own the factory to travel to and from different areas with ease.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>The FIB Files:</strong> The FIB Files include four new multi-stage missions for players to complete in return for rewards. Tasks include downing an IAA-protected aircraft, lifting military tech from Fort Zancudo, recovering a missing piece of art (without being seen), and accessing Maze Bank’s secret slush fund.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>New Dispatch Work: </strong>Agents of Sabotage introduces two new Dispatch Work missions, which see players lending a hand to Vincent Effenburger of the Los Santos Police Department.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>New Benefactor Terrorbyte Upgrades: </strong>The Terrorbyte's upgrades include a Collectible Scanner (for the collectible-hunter in all of us), a Master Control Terminal (to keep track of players' business stock, supplies, vehicle storage, and cargo), a Missile Lock-On Jammer (preventing enemies from locking on), and Silent Running mode (which hides the vehicle's radar blip).</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>New Wheels</strong>: Several new vehicles have been added to the game, including the Banshee GTS (which is free to claim for GTA+ Members through January 8), the Chavos V6, the Dinka Jester RR Widebody, and law enforcement versions of the Canis Terminus Patrol and Vapid Caracara Pursuit.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>The Heist Challenge rewards:</strong> Players who completed an eligible Heist Finale from November 7 - December 4 will earn the NOOSE Outfit. Meanwhile, the Police Predator boat is available to claim (via Warstock) by all players until December 15.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Quality-of-life improvements:</strong> Payouts for Drift and Drag Races have been improved, and will now automatically grant Body Armor when launching (and relaunching) missions. Additionally, players can now toggle through siren options when driving law-enforcement vehicles.</p><p dir="ltr">According to Rockstar, there's more new content heading to GTA Online in the near future. Upcoming features include holiday events, new Stunt Races celebrating the Lunar New Year, new Drift Races, the new El Strickler Military Rifle (PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S players only), and additional Transform Race tools for the Rockstar Creator.</p><p>GTA Online's free Agents of Sabotage expansion is available now on PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, and PC. For more info on the Agents of Sabotage update, check out <a href="https://www.rockstargames.com/newswire/article/399a19ka9935ok/gta-online-agents-of-sabotage-now-available">Rockstar's website</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>