<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 16:37:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Black Ops 6 And Warzone Season 2 Trailer Reveals Brand-New Maps, Dual Katanas, And Zombies Staffs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-trailer-reveals-brand-new-maps-dual-katanas-and-zombies-staffs/1100-6528938/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-trailer-reveals-brand-new-maps-dual-katanas-and-zombies-staffs.1088736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-trailer-reveals-brand-new-maps-dual-katanas-and-zombies-staffs/1100-6528938/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528938">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Season 2 arrives in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/" data-ref-id="5000-630093">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone/" data-ref-id="5000-572198">Warzone</a> on January 28. Activision has revealed the season's new gameplay trailer, which features new multiplayer maps, more DLC weapons, and operator skins. The trailer also gives a first look at gameplay and Wonder Weapons for the upcoming Zombies map.</p><p dir="ltr">While most of the post-launch content for Black Ops 6 has forgotten about the game's '90s setting, the Season 2 trailer includes a remixed version of Bush's 1996 hit "Machinehead." Season 2 is themed around ninja-esque operators who are dual-wielding katanas, as seen in the trailer below.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SXpnKJBhL48" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/SXpnKJBhL48" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">One of the multiplayer maps shows gameplay inside a car dealership, which is simply called Dealership. Another multiplayer map features a super-yacht that looks similar to the Hijacked map from Black Ops 2, but this is apparently a new yacht map called Lifeline. A third map is called Bounty, but we don't get to see much of the setting. These three maps will arrive at launch, while two additional maps will drop during the midseason.</p><p dir="ltr">Zombies footage is also featured near the end of the trailer, giving the first look at gameplay on The Tomb map. It also reveals the map's unique Wonder Weapons, which are four staffs similar to the ones used on the fan-favorite Origins map from Black Ops 2.</p><p dir="ltr">Additionally, Activision shared the new <a href="https://x.com/CallofDuty/status/1881754960213512314" rel="nofollow ">promotional art for Season 2</a>, which reveals the katanas, PPSh-41 submachine gun, and FAL rifle as the new weapons in the game.</p><p>Season 2 will bring several game improvements, including the ability to turn off cross-play in Ranked Play modes. Here is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-start-date-and-details/1100-6528774/">everything rumored and announced for Season 2</a> so far.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2 Crosses New Development Milestone As Deadpool Actor Finishes Scenes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/death-stranding-2-crosses-new-development-milestone-as-deadpool-actor-finishes-scenes/1100-6528937/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2-crosses-new-development-milestone-as-deadpool-actor-finishes-scenes.1088715/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/death-stranding-2-crosses-new-development-milestone-as-deadpool-actor-finishes-scenes/1100-6528937/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528937">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/death-stranding-2-story-theories-and-everything-we-know/1100-6516214/" data-ref-id="1100-6516214">Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</a> remains in development and has crossed a milestone. Hideo Kojima has announced that Deadpool actor Shioli Kutsuna, who plays Yukio in the Marvel series, has finished her scenes for the game.</p><p>"Thank you so much for your hard work! Despite the challenges of the pandemic, she handled 3D scanning, performance capture in LA, and both English ADR and Japanese voice recording across various locations. Great job, and much appreciated!" <a href="https://x.com/HIDEO_KOJIMA_EN/status/1881681423893238052" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kojima said</a> (<a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/open-world/death-stranding-2-actors-are-finishing-filming-and-getting-gifts-from-hideo-kojima-but-the-game-still-remains-in-development-so-dont-expect-it-out-any-time-soon/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">via GamesRadar</a>).</p><p>Actors Yasuyuki Kase and Yasuki Kase also finished their scenes, and Kojima thanked them as well. He also presented both Kase and Kutsuna with flowers, as you can see in the image below. While some actors have concluded their work on the game, that doesn't mean the game is done. "The game remains in development," Kojima said.</p><p>Death Stranding 2 also features Norman Reedus, Troy Baker, and Lea Seydoux coming back from the first game, with Elle Fanning joining the series.</p><p>In other news, Kojima recently said his latest project--believed to be Death Stranding 2--is now in the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hideo-kojima-says-his-new-game-is-now-in-crunch-time-wonders-how-much-longer-he-can-stay-creative/1100-6528760/" data-ref-id="1100-6528760">"crunch"</a> part of development ahead of its release. He said he also is beginning to wonder <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hideo-kojima-says-his-new-game-is-now-in-crunch-time-wonders-how-much-longer-he-can-stay-creative/1100-6528760/" data-ref-id="1100-6528760">how much longer he can stay creative.</a></p><p>In addition to Death Stranding 2, Kojima Productions is developing at least two other games: <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/physint/" data-ref-id="5000-617596">Physint</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/od/" data-ref-id="5000-612205">OD</a>. None of Kojima's upcoming projects have release dates as of yet, however.</p><p>Beyond games, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kojima-wants-the-death-stranding-movie-to-be-a-new-dimension-of-what-a-game-adaptation-can-be/1100-6528061/" data-ref-id="1100-6528061">Kojima is partnering with A24 for a a Death Stranding movie</a>, though it's still early days for that project.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chappell Roan's Idea Of A Fun Night Involves Eating An Edible And Playing Video Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/chappell-roans-idea-of-a-fun-night-involves-eating-an-edible-and-playing-video-games/1100-6528934/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/chappell-roans-idea-of-a-fun-night-involves-eating-an-edible-and-playing-video-games.1088664/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/chappell-roans-idea-of-a-fun-night-involves-eating-an-edible-and-playing-video-games/1100-6528934/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528934">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Chappell Roan, like so many of us, loves video games and specifically Fortnite. In a new interview, the "Hot To Go" singer discussed her appreciation for video games and called on Epic to give her a Fortnite skin of her own someday.</p><p>Fortnite already has a "Hot To Go" emote, and Roan teased that a new emote inspired by her song "Good Luck Babe" might also come to Fortnite. But she really wants her own skin.</p><p>"That is what I am going to use this interview for," Roan said. "Please give me a skin. Please."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZEhSOz0VoqQ" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZEhSOz0VoqQ" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Roan also revealed in the interview that she plays Fortnite on Switch ("that's how serious I take it," she said) and already bought the Ariana Grande skin. She was told during the interview about Fortnite's new first-person shooter mode, Ballistic, and joked that she's not interested because it means she wouldn't get to see her Ariana Grande skin.</p><p>Additionally, the 26-year-old said her idea of a perfect night involves video games and recreational drugs. "Well, if I want to have like a really good night I just eat an edible and play video games," she said. "But if I'm trying to have fun like, out, I'll take 'shrooms."</p><p>Roan also mentioned how she hopes Epic can create a Chappell Roan skin of her Statue of Liberty costume, with an apple bong as the back bling.</p><p>Fortnite's next big update is coming on January 31, which is when Fortnite OG Chapter 1, Season 2 goes live. For now, you can <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-play-as-godzilla-in-fortnite/1100-6528891/" data-ref-id="1100-6528891">stomp around the battlefield as Godzilla</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>