<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:55:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed, Xbox's First-Person Fantasy RPG, Is Coming To PlayStation 5 Next Month]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/09/avowed-xboxs-first-person-fantasy-rpg-is-coming-to-playstation-5-next-month</link>
            <guid>1401592</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Avowed, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/avowed">Xbox's first-person fantasy RPG developed by Obsidian Entertainment</a> and released on Xbox and PC last year, is coming to PlayStation 5. More specifically, Avowed launches on PS5 on February 17, a day shy of the game's first anniversary.</p><p>The <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP6312-PPSA26136_00-0827146390058176">Standard Edition</a> will cost $49.99, and the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP6312-PPSA26136_00-0074184226734561">Premium Edition</a>, which includes a digital artbook and soundtrack as well as two player armors and eight companion skins, will cost $59.99. The same day Avowed hits PS5, the game will get a new anniversary update on all platforms that adds New Game Plus, new races to play (Dwarves, Orlan, and Aumaua), a new weapon type, Photo Mode, and more.&nbsp;</p><p>"Explore a dangerous and beautiful land shaped by ancient magic," a <a href="https://www.obsidian.net/news/obsidian/avowed-is-coming-to-playstation-5">blog post</a> reads. "Traverse its wilds, reveal hidden truths, and delve into secrets buried beneath its surface. Play your way by experimenting with a wide range of weapons, abilities, and powers in combat that rewards creativity and adaptability. Shape your journey through the choices you make, from how you fight and explore, to how you answer the Living Lands when they push back."&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Check out the Avowed anniversary update trailer for yourself below:</strong>&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8yhr_UqvElk"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8yhr_UqvElk" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Avowed hits PS5 on February 17 and is currently available on Xbox Series X/S and PC.&nbsp;</p><p>While waiting for its PS5 release, read <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/avowed/high-fun-per-square-foot"><em>Game Informer's </em>Avowed review</a>, and then check out our review of The Outer Worlds 2, which is another game Obsidian Entertainment launched last year.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Have you played Avowed? Let us know what you think of it in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/09/avowed-xboxs-first-person-fantasy-rpg-is-coming-to-playstation-5-next-month]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>