<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 12:49:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Players Warned To Stay Away From Cheaters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-players-warned-to-stay-away-from-cheaters/1100-6531000/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-players-warned-to-stay-away-from-cheaters.1170075/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-players-warned-to-stay-away-from-cheaters/1100-6531000/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531000">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Capcom has found some players are cheating in certain <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds/" data-ref-id="5000-612214">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> quests by modifying the game to output higher rewards, and has warned players against joining modified quests. Players who join these quests, even if they aren't the ones instigating the modifications, run the risk of corrupting their games, or being picked up by Capcom's anti-cheat measures.</p><p>"Modified data can interfere with normal gameplay and even render the game unplayable," Capcom warned in a post on the Monster Hunter <a href="https://x.com/monsterhunter/status/1913216880795410834" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">X account</a> (via <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/capcom-has-a-message-for-monster-hunter-wilds-cheaters" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>). "If you suspect a quest has been modified, please do not play it, or stop playing it immediately."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/monsterhunter/status/1913216880795410834" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">❗Unauthorized Data Modification Warning❗<br>We have confirmed the unauthorized modification of game data in Monster Hunter Wilds for High Rank environment Investigations, Field Surveys, and more.<br>Modified data can interfere with normal gameplay and even render the game… <a href="https://t.co/Z9HZuigQQZ" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/Z9HZuigQQZ</a></p>  — Monster Hunter (@monsterhunter) <a href="https://twitter.com/monsterhunter/status/1913216880795410834?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 18, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>The warning is accompanied by an image showing what players should look for to identify if a quest is legit, or has been modified. The image explains that legitimate quests will only ever have 1-2 target monsters, with a max of five rewards per monster, for example.</p><p>The issue is impacting "High Rank environment Investigations, Field Surveys, and more," following patch 1.010. Capcom also added that future updates will include more robust anti-cheat measures to detect people modifying the game, and prevent players from having to identify hacked quests on their own.</p><p>Monster Hunter Wilds received its first major title update at the start of the month, which added Leviathan-class monster <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-beat-mizutsune-in-monster-hunter-wilds-location-weaknesses-drops/1100-6530639/" data-ref-id="1100-6530639">Mizutsune</a>, a Zoa Shia hunt, new armor and weapons, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-title-update-1-patch-notes-mizutsune-and-new-skills/1100-6530611/" data-ref-id="1100-6530611">heaps more</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>