<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:40:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disco Elysium Fans Should Keep An Eye On Rue Valley, Out Today On PC And Consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disco-elysium-fans-should-keep-an-eye-on-rue-valley-out-today-on-pc-and-consoles/1100-6536111/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disco-elysium-fans-should-keep-an-eye-on-rue-valley-out-today-on-pc-and-consoles.1349797/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536111">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/rue-valley/" data-ref-id="5000-571768">Rue Valley</a>, the isometric, story-driven RPG that looks quite like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/disco-elysium/" data-ref-id="5000-465081">Disco Elysium</a>, arrives today on PC, last- and current-gen Xbox and PlayStation platforms, and Switch. Though they look quite alike and both deal with some heavy themes, the specifics of Rue Valley help it stand apart.</p><p>The game tells the story of a man trapped in a timeloop where each reset changes who he will become and what he can do. Since players can bring their memories and knowledge with them across loops, you'll unlock new dialogue options and other interactions as the story unfolds.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9en2Xglvxr4" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9en2Xglvxr4" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>With each loop, the player-character can be quite unlike his past or future self, said the creative team, with him acting like a "cold-hearted loner in one loop and a melodramatic loudmouth in the next." But all the while, a central mystery and the personal lives of other characters become focal points, with the team exploring some of its more serious themes through these characters.</p><p>Rue Valley's way of grappling with mental health issues led the team at Emotion Spark Studio to collaborate with <a href="https://us.movember.com/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Movember</a>, a leading men's health charity, in hopes of promoting positive change in the lives of players and others.</p><p>“It was really important for us to craft an engaging yet poignant story highlighting the struggles many of us face every day” said Marko Smiljanić, creative director of Emotion Spark Studio. “We’re confident that it will resonate with people in a way that conveys that they’re heard, they’re seen, and they matter.”</p><p>Rue Valley is available now.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disco-elysium-fans-should-keep-an-eye-on-rue-valley-out-today-on-pc-and-consoles/1100-6536111/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>