<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:49:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An Exclusive Look At The Dolls Behind Dragon Quest VII Reimagined's Unique Visuals]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive-interview/2025/12/16/how-square-enix-landed-on-dragon-quest-vii-reimagineds-doll</link>
            <guid>1384813</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p><a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</a> is the latest game to grace the <a href="https://gameinformer.com/cover-reveal/2025/10/21/cover-reveal-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined">cover of <em>Game Informer</em></a>, and to write that cover story, I traveled to Tokyo, Japan, to visit Square Enix's Shibuya offices and play the game, interview the team behind it, and even check out the dolls foundational to this remake's unique aesthetic. While the dolls were out, we captured some exclusive video of each, giving you a close-up look of Reimagined's party members: Hero, Maribel, Kiefer, Ruff, Aishe, and Sir Mervyn.&nbsp;</p><p>Alongside that, we spoke to Reimagined director Masato Yagi about the decision to create a doll-like visual style and the diaorama-esque aeshetic of Estard and the surrounding world. <strong>But before that, check out this exclusive video about the dolls:&nbsp;</strong></p><p url="https://youtu.be/kSBxpnOMQhk" width="640" height="360" responsive="1" show_suggested="1" privacy_mode="0" autoplay="0" show_player="1" start_at=""><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kSBxpnOMQhk" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>When I ask Yagi how the team landed on these dolls, going so far as to pay a local Japanese doll studio, Studio Nova, to create them, he says it's about Akira Toriyama's art in the original game.&nbsp;</p><p>"The reason or factor [for] the doll-and-handcrafted aesthetics is that when you look at the original character designs from Akira Toriyama, when compared with other Dragon Quest character designs, the characters of Dragon Quest VII are drawn in a shorter scale," Yagi says. "I think that really matched the unique aesthetics of the storytelling of Dragon Quest VII. The doll [visual look] really meshed well together [with that art and aesthetic of DQVII]."</p><p>Yagi adds, "The original story of Dragon Quest VII involved, as you know, the protagonists – as they move forward with their progress and their adventures, more islands [to explore and visit] are revealed; there are more areas that they can explore. I think that system just kind of made sense and just fits well with the diorama aesthetic, too."&nbsp;</p><p>You can see firsthand how these doll aesthetics work in Dragon Quest VII Reimagined when it launches on February 5 on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, Switch 2, Switch, and PC.&nbsp;</p><p>In the meantime, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/digital-issue/2025/11/04/the-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-digital-issue-is-now-live">check out this article</a> breaking down everything in the <a href="https://gameinformer.com/cover-reveal/2025/10/21/cover-reveal-dragon-quest-vii-reimagined">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined issue of <em>Game Informer</em></a>, and be sure to <a href="https://gameinformer.com/subscribe">subscribe here</a> if you haven't yet to access the <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/11/04/adventure-doesnt-wait">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined cover story</a>, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/feature/2025/11/04/the-history-of-dragon-quest-as-told-by-creator-yuji-horii">our deep dive into Dragon Quest history</a> with creator Yuji Horii, and so much more.</p><hr><p><em>Do you like the doll aesthetic? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/exclusive-interview/2025/12/16/how-square-enix-landed-on-dragon-quest-vii-reimagineds-doll]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Steam Winter Sale Starts This Week And Includes Discounts On Hades II, Dispatch, Elden Ring Nightreign, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/psa/2025/12/16/the-steam-winter-sale-starts-this-week-and-includes-discounts-on-hades-ii-dispatch</link>
            <guid>1384759</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>It's that time of the year again – snow is falling (in some places), stores are busier than ever, decorations overtake lawns, and the temperatures beg you to stay inside and enjoy some video games. Like every year, Steam is answering the call with its annual Steam Winter Sale and the 2025 edition promises discounts on some of the year's biggest games when it goes live this Thursday, on December 18, at 10 a.m. PT.</p><p>Though we don't know exact pricing discounts just yet, if you're familiar with this yearly sale, you know the discounts can be quite steep. Steam released a trailer highlighting some of the games that will be on sale. If you were waiting to purchase some of the year's biggest and best releases, this might be your moment because the Steam Winter Sale 2025 includes discounts on <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/dispatch">Dispatch</a>, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/hades-ii">Hades II</a>, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a>, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii">Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</a>, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a>, and more.&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/76bmexgiHqo"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/76bmexgiHqo" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Here are the other games mentioned in the Steam Winter Sale 2025 trailer:&nbsp;</p><ul><li>Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon</li><li>Dynasty Warriors: Origins</li><li>Borderlands 4 – <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/borderlands-4/cathartic-chaos">Our Review</a></li><li>Dune: Awakening</li><li>Dying Light: The Beast – <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/dying-light-the-beast/a-deadly-return-to-form">Our Review</a></li><li>The Last of Us Part II Remastered</li><li>Rematch</li><li>Slime Rancher 2</li><li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II – <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii/a-medieval-day-epic">Our Review</a></li><li>Megabonk</li><li>Digimon Story Time Stranger</li><li>R.E.P.O.</li><li>Assassin's Creed Shadows – <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/assassins-creed-shadows/dont-stop-me-naoe-because-im-having-a-good-time">Our Review</a></li><li>Marvel's Spider-Man 2 – <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/marvels-spider-man-2/sticking-the-landing">Our Review</a></li><li>RV There Yet?</li><li>Escape from Duckov</li><li>Dispatch – <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/dispatch/with-great-power-comes-guaranteed-paperwork">Our Review</a></li><li>Deltarune</li><li>Elden Ring Nightreign – <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/elden-ring-nightreign/encapsulating-efficiency">Our Review</a></li><li>Hades II – <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/hades-ii/godlike-indeed">Our Review</a></li><li>Drive Beyond Horizons</li></ul><p>The Steam Winter Sale 2025 begins Thursday, December 18, at 10 a.m. PT and will run through January 5.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>What games are you hoping to pick up? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/psa/2025/12/16/the-steam-winter-sale-starts-this-week-and-includes-discounts-on-hades-ii-dispatch]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>