<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 22:41:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Season 5 Finally Adds Rogue And Gambit]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvel-rivals-season-5-finally-adds-rogue-and-gambit/1100-6536130/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-season-5-finally-adds-rogue-and-gambit.1350379/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536130">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/marvel-rivals/" data-ref-id="5000-624043">Marvel Rivals</a> Season 5 is a formal celebration with the wedding of one of Marvel's most iconic couples. The season adds X-Men's Gambit and Rogue, and developer NetEase has released a new cinematic trailer to tease the couple's big wedding as well as some new costumes players might expect in the Season 5 battle pass, some of which may be obtainable with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-marvel-rivals-codes-for-free-skins-and-rewards/1100-6530202/" data-ref-id="1100-6530202">Marvel Rivals codes</a>.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hXOUHb64164" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/hXOUHb64164" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Season 5: Love is a Battlefield arrives on November 14. As revealed in the trailer above, the season is themed around Gambit and Rogue's wedding, but the ceremony is interrupted by some sort of cosmic energy.</p><p dir="ltr">Gambit is revealed to be the first of the two new characters arriving, and he'll be categorized as a Strategist who blends kinetic energy control with his iconic playing cards. This also means Rogue will likely make her appearance a few weeks after the season's launch.</p><p dir="ltr">Later in the season, NetEase will introduce a new game mode. This is an 18v18 Conquest mode that will be played on the new Grand Garden map. There will also be a non-combat map added to Marvel Rivals. This new map is themed around New York City, and players will be able to go and hangout and emote in this dedicated space.</p><p dir="ltr">Gameplay changes and big fixes are likely included as well. However, more Season 5 details and the full battle pass reveal should be coming soon.</p><p>Most recently, Season 4's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvel-rivals-season-4-5-update-adds-daredevil-and-cross-platform-progression/1100-6535147/">midseason update added Daredevil</a> to the game's lineup of heroes. Last month, Marvel Rivals added the game's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvel-rivals-unleashes-the-zombie-apocalypse-in-its-new-pve-mode/1100-6535521/">first-ever PvE mode</a>, which was themed around Marvel Zombies.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvel-rivals-season-5-finally-adds-rogue-and-gambit/1100-6536130/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>