<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 07:44:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA Previously Had The "Worst CEO" In Gaming, Ex-Activision Boss Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-previously-had-the-worst-ceo-in-gaming-ex-activision-boss-says/1100-6529409/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-previously-had-the-worst-ceo-in-gaming-ex-activision-boss-says.1106271/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-previously-had-the-worst-ceo-in-gaming-ex-activision-boss-says/1100-6529409/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529409">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In 2013, John Riccitiello <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-ceo-resigns/1100-6405525/" data-ref-id="1100-6405525">stepped down as EA's CEO</a> following a tumultuous six-year run on top of the company. During Riccitiello's reign, Activision's Call of Duty franchise overtook Battlefield in terms of popularity, and it didn't help when Riccitiello <a href="https://stealthoptional.com/article/unitys-ceo-devs-pay-per-install-charge-fps-gamers-per-bullet" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">joked that Battlefield players should be charged to reload</a>. Now, ex-Activision Blizzard CEO Bobby Kotick has shared his belief that Riccitiello was the worst CEO in the video game industry.</p><p>During a joint appearance on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D2urSgcuyyo" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Grit</a> with former EA Chief Creative Officer Bing Gordon, Kotick revealed that Activision was afraid that Gordon would assume control of EA and prove to be a good leader for the company.</p><p>"I'm not saying this because [Gordon is] sitting here," said Kotick. "Our fear was always that Bing was going to run [EA]. And we would have paid for Riccitiello to stay a CEO forever... like we thought he was the worst CEO in video games." Gordon also noted that Riccitiello may have hastened his departure from EA as well.</p><p>Regardless of his feelings about Riccitiello, Kotick said that there were multiple attempts in the past to bring EA and Activision together as a single company.</p><p>"[EA] tried to buy us a bunch of times. We had merger conversations," recalled Kotick. Later in the podcast, Kotick admitted that Activision thought that EA's "business [was] in a lot of ways was better than ours," before Gordon pointed out that Blizzard's business is even better than EA's.</p><p>During that same interview, Gordon recalled that EA <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-passed-on-chances-to-buy-guitar-hero-call-of-duty-and-blizzard/1100-6529398/" data-ref-id="1100-6529398">passed on the chance to buy Guitar Hero, Call of Duty, and Blizzard</a> before Activision ultimately swept up all three. Kotick also called <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ex-activision-blizzard-boss-thought-warcraft-was-one-of-the-worst-movies-ever-made/1100-6529392/" data-ref-id="1100-6529392">the Warcraft film one of the worst movies</a> he's ever seen and explained why it was a mistake for Blizzard to focus so much attention on that project.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Could Have Been Bought By This Unexpected Company, Activision Founder Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-could-have-been-bought-by-this-unexpected-company-activision-founder-says/1100-6529405/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-could-have-been-bought-by-this-unexpected-company-activision-founder-says.1106205/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-could-have-been-bought-by-this-unexpected-company-activision-founder-says/1100-6529405/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529405">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>According to Activision founder Bobby Kotick, Berkshire Hathaway's Charlie Munger was at one point in time interested in buying Nintendo, or at least interested in exploring the idea of buying Nintendo.</p><p>Kotick said on the <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/2MN7nJdijzjfcP232NsHZF?si=mHGPjwjXQMiFbuZZEWcgqA" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Grit podcast</a> that Munger was not a fan of video games, but saw an opportunity to potentially make a bid for Nintendo. Munger is said to have floated the idea of spending some of Berkshire's immense holdings on making moves in the video game space. One of Munger's ideas, apparently, was to buy Nintendo.</p><p>"He goes, 'You know, I was looking at a couple other companies in your sector. I think if we bought yours, we should buy that company Nintendo, too,'" Kotick recalled. "He said, 'Have you guys looked at it? I was like, 'Yeah.' It was trading [at the time] at like 13 billion, with 7 billion in cash. He goes, 'You know, I don't think anything is gonna go really bad before I'm dead, and then if it goes bad after I'm dead, they'll just chalk it up to the folly of an 82-year-old, so you don't have to be so concerned about disappointing me."</p><p>This came about at a time when the French conglomerate Vivendi was forced to sell its stake in Activision, and Berkshire Hathaway was in the mix to buy it. That didn't happen, though, as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/activision-blizzard-completes-buyback-from-vivendi/1100-6415550/" data-ref-id="1100-6415550">Activision ultimately bought itself back from Vivendi</a>.</p><p>During one of his weekly Friday lunches with Munger, Kotick asked for advice on how to structure a buyback from Vivendi. It was at this time that Munger reportedly said he wanted to fund the buyback. When he got up to go to the bathroom, Activision's Brian Kelly said to Kotick that if Munger--an adept investor--wanted to buy the stake, then he and Kotick should want that as well. And that's eventually what happened.</p><p>"He didn't like the business [of video games]," Kotick said of Munger. "He thought it was a step removed from gambling. He's like, 'You know, you're preying off people's addictions.' And I was like, 'I'm not. I'm actually giving them joy and fun, and if you ever tried a video game, you'd see that.' He always had this... little bit of an aversion."</p><p>Of course, Berkshire did not buy Nintendo. As for Munger, he passed away in 2023 at the age of 99. Berkshire Hathaway currently has more than <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/how-to-invest/stocks/what-does-berkshire-hathaway-own/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$325 billion in cash</a> and could theoretically try to buy pretty much any company on the open market, but it has not signaled any intent to buy a video game company.</p><h3><strong>Microsoft also tried to buy Nintendo</strong></h3><p>More than 20 years ago, Microsoft tried to buy Nintendo. Then-CEO Steve Ballmer sent staff to Japan to broach the idea, and the team apparently got <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-tried-to-acquire-nintendo-square-and-midway-years-ago/1100-6485939/" data-ref-id="1100-6485939">laughed out of the room.</a></p><p>Berkshire did make a very big investment in the video game space in 2022, when it <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/02/15/investing/warren-buffett-berkshire-hathaway-activision-blizzard-microsoft/index.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">bought almost 15 million shares of Activision Blizzard</a> just before Microsoft announced its intention to buy the company. Berkshire paid an average of about $66.50 per share, and that price surged tremendously after Microsoft announced its plans to buy Activision Blizzard. The deal was ultimately approved at $95 per share, so Berkshire no doubt made a very big profit on the investment.</p><h3><strong>Game Pass issues</strong></h3><p>Also in the interview, Kotick discussed Microsoft's blockbuster $75.4 billion buyout of Activision Blizzard, saying he and Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella "got the deal done in three days." Of course, it took more than a year for regulatory approval, but the framework was apparently decided in just 72 hours. The only disagreement Kotick and Nadella had around the deal focused on Microsoft's vision for Game Pass.</p><p>Kotick mentioned how World of Warcraft has been successful with its $15/month subscription cost, and that's just for one game. "Why would I put that into a Game Pass?" Kotick said. "I said to these guys, 'Why trade our flexible business models where you can do what's actually in the best interest of the customer.' I didn't believe in that. But the beauty if you're Microsoft... you can take that bet."</p><p>Kotick is not the only higher-up who has questioned the economic realities of Game Pass, as companies like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/devolver-is-worried-by-ps-plus-xbox-game-pass-and-/1100-6470836/" data-ref-id="1100-6470836">Devolver Digital have spoken critically of the service since day one.</a> Take-Two's Strauss Zelnick has also discussed why <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/take-two-boss-says-call-of-duty-on-game-pass-will-help-drive-memberships-for-a-period-of-time/1100-6525664/" data-ref-id="1100-6525664">launching new games in Game Pass makes no sense for the company</a>. There are examples, too, of Game Pass actually <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/descenders-publisher-saw-descenders-xbox-one-sales/1100-6469046/" data-ref-id="1100-6469046">helping to drive game sales outside the subscription</a>, and Doom creator John Romero just recently said <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-pass-doesnt-hurt-game-companies-says-doom-co-creator/1100-6529136/" data-ref-id="1100-6529136">Game Pass doesn't hurt companies</a>.</p><p>Microsoft itself previously acknowledged that Game Pass can, in some cases, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-does-decrease-base-game-sales-microsoft-says/1100-6511473/" data-ref-id="1100-6511473">cannibalize game sales</a>--but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-clarifies-its-own-admission-that-game-pass-cannibalizes-some-game-sales/1100-6511503/" data-ref-id="1100-6511503">not in every case</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Almost 30 Years Later, One Of The Longest-Running MMORPGs Is Getting A New Class]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/almost-30-years-later-one-of-the-longest-running-mmorpgs-is-getting-a-new-class/1100-6529406/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/almost-30-years-later-one-of-the-longest-running-mmorpgs-is-getting-a-new-class.1106187/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/almost-30-years-later-one-of-the-longest-running-mmorpgs-is-getting-a-new-class/1100-6529406/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529406">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>One of the first and longest-running MMORPGs ever made, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/tibia/" data-ref-id="5000-18504">Tibia</a>, will receive a new class for the first time ever in its almost 30-year history, developer CipSoft has announced. The Monk class will join Tibia's four original classes--Sorcerer, Paladin, Druid, and Knight--which launched alongside the top-down 2D MMO in 1997.</p><p dir="ltr">As revealed in a <a href="https://www.tibia.com/news/?subtopic=newsarchive&amp;id=8214" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">blog post</a> and teaser video, the Monk will be a melee fighter that can also provide a support role by healing allies. CipSoft said the Monk can be "played in a very special way" but wanted to make sure it fit seamlessly into the world of Tibia and existed in harmony with the game's existing four classes. The team also knew it wanted to introduce a new melee class that could also heal, but didn't want it to encroach on secondary roles like debuffing filled by Paladin and Sorcerers.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DMzXYOz6o7I" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/DMzXYOz6o7I" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">"In fact, one of our main goals was to ensure that the new vocation holds a unique position without undermining the value of others or rendering them obsolete," CipSoft said. "We are very happy about the arrival of the Monk and hope you are just as eager to experience what it is like when they spring into action."</p><p dir="ltr">The Monk will feature a few unique mechanics, such as the Harmony, Virtue, and Serene systems. Using specific attacks will build up Harmony that can then be consumed to heavily boost the Monk's power, while Virtues are powerful buffs the Monk can choose between. Monks in a Serene state will be considerably more powerful, but can only be achieved while playing solo or when there are six or fewer monsters nearby. CipSoft said the Serene system is to ensure that Monks are strong in specific scenarios when Serene, but won't surpass the damage of other classes or the Knight's ability to tank when not in a Serene state.</p><p dir="ltr">CipSoft said it will be rolling out five blogs in the coming days and weeks to dive into the design and development of the Monk. As for when the Monk will be playable, CipSoft said it will officially arrive later this year, with the chance to test the new class starting on February 25.</p><p dir="ltr">Tibia is free-to-play, with the option to pay and upgrade to a premium subscription that grants various perks like an XP boost, access to more areas, the ability to purchase homes, and other benefits.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Black Ops 6 And Warzone Season 2 Reloaded Start Date And Details]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-reloaded-start-date-and-details/1100-6529404/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-reloaded-start-date-and-details.1106184/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-reloaded-start-date-and-details/1100-6529404/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529404">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">The Season 2 Reloaded update for Call of Duty arrives in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/" data-ref-id="5000-630093">Black Ops 6</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone/" data-ref-id="5000-572198">Warzone</a> later this month, and here you'll find everything rumored and announced so far. This includes new melee weapons, more maps, and limited-time events. There's even a rumor of a potential TMNT crossover this season.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Call_of_Duty_Season_2_Reloaded_start_times">Call of Duty Season 2 Reloaded start times</h2><p dir="ltr">Based on the days left for the Season 2 battle pass, the midseason "Reloaded" update should arrive around Thursday, February 20. These seasonal updates usually go live around 9 AM PT / 12 PM ET / 5 PM BST across all platforms.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="210858941" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465614,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Black%20Ops%206%20%26%20Warzone%20-%20Official%20Season%2002%20Launch%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:91,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/black-ops-6-warzone-official-season-02-launch-trailer\/2300-6465614\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465614\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465614\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465614\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465614&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465614,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6529404&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty-black-ops-6,call-of-duty-warzone&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,playstation-5,pc,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;activision,microsoft-game-studios&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty,call-of-duty-warzone&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465614},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465614\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4431718-66.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/msiRnpMN.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1737560280,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="msiRnpMN" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465614" data-src="/videos/black-ops-6-warzone-official-season-02-launch-trailer/2300-6465614/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Black Ops 6 &amp; Warzone - Official Season 02 Launch Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><h2 dir="ltr" id="What_to_expect_from_Season_2_Reloaded">What to expect from Season 2 Reloaded</h2><p dir="ltr">Call of Duty's midseason updates include more game modes, limited-time events, and quality-of-life updates across all modes.</p><p dir="ltr">At the start of Season 2, Activision teased that a melee-focused set of new weapons would be revealed for the midseason update. There is also a St. Patrick's Day: Clover Craze holiday event, and more details should arrive closer to the update.</p><p dir="ltr">Season 2 is themed around ninjas, and multiple dataminers suggest that a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-tmnt-crossover-could-be-coming/1100-6529089/">TMNT-themed crossover is planned</a> for the midseason update. This is rumored to have an event and limited-time game mode themed around the turtles. Rumored operator bundles for the skateboarding, pizza-eating Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles fit the theme of this midseason update, as we have a set of teased melee weapons and the return of Call of Duty's Grind skatepark map.</p><p dir="ltr">Dual katanas were teased in promos for the launch of Season 2, with the additional melee weapons rumored to be a pair of sais, nunchucks, a bo staff, and a skateboard.</p><p dir="ltr">Call of Duty previously had a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-tmnts-shredder-with-a-gun-in-call-of-duty-modern-warfare-2-and-warzone-2/1100-6512543/">TMNT collab with the Shredder operator bundle</a> introduced in 2022's Modern Warfare 2, but the crossover felt odd without mention of the turtles themselves.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4442456-bo6-season-02-announcement-011.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442456" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4442456-bo6-season-02-announcement-011.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4442456"></a><figcaption>Season 2's Grind map</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4442456-bo6-season-02-announcement-011.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Black_Ops_6_multiplayer">Black Ops 6 multiplayer</h2><p dir="ltr">Season 2 Reloaded includes two more multiplayer maps: Bullet and Grind. Bullet is a new map that takes place on a moving bullet train, and this will be available in 6v6 playlists as well as 2v2 Gunfight. Grind is the 6v6 skatepark map originally from Black Ops 2.</p><p dir="ltr">The update also adds a new perk. The Hunter's Instinct is an Enforcer perk in slot two, which, when equipped, will mark the nearest enemy whenever the player eliminates someone.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Zombies">Zombies</h2><p dir="ltr">Players shouldn't expect a new Zombies map. The Tomb arrived with the launch of Season 2, so the midseason update will likely be focused on quality-of-life updates for the map. However, there could be special limited-time modes themed around the upcoming holiday or the rumored TMNT event, similar to the Squid Game mode in Zombies for Season 1.</p><p dir="ltr">Directed Mode also arrives for The Tomb, which is the guided mode that helps players complete the main story quest. Completing the quest in Directed Mode won't allow players to earn all the unique rewards, but anyone looking to complete the story quest for the rewards can use our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-zombies-the-tomb-story-easter-egg-guide/2900-6181/">full guide for The Tomb main Easter egg quest</a> here.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Warzone">Warzone</h2><p dir="ltr">Activision hasn't included many midseason announcements for battle royale. However, the update will add a new perk in slot one called Low Profile, which enables players to move more quickly while crouched and prone, as well as move slightly faster when downed.</p><p dir="ltr">Most of Season 2 of Warzone is dedicated to game improvements and anti-cheat updates, and the developer previously confirmed some of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-dev-confirms-plans-to-scale-back-warzone-content-as-it-looks-to-improve-game/1100-6528901/">new content planned for Season 2 was shifted</a> in order to focus on game updates.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>