<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 19:08:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WoW Classic Is Finally Getting Fresh Servers As Cataclysm Players Move To Pandaria]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-is-finally-getting-fresh-servers-as-cataclysm-players-move-to-pandaria/1100-6527720/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wow-classic-is-finally-getting-fresh-servers-as-cataclysm-players-move-to-pandaria.1035000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-is-finally-getting-fresh-servers-as-cataclysm-players-move-to-pandaria/1100-6527720/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527720">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a> Classic players begging for fresh "vanilla" servers are finally getting their wish, with new servers set to go live on November 21 in celebration of WoW's 20th anniversary. Meanwhile, those playing Cataclysm Classic will progress on to Mists of Pandaria in 2025.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard announced the news as part of its Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct, along the way confirming in advance the new vanilla servers (minus the fresh Hardcore servers that are also coming) will automatically progress to The Burning Crusade Classic when the time comes. Blizzard said that just because TBC is already confirmed doesn't necessarily mean these new servers will keep moving forward all the way to Cataclysm (the expansion players who have kept progressing from WoW Classic's 2019 launch servers are currently on), but it's hard not to get some sense of deja vu.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uYGvtbrDiiw" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/uYGvtbrDiiw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">In an interview with GameSpot, WoW Classic lead software engineer Nora Valletta and software engineer Kevin Vigue offered more details on what players starting from scratch on the fresh servers can expect, their thoughts on moving on to Mists of Pandaria, and what the team has learned from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-classic-season-of-discovery-looks-to-make-a-20-year-old-game-surprising-again/1100-6519561/" data-ref-id="1100-6519561">more experimental swings like Season of Discovery</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard is using advances in server technology to have larger realms that can hold more players but fewer realms overall for this batch of new servers. In a departure from normal, there will not be dedicated role-playing or RPPvP servers as has usually been the case in the past, Valletta confirmed. Quality-of-life improvements, like the world buff-saving Chronoboon Displacer, faction balancing on PvP realms, and updates to make the original game's punishing Honor PvP rank system less punishing, will be present at launch for these new servers, as will a ban (at least in North America and Europe) on the controversial practice of GDKP runs--something Blizzard first implemented in Season of Discovery. In a change from 2019, the game's first raid, Molten Core, won't launch for a few weeks. The new servers will additionally have a group-finder tool (similar to one that appeared in TBC, Vigue said) to help players find groups without the need of an add-on.</p><p dir="ltr">A recent, unpopular change that saw Blizzard update the guild interface in WoW Classic and Season of Discovery to a more modern version will be reverted come the rollout of the new fresh servers, Vigue announced. Players will instead have the option of choosing between the more modern UI or its original appearance: a choice Blizzard doesn't want to make a habit of offering but said felt right in regards to guilds.</p><p dir="ltr">"We realized, especially once we saw the community reaction, 'Yeah, there is something really nostalgic about the original UI and how it's presented and what it means for that game experience,'" Vigue said.</p><p dir="ltr">Adding to the sense of we've been here before is Blizzard's announcement that Cataclysm Classic servers will move on in Summer 2025 to yet another "new" expansion, 2012's Mists of Pandaria. Players may have already revisited Mists of Pandaria as part of modern WoW's Mists of Pandaria Remix event earlier this year, but Valletta and Vigue said they think the two experiences are different enough to warrant another go around.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399083-wowclassic2025roadmap.png" data-ref-id="1300-4399083" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399083-wowclassic2025roadmap.png" data-ref-id="1300-4399083"></a><figcaption>WoW Classic's 2025 roadmap.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399083-wowclassic2025roadmap.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Mists of Pandaria Remix used the expansion as backdrop for players to collect exclusive cosmetics and gain new overpowered abilities that could almost one-shot even the game's toughest bosses, but it still played like modern WoW, with all of its current class design, talents, and abilities. Mists of Pandaria Classic will instead play as it did when it first launched over a decade ago. Vigue and Valletta also raised the point that every expansion was some WoW player's entry point into the MMORPG, and so Mists of Pandaria is, for some people, their "classic." It's an expansion that was perhaps under-appreciated in its time, but players now have fond memories of.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think the fact that MoP Remix was so well received speaks to…how much people love Pandaria as a continent and as an expansion," Vigue said.</p><p dir="ltr">As for the currently ongoing WoW Classic Season of Discovery, Blizzard's more experimental take on original WoW that was released towards the tail end of 2023, there's still some new content coming down the pike. The game's Naxxramas update will arrive later this winter. In addition to vanilla WoW's final raid, it will add new "instanced" content in the form of a new encounter against the Scarlet Crusade as well as the Karazhan Crypts, which Blizzard originally teased back when it first announced Season of Discovery at BlizzCon 2023. Vigue and Valletta wouldn't say whether the new content will be in the forms of raids, dungeons, or a combination of both, and instead said players will have to "discover" what's in store themselves.</p><p dir="ltr">Vigue and Valletta also wouldn't comment on what may come next after Season of Discovery--the "team's always cooking," Valletta said--but did say they have learned a ton from the seasonal server in regards to how to create new content for a 20-year-old game while still trying to maintain its original feeling.</p><p dir="ltr">"We've found Season of Discovery to be incredibly successful," Valletta said. "I think part of what made it successful is that sense of…[the new content] is very much down to earth. It wasn't massive, universe-ending world threats. It's you, yourself, as that character in that world…You're not some mighty fine champion hero who everybody knows and everything revolves around you, right? You exist in the world but the world is the main character, and you're part of that."</p><p dir="ltr">All the WoW Classic news was just one part of the Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct. Blizzard also launched new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/" data-ref-id="1100-6527719">remastered versions of Warcraft 1 and 2</a>, announced a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-and-a-return-to-ungoro-crater/1100-6527722/" data-ref-id="1100-6527722">StarCraft mini-set for Hearthstone</a>, and more.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hearthstone's 2025 Roadmap Includes StarCraft Crossover, Return To Un'Goro Crater]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-and-a-return-to-ungoro-crater/1100-6527722/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hearthstones-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-return-to-ungoro-crater.1034997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hearthstone-2025-roadmap-includes-starcraft-crossover-and-a-return-to-ungoro-crater/1100-6527722/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527722">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/hearthstone-heroes-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-176391">Hearthstone's</a> next mini-set is a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/starcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-20">StarCraft</a> crossover: one that will reimagine the various units of Blizzard's beloved sci-fi RTS in card form. In addition to this, Blizzard announced an entire year's worth of Hearthstone expansions in one go and a dramatic change to the game's Arena mode, giving players a full picture of what to expect in 2025.</p><p dir="ltr">Yes, Blizzard made the bold move of announcing a StarCraft crossover during its Warcraft 30th anniversary direct--a livestream that also celebrated 10 years of Hearthstone. The crossover is the largest mini-set Blizzard has ever done for its digital card game, with 49 total cards.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LFFB2ysJLTQ" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/LFFB2ysJLTQ" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">To learn more, GameSpot sat down with Hearthstone senior game designer Cora Georgiou and game designer Leo Robles Gonzalez ahead of the direct to talk about what it was like adapting StarCraft into card game form, the upcoming changes to Arena, and all of the expansions coming next year.</p><p dir="ltr">Gonzalez said the development team is trying to be a bit more "adventurous," given that the game is a decade old and its players are eager to see new things. That's one of the reasons it went big on the upcoming StarCraft mini-set.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think we're trying to swing pretty hard here," Gonzalez said. "It's the first time we've ever done something this deeply outside of Warcraft."</p><p dir="ltr">Different classes will be able to use a specific StarCraft hero. Each StarCraft faction will have its own set of cards, some of which can be used by any class and others that are class-specific. Warriors, Paladins, and Shamans, for example, can use Jim Raynor and take full advantage of Terran cards, while Death Knights, Hunters, Warlocks, and Demon Hunters can embrace the Zerg swarm with Kerrigan. Meanwhile, Mages, Priests, Rogues, and Druids can use the powers of Artanis, with a focus on powerful, high-mana-cost Protoss units that can be made cheaper.</p><p dir="ltr">Gonzalez said adapting StarCraft into the card game wasn't all that different from adapting Warcraft (both involve lots of research). The main difference was instead of looking to specific characters for card ideas, the team had to draw inspiration from StarCraft's iconic units. Gonzalez said it was also important to capture that feeling of StarCraft's gameplay.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398546-hsheroesofstarcraft-kerriganqueenofblades.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398546" data-ratio="1.1111715139984" data-width="3679" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398546-hsheroesofstarcraft-kerriganqueenofblades.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398546"></a><figcaption>Kerrigan will be usable by Death Knights, Hunters, Warlocks, and Demon Hunters.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398546-hsheroesofstarcraft-kerriganqueenofblades.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">"The gameplay of it--there's micro and there's macro--and it was really important to us to make sure that the macro of, 'What is your game plan overall with one of the three factions'... does that feel quintessentially like them?" Gonzalez said. "That's not something we had to super duper think about with the average Warcraft character."</p><p dir="ltr">The Heroes of StarCraft mini-set will release in January 2025, but the StarCraft crossover was just the tip of the iceberg when it came to Hearthstone announcements. Blizzard also revealed a full 2025 roadmap with three upcoming expansions, as well a major shake-up to the game's Arena mode.</p><p dir="ltr">Arena, Hearthstone's premium draft mode, has been largely unchanged since the game launched in 2014, but that will be changing soon. In the first half of 2025, Blizzard will change Arena in a big way by introducing two versions of Arena to choose from. Normal Arena will be similar to what exists now but sport faster runs while still letting players flex their competitive deck-building muscles. Another new version of the mode, the Underground Arena, will take things even further. The Underground will include players of all skill levels (in contrast to Normal Arena, which will still use a win-based matchmaking system), longer runs, and a new feature called "re-draft on loss" that lets players re-draft cards and edit their deck before going again in order to up their chances of winning. Both Arena modes will have their own ranked system.</p><p dir="ltr">Georgiou said the splitting of Arena into two modes came as a result of wanting to create an easier entry point for newer players while simultaneously giving existing Arena players more challenge and higher stakes. The mode is currently difficult for new players to dive into because of how heavy the competition can be, as many who specialize in Arena have been playing since Hearthstone first released.</p><p dir="ltr">"It was really to raise that ceiling for players who want that but also lower the floor a little bit so Arena can be a place that is welcoming for all types of players again," Georgiou said.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398547-hs_2025_roadmap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398547" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398547-hs_2025_roadmap.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4398547"></a><figcaption>Hearthstone's 2025 roadmap.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4398547-hs_2025_roadmap.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Hearthstone's first expansion set for the new year, Into the Emerald Dream, will transport players to the idealized, natural version of Azeroth as druidic defenders of the dream battle against the forces of the Old Gods. It's something the Hearthstone team has long had in its "back pocket," Georgiou said, and always knew would eventually be an expansion. It was actually in the running to be released last year, but the team pivoted to avoid stepping on the toes of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a>: Dragonflight's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-dragonflight-heads-to-the-emerald-dream-for-its-next-update/1100-6517531/" data-ref-id="1100-6517531">Emerald Dream-themed update</a>. The expansion's mini-set, Druids of the Flame, will add the faction of corrupted elemental druids to further stoke the fires of battle.</p><p dir="ltr">Its second expansion of 2025 is actually a sequel, a first in Hearthstone history--The Shrouded City. This set picks up where 2017's Journey to Un'Goro set left off, as the explorer Elise hunts for a lost Tortollan city, with a Tortollan-themed festival mini-set coming later. The Hearthstone team actually invented the Tortollan race for the original Un'Goro set (which would later be added to WoW), and the upcoming expansion provided a great opportunity to further flesh out the backstory of the Tortollan and "peel back" some of the layers of the original Un'Goro expansion.</p><p dir="ltr">"To be able to revisit an area that is so compelling that had so much that wasn't explored before, and to be able to look at it in a new light, I think will be really, really fun," Georgiou said.</p><p dir="ltr">The third and final Hearthstone expansion for 2025, Heroes of Time, will explore alternative versions of Azeroth's past, where players will find versions of legendary heroes as players "have never seen them before." That will all lead to an epic battle at the end of time with the corrupted leader of the Infinite Dragonflight, Murozond. Given how much of an emphasis WoW has put on the Bronze Dragonflight and Chromie in recent years, it's a little surprising Hearthstone hasn't dived deep on alternate timeline shenanigans yet. But that's worked out in the team's favor.</p><p dir="ltr">"I think doing it when there is so much to pull from in Hearthstone's past feels like the perfect, pun half-intended, time to do it," Gonzalez said. "There's so many characters our fans love and characters from Warcraft that our fans might not even be super exposed to that are in that thematic bucket. It's a really rich theme."</p><p dir="ltr">In other Warcraft news, Blizzard announced as part of the direct that its newly announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/" data-ref-id="1100-6527719">remastered versions of Warcraft 1 and 2</a>, as well as a major 2.0 update for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-iii-reforged/" data-ref-id="5000-504202">Warcraft 3: Reforged</a>, are all available now.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NHL 25 Adds Professional Women's Hockey League This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nhl-25-adds-professional-womens-hockey-league-this-year/1100-6527746/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nhl-25-adds-professional-womens-hockey-league-this-year.1034991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nhl-25-adds-professional-womens-hockey-league-this-year/1100-6527746/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527746">

            
            
  

<section><p>By  on <time datetime="2024-11-13T10:32:55-0800">November 13, 2024 at 10:32AM PST</time></p></section>
        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>EA Sports has announced a multi-year deal with the Professional Women's Hockey League (PWHL) to bring the upstart league's players and teams to NHL 25.</p><p>The PWHL comes to NHL 25 on December 5 with all six teams--these include the Boston Fleet, Minnesota Frost, Montréal Victoire, New York Sirens, Ottawa Charge, and Toronto Sceptres.</p><p>These teams can be used in Play Now, Online Versus, Shootout, and Seasons. PWHL uniforms will be accessible in World of Chel and Hockey Ultimate Team. EA warned that not all player likenesses will be available right away, saying it will "continue to add more" players over time.</p><p>PWHL integration in NHL 25 also includes the Walter Cup--the PWHL's version of the Stanley Cup.</p><p>NHL 25 isn't the first NHL game to feature women, as this <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nhl-22-adds-first-ever-playable-womens-teams-in-new-update-today/1100-6499998/" data-ref-id="1100-6499998">actually began with NHL 22 when EA struck a deal with the International Ice Hockey Federation</a>. Sarah Nurse was on the cover of the following year's game, NHL 23, alongside Trevor Zegras.</p><p>EA's other sports games have added women over the years, too, now spanning EA Sports FC, UFC, and PGA Tour. The PWHL is now in its second season. The Minnesota Frost won the inaugural Walter Cup.</p><p>Beyond the introduction of the PWHL, EA is releasing a major update for NHL 25 this holiday, and one of the most exciting pieces of it is the introduction of the NHL Arcade event series. Beginning November 15 through World of Chel, this is an arcade-style, three-versus-three mode featuring a Big Head mode and power-ups like Supershot and Super Speed, along with big and small goalies.</p><p>The action takes place in a bespoke rink with no glass and no rules. It's not quite like the NHL Hitz days of yesteryear, but it might help satisfy the itch.</p><p>NHL 25 is also introducing the 4 Nations Face-Off in 2025. This is a round-robin tournament featuring players from the USA, Canada, Finland, and Sweden. There will be a dedicated mode for this, and each nation's uniforms will come to the game across a variety of modes. The real-world 4 Nations Face-Off takes place in February 2025, so the update for NHL 25 will likely go live around then.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399082-holidayupdate.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399082" data-ratio="0.56287878787879" data-width="1320" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399082-holidayupdate.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399082"></a><figcaption>NHL 25 gets a big holiday update soon.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4399082-holidayupdate.jpg"></figure><p>Additionally, EA is trying to lure players back to NHL 25 by offering free content to everyone who simply logs in between November 15 and January 2. Everyone who does so will get six vanity items for the arcade mode, along with a special pack for the Road to 4 Nations content that's redeemable immediately. Players will also get a PWHL 83 OVR team building choice pack that will become redeemable when the PWHL integration goes live on December 5.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warcraft 1 And 2 Remastered Make Up A New Warcraft Battle Chest, Available Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today.1034988/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-1-and-2-remastered-make-up-a-new-warcraft-battle-chest-available-today/1100-6527719/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527719">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Blizzard's classic RTS titles <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-orcs-and-humans/" data-ref-id="5000-6383">Warcraft: Orcs and Humans</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-ii-tides-of-darkness/" data-ref-id="5000-2298">Warcraft 2: Tides of Darkness</a> are both getting the "remastered" treatment to celebrate the franchise's 30th anniversary, and they'll be available separately or together alongside <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/warcraft-iii-reforged/" data-ref-id="5000-504202">Warcraft 3: Reforged</a> today in a new Warcraft Battle Chest.</p><p dir="ltr">The news comes as part of Blizzard's Warcraft 30th Anniversary Direct, where the developer kicked things off by paying homage to the games that started the franchise and diving into what's changed, and what's stayed the same, in Warcraft 1 and 2 Remastered. While players will have the option of playing each game with their original visuals (something that can be toggled on and off in real time) the remastered versions also include new, hand-drawn visuals that help make each game's units more sharp and defined while still retaining their classic feel.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ryZ2jiW95qo" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ryZ2jiW95qo" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Warcraft 1's controls have been updated to support modern-RTS staples like right click to move, box unit selection, and a faster game speed. Both games have received various UI and UX adjustments as well, like unit health bars, tooltips, increased unit selection, and a mission select. Warcraft 2 will still support multiplayer and all legacy custom maps will be fully compatible with this new version of the game.</p><p dir="ltr">Warcraft 3: Reforged, the maligned remaster that released in 2020 to negative reviews and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warcraft-3-reforged-a-victim-of-mismanagement-pressure-from-activision-and-budget-cuts-report/1100-6494287/" data-ref-id="1100-6494287">reportedly suffered from budget cuts and a rocky development</a>, is also receiving a major 2.0 update today. The update improves the game's environments and lighting, as well as overhauls its UI. It also adds hotkey customization and a revamped ladder system. Those who prefer playing Warcraft 3 with its original, non-remastered visuals will find the update adds high-rez versions for all the classic Warcraft 3 models as well, with players having the option of mixing and matching which assets, original or HD, they'd like to use.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399076-warcraft2remasteredgameplay.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399076" data-ratio="0.56133540372671" data-width="1288" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399076-warcraft2remasteredgameplay.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399076"></a><figcaption>Warcraft 1 and 2 Remastered each sport new hand-drawn visuals that can be toggled on or off.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4399076-warcraft2remasteredgameplay.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Gamers who grew up playing classic Blizzard titles may remember seeing the large Warcraft and Warcraft 3 Battle Chests on store shelves that gather multiple games or expansions all together in one package. For the first time in a long time, a new Battle Chest is now available, one that includes the remastered versions of all three Warcraft RTS titles. The Battle Chest will be $40, while standalone versions of Warcraft: Remastered and Warcraft 2: Remastered will be $10 and $15 respectively.</p><p dir="ltr">For those who don't need all the new bells and whistles included in the remasters, the original versions of Warcraft 1 and 2 are available together on <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/warcraft_bundle" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GOG</a> for $15.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Dragon Age: The Veilguard's Hair Looks So Darn Good]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/why-dragon-age-the-veilguards-hair-looks-so-darn-good/1100-6527742/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-dragon-age-the-veilguards-hair-looks-so-darn-good.1034898/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/why-dragon-age-the-veilguards-hair-looks-so-darn-good/1100-6527742/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527742">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/dragon-age-the-veilguard/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> has introduced some striking visual changes to the world of Thedas, and while the new art style has been <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dragonage/comments/1eszz0t/opinions_on_the_art_style/" rel="nofollow ">met with mixed reception</a>, there's one aspect of the game's aesthetic that most players seem to agree on: The hair looks really, <em>really</em> good.</p><p dir="ltr">EA and BioWare appear to share the sentiment, and have revealed the recipe for high-quality hair animations via <a href="https://www.ea.com/technology/news/strand-hair-dragon-age-the-veilguard" rel="nofollow ">a new blog post</a> that examines every individual strand of The Veilguard's glorious collective locks. According to the post, each of the game's hairstyles--of which there are over 100--contain 50,000 individually rendered strands of hair. EA and BioWare credit the Frostbite engine for the high-quality results.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1226953407" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465422,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;The%20Good%20and%20The%20Bad%20of%20Dragon%20Age%3A%20The%20Veilguard&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:1479,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/the-good-and-the-bad-of-dragon-age-the-veilguard\/2300-6465422\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465422\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465422\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465422\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465422&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465422,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6527742&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;dragon-age-the-veilguard&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;dragon-age&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;dragon-age&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465422},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465422\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4391345-reviewinprogress_daveilguard_v1_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/mqLC3cXY.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1730127600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="mqLC3cXY" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465422" data-src="/videos/the-good-and-the-bad-of-dragon-age-the-veilguard/2300-6465422/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>The Good and The Bad of Dragon Age: The Veilguard</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">Frostbite has been <a href="https://www.ea.com/frostbite/news/the-future-of-hair-rendering-technology-in-frostbite" rel="nofollow ">working on realistic hair tech</a> for a while now, but the engine's progress truly shines in Veilguard, and it's not simply due to the number of hairstyle options or the amount of hairs on each character's head--length plays a major role, too. The Veilguard features a number of waist-length hair options (curly or straight) that move in combat, realistically responding to momentum, wind, blasts of magic, changes in direction, and other variables. But getting there wasn't easy.</p><p dir="ltr">"With hair attachments that move seamlessly and the decoupling of simulation and render tessellation, this is the first EA game to offer such detailed, physics-driven long hairstyles," the blog post explains. "The Frostbite team increased maximum hair length from 63 points to 255, and implemented a new system for complex hair structures like braids."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1752/17528202/4399041-hairguard.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399041" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1752/17528202/4399041-hairguard.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399041"></a><figcaption>One of Veilguard's longest hairstyle options sees Rook's hair hovering just above their hips.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1752/17528202/4399041-hairguard.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Changes to the Frostbite engine's lighting also played a major role in mastering Veilguard's hair physics, but it wasn't all fun and games--BioWare faced various challenges while working to perfect the way hair moved in-game. The main culprit? Horns.</p><p dir="ltr">"While Strand Hair is present in other EA games, the BioWare team had to push the limits even further for Dragon Age: The Veilguard," the post continues. "For example, implementing Strand Hair technology for characters who have waist-length hair with horns on their head presented some unique challenges."</p><p>Veilguard's beautifully rendered hair options haven't been overlooked by players, many of whom are very <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DragonAgeVeilguard/comments/1gndrbl/the_best_hair_to_date_in_dragon_age_the_veilguard/" rel="nofollow ">pleased with the game's well-animated cosmetic offerings</a> and spent <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-streamer-spent-almost-a-whole-day-making-sure-her-rook-was-a-smokeshow/1100-6527593/">hours perfecting their Rook</a> in the game's character creator. In a medium where "long hair" often translates to "shoulder-length at best," Dragon Age: The Veilguard seems to represent the industry's first major step in finally perfecting the art of realistic, complex hair structures in games. That's good news for everyone, especially <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/mass-effect/">Mass Effect</a> fans, who will likely have access to similarly realistic hair options when the next entry in the franchise finally arrives.</p><p>For more info on BioWare's latest fantasy RPG, check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/dragon-age-the-veilguard-review/1900-6418294/" data-ref-id="1900-6418294">Dragon Age: The Veilguard review-in-progress</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>