<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 14:44:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Just Made It Easier For Devs To Promote Their Games' Accessibility Features]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/steam-just-made-it-easier-for-devs-to-promote-their-games-accessibility-features/1100-6531047/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-just-made-it-easier-for-devs-to-promote-their-games-accessibility-features.1171332/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/steam-just-made-it-easier-for-devs-to-promote-their-games-accessibility-features/1100-6531047/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531047">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Steam is rolling out a new questionnaire for developers that makes it easier for them to highlight <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-xbox-playstation-are-teaming-up-for-accessible-games-initiative/1100-6530272/" data-ref-id="1100-6530272">accessibility features</a> in their games. Later in 2025, it will also become easier for players to search for games with specific accessibility features.</p><p>These updates were outlined in a <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/groups/steamworks/announcements/detail/536595840131663919" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog post</a> on April 22. In the "Edit Store" section for a game on Steamworks, developers can now complete an accessibility support questionnaire to confirm that their game has various gameplay, audio, visual, and input accessibility options. From there, developers can self-identify their game's level of accessibility.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1849/18498836/4481080-dad4d0852ce47f116b63cba4469478ba2b678aa4.png" data-ref-id="1300-4481080" data-ratio="0.41045454545455" data-width="2200" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1849/18498836/4481080-dad4d0852ce47f116b63cba4469478ba2b678aa4.png" data-ref-id="1300-4481080"></a><figcaption>This is what the accessibility support questionnaire game developers can now fill out on Steamworks looks like.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1849/18498836/4481080-dad4d0852ce47f116b63cba4469478ba2b678aa4.png"></figure><p>For now, this will only be visible within Steamworks, but later this year, it will have more public-facing uses. Developers will eventually be able to share information from this questionnaire on the Steam Store and App pages. Steam users will also gain the option to search for specific accessibility features. The following accessibility filters for search have been confirmed by Valve:</p><ul><li>Adjustable Difficulty</li><li>Save Anytime</li><li>Adjustable Text Size</li><li>Subtitle Options</li><li>Color Alternatives</li><li>Camera Comfort</li><li>Custom Volume Controls</li><li>Stereo Sound</li><li>Surround SOund</li><li>Narrated Game Menus</li><li>Playable without Timed Input</li><li>Keyboard Only Option</li><li>Mouse Only Option</li><li>Touch Only Option</li><li>Chat Speech-to-text</li><li>Chat Text-to-speech</li></ul><p>Valve explains that it is implementing these features to bring "a more positive experience on Steam for everyone by making it easier to find games that support Accessibility features." It's not required that devs fill out the questionnaire, but Valve says it is "highly recommended" because it will make it easier for players with accessibility needs to find these games.</p><p>If you're a Steam user, expect to see these game accessibility-focused improvements on Steam sometime this year.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 GameCube Controller Works Outside Of Switch Online, But Could Run Into "Issues"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-gamecube-controller-works-outside-of-switch-online-but-could-run-into-issues/1100-6531045/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-gamecube-controller-works-outside-of-switch-online-but-could-run-into-issues.1171287/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-gamecube-controller-works-outside-of-switch-online-but-could-run-into-issues/1100-6531045/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531045">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nintendo confirmed that the GameCube Controller designed for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Nintendo Switch 2</a> will be compatible with games outside of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/every-gamecube-game-coming-to-switch-2s-switch-online-library/2900-6400/" data-ref-id="2900-6400">Switch Online GameCube Classics library</a>, but some issues may arise when using it in that way.</p><p>In a statement to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/04/switch-2-gamecube-controller-compatible-with-other-games-but-there-may-be-some-issues" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo Life</a>, Nintendo explained that the controller is designed for use with classic games, so issues may arise when using it with other games. This confirms its compatibility with other Switch 2 software, although Nintendo is getting ahead of any problems that arise with that by pointing out that there could be issues. Hopefully, it at least works with games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/super-smash-bros-ultimate/" data-ref-id="5000-480957">Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</a> on Switch 2.</p><p>"The Nintendo GameCube controller is designed for use with the Nintendo GameCube – Nintendo Classics collection of games and is an optional way to play those games," Nintendo's full statement explains. "Since it doesn’t have all the buttons and features found in other controllers that can be used with the Nintendo Switch 2 system, there may be some issues when playing other games. The Nintendo GameCube controller can only be used on Nintendo Switch 2 and is not compatible with Nintendo Switch."</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0MvkSVs8f_w" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0MvkSVs8f_w" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The Switch 2's GameCube controller was revealed alongside the addition of GameCube games to Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pack during the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/switch-2-nintendo-direct-april-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-6391/" data-ref-id="2900-6391">April 2 Switch 2 Direct</a>. It features a very similar layout to the original GameCube controller, but works wirelessly and has the Home, Capture, C, and ZL buttons present on the Joy-Con 2 controllers. A disclaimer in one of Nintendo's trailers suggested that the Switch 2's GameCube Controller wouldn't work with other games, which is why Nintendo had to clarify this in the first place.</p><p>This new GameCube controller will become available for preorder on the My Nintendo Store the same day as Nintendo Switch 2. Currently, that date appears to be May 8. You should also check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">GameSpot's Switch 2 preorder guide</a> if you plan on picking up Nintendo's new system.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney Dreamlight Valley - All Garden Of Whimsy Star Path Duties And How To Complete Them]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-dreamlight-valley-all-garden-of-whimsy-star-path-duties-and-how-to-complete-them/1100-6530844/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-dreamlight-valley-all-garden-of-whimsy-star-path-duties-and-how-to-complete-them.1171239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-dreamlight-valley-all-garden-of-whimsy-star-path-duties-and-how-to-complete-them/1100-6530844/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530844">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/disney-dreamlight-valley/" data-ref-id="5000-563578">Disney Dreamlight Valley</a>'s Wonderland Whimsy update has arrived, introducing multiple beloved characters from Alice and Wonderland for players to meet and befriend. But it wouldn't be a major update without a new Star Path, too. The Garden of Whimsy Star Path brings plenty of items and cosmetics ranging from beautiful floral arrangements to fashions pulled straight from the Court of Hearts!</p><p>Before you can claim things from the Star Path, however, you'll need to complete Star Path duties to unlock currency. Here are all of the Garden of Whimsy Star Path duties and how to complete them.</p><h2>All Garden of Whimsy Star Path duties</h2><ul><li>Cast around for seafood - Go fishing for any seafood</li><li>Catch fish in gold ripples - Go fishing for legendary fish</li><li>Catch fish somewhere dazzling - Go fishing at Dazzle Beach</li><li>Catch fish somewhere peaceful - Go fishing in Peaceful Meadow</li><li>Chat with Belle's beau - Have a daily discussion with Beast</li><li>Chat with a curious young villager - Have a daily discussion with Alice</li><li>Chat with a powerfully frosty villager - Have a daily discussion with Elsa</li><li>Chat with the king of the jungle - Have a daily discussion with Simba</li><li>Chat with your favorite deputy - Have a daily discussion with Woody</li><li>Collect some shoreline shellfish - Pick up Clams, Scallop, or Mussels on Dazzle Beach</li><li>Complete Boutique Challenges - Complete a challenge at Daisy's Boutique</li><li>Cook a fairly fancy appetizer - Cook any 4-star appetizers</li><li>Cook a fairly fancy dessert - Cook any 4-star desserts</li><li>Cook a fairly fancy dinner - Cook any 4-star entrees</li><li>Cook a perfect appetizer - Cook any 5-star appetizers</li><li>Cook a perfect dessert - Cook any 5-star desserts</li><li>Cook a perfect entree - Cook any 5-star entrees</li><li>Cook any 4-star meal - Cook any 4-star meals</li><li>Craft Large Miraculous elixirs - Craft any large-size exilir</li><li>Craft any Training Manual - Craft any Training Manual</li><li>Delight a robot with his favorite gifts - Give favorite gifts to WALL-E</li><li>Dig up a root vegetable with many eyes - Harvest Potatoes</li><li>Enter into a DreamSnaps contest - Submit a DreamSnap</li><li>Feed Squirrel critters their favorite food - Feed Squirrels their favorite food</li><li>Feed the Sunbird critters their favorite food - Feed Sunbirds their favorite food</li><li>Fish somewhere Trustworthy - Go fishing in the Glade of Trust</li><li>Fish somewhere valorous - Go fishing in the Forest of Valor</li><li>Fish somewhere forgotten - Go fishing in the Forgotten Lands</li><li>Fish somewhere frosty - Go fishing in Frosted Heights</li><li>Fish somewhere that's always sunlit - Go fishing in Sunlit Plateau</li><li>Get crafty! - Craft any item</li><li>Give Arendelle's queen her favorites - Give favorite gifts to Anna</li><li>Give Hades or Maui their favorite gifts - Give favorite gifts to Hades or Maui</li><li>Give a book-loving villager her favorite gifts - Give favorite gifts to Belle</li><li>Give a curious villager her favorite gifts - Give favorite gifts to Alice</li><li>Give a stargazing wayfinder gifts - Give favorite gifts to Moana</li><li>Give a villager his favorite gifts - Give favorite gifts to any villagers</li><li>Give any restaurateur in the Valley their favorite gifts - Give favorite gifts to Remy or Tiana</li><li>Give favorite gifts to a tiny Space Ranger - Give favorite gifts to Buzz Lightyear</li><li>Give favorite gifts to the queen of Pride Rock - Give favorite gifts to Nala</li><li>Give gifts to a blonde - Give favorite gifts to Elsa, Kristoff, or Rapunzel</li><li>Give residents of Halloween Town their favorite gifts - Give favorite gifts to Jack Skellington or Sally Gift</li><li>Give some feathered Villagers their favorite gifts - Give favorite gifts to Daisy, Donald, or Scrooge</li><li>Give the Sea Turtle critter their favorite food - Feed Turtles their favorite food</li><li>Give visitors from the Alice in Wonderland Realm their favorite gifts - Give favorite gifts to Alice or the Cheshire Cat</li><li>Go fish! - Go fishing</li><li>Harvest Canola - Harvest Canola</li><li>Harvest something white and fluffy - Harvest Cotton</li><li>Have a chat with a demigod - Have a daily discussion with Maui</li><li>Make small talk - Have a daily discussion with any villager</li><li>Mine for square gems - Mine for Amethyst, Emerald, Ruby, Sapphire, Topaz, or Spinel</li><li>Mine for blue gems - Mine for any blue gem</li><li>Mine for green gems - Mine for any green gems</li><li>Mine for oval gems - Mine for Aquamarine, Citrine, Garnet, Peridot, Tourmaline, or Blue Zircon</li><li>Mine for purple gems - Mine for any purple gems</li><li>Mine for red gems - Mine for any red gems</li><li>Mine for something shiny - Mine for any shiny gems</li><li>Mine for white gems - Mine for any white gems</li><li>Mine for yellow gems - Mine for any yellow gems</li><li>Mine precious gems with a Royal Tool - Mine for any shiny gems</li><li>Open up fresh Memories - Find Memory Orbs</li><li>Pick the fruits that put Snow White to sleep - Harvest Apples</li><li>Practice MINE-fulness - Mine any node</li><li>Say "bonjour" to a tiny chef - Have a daily discussion with Remy</li><li>Serve meals at Chez Remy - Serve meals at Chez Remy</li><li>Serve meals at Tiana's Palace - Serve meals at Tiana's Palace</li><li>Serve meals at in Chez Remy - Serve meals at Chez Remy</li><li>Serve some hungry customers - Serve meals at Chez Remy or Tiana's Palace</li><li>Spend time with a villager - Hang out with any villager</li><li>Tackle Royal Tasks - Complete Dreamlight Duties</li><li>Uproot Night Thorns - Remove Night Thorns or Splinters of Fate</li><li>Whip up a 3-star meal - Cook any 3-star meals</li><li>Work a shift at either restaurant - Serve meals at Chez Remy or Tiana's Palace</li></ul><p>For more on Disney Dreamlight Valley, take a look at our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-dreamlight-valley-guide/1100-6507201/" data-ref-id="1100-6507201">comprehensive guides hub</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530978&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hasbro-announces-new-star-wars-jedi-survivor-black-series-figures-launching-this-year\/1100-6530978\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530590&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-switch-2-amiibo-are-even-more-expensive-than-expected\/1100-6530590\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530648&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-dune-atreides-royal-ornithopter-gets-big-discount-at-amazon\/1100-6530648\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523349&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-collectors-edition-soundtrack-restocked-at-amazon\/1100-6523349\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530999&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-switch-online-adds-another-fire-emblem-gba-game\/1100-6530999\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6531006&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-season-2s-shocking-episode-could-have-been-even-more-violent-but-director-said-no\/1100-6531006\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530099&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nba-2k-play-will-let-you-join-tournaments-for-real-money-from-your-couch\/1100-6530099\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530923&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fanaticals-level-up-sale-features-steep-discounts-on-aaa-games\/1100-6530923\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530944&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-is-crossing-over-with-dark-fantasy-manga-series-berserk-for-its-first-ip-collab\/1100-6530944\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530949&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hello-kitty-island-adventures-fruitful-friendship-update-gives-the-game-a-medieval-spin\/1100-6530949\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530951&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ahead-of-official-oblivion-remastered-release-skyblivion-mod-dev-says-its-a-win-win\/1100-6530951\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530942&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/twisted-metal-season-2-release-date-announced-teaser-sets-up-iconic-characters-introduction\/1100-6530942\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530948&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-big-star-wars-outlaws-surprise-has-been-spoiled-by-a-leak\/1100-6530948\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530956&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/did-nintendo-justify-mario-kart-worlds-80-price\/1100-6530956\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530945&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/rockstar-is-celebrating-4-20-day-in-gta-online-with-hunting-pack-weed-rewards-and-a-yeti\/1100-6530945\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530943&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/final-fantasy-set-to-take-over-magic-the-gatherings-magiccon-in-las-vegas\/1100-6530943\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530930&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/battle-mode-is-back-in-mario-kart-world-two-minigames-confirmed\/1100-6530930\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530932&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/decades-later-mario-64s-baby-penguin-is-still-doomed-in-mario-kart-world\/1100-6530932\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6530931&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/mario-kart-worlds-free-roam-mode-features-missions-hidden-collectibles-and-more\/1100-6530931\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528818&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lunar-remastered-collection-is-available-now-and-exclusive-to-amazon\/1100-6528818\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remaster Without DRM? GOG Wants It To Happen]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/oblivion-remaster-without-drm-gog-wants-it-to-happen/1100-6531043/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remaster-without-drm-gog-wants-it-to-happen.1171236/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/oblivion-remaster-without-drm-gog-wants-it-to-happen/1100-6531043/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531043">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered was released by surprise on April 22, and it's available on PC via Steam. But the game is not available on the popular DRM-free store, GOG.</p><p>In a <a href="https://x.com/GOGcom/status/1915017604592177422" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">social media post</a>, GOG congratulated Bethesda on the game's launch, and said, "We'd love to have this beauty on our platform so you can grab it DRM-free and keep it yours forever."</p><p>GOG added Oblivion Remastered to the <a href="https://www.gog.com/dreamlist/game/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-deluxe-edition-2025" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">"GOG Dreamlist,"</a> which is a collection of games not available yet on GOG. Users can vote for Oblivion Remastered to come to GOG on the page, and submit stories and comments about why they think it should. More than 1,300 people have signed the petition so far.</p><p>"Your votes and shared stories matter, and they're the best way to show the whole world that the games you love should live forever," GOG said.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.gog.com/dreamlist/game/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-deluxe-edition-2025" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">top-upvoted comment</a> on the Oblivion Remastered GOG Dreamlist page includes a user saying Steam is "too intrusive" and all other game-launchers are "annoying or unstable." Another popular comment mentioned GOG's existing relationship with Bethesda to bring 2016's Doom and 2011's The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim to GOG.</p><p>While GOG doesn't have Oblivion Remastered, it is <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Oblivion+Remaster+Without+DRM%3F+GOG+Wants+It+To+Happen&amp;fnauthor=eddienoteddy&amp;fndate=2025-04-23+05%3A34%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-04-23+05%3A54%3A48&amp;fnarticle_id=6531043&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=News&amp;fntype3=Standard+News&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.tkqlhce.com%2Fclick-100770772-15232592%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.gog.com%252Fen%252Fgame%252Felder_scrolls_iv_oblivion_game_of_the_year_edition_deluxe_the&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Foblivion-remaster-without-drm-gog-wants-it-to-happen%2F1100-6531043%2F%3Fftag%3DGSS-05-10aac1i&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">selling Oblivion's original Game of the Year Edition for only $5 right now</a> as part of a special sale.</p><p>Not all new games launch on GOG right away due in part to the store's anti-DRM policies, and Oblivion Remastered is just the latest example.</p><p>To get a closer look at Oblivion Remastered, check out the screenshot gallery below. The game is available to buy for $50--or cheaper at GameSpot sister site Fanatical--while Game Pass Ultimate members can grab it as part of their membership. If you want all the horse armor, you'll have to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/oblivion-remastered-is-still-charging-for-horse-armor-dlc-history-repeats/1100-6531023/" data-ref-id="1100-6531023">pretend like it's 2006 again and pay extra.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>