<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 17:06:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Riot Games is preparing for the next generation of players]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/how-riot-games-is-preparing-for-the-next-generation-of-players</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-riot-games-is-preparing-for-the-next-generation-of-players.1127007/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/how-riot-games-is-preparing-for-the-next-generation-of-players<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In 2010, the team at </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League of Legends</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Riot Games was feeling nervous. Their scrappy multiplayer online battle arena (MOBA) was taking off, but a few hours south in Anaheim, Blizzard was preparing to launch </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Starcraft II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, a blockbuster PC strategy game that could eat up their audience and smother </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> before it had a chance to explode. It was an inflection point for the studio and game industry as a whole. Both companies were asking the same fundamental question: "what do players want from online games?"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Things worked out fine for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League of Legends</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. 16 years after launch, it's still logging millions of daily average players and driving millions in revenue for Riot Games, which has since spun up other titles like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Teamfight Tactics</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Valorant</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">—and is about to dive into the tag-team fighting game genre with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://2xko.riotgames.com/en-us/">2XKO</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Now, the company—and the game industry as a whole—are asking that question again.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A lot has changed in those 16 years. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/riot-games-100-million-gender-discrimination-settlement-granted-preliminary-approval">Riot Games</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/activision-blizzard-settles-california-discrimination-suit-for-54-million">Blizzard Entertainment</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> had to grow up. Both have settled lawsuits with the California Civil Rights Department over allegations of sexual harassment in the workplace, and both </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/riot-games-lays-off-staff-to-solve-challenges-and-build-for-the-future-">have laid</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> off </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-microsoft-follows-activision-blizzard-merger-with-1-900-layoffs">workers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in the face of rising production costs and plateauing player spending.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> players have aged, meaning many can't commit as much time or physical effort into mastering their favorite champions. Younger players, raised on a feast of survival crafting games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Minecraft</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> or social UGC games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Roblox</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, have different tastes. And as studio co-founder and chief product officer Marc Merrill pointed out to Game Developer in a conversation at DICE 2025, audience expectations for what are now called "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/what-the-heck-is-happening-with-live-service-games-">live service games</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" are higher than ever, raising the stakes for projects that sometimes require hundreds of millions of dollars to get off the ground.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">So, how does the company move forward? Merrill said Riot is eyeing at the "social interactions" that are driving conversation about online games of late, but it's also sticking to its original strategy: converting players into people who say "I play </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League of Legends</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">," instead of "I play video games."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="2XKO"><span>2XKO</span>'s social lobby will be key to its success</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Unlike MOBAs or tactical first-person shooters, fighting games have survived and thrived since the arcade eras thanks to robust, often player-driven meetups where players cheer each other on (or throw around trash talk) in real life. Riot has a history of spinning up esports events, but Merrill acknowledged meeting this community where it lives will require a more different approach.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But a more interesting question was this: while Riot's publishing arms get </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>2XKO</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in front of players, how will the development team help players socialize online? The answer is in the game's pre-match lobby. As the company's revealed in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://2xko.riotgames.com/en-us/news/announcement/whats-in-2xko-alpha-lab/">its closed alpha tests,</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> players spend time between matches not staring at a matchmaking screen, but navigating a digital arcade using customizable avatars.</span></p><p><iframe title="Embedded content" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-WiTEnvhilw?si=wsYrsv2KLgRnBlIV" height="315px" width="100%" allowfullscreen="" data-testid="iframe-video" loading="lazy"></iframe></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Riot's not the first to roll out a feature like this. Capcom's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Street Fighter VI</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has a similar lobby feature. But in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>2XKO</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s case you can see the groundwork for what you might call a "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Roblox</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">-ification" of online spaces. Emotes, character skins, the ability to just run around in circles next to your friends (making it a space for players who might just want to relax and chat with pals instead of square up for matches).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Players in the lobby can even walk over to other arcade cabinets to peer at games in progress—certainly a more engaging way to spectate other games without navigating menus.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Riot's been experimenting with its pre-game lobby design for several years, going so far as to update the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League of Legends</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> launcher to allow players to pre-select what roles they'd like to play before entering a lobby—a significant move that cemented the fixed roles players take on in League matches (top lane, mid lane, "jungler," etc.).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's an effective menu, but it's also overwhelming for new or (speaking from recent personal experience) returning players. "You can dunk on it," Merrill said in reference to the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> main menu as we compared and contrasted the two systems.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A perhaps unfair ribbing of the menu screen experienced by most of Riot Games' customers' aside (that is carefully maintained and updated by hardworking developers, the compare-and-contrast allowed us to discuss Riot's top-level strategy for the "lifespan" of its online games—and how taking a wide a view as possible of that lifespan is essential to its continued market position.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Avoiding conventional &quot;industry logic&quot; about online games">Avoiding conventional "industry logic" about online games</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Merrill laid out two ideas about the future of online games that he fundamentally disagrees with. First, he said it's "absurd" to think that young </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Roblox</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> players are forever bound to the block-based game's ecosystem, "A lot of times the social motivations and [desire] to play where your friends are playing—those things are incredibly powerful," he said. "But that doesn't mean if somebody grew up in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Roblox</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, that all they're gonna do for their life is played like block games or a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Roblox-like</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">." Those players—like any other player—are on the hunt for experiences that resonate with them, those experiences may just take different forms.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The second idea, was that the only way for a company to view an online game's lifespan was through the lens of growth, peak, and inevitable decline. If you followed that logic, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League of Legends</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> would be considered a failure since its monthly average user count </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://prioridata.com/data/league-of-legends/">is estimated</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to have peaked in 2022.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"One thing we try to fight a lot is the mindset that the product life cycle is one of growth, a spike, and then a slow decline. That's also silly," he said. "There is entropy, there's downward pressure, it's hard to keep people engaged over a long period of time and continue to make it fresh. But that doesn't mean there aren't incredible things to do to improve the experience."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Those "things" might not just be updates to the content pipeline. Riot's triple-pronged strategy of esports, animated adaptations, and music productions are all part of the strategy to sustain </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League of Legends</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> even though it may not be as popular as it was in the 2010s. "That would never have happened if we were like 'well, you know, we start to see churn rates increasing, time to go move all resources to something else,'" said Merrill.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Devs who want to follow this strategy but maybe don't have Riot's cash can still study its success. "Look at it from a motivational lens," he continued. "Why do people like this game in the first place? And then it's, are [you] doing a sufficient job of delivering to those expectations or not?" He pointed to Blizzard's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/what-blizzard-is-doing-to-make-sure-world-of-warcraft-never-gets-old">World of Warcraft</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as another game executing on this strategy (without an animated Netflix show in sight...just don't ask about </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0803096/">a certain 2016 feature film</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Elsewhere, Riot continued experimenting in a bid to minimize the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/riot-games-is-taking-cross-team-chat-out-of-league-of-legends-to-curb-toxicity">infamous toxicity</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that's become affiliated with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League of Legends</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Merrill repeated the company's talking point that in-game harassment is far less prevalent than it may seem from the outside (but the few bad eggs going above and beyond to hurt people have a big impact, he acknowledged), but there are fascinating new frontiers to explore. Of late, he said Riot is studying how the dynamics of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> matches drive toxicity, sometimes driven by a misalignment between what different teammates want out of a match.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Some [toxic] players feel justified on what they're doing and why," he said, laying out a use case where a player in the "ADC" role (a damage-focused role in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>League of Legends</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">) might feel frustrated by a "support" player not keeping up with them or being repeatedly taken out by the enemy team.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Or there's the inverse—where a support player is playing passively and has an ADC teammate they can't keep up with. Across millions of games being played, some percentage of them will trigger that "emotional spike" for players, and they'll say a thing they might not say otherwise. He compared it to how even the most mild-mannered of people will get aggressive when caught in traffic.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Identifying those mismatches is relatively easy. The solutions are tricky. He said Riot is examining if there are matchmaking solutions to help players looking for similar experiences, saying it's an "untapped frontier." But if Riot overcommits to that strategy, it risks taking away some of the friction of a competitive multiplayer game.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If there's one takeaway for other developers from the multi-pronged approach Riot is taking to changing player demographics, it's that you don't have to look at the popular interest in emerging genres as a sign players aren't into your game. Times change, tastes change, and companies can risk falling behind the curve—but you don't have to look at tomorrow's players as an impossible enigma. Just like yesterday's, they're searching for great experiences, and there's good odds your game might just be what they're looking for.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pantaloon launches micro-indie publishing label to champion 'small games with big hooks']]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/pantaloon-launches-micro-indie-publishing-label-to-champion-small-games-with-big-hooks-</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pantaloon-launches-micro-indie-publishing-label-to-champion-small-games-with-big-hooks.1126917/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/pantaloon-launches-micro-indie-publishing-label-to-champion-small-games-with-big-hooks-<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Indie newsletter and resource hub Pantaloon has launched a publishing label to provide a "home for misfits."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company said it hopes to bring weird and wayward games to market in the micro-indie space.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Pantaloon will offer full brand-lead marketing campaigns, release management and store optimization, production and QA services, development financing, and more.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Pantaloon operates in the micro-indie space, looking to build a label of small games with big hooks. For now, our dev-budgets are in the $30k-$100k sort of range, but we strive to be as flexible as possible on this front," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.pantaloon.io/label-terms">reads an explainer on the Pantaloon website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Pantaloon looking for an &quot;offbeat quality&quot; in projects">Pantaloon looking for an "offbeat quality" in projects</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Pantaloon isn't handcuffed to a genre. We do look for a theme, however. An aesthetic. An intangible offbeat quality that simply makes your game bizarre. We want to explore uncharted genre-waters and find new combinations of systems that haven’t been brought together before."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The label will typically offer a 70/30 revenue split in favor of developers but is prepared to take a smaller cut. Developers who sign with Pantaloon will retain full ownership of their IP and won't be locked into a contract thanks to the use of open termination clauses. In addition, Pantaloon explained it will never force a recoup upon its partners.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The company hopes those terms will "restore the broken power balance in the indie publishing world."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Pantaloon's publishing slate currently includes </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sub-Verge</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> from New Zealand-based developer Interactive Tragedy and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Occlude</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> from UK studio Tributary Games. It will also be handling the Steam release of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Puzzletrunk</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Label founder Jamin Smith said the world "probably doesn't need another indie publisher" but hopes Pantaloon can find success by operating with a different set of principles.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"With an existing awareness platform and terms that give novel agency and security to development partners, we then seek to actively court risk, finding peculiar or experimental games that can chart unexplored or choppy genre-waters," he added.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"'A home for misfits' is more than just a tagline; it’s a call to arms for games that don’t fit traditional publishing structures."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>