<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 16:38:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 GameChat -- Everything We Know About The Console's "Defining" Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-gamechat/1100-6531425/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2-gamechat-everything-we-know-about-the-consoles-defining-feature.1185474/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-gamechat/1100-6531425/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531425">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">One of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Switch 2</a>'s new features is GameChat, a feature so important that Nintendo created a dedicated button, the C button, for it. There are quite a few things to know about GameChat for Switch 2, so we're rounding up everything we've learned so far ahead of the Switch 2 launch on June 5.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="What_is_GameChat_"><strong>What is GameChat?</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">GameChat is a new feature for the Switch 2 that allows groups of up to 12 people to chat while playing games. Nintendo is often criticized for being late to the game when it comes to online functionality, and many have pointed out that GameChat offers what Discord has for years. But GameChat is a built-in service for Switch 2 that Nintendo has been <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/ask-the-developer-vol-17-gamechat-part-1/">working on since 2020</a>, and the company believes it is a "defining" feature of the Switch 2.</p><p dir="ltr">Nintendo's developers said the company wanted to replicate the experience of a "student lounge," that is, a place where people gather and mingle.</p><p dir="ltr">For GameChat on Switch 2, people can share their screens in real time, and they don't have to be playing the same game. Nintendo said, "We wanted to create a space where people would naturally gather, whether it's to play the same game together, or different games, or even just to watch."</p><p dir="ltr">Nintendo said it foresees the possibility of players using GameChat to help them get through a particularly challenging puzzle or part of a game. If two people are playing the same game but separately, one person can ask a friend for help, and the other person can <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/ask-the-developer-vol-17-gamechat-part-1/">share their screen.</a></p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fVjRBTy5irI" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fVjRBTy5irI" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2 dir="ltr" id="The_C_Button"><strong>The C Button</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">Nintendo said it believed it would be "bothersome" to have to pause a game, return to the Home screen, and then launch a GameChat session. So the designers convinced the hardware team to create a dedicated button, the C button, to launch GameChat from. Nintendo's designers said this was a "very last-minute request," and it was made "just before" the Joy-Con controller molds were made. As you can see in the image below, the C button is located at the bottom of the right Joy-Con.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4491211-screenshot2025-05-09at11.03.33am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4491211" data-ratio="0.53649956024626" data-width="1137" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4491211-screenshot2025-05-09at11.03.33am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4491211"></a><figcaption>Behold, the C button (effect added). </figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4491211-screenshot2025-05-09at11.03.33am.png"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Camera_And_Microphone_Support"><strong>Camera And Microphone Support</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">GameChat for Switch 2 leverages the console's built-in microphone, while users can also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/">connect a USB-C camera</a> for video chats. Nintendo is selling its own Switch 2 camera, while a third-party company is offering a<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-official-camera-for-nintendo-switch-2-is-available-to-preorder/1100-6530549/"> Piranha Plant-themed camera. </a>The built-in microphone contains noise-cancelling technology so only the desired sounds come through. Nintendo says someone in the same room could be making a smoothie in a blender and it wouldn't negatively impact the audio quality of a GameChat chat.</p><p dir="ltr">GameChat is baked into Nintendo titles like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-9-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6528874/" data-ref-id="1100-6528874">Mario Kart World</a> and Super Mario Party Jamboree, allowing players to see live footage of their friends and hear them speak in real time during gameplay. As you can see in the image below, GameChat allows users to have multiple feeds at the bottom of their main screen, showing what friends are up to. In some games, like Mario Kart World, your friend's faces can be placed next to their characters, so you can see them during matches.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4491216-screenshot2025-05-09at11.36.04am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4491216" data-ratio="0.57327586206897" data-width="1160" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4491216-screenshot2025-05-09at11.36.04am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4491216"></a><figcaption>What GameChat looks like on Switch 2 with the camera and different games.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4491216-screenshot2025-05-09at11.36.04am.png"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="GameChat_Won_t_Be_Free_Forever"><strong>GameChat Won't Be Free Forever</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">When the Switch 2 launches in June, everyone can use GameChat for free. However, GameChat will become a paid service included with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/heres-everything-coming-to-nintendo-switch-online-when-nintendo-switch-2-launches/2900-6407/" data-ref-id="2900-6407">Nintendo Switch Online</a> beginning April 1, 2026. Some have speculated that Nintendo is going to raise the price of Nintendo Switch Online memberships, too, but that hasn't happened yet.</p><p dir="ltr">Given that GameChat will be a paid Nintendo Switch Online feature in 2026, the C button will be useless for people who don't have a paid membership. Rest assured, though, that pressing the C button without a membership <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/what-happens-if-you-press-the-switch-2s-c-button-without-nso-now-we-know/1100-6530684/">will not lead to anything bad happening.</a> Instead, pressing the button will take you to a page encouraging you to sign up for NSO.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Video_Quality"><strong>Video Quality</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">During the April Nintendo Direct for Switch 2, Nintendo showed off GameChat and many people remarked that the video quality didn't look all that great. The frame rate, in particular, was choppy to say the least. Nintendo explained that it<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-explains-why-switch-2-gamechat-frame-rate-looked-like-that/1100-6530653/"> intentionally made GameChat the smallest footprint possible</a> to save system resources for the games themselves.</p><p dir="ltr">"In order to explain this well, I think it might first help to explain about the resources the system has," Switch 2 hardware director Takuhiro Dohta said, via a translator. "So obviously, chat is meant to run and work simultaneously and coincide with the game you're playing. But we also think it's critical that it doesn't get in the way of the game that's running right now. And so we wanted to definitely make sure we do was to make sure that running game chat alongside the game doesn't result in the game experience or quality being reduced at all in any way.</p><p dir="ltr">"So from a system resource perspective, obviously even the Nintendo Switch had a set of system resources that it needed to tap into to run the system. And now that we have Nintendo Switch 2, there is bigger, more, basically resource budget to use. However, even with that enhanced and larger budget, we try to use as little of that as possible. And they made it happen somehow. And within that small slice of the resource budget, there's other things to take into consideration, like network systems, all that kind of stuff, and all of that taking into account is where we landed in terms of quality of the video that you saw in the footage."</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Safety_Concerns"><strong>Safety Concerns</strong></h2><p dir="ltr">Nintendo previously outlined the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-camera-nintendo-responds-to-safety-and-spying-concerns/1100-6530594/">steps being taken</a> to ensure safety when using GameChat, including audio and video chats. The company <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-clarifies-how-and-why-switch-2-could-collect-monitor-and-record-your-gamechats/1100-6531419/" data-ref-id="1100-6531419">may collect and record video and audio chats</a>, but only in the event that a report is filed; otherwise, the data is stored locally on the Switch 2 device. To begin with, players will not be able to use GameChat with everyone on their friend list by default.</p><p dir="ltr">"We assume some players will have somebody on their friend list who they've only played online with once, and yet somehow, they ended up accepting their friend request. Given that possibility, players might feel uncomfortable if suddenly everyone on their friend list can invite them to a video chat," Switch 2 designer Sumikazu Ono said. "With that in mind, during the initial setup, you can choose the friends you want to be able to chat with from your friend list before you start using GameChat."</p><p dir="ltr">If you join a room created by a friend, players will only see people you or your friend have approved from GameChat. Before joining a room, players will see if a friend of a friend is in the room--if they don't want to join for any reason, they don't have to.</p><p dir="ltr">With regard to protecting the safety of children, Ono said Nintendo had a "lot of internal discussion" on this topic--it was decided that children under 16 can only use GameChat with people on their friend list if their parent or guardian has given permission via the Nintendo Switch Parental Controls app.</p><p dir="ltr">"In the case of voice chat, once a parent gives their child approval to chat with a particular person, their child will always be able to connect with the approved person from then on," Ono said.</p><p dir="ltr">Nintendo takes an "even more cautious" approach for video chats. "When a child tries to start or join a video chat on their Switch 2, a request is sent to the parent's app. The request must be approved before the video chat can begin. While children may feel a bit restricted, we decided to prioritize safety and require parents to approve the request every time," Ono said.</p><p dir="ltr">The Nintendo Switch 2 camera has a "privacy shutter" that closes when not in use--as such, players should be able to see at a glance if the camera is on or off.</p><p dir="ltr">"We want everyone to feel comfortable using this feature, so we've placed a high priority on safety to avoid any unpleasant experiences. Of course, we want all players to follow the Community Guidelines, even when chatting with friends," Ono said.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Preorder_The_Switch_2"><strong>Preorder The Switch 2</strong></h2><p>The Nintendo Switch 2 launches on June 5, priced at $450 by itself or $500 for a bundle that includes the system and a copy of Mario Kart World. Preorders opened in April, and while the initial stock quickly sold through, there should be more waves of preorders in the time ahead. Be sure to consult <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">GameSpot's Switch 2 preorder guide</a> to help give yourself the best chance at securing a unit for launch. While the Switch 2 remains sold out, you can grab a Switch 2 Camera now. </p><h2 id="_"><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?fntitle=Switch+2+GameChat+--+Everything+We+Know+About+The+Console%27s+%22Defining%22+Feature&amp;fnauthor=eddienoteddy&amp;fndate=2025-05-09+08%3A41%3A00&amp;fnupdated=2025-05-09+08%3A41%3A54&amp;fnarticle_id=6531425&amp;fntype1=Games&amp;fntype2=Features&amp;fntype3=Standard+Feature&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FNintendo-Switch-2-Camera%2F15940906362%26subId1%3Dsubid_value%26subId3%3Dxid%3Afr1746805187947fdi&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fswitch-2-gamechat%2F1100-6531425%2F&amp;event_type=click" rel="sponsored nofollow "> </a></h2>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Killing Floor 3 Launches In July After Getting Delayed Earlier This Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/killing-floor-3-launches-in-july-after-getting-delayed-earlier-this-year/1100-6531424/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/killing-floor-3-launches-in-july-after-getting-delayed-earlier-this-year.1185393/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/killing-floor-3-launches-in-july-after-getting-delayed-earlier-this-year/1100-6531424/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531424">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">This summer just got a bit bloodier, as Tripwire Interactive has revealed that Killing Floor 3 will come out July 24. This new release date comes roughly two months after <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/killing-floor-3-delayed-post-launch-update-to-undo-a-controversial-change/1100-6529977/">the co-op FPS was delayed from its original March launch</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Tripwire creative director Bryan Wynia explained that the team has used the extra time to address player issues from the beta. Areas that the studio have focused on include the UI, animations, and design. For example, Tripwire previously showed off a redesigned HUD on <a href="https://forums.tripwireinteractive.com/index.php?threads/kf-3-community-update-hud-enhancements.2341565/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the game's forums</a> that offers a "sleeker, reorganized design and a revamped color scheme." In addition, retuned hit reactions from enemies were showcased <a href="https://x.com/KillingFloor/status/1912968900787994628" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on X</a> last month.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1168204955" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465678,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Killing%20Floor%203%20Is%20Exactly%20What%20It%20Needs%20To%20Be%20%28Hands-On%20Impressions%29&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:514,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/killing-floor-3-is-exactly-what-it-needs-to-be-hands-on-impressions\/2300-6465678\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465678\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465678\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465678\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465678&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465678,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531424&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;killing-floor-3&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,first-person,shooter&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;tripwire-interactive&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;killing-floor&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;killing-floor&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465678},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465678\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4442638-screenshot2025-02-11at4.38.58%E2%80%AFpm.png&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/TqlrfLHz.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1739365200,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="TqlrfLHz" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Killing Floor 3 Is Exactly What It Needs To Be (Hands-On Impressions)</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">"Since delaying the launch of Killing Floor 3, we've dedicated the additional development time to responding to the community's feedback, ensuring the next chapter in the much-loved cult action/horror franchise lives up to our shared vision," Wynia said in a press release.</p><p dir="ltr">This correlates with the delay from earlier this year. In March, Tripwire also promised a post-launch update to Killing Floor 3 that will separate perk classes from characters. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/killing-floor-3-has-three-editions-physical-preorders-available-now/1100-6529177/">Digital preorders are live once again</a> on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S storefronts.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/killing-floor-3-looks-like-2025s-killer-co-op-game/1100-6529407/">Killing Floor 3 could be this year's killer co-op game</a>, letting six people team up to take out bioengineered monsters called Zeds. It's set 70 years after Killing Floor 2, which was released almost a decade ago in 2016.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bam Margera Officially Returning For Tony Hawk Pro Skater 3+4]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bam-margera-officially-returning-for-tony-hawk-pro-skater-34/1100-6531423/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bam-margera-officially-returning-for-tony-hawk-pro-skater-3-4.1185390/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bam-margera-officially-returning-for-tony-hawk-pro-skater-34/1100-6531423/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531423">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Bam Margera has officially confirmed that he'll be in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-release-date-trailer-songs-game-pass/1100-6529971/">Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3+4</a>. When the remakes were first announced, Margera's name was noticeably absent from the roster. In a video posted on Activision's social media channels, Margera teased that he'll be present in the game as a secret skater.</p><p>Why Margera wasn't included at first hasn't been revealed yet, but co-host Roger Bagley of the skating podcast The Nine Club (via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/bam-margera-will-be-in-tony-hawk-34-after-all-after-hawk-intervened-its-claimed/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">VGC</a>) did claim that Tony Hawk lobbied for Margera to be added to the game. Bagley added that there was no updated character model for Margera, so he was flown up to developer Iron Galaxy Studios to have his body and face scanned, footage of which you can see in the video below.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="625356902" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465967,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Tony%20Hawk%E2%80%99s%20Pro%20Skater%203%20%2B%204%20-%20Bam%20Margera%20%7C%20Behind%20The%20Scenes%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:54,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-bam-margera-behind-the-scenes-trailer\/2300-6465967\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465967\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465967\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465967\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465967&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4491175-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/huwjM0h6.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1746797400,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="huwjM0h6" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3 + 4 - Bam Margera | Behind The Scenes Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Since Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3+4 was first announced, more details on the game have slowly been revealed. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-every-skater-revealed/2900-6310/">The rest of the roster has been confirmed</a>, and if you don't feel like playing as a digital recreation of legends like Rodney Mullen or Eric Koston, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tony-hawks-pro-skater-3-4-preorders-are-live-collectors-edition-includes-skateboard/1100-6529864/">you can step into the armored boots of the Doom Slayer</a> if you preorder the game. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tony-hawks-pro-skater-34-soundtrack-revealed-includes-mix-of-new-and-old/1100-6530119/">The full soundtrack has also been revealed</a>, and there's a healthy selection of old favorites from the original games and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tony-hawk-is-to-blame-or-credit-for-34s-controversial-soundtrack-changes/1100-6530488/">new tracks that Hawk himself picked</a>.</p><p>"Ace of Spades" by Motorhead, "96 Quite Bitter Beings" by CKY, "Amoeba" by Adolescents, are some of the classic tunes you can kickflip to as part of the substantially expanded soundtrack. Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3+4 arrives on July 11, and it'll launch for PC, PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, and Switch 2.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33's New Patch Nerfs The Strongest Party Member]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33s-new-patch-nerfs-the-strongest-party-member/1100-6531420/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33s-new-patch-nerfs-the-strongest-party-member.1185351/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33s-new-patch-nerfs-the-strongest-party-member/1100-6531420/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531420">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Sandfall Interactive and Kepler Interactive have released Patch 1.2.3 for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33/" data-ref-id="5000-631965">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>, and it nerfs Maelle, a party member who can deal absolutely massive amounts of damage with the right character build.</p><p>Expedition 33 is a turn-based RPG, and each <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-party-members-in-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-their-abilities/2900-6501/" data-ref-id="2900-6501">party member</a> acquired over the course of the game has a set of abilities that offer up a distinct playstyle. Maelle's abilities center around switching between Offensive, Defensive, and Virtuose stances to maximize defense or damage. But a powerful late-game ability called Stendahl was a little too powerful, and with the right Pictos equipped, players can deal several million in damage using this ability.</p><p>On May 8, the developers admitted that they made Stendahl a little too powerful and would <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/expedition-33-patch-will-fix-one-of-the-most-broken-builds-in-the-game/1100-6531392/" data-ref-id="1100-6531392">nerf it in the next patch</a>. Now that the patch notes are here, Stendahl damage has been reduced by a whopping 40%. While that's a pretty massive nerf, Maelle's Medalum weapon now doubles all damage in Virtuose stance. This patch also brings improved widescreen support with it, and gets rid of a lot of areas where players could get stuck while exploring the world map.</p><p>Don't expect this to be the final balance pass for Expedition 33 either, as the <a href="https://www.expedition33.com/post/patch-notes-v1-2-3" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">patch notes</a> tease that more is on the way. "This is the first in a series of patches we are looking to do over the coming months," Sandfall Interactive says. "We are still investigating many feature requests and issues for future updates." You can read the Patch 1.2.3 notes below:</p><h6>Steam Deck</h6><ul><li>Fixed backgrounds of various menus not displaying properly on the Steam Deck</li></ul><h6>Xbox Game Pass</h6><ul><li>PC GAMEPASS: PS5 controllers are now compatible</li></ul><h6>Various Ultrawide Fixes</h6><ul><li>Gameplay no longer becomes zoomed after a cutscene occurs in ultrawide resolutions</li><li>The Options menu image will no longer be stretched in ultrawide resolutions</li><li>Combat UI now adapts correctly to ultrawide resolutions</li><li>Game will no longer minimize upon changing settings in ultrawide resolution</li><li>Cutscenes won’t letterbox in 32:9 aspect ratio</li><li>Title screen now displays fullscreen when the game is launched in ultrawide resolution</li></ul><h6>Mouse and Keyboard</h6><ul><li>UI button prompts in Expedition Menu are now visible and fully able to be triggered with Keyboard</li><li>Mouse buttons do not become unresponsive after first use</li><li>With mouse cursor on screen, using 'WSAD' or directional arrows to navigate in UI or trigger any other functionality will no longer hide the cursor instead of doing the intended action</li><li>Left Mouse-button click will no longer block the player from using Keyboard to navigate menus</li><li>Mouse input is not lost after the first Jump counter attack if it is pressed only once</li><li>Each year, the number decreases, erasing more lives. Soon, she will mark “33.” When she does, we will embark on our final mission—to destroy the Paintress and end her deadly cycle for good.</li></ul><h6>Fixed areas of the world map where you can get stuck:</h6><ul><li>Between lanterns scattered on the ground near Stone Wave Cliff portal</li><li>While walking on the ship wreck near the Forgotten Battlefield level entrance</li><li>Between lanterns on the ground near Bourgeon encounter next to Stone Wave Cliffs level</li><li>Between two small rocks located between Spring Meadows and Abbest Cave</li><li>Between vases and corals when jumping from rooftopps</li><li>Between various rocks</li><li>In ruins behind Flying Manor level entrance</li><li>Near the bridge between Flying Waters and Spring Meadows</li><li>In the rocks on the World Map, near Flying Waters</li><li>Next to hardened land, close to the Flying Waters location exit</li></ul><h6>Fixed situations where Esquie specifically would get stuck (poor guy):</h6><ul><li>When taking off from paint bridges, making him fall through the bridge and restrict movement</li><li>When flying into bottom parts of levitating structures near Visages</li><li>Near the Flying Waters entrance level</li><li>Near a giant hammer when traversing close to Blades' Graveyard level</li></ul><h6>Weapon and skill fixes and tuning:</h6><ul><li>Fixed Lithelim attribute scaling not working at high level. Reduced initial Vitality scaling from A to C (will still end at S at max level). Added Luck scaling starting at D.</li><li>Fixed Blizzon attribute scaling not working at high level. Reduced initial Luck scaling from B to C (will still end at S at max level). Added Defense scaling starting at D.</li><li>Fixed Medalum third Lumina doubling all damage in Virtuose Stance instead of doubling only Burn damage.</li><li>Stendhal: Reduced damage by 40%.</li></ul><h6>Other fixes</h6><ul><li>Boss encounter in Stone Wave Cliffs can now be finished on NG+</li><li>You will no longer be blocked by the Journal UI window after opening the first Journal in the Spring Meadows</li><li>Fixed being unable to shoot in Free aim while exploring levels due to worn triggers</li><li>Lune and Monoco no longer spawn in same place during end of theirs Level 6 relationship quests if they are completed without going to camp</li><li>If at camp you pick “remember the objective”, then quickly choose to "go to sleep" and immediately after press "leave", the screen no longer goes black</li><li>You can no longer trigger the "Discovering the truth" cutscene in Old Lumière a second time in a row, splitting the party forever with only Verso and Maelle in it.</li><li>Update to rolling credits</li></ul><p>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is available for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S. You can try it out through Xbox Game Pass if you aren't already one of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-numbers-keep-climbing-as-more-players-jump-into-the-rpg/1100-6531328/" data-ref-id="1100-6531328">2 million people</a> who have bought the game.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>