<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 20:06:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hello Kitty Island Adventure's Fruitful Friendship Update Gives The Game A Medieval Spin]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hello-kitty-island-adventures-fruitful-friendship-update-gives-the-game-a-medieval-spin/1100-6530949/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hello-kitty-island-adventures-fruitful-friendship-update-gives-the-game-a-medieval-spin.1167249/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hello-kitty-island-adventures-fruitful-friendship-update-gives-the-game-a-medieval-spin/1100-6530949/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530949">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/hello-kitty-island-adventure/">Hello Kitty Island Adventure</a>'s latest seasonal content drop--the Fruitful Friendship update--is available now on Apple Arcade.</p><p dir="ltr">Starting on April 18, players can join Kitty White, Kuromi, My Melody, and the rest of the Sanrio crew in the Imagination Celebration, a medieval-themed limited-time event complete with princess dresses, suits of armor, wizard robes, and castle-worthy furniture. Players must help Hello Kitty &amp; Co. collect Mystic Stones to restore magic to the Kingdom of Friendship. The Imagination Celebration Event ends on May 22.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mthep19u6aw" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Mthep19u6aw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">But the Fruitful Friendship update has plenty more in store. It also includes a new feature in which players help Keroppi plant and maintain an orchard located on City Town's rooftops, allowing players to grow 13 new fruits. These new fruits can then be used to concoct new types of Fruit Sandos in the Imagination Cafe.</p><p dir="ltr">The update also includes a City Town newcomer and new visitor quests. Players can help decorate a cabin to serve as a home for Retsuko's new friend, Puko, and new quests for pre-existing City Town visitors have also been added.</p><p dir="ltr">Lastly, Fruitful Friendship is introducing a number of player-requested quality-of-life improvements, like a map to help players navigate City Town's Sewers and an updated tool wheel.</p><p>But even more seasonal content is on the way, according to developer Sunblink Entertainment, which directed players to "prepare for an <em>egg-cellent</em> island takeover of an iconic Sanrio pal." The developer added that "Players can look forward to exciting content update coming soon."</p><p>Hello Kitty Island Adventure is available to play via Apple Arcade, PC (via Steam), and Nintendo Switch.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lords Of The Fallen 2.0 Update Gets A Surprise Friend Pass Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-update-gets-a-surprise-friend-pass-feature/1100-6530947/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-update-gets-a-surprise-friend-pass-feature.1167192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-update-gets-a-surprise-friend-pass-feature/1100-6530947/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530947">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>CI Games has revealed Lords of the Fallen version 2.0 and it comes with plenty of surprising features, including shared progress co-op saving and a Friend Pass. However, the Steam release has been delayed.</p><p>Co-op was one of Lords of the Fallen's standout features, but now the update lets both players save all main story progress. There are some caveats, though. Both players need to be on the same "New Game" and must have defeated a similar number of bosses. They will retain all loot and 100% vigor.</p><p>There's also a new Friend Pass that lets players invite another person even if they don't own the game. The invited friend gets to keep all loot and character classes.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2jQ3S2JzA9s" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2jQ3S2JzA9s" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The new update adds a dedicated jump button and a refined lock-on function, as well as an overhauled character creator. The animations should look smoother and as a result, weapons and evasions should feel more responsive. The user interface has also been cleaned up, and the Umbral Lamp now can guide players to the next destination.</p><p>In a now-deleted <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1501750/view/527592442371768492" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam blog post</a>, CI Games apparently stated that the <a href="https://wccftech.com/lords-of-the-fallen-2-0-out-now-with-enhanced-combatmovement-and-free-friends-pass" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam release is seeing a small delay due to a technical issue</a>, but the 2.0 update should be live on PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and the Epic Games Store.</p><p>In GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/lords-of-the-fallen-review-dark-slog/1900-6418133/" data-ref-id="1900-6418133">Lords of the Fallen review</a>, we said, "While Lords of the Fallen has all the right Souls-like elements, its disjointed pacing and painful checkpoint system make much of the game a slow and frustrating march."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4 Is Crossing Over With Dark Fantasy Manga Series Berserk For Its First IP Collab]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-is-crossing-over-with-dark-fantasy-manga-series-berserk-for-its-first-ip-collab/1100-6530944/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4-is-crossing-over-with-dark-fantasy-manga-series-berserk-for-its-first-ip-collab.1167126/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-is-crossing-over-with-dark-fantasy-manga-series-berserk-for-its-first-ip-collab/1100-6530944/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530944">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-iv/" data-ref-id="5000-504255">Diablo 4's</a> first external IP crossover event is coming, and it's with none other than the dark fantasy masterpiece, Berserk.</p><p dir="ltr">Blizzard hasn't gone into too much detail on what all the crossover will entail, so far only tweeting out a short animated teaser showing a Brand of Sacrifice-marked Barbarian outfitted with Berserk's iconic Berserker armor and Dragonslayer sword. Considering the teaser doesn't say Diablo 4 specifically (and lists iOS and Android), it looks like the event will come to both Diablo 4 and the free-to-play <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-immortal/" data-ref-id="5000-489022">Diablo Immortal</a>. No other details, including dates for the event or what all it will entail, have been officially announced.</p><p dir="ltr">For those not in the know, Berserk, by the late author Kentaro Miura, is considered a seminal work in the manga space. Not for the faint of heart, it tells the tale of the mercenary known as Guts and his quest to survive a punishing dark fantasy world. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/berserk-creator-kentaro-miura-has-passed-away/1100-6491749/" data-ref-id="1100-6491749">Miura passed away in 2021</a>, leaving the longrunning manga unfinished, though <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/berserk-manga-to-continue-in-2022/1100-6504227/" data-ref-id="1100-6504227">new chapters created by Miura's friend Kouji Mori</a>, alongside Miura's various assistants and apprentices, have slowly been released since Miura's death.</p><p dir="ltr">The manga's influence, from its dark fantasy themes to its iconic suits of armor and weapons, can be seen everywhere. Anytime a character uses a comically oversized sword, Berserk is likely the inspiration, and games like From Software's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/dark-souls/" data-ref-id="5000-83346">Dark Souls</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/elden-ring/" data-ref-id="5000-497664">Elden Ring</a> haven't shied away from wearing their Berserk influences for all to see.</p><p dir="ltr">While Berserk is the first external IP to be featured in Diablo (with another IP crossover slated for later this year, according to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-2025-roadmap-highlights-new-crossovers-endgame-updates/1100-6530666/" data-ref-id="1100-6530666">Diablo 4's 2025 roadmap</a>), both Diablo 4 and Diablo Immortal did crossover with another Blizzard IP, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft</a>, last year. That crossover was to celebrate World of Warcraft's 20th anniversary, and saw a number of pricey WoW-themed armor sets and cosmetics inspired by some of the game's iconic characters like Sylvanas Windrunner and The Lich King added to Diablo 4's premium shop. Various cosmetics and WoW-themed items also appeared in Blizzard's Diablo mobile game.</p><p dir="ltr">The Berserk crossover will be coming as part of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-8-is-all-about-bosses-and-its-bringing-back-a-fan-favorite/1100-6530012/" data-ref-id="1100-6530012">Diablo 4 Season 8, which will overhaul the game's endgame bosses</a> and see the return of a fan-favorite from Diablo 3, Belial. Diablo 4 Season 8 begins April 29.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New DLC Gets Price Cut Before Release Due To "Events Happening In The World"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-dlc-gets-price-cut-before-release-due-to-events-happening-in-the-world/1100-6530941/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-dlc-gets-price-cut-before-release-due-to-events-happening-in-the-world.1167123/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-dlc-gets-price-cut-before-release-due-to-events-happening-in-the-world/1100-6530941/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530941">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Rockfish Games has announced that it's dropping the price of its upcoming DLC expansion for Everspace 2 ahead of its May 12 release due to "events happening in the world."</p><p>The expansion, Wrath of the Ancients, was originally going to cost $30. However, Rockfish Games reduced the price to $25. The studio also recently reduced the price of Everspace 2's first expansion, Titans, from $15 to $12.</p><p>Rockfish Games clarified that even though the price for Wrath of the Ancients has been lowered, no content has been cut from it. It contains new stories, side quests, enemies, and a new playable Wraith ship.</p><p>"As an independent studio, we are lucky to be in a position to be able to do this based on the support of an amazing community," Rockfish Games said in a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1128920/view/524214742651240614?l=english" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam blog post</a>. "If you were genuinely looking forward to giving us that little bit extra, thank you! We will have a new artbook and soundtrack gathering together content from our DLCs available when Wrath of the Ancients launches that you can put that money towards instead."</p><p>The studio didn't specify "events happening in the world," but acknowledged the rising costs of everything and feelings of uncertainty. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-prices-have-increased-in-some-regions-but-not-the-us/1100-6530829/" data-ref-id="1100-6530829">PS5 console</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-plus-prices-have-increased-in-certain-regions-but-not-the-us/1100-6530919/" data-ref-id="1100-6530919">PS Plus prices</a> have increased, and certain games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-defends-mario-kart-worlds-80-price-tag/1100-6530643/" data-ref-id="1100-6530643">Mario Kart World are now $80</a>. It's also possible that Rockfish Games is referring to the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/esa-says-tariffs-will-have-a-detrimental-impact-on-entire-gaming-industry-not-just-nintendo/1100-6530636/" data-ref-id="1100-6530636">Trump tariffs that are impacting the video game industry</a>.</p><p>Everspace 2 is an open-world space shooter that follows Adam, a clone pilot who aims to escape the Demilitarized Zone of Cluster 34. It features a robust single-player campaign, plenty of side missions, loot, and additional challenges to partake it in. Everspace 2 is available on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>