<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 05:00:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Panzer Dragoon 2 Zwei: Remake May Be Near Release Date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/panzer-dragoon-2-zwei-remake-may-be-near-release-date/1100-6534600/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/panzer-dragoon-2-zwei-remake-may-be-near-release-date.1293162/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534600">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In 2020, a remake of Sega's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/panzer-paladin-review/1900-6417520/" data-ref-id="1900-6417520">Panzer Dragoon</a> was released on modern consoles by Forever Entertainment. Now, a remake of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/panzer-dragoon-ii-zwei/" data-ref-id="5000-5090">Panzer Dragoon 2 Zwei</a> is on the horizon from Forever Entertainment and developers MegaPixel Studio and Storm Trident. It may even be coming sooner than expected.</p><p><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/panzer-dragoon-ii-zwei-remake-confirmed-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc-first-details-and-screenshots" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gematsu</a> shared the announcement that Panzer Dragoon 2 Zwei: Remake will make its public debut September 25-28 at the Rainy Frog booth at the 2025 Tokyo Game Show. The publisher didn't share a release date, but the game will be available on Nintendo Switch, Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 4, and PlayStation 5.</p><p>Panzer Dragoon 2 Zwei was originally released in 1996 on Sega Saturn as a prequel to the first game. Players assume control of Jaen Jaqeue Lundi, a young man who defies convention by raising and training a dragon named Lagi. The dragon is the players' means of transport and their primary weapon in the game, as Lagi and Jaen face an onslaught of deadly enemies while uncovering secrets of lost civilizations.</p><p>Like the original, Panzer Dragoon 2 Zwei: Remake will be a rail shooter. It will also have some modern touches, including branching routes and an evolution of Lagi's powers that depends upon players' performance and play style. Additionally, players can utilize a berserk attack and replay mission variants after the campaign is finished.</p><p>Fans who buy Panzer Dragoon 2 Zwei: Remake will have the option of choosing between classic and modern controls. The game will also feature modernized graphics as well as a remastered version of the soundtrack included alongside the original score.</p><div data-embed-type="html"><p><i>Click the button below to add GameSpot as a preferred source on Google</i></p></div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/panzer-dragoon-2-zwei-remake-may-be-near-release-date/1100-6534600/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2's Festival Of The Lost Is Getting New Activities; Check Out The Armor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2s-festival-of-the-lost-is-getting-new-activities-check-out-the-armor/1100-6534597/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destiny-2s-festival-of-the-lost-is-getting-new-activities-check-out-the-armor.1293030/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534597">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">After several years of plundering Lost Sectors to kill pumpkin-headed bosses, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/destiny-2/" data-ref-id="5000-463450">Destiny 2</a> players will have some new spooky activities to complete when this year's Festival of the Lost rolls around.</p><p dir="ltr">Bungie mentioned a few changes coming to Destiny's yearly Halloween event during its <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/cwlUS_JcarQ" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">livestream</a> detailing the upcoming <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/destiny-2-regenades-everything-we-just-learned-about-the-star-wars-inspired-expansion/2900-7004/" data-ref-id="2900-7004">Renegades expansion</a>. Alongside the yearly drops of themed cosmetic armor and special weapons, developers mentioned both a new six-player PvE activity and a three-player PvP activity.</p><p dir="ltr">The six-player activity is called Haunted Altars, and according to Destiny design lead Clayton Kisko, it sees the Headless Ones--huge Halloween-themed boss monsters who sport pumpkins where their heads used to be--finally escaping from the Lost Sectors where they've been holed up for previous festivals. As for the PvP activity, it's called Red Rumble. Bungie didn't provide any details as to what the activities will actually be, but they should shake up the formula of raiding Lost Sectors, which has been the mainstay activity since back before the release of the Beyond Light expansion.</p><p dir="ltr">This year also sees the return of "hocus-focusing," which allows you to pick the loot you'll receive during the event. You'll need Eerie Engrams, which drop from Festival activities, and Candy, the currency you'll get throughout the Festival of the Lost period. Hocus-focusing allows you to receive specific weapons from the Festival loot pool, or to grab Exotic gear, as long as you have the Candy to pay for it.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4564623-destiny2festivalofthelost2025armor.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4564623" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4564623-destiny2festivalofthelost2025armor.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4564623"></a><figcaption>Destiny 2's Festival of the Lost armor for 2025</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4564623-destiny2festivalofthelost2025armor.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Alongside a few new details about Destiny 2's Halloween celebration, Bungie also showed off this year's Festival of the Lost cosmetic armor ornaments, which are themed around pop-culture killers. Players voted between armor sets themed on Slashers and Specters back in January, but it seems as though Bungie combined elements of both groups into the final armor set.</p><p dir="ltr">Hunters can grab armor themed around the look of a ghostly bride (which also blends in some of the Ghost Face-esque look inspired by the slasher from the Scream movies); Titans get a look inspired by hockey mask-wearing murderer Jason Vorhees of Friday the 13th; and Warlocks can dress up as a creature akin to the internet's favorite tall spindly faceless child-stalker, the Slenderman.</p><p dir="ltr">As usual, those armor ornaments will be available through the Eververse Store for Silver, Destiny 2's premium currency--so don't expect to earn them through gameplay.</p><p>Bungie ran down lots of details about Renegades during the livestream, as well as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2s-power-grind-should-get-less-grindy-in-renegades-expansion/1100-6534592/">changes it's making to Destiny 2's loot and Power grind</a>, based on player feedback.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2s-festival-of-the-lost-is-getting-new-activities-check-out-the-armor/1100-6534597/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iPhone 17 Supports 120Hz, Uses Similar Cooling Tech To Xbox One X]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/iphone-17-supports-120hz-uses-similar-cooling-tech-to-xbox-one-x/1100-6534595/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/iphone-17-supports-120hz-uses-similar-cooling-tech-to-xbox-one-x.1293027/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534595">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Today, during its latest livestreamed reveal presentation, Apple unveiled the iPhone 17 and its four different models: iPhone 17, iPhone Air, iPhone 17 Pro, and iPhone 17 Pro Max. While the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/iphone-17-officially-announced-with-four-new-versions/1100-6534588/">"impossibly thin" iPhone Air</a> has grabbed headlines, each member of this new generation of iPhone features a pair of new tech additions that mobile gaming enthusiasts will particularly find interesting.</p><p dir="ltr">First is the new Super Retina XDR display, which not only features the Ceramic Shield 2 for better protection, but will also support ProMotion up to a 120Hz refresh rate. NetEase's free-to-play RPG Destiny Rising has been confirmed to be among the first iOS games to utilize the 120Hz tech.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4564616-iphone-17-pro.png" data-ref-id="1300-4564616" data-ratio="0.57430488974113" data-width="2086" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4564616-iphone-17-pro.png" data-ref-id="1300-4564616"></a><figcaption>iPhone 17 Pro</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4564616-iphone-17-pro.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Next is the vapor chamber cooling technology, which was also a feature of the Xbox One X. This cooling tech is designed to "enhance heat dissipation and performance" thanks to deionized water sealed inside the chamber, which is "laser-welded into the aluminum chassis to move heat away from the powerful A19 Pro, allowing it to operate at even higher performance levels," according to the <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2025/09/apple-unveils-iphone-17-pro-and-iphone-17-pro-max/" rel="nofollow ">official announcement</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Other gaming-relevant features found in the new set of iPhones include the A19 Pro chip, which sports a 6-core CPU and GPU architecture that Apple says will "deliver up to 40% better sustained performance than the previous generation." The new N1 wireless networking chip, meanwhile, will support Wi-Fi 7, Bluetooth 6, and Thread for online multiplayer games.</p><p dir="ltr">The iPhone 17 in all of its forms is set to launch September 19, with preorders scheduled to begin one week prior on September 12.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/iphone-17-supports-120hz-uses-similar-cooling-tech-to-xbox-one-x/1100-6534595/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft's Superman DLC Is Out Now, And Adorable Pup Krypto Is Included]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/minecrafts-superman-dlc-is-out-now-and-adorable-pup-krypto-is-included/1100-6534590/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecrafts-superman-dlc-is-out-now-and-adorable-pup-krypto-is-included.1292997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534590">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The new DC movie Superman did very well in theaters this year, and now there is a new DLC pack based on it that's available in Minecraft.</p><p>Developed by <a href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/marketplace/creator/oreville-studios" rel="nofollow ">Oreville Studios</a>, the Superman DLC (<a href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/marketplace/buy-minecoins" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">1,510 Minecoins</a>) includes 11 skins in all. You can play as Superman and use some of his powers like super strength, heat vision, and super breath to take down enemies in Metropolis like Lex Luthor. Players can visit Superman's Fortress of Solitude or just chill with Krypto the dog.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E4Ba84ak570" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/E4Ba84ak570" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Oreville Studios also worked on Minecraft DLC based on Disney's The Incredibles and Rovio's Angry Birds, among others.</p><p>Superman the movie from director James Gunn and starring David Corenswet earned more than $600 million worldwide this year, ranking as the <a href="https://www.boxofficemojo.com/year/world/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">No. 7 biggest movie of 2025 so far.</a> A sequel, Man of Tomorrow, is coming to theaters in July 2027.</p><p>Minecraft is one of the best-selling games in history, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/top-10-best-selling-video-games-of-all-time/2900-4814/#1" data-ref-id="2900-4814">surpassing 300 million copies sold.</a> The game has welcomed all manner of licensed crossovers, including The Simpsons, Halo, SpongeBob, and so many more. A Minecraft Movie, released earlier this year, grossed more than $950 million globally and is the No. 3 highest-grossing movie of 2025.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/minecrafts-superman-dlc-is-out-now-and-adorable-pup-krypto-is-included/1100-6534590/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>