<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 20:09:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brutal Co-Op Beat 'Em Up Terrifier: The ARTcade Game Gets November Release Date]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/10/23/brutal-co-op-beat-em-up-terrifier-the-artcade-game-gets-november-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/brutal-co-op-beat-em-up-terrifier-the-artcade-game-gets-november-release-date.1333291/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Art the Clown from the Terrifier series of horror movies has sliced through three movies so far and is even a marquee haunted house at Universal's Halloween Horror Nights season of events this year. He'll soon be tearing into games, though, as <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/terrifier-the-artcade-game">Terrifier: The ARTcade Game</a> is launching on PlayStation 5 and PC via Steam next month on November 21.&nbsp;</p><p>Publisher SelectaPlay and developer Relevo revealed this news with a new gameplay trailer highlighting the special occasion. This trailer also features Terrifier: The ARTcade Game's theme song, which is composed by Cody Carpenter, the son of horror legend and <em>Halloween </em>creator John Carpenter. Not surprisingly, Carpenter follows in his father's footsteps with a nightmare-inducing synth-fueled theme for Art the Clown in video game form.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Check it out for yourself in the latest Terrifier: The ARTcade Game trailer below:&nbsp;</strong></p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XNZp1zCvGTA"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XNZp1zCvGTA" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>As you can see, Terrifier: The ARTcade Game features vibrant pixel art, but it's still full of the blood and guts you expect if you've seen Art the Clown on the silver screen. While you can go it solo, the game also features local co-op for up to four players, and you can work together (or against each other) in various game modes while using a variety of weapons like chainsaws, cleavers, and more.&nbsp;</p><p>SelectaPlay says players can expect multiple stages with different paths to explore, plenty of enemies to defeat, boss battles at the end of each stage, a chiptune soundtrack, finisher attacks, and six game modes when Terrifier: The ARTcade Game launches on PlayStation 5 and PC on November 21.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Are you going to check out Terrifier: The ARTcade Game next month? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/10/23/brutal-co-op-beat-em-up-terrifier-the-artcade-game-gets-november-release-date]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>