<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:16:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur Celebrates Its Game Awards Blowout With A Major New Update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/clair-obscur-celebrates-its-game-awards-blowout-with-a-major-new-update/1100-6536925/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1381501</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536925">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It was almost a foregone conclusion, but Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 absolutely crushed it at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-game-awards-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-7341/" data-ref-id="2900-7341">The Game Awards</a> this year, taking home little polygonal statues for <a data-target="true" href="https://www.gamespot.com/">a record-setting number of categories</a> it was nominated for. When the game's director, Guillaume Broche took the stage, he thanked <a data-target="true" href="https://www.gamespot.com/">a number of individuals</a>, but he ended his speech by giving a very special thank you to us, the players, not with a speech, but with a rather sizable update for the game that dropped the second he walked on stage to accept the award.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6WPmS4eSknc" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6WPmS4eSknc" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Dubbed "The Thank You Update", this is no mere costume/weapon set, though there's over a dozen each of those to go find too. This is an all-encompassing update that brings everything from quality-of-life updates--a Picto/Lumina filter, a long-overdue photo mode, and an option to escape from battles, to a completely new area called "Verso's Drafts," with a bunch of new story content, mostly about Verso's childhood, and the final music tracks written by Lorien Testard for the game.</p><p>You can watch the trailer for it here, but, really, we're very sorry, this is a Jack from Lost situation now; you're gonna have to go back and play. The Thank You Update/patch 1.5.0 is available right now on all platforms. The full patch notes are below:</p><h3><b>New Content</b></h3><ul><li>Verso's Drafts, a new playable environment, taking the characters of Expedition 33 to a brand-new location with new enemy encounters and surprises to discover :)  <ul><li>Located on the World Map, next to Lumière - Accessible from Act III</li><li>Esquie’s Underwater ability is required!</li></ul></li><li>New text and UI game localizations into Czech, Ukrainian, Latin American Spanish, Turkish, Vietnamese, Thai, and Indonesian, bringing the total number of supported languages to 19, with more to come!</li><li>New costumes for each member of the Expedition, giving even more customization options for players throughout their adventure</li><li>New boss battles for late-game players to overcome in the Endless Tower - They are variations of iconic bosses from the main game, designed to be even more challenging</li><li>Added new Luminas and Weapons</li><li>Added the "Old Key" quest item to the final area of the game - Previously obtainable only during the Prologue, this addition gives players a second chance to collect all journals within a single playthrough</li></ul><h3><b>New Features</b></h3><ul><li>Added Photo Mode with plenty of settings and options for players to get creative with while capturing your favourite moments from the game, accessible at any time from the pause menu!</li><li>Added Lumina Sets feature, allowing players to save up to 50 different lumina loadouts for adapting to plenty of different fighting tactics at any moment</li><li>Added Abandon Battle option in the pause menu which can now be opened in battle</li><li>Added HUD Scale setting, allowing players to adjust the size of in-game HUD elements from 80% to 120%</li><li>Added FSR 4 support, including AMD temporal upscaling for sharper visuals and Frame Generation for smoother gameplay on compatible GPUs</li><li>Added new filters for Pictos and Luminas and improved the UI</li><li>Added input remapping for controller</li></ul><h3><b>Handheld PC improvements</b></h3><ul><li>The game is now certified on Steam Deck and ROG Xbox Ally!</li><li>Global improvement of text legibility</li><li>Fixed multiple fog and lighting issues:  <ul><li>Overly intense effects during the Flying Manor boss fight (which also impacted some cinematics)</li><li>Overexposed areas in the Visages</li><li>Overly dark areas in the Endless Tower</li></ul></li><li>Fixed FPS being capped at 30 on Steam Deck</li><li>VSync can now be properly disabled in the settings when playing on Steam Deck</li><li>Graphic settings are now adjusted for Steam Deck users</li><li>Improved first-time setup flow:  <ul><li>Controller input is now supported in installation wizards (no longer touchscreen-only)</li></ul></li><li>External controllers now switch seamlessly with the Steam Deck controls</li></ul><h3><b>Bug Fixes</b></h3><ul><li>Fixed an issue where using Battle Retry after a cinematic or automatic trigger could spawn the player out of the world if the last save was created in a different location</li><li>The playtime displayed on save files now accurately reflects total playtime, including time spent on Game Overs<br>(Note: this fix does not retroactively update existing save files.)</li><li>Fixed inventory behaviour so that sort order now persists after closing the game menu</li><li>Fixed issue preventing Intel XeSS Frame Generation setting from being accessible on PC Game Pass</li><li>Fixed an issue where the usage of particular diacritic marks (e.g. ^, ~, ´, `) in Windows is blocked after launching the title</li><li>Fixed Breaking Death always breaking all enemies when the character dies, it should only break the enemy that killed the character - As a result, it shouldn’t work when the character kills themself anymore</li><li>Characters' turn order during a First Strike, triggered by attacking an enemy on the map, now correctly respects characters' Speed</li><li>Fixed Boucharo giving +150% Critical chance instead of +50% Critical chance</li><li>Fixed some Luminas giving unintended hidden +10% damage:  <ul><li>Sweet Kill</li><li>Teamwork</li><li>Dead Energy II</li><li>First Strike and others</li></ul></li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        <div>
	<p>
		Latest in
		Clair Obscur: Expedition 33
	</p>

	
</div>
  
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/clair-obscur-celebrates-its-game-awards-blowout-with-a-major-new-update/1100-6536925/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Game Awards 2025 Keeps The Legend Of Flute Guy Strong]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-keeps-the-legend-of-flute-guy-strong/1100-6536923/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1381405</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536923">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Each year The Game Awards sees its fair share of viral moments both cringe and heartwarming, but none have persisted through the years quite so much as orchestra member Pedro Eustache--better known as "Flute Guy." Fittingly, Flute Guy once again got his moment in the spotlight this year, showing off his strangest flute variant yet.</p><p>Ever since he <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=26w76OmzEKI" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">went viral in 2022</a> for enthusiastically playing the Xenoblade Chronicles 3 medley on a strange-looking tenor flute, Eustache has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-game-awards-2024-how-to-watch-start-times-and-what-to-expect/1100-6528392/" data-ref-id="1100-6528392">been a regular feature of The Game Awards</a>. Each year he seems to get more dedicated airtime during the orchestral section, playing bigger and more unusual flutes.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1597/15975876/4621613-screenshot%28917%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4621613" data-ratio="0.56235294117647" data-width="1700" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1597/15975876/4621613-screenshot%28917%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4621613"></a><figcaption>Pedro Eustache playing a strange new flute during the Clair Obscur tribute</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1597/15975876/4621613-screenshot%28917%29.jpg"></figure><p>2025, of course, is no different, with Eustache even getting his own announcement video on The Game Awards' <a href="https://x.com/thegameawards/status/1997327335725596961" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">social media pages</a> in the lead up to the show. His appearance in the orchestral section didn't disappoint, with his flute part highlighted through the Death Stranding 2 arrangement, and his part in the Clair Obscur section played on a strange new flute that appears to be made out of PVC pipe.</p><p>Flute Guy, and the whole orchestral mix, added some needed drama to one of the most obvious Game of the Year announcements The Game Awards has seen. Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 became the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-just-made-the-game-awards-history/1100-6536918/" data-ref-id="1100-6536918">most award-winning game</a> in the awards show's history when it picked up nine awards, including Game of the Year. It had previously secured the record for most nominated game, receiving 13 total nominations. Clair Obscur has also been revealed as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-is-gamespots-game-of-the-year-2025/1100-6536771/" data-ref-id="1100-6536771">GameSpot's Game of the Year for 2025</a>.</p><p>For all the rest of the winners, losers, and surprises from The Game Awards 2025, check out our list of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-game-awards-2025-all-the-biggest-announcements/2900-7341/" data-ref-id="2900-7341">all the biggest announcements</a> from the show, as well as our roundup of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-game-awards-2025-winners-nominees/2900-7258/" data-ref-id="2900-7258">all the 2025 winners</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-game-awards-2025-keeps-the-legend-of-flute-guy-strong/1100-6536923/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>