<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 10:49:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BioShock 4 Won't Be Canceled, Promises Take-Two Boss]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bioshock-4-wont-be-canceled-promises-take-two-boss/1100-6533791/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bioshock-4-wont-be-canceled-promises-take-two-boss.1265331/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533791">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>BioShock fans may be understandably curious about the fate of the next game in the series following leaks that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bioshock-remake-cancelled-as-bioshock-4-reportedly-fails-a-review/1100-6533650/" data-ref-id="1100-6533650">BioShock 4 failed an internal review</a> and Cloud Chamber studio head Kelley Gilmore was reportedly ousted by 2K Games as a result. However, Strauss Zelnick--the CEO of 2K Games' parent company, Take-Two Interactive--has essentially promised fans that BioShock 4 is still on the way and it won't be canceled.</p><p>"It's going to come out," Zelnick told <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bioshock-4-is-going-to-come-out-take-two-ceo-strauss-zelnick-promises-that-i-can-say-hand-on-heart-without-question" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IGN</a>. "That I can say hand on heart, without question ... We don't talk about how long our development cycles are. We have had some ups and downs along the way. That is accurate. And we have had changes in studio leadership. That said, we have very big shoes to fill on BioShock because of the legacy of Ken Levine, the legacy of what has gone before, which has been so successful. And we need to make sure that this experience is true to the BioShock DNA on the one hand, and a massive step forward on the other hand. That's always challenging. We think we're up to the challenge, but it has not been seamless."</p><p>The same report that noted BioShock 4's latest setback also indicated that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bioshock-4-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6530162/" data-ref-id="1100-6530162">a remake of the original BioShock was canceled</a> earlier this year. 2K Games acknowledged the original report and called Cloud Chamber's BioShock 4 "good game," but reiterated its commitment "to delivering a great one."</p><p>There hasn't been a new game in the BioShock series since 2013's BioShock Infinite, and a proposed BioShock movie has also had difficulty breaking out of development. Francis Lawrence is attached to direct BioShock at Netflix, and he recently revealed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-tricky-bioshock-movie-is-not-dead-brings-on-a-new-writer/1100-6531560/" data-ref-id="1100-6531560">a new draft of the film has been written</a> by Terminator: Dark Fate scribe Justin Rhodes.</p><p>As for BioShock creator Ken Levine, his next title, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/judas/" data-ref-id="5000-577619">Judas</a>, remains in development at Ghost Story and it will eventually be published by Take-Two. However, a release date for Judas has yet to be announced.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/bioshock-4-wont-be-canceled-promises-take-two-boss/1100-6533791/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Universal Teases Fallout And Five Nights At Freddy's Halloween Horror Nights Houses]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/universal-teases-fallout-and-five-nights-at-freddys-halloween-horror-nights-houses/1100-6533789/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/universal-teases-fallout-and-five-nights-at-freddys-halloween-horror-nights-houses.1265325/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533789">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>This year's Halloween Horror Nights at Universal Studios in California and Universal Orlando in Florida will feature haunted houses devoted to Fallout and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/five-nights-at-freddys-universal-halloween-horror-nights-teaser-features-some-familiar-faces/1100-6533541/" data-ref-id="1100-6533541">Five Nights At Freddy's</a>--and while both are inspired by video games, both houses will lean into their respective live-action adaptations.</p><p>The theme parks haven't shared any of the footage of this year's HHN houses yet, but the creative team on both coasts has offered a few teasers about what fans can expect to see.</p><p>While speaking with <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-features/halloween-horror-nights-houses-fallout-terrifier-five-nights-at-freddys-1236339724/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Hollywood Reporter</a>, Universal revealed that Amazon Prime's Fallout series provided the HHN team with 3D models of Walton Goggins' The Ghoul to ensure that masks used in the attraction are identical to his face on the show. Universal Orlando's Lora Sauls also said that a teaser has been filmed, with "one of their characters for us to tease their second season in the house."</p><p>Universal Orlando's Mike Aiello added that the Fallout house will be a montage of different locations from the show and the games, with appearances by Lucy (played by Ella Purnell in the series), The Ghoul, Maximus (played by Aaron Moten in the series), and a 500-pound animatronic bear.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OWPC6syuNU4" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OWPC6syuNU4" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Speaking of animatronics, the Five Nights At Freddy's house will feature full-size animatronic recreations of Freddy Fazbear and his pals as created by Jim Henson's Creature Shop. Universal Hollywood's John Murdy called them "the most complicated animatronic figures that we’ve ever done" for HHN. He added that guests will "see a fully animated Freddy Fazbear performing like he would in the movie or the video game" in a convincing recreation of the pizzeria that serves as the setting for the games and movies. Even the game's famous security room will be a part of the attraction.</p><p>Universal Orlando will kick off the Halloween festivities with Five Nights At Freddy's on August 29, while Universal Studios will wait a little longer and start the FNAF event on September 4. Halloween Horror Nights on both coasts will run until November 2.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/universal-teases-fallout-and-five-nights-at-freddys-halloween-horror-nights-houses/1100-6533789/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia Says AI Chips Don't Have Kill Switch, Calls Them Open Invitation To Disaster]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nvidia-says-ai-chips-dont-have-kill-switch-calls-them-open-invitation-to-disaster/1100-6533787/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-says-ai-chips-dont-have-kill-switch-calls-them-open-invitation-to-disaster.1265289/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533787">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>No backdoors, no kill switches, no spyware. That's Nvidia's pledge after an accusation from the Cyberspace Administration of China, which asked Nvidia last week to provide documents about security vulnerabilities in Nvidia's H20 data center GPUs, specifically citing "backdoor" security risks. Nvidia responded officially <a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/no-backdoors-no-kill-switches-no-spyware/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">with a blog post</a> the company's chief security officer, David Reber Jr.</p><p>"Embedding backdoors and kill switches into chips would be a gift to hackers and hostile actors," Reber wrote. "It would undermine global data infrastructure and fracture trust in U.S. technology. Established law wisely requires companies to fix vulnerabilities--not create them."</p><p>The Cyberspace Administration of China's concerns stem specifically from the Nvidia's H20 GPU, which is made for the Chinese market and designed to comply with US export guidelines. <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/nvidia-blasts-proposals-for-chip-backdoors-as-us-considers-kill-switch/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Ars Technica notes</a> that U.S. lawmakers are considering a Chip Security Act that would "require exported chips to be built with 'location verification,'" and "calls for an assessment of mechanisms to stop unauthorized use." In other words, a kill switch.</p><p>If you've watched the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@lockpickinglawyer" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lockpicking Lawyer</a> on YouTube for even a couple of minutes, you know there's no such thing as a lock that can't be picked--just ones that require more specialized tools. The same goes for hardware backdoors. Once there's a door there, someone will find a way to walk through it. Something as ubiquitous as Nvidia GPUs, which populate data centers and consumer PCs all over the world, makes for an especially appealing target.</p><p>Reber cites the "<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clipper_chip#Technical_vulnerabilities" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Clipper Chip Debacle</a>," in which the NSA and U.S. government pushed for a chip to be installed in telecommunications devices that would allow backdoor access through an encrypted key. Launched in 1993, security experts found multiple vulnerabilities in the next couple of years, and the chip fell out of favor before it was ever adopted.</p><p>"Security researchers discovered fundamental flaws in the system that could allow malicious parties to tamper with the software," and "that created central vulnerabilities that could be exploited by adversaries." In other words, this kind of backdoor access might give the U.S. government access to GPUs, but it would also give other governments and other malicious actors access as well, with some effort.</p><p>"Some point to smartphone features like 'find my phone'... as models for a GPU kill switch," Reber continued, explaining that those are user-controlled software options. "Hardwiring a kill switch is something entirely different: a permanent flaw beyond user control, and an open invitation to disaster... That's not sound policy. It's an overreaction that would irreparably harm America's economic and national security interests."</p><p>"For decades, policymakers have championed industry’s efforts to create secure, trustworthy hardware," Reber wrote. "Governments have many tools to protect nations, consumers and the economy. Deliberately weakening critical infrastructure should never be one of them."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nvidia-says-ai-chips-dont-have-kill-switch-calls-them-open-invitation-to-disaster/1100-6533787/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take-Two Boss Addresses Rumored Price Hike For Grand Theft Auto 6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/take-two-boss-addresses-rumored-price-hike-for-grand-theft-auto-6/1100-6533788/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-two-boss-addresses-rumored-price-hike-for-grand-theft-auto-6.1265274/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6533788">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>There's been a lot of speculation about the cost of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi/" data-ref-id="5000-569323">Grand Theft Auto 6</a>, with some companies <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-costing-100-could-reward-players-too-analysts-argue/1100-6529948/" data-ref-id="1100-6529948">hoping that it will debut at $100</a> to open the door for more games to drop at that price. The current ceiling for gaming prices appears to be $80, but Strauss Zelnick--the CEO of Rockstar Games' parent company, Take-Two Interactive--doesn't seem to be very enthusiastic about raising the price for GTA 6.</p><p>"I think our approach may be a little bit different," replied Zelnick when asked about pricing GTA 6 at $80 during Take-Two's August 7 investor call. "We believe that any consumer experience is the intersection of the thing itself and what you paid for the thing. So our goal is to vastly exceed expectations. We want to put out the best entertainment on Earth, and we want to deliver more value than what we charge for it. We think we've generally speaking, gotten that right."</p><p>"Variable pricing has been the nature of this industry forever," added Zelnick. "You know, most Frontline releases will go out at a higher price, sometimes with special editions, and then over time usually the price is discounted to optimize for the largest possible market. And I don't think that's going to change anytime soon ... The rubric that informs us is really that of delivering more value than what we charge."</p><p>Earlier this week, Alinea Analytics' Rhys Elliott laid out a similar argument about why <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-doesnt-need-to-cost-100-because-gta-online-is-the-real-cash-cow-analyst-says/1100-6533731/" data-ref-id="1100-6533731">it's a bad idea to launch GTA 6 at $100</a>. Elliot suggests that GTA Online is the real cash cow for the franchise, and Rockstar can't risk alienating the players who have stayed with the game for well over a decade now. He also noted that a higher price point raises the risk of players sticking with GTA 5 over its much-anticipated sequel.</p><p>In other GTA news, former Rockstar employee--and longtime in-game DJ--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-unlikely-to-feature-this-longtime-in-game-radio-host/1100-6533727/" data-ref-id="1100-6533727">Lazlow Jones recently revealed he's unlikely to return for GTA 6</a>. However, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-could-carry-forward-this-feature-from-gta-5/1100-6532421/" data-ref-id="1100-6532421">real-world musicians may still have a few radio stations of their own</a> in the upcoming sequel.</p><p>Grand Theft Auto 6 will hit PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S on May 26, 2026.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/take-two-boss-addresses-rumored-price-hike-for-grand-theft-auto-6/1100-6533788/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>