<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:28:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Nintendo Switch 2 has topped 17 million sales worldwide]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-nintendo-switch-2-has-topped-17-million-sales-worldwide</link>
            <guid>1423684</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">February 3, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Hardware image via Nintendo</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Nintendo Switch 2 continues to outpace its predecessor after selling 17.37 million units worldwide.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2026/260203_3e.pdf">As noted in Nintendo's fiscal report for the past nine months</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the console launched on June 5, 2025, and reached that milestone on December 31, 2025.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For context, the original Switch sold 17.79 million units by March 2018—just over a year after it hit shelves on March 3, 2017.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sticking with the Switch 2 for a moment, Nintendo said hardware sales were driven by the "Nintendo Switch 2 + Mario Kart World Bundle" and "Nintendo Switch 2 + Pokémon Legends: Z-A – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Bundle."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As you might expect, the success of those bundles had a positive impact on software sales. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Kart World</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has now sold 14.03 million units worldwide since launching alongside the Switch 2, while </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Pokémon Legends: Z-A </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">has recorded sales of 8.41 million units.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Other notable sellers include </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Donkey Kong Bananza</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (4.25 million units sold) and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kirby Air Riders</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (1.76 million units sold). Overall, the Switch 2 has delivered cumulative software sales of 37.93 million units worldwide.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-union-representatives-call-for-resignation-of-ceo-yves-guillemot" target="_self" data-discover="true">Ubisoft union representatives call for resignation of CEO Yves Guillemot</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The original Switch cements its place in history&nbsp;">The original Switch cements its place in history&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo recorded consolidated net sales of 1.9 trillion yen ($12.2 billion) over the past nine months—an increase of 99.3 percent year-on-year.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sales declined by 10.1 percent year-on-year within the company's IP related business, mainly due to an increase in revenue related to The Super Mario Bros. Movie (although a sequel will touch down in April).&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Digital sales increased by 14.7 percent to 282 billion yen ($1.8 billion) over the same nine-month period and accounted for 50.4 percent of total software sales.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Nintendo Switch boasted around 129 million annual playing users during the 2025 calendar year, which is perhaps unsurprising given the console has now sold 155.37 million units worldwide to become the best-selling console in Nintendo history.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The handheld-hybrid looked certain to steal the crown from the Nintendo DS for some time, but has now cemented its place in the record books.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo said the "connections" it built with consumers through the Nintendo Switch have supported the smooth launch of the Switch 2.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Looking ahead, Nintendo hopes the launch of new titles such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Pokémon Pokopia</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Tennis Fever</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Yoshi and the Mysterious Book </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">will continue to drive momentum.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-nintendo-switch-2-has-topped-17-million-sales-worldwide]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft union representatives call for resignation of CEO Yves Guillemot]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-union-representatives-call-for-resignation-of-ceo-yves-guillemot</link>
            <guid>1423630</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">February 3, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>5 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Two Ubisoft union representatives have warned that it will be impossible for company management to rebuild trust with employees while long-serving CEO, Yves Guillemot, remains in power.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Speaking to Game Developer about the current climate at the French publisher, Marc Rutschlé and Chakib Mataoui—who both ply their trade at Ubisoft Paris and serve as union representatives for Solidaires Informatique—indicated staff at the company panicked and angry after experiencing what they described as a "betrayal" from top management.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rutschlé and Mataoui shared their views just weeks after the French publisher </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-is-dismantling-its-studio-ecosystem-to-become-a-more-gamer-centric-company">announced a sweeping "reset"</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that kicked off with studio closures, game cancellations, the promise of more cost-cutting, and the announcement of a return-to-office (RTO) mandate that will require staff to work on-site five days a week.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Screenshots of internal messages viewed by Game Developer suggest the initial response to that announcement was one of widespread shock, disbelief, and condemnation.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/qa-workers-at-blizzard-ratify-union-contract-with-microsoft" target="_self" data-discover="true">QA workers at Blizzard ratify union contract with Microsoft</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Guillemot himself was also called out in multiple messages posted on the company's internal communications platform, Agora, with some employees questioning why he remains in charge after presiding over what will eventually be five years of downsizing when Ubisoft concludes its €500 million cost-reduction plan in 2028.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the wake of that announcement, Rutschlé and Mataoui feel Guillemot must head for the exit if there is any hope of the company regaining the trust of its employees. Although Rutschlé doesn't believe Ubisoft's struggles are solely the fault of Guillemot, he explained that as CEO he is ultimately responsible.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It's his company, at the end of the day," says Rutschlé. "But everyone around him are just yes men. That was also the issue during the sexual [harassment] scandal in 2020."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When asked directly whether he would like to see a change in leadership at the very top, Rutschlé had a simple answer: "Sure. I expect nothing from this guy."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a sentiment shared by Mataoui, who questioned Guillemot's decision to name his son, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-announces-leadership-for-tencent-backed-subsidiary">Charlie Guillemot</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, as co-CEO of a new subsidiary that will house some of the company's biggest franchises. He said that, apart from being an instance of nepotism, Guillemot's habit of promoting those closest to him is negatively impacting Ubisoft's ability to craft hit video games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"If you just put your white male friends in [those jobs], then you don't promote any diversity or get any new opinions or ideas," continued Mataoui. "We are in a creative job. We need new ideas to come in to [help us] make great new games. But we don't have that. We don't have this mindset for creativity."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-ashes-of-creation-developer-intrepid-studios-shuts-down" target="_self" data-discover="true">Report: Ashes of Creation developer Intrepid Studios shuts down</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Mataoui said it feels as if the current cohort of Ubisoft executives "don't understand their social responsibility to employees" and suggested that workers themselves should be able to elect people to oversee the company. "I'd rather have a manger who I consent to give my workforce, than a manager who I cannot trust. The situation right now is that we don't trust these people," he added.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Notably, both Mataoui and Rutschlé said the management team at Ubisoft failed to actively rebuild bridges with employees after the company was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-ubisoft-paradox-how-the-publisher-enabled-a-culture-of-abuse-and-control">accused of enabling a culture of fear and control in 2020</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> by allegedly cultivating a workplace where abusers could thrive.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rutschlé explained those reports, coupled with the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nft-peddler-ubisoft-complains-that-players-simply-don-t-get-the-pitch">company's decision to enter the divisive NFT market</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> shortly after, only served to eradicate any remaining goodwill between workers and management.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Now, he said it feels as if there is no going back. "I think Guillemot should move away at this point," said Rutschlé. "I think the level of hate people have for him [means] he should move on. Then, we could build some sort of trust again."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Five-day return-to-office mandate has left some Ubisoft workers feeling &quot;doomed&quot;">Five-day return-to-office mandate has left some Ubisoft workers feeling "doomed"</h2><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/analyzing-the-2026-gdc-state-of-the-industry-report-game-developer-podcast-ep-63" target="_self" data-discover="true">Analyzing the 2026 GDC State Of The Industry Report - Game Developer Podcast Ep. 63</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The return-to-office policy announced by Ubisoft is viewed as particularly incendiary by Rutschlé and Mataoui, who said it shows a complete disregard for the personal wellbeing and livelihoods of employees.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Most [employees] were very, very panicked by the [RTO] announcement because they started their lives very far from Paris and from their studios—and now they're being asked to come back knowing that their paycheck doesn't help with living in the Paris area," said Mataoui.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rutschlé agreed with that assessment and suggested there is a feeling of impending "doom" internally, with the RTO policy again being called out as particularly egregious. "The whole return-to-office policy is very hard to take," said Rutschlé, who claimed Ubisoft must be aware it will cost some employees—such as those who might have recently purchased homes or who have families—their jobs at the company.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He added that Ubisoft previously struck agreements with some employees that facilitated a level of remote working. Those, he suggested, have now been torched without reason. "We asked them for documentation or analysis that showed a link between production or creativity with the return to the office. They had none," Rutschlé continued. "So it's like 'okay, let's do that then.' As a union representative, I'm like 'what the fuck, man?.'"&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rutschlé suggested the newly-announced restructure and ongoing cost-cutting is simply a way for Ubisoft to "make big announcements that make shareholders happy." Those announcements, however, have sometimes rubbed shareholders the wrong way (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://insider-gaming.com/investors-demand-ubisoft-to-renegotiate-tencent-deal/">thanks Insider Gaming</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) and tanked Ubisoft's valuation on the stock market (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/ubisoft-shares-tumble-after-assassins-creed-creator-unveils-restructuring-2026-01-22/">via Reuters</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Mataoui claimed the only way Ubisoft can now course-correct is to remove the entire board of directors and recruit "fresh minds" who are willing to lead with integrity and accountability. Rutschlé said it's also vital for Ubisoft workers across the world—especially in locations such as Montreal, which is viewed as an influential studio within the company—to organize in order to secure their own futures and hold management to account.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Join the unions," said Rutschlé, when asked whether he has a message for his colleagues across the globe. "At least organize yourself within your workplace, because our bosses are speaking to each other so we should do that too."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ubisoft workers will have the opportunity to stand shoulder-to-shoulder later this month as part of an </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-it-s-time-for-real-accountability-ubisoft-unions-call-international-strike">international strike</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that has been called by Solidaires Informatique and four other unions based in France.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-union-representatives-call-for-resignation-of-ceo-yves-guillemot]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>