<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 20:58:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baby Steps Punishes You In The Funniest Way If You Skip Too Many Cutscenes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baby-steps-punishes-you-in-the-funniest-way-if-you-skip-too-many-cutscenes/1100-6535322/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baby-steps-punishes-you-in-the-funniest-way-if-you-skip-too-many-cutscenes.1320241/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535322">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Literal walking simulator Baby Steps is already a punishing affair, but the game has one last trick up its sleeve that might make certain players fume with rage.</p><p>If you skip enough cutscenes in the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/well-this-esrb-description-sure-is-a-wild-ride/1100-6534659/" data-ref-id="1100-6534659">wacky and raunchy Baby Steps</a>, you'll be treated (or penalized, depending how you look at it) with a meandering 28-minute long cutscene full of meta jokes and haphazard conversation topics, which user Cuttyflame shared on YouTube (per <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/sim/skipping-all-baby-steps-cutscenes-unlocks-a-secret-28-minute-punishment-cutscene/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PC Gamer</a>).</p><p>Baby Steps, which was made by Ape Out developers Gabe Cuzzillo, Maxi Boch, and QWOP creator Bennett Foddy, actively discourages players you skipping story cutscenes, requiring you to complete minigames that increase in complexity each subsequent time you try to skip a scene.</p><p>Skipping around 30 cutscenes results in this shaggy dog story of a cutscene playing at the end of the story, according to Cuttyflame.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mQahQACsvPU" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mQahQACsvPU" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The secret ending cutscene has protagonist Nate, voiced by Cuzzillo, reaching the cabin of donkey-human hybrid Moose, voiced by Foddy. Nate makes some fourth wall-breaking comments about the player skipping cutscenes, beginning a long-winded conversation with a spread of topics.</p><p>From their interest in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/naughty-dogs-new-ip-intergalactic-has-the-deepest-gameplay-the-studio-has-ever-done/1100-6531793/" data-ref-id="1100-6531793">Naughty Dog's next game</a> to their favorite fictional clowns, Cuzzillo and Foddy go on and on, adding in additional jabs toward cutscene skippers and joking that they'll likely skip this scene as well.</p><p>The role of non-interactive cinematics in what is otherwise a very interactive medium of entertainment has always been a subject of debate, but this extended scene almost feels like Cuzzillo and Foddy putting a spotlight on their voicework and shaming players for missing out on it, though all in good fun.</p><p>Baby Steps is currently available only on PlayStation 5 and PC, along with being <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baby-steps-is-steam-deck-verified-meaning-you-can-just-throw-the-whole-system-when-frustrated/1100-6534828/" data-ref-id="1100-6534828">verified for Steam Deck</a>. Just think twice about skipping those cutscenes, though.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baby-steps-punishes-you-in-the-funniest-way-if-you-skip-too-many-cutscenes/1100-6535322/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Company Of Heroes Dev Wants To Release Games Faster But Isn't Going All In On AI]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/company-of-heroes-dev-wants-to-release-games-faster-but-isnt-going-all-in-on-ai/1100-6535317/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/company-of-heroes-dev-wants-to-release-games-faster-but-isnt-going-all-in-on-ai.1320238/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535317">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Company of Heroes developer Relic Entertainment is keen to make and release games faster, CEO Justin Dowdeswell said in a new interview, but the company isn't banking on AI to get there.</p><p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/why-relic-entertainment-wants-to-make-games-more-quickly" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GI.biz</a>, Dowdeswell said one of the company's Achilles heels is that it has taken too long to release new games. "There's long stretches of time between game releases, and you lose touch with the players, people lose touch with what you're up to--and they generally cost a lot more, the longer they take," he said.</p><p>Part of what Relic will look to do in the future is "get to market more frequently," and that doesn't mean the company wants to lower the quality bar and simply ship things faster for the sake of it.</p><p>How can Relic achieve this? Already, the studio has improved how fast it can prototype new ideas, Dowdeswell said, noting that staffers can now get a prototype up and running in four weeks. The executive added that improving project management and specifically controlling scope is another way.</p><p>Could AI help Relic make games even faster, as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstations-plan-to-use-ai-to-speed-up-development-started-with-spider-man-2/1100-6526809/" data-ref-id="1100-6526809">some developers are attempting</a>? Dowdeswell said businesses around the world today are "trying to figure out" how AI can help them, and right now, AI tools and systems are helpful for Relic in "workflows around the office."</p><p>"Even just reviewing something or summarizing something. I get more done. And I think that there's something in that concept of getting more done, that's part of where the power is," he said.</p><p>As for actual game development, Dowdeswell said humans will continue to be essential to the process. "We still need people making decisions, we still need people coming up with ideas, we still need people creating an architecture," he said. "And for me at least, it's not about replacing people, it's just [about taking] some of the slightly more annoying things off the list and getting them done more quickly. There's power in that."</p><p>Dowdeswell said AI may be able to be implemented in game development to help people with "augmenting skills" they already have.</p><p>Relic "can't ignore" AI, Dowdeswell said, but he's not ready to go all-in yet, either. "So I think understanding how it serves us and where it serves us is the starting point. And then as we gain experience with it, understanding where we want it to stop, I think that's important," he said.</p><p>Another area of concern around AI for Relic is regarding public perception. Right now, Dowdeswell said, "I don't think we have an answer for that," but it's something the studio is "in the middle of figuring out collectively."</p><p>People have concerns about AI for a variety of reasons, including the possibility of job losses, copyright and plagiarism issues, and a number of other elements. Thanks in part to AI, Nvidia's market cap has exceeded $4 trillion and the company is now the world's most valuable by a significant margin. Some have expressed fears of an AI bubble that could pop and lead to a number of negative consequences.</p><p>Sony has been using AI tools for game development for years, crediting machine-learning systems for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstations-plan-to-use-ai-to-speed-up-development-started-with-spider-man-2/1100-6526809/" data-ref-id="1100-6526809">helping speed up development on Marvel's Spider-Man 2.</a> EA Sports said <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-says-cfb-25-would-not-have-been-as-good-without-the-developers-using-ai/1100-6525428/" data-ref-id="1100-6525428">CFB 25 might not have turned out as good without the developers using machine-learning and AI.</a> Meanwhile, Candy Crush developers who got laid off by Activision Blizzard said they are <a href="https://mobilegamer.biz/laid-off-king-staff-set-to-be-replaced-by-the-ai-tools-they-helped-build-say-sources/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">being replaced by AI tools they helped create.</a> A recent report from <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/61cef75e-ceba-43ee-80e3-040756c6154f" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Financial Times</a> said EA might look to further implement AI systems to help ramp up development amid its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/unpacking-eas-55-billion-sale-to-go-private-what-does-it-all-mean/1100-6535168/" data-ref-id="1100-6535168">private sale to an investor consortium.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/company-of-heroes-dev-wants-to-release-games-faster-but-isnt-going-all-in-on-ai/1100-6535317/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-Elder Scrolls Online Devs Behind Canceled MMO Project Blackbird Game Launch A New Studio]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ex-elder-scrolls-online-devs-behind-canceled-mmo-project-blackbird-game-launch-a-new-studio/1100-6535321/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ex-elder-scrolls-online-devs-behind-canceled-mmo-project-blackbird-game-launch-a-new-studio.1320205/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535321">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Earlier this year, Microsoft unleashed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-xbox-games-cancelled-and-studios-closed-in-microsofts-latest-mass-layoffs/2900-6726/" data-ref-id="2900-6726">a massive wave of layoffs</a> and game cancellations, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-cancels-new-mmo-from-elder-scrolls-online-team-in-latest-wave-of-cuts-report/1100-6532915/" data-ref-id="1100-6532915">Project Blackbird</a>, an MMO that was described as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-details-emerge-about-elder-scrolls-online-teams-reportedly-canceled-mmo/1100-6533760/" data-ref-id="1100-6533760">a cross between Cyberpunk 2077 and Destiny</a> from the team behind The Elder Scrolls Online. Now, that team has reunited to form an employee-owned studio, Sackbird Studios.</p><p>The studio shared the announcement on <a href="https://www.sackbirdstudios.com/news/studio-takes-flight" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">its official site</a>, and noted that Sackbird is self-funded "for multiple years" without the aid of outside investors. That will allow the team to retain full creative control of their own games.</p><p>"After years in AAA, we wanted the freedom to take smart risks without waiting for a greenlight or chasing quarterly targets, said Sackbird Studios chief creative officer David Worley in a statement. "We're fully employee-owned and funded, which means we only answer to people who are passionate about games."</p><p>"We're grateful for our time at ZeniMax Online Studios; it shaped us as developers and as people," added Sackbird CEO Lee Ridout. "When I learned that Blackbird was being cancelled and a lot of people were losing their jobs, it lit a fire. We realized the best way to protect our craft--and our team--was to create a studio where creative independence isn't negotiable."</p><p>The announcement notes that there are under ten current employees in the studio. Sackbird isn't ready to disclose its first game yet beyond sharing that it will be an original project, which will be available on PC and consoles. The studio also reaffirmed the team's desire to craft "bold, character-driven experiences free from corporate compromises."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ex-elder-scrolls-online-devs-behind-canceled-mmo-project-blackbird-game-launch-a-new-studio/1100-6535321/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Outer Worlds 2 Is Getting Some Pricy Customizable Xbox Controllers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-outer-worlds-2-is-getting-some-pricy-customizable-xbox-controllers/1100-6535316/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-outer-worlds-2-is-getting-some-pricy-customizable-xbox-controllers.1320109/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535316">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-outer-worlds-2/" data-ref-id="5000-533237">The Outer Worlds 2</a> caused some waves among fans when it was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-outer-worlds-2-releases-in-october/1100-6532242/" data-ref-id="1100-6532242">set to be $80 at launch</a>. Microsoft subsequently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-outer-worlds-2-premium-edition-includes-5-day-early-access/1100-6532295/" data-ref-id="1100-6532295">walked back the price to $70</a>, but if you want to spend extra money, there's a pair of pricey Outer Worlds 2-inspired Xbox controllers heading your way.</p><p>Microsoft has announced that players <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/accessories/controllers/the-outer-worlds-2-xbox-controllers#standard" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">can now purchase controllers</a> adorned with The Outer Worlds 2's Moon Man and art from the game. But the most intriguing part of these controllers is that fans can customize the designs with Xbox Design Lab. For example, players can choose to go for metallic D-Pad and triggers, or opt in on rubber side and back grips.</p><p>There are two different controllers available. The standard Xbox wireless controller will be $95, while the Xbox Elite Wireless Controller Series 2 will go for $185. The Elite model has more features including optional back paddles, thumbsticks with adjustable tension, and a shorter hair-trigger lock. While those controllers aren't cheap, they definitely feel in line with something that the game's Earth Directorate would put out into the universe.</p><p>Earlier this year, Obsidian Entertainment <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/meet-the-outer-worlds-2-companions-whom-you-cant-romance/1100-6534102/" data-ref-id="1100-6534102">introduced the companion characters</a> from The Outer Worlds 2, while stressing that there will be no romance in the game. Obsidian has acknowledged that the developers at <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-outer-worlds-2-has-been-developed-with-help-from-halo-devs/1100-6532744/" data-ref-id="1100-6532744">Halo Studios offered their advice</a> and guidance on the game. The studio also demonstrated that the sequel will allow <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-outer-worlds-2-lets-players-choose-between-first-and-third-person/1100-6532273/" data-ref-id="1100-6532273">players to swap from first-person to third-person at will</a>.</p><p>The Outer Worlds 2 will hit Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC on October 29, and will be a day-one Game Pass Ultimate release.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-outer-worlds-2-is-getting-some-pricy-customizable-xbox-controllers/1100-6535316/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision Teases News About Call Of Duty's Much-Loved Non-SBMM Playlists]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/activision-teases-news-about-call-of-dutys-much-loved-non-sbmm-playlists/1100-6535315/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-teases-news-about-call-of-dutys-much-loved-non-sbmm-playlists.1320070/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535315">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2025-everything-we-know-about-rumored-black-ops-2-sequel/1100-6529073/" data-ref-id="1100-6529073">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 multiplayer beta</a> added new playlists recently that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-beta-adds-non-sbmm-playlist-opens-for-everyone/1100-6535236/" data-ref-id="1100-6535236">only factor in skill "minimally,"</a> and that's something hardcore fans have wanted for some time. The feedback around these non-SBMM playlists has been pretty positive, and now Activision has said its development teams are "inspired" by the feedback from these tests, and the feedback around the beta so far in general.</p><p>The non-SBMM playlists in Black Ops 7 are referred to as "open" playlists. Activision said it will have "some updates to share with everyone in the coming days" about their future in COD going forward.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="897564549" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466369,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Call%20of%20Duty%3A%20Black%20Ops%207%20%7C%20Multiplayer%20Gameplay%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:160,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-gameplay-reveal-trailer\/2300-6466369\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466369\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466369\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466369\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466369&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466369,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6535315&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty-black-ops-6,call-of-duty-black-ops-7&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,playstation-5,pc,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;activision,microsoft-game-studios&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466369},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466369\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4571949-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/xRGE1ylJ.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1758553800,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="xRGE1ylJ" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 | Multiplayer Gameplay Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Many are hoping to see these "open" playlists stick around for launch, and in fact, <a href="https://x.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/1974646289347575911" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">one report said that is indeed the plan</a>. However, Activision has yet to make any official announcements.</p><p>SBMM is a hot-button issue in a lot of multiplayer games, including Call of Duty. Some portion of the audience enjoys and embraces SBMM because they say it helps place them into matches with people more aligned with their skills. Other people, including hardcore players, want to see less SBMM.</p><p>For years, hardcore Call of Duty fans have bemoaned how <a href="https://x.com/charlieINTEL/status/1974517777450045878" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Activision reportedly "turned up" SBMM</a> and created what some thought was a negative experience because of it. With this new change for the Black Ops 7 beta, people are saying it's exactly what they've wanted to see for years, with faster matchmaking times, lower pings, and matches populated by players with a variety of skill levels.</p><p>The Black Ops 7 multiplayer beta wraps up on October 9, and on that very same day, Activision will launch <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/call-of-duty-season-6-arrives-to-black-ops-6-and-warzone-with-chucky-a-chainsaw-and-a-slasher-mode/2900-7113/" data-ref-id="2900-7113">Black Ops 6 and Warzone's Season 6, including the new Halloween content</a>. Also going live on October 9 is a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-free-trial-starts-just-before-battlefield-6-launch/1100-6535286/" data-ref-id="1100-6535286">free week-long Black Ops 6 trial</a> that allows people to try the multiplayer and Zombies, as well as campaign. The timing is notable given that the free trial is going live just before the rival FPS <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/" data-ref-id="1100-6526583">Battlefield 6</a> launches on October 10.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/activision-teases-news-about-call-of-dutys-much-loved-non-sbmm-playlists/1100-6535315/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>