<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 13:09:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oblivion Remastered Gets Its First Update With A Whole Bunch Of Fixes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/oblivion-remastered-gets-its-first-update-with-a-whole-bunch-of-fixes/1100-6532121/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oblivion-remastered-gets-its-first-update-with-a-whole-bunch-of-fixes.1208133/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/oblivion-remastered-gets-its-first-update-with-a-whole-bunch-of-fixes/1100-6532121/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532121">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-review/1900-6418359/" data-ref-id="1900-6418359">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a> has been a hit out of the gate, but even Bethesda and developer Virtuos acknowledge that it isn't perfect. There are bugs and glitches in Oblivion Remastered just as there are in almost every video game upon release, particularly Bethesda games. Now, Betheda is sharing the first update for the game to address some of these issues.</p><p>Through the game's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2623190/view/536603447519088660" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">official Steam page</a>, Bethesda laid out the contents of Oblivion Remastered's Update 1.1. This is the first of two separate updates that Bethesda plans to launch in the near future, although the second one doesn't have a date attached to it yet. Update 1.1 and its follow-up will be released on the Steam Beta first before being shared with Oblivion Remastered's console counterparts.</p><p>Update 1.1 is out today, June 5, on Oblivion Remastered's Steam Beta, and the wider rollout of the update will begin on June 11. The initial update is intended to tackle the major bugs that have come up, although some of the glitches addressed--including the disappearance of Vincente Valtieri's hair and High Chancellor Ocato's immobile arms--are unintentionally funny. The second planned update will concentrate on improving the game's performance. Bethesda didn't provide any details beyond that.</p><p>While the wait for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-wait-for-elder-scrolls-6-just-reached-a-sad-milestone/1100-6528679/" data-ref-id="1100-6528679">The Elder Scrolls VI</a> has been excruciating for some players, Oblivion Remastered has reminded others why they loved the franchise in the first place. Skyrim Grandma, aka Shirley Curry, even <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/skyrim-grandma-ends-streaming-retirement-to-play-oblivion-remastered/1100-6531994/" data-ref-id="1100-6531994">came out of her streaming retirement</a> to try her hand at Oblivion Remastered. To date, Oblivion Remastered is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/oblivion-remastered-is-already-the-third-best-selling-game-of-2025/1100-6531317/" data-ref-id="1100-6531317">the third-highest-selling game</a> of the year, with only <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds/" data-ref-id="5000-612214">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows/" data-ref-id="5000-571922">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a> ahead of it in the No. 1 and No. 2 slots.</p><p>The complete notes for Update 1.1 are included below.</p><h2>General</h2><ul><li>Enabled ToggleHudVisibility and ShowHud console commands</li></ul><h2>UI</h2><ul><li>Fix for missing text when installing the Deluxe Upgrade</li><li>Fix 'Skip' button not showing correctly during intro</li><li>Fix for Redguard Origin stats being reversed</li><li>Fix for not automatically showing Local Map when inside interior spaces</li><li>Fix for being unable to name Enchanted items when using a controller</li><li>Fix punctuation issues in Chinese translation</li><li>Localized string fixes</li><li>Fix for interacting with Daedric Shrines not displaying subtitles</li></ul><h2>Crashes</h2><ul><li>Fix crash when loading after fast travel to Vilverin</li><li>Fix crash when exploring Crayfish Cave</li><li>Fix crash when fighting Stunted Scamps</li><li>Fix crash when paying the fine after stealing in Castle Bravil</li><li>Fix for crash when loading Quicksaves</li><li>Fix crash when loading after fast travel to Mortal Camp</li><li>Fix for crash when loading a save in Quill-Weave's house</li><li>Fix crash when rapidly switching between Quality and Performance modes</li><li>Fix crash when storing items in a chest in Frostcrag Spire</li><li>Fix crash when creating multiple potions at once using stolen ingredients</li><li>Fix various CPU crashes</li></ul><h2>Gameplay</h2><ul><li>Fix player animation issues when mounting horses</li><li>Fix High Chancellor Ocato arms not animating</li><li>Fix Shambles' animations getting stuck when attacking</li><li>Fix for Staff of Sheogorath not freezing enemies</li><li>Fix for Cap'n Dugal not spawning</li><li>Fix for Light spells not showing VFX</li><li>Fix for offset Map Markers when running on a secondary monitor</li><li>Fix for Local Map being blank when opening</li><li>Fix Peryite Shrine's voiceover being cut off</li><li>Fix for First Person camera being set above the player's head</li><li>Fix for Chameleon VFX being stuck on player</li><li>Fix for player's skin textures not matching when infected with a disease</li></ul><h2>System</h2><ul><li>Fix player settings being reset when updating Settings</li><li>Fix XCloud mirroring settings from PC to XBOX</li><li>Fix for infinite loading issues</li><li>Fix for freezing when pressing Alt+Tab</li><li>Fix autosaving creating a new group of saves</li><li>Fix for old save files being renamed when the character is renamed at the Sewer exit</li><li>Fix for small Display Resolution sizes not showing correctly in Windowed Mode</li></ul><h2>Quests</h2><ul><li>The Battle for Kvatch - Fix Savlian becoming stuck after Castle Courtyard fight</li><li>A Knife in the Dark - Fix for Vincente Valtieri losing his hair</li><li>Finding the Thieves Guild - Fix for NPCs not appearing</li><li>The Sunken One - Fix for a Diary page being hidden under a bowl</li><li>The Elven Maiden - Fix for crash when Hieronymus Lex attempts to take Llathasa's Bust out of the cupboard in Myvryna Arano's house</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who Plays James Bond In 007 First Light? Fans Believe They've Worked It Out]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/who-plays-james-bond-in-007-first-light-fans-believe-theyve-worked-it-out/1100-6532125/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/who-plays-james-bond-in-007-first-light-fans-believe-theyve-worked-it-out.1208130/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/who-plays-james-bond-in-007-first-light-fans-believe-theyve-worked-it-out/1100-6532125/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6532125">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Hitman developer IO Interactive has officially announced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-james-bond-game-first-light-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6531773/" data-ref-id="1100-6531773">007 First Light</a>, the studio's new third-person James Bond game. A <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/007-first-light-trailer-reveals-the-first-ever-james-bond-origin-story/1100-6532111/" data-ref-id="1100-6532111">flashy trailer at Sony's State of Play</a> revealed a first look at the younger version of the British super-spy, but everyone is wondering: Who is playing James Bond?</p><p>We still don't know, but fans believe they've worked it out. Immediately after the trailer aired, people on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/JamesBond/comments/1l3icpc/i_think_the_actor_for_the_james_bond_game_is/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Reddit</a> and <a href="https://x.com/search?q=patrick%20gibson%20james%20bond&amp;src=typed_query" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">elsewhere</a> said they think Irish actor Patrick Gibson is playing the role. He's known for his roles in The Tudors, Shadow and Bone, and Tolkien. Most recently, he played a young Dexter Morgan on the Dexter prequel series Original Sin. Indeed, Gibson certainly looks the part. But anything is possible.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/GameRoll_/status/1930385920907227230" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">The new James Bond is 100% played by Patrick Gibson.<br>He’s an Irish actor who I know as playing Dexter in Dexter: Original Sin.<br>He’s a PHENOMENAL actor and I’m sure he’ll be GREAT as Bond! <a href="https://t.co/q58Cn0eQE7" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/q58Cn0eQE7</a></p>  — GameRoll (@GameRoll_) <a href="https://twitter.com/GameRoll_/status/1930385920907227230?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 4, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>As of yet, however, IO Interactive has yet to announce who is playing Bond in First Light. What we do know is that <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/007-first-light-reveals-new-young-james-bond-with-the-walking-deads-lennie-james-set-to-co-star" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Walking Dead's Lennie James plays Bond's mentor, John Greenway</a>. This is a brand-new character, but some of the Bond series veterans like M, Q, and Moneypenny will appear in First Light as well.</p><p>Like Bond himself, actors playing those roles have yet to be confirmed, nor do we know who's playing the mysterious character Isola or any of the "whole new cast of villains."</p><p>First Light tells the story of how James Bond became 007, picking up with Bond when he was a 26-year-old recruit from the Royal Navy. Like the movies, First Light will tell a globe-trotting story focused on action and espionage.</p><p>First Light launches in 2026 for PS5, Xbox Series X|S, Switch 2, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>