<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 19:06:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Developer Of Until Dawn's PS5 Remake Is "Effectively Closed" - Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-developer-of-until-dawns-ps5-remake-is-effectively-closed-report/1100-6529926/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-developer-of-until-dawns-ps5-remake-is-effectively-closed-report.1126239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-developer-of-until-dawns-ps5-remake-is-effectively-closed-report/1100-6529926/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529926">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Ballistic Moon, the studio behind the PC and PS5 remake of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/until-dawn/" data-ref-id="5000-616356">Until Dawn</a> released last year, is now "effectively closed" after failing to find a publisher for its next game.</p><p>A new report from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-remake-developer-ballistic-moon-effectively-closed/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Insider Gaming</a> reveals that only the studio founders and a handful of others potentially remain employed there at this point. The studio reportedly couldn't find funding for its next game, and Sony didn't give the studio any support for future work on the Until Dawn franchise. Ballistic Moon has yet to comment on this situation.</p><p>Ballistic Moon is a U.K. developer founded in 2020 by industry veterans from studios like EA and Supermassive Games. So far, Ballistic Moon's only game is 2024's remake of Until Dawn, which brought the beloved PS4 choose-your-own-adventure horror adventure game to Unreal Engine 5. It featured a recomposed musical score, changed the gameplay camera to a third-person perspective rather than a fixed-camera one, and added a post-credit scene teasing a sequel. It received a <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/until-dawn/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lukewarm reception</a> compared to the original.</p><p>It's unclear if there is a Until Dawn sequel in active development right now, but if one is, it seems that Ballistic Moon is not the studio working on it. Whatever Ballistic Moon's next project was, Insider Gaming explains that the studio couldn't find funding or an interested publisher for it. Ballistic Moon had actually <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/until-dawn-remake-developer-ballistic-moon-lays-off-several-staff" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">laid off some developers</a> prior to the Until Dawn remake's release last October, although this report explains that many of the 20 or so remaining developers were cut in December.</p><p>If you want to play Ballistic Moon's take on Until Dawn, it's available on PC and PS5. A <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-until-dawn-trailer-serves-up-fresh-nightmares/1100-6529477/" data-ref-id="1100-6529477">movie based on Until Dawn</a> also hits theaters next month.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>