<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 20:16:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon's Big MMO That Started Strong Is Shutting Down]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazons-big-mmo-that-started-strong-is-shutting-down/1100-6537436/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1407505</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537436">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Amazon Games has <a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/news/articles/the-future-of-new-world-aeternum-what-to-expect" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">announced </a>that the MMO New World: Aeternum will go offline at the end of January 2027. The announcement isn't a total surprise, though, as some theorized this would be the case after the developer announced that the MMO would get <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-world-aeternum-is-ending-new-content-after-season-10/1100-6535786/" data-ref-id="1100-6535786">no more new content</a> after the Nighthaven seasonal update last year. In October 2025, Amazon <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-cuts-hit-video-game-division-reducing-work-on-mmos/1100-6535769/" data-ref-id="1100-6535769">cut more jobs at its gaming division</a> that specifically impacted the MMO teams.</p><p>Aeternum's final day on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S is January 31, 2027. As of today, January 15, the game is being delisted. Everyone who has the game can keep playing, and Amazon announced that the Nighthaven event is being extended until the eventual shutdown.</p><p>"We want to thank the players for your dedication and passion. We are grateful for the time spent crafting the world of Aeternum with you. Together we built something special. While we are saddened to say goodbye, we’re honored that we were able to share so much with the community," the developer wrote in the announcement.</p><p><span>New World launched in September 2021 for PC and came to consoles in October 2024. The game had a strong start, reaching a peak of more than 900,000 concurrent users. The game's playerbase on Steam ticked up with new updates, but has fallen down to about </span><a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1063730/charts/#3y" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">1,100 concurrent players on Steam.</a></p><p>Amazon also clarified that it will keep selling microtransactions for New World until July 19, 2026, after which the Marks of Fortune currency will be removed from sale, along with all other items. Refunds will not be provided to people who have a balance of Marks of Fortune.</p><p>While New World will not get any more new content, Amazon said it will monitor the game for "bugs and performance to ensure the game runs smoothly as things wind down."</p><p>Amazon has struggled with games in recent years. Amazon's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazons-crucible-is-shutting-down-for-good/1100-6483150/" data-ref-id="1100-6483150">free-to-play shooter Crucible stalled and was eventually canceled</a>, while the company was making a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-reportedly-cancels-its-lord-of-the-rings-mmo/1100-6490277/" data-ref-id="1100-6490277">Lord of the Rings MMO until a supposed contract dispute ended things</a>. Amazon also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-cancels-its-new-game-breakaway/1100-6457880/" data-ref-id="1100-6457880">had a game in the works called Breakaway that was canceled</a>.</p><p>A <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-01-29/amazon-game-studios-struggles-to-find-a-hit" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report from Bloomberg</a> documented an apparent pattern of mismanagement at Amazon's video game division. In 2021, Amazon CEO Andy Jassy <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-ceo-replacing-jeff-bezos-wont-abandon-gaming/1100-6487107/" data-ref-id="1100-6487107">pledged a commitment to gaming</a>, but that was years ago. The company isn't abandoning games altogether, of course, as it's publishing Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis and Tomb Raider: Catalyst.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazons-big-mmo-that-started-strong-is-shutting-down/1100-6537436/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Players Threw A Lot Of Snowballs In The Cold Snap Event]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-players-threw-a-lot-of-snowballs-in-the-cold-snap-event/1100-6537434/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1407412</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537434">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The Arc Raiders winter event, Cold Snap, has concluded, and now developer Embark has shared some statistics about the milestones players achieved during it.</p><p>In a graphic shared on social media, the developer listed off what players did, including throwing 95 million snowballs. A total of 91 million players got knocked out by snowballs. Additionally, players used snowballs to take down Arc enemies--10,577, to be precise. What's more, 3.5 million players were knocked out due to the cold.</p><p>Embark also added fireworks to the game for the Cold Snap event, and players fired 2.9 million rounds of fireworks and threw 9.2 million firecrackers. Players were also feeling festive and relaxed, apparently, as a total of 108 players played instruments for more than 20 minutes without stopping during the event.</p><div data-embed-type="html"><blockquote><p dir="ltr">95 million snowballs.<br>A million Candleberry Banquets.<br>108 Raiders who really knew how to throw a party.<br>We took on the ARC and the cold, and came out still standing.<br>Got a Cold Snap story of your own? Tell us your favorite moments from the winter update! <a href="https://t.co/Staqam9VyE" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/Staqam9VyE</a></p>  — ARC Raiders (@ARCRaidersGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/ARCRaidersGame/status/2011861051390783521?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 15, 2026</a></blockquote>


  






  </div><p>In other news, Arc Raiders publisher Nexon recently announced that the game had <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-players-get-this-free-pickaxe-as-game-passes-12-million-copies-sold/1100-6537346/" data-ref-id="1100-6537346">passed 12.4 million in sales</a>, generating <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-continues-to-be-a-huge-hit-reportedly-achieving-these-new-records/1100-6537168/" data-ref-id="1100-6537168">hundreds of millions of dollars.</a> The game's newest update <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-update-nerfs-weapons-and-introduces-abyss-cosmetics/1100-6537384/" data-ref-id="1100-6537384">nerfed some weapons and introduced new cosmetics. </a></p><p>Given the huge success of Arc Raiders so far, it's no big surprise that Hollywood has come calling. Embark has said it's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-has-received-movie-and-tv-offers/1100-6537191/" data-ref-id="1100-6537191">gotten TV and movie pitches</a>, but no deals have materialized as of yet.</p><p>GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/arc-raiders-review-us-against-the-world/1900-6418435/" data-ref-id="1900-6418435">Arc Raiders review</a> scored the game a 9/10. "We can all kill each other in Arc Raiders. The fact that most of us are choosing instead to lend a helping hand, if not a sign that humanity will be all right in the real world, at the very least makes for one of the best multiplayer games I've ever played," reviewer Mark Delaney said.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-players-threw-a-lot-of-snowballs-in-the-cold-snap-event/1100-6537434/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>