<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:22:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Finally Fixes An Annoying Part About Console-Specific Livestreams]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-finally-fixes-an-annoying-part-about-console-specific-livestreams/1100-6536419/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-finally-fixes-an-annoying-part-about-console-specific-livestreams.1360594/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536419">

            
            
  


    


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container" data-in-content-placements="[{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-incontent-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:1,&quot;minElements&quot;:2},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:4,&quot;minElements&quot;:5}]},{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-banner-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:7,&quot;minElements&quot;:8},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:10,&quot;minElements&quot;:11},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:13,&quot;minElements&quot;:14}]}]">
                <p>The Xbox Partner Preview showed off a bunch of cool and interesting projects coming to Xbox consoles and PC in the future, including Armatus, The Mound: Omen of Cthulhu, and Raji: Kaliyuga. However, the event itself bucked an annoying trend that other trailer showcases continue to follow, as each trailer that aired during the event showed the logos for <em>every</em> console the game will launch on, not just Xbox.</p><p>Traditionally, when a game makes an appearance during one of these events, the final shot confirms the game for the host company's consoles--PlayStation consoles for Sony, the Switch or Switch 2 for Nintendo, and so on. However, in yesterday's event the PS5 and Nintendo Switch 2 logos appeared multiple times throughout the showcase.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4608421-armatus.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4608421" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4608421-armatus.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4608421"></a><figcaption>The final shot from the Armatus trailer that aired during the Xbox Partner Preview.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4608421-armatus.jpg"></figure><p>Of the 16 titles shown during the Xbox Partner Preview, 13 of them included either a PlayStation or Nintendo Switch logo in their ending graphic. The three exceptions were Echo Generation 2, Roadside Research, and Cloverpit, but all three of them are, as of this writing, only coming to Xbox consoles.</p><p>This small detail seems to be another nod toward Xbox's strategy of catering to as many platforms as possible through its "This is an Xbox" campaign and Xbox Play Anywhere, where players purchase a game on one platform and have access to it on Xbox, PC, and mobile devices. The Partner Preview yesterday, in fact, began with the confirmation that every game shown during the event would have Xbox Play Anywhere capabilities.</p><p>The Xbox Partner Preview brought 16 game updates and new reveals, including <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/im-making-this-for-me-not-to-make-everyone-happy-vampire-survivors-creator-on-his-next-game/1100-6536362/" data-ref-id="1100-6536362">Vampire Crawlers from poncle</a>, the previously-mentioned Armatus from Godfall developer Counterplay Games, and Tides of Annihilation from Chinese studio Eclipse Glow Games.</p>
  
                        
        
    
    
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-finally-fixes-an-annoying-part-about-console-specific-livestreams/1100-6536419/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next Blox Fruits Update: Everything You Need To Know]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-blox-fruits-update-everything-you-need-to-know/1100-6536040/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-blox-fruits-update-everything-you-need-to-know.1360522/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536040">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>If you're looking for information on the next <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/blox-fruits/" data-ref-id="5000-632858">Blox Fruits</a> update, you have come to the right place. One of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/roblox-game-client/" data-ref-id="5000-451936">Roblox</a>’s most popular and most entertaining games, Blox Fruits is a seafaring adventure that pulls inspiration from the iconic anime franchise One Piece.</p><p>Since launching in 2019, this swashbuckling experience has remained at the top of the charts and received a steady stream of updates to refine and improve the title. With such a large and fervent playerbase, there’s little surprise that the demand for updates is huge.</p><p>So, for those of you out there who have already scoured the many seas and are looking for more content to find and loot to plunder, we’re detailing all the information available on the next Blox Fruits update. You can find all the details below:</p><h2 id="When_is_the_next_Blox_Fruits_update_coming_">When is the next Blox Fruits update coming?</h2><p>There is currently no official release date for Blox Fruits Update 29. However, given the previous cadence of releases and fan speculation, many are assuming it will drop in either late January or early February of 2026.</p><h2 id="When_was_the_last_Blox_Fruits_update_">When was the last Blox Fruits update?</h2><p>The last major update for Blox Fruits was Update 28, otherwise known as The Tiger Update. This update added the Tiger fruit (formerly the Leopard), introduced the Werewolf Blox Fruit mutation, and the Trick or Treating event.</p><h2 id="Blox_Fruits_update_patch_notes">Blox Fruits update patch notes</h2><p>Below are all of <span>the <a href="https://blox-fruits.fandom.com/wiki/Updates#28" rel="nofollow ">patch notes</a> for</span> Blox Fruit Update 28: The Tiger Update</p><p><strong>Increased Max Level Capacity: 2750-2800</strong></p><p><strong>Reworked Blox Fruit:</strong></p><ul><li>Tiger (formerly Leopard)</li></ul><p><strong>New Blox Fruit mutation:</strong></p><ul><li>Werewolf</li></ul><p><strong>New Event</strong></p><ul><li>Trick Or Treating</li><li>The First, Second annd Third Seas are decorated for Halloween.</li><li>Mygame43's bunker has been added to the Cafe.</li></ul><p><strong>New Accessories:</strong></p><ul><li>Pumpkin Mask</li><li>Coven Witch Hat</li></ul><p><strong>New NPCS</strong></p><ul><li>Witch</li><li>Halloween Gacha Dealer</li></ul><p><strong>New Boss</strong></p><ul><li>Rip_Return</li></ul><p><strong>New Boss Raid</strong></p><ul><li>Unbound Werewolf</li></ul><p><strong>New potions</strong></p><ul><li>Disguise Elixir</li><li>Suspicious Growth Potion</li><li>Big Head Elixir</li><li>Pumpkin Potion</li><li>Lava Bomb Elixir</li><li>Monster Mash Elixir</li><li>Candy Concoction</li></ul><p><strong>New Currency</strong></p><ul><li>Candy Corn</li></ul><p><strong>New Fish</strong></p><ul><li>Jack-O-Fish</li><li>Jester Clownfish</li><li>Zombie Bass</li><li>Vampire Squid</li><li>Terrorbones</li></ul><p><strong>New Sunken Chests</strong></p><ul><li>Fall Chest</li><li>Halloween Chest</li></ul><p><strong>New Player Profile Backgrounds</strong></p><ul><li>Full Moon</li><li>Halloween Tapestry</li></ul><p><strong>Changes</strong></p><ul><li>The Titles Specialist interface has been redesigned.</li></ul><p><strong>Tiger + Werewolf</strong></p><ul><li>M1: Transformed and awakened hits now break Observation.</li><li>Z: The final projectile breaks the Observation, has a larger area of effect and hitbox. The awakened final blow has a longer range.</li><li>X: Now breaks Observation (both on the ground and in the air).</li><li>C: Improved Hitboxes for Grabbing and Punching.</li><li>F: While awake, the user no longer takes damage when using the move against enemies.</li><li>Improved Werewolf: Defeating an enemy while awake will now fully restore the user's health</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-blox-fruits-update-everything-you-need-to-know/1100-6536040/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox Blox Fruits Stock And Restock Times]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/roblox-blox-fruits-stock-and-restock-times/1100-6536033/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roblox-blox-fruits-stock-and-restock-times.1360519/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536033">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>If you are an ardent <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/blox-fruits/" data-ref-id="5000-632858">Blox Fruits</a> player, the ocean-faring <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/roblox-game-client/" data-ref-id="5000-451936">Roblox</a> experience that has taken the world by storm, then you will want to keep a keen eye on the many stock options scattered around the Blox Fruits seas. Those titular fruits are the keys to success, but not only are some rarer than others, but vendors constantly change their wares, so we’re here to explain everything you need to know about the Blox Fruits stock as well as restock times.</p><h2 id="What_is_the_Blox_Fruits_Stock_System_">What is the Blox Fruits Stock System?</h2><p>The most important part of Blox Fruit is, unsurprisingly, those titular Blox Fruits. If you want to expand your collection, you will need to amass some money through regular gameplay and then head to a vendor to buy Blox Fruit.</p><p>Sadly, not all of the Blox Fruit are available at once, and their appearance is dictated by their rarity. So, you’re much more likely to see common Blox Fruit than you are rare ones. Anyone wanting to expand their abilities or collect all of the Blox Fruit will need to routinely visit the in-game vendors with the hopes of eventually finding and purchasing every Blox Fruit in the game. Regular vendors have at least three Blox Fruit, while the Advanced Fruit Dealer on Mirage Island holds five.</p><h2 id="How_often_do_Blox_Fruits_stocks_refresh_">How often do Blox Fruits stocks refresh?</h2><p>The regular Blox Fruit stocks offered by Normal dealers change every four hours. Meanwhile, the Advanced dealers change their stock every two hours instead.</p><h2 id="When_do_Blox_Fruits_stocks_refresh_">When do Blox Fruits stocks refresh?</h2><p>The Blox Fruits vendors' stock refreshes at a set time depending on your region. So, every four hours, or at one of the times listed below:</p><table data-max-width="true"><thead><tr><th scope="col">Timezone</th><th scope="col">1st Restock</th><th scope="col">2nd Restock</th><th scope="col">3rd Restock</th><th scope="col">4th Restock</th><th scope="col">5th Restock</th><th scope="col">6th Restock</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Pacific Time</td><td>12 AM</td><td>4 AM</td><td>8 AM</td><td>12 PM</td><td>4 PM</td><td>8 PM</td></tr><tr><td>Mountain Time</td><td>1 AM</td><td>5 AM</td><td>9 AM</td><td>1 PM</td><td>5 PM</td><td>9 PM</td></tr><tr><td>Central Time</td><td>2 AM</td><td>6 AM</td><td>10 AM</td><td>2 PM</td><td>6 PM</td><td>10 PM</td></tr><tr><td>Eastern Time</td><td>3 AM</td><td>7 AM</td><td>11 AM</td><td>3 PM</td><td>7 PM</td><td>11 PM</td></tr><tr><td>Atlantic Time</td><td>12 AM</td><td>4 AM</td><td>8 AM</td><td>12 PM</td><td>4 PM</td><td>8 PM</td></tr><tr><td>BST (UK TIME)</td><td>12 AM</td><td>4 AM</td><td>8 AM</td><td>12 PM</td><td>4 PM</td><td>8 PM</td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="How_do_I_know_what_Blox_Fruits_will_be_stocked_">How do I know what Blox Fruits will be stocked?</h2><p>There is no way to find out ahead of time which Blox Fruits will be stocked by the Normal Dealer or the Advanced Dealer. However, you can use<a href="https://bloxhttps//blox-fruits.fandom.com/wiki/Blox_Fruits_%22Stock%22.-fruits.fandom.com/wiki/Blox_Fruits_%22Stock%22." data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"> third-party websites </a>and apps to see exactly which Blox Fruits are in stock at the current moment in time. </p><h2 id="How_to_check_Blox_Fruit_stock_in_game">How to check Blox Fruit stock in-game</h2><p>If you want to check the Roblox Blox Fruit stock, you will have to find and interact with any of the many dealers within the game. If you are looking for a particular fruit, or just want to make checking stock easier, you can save next to a dealer and then respawn next to them, to save yourself a journey.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/roblox-blox-fruits-stock-and-restock-times/1100-6536033/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>