<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 18:01:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cronos: The New Dawn - Best Upgrades To Buy First]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cronos-the-new-dawn-best-upgrades-to-buy-first/1100-6534145/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cronos-the-new-dawn-best-upgrades-to-buy-first.1287858/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534145">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/cronos-the-new-dawn/" data-ref-id="5000-647672">Cronos: The New Dawn</a> is a pretty difficult game, and it's made even harder by the fact that there's a finite amount of upgrade materials available to you in a single run. As such, you'll want to make informed decisions throughout your journey to ensure your health, inventory, and weapons are all able to withstand what the game throws at you.</p><p>While you'll start to obtain more of both materials in the back half of the game, the opening hours can often feel restrictive, forcing you to make very tough decisions about what upgrades will improve your chances of success. Below, we'll list out the best early upgrades we think you should go with to feel confident in taking on the challenges ahead.</p><div data-embed-type="toc"><p><span><strong>Table of Contents</strong> [<a data-toggle="collapse" href="#toc_list">hide</a>]</span></p><ul id="toc_list"><li><a href="#What_to_know_about_upgrade_materials_in_Cronos__The_New_Dawn">What to know about upgrade materials in Cronos: The New Dawn</a></li><li><a href="#Best_upgrades_to_buy_first_in_Cronos__The_New_Dawn">Best upgrades to buy first in Cronos: The New Dawn</a><ul><li><a href="#Temporal_Shell___Inventory_Slots_and_Suit_Integrity">Temporal Shell - Inventory Slots and Suit Integrity</a></li><li><a href="#Sword_MK_1615__Handgun____Stability_and_Charge_Speed">Sword MK-1615 (Handgun) - Stability and Charge Speed</a></li><li><a href="#Hammer_PROV_2030__Shotgun____Firepower_and_Charge_Speed">Hammer PROV-2030 (Shotgun) - Firepower and Charge Speed</a></li></ul></li></ul></div><h2 id="What_to_know_about_upgrade_materials_in_Cronos__The_New_Dawn">What to know about upgrade materials in Cronos: The New Dawn</h2><p>There are two types of upgrade materials: Energy and Cores.</p><p>Energy is used to upgrade your weapons. It's plentiful throughout the game, usually sitting on shelves or other places where you might find items, though it will also sometimes drop from defeated enemies.</p><p>Cores, meanwhile, are used to level up your suit (health and inventory space), as well as your Torch Fuel and Pyre items. These are rare and typically found by seeking out optional paths--such as through chainlocked doors--or by petting cats that are hiding in the world.</p><h2 id="Best_upgrades_to_buy_first_in_Cronos__The_New_Dawn">Best upgrades to buy first in Cronos: The New Dawn</h2><p>Here are the best upgrades to focus on first in Cronos: The New Dawn.</p><h3 id="Temporal_Shell___Inventory_Slots_and_Suit_Integrity">Temporal Shell - Inventory Slots and Suit Integrity</h3><p>Cronos: The New Dawn is very stingy with inventory space, so managing it properly can be a very stressful experience. Is it worth dropping some much-needed ammo to carry a vintage item you found that can be sold back in a safe room for a big chunk of Energy? Should you carry more healing items, or bring along the bolt cutters you found a bit ago that can help you open chainlocked doors?</p><p>It's a lot to think about, but it can be made much easier by investing in Inventory Slot upgrades early so that you can carry some extra items. However, you'll also need to worry about your health, especially in the opening hours when you're coming to grips with how the game plays and may be making more mistakes. As such, it's a good idea to use some Cores to upgrade your Suit Integrity early on, too.</p><p>So, how do you decide which to upgrade? Your best bet in the first half of the game is to switch between the two each time you have enough Cores for an upgrade. Once you fill in the fourth Suit Integrity slot and have your health to 200, you should probably go all-in on Inventory Slots until it's maxed out. The back half of the game is overflowing with stuff to pick up, as well as additional weapons that you'll want to bring with you, so you'll be thankful to have more space for them all.</p><h3 id="Sword_MK_1615__Handgun____Stability_and_Charge_Speed">Sword MK-1615 (Handgun) - Stability and Charge Speed</h3><p>You may be inclined to start with Firepower upgrades for the Sword MK-1615, but since most normal enemies will take between 1-3 headshots from this handgun either way, upgrading its damage is less important than with the shotgun (as we'll discuss below). Besides, more damage is irrelevant if your bullets don't hit their target, meaning your best bet is usually going to be to toss at least a few upgrades into Stability. This will reduce the wobbly aiming and make it easier to re-center after taking shots.</p><p>Speaking of taking shots with the handgun, you'll want to make sure you're charging each shot you take to do maximum damage. So, investing into Charge Speed can make a huge difference when enemies are closing in on you rapidly, allowing you to get your shots out quicker and reposition when needed.</p><h3 id="Hammer_PROV_2030__Shotgun____Firepower_and_Charge_Speed">Hammer PROV-2030 (Shotgun) - Firepower and Charge Speed</h3><p>The shotgun is your true heavy hitter throughout much of the game. Unlike the handgun, which benefits less from Firepower, you'll want to pump up the shotgun's Firepower stat as much as possible. This makes it an immensely deadly weapon against bosses, as well as well as a useful tool for herding enemies into a group and downing them all with a single blast.</p><p>Because you'll be using this against difficult bosses and hordes of foes, it's also imperative that you level up its Charge Speed as much as possible. Even with points invested, it can take quite a while to charge up, but every little bit of time saved is still time you're not vulnerable to enemy attacks.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cronos-the-new-dawn-best-upgrades-to-buy-first/1100-6534145/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path Of Exile 2's First Post-Third Edict Update Brings League Improvements--Full Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-first-post-third-edict-update-brings-league-improvements-full-patch-notes/1100-6534449/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2s-first-post-third-edict-update-brings-league-improvements-full-patch-notes.1287813/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534449">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/path-of-exile-2/" data-ref-id="5000-504817">Path of Exile 2's</a> massive <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-path-of-exile-2-huge-third-edict-update-looks-to-deal-with-every-problem-upsetting-fans/1100-6534132/" data-ref-id="1100-6534132">The Third Edict update</a> is getting even better, as a patch scheduled for later this week will bring improvements not only to the game's first seasonal league but also to new mechanics like sprint.</p><p dir="ltr">The Third Edict launched August 29 and added Act IV of Path of Exile 2's campaign, two temporary "interlude" acts to help players reach the endgame, and the ARPG's first seasonal league, Rise of the Abyssal. Developer Grinding Gear Games says it's been keeping a close eye on player feedback since the update's launch, and now it's almost ready to release <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2694490?emclan=103582791474292391&amp;emgid=521975626158047245" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">patch 0.3.0b</a> to address various issues.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zXLzXS4I2ak" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/zXLzXS4I2ak" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Many of the upcoming changes are to Rise of the Abyssal, making the abilities of certain enemies more manageable. That includes the Vessel of Kulemak boss. It will be easier to read and dodge its arena-wide cleave attack, and while its Teleport Slam ability can no longer be avoided, it will deal reduced damage. Other enemies, like Abyssal Stranglers and the Shepherd of the Pit, have had the damage dealt by certain abilities reduced.</p><p dir="ltr">In terms of the overall game, there are tons of little improvements, including changes to many areas and enemies in Act IV. Certain bosses like The Scourge of the Skies, Kurtog, and the Great White One will have more abilities that can't be avoided. Other bosses will become a little more manageable thanks to improved telegraphing of Yama the White's Future Sight skill and increased cooldown between Torvian, Hand of the Saviour's skills. In the case of Torvian, the projectile speed of their bouncing axes will be reduced and they'll deal less freeze build-up. Another enemy, Quill Crabs, will additionally deal less damage.</p><p dir="ltr">One mechanic that is being slightly tweaked is the game's new sprint function, which allows players to come out of a roll in a run in order to more quickly navigate maps or flee from enemies. Players found they would still be locked on to enemies while sprinting, resulting in their character unintentionally turning around when casting an ability. With patch 0.3.0b, sprinting will make it so players are no longer locked onto enemies.</p><p dir="ltr">The update will also address a whole lot of bugs, including one that was causing the Warbringer's Answered Call Notable Passive to not summon Ancestral Spirit minions properly. It will also fix various instances that would cause the client to crash.</p><p dir="ltr">You can read the full Path of Exile 2 patch 0.3.0b patch notes below, with the patch expected to arrive by the end of the week. In a recent interview, Path of Exile 2 director Jonathan Rogers confirmed the ARPG <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-wont-leave-early-access-in-2025-dont-believe-thats-possible-anymore/1100-6534129/" data-ref-id="1100-6534129">won't be leaving early access in 2025</a>. He said "things have taken a bit longer than we'd hoped" but that he believed it wouldn't be "too much longer" before Grinding Gear Games is finished with the game's remaining two story acts. Rogers said The Third Edict update is Grinding Gear Games' attempt at "solving every problem people are currently unhappy about."</p><h2 dir="ltr">Path Of Exile 2 The Third Edict Update 0.3.0b Patch Notes</h2><h3>Rise of the Abyssal Changes</h3><ul><li>Abyssal Monsters can now be bound as Spectres.</li><li>The Vessel of Kulemak's Teleport Slam can no longer be avoided, and the damage it deals has been reduced.</li><li>Improved the telegraphing for the Vessel of Kulemak's arena-wide cleave. The cleave has also been made easier to dodge in the final part of the fight.</li><li>The "Area is overrun by the Abyssal" Map Modifier now spreads Pits over a larger amount of the area.</li><li>The Strider of the Pit's Spear Slam now has a global cooldown, and they now stop tracking you with their Storm skill when you are far enough away.</li><li>Reduced the damage of the Crystal Wall used by Abyssal Stranglers.</li><li>Reduced the movement speed of the Shepherd of the Pit, and reduced the damage dealt by their ground effect.</li><li>Improved the invulnerability visual effect for the Lightless Moray. The ignite chance and damage from its shade form explosion has also been reduced.</li><li>Abyssal Monsters now introduce some of their skills over the first 3 Acts instead of being able to use all of their skills from Act 1.</li><li>Removed the motion blur effect played when Abyssal Pits closed.</li></ul><h3>Other Changes and Improvements</h3><ul><li>One-time Rare Monsters found in the Campaign no longer have their fixed hidden modifiers when used as tamed beasts, or spectres.</li><li>You will no longer remain locked onto enemies while sprinting. This improves cases where you would sprint away from an enemy then unintentionally turn around to use a skill targeting that enemy.</li><li>You can now use Instance Management (Ctrl+click) on the button to jump in the Well of Souls.</li><li>You can now use /hideout and similar commands from the Well of Souls.</li><li>Map areas now have versions with no Map Boss present.</li><li>Vendor windows will now remember any search text you've entered on a per NPC basis, until you exit to character selection.</li><li>Boss fights with two bosses should now correctly restart from the beginning when a player Resurrects at Checkpoint after killing just one boss.</li><li>The Soul Siphoner monster modifier has been reworked. The inner ring now reduces damage dealt, and the outer ring reduces Skill Speed for each time you use a Skill while standing in it. Both rings deal Physical Damage over Time (previously both rings prevented Mana recovery, drained Mana and dealt Lightning Damage over time).</li><li>Forge Hammer no longer costs mana when used to recall the Hammer, and other skills such as Warcries cannot empower that use.</li><li>Doedre's Dark Design, triggered by the Doedre's Undoing Support, now deals Spell Damage instead of Secondary Damage.</li><li>Added missing Duration and Ground Effect types to the His Foul Emergence Skill to allow it to function with relevant support gems.</li><li>Temporarily disabled the following Rogue Exiles: Taua, the Ruthless, Ulfred, the Afflicted, Drusian, the Artillerist, and Doran, the Deft.</li><li>The Derelict Mansion Map Boss arena no longer requires finding a tome to open.</li><li>The boss arena in Derelict Mansion Map will now be open if you die to the bosses after opening it once.</li><li>The Razed Fields Map no longer stops you from entering the boss arena after it has been started.</li><li>The barrier outside the church in Arastas can no longer be broken early.</li><li>Improved the telegraphing of Yama the White's future sight skill.</li><li>Increased the cooldown for some of Torvian, Hand of the Saviour's skills. The projectile speed of their bouncing axe skill has been reduced, and the amount of freeze build up Torvian causes when under the effects of the Twilight Order's Sword buff has been reduced.</li><li>The Scourge of the Skies bird storm skill can no longer be avoided.</li><li>The slam combo skill used by Kurtog, Lord of Kin can no longer be avoided.</li><li>Some of the skills used by Great White One can no longer be avoided.</li><li>The tracking of Azmadi, the Faridun Prince's triple lacerate skill is now more lenient.</li><li>You can now use portals after defeating Siora, Blade of the Mists.</li><li>Oswin, the Dread Warden now removes all the debuffs he has applied to the player when he is killed.</li><li>Reduced the likelihood of Treant Foulspawns firing projectiles whilst walking.</li><li>Reduced the damage of Quill Crab's quill projectiles.</li><li>Updated the description of Lifetap Support to clarify it turns a Supported Skills Mana cost into a Life cost, rather than stating "a portion of".</li><li>Updated the Tabna's Pillar World Map Icon to correctly describe the benefits it provides.</li><li>Updated the Navali's Rest World Map Icon to indicate it provides a permanent benefit.</li><li>Corrected and simplified Meditate's description. This is purely a description change.</li><li>Clarified the Skill Description for Infernal Cry to indicate that it only Empowers Melee Attacks.</li><li>Thunderous Leap's description no longer inaccurately mentions that it only detonates spear skills. As with any detonator skill, it detonates anything that is capable of being detonated.</li></ul><h3>Bug Fixes</h3><ul><li>Fixed an issue where Ancestral Spirits, granted by the Warbringer's Answered Call Notable Passive Skill, was failing to summon Ancestral Spirit Minions.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you were unable to dodge roll past enemies when you were partially surrounded.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the "Abyssal Pits in Area always have Rewards" modifier was not functioning correctly.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Whirling Slash's travel distance could no longer change based on your attack speed.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Spectres and Tamed Beasts could benefit from the out-of-combat life regeneration common to all persistent minions while in combat.</li><li>Fixed a bug where reloading could fail on Crossbows, most noticeably when weapon swapping.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Persistent Skills could not be activated when shapeshifted into Demon Form.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the Brutus' Brain Support which causes supported Minions to take no damage, still worked with the Damage from hits is taken from your Damageable Companion's Life before you, from the Starkonja's Head Unique Helmet.</li><li>Fixed a bug where increases to Frost Bomb limit was not functioning correctly with Spell Cascade Support.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Ahn's Citadel Support was not obtainable.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Defy II Support was only disallowing Insufficient Mana from preventing the use of supported Melee Attacks rather than any supported Attacks.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the Twin Bow's Attack Speed was unintentionally higher than other Bow base types with the same implicit (Dualstring Bow and Gemini Bow). It now has an Attack time of 1.1 seconds (previously 1.2).</li><li>Fixed a bug where Ember Fusillade when supported by Wildshards would be able to "keep" the additional projectiles from a Wildshards proc by interrupting it fully firing.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Resonating Shield, Shield Wall, and Fortifying Cry's shockwaves did not scale with area damage modifiers.</li><li>Fixed an issue where some Infusion Duration small passives were labelled as "Infusion Damage". A Notable in the Sorceress starting area has also been renamed from "Infused Spell Damage" to instead be "Principal Infusion".</li><li>Fixed a bug where Grisly Pyre from the His Winnowing Flame Skill did not describe how much damage it was dealing from consuming ignites on enemies.</li><li>Fixed a bug which allowed Forge Hammer to be used in cases where it should be unusable.</li><li>Fixed a bug where some Map Device microtransactions would place you inside the Map Device when returning from a Map, and others were missing their interactable object.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the final Act 4 Boss could spawn a duplicate version during the fight.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Travel Skills could not be used in Azmadi, the Faridun Prince's Boss arena.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the Wayward Isle Map sometimes could not be completed.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Siora, Blade of the Mists, and Thariel, the Umbral Wraith had a lingering damage reduction buff.</li><li>Fixed a bug where defeating Manoki, the Chosen in The Jade Isles Map did not complete the Map.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the Wetlands Map Boss was not attacking as they were constantly trying to path to a rock that doesn't exist.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you could be unable to enter the Boss arena in the Razed Fields Map.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the Wetlands, Lofty Summit, Derelict Mansion, and Ornate Chambers Maps sometimes did not allow you to use a portal in the Boss arena after defeating the Boss.</li><li>Fixed an issue where some of the Mighty Silverfist's attacks were not correctly telegraphing that they were unavoidable.</li><li>Fixed a bug where rare monster packs could spawn in invalid locations in the Rugosa and Hidden Grotto Maps.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Skeletal Cobras and Tawhoa Mystic monsters were missing their Monster Categories.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the slowing debuff from the water in Solitary Confinement was not affected by Slow Potency, for reals this time.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the Tawhoan Tower Shield, Golden Targe, Blacksteel Crest Shield and Desert Buckler basetypes did not have any block chance, or grant Raise Shield or Parry for the respective basetype. This change does not apply to existing items.</li><li>Fixed an issue that prevented you from completing The Grand Quest (quest) and from obtaining your first 2 Expedition Skill Points if you had held a Logbook before talking to Dannig and obtaining your rewards.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the travelling merchant in the Khari Crossing sometimes did not come out of hiding after killing the surrounding monsters.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you were unable to store more than 300 Simulacrum Splinters in the Delirium Stash Tab.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Uncut Gems would not be sorted correctly in the Gem Stash.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Unique Items introduced in 0.3.0 could not be stored in the Unique Stash Tab.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the cutscene for entering Endgame from the Interludes was not playing.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Player 2 was unable to interact with The Well of Souls in Couch Co-Op.</li><li>Fixed a bug with UI navigation in Couch Co-Op after interacting with the salvage bench.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you were unable to travel to The Ziggurat Refuge from a waypoint when using a controller.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the game would not always unpause after applying a Vaal Orb to an Essence when using a controller.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the Amanamu's Void debuff was missing a description.</li><li>Fixed a bug where items for sale at the Gambler were sometimes not detailing whether the base type provided Armour, Evasion Rating, or Energy Shield.</li><li>Fixed a bug where you could not filter using negative numbers in the in-game Trade Market.</li><li>Fixed a bug where some players would not have a selected Hideout after logging into a different platform.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the "Show only Available" option in the Cosmetics window did not work until you un-ticked and re-ticked it.</li><li>Fixed a bug where part of the Passive Skill Tree was not visible when using right-panel mode on controller.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Forge Hammer could cause desync in specific circumstances.</li><li>Fixed desync that could occur when placing a totem.</li><li>Fixed desync that could occur with Earthshatter.</li><li>Fixed a client crash that could occur on controller input mode when certain items were placed into the crafting slot of the Essence Stash Tab.</li><li>Fixed a client crash that could occur when equipping the Merit of Service Unique Shield.</li><li>Fixed a client crash that could occur with Tempest Bell in party play.</li><li>Fixed a client crash that could occur with Storm Lance.</li><li>Fixed two other client crashes.</li><li>Fixed two instance crashes.</li></ul><div data-embed-type="html"><p><i>Click the button below to add GameSpot as a preferred source on Google</i></p></div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        <div>
	<p>
		Latest in
		Path of Exile 2
	</p>

	
</div>
  
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-first-post-third-edict-update-brings-league-improvements-full-patch-notes/1100-6534449/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong Release Date And Time]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-and-time/1100-6534447/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-and-time.1287774/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534447">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>After years and years of development and fears that the it might never release, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-everything-we-know-about-team-cherrys-metroidvania/1100-6520282/" data-ref-id="1100-6520282">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>'s release date is September 4. If you've been waiting for years and want to play the game the moment it unlocks, developer Team Cherry has published the exact launch times for the game.</p><p>The long-awaited <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-metroidvania-games/2900-4005/" data-ref-id="2900-4005">metroidvania</a> game launches on September 4 at 7 AM PT. Below you can see more global unlock times.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="359777696" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466275,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Hollow%20Knight%3A%20Silksong%20-%20Official%20Release%20Date%20Reveal%20Gameplay%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:112,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/hollow-knight-silksong-official-release-date-reveal-gameplay-trailer\/2300-6466275\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466275\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466275\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466275\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466275&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466275,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6534447&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;hollow-knight-silksong&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,platformer,metroidvania&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch,pc,linux,macintosh,playstation-5,xbox-series-x,nintendo-switch-2,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;team-cherry&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;hollow-knight&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;hollow-knight&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466275},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466275\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4553970-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/gLtOK2AW.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1755787620,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="gLtOK2AW" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Hollow Knight: Silksong - Official Release Date Reveal Gameplay Trailer</p>
      </div>
<h2><strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong release times</strong></h2><h3><strong>September 4</strong></h3><ul><li>7 AM PT</li><li>10 AM ET</li><li>4 PM CEST</li><li>11 PM JST</li></ul><p>As announced previously, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksongs-price-is-cheaper-than-you-might-have-guessed/1100-6534401/" data-ref-id="1100-6534401">Silksong will cost $20</a> at launch on all platforms. There will be a free Switch 2 upgrade for original Switch owners.</p><h2><strong>What is Hollow Knight: Silksong?</strong></h2><p>Hollow Knight: Silksong is the long-awaited sequel to Team Cherry's 2017 game Hollow Knight. The game sold more than 15 million copies and was highly regarded critically. The sequel, Silksong, was originally going to be DLC for Hollow Knight, but Team Cherry said its scope grew to the point that it had become a full, standalone game. Silksong has players becoming the character Hornet in a 2D platforming world. The game has new enemy types and bosses, and the <a href="https://www.altchar.com/game-news/team-cherry-post-hollow-knight-silksong-dev-update-e3-demo-axgGa3o4jK8P" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Greymoor area is among the biggest Team Cherry has ever created.</a></p><h2><strong>Why did Hollow Knight: Silksong take so long to come out?</strong></h2><p>Team Cherry founders Ari Gibson and William Pellen said Silksong was not stuck in development hell or anything like that. The enormous success of the 2017 game allowed the Australia-based developers to develop the follow-up at their own pace.</p><p>"It was never stuck or anything," Gibson told <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-08-21/why-silksong-team-cherry-s-sequel-to-hollow-knight-took-so-long-to-make" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Bloomberg</a>. "It was always progressing. It's just the case that we're a small team, and games take a lot of time. There wasn't any big controversial moment behind it."</p><p>One of the reasons why Silksong did not come out sooner was due to how, as previously stated, it was originally envisioned as an expansion to Hollow Knight. As for why Team Cherry went quiet and didn't discuss development updates with fans over the years, Gibson said the team opted not to because, "All we could really say is, 'We're still working on it.'"</p><p>Pellen added: "Instead of popping up and bugging people for the sake of it, it felt like our actual responsibility was just to work on the game."</p><p>At one point, Silksong was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/12/22175400/hollow-knight-silksong-sequel-xbox-game-pass-trailer" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">officially scheduled to launch before June 2023</a>, and Pellen said the team did "genuinely believe" the game would make it out then. But that didn't happen, of course.</p><p>The wait could have been even longer. Gibson said Team Cherry has a development structure that allows its members to "see results fasts," with ideas turning into real elements of the game "almost immediately." That was a fun way to work, Gibson said, but it also presented challenges.</p><p>"I remember at some point I just had to stop sketching," Gibson said. "Because I went, 'Everything I'm drawing here has to end up in the game. That's a cool idea, that's in. That's a cool idea, tha'ts in.' You realize, 'If I don't stop drawing, this is going to take 15 years to finish.'"</p><h2><strong>Is Hollow Knight: Silksong on Game Pass?</strong></h2><p>Hollow Knight: Silksong <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-will-be-on-xbox-game-pass/1100-6534209/" data-ref-id="1100-6534209">will be available at launch for Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass subscribers</a>. Alternatively, as mentioned, it can be purchased outright for $20.</p><div data-embed-type="html"><p><i>Click the button below to add GameSpot as a preferred source on Google</i></p></div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-release-date-and-time/1100-6534447/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>