<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 20:34:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phasmophobia's Next Map, Nell's Diner, Hints At The Game's Exciting Future]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/phasmophobia-next-map-nells-diner-hints-at-the-games-exciting-future/1100-6536105/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phasmophobias-next-map-nells-diner-hints-at-the-games-exciting-future.1349215/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536105">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/phasmophobia/" data-ref-id="5000-509328">Phasmophobia</a> first exploded onto the scene during the pandemic. The co-op ghost-hunting and investigation game was a hit when many people were spending more time at home but still seeking social experiences, and it's continued to grow and evolve in the years since. Its latest major update adds Nell's Diner, an Americana-infused map that pairs a desolate stretch of highway out front with an eerily familiar greasy-spoon setup inside. I recently took an early tour of the diner, and I was delighted to see how it hints at the future of what is surely one of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-multiplayer-horror-games/2900-7149/" data-ref-id="2900-7149">best multiplayer horror games</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Nell's Diner, Phasmophobia art director Corey Dixon told me, is full of unique assets, many more interaction points than a typical map in the game, and several Easter eggs. Back when the game was developed by a single person, Daniel Knight, his expertise was in programming, not things like art direction, which is why today Phasmophobia still mostly uses some generic assets for things like furnishings, vehicles, and even the feared ghosts themselves. But as Phasmophobia turns a corner and heads toward its exit from 1.0, the team is looking to overhaul its visual identity. That's been the thinking behind recent map makeovers like the run-down Grafton Farmhouse or its more lavish cousin, the Bleasdale Farmhouse.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I_z3_9n4YtU" data-width="854" data-height="480">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/I_z3_9n4YtU" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">In the future, this also means things like character models are getting a re-do and a cosmetics shop is on the way, but before any of that comes Nell's Diner, a brand-new map that looks quite unlike anything else in the game. Out front, the neon sign hazily buzzes through the fog, luring passersby who might've pulled off the road amid a tiring trip. When ghost investigators in Phasmophobia arrive on the scene, it'll be after <em>something</em> has gone on, which Dixon said is intentionally left for players to determine. A police vehicle is left out front with its lights still spinning, and indoors, some kind of ruckus has clearly occurred, with stools overturned and the kitchen left in a messy state.</p><p dir="ltr">Things like the cash register, various cooking supplies such as a mixer, a whipped cream dispenser, a functioning TV that plays a John Denver movie, and a classic-looking jukebox by the front door all give off a distinctly different feel from places like the residential Tanglewood Drive or the decrepit Sunny Meadows asylum. For one, they're all interactable; in some cases, they do one thing when players toy with them and another when a ghost does. But they're also bespoke assets chosen for the diner map. No longer is the team relying on asset packs from webshops that could turn up in other games--which, I'd add, helps Phasmophobia stand above its many copycats. It's more colorful, and because of the divide between customer and employee, it displays a few looks depending on where you are in the building.</p><p dir="ltr">Though no timeline is ready for sharing, Dixon told me the team would like to one day rework all the old maps with a similar eye to how they tackled the two farmhouses: major visual overhauls with some added focus on remapping the space when gameplay reasons call for it. They want the maps to feel lived in and genuine, not something too video gamey. In the diner, this manifests as the team including a hiding space that amounts to tucking behind a vending machine that's been pulled away from the wall for repairs.</p><p dir="ltr">The team is also giving more attention to its lore, especially now that a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/phasmophobia-movie-coming-from-blumhouse-to-haunt-theaters/1100-6532047/" data-ref-id="1100-6532047">Phasmophobia movie is on the way</a>. Dixon told me that Kinetic Games has decided to make lore a focal point as of late.</p><p dir="ltr">"We've got a backstory that we're hoping to weave into the game in subtle ways--in Easter eggs for certain ghosts, and even hints about the company the ghost hunters themselves are working for. Some of the maps may take on additional meaning and significance, too." He added that, across the whole game, there's "more going on than it seems on the surface." Some of those Easter eggs are to be discovered on the Nell's Diner map, Dixon said. "We’re sure it won’t take players long to figure out where to look, and when they do, they’ll love the surprises that are in store."</p><p dir="ltr">We played three rounds on Nell's Diner, giving me a firsthand look at things like its manager's office, multiple arcade cabinets showing off clever in-universe video games, the walk-in freezer with its persistent cold temperatures acting as a red herring ready to fool any newcomer into thinking they've found some evidence of ghost activity, and several looping opportunities, including the interior itself basically being a big loop. It features doors on either end of the customer area leading to the employees-only section out back. I asked if Nell's Diner has any secrets for players to find, and though Dixon didn't want to spoil anything so openly, he did confirm a keen eye will be rewarded.</p><p dir="ltr">For players who love maps like Tanglewood and other residences, Nell's Diner offers a space similar in size but aesthetically unlike anything to date. It's a "small" map, according to the dev team's own designation, and though it's certainly a fair label compared to the game's more expansive settings, it does well to illustrate the big plans the team has for the future of Phasmophobia.</p><p dir="ltr">Nell's Diner launches soon in Phasmophobia, as part of a free update on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/phasmophobia-next-map-nells-diner-hints-at-the-games-exciting-future/1100-6536105/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoD: Black Ops 7 Campaign Endgame Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-campaign-endgame-explained/1100-6536100/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cod-black-ops-7-campaign-endgame-explained.1349212/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536100">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Treyarch's latest <a href="https://x.com/Treyarch/status/1987943453368742003" rel="nofollow ">Dev Talk video</a> explains<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-7/" data-ref-id="5000-681591"> Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a>'s new endgame campaign content. It also shows one of the mission types and abilities players can expect to play in Black Ops 7's post-campaign content. Here is everything players need to know about how to unlock and play the campaign's endgame.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=inK3eFlCIu4" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/inK3eFlCIu4" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Treyarch confirmed there are a total of 11 campaign missions, and there will be a conclusion to the story, but completion of the story unlocks a twelfth mission as "endgame content." This is designed to add replayability and post-launch story to Black Ops 7's campaign.</p><p dir="ltr">The endgame grants access to Black Ops 7's full Avalon map. This allows for open-world gameplay with up to 32 players dropping into PvE matches inspired by Modern Warfare 2's DMZ mode and Modern Warfare 3's Zombies mode.</p><p dir="ltr">The endgame can be played solo or in a squad of up to four players. Treyarch confirmed that only one player needs to beat the campaign to earn access to the content, and they can be the party host and invite others who haven't completed the campaign yet.</p><p dir="ltr">Players can choose one of the main characters from the Black Ops 7 campaign or select a completely different operator to customize. Players can customize their operator in the endgame with the skills and abilities featured in the campaign, such as grappling hooks and the cloaking ability of Active Camo. There are also unique abilities featured in endgame. In the video, Treyarch design director Kevin Drew discussed the endgame's Shadow Break ability, which allows the player to create an area-of-effect blast that warps nearby enemies into the sky and kills them. Players can combine the abilities with other tech and gear to create unique moments in the endgame.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4599924-bo7-endgame-004.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4599924" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1680" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4599924-bo7-endgame-004.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4599924"></a><figcaption>Endgame character customization</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394540/4599924-bo7-endgame-004.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The Avalon map includes several points of interest from the Black Ops 7 campaign, as well as locations from Black Ops 2, Black Ops 4, and last year's Black Ops 6. The map features areas with four tiers of difficulty, and players will need to level up and progress to become powerful enough to fight through the higher-tier zones of Avalon.</p><p dir="ltr">Similar to extraction shooters, the endgame is designed around high-risk and high-reward missions, and players will need to survive and successfully exfiltrate from Avalon at the end of a session. If a player dies, they lose everything and will need to start over.</p><p dir="ltr">This is the first time Call of Duty is launching a game with full progression, as endgame allows players to level up, earn unique camos, and make battle pass progression all while playing the game's campaign content.</p><p>Treyarch's recent Dev Talk video discussed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-dev-reveals-highly-requested-changes-to-aim-assist-perks-and-movement/1100-6535601/">multiplayer changes players can expect at launch</a>, including adjustments to the game's movement, aim assist, and perks. The full <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-dev-reveals-season-1-content-new-maps-and-holiday-events-confirmed/1100-6535666/">Season 1 roadmap for Black Ops 7</a> can be found here, which includes six new multiplayer maps, three zombies maps, new weapons, seasonal events, and more.</p><p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 launches on November 14 for PlayStation 4 and 5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-7-campaign-endgame-explained/1100-6536100/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4 Skeleton World Boss Is Just A Big Pile Of Rocks In China]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-skeleton-world-boss-is-just-a-big-pile-of-rocks-in-china/1100-6536101/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4-skeleton-world-boss-is-just-a-big-pile-of-rocks-in-china.1349209/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536101">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Three years after releasing in the West, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/diablo-iv/" data-ref-id="5000-504255">Diablo 4</a> is finally coming to China on December 12, but not without some noticeable visual changes that make Blizzard's ARPG less bloody and horrific than usual.</p><p dir="ltr">The game finally received <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-will-release-in-a-new-massive-market-soon/1100-6533422/" data-ref-id="1100-6533422">approval</a> from China's National Press and Publication Administration earlier this year, and will now officially launch in December with a free trial and some unique cosmetics for those who pre-register. In order to launch in China, Blizzard has had to make some changes to the dark fantasy world of Sanctuary in order to abide by Chinese government regulations regarding the depiction of skeletons and blood.</p><p dir="ltr">Considering Diablo 4 is filled to the brim with blood, gore, and bones (including an entire Necromancer class that summons skeleton armies), Blizzard had its work cut out for it. Players in China are now beginning to participate in the game's beta, in the process revealing some of the creative solutions Blizzard has come up with in order to release Diablo 4 in the region.</p><p dir="ltr">As highlighted by <a href="https://www.wowhead.com/diablo-4/news/diablo-4s-chinese-servers-will-have-some-cosmetic-differences-for-players-379189" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wowhead</a>, blood in the Chinese version of Diablo 4 is instead depicted as a brown-orange mist that comes out of enemies when hit. For a game where massive groups of enemies explode in a cloud of red, having what looks like dust burst out from enemies instead is definitely a major difference that is noticeable from the game's opening moments.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4599928-diablo4wanderingdeathchina.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4599928" data-ratio="0.76640625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4599928-diablo4wanderingdeathchina.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4599928"></a><figcaption>Diablo 4's Wandering Death world boss looks a bit different in China (via Wowhead).</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4599928-diablo4wanderingdeathchina.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">While we don't yet know how Blizzard reimagined Necromancers' skeletal minions, one prominent skeleton enemy, the Wandering Death world boss, may offer a clue. Instead of a colossal-skeleton spirit, the Chinese version of Wandering Death is a giant collection of rocks that Western players would have a hard time guessing is even the same enemy. It remains to be seen if Blizzard has taken a similar rock approach to all skeletons in the game, but it certainly makes for a much different vibe.</p><p dir="ltr">Even some ability icons have been changed. The Rogue ability Penetrating Shot, which in the Western version of Diablo 4 uses an icon depicting an arrow passing through two skulls, is similar in the Chinese version but somehow more unsettling. Instead of skulls, the Chinese ability icon depicts two creepy masks skewered by an arrow.</p><p dir="ltr">There will no doubt be plenty other noticeable differences once the game is out in full. However, all the changes are expected to be cosmetic only, with the game playing the same as it currently does in all regions.</p><p dir="ltr">In the West, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-11-might-be-its-biggest-rework-yet/1100-6535476/" data-ref-id="1100-6535476">Diablo 4 Season 11</a> will launch on December 9, just a few days before the game's arrival in China. Season 11 will bring updates both big and small to the ARPG, including major changes to systems like Masterworking and Tempering as well as smaller quality-of-life tweaks like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-11-will-finally-unlock-waypoints-from-the-start/1100-6536097/" data-ref-id="1100-6536097">Waypoints being unlocked from the start</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-skeleton-world-boss-is-just-a-big-pile-of-rocks-in-china/1100-6536101/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight: Silksong's New Patch Finally Nerfs The Muckmaggots]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksongs-new-patch-finally-nerfs-the-muckmaggots/1100-6536098/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-silksongs-new-patch-finally-nerfs-the-muckmaggots.1349146/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536098">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>If there's a common complaint about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/hollow-knight-silksong/" data-ref-id="5000-493311" data-mce-href="/games/hollow-knight-silksong/">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a>, it's that the game can be punishingly hard at times. Team Cherry has previously shared a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-patch-makes-the-game-easier/1100-6534577/" data-ref-id="1100-6534577" data-mce-href="/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-patch-makes-the-game-easier/1100-6534577/">PC Patch to lower Silksong's difficulty</a>, but the game's newest update goes even further by nerfing the damned Muckmaggots that make things so difficult in Bilewater and the Putrified Ducts.</p><p>The Muckmaggots previously ate Hornet's silk with impunity, and even binding these creatures forced players to use what little silk they had to hold them back. The update makes it easier to clear out the Muckmaggots with the Wreath of Purity, which gives Hornet a chance to heal herself by using a second bind.</p><p>Silksong's Chinese translation has also been updated with fan-made translation by Team Cart Fit. Team Cherry <a href="https://www.teamcherry.com.au/blog/silksong-patch-4" data-target="true" data-mce-href="https://www.teamcherry.com.au/blog/silksong-patch-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">praised the new translation</a> by calling it "well-versed in the (quite dense) narrative and lore of both Hollow Knight games" and thanked the members of the team for letting the studio use it. The earlier Chinese translation drew criticisms from native Chinese speakers and led to the game being review-bombed.</p><p>Some of the other beneficial changes in the patch include the elimination of the same delivery in a row from couriers, as well as enabling rumble comparability with more controllers. However, the game is making Gurr the Outcast a little bit harder to fight by decreasing the time he stands unmoving.</p><p>The latest patch is currently only available for PC users, but Silksong players on consoles will get it in the near future. The complete patch notes are included below.</p><h2>Hollow Knight: Silksong Patch 4 (1.0.29242) Notes</h2><ul><li>Updated Simplified Chinese translation to use fan translation provided by Team Cart Fix.</li><li>Switched to Unity's Input System to improve overall controller support. This includes rumble features now working for various controllers, and additional controllers being recognized. Some issues may remain. For a full list of supported controllers and features, please <a href="https://docs.unity3d.com/Packages/com.unity.inputsystem@1.14/manual/SupportedDevices.html" data-target="true" data-mce-href="https://docs.unity3d.com/Packages/com.unity.inputsystem@1.14/manual/SupportedDevices.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">visit this site</a>.</li><li>Added additional dithering levels to advanced options. Defaults to 'low'.</li><li>Added film grain effect to advanced options. Defaults to ‘off’</li><li>Various localisation fixes implemented across all languages.</li><li>Fixed Styx not giving rosaries when delivering the Queen's Egg.</li><li>Fixed Druid's Eyes sometimes not equipping correctly when first acquired.</li><li>Fixed some down attack colliders getting stuck on in rare instances.</li><li>Fixed several instances of Hornet's plasmified state clearing when not intended (eg Bellway travel).</li><li>Fixed issues entering the plasmified state when killing a Winged Lifeseed, rather than using the Plasmium Phial.</li><li>Reduced unintentionally long bind time when using Multibinder with the Shaman crest.</li><li>Updated Multibinder's initial bind to clear maggots, per community comments.</li><li>Wreath of Purity durability increased.</li><li>Fixed void incorrectly conducting electricity.</li><li>Gurr the Outcast trap-throw attack updated from single lob to spin-style, to reduce time spent static. Other slight refinements.</li><li>Fixed Beast Crest fury slashes not piercing as intended.</li><li>Fixed Rune Rage damage scaling incorrectly.</li><li>Fixed Thread Storm damage tapering (additional hits don't taper down as sharply).</li><li>Fixed rare instances of regaining control when grabbed by a Wraith.</li><li>Fixed couriers incorrectly offering the same delivery immediately after completing it.</li><li>Fixed additional instances of Hornet being able to push some enemy types through the floor.</li><li>Fixed issues when using Harpoon to stun or kill certain bosses.</li><li>Fixed Fractured Mask not protecting against volt hazards.</li><li>Various smaller tweaks and fixes.</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksongs-new-patch-finally-nerfs-the-muckmaggots/1100-6536098/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diablo 4 Season 11 Will Finally Unlock Waypoints From The Start]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-11-will-finally-unlock-waypoints-from-the-start/1100-6536097/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/diablo-4-season-11-will-finally-unlock-waypoints-from-the-start.1349080/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536097">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-11-might-be-its-biggest-rework-yet/1100-6535476/" data-ref-id="1100-6535476">Diablo 4 Season 11</a> is bringing huge changes to Blizzard's ARPG, among them a major departure for how the game's map and Waypoints work.</p><p dir="ltr">Since launch, players of Diablo 4 every season have had to unlock most fast-travel Waypoints at the beginning of each new season. This was because discovering Waypoints and uncovering fog of war from the map was tied to Diablo 4's zone-based Renown system, which partially reset each season.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fzBb0OsE0AY" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fzBb0OsE0AY" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Come Season 11, that will no longer be the case. In an interview with Diablo content creator <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fzBb0OsE0AY" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DuQ</a>, lead live game designer Colin Finer said players who skip the campaign at the start of a new season will have all Waypoints unlocked. Skipping the campaign requires players to have completed it once before.</p><p dir="ltr">It's a big change that will make the start of each new season go significantly faster, as players will no longer need to mount up and manually travel to various locations, unlocking Waypoints along the way. Instead, Waypoints will be available from the start, letting players quickly and easily travel to wherever they need to go, which should substaintially speed up the start of each season.</p><p dir="ltr">The change goes hand-in-hand with one of Diablo 4's other big Season 11 changes, as the game will be removing the current Renown system that Waypoints are tied to in favor of a new Season Rank system. Many of the most important rewards from Renown, like additional skill and Paragon points, will instead be tied to completing seasonal objectives as part of Season Rank. Altars of Lilith, another aging piece of Diablo 4 that saw players exploring the map and was tied to the Renown system, are also seeing a big change. They are being reworked to no longer grant permanent stat boosts and will instead grant experience and other minor rewards when discovered.</p><p dir="ltr">Other huge system reworks coming in Season 11 include significant changes to how Masterworking and Tempering gear works, adjustments to defense and healing, updates to make <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4s-monsters-are-getting-deadlier-and-smarter-in-season-11/1100-6535477/" data-ref-id="1100-6535477">monsters smarter and more deadly</a>, and the reintroduction of leaderboards in the form of a new challenge dungeon called The Tower.</p><p dir="ltr">Diablo 4 Season 11 is set to begin on December 9. Blizzard has not yet officially announced Diablo 4's second expansion, but it's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4s-second-expansion-isnt-coming-until-2026/1100-6529452/" data-ref-id="1100-6529452">expected to arrive in 2026</a>, and just might introduce the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/evidence-of-a-diablo-4-paladin-class-may-have-just-leaked/1100-6533963/" data-ref-id="1100-6533963">Paladin class</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/diablo-4-season-11-will-finally-unlock-waypoints-from-the-start/1100-6536097/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>