<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gameinformer_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gameinformer_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gameinformer_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:45:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty Will No Longer Release Back-To-Back Modern Warfare Or Black Ops Games]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/10/call-of-duty-will-no-longer-release-back-to-back-modern-warfare-or-black-ops-games</link>
            <guid>1378459</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Less than a month after the launch of <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/call-of-duty-black-ops-7">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a>, Activision has revealed that it will no longer release back-to-back releases of Black Ops or Modern Warfare subseries games. That's especially relevant, considering this year's Black Ops 7 follows last year's&nbsp;<a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/call-of-duty-black-ops-6" target="_blank">Black Ops 6</a>; before that, the Call of Duty team released&nbsp;<a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-iii/not-so-special-ops" target="_blank">Modern Warfare III</a>&nbsp;in 2023, one year after <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-ii/wide-of-the-mark">Modern Warfare II</a> in 2022.</p><p>It sounds like this type of release cadence won't happen again moving forward, according to a new <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2025/12/call-of-duty-message-from-the-team">blog post</a> from the Call of Duty team. In the post, the team thanks the community for the feedback over the last few months, noting, "We also know that for some of you, the franchise has not met your expectations fully." It then says, "To be very clear, we know what you expect and rest assured we will deliver, and overdeliver, on those expectations moving forward."&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3TMNklf_qtQ"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3TMNklf_qtQ" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>The blog post then details the future of Black Ops 7, including a free week of multiplayer and zombies next week, a Double XP weekend, and "unprecedented seasonal support," before announcing the aforementioned release cadence change for the franchise.</p><p>"We will no longer do back-to-back releases of Modern Warfare or Black Ops games," the post reads. "The reasons are many, but the main one is to ensure we provide an absolutely unique experience each and every year. We will drive innovation that is meaningful, not incremental. While we aren't sharing those plans today, we look forward to doing so when the time is right."&nbsp;</p><p>The post concludes by stating that the future of Call of Duty is strong and that the teams involved believe the best days are ahead. We'll see how this plays out for the franchise in the coming years. In the meantime, read <em>Game Informer's </em><a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/call-of-duty-black-ops-7/good-luck-have-fun">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 review</a>.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>How do you feel about this change? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/10/call-of-duty-will-no-longer-release-back-to-back-modern-warfare-or-black-ops-games]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>