<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:11:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix Games exec prepares bowl of word salad to announce new role as VP of GenAI for Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/netflix-games-exec-prepares-bowl-of-word-salad-to-announce-new-role-as-vp-of-genai-for-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflix-games-exec-prepares-bowl-of-word-salad-to-announce-new-role-as-vp-of-genai-for-games.1026651/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/netflix-games-exec-prepares-bowl-of-word-salad-to-announce-new-role-as-vp-of-genai-for-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Netflix Games has thrown its weight behind generative AI less than two weeks after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/netflix-closes-its-only-aaa-game-studio">shuttering its only triple-A development studio</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The streaming giant has appointed Mike Verdu as its new VP of GenAI for Games so it can capitalize on what it calls a "once in a generation inflection point for game development and player experiences." Verdu previously served as VP of Netflix Games but earlier this year revealed he would be </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/netflix-games-boss-mike-verdu-is-taking-on-a-new-role-at-the-streamer">taking on a new role at the company</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. At the time, he said his new position would champion "innovation in game development."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7259029850827423744/">Speaking about his new role on Linkedin</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Verdu waxed lyrical about the potential of generative AI and said the technology will "accelerate the velocity of development and unlock truly novel game experiences that will surprise, delight, and inspire players."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I am focused on a creator-first vision for AI, one that puts creative talent at the center, with AI being a catalyst and an accelerant," he added. "AI will enable big game teams to move much faster, and will also put an almost unimaginable collection of new capabilities in the hands of developers in smaller game teams."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Verdu suggested figuring out how to harness generative AI technology is the next big challenge facing the game industry.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I don't think I've been this excited about an opportunity in this industry since the 90s, when we saw a new game launch every few months that redefined what was possible. It was an incredible time to be making games as talented creators showed all of us what the future looked like. Guess what? We're back to those days of seemingly unlimited potential and the rapid pace of innovation, which resulted in mind-blowing surprises for players every few months," he added.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I can't believe how lucky I am to be alive when a wave this big is about to hit the game industry. Many view this technology with fear, but I am a game-maker at heart and I see its potential to unlock all of us, to create mind-blowing new experiences for players, to lift us to new heights. Yes, we'll have to adapt and change, but when have we failed to meet that challenge as an industry?"</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Major game companies continue to board the generative AI bandwagon">Major game companies continue to board the generative AI bandwagon</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Verdu isn't the first executive to whisper sweet nothings into the primordial ear of generative AI. Amazon Games CEO Christoph Hartmann previously claimed the technology can be used to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/amazon-games-ceo-thinks-genai-can-help-make-better-ideas-for-games">streamline production</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> without "taking work away from anyone."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA boss Andrew Wilson has repeatedly espoused the supposed benefits of the technology, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/ea-ceo-60-percent-of-dev-processes-could-be-impacted-by-generative-ai-">suggested 60 percent of the company's development processes could be "impacted" by generative AI</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Those remarks came shortly after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-will-spend-over-125-million-laying-off-5-percent-of-its-workforce">EA laid off 5 percent of its workforce</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Other notable players like Square Enix, Ubisoft, and Embracer Group have also begun experimenting with the technology, but how do developers in the production trenches feel about its looming presence?</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A recent </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/survey-reveals-devs-consider-genai-double-edged-sword-in-game-development">Game Developer Collective survey</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> indicated many devs feel generative AI represents a double-edged sword. 30 percent of respondents said the technology could reduce development costs, but 35 percent also felt it would reduce the quality of titles produced in the next 12 months.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There are also ethical and legal concerns about how some generative AI technologies have been trained, and who actually owns the content produced by tools (such as those developed by OpenAI) that have consumed "publicly available information"–including copyrighted material and personal information. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-67826601">As noted by the BBC</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the New York Times is currently suing both OpenAI and Microsoft for billions over allegations of copyright infringement.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Others are concerned the dawn of generative AI could eventually result in more job losses across the industry. SAG-AFTRA is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/sag-aftra-authorizes-video-game-actor-strike-over-ai">currently striking</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in a bid to prevent that outcome by securing AI protections for video game performers.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>