<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - www.gamedeveloper.com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for www.gamedeveloper.com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 16:19:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hades devs: accidentally inventing a subgenre was 'surreal']]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/hades-devs-say-accidentally-inventing-a-subgenre-was-surreal-</link>
            <guid>1447087</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Supergiant Games</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The evolution of subgenres in game development is a fascinating topic. What is the alchemy that makes one game a hit, and the other a mass inspiration?&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The developers who make such games certainly don't have all the answers. At the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/clair-obscur-keeps-riding-high-at-2026-dice-awards">2026 DICE Awards</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, we asked Supergiant Games' Greg Kasavin and Amir Rao (fresh off of winning the "Best Action Game" award for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.supergiantgames.com/games/hades-ii">Hades II</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) about the experience of watching </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hades</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> become such an inspirational text for other independent developers. Not only did the game sell over a million copies, but its approach to run-based storytelling, area-based upgrades, and character design have become essential for games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1835240/Spiritfall/">Spiritfall</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1123770/Curse_of_the_Dead_Gods/">Curse of the Dead Gods</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1763250/SWORN/">Sworn</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, just to name a few. The phrase "Hades-like" is now a jumping off point for a certain subcategory in the roguelike genre.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It was really surreal for us," said Kasavin when asked about the phenomenon. "When we were making </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hades</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, we thought we were simply making a roguelike. We were playing games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dead Cells</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Slay the Spire</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and were just making a game in that genre."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/outgoing-sucker-punch-boss-hopes-studio-can-make-games-in-shorter-periods-of-time-" target="_self" data-discover="true">Outgoing Sucker Punch boss hopes studio can make games in 'shorter periods of time'</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hades </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">didn't invent the roguelike genre (that would obviously be </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Rogue</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Rogue Legacy</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> being a major modern point of inspiration), but it offered developers a narrative framework that not only unlocked potential storytelling opportunities, but helped shape the flow and pace of general gameplay. The "home base" area that players return to between runs acts as a hub for storytelling and signifying progression, and the loop of "clear encounter, meet character, receive reward from said character, rinse and repeat" is a replicable structure that doesn't require a cast of Classical Greek gods to lean on.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Did the aforementioned gods grant Supergiant Games some form of boon to make this possible? "I did not discount that as a possibility," joked Kasavin. But luckily for the rest of the game development world, you don't need an oracle to understand the path to Supergiant's success</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Gods ain't gonna help you son">Gods ain't gonna help you son</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Kasavin and Rao both shared a more pertinent sentiment about the process of making </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hades </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hades II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">—that they and their peers at Supergiant treated the game as being "their own spin" on an existing genre, not an effort to reinvent the medium.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rao observed that when it comes to genre definitions, that conversation took place entirely after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hades </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">left Early Access, and that it was determined entirely by popular reception. It wasn't something that could be planned or even controlled. "That's just a part of a reception and conversation at a time where we're not part of the conversation anymore."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It's almost in some respects like some of the stuff we did with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Bastion</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">," said Kasavin, alluding to Supergiant's first game. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Bastion</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was an isometric hack-and-slash game elevated by the voice of narrator Logan Cunningham, who provided running commentary on the player's actions while unspooling a story of a world wracked by calamity. The highly-polished gameplay was built on familiar principles, but Cunningham's voice, the sharp storytelling, and artist Jen Zee's clear perspective catapulted the game—and its makers—into history.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We thought there was kind of a niche we could carve out for ourselves, like infusing it with more narrative, making it a little bit more forgiving," Kasavin said when recalling the making of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hades</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "It succeeded beyond our wildest expectations, to the point where we suddenly realize people are talking about it like it's this kind of subgenre."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"That's how that stuff happens sometimes right? We had no clue whatsoever—we didn't think we were doing anything innovative at the time."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"There was no other way we could make this game," Rao added. "We just made the decisions that felt right and natural to us."&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' 4X strategy game Zephon, Iron Anchor Studios' Down With The Ship, and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/hades-devs-say-accidentally-inventing-a-subgenre-was-surreal-]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>