<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 21:46:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mobile dev Sandsoft is laying off around 65 employees and closing two studios]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mobile-dev-sandsoft-is-laying-off-around-65-employees-and-closing-two-studios</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mobile-dev-sandsoft-is-laying-off-around-65-employees-and-closing-two-studios.1251447/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">July 23, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sandsoft, a mobile developer headquartered in Saudi Arabia, is closing its studios in Riyadh and Barcelona, Spain, while laying off around 65 employees in the process.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">First </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://mobilegamer.biz/sandsoft-is-closing-its-barcelona-and-riyadh-studios-up-to-65-staff-affected/">reported by MobileGamer.Biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> earlier today, the layoffs are affecting around 40 staff members in Barcelona and 25 in Riyadh. The outlet was told that the job cuts are affecting employees working on internally developed games, while those working in publishing are safe. The studio is looking into transitioning some of the affected members into the latter, but there's no confirmation as of yet.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Sandsoft is doubling down on publishing, an area of our business where we’ve already demonstrated significant growth and see significant opportunities for future success," Sandsoft CEO David Fernández told MobileGamer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"As part of this strategic shift, we’ve made the difficult decision to close our internal studios in Barcelona and Riyadh. We deeply appreciate the team’s creativity and dedication, and we’re fully committed to supporting everyone through this transition."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A spokesperson added that the decision "isn't about the quality of work or talent at these studios," and that "it's really about concentrating our resources where we can have the biggest impact and build sustainable growth." As such, the team will now be concentrating solely on publishing.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/igea-launches-game-on-australia-to-assist-and-promote-local-developers" target="_self" data-discover="true">IGEA launches Game On Australia to assist and promote local developers</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Sandsoft still has two offices in Finland and China">Sandsoft still has two offices in Finland and China</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.pocketgamer.biz/sandsoft-plots-hybridcasual-expansion-with-three-new-deals/">reported by PocketGamer.Biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Sandsoft signed three new games as recently as March of this year. Back then, the studio also said it had "several more" games in testing and scheduled to release throughout the year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Riyadh studio is closing merely three years after opening, while the Barcelona studio was opened in 2023. Earlier that same year, Fernández spoke to MobileGamer.Biz about a plan to become a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://mobilegamer.biz/sandsoft-is-closing-its-barcelona-and-riyadh-studios-up-to-65-staff-affected/">mega publisher</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Our ambition is to be a leader in the mobile games industry, from our region to the world, in the same way that you have in the U.S. not just mobile, but larger organizations —you have the Activisions, you have the Take-Twos, you have Electronic Arts," Fernández said. "Looking to China, you have Tencent and you have NetEase. We want to be one of those."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mobile-dev-sandsoft-is-laying-off-around-65-employees-and-closing-two-studios]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>