<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamedeveloper_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamedeveloper_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamedeveloper_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:46:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Discord's potential IPO means for its business and the video game industry]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/what-discord-s-potential-ipo-means-for-its-business-and-the-video-game-industry</link>
            <guid>1406734</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Last week,&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2026-01-06/chat-platform-discord-is-said-to-file-confidentially-for-ipo?embedded-checkout=true">Bloomberg reported</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;that Discord has filed confidentially for an initial public offering. With more than 200 million monthly users globally, Discord is among the few major social media platforms to remain private.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Now, it&nbsp;could be about to push ahead with the largest IPO in the video game industry since 2021, when Roblox Corp. and several other companies went public, according to PitchBook senior research analyst Eric Bellomo, speaking to Game Developer. It means Discord, used by both industry professionals and consumers, is at a juncture that will certainly have an impact on the platform itself and the wider industry.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bloomberg reported that Discord is working with Goldman Sachs Group and JP Morgan Chase on the listing. Discussions are ongoing, and the company could still decide to hit the brakes. Discord told Bloomberg that it remains focused on "delivering the best possible experience for users and building a strong sustainable business."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Talk about a potential IPO has been ongoing for some time, and continued when Discord co-founder and former CEO Jason Citron stepped down in April 2025 and named former Activision Blizzard vice chairman Humam Sakhhini as his successor. Just a month prior,&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/05/technology/discord-ipo.html">the New York Times reported</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;the company was in talks with bankers about an IPO.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-it-had-nothing-to-offer-halifax-union-calls-out-ubisoft-after-first-talks-following-studio-closure" target="_self" data-discover="true">'It had nothing to offer:' Halifax union lambasts Ubisoft after first talks following studio closure</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Humam and I are fundamentally aligned that creating long-term value requires long-term thinking and focusing on an amazing user experience,"&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://discord.com/blog/passing-the-torch">Citron said in a public letter to staff when announcing his exit as chief exec</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Discord was born out of a failed mobile game studio by Citron and Stanislav Vishnevisky. Though the game didn't take off, its internal messaging tools worked, and the company pivoted from the Hammer &amp; Chisel studio into Discord. It succeeded—and quickly—as a chat platform for gamers and has continued to grow; the company made a reported $890 million in revenue in 2024, almost double what it earned in 2022. Investors valued the company at $15 billion after a&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-09-15/chat-app-discord-is-worth-15-billion-after-new-funding">$500 million funding round in 2021</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The sheer amount of financing pumped into Discord over the years means it's not necessarily surprising that Discord would seek to go public. Investors, at some point, want to make a return on their&nbsp;investment.&nbsp;An acquisition, like the $12 billion bid Discord rejected from Microsoft in 2021, is one way to achieve that goal. An IPO is another. Discord will still have institutional investors, Bellomo said, but an IPO widens who can buy shares in a company.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It brings liquidity," Bellomo said, "It's also a way to finance future operations without navigating these kinds of opaque and sometimes slow private markets."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/rockstar-launches-an-official-mod-marketplace" target="_self" data-discover="true">Rockstar Games launches an official mod marketplace</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Discord, as a private company, focuses primarily on growing its user base as a free-to-use platform. "When they stay private, they can test different ways to monetize their user base," Bellomo said. "They are primarily a freemium service right now, but there's a lot more latitude to experiment, to fail in some cases, and keep growing. As a public company, that balance shifts."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="&quot;It's a key validation that gaming can still be a venture scale ecosystem and still attract venture dollars and continue to grow&quot;">"It's a key validation that gaming can still be a venture scale ecosystem and still attract venture dollars and continue to grow"</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Discord, as a public company, has to publicly report to shareholders who demand growth—both in the user base and how Discord is able to monetize its service. Discord, as it stands, is a perfectly fine product to use at its free tiers. Its Nitro subscription makes that basic service better, in some ways, like allowing better streaming quality, custom emojis, and the ability to upload larger files. Discord's main Nitro subscription is $10 a month, and its Basic tier is $2.99 a month.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The sort of further monetization expected of a public company could look like "the introduction of an advertising service, higher prices, more tiers, additional services to businesses, so B2B offerings in the form of ecommerce infrastructure or game publishing services."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-ubisoft-laying-off-staff-at-abu-dhabi-studio" target="_self" data-discover="true">Update: Ubisoft confirms layoffs at Abu Dhabi studio</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"The primary distinction is, as a consumer product in the private markets, you can really focus on growth and experimentation," Bellomo said. "On the monetization front, as a public company, you need to both grow and monetize more and more each quarter."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Despite being a multi-billion company, Discord has had this reputation as a platform for gamers; it's dialed into the culture it has cultivated as a company. Discord has a lot in common with a chat platform like Slack, but the target audience is clearly different. It's the gamer's platform, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://kotaku.com/discord-reddit-ipo-gaming-server-gta-6-enshitification-1851768033">there is already concern regarding what some call the</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;"enshittification" of companies that go public and become fixated on delivering value to shareholders.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A key challenge for Discord will be in maintaining that image as "a third digital space, and one that is very welcoming of tech-forward users and its user base culture," Bellomo said. "Its credibility attracts new users to the platform, and it will need to do so while also monetizing those users more in the future."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Beyond the direct impact on Discord as a platform and the business around it, the potential IPO has wider implications for the video game industry. Bellomo said the massive IPO validates the video game industry for investors in a period where there has been "a pretty precipitous decline in the number of investors who are actively writing checks to gaming startups."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It's a key validation that gaming can still be a venture scale ecosystem and still attract venture dollars and continue to grow," Bellomo said, while noting that the industry's trajectory goes well beyond what happens with the Discord IPO.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The second big impact an IPO of Discord's size has on the industry is in transparency, Bellomo said. The fact a public company needs to make its financials available to existing and prospective investors will be an asset for those looking to conduct an industry health check, which often includes keen-eyed reporters.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Another undercurrent behind Discord's potential IPO is the scrutiny the company has faced over its approach to child safety. Like&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Roblox</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Discord has been sued for allegedly&nbsp; facilitating the exploitation of children.&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/discord-rolls-out-new-teen-safety-and-moderation-tools-for-guardians">Discord rolled out new safety and moderation tools</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;in November following the filing of several lawsuits,&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.njoag.gov/ag-platkin-sues-messaging-app-discord-for-unlawful-practices-that-expose-nj-kids-to-child-predators-and-violent-sexual-content/">including one from New Jersey attorney general Matthew J. Platkin</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. In September, Sakhnini was asked to appear at a House Oversight and Government Reform Committee to testify regarding the platform's role in "the radicalization of online forum users," citing the killing of conservative influencer Charlie Kirk.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That hearing does not appear to have been scheduled at the time of writing.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Columnist, Game Developer</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nicole Carpenter is a veteran reporter who has been covering the video game industry for over a decade.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/what-discord-s-potential-ipo-means-for-its-business-and-the-video-game-industry]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['It had nothing to offer:' Halifax union lambasts Ubisoft after first talks following studio closure]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-it-had-nothing-to-offer-halifax-union-calls-out-ubisoft-after-first-talks-following-studio-closure</link>
            <guid>1406689</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">January 15, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Photograph and logo via Ubisoft</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">CWA Canada has accused Ubisoft of failing to adequately prepare for its first meeting with union representatives at its recently-shuttered Halifax studio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-closes-halifax-studio-weeks-after-workers-vote-to-unionize">Ubisoft announced the closure last week</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and indicated the move was part of on an ongoing restructuring program. The news, however, came just weeks after the majority of workers at the Canadian studio </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-halifax-workers-form-a-union">voted to unionize</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> under the CWA Canada banner.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The timing raised eyebrows. CWA Canada quickly released a statement outlining plans to "pursue every legal recourse" to protect the rights of union members, before </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/cwa-canada-seeking-answers-from-ubisoft-lawyers-over-halifax-closure">calling on Ubisoft lawyers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to prove the closure was based solely on financial necessity.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ubisoft purportedly agreed to provide evidence this week, but according to CWA Canada arrived to the first meeting between both parties on January 14, 2026, woefully underprepared.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I write to share news from a disappointing meeting with Ubisoft this morning. Ubisoft came to the table with nothing. No documentation proving financial distress, and no plan to find work at other Ubisoft operations or&nbsp;increase severance," explained CWA Canada in a note sent to all Halifax workers yesterday and shared with Game Developer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"When Ubisoft's lawyers asked 'what WE want?' we told them our priority was getting everyone&nbsp; real jobs either remotely or at other Canadian locations. We also explicitly raised the issue of people on parental leave being treated incredibly unfairly by being told they won't qualify for the proposed 2 month severance notice pay in full, like everyone else."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/what-discord-s-potential-ipo-means-for-its-business-and-the-video-game-industry" target="_self" data-discover="true">What Discord's potential IPO means for its business and the video game industry</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Ubisoft Halifax union questions Ubisoft's &quot;commitment to treating people fairly&quot;">Ubisoft Halifax union questions Ubisoft's "commitment to treating people fairly"</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">CWA Canada described the meeting—which was attended by five people including a lawyer and human resources manager from Ubisoft Montreal and the CWA Canada union senior staff representative—as "frustrating."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"[Ubisoft's] lack of preparation along with the fact that they gave no advance notice of the closure, makes us question their intentions and their commitment to treating people fairly," continues the note. "We continue demanding&nbsp;real information, and to get the answers and the compensation you deserve after 10 years with this company."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">CWA Canada president Carmel Smyth reiterated that Ubisoft "had nothing to offer" during the meeting and claimed the publisher was "non-committal" about the union's request to relocate workers impacted by the closure of its Halifax studio.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Smyth said Ubisoft pledged to provide financial documentation related to the shuttering by January 16, 2026, but expressed doubt as to whether it will actually deliver the goods.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/rockstar-launches-an-official-mod-marketplace" target="_self" data-discover="true">Rockstar Games launches an official mod marketplace</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">CWA Canada </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://cwacanada.ca/2026/01/13/union-files-labour-board-complaint-over-ubisoft-halifax-shutdown/">filed a labor complaint</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> against Ubisoft with the Nova Scotia Labour Board earlier this week that directly accuses the Assassin's Creed maker of torching Ubisoft Halifax to keep out the union.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Smyth said Ubisoft will eventually need to provide financial information to the Labor Board to support its current position—but noted that could take months.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For now, union representatives stressed they will keep fighting for better compensation and jobs for those impacted by the closure.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer has approached Ubisoft for comment.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-it-had-nothing-to-offer-halifax-union-calls-out-ubisoft-after-first-talks-following-studio-closure]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>