<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:21:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All These Games Sold Exactly One Copy In The US In October]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-these-games-sold-exactly-one-copy-in-the-us-in-october/1100-6536387/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-these-games-sold-exactly-one-copy-in-the-us-in-october.1359547/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536387">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Battlefield 6 sold <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6s-first-month-sales-were-higher-than-any-game-since-2022-in-the-us/1100-6536380/" data-ref-id="1100-6536380">many, many copies in the US in October</a>, but which games sold precisely one copy? As it turns out, lots of games did that.</p><p>Circana's Mat Piscatella <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3m632god4cc25" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">shared</a> a list of games that sold one physical copy in the US in October, and they include Burnout Paradise for Xbox 360, The Incredibles 2: Rise of the Underminer for Game Boy Advance, and Backyard Baseball for the PlayStation 2.</p><p>You can see a longer list below, but note that it's not exhaustive. Some games only sold two copies in October, including <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3m633aj3ay225" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tom Clancy's End War for the PSP.</a></p><p>Something we do not know here is who is buying these games, where they're buying them, or why they're buying them. But Piscatella said it's not out of the ordinary. "Happens every month. There was a copy somewhere in the store for who knows how long," Piscatella said.</p><h2><strong>Games that sold one physical copy in the US in October:</strong></h2><ul><li>Burnout Paradise (Xbox 360)</li><li>Carnival Games: Wild West 3D (3DS)</li><li>The Incredibles 2: Rise of the Underminer (Game Boy Advance)</li><li>Imagine Fashion Stylist (Nintendo DS)</li><li>Spore (PC)</li><li>Backyard Baseball (PS2)</li><li>Hasbro Family Game Night 3 (PS3)</li><li>Cooking Mama Cookstar (PS4)</li><li>Ultra Bust A Move (original Xbox)</li></ul><p>As for Battlefield 6's chart-topping results, Circana doesn't share unit-sales data, but the game was No. 1 for October and quickly became the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/2025-best-selling-games/2900-6281/" data-ref-id="2900-6281">No. 1 best-selling game overall in the US for 2025 so far.</a> Battlefield 6 even outpaced the first-month sales of Black Ops 6 and Modern Warfare 3.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/all-these-games-sold-exactly-one-copy-in-the-us-in-october/1100-6536387/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pricey WoW Transmog Changes Have Players Angry And Confused]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pricey-wow-transmog-changes-have-players-angry-and-confused/1100-6536391/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pricey-wow-transmog-changes-have-players-angry-and-confused.1359544/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536391">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/world-of-warcraft/" data-ref-id="5000-3919">World of Warcraft's</a> upcoming <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/in-world-of-warcraft-midnight-whats-old-is-new-again/1100-6534043/" data-ref-id="1100-6534043">Midnight expansion</a> is bringing sweeping changes to the MMORPG's transmog system, but they look to be far more expensive than players were led to believe.</p><p dir="ltr">Earlier this year when Midnight was fully revealed, developer Blizzard announced it would be overhauling the game's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-midnight-is-finally-making-transmog-much-cheaper-and-more-convenient/1100-6534017/" data-ref-id="1100-6534017">cosmetic outfit system in a way that would save players gold</a>. Instead of having to pay gold to transmog individual gear pieces, players would instead transmog gear slots. That slot would then retain its appearance regardless of whatever item was equipped, useful as players level up and equip new gear over the course of an expansion or season.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WmG98apVwKw" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/WmG98apVwKw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Sounds good on paper. However, the system is now testable on the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/world-of-warcraft-midnight-beta-details-shared-by-blizzard/1100-6535837/" data-ref-id="1100-6535837">WoW: Midnight beta</a>, and as broken down by <a href="https://www.wowhead.com/news/it-costs-5-700-gold-to-save-a-full-set-of-transmog-to-an-outfit-slot-in-midnight-379350" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Wowhead</a>, players are discovering these supposedly cost-saving changes are actually extremely expensive.</p><p dir="ltr">At Midnight's level cap of 90, equipping a full transmog gear outfit costs around 5,700 gold, over four times more expensive than it is to equip that same set in the game right now. That means that unless a player changes their full set of gear five times, the current system is actually cheaper.</p><p dir="ltr">Transmog costs actually scale with level as well, so players will want to save their transmogs at lower levels to save on gold costs. It should be noted that players can save an appearance set for free just as they currently do, but actually equipping that set is where the gold costs comes in.</p><p dir="ltr">Outfit slots, a new feature in Midnight, also cost money. These are essentially saved transmog sets where players can go ahead and pay the transmog fee and then save that outfit for later use without having to pay the gold cost again. While players will be given two slots for free, additional slots (up to 20) cost increasingly more gold. The first few are hardly noticeable, with slot three costing 100 gold, slot four costing 500, and slot 5 costing 1,000. From there the gold costs begin to increase rapidly, with the last three slots costing 100,000 gold each.</p><p dir="ltr">Adding to the costs is the fact that outfits slots aren't account-wide and are instead on a per-character basis. For players who want multiple outfits on multiple characters, the gold costs begin to add up rather quickly, potentially costing millions of gold for those who want all 20 slots on multiple characters.</p><p dir="ltr">Outfit slots are mostly for players who want to be able to jump between transmog outfits frequently, and will work with the game's new "Situations" system. In this new system, players can change between their saved outfits automatically depending on the circumstances, and have a different appearance based on specific activities, like a cozy outfit when they are at their house or a different one when out in the open world or doing dungeons.</p><p dir="ltr">For those who change outfits often, the new system does technically save players gold. But for others who use transmog more casually, it could actually be more expensive. It's also a far more confusing system--one where players will now need to weigh the costs of buying new outfit slots and saving transmog sets versus overriding an existing set in an effort to save gold.</p><p dir="ltr">It's worth noting that all these prices are on the Midnight beta and will likely change before the expansion launches early next year, especially given the negative reception from players. But considering this feature was pitched as saving fashion-forward players money, as opposed to costing more, this feels like Blizzard took an easy win and instead turned it into a loss.</p><p dir="ltr">In other WoW news, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-player-housing-finally-arrives-december-2-after-decades-of-waiting/1100-6536160/" data-ref-id="1100-6536160">early access to the game's housing system</a> will arrive on December 2. Blizzard recently found itself in another controversy when it revealed a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/wow-new-premium-currency-is-player-friendly-and-more-efficient-blizzard-says/1100-6536042/" data-ref-id="1100-6536042">premium currency</a> that will be used just for housing items on WoW's in-game shop, despite other items like mounts and transmog sets having always been sold for real currency.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pricey-wow-transmog-changes-have-players-angry-and-confused/1100-6536391/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Back to the Future's Marty McFly And The DeLorean Are Seemingly Coming To Fortnite]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/back-to-the-futures-marty-mcfly-and-the-delorean-are-seemingly-coming-to-fortnite/1100-6536389/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/back-to-the-futures-marty-mcfly-and-the-delorean-are-seemingly-coming-to-fortnite.1359481/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536389">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It's looking more and more like characters from multiple movies will be featured in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-7-start-date-new-map-and-everything-we-know-so-far/1100-6536068/" data-ref-id="1100-6536068">Fortnite Chapter Seven</a> near the end of this month. Kill Bill's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kill-bills-the-bride-rides-into-fortnite-in-chapter-7-teaser/1100-6536383/" data-ref-id="1100-6536383">The Bride has already been confirmed</a>, and now it looks like Marty McFly from Back to the Future will arrive shortly thereafter. And it seems likely that Marty will be bringing Doc Brown's time-traveling DeLorean with him.</p><p>Leaks from a Fortnite Chapter Seven event appears to indicate that Marty will be a part of the Battle Pass with the Bride. The leak from Shiina doesn't specify if or how the DeLorean will be utilized, but Epic Games is already using the car in Rocket League.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/ShiinaBR/status/1991464160996344068" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">LEAKED CHAPTER 7 INFO FROM CREATOR EVENT 💀 <br>- Hot air balloons <br>- Driveable Reboot Vans<br>- Solo VS Bots mode <br>- Rift A Palooza events that spawn rifts<br>- Gameplay UI update<br>- Battle Pass has Marty McFly and The Bride <a href="https://t.co/l9lBrLZMIz" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/l9lBrLZMIz</a></p>  — Shiina (@ShiinaBR) <a href="https://twitter.com/ShiinaBR/status/1991464160996344068?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 20, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Some of the other rumored characters said to be heading to Chapter Seven include <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-dataminers-suggest-harry-potter-and-spongebob-collabs-could-be-next/1100-6535870/">Harry Potter</a> and <a href="https://x.com/HYPEX/status/1960756104935194890" rel="nofollow ">James Bond</a>. Other reports suggest that the next Fortnite map "will begin with a distinctive Los Angeles flavor and will have a desert biome." Since Epic is spelling out the word "seven" for this chapter, it's led to speculation that The Seven--a team of heroes who used to appear in Fortnite--may finally get their comeback.</p><p>The current Simpsons-themed mini-season is set to conclude on November 29. In the meantime, a giant--and shirtless-Homer Simpson <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/leaked-underwear-homer-would-be-first-fortnite-skin-with-nipples/1100-6536357/" data-ref-id="1100-6536357">is bringing his nipples to the game</a>. In the eight years since Fortnite was launched, no character has ever been shown with nipples until now.</p><p>Earlier this week, Epic CEO Tim Sweeney announced a collaboration <a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/news/unity-and-epic-games-together-advance-the-open-interoperable-future-for-video-gaming" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">with Unity</a>, which will eventually bring Unity games into Fortnite. Next year, Fortnite will also be able <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-can-start-hosting-standalone-games-next-year/1100-6536354/" data-ref-id="1100-6536354">to host standalone games</a>.</p><p>Fortnite was also recently added to the Xbox PC Store, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnites-xbox-pc-store-launch-is-going-very-badly/1100-6536332/" data-ref-id="1100-6536332">the launch didn't go very well</a> at all.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/back-to-the-futures-marty-mcfly-and-the-delorean-are-seemingly-coming-to-fortnite/1100-6536389/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PokePark Kanto's Big Adventure Comes With Big Restrictions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokepark-kantos-big-adventure-comes-with-big-restrictions/1100-6536388/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokepark-kantos-big-adventure-comes-with-big-restrictions.1359475/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536388">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>PokePark Kanto is a new, permanent Pokemon theme park opening in Japan next February. It is designed to make visitors feel like real Pokemon trainers as they explore a lively town area and a large forest inspired by the anime and video games. While many fans may be excited to catch 'em all, they may be surprised to learn that a major part of the park comes with strict entry rules.</p><p>The Pokemon Forest has many safety restrictions that limit who can enter. According to the park's <a href="https://www.pokepark-kanto.co.jp/ppark/ticketInfo/type/index#about-forest" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">English-language site</a>, visitors must be able to walk up 110 steps without help, as well as wheelchair users and children under five are not allowed in the Forest. People who are pregnant, have heart or blood pressure issues, have been drinking alcohol, or feel unwell on the day of their visit are also restricted from entering.</p><p>The park will be situated within Yomiuriland, Tokyo's largest theme park. PokePark Kanto is split into two main areas: the Pokemon Forest and Sedge Town. The Forest is a 500-meter nature trail filled with hills, tunnels, and stairs, where visitors can find statues of Pokemon in their natural habitats. Sedge Town offers shops, rides, and a gym where guests can watch <a href="https://www.pokepark-kanto.co.jp/ppark/event/4/detail/index" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">special Pokemon stage shows</a>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15976769/4607751-chrome-capture-2025-11-20.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4607751" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15976769/4607751-chrome-capture-2025-11-20.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4607751"></a><figcaption>Sedge Town illustration. Image credi: Pokemon Company</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1597/15976769/4607751-chrome-capture-2025-11-20.jpg"></figure><p>These rules may limit the enjoyment of certain areas of the park for some guests, especially since both ticket types include access to the Forest. The Ace Trainer's Pass (14,000 yen) allows free entry to both areas and offers extra perks like priority lines, reserved show seats, meet-and-greets, and special merchandise. The lower-priced Trainer's Pass (7,900 yen) includes unlimited entry to Sedge Town and a timed slot for the Forest. The park also forbids certain items, including drones, suitcases, and selfie sticks. Like most theme parks, it also bans most outside food and drink, with exceptions for infants and those with dietary restrictions.</p><p>The Sedge Town area will become more accessible as the park plans to introduce a Town-only pass by Summer 2026 to "ensure everyone can safely and comfortably enjoy the park." This new option will be the park's cheapest ticket, priced at 4,700 yen for adults, 4,200 yen for seniors, and 2,800 yen for children and guests with disabilities.</p><p>Residents of Japan can enter a ticket lottery by registering on the official PokePark KANTO website starting at 6 PM (JST) on November 21, 2025, which requires site membership and SMS verification using a Japan-capable mobile phone. The lottery covers tickets for the period of February 5 to March 31, 2026, with registration open from November 21 to December 8. Winners will be notified in the latter third of each month, and payments must be completed between December 21 and December 31. No information is yet available for fans outside of Japan about being able to come to the park.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokepark-kantos-big-adventure-comes-with-big-restrictions/1100-6536388/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>