<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:18:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty Was 2025's Top Franchise On Game Pass]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-was-2025s-top-franchise-on-game-pass/1100-6536860/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1379344</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536860">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It seems telling that Microsoft and Activision haven't been touting sales numbers for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-7/" data-ref-id="5000-681591">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7</a>, a sequel that hasn't been as well-received by players as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/" data-ref-id="5000-630093">Black Ops 6</a> was a year earlier. Regardless, Microsoft has announced that the Call of Duty franchise led the charge on Xbox Game Pass in 2025 in two key categories.</p><p>On social media, the official account for Xbox Game Pass noted that Call of Duty ranked first for total players and hours in 2025. Specific figures beyond that weren't included in the announcement.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://twitter.com/xboxgamepass/status/1998878735626567997?s=46" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">In addition to #1 in November, <a href="https://twitter.com/CallofDuty?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@CallofDuty</a> closed out 2025 as the #1 franchise on Xbox Game Pass for total players and hours all year 🫡<br>Here’s to <a href="https://twitter.com/CallofDuty?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@CallofDuty</a> &amp; its worldwide community. Season 1 of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackOps7?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BlackOps7</a> + Call of Duty: Warzone is just getting warmed up.</p>  — Xbox Game Pass (@XboxGamePass) <a href="https://twitter.com/XboxGamePass/status/1998878735626567997?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 10, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p>The timing is interesting because Activision released a statement of its own earlier this week which acknowledged that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-will-no-longer-do-back-to-back-black-ops-or-modern-warfare-games/1100-6536815/" data-ref-id="1100-6536815">Black Ops 7 fell short of the mark the publisher set for itself</a>. Furthermore, Activision pledged to refrain from any future CoD year-to-year releases that are direct sequels, as Black Ops 6 and 7 were.</p><p>"[We know] that for some of you, the franchise has not met your expectations fully," reads the statement. "To be very clear, we know what you expect and rest assured we will deliver, and overdeliver, on those expectations as we move forward ... We will no longer do back-to-back releases of Modern Warfare or Black Ops games. The reasons are many, but the main one is to ensure we provide an absolutely unique experience each and every year. We will drive innovation that is meaningful, not incremental. While we aren't sharing those plans today, we look forward to doing so when the time is right."</p><p>Despite the mixed message that comes from the close arrival of these statements, it's entirely plausible that Call of Duty was No. 1 on Game Pass despite under-performing in other metrics. At least <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-is-underperforming-in-2025-analyst-says-citing-burnout-creative-decisions-and-ai-slop/1100-6536669/" data-ref-id="1100-6536669">one video game analyst chastised Microsoft</a> for "dropping the ball" and blamed Black Ops 7's disappointing performance on burnout, poor creative decisions, and its use of AI slop.</p><p>The real question now is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-hasnt-been-outsold-by-another-shooter-in-the-us-since-2006/1100-6536492/" data-ref-id="1100-6536492">whether EA's Battlefield 6 will outperform</a> Black Ops 7 in sales. As of early November, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-reaches-10-million-copies-sold-but-wont-be-enough-to-topple-call-of-duty-analyst-says/1100-6535920/" data-ref-id="1100-6535920">Battlefield 6 sold 10 million copies</a> across all platforms. It remains to be seen if that will be enough to unseat Call of Duty as the top-selling franchise of the year. Call of Duty hasn't been beaten in that category by another shooter since 2006.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-was-2025s-top-franchise-on-game-pass/1100-6536860/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kim Kardashian Is Coming To Fortnite This Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kim-kardashian-is-coming-to-fortnite-this-week/1100-6536858/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1379341</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536858">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fortnite/" data-ref-id="5000-125765">Fortnite</a> has drawn upon some of the most iconic characters from the world of fiction, which <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-boss-reveals-how-zero-hour-event-brought-together-the-ultimate-crossover/1100-6536588/" data-ref-id="1100-6536588">recently led to a massive crossover</a>. Now, the game is apparently expanding its roster to reality TV stars, as Kim Kardashian is slated to make her Fortnite debut on December 13. The influencer, model, and part-time actress <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kim-kardashian-isnt-happy-with-how-microtransactio/1100-6440504/" data-ref-id="1100-6440504">has had her own hit mobile game</a>, but this is her first appearance in an existing game.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EE1t45vRyCs" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EE1t45vRyCs" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Kardashian's appearance in the game is also a collaboration with her clothing line SKIMS. So far, dataminers have determined that Kardashian will have at least three main skins, eight alternate outfits, and various hairstyles to choose from. Via <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/kim-kardashian-fortnite-skins-leaked-release-date-prices-and-all-cosmetics-revealed/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Vice</a>, the potential pricing for these items is reproduced below.</p><ul><li>Kim Kardashian (Fur Coat): 1,500 V-Bucks</li><li>Kim Kardashian (SKIMS Suit): 1,500 V-Bucks</li><li>Kim Kardashian (Leather Suit): 1,500 V-Bucks</li><li>Kim Kardashian Purse (Pickaxe): 800 V-Bucks</li><li>Emote (Paper Magazine Pose): 500 V-Bucks</li><li>Makeup Backpack (Back Bling): 400 V-Bucks</li><li>Ring Light and Phone (Back Bling): 400 V-Bucks</li><li>Jet (Glider): 1,200 V-Bucks</li></ul><p>The pricing for the Kim Kardashian bundle and its full contents have yet to be shared. Additionally, there will be a Kim Kardashian Pickaxe that players can purchase in the Fortnite store and wield in battle.</p><p>According to Epic Games, the launch of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-7-season-1-exotic-and-mythic-weapons-and-items-guide/1100-6536586/" data-ref-id="1100-6536586">Fortnite Chapter 7</a> led to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnites-chapter-7-launch-reportedly-propelled-the-game-to-3-million-concurrent-players/1100-6536598/" data-ref-id="1100-6536598">3 million concurrent players</a>. Meanwhile, Fortnite leakers are reporting that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-next-fortnite-collab-will-reportedly-feature-bleach-characters/1100-6536834/" data-ref-id="1100-6536834">characters from Bleach are coming in 2026</a>, and so is "Restarter Island," a new feature <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-leak-suggests-itll-get-call-of-duty-warzones-most-unique-feature/1100-6536606/" data-ref-id="1100-6536606">that resembles the Gulag</a> from the Call of Duty franchise. That will reportedly let eliminated players compete in a random 1v1 minigames, before letting the winner respawn in their battle royale match.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kim-kardashian-is-coming-to-fortnite-this-week/1100-6536858/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Legendary Dev's Long-Lost NES Game Is Getting Its First-Ever Release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/legendary-devs-long-lost-nes-game-is-getting-its-first-ever-release/1100-6536857/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1379338</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536857">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In 2012, programmer Chris Oberth passed away after a career that spanned from the dawn of video games in the late '70s to the PlayStation 2 era. Now, one of Oberth's unfinished games, Xcavator 2025, has been completed and it's slated for a physical release on the console it was originally intended for: the NES.</p><p>The Video Game History Foundation--with the permission and support of Oberth's family--found the source code for Xcavator 2025 in Oberth's development archives. It was originally developed by Incredible Technologies Inc., the company behind the Golden Tee Golf and Big Buck Hunter arcade games. However, it was rejected by publishers in 1991, and it was never seen again until now.</p><p>To finish the game, the VGHF teamed up with Mega Cat Studios, which was guided by the remaining materials to recapture the spirit of Oberth's original vision. Towards that end, Mega Cat Studios' development team only used the tools and environments that would have been available at the time. A standalone trailer for Xcavator 2025 isn't available yet, but the first footage was screened during the Day of the Devs: The Game Awards Edition at the 1 hour 43:31 mark below.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4nCX95t5cWY" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="6210">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4nCX95t5cWY?start=6210" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>The physical release of Xcavator 2025 on a working NES cartridge is being handled by iam8bit. Xcavator 2025 <a href="https://www.iam8bit.com/products/xcavator-2025" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">is available for preorder now</a>, and it's going for $100. This game will include an "authentically retro package," as well as a 14-page manual that includes background info on both Oberth and Xcavator 2025. All of the profits from this release will be donated to the Video Game History Foundation, which is an official non-profit organization dedicated to preserving gaming history.</p><p>This isn't the first time that the VGHF has resurrected one of Oberth's lost titles. In 2020, the organization released <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-lost-nes-game-based-on-a-tom-cruise-classic-has-/1100-6478023/" data-ref-id="1100-6478023">a restored version of Oberth's Days of Thunder NES game</a>, which was based on the 1990 feature film starring Tom Cruise. This was an alternate version that was separate from the Days of Thunder game that was released on the NES, PC, and Amiga. The limited run of Oberth's Days of Thunder sold out quickly, and we wouldn't be shocked if Xcavator 2025 has the same kind of success.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/legendary-devs-long-lost-nes-game-is-getting-its-first-ever-release/1100-6536857/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>