<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed - gamespot_com</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gamespot_com.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed for gamespot_com</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:41:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kirby Air Riders Won't Have DLC, Sakurai Confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kirby-air-riders-wont-have-dlc-sakurai-confirms/1100-6535652/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kirby-air-riders-wont-have-dlc-sakurai-confirms.1332835/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535652">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Through two separate Nintendo Direct presentations, producer Masahiro Sakurai has waxed informative about his team's next project, Kirby Air Riders, for a combined one hour and 49 minutes. During today's Direct, Sakurai confirmed that, when the game launches in November, what you see is what you get--there will be no downloadable content coming post-launch.</p><p dir="ltr">The announcement came toward the end of the presentation, just as Sakurai was getting ready to sign off. "Just so you know, we're not planning any DLC. Everything is here," Sakurai said. He then confirmed that there are no plans to continue the Kirby Air Riders format going forward, saying he's "not planning on making this an ongoing series."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4589678-kirby-air-riders.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4589678" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4589678-kirby-air-riders.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4589678"></a><figcaption>Kirby Air Riders</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4589678-kirby-air-riders.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">"I've thrown everything I have into this game from the start," Sakurai continued. "So, I hope you don't miss this opportunity."</p><p dir="ltr">The full Direct livestream showed that Kirby Air Riders players will not be lacking for content, however, as multiple new modes, characters, costumes, and more were presented throughout the hour-long broadcast. Among the announcements were a story mode called Road Trip, multiple new characters, and My Machine, where players can build and customize their own air riders to take into races.</p><p dir="ltr">The Direct also confirmed that multiple key features from the original Kirby Air Ride would return in Kirby Air Riders. All nine tracks from the original Kirby Air Ride will be included in this new game, bringing the total number of tracks to 18, while Top Ride--a mode where players race from a top-down perspective rather than the traditional on-track view--will also be included.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kirby-air-riders-nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide/1100-6534089/" data-ref-id="1100-6534089">Kirby Air Riders</a> is set to launch November 20 exclusively on Nintendo Switch 2.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kirby-air-riders-wont-have-dlc-sakurai-confirms/1100-6535652/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring For Switch 2 Delayed To 2026 Due To "Performance Adjustments"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-for-switch-2-delayed-to-2026-due-to-performance-adjustments/1100-6535648/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-for-switch-2-delayed-to-2026-due-to-performance-adjustments.1332748/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535648">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Elden Ring's Switch 2 port is not going to release on time. From Software and Bandai Namco have confirmed that the Elden Ring: Tarnished Edition for Nintendo's console has been pushed to 2026.</p><p>Development "continues wholeheartedly," the developer said in a statement. But a delay was necessary to give the team time for "performance adjustments."</p><p>Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-rings-switch-2-performance-isnt-that-great-reports-say/1100-6534171/" data-ref-id="1100-6534171">people who played Elden Ring on Switch 2 said it was in rough shape</a>, with the frame rate in particular getting called out for being poor. Bandai Namco <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-rings-switch-2-performance-isnt-that-great-reports-say/1100-6534171/" data-ref-id="1100-6534171">forbade media from showing footage of the game</a>, so we haven't actually seen it in action as of yet, however.</p><p>"We apologize to players looking forward to the game and thank you for your patience and support," the developer said about the delay.</p><p>The Tarnished Edition includes the base game and the Shadow of the Erdtree expansion. Author George R.R. Martin worked on Elden Ring's backstory and lore.</p><p>Elden Ring was the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/top-10-best-selling-games-of-2022-in-the-us/1100-6510556/">No. 2 best-selling game of 2022 in the US</a> and sold <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/fromsoftware/comments/1hew72p/elden_ring_has_sold_over_286_million_copies_as_of/#:~:text=Full_Data_6240-,Elden%20Ring%20has%20sold%20over%2028.6%20million%20copies%20as%20of,IP%20of%20modern%20console%20generation" rel="nofollow ">nearly 30 million copies as of the end of 2024</a> across Xbox, PlayStation, and PC. No sequel has been announced, but the standalone multiplayer spin-off, Elden Ring Nightreign, came out this past May. It's not confirmed for Switch 2, however.</p><p>Assuming it releases in 2026, Elden Ring will join From Software's The Duskbloods in launching for Switch 2 next year. That is a new action-RPG exclusive to Switch 2 developed by From Software and directed by Hidetaka Miyazaki.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-for-switch-2-delayed-to-2026-due-to-performance-adjustments/1100-6535648/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>