<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:54:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony in “early stages” of making a hand held PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/25/sony-in-early-stages-of-making-a-hand-held-ps5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-in-%E2%80%9Cearly-stages%E2%80%9D-of-making-a-hand-held-ps5.1044990/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/25/sony-in-early-stages-of-making-a-hand-held-ps5/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Bloomberg are reporting that Sony are in the early stages of developing a portable console that will play PlayStation 5 games without streaming. According to the report that was the original plan for the PlayStation Portal, making it a direct competitor to Valve’s SteamDeck, but it was shelved in favour of the streaming only device.</p>
<p>Sony have had some success with hand held devices in to the past but has never managed to compete with Nintendo’s hand held offerings. The big question here is does anyone want a PS5 Portable? It’s going to be expensive, no doubt there, and they would be going up against mobile phone gaming. Nintendo’s Switch is portable but I honestly can’t remember the last time I saw someone using one on the commute to work,&nbsp; it is a big bulky device and for short trips everyone seems quite happy with a round of two of Candy Crush.</p>


<p>The device is said to be years away from release but many factors are in play and it may never become a real product.</p>
<p>A hand held PS5 does seem to be a very niche product but that does appear to be something Sony want to pursue, the PlayStation Portal and the PS5 Pro being current examples of that strategy.</p>
<p>Sony recently announced that the PlayStation Portal will begin<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/20/the-playstation-portal-is-finally-getting-ps-plus-cloud-streaming/"> beta tests of streaming games from the PlayStation Plus catalogue</a>, rather from the users own PS5.</p>

<p>Sony’s last hand held device, the PS Vita, started strongly but support for it soon dropped off.&nbsp; Many of Sony’s key franchises had their own unique games on the console including Uncharted, Wipeout, Resistance Fall of Man, and Killzone, and while most of these were impressive the console also had some terrible exclusives, the PS Vita version of Call of Duty Black Ops was a universally derided. As the years rolled on many previously announced games such as Bioshock were quietly cancelled.</p>
<p>Would you buy a hand held PS5 and more importantly, how much are you willing to pay? Let us know in the comments.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-25/sony-working-on-new-handheld-console-for-ps5-games-to-rival-nintendo-s-switch?leadSource=reddit_wall&amp;embedded-checkout=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bloomberg (Paywall)</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed Dev Says Missable Content Is Core to What Makes RPGs Special]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/avowed-dev-says-missable-content-is-core-to-what-makes-rpgs-special/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-dev-says-missable-content-is-core-to-what-makes-rpgs-special.1044987/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/avowed-dev-says-missable-content-is-core-to-what-makes-rpgs-special/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>As we get closer to the release of Avowed, Obsidian Entertainment is sharing more tidbits about the game as well as what they think is core to the RPG genre. Speaking to Gamesradar, Obsidian's Region Director and Senior Area Designer Berto Ritger <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/rpg/avowed-dev-channels-baldurs-gate-3-by-admitting-that-the-core-of-rpgs-is-missable-content-that-most-players-might-not-ever-see/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a> that missable content is what makes them special, hinting that the same design guideline will apply to Avowed.</p>
<p><em>I think the core of RPGs that makes them special is missable content, to be honest, and it makes the experience feel so much more personal to how you play the game. If you talk to somebody like, 'Oh, I found this thing under the docks. There's this little secret under there on the eastern side of the docks that you can find. And you can also climb up to the top, and there's stuff up there.' But if you find that, and your friend doesn't, they found something else, and it creates a very interesting dialogue about the game.</em></p>
<p><em>We want to draw your attention to things that we want you to engage with. The lighthouse is very tall, and so everybody's going to see a big, tall thing and want to go climb. And so we want to support that as well. And you can do that, and you can jump off into the ocean if you like. And so we try to draw your attention that way.</em></p>
<p>During my recent <a href="https://wccftech.com/avowed-hands-on-preview-eora-from-a-whole-new-perspective/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hands-on preview</a>, I didn't exactly stumble upon lots of missable content. Then again, it was just the first area of the game, Dawnshore. That kind of stuff might be reserved for the latter areas. However, I did enjoy my time with Avowed:</p>
<p><em>Overall, this hands-on experience definitely left me hopeful and eager for the final version. It's unlikely to be a big success on the scale of Skyrim or Baldur's Gate 3, but it looks like another fun and engaging role-playing game from Obsidian that improves on their previous first-person title. All the worldbuilding work done for the Pillars of Eternity games will certainly pay off, too, both for returning fans of the isometric cRPGs who get to enter Eora from a wholly different perspective and for newcomers who will feel the depth and uniqueness of this fantasy setting.</em></p>
<p>The game launches on February 18, 2025 for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cities: Skylines 2 Console Delay Is Due To Hardware Limitations, Developer Says]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cities-skylines-2-console-delay-is-due-to-hardware-limitations/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cities-skylines-2-console-delay-is-due-to-hardware-limitations-developer-says.1044975/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/cities-skylines-2-console-delay-is-due-to-hardware-limitations/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>If you have been waiting to play Cities: Skylines 2 until it launches on console, you’re going to be waiting a bit longer. In an update <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/949230/view/4486243201365051600" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">released on Steam</a>, the game’s developer Colossal Order says that it still doesn’t have an update on a release date for the console version of the game on Xbox Series and PlayStation 5. </p>



<p>In its latest message to players, the developer says that while the game’s console release continues to be a “top priority”, its delay continues to be due to “hardware limitations” of the consoles themselves.</p>



<p>“Currently, we are experiencing both simulation issues (CPU) and graphics issues (GPU) which become noticeable when players take certain actions that cause frame rate drops or memory overload,” they said. “These issues are particularly challenging due to the hardware limitations of consoles.”</p>



<p>They then continued with an example of one issue consoles pose, saying, “When placing larger buildings that involve numerous entities, the system struggles to handle the data load. During the calculation process (e.g., checking if there’s enough space or if any entities overlap with existing assets), performance bottlenecks arise, resulting in these noticeable issues.”</p>



<p>The studio says they’ve gotten the game to a “playable state” by lowering the overall graphics quality “significantly”, but it brings it to a level of compromise that they “are not willing to make”.</p>



<p>“Once we get it to an acceptable level, further optimizations are needed for both simulation and memory usage before we are ready to share the console version,” they said. “Until they are resolved, we cannot provide a release estimate to avoid it being premature and potentially misleading. The console release remains a top priority for us, we have multiple solutions being explored with experts actively involved, and we’re working hard to bring you the console version of Cities: Skylines II.”</p>



<p>Cities: Skylines 2 was originally supposed to release on console alongside the game’s PC release over a year ago. Instead, it has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cities-skylines-2-console-release-delayed-pc-still-on-target/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">been met with multiple delays</a>.</p>



<p>When do you think we’ll see Cities: Skylines 2 released for console? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-sued-over-return-to-office-mandate/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft being sued over its recent return to office</a> mandate. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mass Effect trilogy director Casey Hudson’s Humanoid Origin to shut down]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/mass-effect-trilogy-director-casey-hudsons-humanoid-origin-to-shut-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mass-effect-trilogy-director-casey-hudson%E2%80%99s-humanoid-origin-to-shut-down.1044972/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/mass-effect-trilogy-director-casey-hudsons-humanoid-origin-to-shut-down<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>"An unexpected shortfall of funding left us unable to sustain operations."</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Humanoid Origin [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/humanoid-origin">Humanoid Origin</a>, the studio <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2021/06/casey-hudson-establishes-humanoid-studios">founded in June 2021</a> by <em><a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>s Effect</em> trilogy director Casey Hudson, which <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2022/03/casey-hudson-led-humanoid-studios-developing-aaa-multiplatform-character-driven-sci-fi-game">announced in March 2022</a> that it was working on a “multiplatform AAA game” focused on “character-driven narrative in an all-new science-fiction universe,” will shut down, the company said in a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/humanoid-origin_earlier-today-we-informed-our-staff-that-activity-7266889657370447874-9uwE/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">LinkedIn post</a>. <span id="more-929870"></span></p><p>“Earlier today, we informed our staff that Humanoid Origin will be shutting down,” the post reads. “Despite efforts to shield the studio from broader challenges in the industry, an unexpected shortfall of funding left us unable to sustain operations.</p><p>“We’re heartbroken that we will not be able to bring our new science-fiction universe to completion. Our main concern at this time however is for our team, and we are committed to supporting them in their transition to new employment.”</p><p>Humanoid Origin is based in Edmonton, Alberta, Canada, and aimed to become a company that would “unleash the creative freedom of developers.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't Let Your Weapons Decay If You Want To Survive Stalker 2]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-weapon-upgrade-attachment-repair-broken-1851707644</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dont-let-your-weapons-decay-if-you-want-to-survive-stalker-2.1044948/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-weapon-upgrade-attachment-repair-broken-1851707644<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It happens to the best of us: You’re delving into a dank, decrepit bunker in the post-apocalypse searching for rare loot, casually popping off shots at the various rat-like mutants scurrying through the dark when your weapon jams. In a moment of panic, you attempt to reload and clear the jam, but your weapon is so degraded it’s unusable. What now? In <em>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2</em>, these situations occur rapidly and frequently, making the series’ signature dangerous environment more harsh than ever. Thanks,realism. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195624" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: August 2023 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="279" data-playlist="195624,196395,196049" data-current="195624"><div><p>The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: August 2023 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21125.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>But if this kind of busy work has you down, fret not. This guide will cover best practices for maintaining your <em>Stalker 2</em> weapons through repairs, upgrades, and occasional upgrades.</p><h2 id="h176487"><a id="disrepair"></a>Finding Weapons In Disrepair Is Very Common</h2><figure id="" data-id="f0aa4339ccd118144aaeddad5478a50c" data-recommend-id="image://f0aa4339ccd118144aaeddad5478a50c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The weapon repair screen in Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl shows multiple options." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The weapon repair screen in Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl shows multiple options." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->GSC Game World  / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f0aa4339ccd118144aaeddad5478a50c" data-recommend-id="image://f0aa4339ccd118144aaeddad5478a50c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The weapon repair screen in Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl shows multiple options." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Whenever you defeat an enemy and loot them, it’s common to scoop up a poor-quality rifle or handgun. You’ll note the broken weapon icon, typically in yellow or red, in the corner of the weapon preview window. This icon indicates your weapon is in poor condition, and if you continue using it, it will break and become unusable.</p><p>However, you can repair just about any weapon in the game by visiting a local Technician. They’re found inside safe zones, the first being Lens at Zalissya. Be wary, though. Repairing a weapon is expensive, so you likely won’t be able to fix every gun you scoop up from bandits.</p><h2 id="h176488"><a id="attachment"></a>Weapon Attachments Make Existing Weapons Better</h2><p>At the start, you’ll rock a lot of stock equipment without attachments. Why? Because you can’t afford any early on. Attachments cost a lot of coupons, especially the high-end scopes and suppressors, which you’ll find most valuable in the Zone.</p><p>Sure, you can find the occasional weapon attachment out in the world or receive one as a reward for completing a side quest, but you’ll be running low-end rifles and shotguns to start.</p><p>Once you unlock weapon attachments, keep compatibility in mind. Just because you found a suppressor doesn’t mean it’ll work on every weapon in your arsenal. Some suppressors are only designed for pistols, for instance. </p><p>To equip an attachment from your inventory, hold down T on keyboard or Up on the controller d-pad to open the weapon attachments menu. Here, you can select which piece to equip.On PC, you can also the weapon in your inventory and select an attachment from the drop-down menu.</p><h2 id="h176489"><a id="upgrade"></a>Weapon Upgrades Are A Boon</h2><figure id="" data-id="b15f03c0f61d5436eb8588c7e5f06427" data-recommend-id="image://b15f03c0f61d5436eb8588c7e5f06427" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The weapon upgrade menu in Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl shows an AKM-74S being worked on." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The weapon upgrade menu in Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl shows an AKM-74S being worked on." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->GSC Game World / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b15f03c0f61d5436eb8588c7e5f06427" data-recommend-id="image://b15f03c0f61d5436eb8588c7e5f06427" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The weapon upgrade menu in Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl shows an AKM-74S being worked on." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Now that you have a fully repaired weapon with attachments equipped, it’s time to upgrade it to increase its stats. You’ll need to visit the Technician again for this.As with repairs, don’t expect anything free or cheap. You’ll spend a lot of coupons upgrading your weapons in <em>Stalker 2</em>, but it’s worthwhile.</p><p>Depending on the weapon, you can upgrade various components, including the barrel, magazine, forward grip, stock, upper receiver, lower receiver, and more. Depending on how much you’re willing to spend and the upgrade path you’d like to take, you can focus on increasing aiming speed, reducing spread, or bolstering penetration capabilities. In time, you’ll have a small arsenal of fully upgraded weapons that will take down a Burer or Controller! And depending on your feelings about four-legged friends, you might want to pack a few extra upgraded weapon to deal with the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-blind-dogs-kill-pet-review-warning-xbox-pc-1851705457&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/stalker-2-blind-dogs-kill-pet-review-warning-xbox-pc-1851705457">copious amounts of wild dogs</a></span> in <em>Stalker 2</em>’s beginning sections!</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Removing Avatars Because You All Forgot About Them]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-avatars-editor-app-delist-series-x-s-removed-360-1851707586</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-removing-avatars-because-you-all-forgot-about-them.1044945/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/xbox-avatars-editor-app-delist-series-x-s-removed-360-1851707586<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="efc2a7024bc78f4082d656d41ee87ae9" data-recommend-id="image://efc2a7024bc78f4082d656d41ee87ae9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Xbox avatars. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows Xbox avatars. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Xbox / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="efc2a7024bc78f4082d656d41ee87ae9" data-recommend-id="image://efc2a7024bc78f4082d656d41ee87ae9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Xbox avatars. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Microsoft has quietly confirmed that it is ditching avatars on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/goodbye-to-the-xbox-one-the-most-pointless-console-i-h-1845692715&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/goodbye-to-the-xbox-one-the-most-pointless-console-i-h-1845692715">Xbox One</a></span> and Xbox Series X/S consoles next year after a decade of support. You might have assumed avatars had already been killed off in the past, but nope. Apparently they were still around, but not for much longer. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196181" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="196181,196230,196406" data-current="196181"><div><p>The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21718.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20080726074506/http://www.gamasutra.com/php-bin/news_index.php?story=19519&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20080726074506/http://www.gamasutra.com/php-bin/news_index.php?story=19519" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xbox avatars were introduced back in the Xbox 360 era</a></span> during <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nxe-impressions-creating-an-avatar-playing-with-my-xb-5070578&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nxe-impressions-creating-an-avatar-playing-with-my-xb-5070578">a major update that landed in 2008</a></span>. And for a few years, Microsoft really pushed these digital avatars, letting you buy them clothes and use them in games and apps, as well as making them a prominent feature on the console’s dashboard. But by the time the Xbox One arrived in 2013, avatars were already being pushed aside and in recent years (and after numerous Xbox updates), avatars are hard to find, barely have a presence on the dashboard, and feel like a relic of a different era. And starting next year, they will be removed entirely. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-avatars-are-going-away-next-year-but-dont-worry-your-360-avatar-is-safe/1100-6528032/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-avatars-are-going-away-next-year-but-dont-worry-your-360-avatar-is-safe/1100-6528032/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As spotted by <em>GameSpot</em></a></span>, Microsoft updated its <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/account-profile/profile/xbox-avatar-editor-app-faq&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://support.xbox.com/en-US/help/account-profile/profile/xbox-avatar-editor-app-faq" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">support page for Xbox avatars</a></span> and confirmed that on January 9, 2025, they will be removed from Xbox One and Xbox Series X/S consoles. You will no longer see avatars on profile pages after this date. </p><p>Microsoft says that “due to low engagement,” the avatars are being removed, and the Xbox Avatar Editor app is going with them. So if you want to have your avatar as your profile pic, you have until January to do that. </p><p>Any players who purchased items for their Xbox Avatar on Xbox One or Series X/S since November 1, 2023 will have those purchases refunded. </p><p>Microsoft clarified that this change won’t affect Xbox 360 avatars, which are officially known as “Xbox Original Avatars.”  Those will continue to live on for the time being in games and apps that support them.</p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[15 Things We Noticed In The New Sonic The Hedgehog 3 Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-trailer-shadow-gun-rouge-eggman-gerald-moon-1851707554</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/15-things-we-noticed-in-the-new-sonic-the-hedgehog-3-trailer.1044942/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-trailer-shadow-gun-rouge-eggman-gerald-moon-1851707554<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="a415ecc2e06e2581e2f59f425c439ed8" data-recommend-id="image://a415ecc2e06e2581e2f59f425c439ed8" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow holds a gun while sitting on a motorcycle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Shadow holds a gun while sitting on a motorcycle." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a415ecc2e06e2581e2f59f425c439ed8" data-recommend-id="image://a415ecc2e06e2581e2f59f425c439ed8" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow holds a gun while sitting on a motorcycle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 </em>got a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-second-trailer-shadow-hedgehog-keanu-reeves-1851706485&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-second-trailer-shadow-hedgehog-keanu-reeves-1851706485">new trailer this morning</a></span>, and it really underlines how this movie is an adaptation of <em>Sonic Adventure 2</em>. We knew it would be taking pieces of the Dreamcast game, such as introducing Shadow the Hedgehog and delving into his tortured past, but this new trailer really brings home that some of the biggest story beats from <em>Sonic Adventure 2 </em>are making their way to the big screen. If you’ve never played the game or need a refresher, we’re here to break down the trailer scene by scene.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="a1cd41e6df868e346d783a8867e266ac" data-recommend-id="image://a1cd41e6df868e346d783a8867e266ac" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic, Tails, and Knuckles are shown in a children's establishment called Chao Garden with several Chao mascots." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Sonic, Tails, and Knuckles are shown in a children's establishment called Chao Garden with several Chao mascots." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a1cd41e6df868e346d783a8867e266ac" data-recommend-id="image://a1cd41e6df868e346d783a8867e266ac" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic, Tails, and Knuckles are shown in a children's establishment called Chao Garden with several Chao mascots." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Chao are little alien-like creatures in the <em>Sonic </em>universe, looked after by the blue blur and his friends. These guys debuted in <em>Sonic Adventure </em>and have been a mainstay in the franchise since, but they’ve never appeared in the movies, until now…sort of. It looks like Chao will debut in the live-action films as mascots—in the trailer we see Sonic, Tails, and Knuckles hanging out in a Chuck E. Cheese-like establishment in Tokyo, where performers and servers are dressed as the little guys. The place is then shown being attacked by what we assume are Doctor Robotnik’s machines. Between this and the fact that Sega <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/sonic-boss-suggests-it-wont-make-a-standalone-chao-garden-game/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/sonic-boss-suggests-it-wont-make-a-standalone-chao-garden-game/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">refuses to make a standalone Chao Garden game</a></span>, Chao can’t catch a break.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="f7d812220e5a5ed7ec08c0fcf7561391" data-recommend-id="image://f7d812220e5a5ed7ec08c0fcf7561391" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A child asks Tails if he is Detective Pikachu and Knuckles mocks him." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A child asks Tails if he is Detective Pikachu and Knuckles mocks him." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f7d812220e5a5ed7ec08c0fcf7561391" data-recommend-id="image://f7d812220e5a5ed7ec08c0fcf7561391" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A child asks Tails if he is Detective Pikachu and Knuckles mocks him." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Regrettably, the <em>Sonic </em>movies love a pop culture reference. So when three anthropomorphic animals show up in Tokyo, a child is shown asking if Tails is <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/detective-pikachu-returns-pokemon-review-switch-1850915720&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/detective-pikachu-returns-pokemon-review-switch-1850915720">Detective Pikachu</a></span>. Knuckles responds, “He does look like a Pokémon,” before imitating the little yellow guy with a “Pika, Pika!”</p><p>If you ever wanted to hear Idris Elba do that, I guess that’s for you.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="e9dc7bf8d3f34b6a3011bc4acec20b31" data-recommend-id="image://e9dc7bf8d3f34b6a3011bc4acec20b31" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Gerald is shown looking at schematics for the Eclipse Cannon as Shadow powers up." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Gerald is shown looking at schematics for the Eclipse Cannon as Shadow powers up." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e9dc7bf8d3f34b6a3011bc4acec20b31" data-recommend-id="image://e9dc7bf8d3f34b6a3011bc4acec20b31" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Gerald is shown looking at schematics for the Eclipse Cannon as Shadow powers up." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Gerald Robotnik, the grandfather of series antagonist Eggman, is a bit of a wildcard in <em>Sonic 3</em>—he was long dead by the time <em>Sonic Adventure 2 </em>begins. In <em>Sonic 3</em>, Gerald is still alive, apparently working with his grandson and Shadow toward world domination. There’s some inherent deception in Gerald and Shadow’s plans in the game, so things might not be all that they seem.</p><p>We see Gerald in what appears to be a jail cell, looking at schematics of the Eclipse Cannon drawn on a wall. This is a superweapon attached to the Space Colony Ark, the space station he and Shadow lived on at some time before the events of <em>Sonic Adventure 2</em>.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="f47567d096bef4e38eb57fc95019ce36" data-recommend-id="image://f47567d096bef4e38eb57fc95019ce36" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Both Robotniks are shown walking up to Sonic and friends who are tied to a pole." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Both Robotniks are shown walking up to Sonic and friends who are tied to a pole." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f47567d096bef4e38eb57fc95019ce36" data-recommend-id="image://f47567d096bef4e38eb57fc95019ce36" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Both Robotniks are shown walking up to Sonic and friends who are tied to a pole." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>In the first trailer for <em>Sonic the Hedgehog 3</em>, Jim Carrey’s Doctor Robotnik was shown teaming up with Sonic to take down Shadow, as he and his friends deemed the antihero too powerful for them to take on by themselves. However, the second trailer has dropped this facade, and it looks like the villain will be teaming up with his grandfather and Shadow. I’m less surprised by the turn than I am by Paramount marketing one thing and then undermining it one trailer later.</p><p>Ultimately, it leads to a more true adaptation of <em>Sonic Adventure 2</em>, but I was interested in seeing the begrudging team-up lasts the whole film, instead of just part of it. </p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="ab5246ba1adf0a540b437d46578d1c09" data-recommend-id="image://ab5246ba1adf0a540b437d46578d1c09" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic and friends appear in Tom and Maddie's living room." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Sonic and friends appear in Tom and Maddie's living room." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ab5246ba1adf0a540b437d46578d1c09" data-recommend-id="image://ab5246ba1adf0a540b437d46578d1c09" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic and friends appear in Tom and Maddie's living room." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Tom and Maddie Wachowski are both returning as Sonic’s human parents, and while the last trailer showed Tom <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-shadow-gerald-trailer-explained-1851632861&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-shadow-gerald-trailer-explained-1851632861">in what looked like a real dangerous situation</a></span>, we do see the two relaxing in their Green Hills home. Well, before Sonic and the others teleport into their living room and tell them they need help fighting Shadow and the Robotniks. Tom is also seen wearing a knitted Donut Lord sweater covered in donuts. These movies sure do commit to a bit.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="bd3956ddb019a113a9045491fcc907b0" data-recommend-id="image://bd3956ddb019a113a9045491fcc907b0" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The human cast of Sonic the Hedgehog 3 is shown in G.U.N. uniforms." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The human cast of Sonic the Hedgehog 3 is shown in G.U.N. uniforms." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bd3956ddb019a113a9045491fcc907b0" data-recommend-id="image://bd3956ddb019a113a9045491fcc907b0" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The human cast of Sonic the Hedgehog 3 is shown in G.U.N. uniforms." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Sonic the Hedgehog 2 </em>introduced G.U.N., the Guardian Units of Nations military group that was founded to protect Earth from aliens like Sonic and his friends. The organization was revealed through an extended wedding subplot revealing Maddie’s sister Rachel was unknowingly getting married to an undercover agent. While she wasn’t thrilled, it seems like she and the rest of the human cast are shown working with G.U.N. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="2410a8bc1e2d13ee56147f6b83230b72" data-recommend-id="image://2410a8bc1e2d13ee56147f6b83230b72" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Robotnik rises through the floor next to Shadow, Gerald, a conspicuous space, and Agent Stone." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Robotnik rises through the floor next to Shadow, Gerald, a conspicuous space, and Agent Stone." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2410a8bc1e2d13ee56147f6b83230b72" data-recommend-id="image://2410a8bc1e2d13ee56147f6b83230b72" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Robotnik rises through the floor next to Shadow, Gerald, a conspicuous space, and Agent Stone." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Next we see shots of both Sonic and Robotnik’s teams, but there’s something a little fishy about one of them. While Sonic, Knuckles, and jetpack-wearing Tails all look fine running through the forests of Green Hill, it’s the line-up of both Robotniks, Shadow, and Agent Stone that’s odd. There’s a noticeable gap between Stone and Robotnik that looks strange from a shot composition standpoint. If <em>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 </em>is an adaptation of <em>Sonic Adventure 2</em>, there’s one major player who appears absent from the film: Rouge the Bat.</p><p>The treasure-hunting double-agent acts as Knuckles’ rival in the Dreamcast game, and it’s a bummer that she doesn’t appear to be in the movie that adapts her debut alongside Shadow. Unless this is a <em>Spider-Man: No Way Home </em>situation in which she, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-post-credits-scene-amy-rouge-metal-chaos-silver-1851698899&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-post-credits-scene-amy-rouge-metal-chaos-silver-1851698899">or some other <em>Sonic </em>character</a></span>, is meant to be standing in that empty space but has been edited out to surprise fans when the movie premieres. There’s also a possibility this <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-trailer-robotnik-metal-quill-theory-ending-1851634404&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-3-trailer-robotnik-metal-quill-theory-ending-1851634404">could be Metal Sonic</a></span>, as fans have been theorizing since the first trailer that the synthetic hedgehog could be making his debut in either this film or the next one.</p><p>If Robotnik is turning coat in this movie, it would make some sense for him to build the robohog. But I worry the film could feel pretty bloated if Paramount smooshed another <em>Sonic </em>storyline into an <em>Adventure 2 </em>adaptation, and we already have one villainous hedgehog. God, let it be Rouge.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="8cc7de88b565b3d40865e2747e74e874" data-recommend-id="image://8cc7de88b565b3d40865e2747e74e874" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow powers up the Eclipse Cannon." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Shadow powers up the Eclipse Cannon." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8cc7de88b565b3d40865e2747e74e874" data-recommend-id="image://8cc7de88b565b3d40865e2747e74e874" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow powers up the Eclipse Cannon." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>One of the big plot points of <em>Sonic Adventure 2 </em>is that the Chaos Emeralds, gems of near-limitless energy, were used to power the Eclipse Cannon. From what we can see in the trailer, it looks like Shadow himself is the weapon’s energy source this time around. The Chaos Emeralds were used in the second movie, but haven’t been shown in the trailers for <em>Sonic the Hedgehog 3</em> yet. So this might be one of the embellishments the movie is taking with the source material, although there is reason to believe the Chaos Emeralds will appear elsewhere in the movie. We’ll get to that in a minute.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="31fb6ca9906789ea27946e66a9945ca9" data-recommend-id="image://31fb6ca9906789ea27946e66a9945ca9" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Both Robotniks talk as Shadow runs behind them." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Both Robotniks talk as Shadow runs behind them." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="31fb6ca9906789ea27946e66a9945ca9" data-recommend-id="image://31fb6ca9906789ea27946e66a9945ca9" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Both Robotniks talk as Shadow runs behind them." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Carrey’s portrayal of the Egghead has been getting progressively closer to his in-game design with each movie. While he’s had the black-and-red throughline in each of his outfits, he got the bald head and long mustache in <em>Sonic 2</em>, and this time around he’s got the gut and the long red coat. He still keeps his goggles on his forehead, because you don’t pay Jim Carrey millions of dollars to hide his face, but his transformation into the Doctor Eggman we know looks pretty much complete now.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="740a2cd20e489d252ac5bd4cc11df372" data-recommend-id="image://740a2cd20e489d252ac5bd4cc11df372" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The Eclipse Cannon is shown being fired through the moon." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Eclipse Cannon is shown being fired through the moon." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="740a2cd20e489d252ac5bd4cc11df372" data-recommend-id="image://740a2cd20e489d252ac5bd4cc11df372" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The Eclipse Cannon is shown being fired through the moon." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>One of Eggman and Shadow’s power plays in <em>Sonic Adventure 2 </em>is demonstrating the Eclipse Cannon’s capabilities by blowing a hole through the moon. This plot beat has become kind of a meme at this point, as most <em>Sonic </em>games that follow don’t reflect it. Sega tried to explain this as the moon having turned, so every time we see it in subsequent games we’re just seeing the side that isn’t broken. [The moon is in a synchronous rotation orbit with the Earth, and as such never turns from our perspective—<em>Nerdy Ed</em>] But more recently, the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-x-shadow-generations-dark-beginnings-anime-expo-1851580851&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-x-shadow-generations-dark-beginnings-anime-expo-1851580851"><em>Shadow Generations: Dark Beginnings </em>animated series</a></span> has shown the moon broken with a ring of shattered pieces around the remaining satellite. In <em>Sonic the Hedgehog 3</em>, it looks like they’re slicing off part of the moon’s lower hemisphere, to which Sonic responds, “Somebody better call Google Maps.” Groan.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="2b63cbab3edf554b935df369d3005897" data-recommend-id="image://2b63cbab3edf554b935df369d3005897" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow and Maria are shown sitting together in a field of flowers, then looking at each other through a test tube, then Shadow looks at the same test tube now shattered." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Shadow and Maria are shown sitting together in a field of flowers, then looking at each other through a test tube, then Shadow looks at the same test tube now shattered." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2b63cbab3edf554b935df369d3005897" data-recommend-id="image://2b63cbab3edf554b935df369d3005897" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow and Maria are shown sitting together in a field of flowers, then looking at each other through a test tube, then Shadow looks at the same test tube now shattered." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Shadow’s tragic backstory <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-movie-shadow-maria-death-actor-1851227374&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-movie-shadow-maria-death-actor-1851227374">centers around his friendship with Maria Robotnik</a></span>, Eggman’s terminally ill cousin who he was meant to save as a research subject on immortality. We see a couple of scenes of Shadow reflecting on their friendship, including what looks like a dream sequence in which the two imagined living on Earth. They lived on Space Colony Ark most of Maria’s life, but we see a shot here of the two sitting together in a field of flowers.</p><p>Maria wanted nothing more than to be able to live on Earth again, and she and Shadow would dream of going down there until her untimely death acted as the catalyst for the events of <em>Sonic Adventure 2</em>. It’s still unclear just how <em>Sonic 3 </em>will portray her death, but the trailers aren’t subtle about her demise. </p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="a415ecc2e06e2581e2f59f425c439ed8" data-recommend-id="image://a415ecc2e06e2581e2f59f425c439ed8" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow holds a gun while sitting on a motorcycle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Shadow holds a gun while sitting on a motorcycle." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a415ecc2e06e2581e2f59f425c439ed8" data-recommend-id="image://a415ecc2e06e2581e2f59f425c439ed8" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shadow holds a gun while sitting on a motorcycle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Shadow’s brief affair with firearms in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/shadow-the-hedgehog-game-gamecube-ps2-xbox-2005-year-of-1851700937&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/shadow-the-hedgehog-game-gamecube-ps2-xbox-2005-year-of-1851700937">his 2005 self-titled game</a></span> is one of the more regrettable things Sega has done with the character, but I will not deny that I popped off when the new trailer showed him on a motorcycle, holding a pistol. It’s so stupid, but these movies are the only thing that gets me near an MCU level of “I understood that reference” sheepdom. I have to clap and cheer.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="efef10791c07915dc699dd1875009d56" data-recommend-id="image://efef10791c07915dc699dd1875009d56" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Agent Stone looks up at something off-screen while shown in tattered clothing." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Agent Stone looks up at something off-screen while shown in tattered clothing." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="efef10791c07915dc699dd1875009d56" data-recommend-id="image://efef10791c07915dc699dd1875009d56" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Agent Stone looks up at something off-screen while shown in tattered clothing." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Lee Majdoub’s Agent Stone is probably one of the only universally liked human characters in the <em>Sonic </em>movies, unless you count Carrey’s Robotnik. He’s mostly characterized by his homoerotic devotion to Robotnik, but the glimpses we’ve seen of him in this trailer imply he might not be able to follow the ol’ Egghead to the places this story is taking him. He remarks about how dark the plans are getting, and we even see him roughed up alongside civilians as he looks on at the carnage Shadow and Eggman are causing. Could he break out of this toxic relationship in this movie? </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="a78ab9269b4364e2c084c1c46247e8f3" data-recommend-id="image://a78ab9269b4364e2c084c1c46247e8f3" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic and Shadow fight as a volcano erupts around them." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Sonic and Shadow fight as a volcano erupts around them." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a78ab9269b4364e2c084c1c46247e8f3" data-recommend-id="image://a78ab9269b4364e2c084c1c46247e8f3" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sonic and Shadow fight as a volcano erupts around them." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The final important shots of the trailer show Sonic and Shadow locked in a fierce fight. It seems like they’re fighting at a volcanic eruption site. There are two important shots that fans think might imply something big for the climactic fight: At one point, we get a close-up on Sonic’s eyes, which, if you look closely, reflect multi-colored light that could be the Chaos Emeralds. There’s another shot where you can briefly see what looks like a golden streak of energy dashing past the volcanic eruptions.</p><p>Fans think this might mean Sonic and Shadow may use the Chaos Emeralds to change into their Super forms. In the <em>Sonic Adventure 2</em> game, Sonic and Shadow change into their Super Saiyan-like forms to team up and reverse Gerald’s plan to destroy the world, but it would be a twist if we got two superpowered hedgehogs facing each other in the final moments. Along with the conspicuous space in the Team Dark line-up, it does imply the movie may still have surprises in store when <em>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 </em>premieres on December 20.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="79574862f6e0ec658dd15f16086c266a" data-recommend-id="image://79574862f6e0ec658dd15f16086c266a" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Eggman sees Gerald dressed as Santa and tackles him in a hug." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Eggman sees Gerald dressed as Santa and tackles him in a hug." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Paramount / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="79574862f6e0ec658dd15f16086c266a" data-recommend-id="image://79574862f6e0ec658dd15f16086c266a" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Eggman sees Gerald dressed as Santa and tackles him in a hug." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The final scene in the trailer is a gag between both Robotniks, with Gerald shown dressed up as Santa Claus as his grandson excitedly tackles him into a Christmas tree. It’s unclear if this is a real scene in the movie, or just a little something Paramount paid Carrey to do because the movie is coming out so close to Christmas. Maybe Eggman is thinking of all the childhood family time he missed out on that made him the way he is. Or maybe <em>Sonic 3</em> has a Christmas subplot.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Game Awards Lets You Vote Inside Fortnite With A Virtual Geoff Keighley]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-game-awards-lets-you-vote-inside-fortnite-with-a-virtual-geoff-keighley/1100-6528036/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-game-awards-lets-you-vote-inside-fortnite-with-a-virtual-geoff-keighley.1044927/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-game-awards-lets-you-vote-inside-fortnite-with-a-virtual-geoff-keighley/1100-6528036/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528036">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The Game Awards, coming up this December 12, will honor 2024's best games, and Fortnite players will be able to vote on one category from within the game.</p><p>Studio 568 created a dedicated Fortnite island for event, and it's here where players can vote for the Best Fortnite Island of 2024. Additionally, host Geoff Keighley will show up in the game through a virtual avatar created by Epic's MetaHuman technology. Keighley flew to England to have himself scanned to create his digital likeness, and as you can see in the video below, it's pretty impressive.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u3JnlvOR5Xc" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/u3JnlvOR5Xc" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">The Game Awards Vote in Fortnite, as it's called, is a Fortnite hub world where players van visit the 10 creator-made islands that are in the running for Best Fortnite Island of 2024. Fans can vote on their favorite, and the winner will be announced during The Game Awards on December 12.</p><p dir="ltr">Voting is active until December 11 at 6 PM PT / 9 PM ET.</p><p dir="ltr">There is also a dedicated The Game Awards Fortnite map where players can try their aim in a target-shooting arena. Players unlock more powerful weapons each round, and there are round- and session-based leaderboards. You can visit the island by using this code: 0853-1358-8532.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4405225-geoff.gif" data-ref-id="1300-4405225" data-ratio="0.56273764258555" data-width="789" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4405225-geoff.gif" data-ref-id="1300-4405225"></a></figure><p dir="ltr">Keighley <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/news/2024-best-fortnite-island-the-game-awards" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">said</a> the voting event inside Fortnite is "just a prototype" for where The Game Awards will go in the next decade as it relates to pushing boundaries. "Imagine a day when we can announce a new game, and then the screen opens and you can actually jump <em>into </em>that game to play a quick demo!" he said.</p><p dir="ltr">The top category at The Game Awards, Game of the Year, has six nominees this year: Astro Bot, Balatro, Black Myth: Wukong, Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree, Final Fantasy VII: Rebirth, and Metaphor: ReFantazio. You can see all the categories and nominees below.</p><p dir="ltr">In addition to the awards being handed out, The Game Awards will have new game announcements and updates on existing games. Check back with GameSpot for all the news as it's announced.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Pauses Certain Players' Windows Updates Over Ubisoft-Game Stability Issues]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-pauses-certain-players-windows-updates-over-ubisoft-game-stability-issues/1100-6528037/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-pauses-certain-players-windows-updates-over-ubisoft-game-stability-issues.1044924/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-pauses-certain-players-windows-updates-over-ubisoft-game-stability-issues/1100-6528037/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528037">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>After multiple reports of compatibility issues, Microsoft has stopped automatically pushing Windows updates to PCs that have a variety of Ubisoft games installed, including Star Wars Outlaws, Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora, and Assassin's Creed Valhalla.</p><p>The Windows 11 24H2 update has been in testing for most of 2024 and started rolling out to most users last month. Those who have updated and enjoyed some games from Ubisoft have reported instabilities with many titles, including startup issues and frequent crashes. Microsoft has become aware of the issues and is investigating, pausing automatic updates on Windows machines that have various Ubisoft titles installed. The company also recommends that players don't manually update until a fix has been found.</p><p>According to a post on <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/release-health/status-windows-11-24h2#3448msgdesc" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Microsoft's known issues for 24H2</a>, it lists the following Ubisoft titles as having potential issues with the Windows update:</p><ul><li>Assassin's Creed Valhalla</li><li>Assassin's Creed Origins</li><li>Assassin's Creed Odyssey</li><li>Star Wars Outlaws</li><li>Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</li></ul><p>Ubisoft has started trying to fix things on its end, with the <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/star-wars/outlaws/news-updates/1sXCR6GmB3Kn7OrKiy8DPO/star-wars-outlaws-title-update-140" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">latest patch for Star Wars Outlaws</a> providing a workaround if you have already updated to 24H2. The patch notes do say, however, that this fix isn't optimized and could still exhibit performance and stability issues until a permanent solution is found.</p><p>The best solution then is to avoid the 24H2 update entirely if you can, which should be easy enough now that Microsoft has taken action to prevent accidental automatic updates. You can roll back your Windows version via a new installation if you're stuck with the update and are struggling with some of the games listed above, as a fix from Microsoft or Ubisoft doesn't seem to be imminent.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cities: Skylines 2 studio blames ongoing console delay on "hardware limitations"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-studio-blames-ongoing-console-delay-on-hardware-limitations</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cities-skylines-2-studio-blames-ongoing-console-delay-on-hardware-limitations.1044918/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-studio-blames-ongoing-console-delay-on-hardware-limitations<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>But release remains "top priority".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/cities-skylines-2-screen-crop.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Colossal Order/Paradox Interactive</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/cities-skylines">Cities: Skylines</a> 2 developer Colossal Order has admitted it's still no closer to announcing a console release date for the beleaguered city builder sequel, having run into what it calls "hardware limitations" impacting performance on Xbox Series X/S and PlayStation 5.
</p>
<p>
Cities: Skylines 2 was originally due to launch for Xbox and PlayStation 5 alongside the PC release last October, but Colossal Order and Paradox announced a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-console-release-gets-delayed">last-minute delay</a>, pushing it into 2024 to give it "more time to reach the quality targets we have set". However, following the game's disastrous launch on PC - plagued by complaints of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-fans-complain-of-performance-woes-after-developer-admits-it-missed-target">poor performance</a> and simulation issues - Paradox opted to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-console-launch-delayed-again">delay its console release indefinitely</a>.
</p>
<p>
Since then, we've not heard much about the game's progress on Xbox and PlayStation, but Colossal Order has now shared on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/949230/view/4486243201365051600">update on Steam</a>, detailing some of the challenges it's facing bringing Cities: Skylines 2 to consoles. "Currently, we are experiencing both simulation issues (CPU) and graphics issues (GPU) which become noticeable when players take certain actions that cause frame rate drops or memory overload," it explained. "These issues are particularly challenging due to the hardware limitations of consoles."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Coming October 24th, 2023 I Pre-Order Now I Cities: Skylines II Official Gameplay Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MX9YWu5wkGg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Coming October 24th, 2023 I Pre-Order Now I Cities: Skylines II Official Gameplay Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MX9YWu5wkGg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/MX9YWu5wkGg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Cities: Skylines 2 gameplay trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MX9YWu5wkGg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"For instance," it continued, "when placing larger buildings that involve numerous entities, the system struggles to handle the data load. During the calculation process (e.g., checking if there’s enough space or if any entities overlap with existing assets), performance bottlenecks arise, resulting in these noticeable issues."
</p><p>
Colossal Order says it's managed to get the game in a "stable and playable state" on consoles by "significantly lowering the graphics quality", but  adds the compromise pushes things to a level it's "not willing to make." As such, its first task is to get the graphics quality to an "acceptable level", after which, "further optimisations are needed for both simulation and memory usage before we are ready to share the console version."
</p>
<p>
As to what all this means for Cities: Skylines 2's console launch date, it remains indefinitely delayed. "Until [these issues] are resolved," Colossal Order concluded, "we cannot provide a release estimate to avoid it being premature and potentially misleading. The console release remains a top priority for us, we have multiple solutions being explored with experts actively involved, and we're working hard to bring you the console version of Cities: Skylines 2."
</p>
<p>
Given the string of apologies Paradox has been forced to make following Cities: Skylines 2's release (in April it said "sorry" again after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-publisher-refunds-dlc-and-admits-we-let-you-down">releasing heavily criticised DLC</a>) getting the console version into an "acceptable state" is certainly the right move. But seeing as the company <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-performance-has-not-achieved-the-benchmark-we-targeted-paradox-admits-ahead-of-launch">acknowledged</a> the PC release had "not achieved the benchmark we targeted" <em>before</em> launch and still pushed it out, console players would probably be wise to be wary.
</p>
<p>
Colossal Order's console update comes ahead of a PC patch tomorrow, 26th November, promising "gameplay fixes, UI improvements, and more". It's also releasing the next of its free community created region packs - this one focusing on the United Kingdom - today.
</p><p>
Speaking to Eurogamer about Paradox's troubles earlier this year - which have included delays for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/prison-architect-2-indefinitely-delayed-by-paradox">Prison Architect 2</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2">Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2</a>, as well as the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sims-like-rival-life-by-you-has-been-cancelled-after-indefinite-delay">cancellation of Life by You</a> - Paradox CEO Fredrik Wester <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/paradox-ceo-admits-it-made-the-wrong-calls-in-several-projects-following-cancellation-of-life-by-you">admitted</a>, "It is clear that we have made the wrong calls in several projects, especially outside of our core, and this must change."
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path of Exile 2 Endgame Activities in Early Access Promise Hundreds of Hours of Play]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/path-of-exile-2-endgame-activities-in-early-access/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2-endgame-activities-in-early-access-promise-hundreds-of-hours-of-play.1044900/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/path-of-exile-2-endgame-activities-in-early-access/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The true testament to an ARPG’s longevity is always in the endgame. While the campaign is an excellent appetizer, it’s often only meant to introduce the world, mechanics, and gameplay to new players. Once you complete the story mode, the game opens up. Thankfully, you don’t have to fret because Path of Exile 2 endgame activities offer hundreds of hours of playtime. It’s a lot to take in!</p>



<h2 id="h-exploring-the-endgame-in-path-of-exile-2">Exploring the Endgame in Path of Exile 2</h2>



<p>Once you finish the multi-act campaign in Path of Exile 2, the game opens up with various endgame activities. You can explore unique biomes, uncover robust crafting mechanics, challenge optional bosses, and run mysterious dungeons with varying difficulty levels, challenges, and rewards. </p>



<figure><figcaption>Image via Grinding Gear Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>The game’s endgame includes Trial of the Sekhemas, The Trial of Chaos, Breach, Expedition, Ritual, Delirium, and the Pinnacle Threats.</p>



<h3 id="h-trial-of-the-sekhemas">Trial of the Sekhemas</h3>



<p>If you intend to evolve your class with one of the many available Ascendencies, you must run The Trial of Sekhemas—a challenging gauntlet that tests your resolve. It features rogue-like mechanics, with every room posing a unique trial, and every floor offers a potent boss fight at the end. The rewards will help you push to new heights, though.</p>



<h3 id="h-the-trial-of-chaos">The Trial of Chaos</h3>



<p>Throughout the Vaal Jungle, you’ll uncover the Temple of Chaos, another test that allows you to unlock class Ascendencies. To gain access, you require a token from the Trialmaster. From there, every room within the ordeal poses a hazard to your health, and you can go double or nothing on rewards.</p>



<h3 id="h-breach">Breach</h3>



<p>An endgame Breach is a portal from another dimension in which demons and monsters await. Upon entering a Breach, you will bridge the worlds and enter the opposing realm, slaying demons to keep the Breach open while unlocking XP and rewards for killing mobs.</p>



<h3 id="h-expedition">Expedition</h3>



<p>Expeditions task you with uncovering rare artifacts dug up using explosives. But the site isn’t clear of enemies, which means you’ll utilize your class abilities to punish corpses and put down monsters before reclaiming artifacts from the area. The more you uncover, the more mobs you draw to the dig site. </p>







<h3 id="h-ritual">Ritual</h3>



<p>Scattered across Wraeclast, you’ll discover Ritual Altars built by the King in the Mists. These altars require a tribute in the form of monster kills, which feed the ritual site and resurrect the King in the Mists’ dark forces. You’ll squash everything in sight for mighty rewards.</p>



<h3 id="h-delirium">Delirium</h3>



<p>Endgame maps in Path of Exile 2 may occasionally succumb to Delirium, in which a mysterious entity reworks the zone, creating a nightmarish landscape. The longer you remain in the Delirium, the greater the rewards, but the more powerful the enemies you face with every passing minute.</p>



<h3 id="h-pinnacle-threats">Pinnacle Threats</h3>



<p>As you explore the various areas in PoE2, you’ll encounter a Fortress of flame and ash, with a maze full of mystery, danger, and potential rewards. If you’re willing to venture into Pinnacle Threats, you’ll be rewarded for your efforts, but the challenge is not without perils that could end your adventure.</p>



<p>Which endgame mode are you most excited to play? Let us know over at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming community forums</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>Before you run off excitedly, don’t forget to check out everything included in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/heres-whats-inside-each-of-the-path-of-exile-2-supporter-packs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Path of Exile 2 Supporter Packs on Steam</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Sued Over Return To Office Mandate]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-sued-over-return-to-office-mandate/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-sued-over-return-to-office-mandate.1044897/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-sued-over-return-to-office-mandate/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-70269">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>As if things couldn’t get more interesting for Ubisoft, the company now finds itself with a lawsuit on its hands. Unions at Ubisoft Barcelona have sued the French publisher over its recent return to office mandates.</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/report-ubisoft-barcelona-unions-file-lawsuit-against-return-to-office-mandate" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">GamesIndustry.biz</a> (GIBiz), the unions — for both AAA and mobile teams —  are demanding Ubisoft ensure protections for remote work and walk back the recent policy changes. </p>







<p>The changes that were announced back in September mandated that all Ubisoft employees work in office <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-mandating-3-days-in-office-for-all-employees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at least three days per week</a>. At the time, Ubisoft said these changes were being done to “enhance creativity and teamwork”. Under the old remote work policy, employees were able to chose up to 60% of days to be worked remotely. On top of that, there were also fully-remote workers on staff. The new mandate was to be followed by all employees, even t hose with prior full-time remote agreements.</p>



<p>According to the unions via GIBiz, the change by Ubisoft was done “suddenly and without transparency”. It would also “create logistical problems as offices aren’t prepared to accommodate all remote workers at once.”</p>



<p>It was added that both parties were ready for negotiations. However, Ubisoft management hadn’t submitted a proposal before the lawsuit was filed on October 14.</p>



<p>Ubisoft has yet to comment on the lawsuit.</p>



<p>What do you think of Ubisoft being sued by union employees over their return to office mandate? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our full&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stalker-2-review-heart-of-chornobyl/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">review of STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/conor-mcgregor-hitman-character-cut/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/conor-mcgregor-hitman-character-cut/">Conor McGregor’s Hitman Partnership Cut After Sexual Assault Verdict</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Conor McGregor’s character has been eliminated from Hitman: World of Assassination following his guilty sexual assault verdict.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/troy-baker-will-return-next-project-naughty-dog/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/troy-baker-will-return-next-project-naughty-dog/">Troy Baker ‘Will Return’ For Naughty Dog’s Next Project</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It has been reported that Troy Baker WILL return to Naughty Dog to work with Neil Druckmann once again. Get the full story here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/windows-update-stops-ubisoft-games-from-working/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/windows-update-stops-ubisoft-games-from-working/">Latest Windows Update Stops Ubisoft Games from Working</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The new Windows 11 24H2 update is causing issues while playing certain Ubisoft games. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Children of the Sun update ‘Nightmare Paralysis’ now available, adds horde mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/children-of-the-sun-update-nightmare-paralysis-now-available-adds-horde-mode</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/children-of-the-sun-update-%E2%80%98nightmare-paralysis%E2%80%99-now-available-adds-horde-mode.1044885/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/children-of-the-sun-update-nightmare-paralysis-now-available-adds-horde-mode<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Take on platoons of THE CULT's brainwashed minions.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Devolver Digital [383 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/devolver-digital">Devolver Digital</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Rene Rother [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/rene-rother">Rene Rother</a> have released a free update for third-person puzzle <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,939 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > Children of the Sun [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/children-of-the-sun">Children of the Sun</a></em>, dubbed “Nightmare Paralysis,” which adds a new horde mode to the game. <span id="more-929861"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p>“Nightmare Paralysis,” a free update available now for all players, introduces a challenging new horde mode that will truly test THE GIRL’s tele-kill-netic abilities to send one bullet flying in new directions after it lands a hit.</p><p>Take on entire platoons of THE CULT’s brainwashed minions, but watch out for a new enemy that can fire back. The sniper cultist has a bullet with your name on it, and will put a premature end to your quest for vengeance if you don’t find a way to deal with them. And if you’re wondering how THE GIRL can take on an entire horde of cultists with only one bullet, well, now she can reload: by shooting herself.</p><p>“Nightmare Paralysis” also features dynamic weather, levels that shift as you play and more. This update adds a whole new dimension to Children of the Sun’s violent road trip of revenge, and it’s available right now on PC, free to everyone who owns the game.</p></blockquote><p><em>Children of the Sun</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,785 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1309950/Children_of_the_Sun/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Free Update “Nightmare Paralysis” Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Children of the Sun - Free Update &quot;Nightmare Paralysis&quot; Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VHi1Y4JXmxI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deep Rock Galactic To Get Haunted And Hostile Roguelite Spin-Off; Check Out The Debut Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/deep-rock-galactic-to-get-haunted-and-hostile-roguelite-spin-off-check-out-the-debut-trailer/1100-6528035/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deep-rock-galactic-to-get-haunted-and-hostile-roguelite-spin-off-check-out-the-debut-trailer.1044882/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/deep-rock-galactic-to-get-haunted-and-hostile-roguelite-spin-off-check-out-the-debut-trailer/1100-6528035/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528035">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Deep Rock Galactic is getting a roguelite spin-off called Rogue Core, planned for early-access release in 2025. Watch the pre-alpha gameplay teaser below.</p><p>Rogue Core is based on the same structure as Deep Rock Galactic. It still takes place on the hostile but resource-rich planet of Hoxxes IV. You can still play with up to four players in co-op. You still play as gun-toting dwarves delving into the deep places of the earth. However, instead of working miners, you'll play as the more militaristic Reclaimers, sent to investigate the abandoned deep mines close to the planet's core.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="122965252" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465512,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Deep%20Rock%20Galactic%3A%20Rogue%20Core%20-%20Pre-Alpha%20Gameplay%20Teaser&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:108,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/deep-rock-galactic-rogue-core-pre-alpha-gameplay-teaser\/2300-6465512\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465512\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465512\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465512\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465512&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465512,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6528035&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;deep-rock-galactic,deep-rock-galactic-rogue-core&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,first-person,shooter&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-one,playstation-5,playstation-4&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;ghost-ship-games,coffee-stain-publishing,skybound-llc,soft-source-pte-ltd&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;deep-rock-galactic&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;deep-rock-galactic&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465512},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465512\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4405111-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/x58pS0oU.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1732546260,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="x58pS0oU" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Deep Rock Galactic: Rogue Core - Pre-Alpha Gameplay Teaser</p>
      </div>
<p>These deep mines were excavating Expenite, a rare mineral found only close to Hoxxes IV's heart. Unlike Deep Rock Galactic, you won't start a run fully equipped. Instead you'll use Expenite to upgrade your Reclaimer's weapons and equipment. If you are playing with friends, this becomes a "draft" where all players pick from the same set of options. What one player takes will be blocked off from another, so you'll have to strategize with your crew to maximize each upgrade's impact. You can also loot improvements from special rooms or by completing difficult challenges. In the final game there will be five (or more classes), but only two have been announced: the sword-toting Slicer and the drone-handling Falconeer. Rogue Core will also feature permanent progress between runs and spaceship hub called the RV-09 Ramrod.</p><p>As for the game's environment, the trailer shows off deep-sea floors with shifting stone walls, abandoned caverns flush with mining equipment, and the hostile, barren rock of the core itself. The closer you get to the center of the planet, and finishing your run, the more the game's biomes will resemble the hostility of the core. Rogue Core has new and returning enemies, including boss battles.</p><p>According to a blog post and developer Q&amp;A on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2605790/view/4482865501645572470" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam</a>, Rogue Core started as an expansion to the base game, but it developed its own identity. Developer Ghost Ship Games also wished to put Rogue Core in early access, which it couldn't do if it were DLC. The game is currently in pre-alpha and Ghost Ship plans to release it in early access sometime in 2025.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/103097971921006863809?rel=author">Grace Benfell</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Chapter 6 leaks point to Godzilla crossover]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-chapter-6-leaks-point-to-godzilla-crossover</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-chapter-6-leaks-point-to-godzilla-crossover.1044879/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-chapter-6-leaks-point-to-godzilla-crossover<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-11-25-182251.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Trailer screenshot from Godzilla vs Kong.</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> Chapter 6 is less than a week away, and the leaks have begun. 
</p>
<p>
Over the weekend, a Godzilla collaboration was teased by multiple reliable Fortnite leakers, including <a href="https://x.com/ShiinaBR/status/1859974115387711651">ShiinaBR</a>, which fitted with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-chapter-6-map-features-japanese-theme-leaks-suggest">repeated leaks that the game's sixth Island map would feature a Japanese theme</a>.  
</p>
<p>
Now, purported artwork for Fortnite's Chapter 6 battle pass has popped up online - and Godzilla is included. The artwork appears to confirm Fortnite's upcoming Japanese theming, and also includes Baymax from Disney and Marvel's Big Hero 6.
</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
It seems likely we're seeing the skins set to become available in the Fortnite Chapter 6 Season 1 battle pass, which also include samurai sword-toting warriors and another cat person.
</p>
<p>
Other recent leaks suggest upcoming collaborations with Demon Slayer and Disney's Avatar are also due to arrive in Fortnite soon. 
</p>
<p>
Fortnite's all-new Chapter 6 is set to kick off this weekend, following a finale concert event for the game's current Chapter 2 Remix that's set to feature Snoop Dogg, Eminem, Juice WRLD and Ice Spice. The event will debut music from self-proclaimed Fortnite fan Juice WRLD, set to be included on the late star's new posthumously-released album. Anyone loading into Fortnite over the next few days will also be granted a Juice WRLD skin and other items free.
</p><p>
Still, all of that feels like it's been overshadowed slightly by the announcement of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-reviving-original-map-as-permanent-addition-featuring-multiple-classic-seasons">Fortnite OG - the return of the game's fan-favourite original map as a new permanent mode</a>. That arrives a week after Chapter 6's debut this weekend, next Friday 6th December.
</p>
<p>Last week, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnites-permanent-og-mode-will-have-its-own-battle-pass">Fortnite developer Epic Games revealed another battle pass would be offered for Fortnite OG</a>, meaning the game will now feature four available at any one time for the game's main battle royale, OG, music and Lego modes. All of these will now be wrapped into the Fortnite Crew subscription, however, which will retain it's current pricetag.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gladiator II May Have Starred Timothée Chalamet If Not For This Hulu Series]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/gladiator-ii-ridley-scott-paul-mescal-timothee-chalamet-1851707421</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gladiator-ii-may-have-starred-timoth%C3%A9e-chalamet-if-not-for-this-hulu-series.1044867/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/gladiator-ii-ridley-scott-paul-mescal-timothee-chalamet-1851707421<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="c93ea617a0f3cefc86131538189ceb23" data-recommend-id="image://c93ea617a0f3cefc86131538189ceb23" data-format="jpg" data-width="1360" data-height="907" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Paul Mescal ready for battle" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Paul Mescal ready for battle" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Aidan Monaghan</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c93ea617a0f3cefc86131538189ceb23" data-recommend-id="image://c93ea617a0f3cefc86131538189ceb23" data-format="jpg" data-width="1360" data-height="907" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Paul Mescal ready for battle" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The next time someone tries to tell you nothing productive comes from binge-watching TV, just point them to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/denzel-washington-gay-kiss-man-gladiator-2-cut-bisexual-1851698725&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/denzel-washington-gay-kiss-man-gladiator-2-cut-bisexual-1851698725"><em>Gladiator II</em></a></span>. In a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-features/making-of-gladiator-ii-ridley-scott-paul-mescal-1236066080/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-features/making-of-gladiator-ii-ridley-scott-paul-mescal-1236066080/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Hollywood Reporter</em> feature</a></span> on the making of the Ridley Scott-helmed film, it was revealed that the director binge-watching Paul Mescal’s Hulu series <em>Normal People </em>is what helped the actor land the leading role of Lucius Verus.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Only Scott knows what led him to the drama series about an emotionally complex relationship in which Mescal plays a sensitive man who breaks down during a therapy session. Whatever the reason, it helped Scott pick him over more established stars like Timothée Chalamet and Miles Teller. Since the feature explains how Paramount co-presidents of film Daria Cercek and Michael Ireland watched Mescal star as Stanley Kowalski in the 2022 revival of <em>A Streetcar Named Desire </em>in London before making their decision, that means Scott chose Mescal after Chalamet won a brutal knife fight as Paul Atreides in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dune-prophecy-valya-harkonnen-the-voice-1851706532&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dune-prophecy-valya-harkonnen-the-voice-1851706532"><em>Dune</em></a></span> and Teller competed in a shirtless football game as Lt. Bradley ‘Rooster’ Bradshaw in <em>Top Gun: Maverick</em>.</p><p>“Any studio would always prefer to have a known star,” <em>Gladiator II </em>producer Doug Wick says. However, he also later admitted, “no other actor came close.”</p><p>Mescal proved to be a fit for the physically demanding role which involved dealing with “borderline heat stroke from time to time” according to the star, who worked under sweltering conditions in Morocco and Malta where the film was shot. Risking his health paid off, as <em>Gladiator II’</em>s<em>&nbsp;</em>$106 million <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.usatoday.com/story/entertainment/movies/2024/11/24/wicked-gladiator-ii-box-office-record-numbers/76554624007/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/entertainment/movies/2024/11/24/wicked-gladiator-ii-box-office-record-numbers/76554624007/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">opening weekend box office</a></span> should be enough for any studio to greenlight a second sequel. Before a single ticket was sold, Scott already had a “soft footprint” for a possible <em>Gladiator III</em>. Mescal and Scott already have plans to work together again in thriller <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/ridley-scott-paul-mescal-the-dog-stars-1236056715/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/ridley-scott-paul-mescal-the-dog-stars-1236056715/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The Dog Stars</em></a></span><em>. </em>Although Mescal says the pair haven’t extensively discussed making another <em>Gladiator</em> film, “it’s an idea that I’d be excited about.”</p><p>Before you re-enter the <em>Gladiator </em>arena, pay your respects to <em>Normal People</em>, the series responsible for one of the biggest films of 2024 looking the way it does.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hitman Ditching Conor McGregor After Civil Jury Finds Him Liable For Sexual Assault]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hitman-conor-mcgregor-ufc-sexual-assault-jury-liable-1851707467</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hitman-ditching-conor-mcgregor-after-civil-jury-finds-him-liable-for-sexual-assault.1044864/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/hitman-conor-mcgregor-ufc-sexual-assault-jury-liable-1851707467<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="ca424172748f60aeaafe25523f314f94" data-recommend-id="image://ca424172748f60aeaafe25523f314f94" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Conor as seen in Hitman 3. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows Conor as seen in Hitman 3. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->IOI / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ca424172748f60aeaafe25523f314f94" data-recommend-id="image://ca424172748f60aeaafe25523f314f94" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows Conor as seen in Hitman 3. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hitman-3-the-kotaku-review-1846083354&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hitman-3-the-kotaku-review-1846083354"><em>Hitman</em></a></span> developer IO Interactive is distancing itself and its popular franchise from controversial mixed marital arts fighter Conor McGregor following a recent Irish High Court ruling in which a jury found him liable for sexually assaulting a woman in 2018. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>On November 22, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/22/world/europe/conor-mcgregor-sexual-assault.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/22/world/europe/conor-mcgregor-sexual-assault.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a civil jury in Dublin, Ireland ruled in favor</a></span> of a woman who accused the UFC superstar of sexually assaulting her in a hotel room in December 2018. McGregor is not facing any criminal charges, but the court ruled that the fighter needs to pay the woman $257,000. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.espn.com/mma/story/_/id/42545434/civil-jury-ireland-says-mcgregor-sexually-assaulted-woman&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.espn.com/mma/story/_/id/42545434/civil-jury-ireland-says-mcgregor-sexually-assaulted-woman" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">In a now-deleted tweet</a></span>, McGregor claimed he is appealing the decision. As a result of the ruling, IO Interactive is going to remove the UFC fighter from <em>Hitman</em>.</p><p>On Monday, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/Hitman/status/1861049881160273921&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/Hitman/status/1861049881160273921" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IOI released an official statement on Twitter</a></span> announcing that it had made a decision to ends its “collaboration” with McGregor. The UFC fighter was added as an <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://hitman.fandom.com/wiki/The_Disruptor&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://hitman.fandom.com/wiki/The_Disruptor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">“Elusive Target” to <em>Hitman 3</em> over the summer</a></span>. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://hitman.fandom.com/wiki/Elusive_Targets#:~:text=November%2015th,th%2C%202024&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://hitman.fandom.com/wiki/Elusive_Targets#:~:text=November%2015th,th%2C%202024" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">His character returned to the game earlier this month</a></span>, but is being removed immediately according to IOI’s statement. </p><p>“In light of the recent court ruling regarding Conor McGregor, IO Interactive has made the decision to cease its collaboration with the athlete, effective immediately,” said IOI Interactive on social media. </p><p>“We take this matter very seriously and cannot ignore its implications. Consequently, we will begin removing all content featuring Mr. McGregor from our storefronts starting today.”</p><p>This is far from McGregor’s first time in court, as the fighter has a long history of alleged criminal activity. In 2023, a woman accused the athlete of attacking her on a yacht the previous summer and forcing her to jump off to escape him. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://cagesidepress.com/2023/02/23/lawsuit-alleged-yacht-assault-conor-mcgregor-dropped/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://cagesidepress.com/2023/02/23/lawsuit-alleged-yacht-assault-conor-mcgregor-dropped/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The woman dropped the case without stated cause</a></span> after a brick was thrown through her window and an attempt was made to set her car on fire outside her home.</p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Premium PlayStation accessories to receive black variants]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/premium-playstation-accessories-black/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/premium-playstation-accessories-to-receive-black-variants.1044861/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/premium-playstation-accessories-black/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-70270">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>PlayStation is set to release black variants of three premium accessories: the DualSense Edge, the Pulse Elite, and the Pulse Explore, according to reliable leaker <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/ces-accessoires-ps5-sortiront-bientot-dans-un-tout-nouveau-coloris-59696" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">billbil-kun</a>.</p>



<p>At the moment, these accessories are only available in standard white, with the exception of the DualSense Edge, which has received a 30th anniversary version.</p>



<p>As well as revealing that Sony is working on these new variants, billbil-kun went further, revealing the price of each of the products:</p>



<ul>
<li>DualSense Edge wireless controller – Black: €239.99 / £209.99 / US$199.99.</li>



<li>Pulse Elite wireless headphones – Black: €149.99 / £129.99 / US$149.99.</li>



<li>Pulse Explore wireless headphones – Black: €219.99 / £199.99  / US$199.99.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-when-the-announcement-may-happen">When the announcement may happen?</h2>



<p>PlayStation’s 30th anniversary will be on December 3rd, so there’s no better time to announce these new versions.</p>



<p>If they follow the pattern, the announcement should be made on the PS Blog followed by posts on social media.</p>



<p>Of course, fans aren’t waiting for an announcement of new accessory colors. The community has long been demanding an event with the next PS5 exclusives. With The Game Awards approaching, maybe PlayStation will surprise everyone there.</p>



<p>Are you planning to buy any premium PlayStation accessories in black color? Tell us in the comments and join the discussion in our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/">forum</a>!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/conor-mcgregor-hitman-character-cut/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/conor-mcgregor-hitman-character-cut/">Conor McGregor’s Hitman Partnership Cut After Sexual Assault Verdict</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Conor McGregor’s character has been eliminated from Hitman: World of Assassination following his guilty sexual assault verdict.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/troy-baker-will-return-next-project-naughty-dog/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/troy-baker-will-return-next-project-naughty-dog/">Troy Baker ‘Will Return’ For Naughty Dog’s Next Project</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It has been reported that Troy Baker WILL return to Naughty Dog to work with Neil Druckmann once again. Get the full story here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/windows-update-stops-ubisoft-games-from-working/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/windows-update-stops-ubisoft-games-from-working/">Latest Windows Update Stops Ubisoft Games from Working</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The new Windows 11 24H2 update is causing issues while playing certain Ubisoft games. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-announcement-denied/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-announcement-denied/">Christopher Judge Denies God of War Announcement Tease</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Christopher Judge has taken to X (formerly Twitter) to deny that he was teasing an announcement about God of War.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 and Warzone Go Off the Deep End With New Shark Skin Bundle]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-warzone-go-off-the-deep-end-with-new-shark-skin-bundle</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-warzone-go-off-the-deep-end-with-new-shark-skin-bundle.1044855/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-warzone-go-off-the-deep-end-with-new-shark-skin-bundle<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> and Warzone’s descent into the weird and wonderful continues this week with a shark skin that does exactly what you’d expect: turn you into a shark.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The G’Day Bait Tracer Pack, priced 2,400 Call of Duty Points or around $20, includes the Bloke Biter shark skin for operator Carver.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As is Call of Duty tradition, you can’t buy the shark skin on its own. You can only get it as part of a bundle that includes weapon blueprints and a bunch of cosmetics designed to add value to that $20 purchase. Check it out in the screenshot gallery below.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 and Warzone's Bloke Biter Shark Skin Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">COD’s shark skin comes as no surprise. Indeed, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-skins-revealed-including-a-shark-a-raccoon-and-a-parasite-warrior">Activision had signalled its arrival as part of Black Ops 6 and Warzone Season 1</a>, although only now are we seeing it in all its glory. But it has revived commentary about Call of Duty’s silly outfits, weapon skins, and other visual effects that some have said they’d actually pay not to see in-game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Let’s remember that Black Ops 6 is a game packed with zombies, and as for operator skins already lets you play dress up as a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/30-call-of-duty-bundle-turns-you-into-a-dragon-knight-that-looks-straight-out-of-skyrim-and-some-players-say-they-would-be-willing-to-pay-not-to-see-it">dragon knight</a>, a parasite warrior, and a raccoon. If you’re playing Black Ops 6 Multiplayer during Season 1 you’ll have no-doubt spotted these outlandish visual effects out in the battlefield. Now, COD’s jaws-dropping shark skin is in the wild, Nuketown just got a lot fishier.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking of Zombies mode, we've got <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/Essential_Zombies_Tips_and_Tricks"><u>Essential Zombies Tips and Tricks</u></a> to help you get started, plus a guide on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/How_to_Exfil_in_BO6_Zombies"><u>How to Exfil</u></a>. Both Zombies maps are full of easter eggs and secrets; here's everything we've found in both <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/Terminus_Easter_Eggs_and_Secrets"><u>Terminus</u></a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/Liberty_Falls_Secrets_and_Easter_Eggs"><u>Liberty Falls</u></a>, including <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/How_to_Pack-a-Punch_in_Liberty_Falls"><u>How to Pack-a-Punch in Liberty Falls </u></a>and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/How_to_Get_the_Meteor_Easter_Egg"><u>How to Get the Meteor Easter Egg</u></a> in Terminus.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Drops to $30 for Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-drops-to-30-for-black-friday</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-drops-to-30-for-black-friday.1044852/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-drops-to-30-for-black-friday<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Target <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/events/black-friday">Black Friday</a> sale gives you a reason to dive headfirst into intergalactic chaos without blowing your holiday budget. As of November 24, Helldivers 2 for PlayStation 5 is marked down to just $29.99. That’s 25% off the usual $39.99 price tag, meaning you’ll save $10 while signing up to save humanity.</p><div catalogid="f92732a8-eb2f-4b10-a7ab-8caafdd155f8" id="211656"><div id="211656" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Hell Divers 2 - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Set in the not-so-friendly expanse of the galaxy, Helldivers 2 lets you join squads of up to four players to take on equally thrilling and chaotic missions. You’ll face swarms of alien enemies, customize your loadouts to rain down destruction, and wrestle with the constant danger of friendly fire (hey, accidents happen). With gameplay that’s fast, ferocious, and just a bit bonkers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whether you prefer to sneak through enemy territory or go full Rambo with explosions galore, Helldivers 2 has you covered. The game’s loadout options let you tailor your approach to combat and possibly earn some bragging rights along the way. (Try not to “accidentally” take out your squad mates with a misplaced grenade. We’ve all been there.)</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Friday is the perfect excuse to add this gem to your PS5 collection. The $29.99 price tag makes it one of the better deals we’ve seen for a highly rated recently released game. Whether you’re playing solo or coordinating mayhem with friends, Helldivers 2 promises endless hours of galactic carnage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-review">Our review for Helldivers 2 scored a 9/10</a> as a multiplayer breath of fresh air: "Helldivers 2's combat feels fantastic, its missions stay fresh and interesting, and its smart progression system doesn’t nickel and dime you."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But like any good Black Friday deal, this one won’t last forever. Head to Target before your chance to save $10 blasts off into space.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 25, 2024 4:25 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>