<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 03:18:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best iPhone Accessories to Buy in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-iphone-accessories</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-iphone-accessories-to-buy-in-2025.1109208/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-iphone-accessories<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">As one of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-smartphone"><u>best smartphones</u></a> around, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-iphones-to-buy"><u>iPhone</u></a> comes with a wealth of features to keep you entertained for hours. That doesn’t mean you can’t enhance your experience even more with a few accessories. Whether you enjoy mobile gaming, want to charge your phone wirelessly, or need to protect your device from scratches, there’s an accessory out there that’s suitable for you. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">TL;DR – These Are the Best iPhone Accessories in 2025:</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The lastest iPhone lineup, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/iphone-16-review">iPhone 16,</a> comes as a rather barebones package, so you might want to grab a pair of earbuds or a wall charger. It's no secret that the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-smart-watches">best smartwatch</a> for iPhone is Apple Watch Series 10, and you can always stay in the iOS ecosystem with Apple’s other official accessories. But going off-piste could mean enjoying some more affordable options on things like screen protectors, chargers, or even a cleaning kit to maintain your smartphone. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Contributions from </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/person/georgieperu"><em>Georgie Peru</em></a><em> and </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/person/RudieObias"><em>Rudie Obias</em></a></p><p id="best-wireless-earbuds"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best wireless earbuds" id="airpodspro">1. Apple AirPods Pro 2</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best Wireless Earbuds for iPhone</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213253"><div id="213253" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Apple AirPods Pro 2</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Enjoy Apple’s H2 chip and experience better noise cancellation, crisp audio, and rich bass. Including four pairs of silicone tips, you can comfortably wear the Apple AirPods Pro 2 for long periods of time.</p></div></div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>iPhone 6s or newer</p></div><div><div><div><p>Effective noise-canceling</p></div><div><p>Seamlessly pair with iPhone</p></div></div><div><p>No high-resolution Bluetooth audio</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s no surprise that the Apple AirPods Pro are the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-wireless-earbuds">best wireless earbuds</a>, especially for iPhones. They feature excellent and rich audio for music and podcasts, top-of-the-line noise canceling to block out ambient and background noise, and they sync seamlessly to the iPhone via iOS and Apple Keychain. These earbuds also have spatial audio features that make listening to your favorite music an immersive experience. These are the very <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-apple-airpods-models">best AirPods</a> you can buy right now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Want a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-iphone-earbuds">great iPhone earbuds</a> alternative? IGN expert Nick Woodard did <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/apple-airpods-4-with-anc-review"><u>hands-on testing of the Apple AirPods 4 with ANC</u></a>, giving the headphones an 8/10. He even stated the earbuds “go head-to-head in several categories with the AirPods Pro 2,” making the AirPods 4 a great lower-cost option that still seamlessly works with iPhones. </p></div><p id="best-case"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best case" id="smartishslimcase">2. Smartish Slim Case</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best iPhone Case</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213254"><div id="213254" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Smartish Slim Case</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Lightweight protection doesn’t have to cost a lot. With a range of designs to choose from, this stylish iPhone 16 case works with MagSafe chargers and accessories.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>iPhone 16, 16 Plus, 16 Pro, 16 Pro Max</p></div><div><p>Material</p><p>Hard plastic and rubber </p></div></div><div><div><p>Absorbs shock during fall</p></div><div><p>Yellowing of certain color ways over time</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The iPhone is an expensive and delicate piece of tech. Although it’s less prone to shattering if dropped these days, we still recommend wrapping your phone in a lightweight, yet durable case – like the Smartish Slim Case.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Made from tough hard plastic and rubber, this case features cushioned corners that absorb and disperse impact away from the phone itself to prevent cracking if dropped. It’s also designed with raised bumpers, so the display won’t sit flush with a flat surface when facedown. Meanwhile, the Smartish Slim Case is made with MagSafe built-in for wireless charging and other accessories.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It comes in nine colors and styles, including black, blue, transparent, purple, and more. Plus, the case is available in various sizes to fit all the latest iPhone 16 models. </p></div><p id="best-wall-charger"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best wall charger" id="ankerusbc736">3. Anker USB-C 747 Charger</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best Wall Charger for iPhone</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213255"><div id="213255" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Anker USB-C 747 Charger</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Charge up multiple devices simultaneously and experience fast charging on your iPhone.</p></div></div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>iPhone 6s or newer</p></div><div><div><div><p>Charges multiple devices simultaneously</p></div><div><p>Faster charging than standard wall charger</p></div></div><div><p>Larger than standard charging block</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Equipped with three USB-C ports and one USB-A port, the Anker USB-C 747 Charger is the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-usb-c-chargers-2023">best USB-C charger</a> you can find – ready to charge up your iPhone and a few other devices simultaneously – all while keeping compact dimensions. Delivering a total of 150W of power, it’s an absolute workhorse so it’ll have no trouble juicing up a power-hungry iPad or MacBook and your iPhone at the same time. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even with two or three devices plugged into this wall charger, an iPhone should still hit max charging speeds when connected to the charger’s USB-C port. That’s thanks to its dynamic power distribution. Considering the average charging block taps out at 20W, charging will be measurably faster. Anker also includes technology to measure temperature, keeping things safe as you juice up quickly. </p></div><p id="best-car-mount"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best car mount" id="iottievelox">4. iOttie Velox Magnetic Dash Mount</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best Car Mount for iPhone</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213256"><div id="213256" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>iOttie Velox Magnetic Dash Mount</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Compatible with MagSafe phone cases, this wireless charger is a must-have if you travel regularly in your car and want to keep your phone’s battery topped up.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>iPhone 8 or newer</p></div><div><p>Material</p><p>Soft plastic and silicone</p></div></div><div><div><div><p>Strong magnets hold device in place</p></div><div><p>Has wireless charging functionality</p></div></div><div><p>Only compatible with MagSafe cases</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s illegal to use your iPhone while driving – distracted driving is one of the biggest causes for accidents. Go hands-free and mount it on your car’s dashboard or windshield. The iOttie Velox Magnetic Dash Mount attaches to your car with a strong suction cup, while its powerful magnets keep your device in place to use in either landscape or portrait modes. It’s a wireless charger too, so your device will get some juice via your vehicle’s cigarette lighter. </p></div><p id="best-screen-protector"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best screen protector" id="ferilinso">5. Spigen Tempered Glass Screen Protector</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best iPhone Screen Protector</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213258"><div id="213258" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Spigen  Tempered Glass Screen Protector</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Keep your iPhone 16 safe with this top-notch screen protector that's easy to install and keeps full functionality of the display. </p></div></div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>iPhone 15, iPhone 16</p></div><div><div><p>Keeps phone's ultimate clarity and functionality intact</p></div><div><p>Occasional issues with edge adhesion </p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Made from tempered glass, the Spigen Tempered Glass Screen Protector keeps your iPhone 16’s display scratch-free and pristine, preventing pricey screen replacements. This screen protector differentiates itself from others by providing unique layers of protection to the tempered glass while keeping the ultimate clarity and functionality of the phone’s stunning display fully intact. So, the iPhone’s sharp resolution and impressive touch response will be just as great with the screen protector installed.   </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're specifically buying the new iPhone 16 Pro models, check out the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-iphone-16-pro-screen-protectors"><u>best iPhone 16 Pro screen protectors</u></a>. Most picks are also available in other iPhone models as well.</p></div><p id="best-wireless-charger"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best wireless charger" id="magsafecharger">6. Apple MagSafe Charger</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best Wireless Charger for iPhone</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213259"><div id="213259" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Apple MagSafe Charger</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Apple’s latest MagSafe Charger provides wireless charging up to 25W, a strong magnetic system, and Qi charging support. </p></div></div><div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>iPhone 12 or newer (for MagSafe)</p></div><div><p>Material</p><p>Aluminum and soft plastic</p></div></div><div><div><p>Up to 25W wireless charging speeds</p></div><div><p>Doesn't include wall charger</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Plenty of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-wireless-charger"><u>great wireless chargers</u></a> are available, but when it comes to iPhones, it’s best to find a charger ready to take advantage of the MagSafe technology the phones are packing. Since Apple invented MagSafe for a stronger, more reliable connection between a wireless charger to an iPhone 12 or later, the company's latest generation of MagSafe Charger is the best, most effective option for the iPhone. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The MagSafe Charger features a sleek, slim hockey-puck design with a strong magnet that aligns with the back of the iPhone for charging. The powerful connection between the two devices means there shouldn’t be any problem when picking up the phone to answer calls or checking socials while charging. The durable, high-quality materials used in its build mean the charger can handle some wear and tear too. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Unlike other wireless chargers, which are often limited to 7.5W speeds when charging an iPhone, the Apple MagSafe Charger can reach up to 25W with a 30W or 35W USB-C power adapter. Unfortunately, that wall charger will need to be purchased separately. Still, this option offers excellent value, as it features Qi2 and Qi support – any device that has Qi charging can juice up wirelessly. </p></div><p id="best-battery-pack"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best battery pack" id="magsafebatterypack">7. Anker MagGo Power Bank</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best Battery Pack for iPhone</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213261"><div id="213261" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Anker MagGo Power Bank</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Align this Qi2-certified, MagSafe compatible battery pack perfectly to your iPhone and charge wirelessly on the go. </p></div></div><div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>iPhone 12 or newer (for MagSafe)</p></div><div><p>Material</p><p>Aluminum and soft plastic</p></div></div><div><div><p>MagSafe compatible for secure connection to iPhone</p></div><div><p>Includes a tiny smart display</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Need to charge up your device on the go? Skip the hassle of cable management by grabbing the Anker MagGo Power Bank instead. Similar to the Apple MagSafe Charger, this battery pack is MagSafe-compatible for a secure, stable connection to the back of your phone. Just be prepared for it to add some bulk to your device. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With a 10,000mAh capacity, the Anker MagGo Power Bank can juice up your iPhone about 1.5 times before needing to be recharged itself. Thanks to the MagSafe compatibility, iPhone charging speeds hit up to 15W. If faster charging is necessary, the battery pack can also connect to an iPhone via USB-C instead, delivering up to a 27W output.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But what makes the MagGo Power Bank even more of a standout is the tiny smart display on its side. The TFT screen provides handy info on battery levels and charging times, and a little kickstand holds up your phone for easy viewing when charging. Not to mention the fun color options this battery pack comes in.  </p></div><p id="best-charging-cable"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best charging cable" id="ankerusbc">8. Anker USB-C to USB-C Cable</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best Charging Cable for iPhone</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213260"><div id="213260" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Anker USB-C to USB-C Cable</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Available in a range of lengths, the iPhone 15  and iPhone 16 can be charged easily and affordably with this pair of durable, braided fast charging cables.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>iPhone 15 or newer</p></div><div><p>Material</p><p>Thermoplastic elastomers and nylon</p></div></div><div><div><p>Available in range of sizes</p></div><div><p>Only works for newest iPhones</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">While there’s no shortage of cheap iPhone cables, the Anker USB-C to USB-C Cable is one of the best charging cables – thanks to its 6ft length and braided-nylon design for durability (it won’t fray after a few weeks of use), and its very affordable price at $16 for a two-pack. It also comes in three colors, including black, red, and silver.</p></div><p id="best-power-bank"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best power bank" id="belkin">9. Mophie Powerstation Plus</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3" id="belkin">Best Portable Power Bank for iPhone</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213263"><div id="213263" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mophie Powerstation Plus</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>This 10,000mAh power bank has built-in cables, so you don't have to worry about forgetting them.</p></div></div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>iPhone 6s or newer</p></div><div><div><p>Durable USB-C and Lightning cables attached</p></div><div><p>Not enough power to charge MacBook</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Nothing is worse than running out of juice on your iPhone when you’re far away from a wall outlet. For a cable-powered <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-portable-charger"><u>portable charger</u></a>, the Mophie Powerstation Plus, remedies this problem. With it comes a 10,000mAh battery for an over a full extra charge to your phone. But what makes this power bank a real standout is the inclusion of built-in, durable USB-C and Lightning cables that tuck away neatly when not in use. It’s perfect for those constantly losing and tangling wires. Beyond those cables, an additional USB-C port is provided to juice up a third device. However, to enjoy up to 30W charging speeds from the USB-C or 20W from the Lightning cable, only one device can be charged at a time. That’s plenty of power for an iPhone or iPad. Just don’t expect to charge a MacBook. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Since the Mophie Powerstation Plus will be spending lots of time getting tossed in bags and pockets to take on the go, the solid aluminum frame and compact build are ideal. Four tiny indicator lights on the side of the power bank also let you know when it’s time for the battery itself to get juiced up. </p><p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Razer Kishi Ultra – Photos</h3></div></output></p></div><p id="best-controller"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best controller" id="backboneone">10. Razer Kishi Ultra</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best iPhone Gaming Controller</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213264"><div id="213264" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Razer Kishi Ultra</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>The Razer Kishi Ultra features console-quality controls, a comfortable grip, and a feature-rich app.</p></div></div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>iPhone 15, iPhone 16</p></div><div><div><p>Customizable via the Razer Nexus app</p></div><div><p>Some features only work with Android </p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s no secret that iPhones weren't always the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-gaming-phone"><u>top gaming phones</u></a>. Still, Apple has made some headway with the A18 chips found in the iPhone 16 models, especially the extra graphics core living in the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/iphone-16-pro-max-review"><u>iPhone 16 Pro Max</u></a>. That’s coupled with higher-tier games coming to iOS like Assassin’s Creed Mirage and Resident Evil. But to really amp up that iPhone gaming experience an extra notch, grabbing the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-phone-controller"><u>best phone controller</u></a> is the way to go</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/razer-kishi-ultra-mobile-gaming-controller-review"><u>We reviewed the Razer Kishi Ultra</u></a> and absolutely loved this phone controller. It connects directly to iPhone 16 and 15 models via USB-C for zero latency when you play, while the controller stretches, flanking the screen for a comfortable grip. On it comes full-size analog sticks, an 8-way D-pad, and hall-effect triggers. But the star of the show is the ultra-responsive and clicky Mecha-Tactile buttons. L4 and R4 buttons are also ready for some macro inputs. It's a major upgrade from just tapping away at the screen, and you can even use this controller away from your phone by connecting to a PC or iPad via USB-C. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Razer Nexus app makes it simple to tinker with the different buttons and controls. You can remap buttons, adjust dead zones, swap RGB lighting, and more. Unfortunately, using the Kishi Ultra with iOS is slightly more limited than with Android, so Sensa HD Haptics and Virtual Controller Mode aren’t available. Still, Razer makes it simple to access Apple Arcade, Steam Link, Xbox Game Pass, and PlayStation Remote Play, so you can get gaming quickly on your iPhone. </p></div><p id="best-portable-bluetooth-speaker"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best portable Bluetooth speaker" id="bosesoundflex">11. JBL Go 3</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best Portable Bluetooth Speaker for iPhone</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213265"><div id="213265" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>JBL  Go 3</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Weighing less than half a pound with a tiny form factor to toss in a bag, this option also has a strap and IP67 rating for portability, though there’s only a 5-hour battery life.</p></div></div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>iPhone 6s or newer</p></div><div><p>Limiting 5 hour battery life</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Pair your iPhone with the JBL Go 3 via Bluetooth for a powerful sonic punch when on the go. Whether you’re streaming podcasts or music, the soundstage is wide with crisp, rich audio despite this speaker's compact design. And when we say “compact,” we mean it. It weighs less than half a pound and measures just 3.6x2.7x1.6 inches, making it easy to toss in a bag or even throw in a pocket. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Adding more reasons why the JBL Go 3 earns the title as the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-bluetooth-speakers">best Bluetooth speaker</a> for portability is its IP67 rating. It’s both waterproof and dustproof, so a little dirt and rain won’t stop the music whether you're at the beach, by the pool, on a picnic, or around the campfire. The only real downside is the slightly limiting five-hour battery life. </p></div><p id="best-cleaning-kit"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="Best cleaning kit" id="ecasp">12. Ecasp Cleaner Kit</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Best Cleaning Kit for iPhone</h3><div catalogid="d08edf02-e857-4fa6-ba06-f12f43deb77d" id="213266"><div id="213266" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Ecasp  Cleaner Kit</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Keep all of the ports on your iPhone free of dust and dirt with this handy little cleaning kit. It can even restore charging cables to their former glory after being buried at the bottom of your bag.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Compatible Apple iPhone</p><p>All models</p></div><div><p>Material</p><p>Metal and soft velvet</p></div></div><div><p>Great for cleaning various devices</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Since you touch your phone all day and even press it against your face when making phone calls, it’s a good idea to clean it every once in a while. Ecasp Cleaner Kit comes with just about everything you need to keep your device clean and working fantastically. It’s a multi-tool set to clean the display, port, edges, and more.  The kit is also good for cleaning a pair of Apple AirPods, an Apple Watch, an iPad, and cables.</p></div><p id="faq"><h2 data-cy="title2" data-toc-title="FAQ">iPhone Accessories FAQ</h2></p><h3 data-cy="title3">What accessories come with an iPhone?</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Once upon a time, buying an iPhone meant getting a whole box of goodies. Earlier models of the iPhone, such as the <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/111864" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">iPhone X</a>, came with wired Apple earbuds, a Lightning to 3.55mm headphone jack adapter, and a power adapter. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">However, as part of Apple’s <a href="https://www.apple.com/environment/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">new environmental goals</a>, more recent iPhone models only come with the USB-C charging cable (iPhone 15 and later), with an included recommendation that purchasers “re-use your current USB-A to lightning cables, power adapters, and headphones.”</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Can I use any USB-C charger for my iPhone? </h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The occasional rumor will circulate that it’s bad form to use non-Apple chargers on your iPhone. This is generally not true, as any compabitle cable will work to power your phone, but there are some stipulations to pay attention to. If you want to guarantee you get the highest quality of charging power (and not bunk cords that damage your device's battery), check whether a charger is "<a href="https://mfi.apple.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MFi-certified</a>," meaning it was made for iPhone and certified by Apple. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">What gaming accessories are good for iPhones?</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">As big studios continue to release mobile versions of their most popular games, you may be wondering what you can do to optimize your iPhone gaming experience. While the Razer Kishi Ultra is our pick for the best gaming accessory, other options are <a href="https://www.amazon.com/iPhone-Game-Accessories/s?k=iPhone+Game+Accessories" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on the market</a>, including iPhone-compatible <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/accessories/all/gaming?fh=4684%2B4a77%2B45ef" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wireless gaming controllers</a>. You can even use <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/remote-play/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Playstation's Remote Play</a> app alongside a Sony controller and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-wireless-bluetooth-headphones">best wireless headphones</a> to bring the console experience to your Apple device. 
</p></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Feb 13, 2025 11:00 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digimon Story: Time Stranger Preorders Are Already Live For PS5, Xbox, And PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/digimon-story-time-stranger-preorders-are-already-live-for-ps5-xbox-and-pc/1100-6529499/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/digimon-story-time-stranger-preorders-are-already-live-for-ps5-xbox-and-pc.1109205/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/digimon-story-time-stranger-preorders-are-already-live-for-ps5-xbox-and-pc/1100-6529499/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529499">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Bandai Namco announced the next entry in the long-running Digimon Story RPG series, Digimon Story: Time Stranger, will launch on PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC later in 2025. The game will let players recruit and train their own team of digital monsters and use them in turn-based battles while on a time-hopping quest that spans the real and digital worlds. While no specific release date has been confirmed, preorders for the game are already live at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DW1T1HV7?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D24348%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fvideo-games%2Fplaystation-5%2Fproducts%2Fdigimon-story-time-stranger---playstation-5%2F422053.html&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdigimon-story-time-stranger-preorders-are-already-live-for-ps5-xbox-and-pc%2F1100-6529499%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GameStop</a>.</p><h2>Digimon Story: Time Stranger Preorder Bonus</h2><p>No preorder bonuses have been announced for Digimon Story: Time Stranger, but we'll be sure to update this post if anything new is confirmed.</p><p>While Digimon Story: Time Stranger appears to be an all-new storyline within the series, the Digimon Story franchise has been around since the Game Boy Advance. The latest prior releases in the series are Digimon Story Cyber Sleuth and its prequel Cyber Sleuth - Hacker's Memory, both of which feature similar turn-based combat and story presentation as Time Stranger. If you're looking to play them before the new game is out, you can grab both in a single package with the Digimon Story Cyber Sleuth Complete Edition, which is available for just <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Digimon-Story-Cyber-Sleuth-Complete-Nintendo/dp/B07V42555Q?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$25.45 on Nintendo Switch</a>, or <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Fdigimon-story-cyber-sleuth-complete-edition&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdigimon-story-time-stranger-preorders-are-already-live-for-ps5-xbox-and-pc%2F1100-6529499%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">$43.49 on PC via Fanatical</a> (was $50).</p><p>Several other recent Digimon games are also on sale right now, including Digimon Survive, which melds a visual novel narrative with tactical combat segments. You can grab it on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Digimon-Survive-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B07TYG7771?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Nintendo Switch</a> for $22, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Digimon-Survive-PlayStation-4/dp/B07V1JYNVM?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS4</a> for $13.89, or <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Fdigimon-survive&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdigimon-story-time-stranger-preorders-are-already-live-for-ps5-xbox-and-pc%2F1100-6529499%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on PC</a> for $50.88 (was $60). There's also Digimon World: Next Order, which is the latest entry in Digimon's <em>other </em>long-running RPG series. Digimon World: Next Order focuses more on the monster-taming aspects of the series and features a unique real-time combat system and town management that sets it apart from the traditional JRPG gameplay of the Digimon Story series. You can pick up Digimon World: Next Order <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Digimon-World-Next-Order-PlayStation-4/dp/B01LZ4MLV8?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on PS4</a> for $23.71 or <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Fdigimon-world-next-order&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdigimon-story-time-stranger-preorders-are-already-live-for-ps5-xbox-and-pc%2F1100-6529499%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on PC</a> for $50.88.</p><h2>More Digimon Games</h2><ul><li><strong>Digimon Story Cyber Sleuth: Complete Edition</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Digimon-Story-Cyber-Sleuth-Complete-Nintendo/dp/B07V42555Q?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Switch</a> -- $25.45</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Fdigimon-story-cyber-sleuth-complete-edition&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdigimon-story-time-stranger-preorders-are-already-live-for-ps5-xbox-and-pc%2F1100-6529499%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PC</a> -- $43.49</li></ul></li><li><strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Digimon-Story-Cyber-Sleuth-Hackers-PlayStation/dp/B06Y3BVJ16?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Digimon Story Cyber Sleuth - Hacker's Memory (PS4)</a> </strong>-- $16</li><li><strong>Digimon Survive</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Digimon-Survive-Nintendo-Switch/dp/B07TYG7771?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Switch</a> -- $22</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Digimon-Survive-PlayStation-4/dp/B07V1JYNVM?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS4</a> -- $13.89</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kqzyfj.com%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Fdigimon-survive&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdigimon-story-time-stranger-preorders-are-already-live-for-ps5-xbox-and-pc%2F1100-6529499%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PC</a> -- $50.88</li></ul></li><li><strong>Digimon World: Next Order</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Digimon-World-Next-Order-PlayStation-4/dp/B01LZ4MLV8?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS4</a> -- $23.71</li><li><a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.fanatical.com%2Fen%2Fgame%2Fdigimon-world-next-order&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdigimon-story-time-stranger-preorders-are-already-live-for-ps5-xbox-and-pc%2F1100-6529499%2F%3Fftag%3DCAD-01-10abi2f&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PC</a> -- $50.88</li></ul></li></ul><p><em>Disclosure: GameSpot and Fanatical are both owned by Fandom.</em></p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-buy-one-get-one-half-off-movie-tv-shows-blu-ray-amazon-february-2025/1100-6529351/">Amazon Kicks Off B1G1 50% Off Movie And TV Series Sale</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-accessory-sale-how-to-save-20-on-playstation-portal-helldivers-2-dualsense-controller-and-more/1100-6529304/">PS5 Accessory Sale - How To Save 20% On PlayStation Portal, Helldivers 2 DualSense Controller, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-preorder-deals-collectors-edition-amazon/1100-6526606/">Like A Dragon: Pirate Yakuza In Hawaii Collector's Edition In Stock At Amazon</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-on-sid-meiers-civilization-7-preorders-for-pc-mac-early-access-starts-february-6/1100-6525971/">Save On Sid Meier's Civilization 7 Preorders For PC &amp; Mac - Early Access Starts February 6</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/apple-airpods-4-discounted-to-only-100-at-amazon/1100-6526375/">Apple AirPods 4 Discounted To Only $100 At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-festival-riffmaster-guitar-controller-gets-biggest-discount-yet/1100-6528970/">Fortnite Festival Riffmaster Guitar Controller Gets Biggest Discount Yet</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-preorders-where-to-get-steelbook-edition-and-best-deals/1100-6526687/">Monster Hunter Wilds Preorders - Where To Get Steelbook Edition And Best Deals</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/geforce-rtx-50-series-gpus-launched-today-but-its-not-easy-to-grab-one/1100-6528684/">GeForce RTX 50-Series GPUs Launched Today, But It's Not Easy To Grab One</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/104300651635509044736?rel=author">Brendan Hesse</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529406&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/almost-30-years-later-one-of-the-longest-running-mmorpgs-is-getting-a-new-class\/1100-6529406\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529339&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fortnite-chapter-6-season-2-start-date-theme-battle-pass-leaks-and-rumors\/1100-6529339\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529362&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/rpg-fans-should-check-out-this-square-enix-game-sale-on-amazon\/1100-6529362\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529412&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-barrow-dyad-exotic-quest-guide-how-to-start-and-complete-derealize\/1100-6529412\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529351&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-buy-one-get-one-half-off-movie-tv-shows-blu-ray-amazon-february-2025\/1100-6529351\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529342&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-talks-switch-2-demand-and-gives-small-update-on-pricing\/1100-6529342\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529393&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-texas-chain-saw-massacres-50th-anniversary-is-almost-50-off-at-amazon\/1100-6529393\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529404&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-reloaded-start-date-and-details\/1100-6529404\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529395&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tony-hawk-was-living-in-his-car-when-he-was-offered-300k-for-thps-former-activision-ceo-claims\/1100-6529395\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529363&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/with-switch-2-coming-nintendo-explains-why-it-must-go-beyond-traditional-games\/1100-6529363\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529284&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-state-of-play-returns-on-february-12\/1100-6529284\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529447&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/avowed-early-access-launch-times-revealed\/1100-6529447\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529371&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/free-to-play-delta-force-will-add-paid-black-hawk-down-campaign-february-21\/1100-6529371\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529442&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fortnite-may-be-gearing-up-for-fast-furious-season\/1100-6529442\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529353&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-actor-kaitlyn-dever-shuts-down-off-screen-rumor-about-season-2\/1100-6529353\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529435&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tides-of-annihilation-looks-like-stellar-blade-meets-arthurian-legend-in-debut-trailer\/1100-6529435\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529341&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/psn-is-down\/1100-6529341\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mobile Suit Gundam SEED: Battle Destiny Remastered announced for Switch, PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/mobile-suit-gundam-seed-battle-destiny-remastered-announced-for-switch-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mobile-suit-gundam-seed-battle-destiny-remastered-announced-for-switch-pc.1109172/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/02/mobile-suit-gundam-seed-battle-destiny-remastered-announced-for-switch-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out on May 22.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,642 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > B.B. Studio [224 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment/bandai-namco-studios/bb-studio">B.B. Studio</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > Mobile Suit Gundam SEED: Battle Destiny Remastered [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mobile-suit-gundam-seed-battle-destiny-remastered">Mobile Suit Gundam SEED: Battle Destiny Remastered</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,654 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [22,363 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1857740/MOBILE_SUIT_GUNDAM_SEED_BATTLE_DESTINY_REMASTERED/" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch on May 22 worldwide. <span id="more-943419"></span></p><p><em>Mobile Suit Gundam Seed: Battle Destiny Remastered</em> is a remastered version of the <a title="Platforms > PS Vita [7,378 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vita">PS Vita</a> game <em>Mobile Suit Gundam SEED: Battle Destiny</em>, which was released only in Japan on June 7, 2012.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Bandai Namco:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Become a pilot in the world of <em>Mobile Suit Gundam SEED</em>, for the first time available with English localization! Engage in thrilling, <a title="Genres > Action [2,494 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>-packed Gundam battles, complete missions, and tune up your newly acquired Mobile Suits!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong> Battle Across Turbulent Times!</strong> – Relive legendary moments from <em>Mobile Suit Gundam SEED</em> and <em>Mobile Suit Gundam SEED Destiny</em> with enhanced maps and graphics. Choose your faction from Earth Alliance Forces, ZAFT, or the Archangel, and complete missions alongside familiar pilots and Mobile Suits from the series.</li><li><strong> Over 100 Mobile Suits!</strong> – All Mobile Suits have been redesigned with high-resolution model textures. Unlock more Mobile Suits and missions from the main <em>Mobile Suit Gundam SEED</em> series, and battle into additional side stories from the <em>Mobile Suit Gundam SEED</em> universe.</li><li><strong> Tune Up Your Suits!</strong> – Strengthen your suits and weaponry in the redesigned UI menu. Tune your suits to match your playstyle as you embark on missions and take on stronger opponents!</li><li><strong> System <a title="Companies > Enhance [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a>ments</strong> – New lock-on modes and controller settings have been added for smoother gameplay.</li></ul><p>*Product is based on <em>Mobile Suit Gundam SEED: Battle Destiny</em> released in 2012. Some specifications may differ.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/mobile-suit-gundam-seed-battle-destiny-remastered/february-13-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="MOBILE SUIT GUNDAM SEED BATTLE DESTINY REMASTERED - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NX1GfnTWz-w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『機動戦士ガンダムSEED BATTLE DESTINY REMASTERED』アナウンスメントトレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gLuVjyYn7tc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_944136"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia delays the RTX 5070 till after AMD’s reveal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/612650/nvidia-delays-rtx-5070-after-amd-9070</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-delays-the-rtx-5070-till-after-amd%E2%80%99s-reveal.1109148/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/612650/nvidia-delays-rtx-5070-after-amd-9070<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/sean-hollister">Sean Hollister</a> <span>is a senior editor and founding member of The Verge who covers gadgets, games, and toys. He spent 15 years editing the likes of CNET, Gizmodo, and Engadget.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>As always, the most important Nvidia graphics card is the one you can actually buy, and Nvidia’s talked a big game for its RTX 5070, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/8/24338999/nvidia-rtx-5070-vs-rtx4090-performance-price">making the dubious but nuanced claim</a> it can deliver RTX 4090 performance for just $549. On February 28th, AMD will get its chance to intercept with the Radeon RX 9070 and 9070 XT, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/612375/amd-will-reveal-radeon-rx-9000-gpus-february-28th">in a streaming event it just announced today</a>. But Nvidia has now made its own wiggle room, delaying the launch of the RTX 5070 from February to March 5th, <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nvidia.com%2Fen-us%2Fgeforce%2Fgraphics-cards%2F50-series%2Frtx-5070-family%2F" rel="sponsored">its product page reveals today</a>.</p><p>Nvidia will ship its $749 RTX 5070 Ti ahead of AMD’s event, though, on February 20th, a week from today.</p><p>AMD has telegraphed that it <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/9/24240173/amd-udna-gpu-ai-gaming-rdna-cdna-jack-huynh">won’t be competing</a> with Nvidia’s latest and greatest cards, so price is the one big lever that AMD can potentially pull in order to compete. (The AMD Radeon 9070 cards <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24336246/amd-radeon-rx-9070-series-rdna-4-fsr-4-ces-2025#:~:text=in%20a%20branding%20slide%20for%20RDNA%204%2C%20AMD%20appears%20to%20suggest%20the%209070%20series%20will%20offer%20similar%20performance%20to%20the%20Nvidia%20GeForce%20RTX%204070%20Ti%20and%20RTX%204070%20Super.">appeared to be targeting</a> Nvidia 4070 Ti and 4070 Super levels of performance, not necessarily higher.) But Nvidia, a company that can now make <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/20/24301811/nvidia-just-made-nearly-20-billion-in-pure-profit-in-a-single-quarter">$20 billion in pure profit in a single quarter</a>, could theoretically counter that if it feels it needs to, and now has more room to do so.</p><p>All that said, <a href="https://videocardz.com/newz/amd-reportedly-working-on-gaming-radeon-rx-9000-gpu-with-32gb-memory">there is a rumor</a> that AMD may be working on a more potent card than its already-announced RX 9070 and 9070 XT, one with 32GB of RAM. AMD gaming marketing boss <a href="https://x.com/AzorFrank/status/1890123828367601764">Frank Azor says</a> the 9070 XT won’t be a 32GB card, but did not address the larger rumor.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Massive Stalker 2 Patch Has Over 1,700 Changes, Including Big Bug Fixes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/massive-stalker-2-patch-has-over-1700-changes-including-big-bug-fixes/1100-6529496/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/massive-stalker-2-patch-has-over-1-700-changes-including-big-bug-fixes.1109145/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/massive-stalker-2-patch-has-over-1700-changes-including-big-bug-fixes/1100-6529496/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529496">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Stalker 2's much-anticipated 1.2 patch is here, and it continues where the last few 1.1 updates left off--and then some. According to its announcement on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1643320/view/579378232238800945" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam</a>, Stalker's 1.2 patch has more than 1,700 individual fixes and improvements, including a large number of bug fixes, NPC behavioral changes, revamped visuals, and more.</p><p dir="ltr">There are truly too many changes to go over here in detail, but some of the major ones include an overhaul to NPC shooting accuracy, with reduced wall penetration and better shot randomization. The update also revamps how the game's stealth works, gives some enemies (like the Controller) new abilities, and improves NPC behavior overall. It improves performance during certain sequences, and fixes dozens of major and minor issues that could affect main story and side quests. More than 450 improvements were made to the game's map and level design, including several sections where the player could get stuck, such as X-17 Lab.</p><p dir="ltr">Stalker 2 was generally praised for its atmosphere and unique presentation when it first released last year. However, many players and critics noted its many bugs. In GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-review-in-the-zone/1900-6418320/">Stalker 2 review</a>, critic Richard Wakeling listed its "torrent of technical problems," but said that it's "difficult to not to fall under its enticing spell." With the introduction of this most recent patch and its predecessors, hopefully most of those bugs are a thing of the past. Stalker 2 is also available on Xbox Series X|S.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atari and Jeff Minter team on remake of classic arcade game I, Robot]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/atari-and-jeff-minter-team-on-i-robot-remake</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atari-and-jeff-minter-team-on-remake-of-classic-arcade-game-i-robot.1109142/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/atari-and-jeff-minter-team-on-i-robot-remake<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Llamasoft/Atari</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game designer Jeff Minter and his studio Llamasoft are going back to the past with a remake of Atari's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PgN3u8JtGw8">I, Robot</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For Minter and Llamasoft, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>I, Robot </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">will be the latest in a legacy of remakes and retro-inspired adaptations, following 2018's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Minotaur Arcade Vol 1. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">In the past, Minter has had a hand in remaking 8-bit classics </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tempest </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Defender, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">along with his own Atari ST/Amiga game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Llamatron.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Throughout his 45-year career, Jeff has retained the spirit of a true indie developer," reads a statement from Atari game VP Ethan Sterns. The remake, which is expected to release later this year for PlayStation, Xbox, Switch, PC, and Atari VCS was described by Sterns as "quintessential Minter."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The upcoming "reality-defying reinvention" of the 1984 arcade future will see players explore levels and turn red tiles to blue to escape. Changes to the original game come in reducing the level count from 126 to 55, adding in the modern magic of online leaderboards, and implementing procedural music that "builds as you excel."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="A brief history of ">A brief history of <span>I, Robot</span></h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Designed by </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Missile Command </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tempest's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Daid Theurer, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>I, Robot </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">first released in June 1984 as an arcade game. At the time, it was famously the first commercially produced arcade game rendered entirely in real-time, 3D polygon graphics, and the first to feature camera control options. It's also one of Atari's final two arcade games (alongside </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Star Wars: Return of the Jedi </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">that same year) before the company was split up and eventually formed into its current-day incarnation.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/how-the-iconic-jeff-minter-stays-inspired-after-43-llama-filled-years-of-game-development" target="_self" data-discover="true">How the iconic Jeff Minter stays inspired after 43 llama-filled years of game development</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Initially, the game was a financial flop and fewer than 1,000 units were created. Few are said to currently exist, and the game has since been regarded as a pioneer for its then-innovative graphics. When Atari's 50th anniversary game bundle released in 2022, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>I, Robot </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">was included, marking the title's first-ever re-release for non-arcade game hardware.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If you're curious what a "quintessential Minter" reimagining of a game like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>I, Robot </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">could look like, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/how-the-iconic-jeff-minter-stays-inspired-after-43-llama-filled-years-of-game-development">this 2024 interview with Minter </a></span><span data-testid="content-text">offers an in-depth exploration of his game making ethos and a candid look at how--and why--he creates such distinctive games like Gridrunner, Polybius, and others mentioned above.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As Minter explained in that 2024 chat, he's not typically the type to create games that chase a wide audience or as many people as possible. "That's a different kind of motive than what drives me, really. I'm more interested in pursuing the ideas I have, and I don't really care that much if they're wildly successful or not."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Oh, it'd be nice if they were. I'm not saying I would turn that down. But I'm not that bothered if they're not," said Minter. "As long as I can carry on doing what I'm doing, I'm happy, you know?”</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed - All Totem Of Perseverance Pieces And Locations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-all-totem-of-perseverance-pieces-and-locations/1100-6529504/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-all-totem-of-perseverance-pieces-and-locations.1109118/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-all-totem-of-perseverance-pieces-and-locations/1100-6529504/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529504">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/avowed/" data-ref-id="5000-516154">Avowed</a>, you can find and assemble totems in each region that provide passive buffs. In Galawain's Tusks you can assemble the Totem of Perseverance by finding the totem base and six pieces throughout the region. A list of the totem pieces can be purchased from a vendor in Solace Keep, but this list does not provide map markers for the totem pieces. Once you have collected the totem pieces, they can be assembled at camp.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>The totem pieces can be collected in any order.</strong></p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Totem_Base">Totem Base</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443958-galawain8.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443958" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443958-galawain8.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443958"></a><figcaption>The Shrine to Galawain is located in the northeast part of Twinedwood.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443958-galawain8.jpeg"></figure><p>The Totem Base can be found in the Shrine to Galawain in the north part of Twinedwood. It is located on an altar in the west part of the shrine.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443959-galawain5.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443959" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443959-galawain5.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443959"></a><figcaption>The totem base is located in the Shrine to Galawain.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443959-galawain5.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Antler_of_the_Persevering_Stag">Antler of the Persevering Stag</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443961-galawain2.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443961" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443961-galawain2.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443961"></a><figcaption>This totem piece is located underneath the western part of the Bridge to the Garden.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443961-galawain2.jpeg"></figure><p>The Antler of the Persevering Stag can be found in the southeast part of Galawain's Tusks, near the Bridge to the Garden. Go to the start of the bridge, but instead of crossing, look to the side of the bridge to find a path underneath it. The totem piece is on a ledge just underneath the bridge.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443960-galawain.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443960" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443960-galawain.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443960"></a><figcaption>The Antler of the Persevering Stag is located on a ledge under the bridge.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443960-galawain.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Hunter_s_Arrows_of_Slaying">Hunter's Arrows of Slaying</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443962-galawain9.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443962" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443962-galawain9.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443962"></a><figcaption>This totem piece is in the Slumbering Fields.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443962-galawain9.jpeg"></figure><p>The Hunter's Arrows of Slaying can be found in the Slumbering Fields in the west. From the Slumbering Field fast travel point, head north through the two archways.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443963-galawain22.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443963" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443963-galawain22.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443963"></a><figcaption>Head towards the first arch and through the second one just past it.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443963-galawain22.jpeg"></figure><p>Head forward and take a left under another archway. Head forward until you reach a ledge, and then follow the path to the left.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443964-galawain23.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443964" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443964-galawain23.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443964"></a><figcaption>Past this arch, head straight until you reach a cliff, take a left up into the ruins.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443964-galawain23.jpeg"></figure><p>At the end of the path, climb up and into the small ruins to find the totem piece sitting in an open chest.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443965-galawain7.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443965" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443965-galawain7.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443965"></a><figcaption>The Hunter's Arrows of Slaying is inside a small circular building.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443965-galawain7.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Hunter_s_Arrows_of_Surviving">Hunter's Arrows of Surviving</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443966-galawain14.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443966" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443966-galawain14.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443966"></a><figcaption>This totem piece is in the Lost Village, but you need to start at the Pargrun Cache to the northwest.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443966-galawain14.jpeg"></figure><p>The Hunter's Arrows of Surviving can be found in the Lost Village in the northern part of Galawain's Tusks. Despite being in the Lost Village, you will need to start at the Pargrun Cache nearby. To get there approach from the south and navigate through a spider-cave to reach the Pargrun Cache.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443967-galawain12.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443967" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443967-galawain12.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443967"></a><figcaption>When looking at the cache, turn left and follow the path towards the ruins in the back of this image.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443967-galawain12.jpeg"></figure><p>From the cache, follow the rock formation to the left down by a river of lava. At the end are some small ruins, the totem piece is inside.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443968-galawain13.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443968" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443968-galawain13.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443968"></a><figcaption>The totem piece is inside the ruins at the end of the lava river.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443968-galawain13.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Antler_of_the_Pursued_Stag">Antler of the Pursued Stag</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443970-galawain18.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443970" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443970-galawain18.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443970"></a><figcaption>This totem piece is north of the Pargrun Cache and requires Yatzli.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443970-galawain18.jpeg"></figure><p>The Antler of the Pursued Stag is north of the Pargrun Cache and will require you to bring Yatzli to use disillusion.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443971-galawain15.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443971" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443971-galawain15.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443971"></a><figcaption>Use Yatzli to clear the illusion to enter the cave.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443971-galawain15.jpeg"></figure><p>Directly across from the cache is a rock you need to have Yatzli clear. Once inside the cave, head left and use fire to clear vines blocking a doorway.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443972-galawain16.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443972" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443972-galawain16.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443972"></a><figcaption>Use fire to clear the vines blocking the door.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443972-galawain16.jpeg"></figure><p>The Antler is inside on a table.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443973-galawain17.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443973" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443973-galawain17.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443973"></a><figcaption>The Antler is past the vine-blocked door in the cave.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443973-galawain17.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Wolf_s_Pelt_Trophy">Wolf's Pelt Trophy</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443974-galawain21.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443974" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443974-galawain21.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443974"></a><figcaption>This totem piece is located on top of the Ash Forest Outpost.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443974-galawain21.jpeg"></figure><p>The Wolf's Pelt Trophy can be found in the Ash Forest, on top of the Ash Forest Outpost. To the left of the outpost is a series of ledges from which you can climb up and reach the roof.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443975-galawain19.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443975" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443975-galawain19.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443975"></a><figcaption>Head up the stone path shown here to reach the roof.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443975-galawain19.jpeg"></figure><p>The pelt is on the roof.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443976-galawain20.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443976" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443976-galawain20.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443976"></a><figcaption>The Wolf's Pelt is on the roof of the Ash Forest Outpost.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443976-galawain20.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Hunter_s_Arrows_of_Seeking">Hunter's Arrows of Seeking</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443977-galawain4.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443977" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443977-galawain4.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443977"></a><figcaption>The Hunter's Arrows of Seeking is on the My. Forja Summit.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443977-galawain4.jpeg"></figure><p>The Hunter's Arrows of Seeking can be found on the My. Forja Summit, which is accessed by going through the Mt. Forja Mines dungeon in the western part of the map. <strong>You will go to the summit as part of the main quest, so you can wait until then if you prefer. </strong>Once you reach the summit through the dungeon door, immediately head to your right and climb to the section of the area in the southeast. The totem piece is up on a ledge.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443978-galawain3.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443978" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443978-galawain3.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443978"></a><figcaption>This totem piece can be found by taking a hard right as soon as you enter the summit via the dungeon.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443978-galawain3.jpeg"></figure><p>Obsidian is no stranger to crafting compelling RPGs. For more help on the team's latest effort, use our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-guides-hub/1100-6529402/">Avowed guides hub</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Black Hole Just Annihilated An Entire Planet In Helldivers 2 On Its Way To Super Earth]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-black-hole-meridian-angel-venture-order-1851763091</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-black-hole-just-annihilated-an-entire-planet-in-helldivers-2-on-its-way-to-super-earth.1109097/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-black-hole-meridian-angel-venture-order-1851763091<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="3d3036790c7219b81b4b59c346ca790f" data-recommend-id="image://3d3036790c7219b81b4b59c346ca790f" data-format="png" data-width="861" data-height="484" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Helldiver watches a planet explode." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="3d3036790c7219b81b4b59c346ca790f" data-recommend-id="image://3d3036790c7219b81b4b59c346ca790f" data-format="png" data-width="861" data-height="484" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Helldiver watches a planet explode." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Helldivers 2 </em>is always changing. One day you might wake up to a new DLC adding <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-illuminate-omens-tyranny-free-update-1851720355&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-illuminate-omens-tyranny-free-update-1851720355">aliens with mind control powers called the Illuminate</a></span>. Another you might encounter a big patch that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-shovel-patch-notes-warbond-hellbomb-1851754765&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-shovel-patch-notes-warbond-hellbomb-1851754765">secretly adds shovels</a></span>. Or you might load up the sci-fi shooter and immediately receive an evacuation order for Angel’s Venture because it’s about to be destroyed by a rogue black hole.  </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196395" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="80" data-playlist="196395,195734,195189" data-current="196395"><div><p>The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21945.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Players who were online at the time could jump to the planetary system in question and behold the destruction of what’s been one of the big battlefields in the Galactic War that began back when <em>Helldivers 2</em> launched in February 2024. Millions of Helldivers died liberating the autumnal planet from Terminid control beginning with  Operation Valiant Enclosure. Players only ever lost one battle there. But this week, it proved to be all for naught when <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qyCgEeXRZ5I&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qyCgEeXRZ5I" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Helldivers</em> dungeon master Joel</a></span> decided to make it the first pawn to fall in a much more sinister game.</p><p>But it’s not the first time a planet was destroyed in <em>Helldivers 2</em>. Meridian was the first to fall, and not at the hands of outside forces. It was players who destroyed that planet last year by turning it into a black hole as a means toward eradicating a mutated Terminid Super Colony of their own unintentional making. It was the first example of Arrowhead Game Studios fundamentally altering its in-game cosmos in service of its grim military storytelling. And it’s not clear it was part of a grander plan. </p><p>Last weekend, players were given the Major Order to go contest the Illuminate’s control of the black hole, lest the aliens fuel it with dark energy for unknown purposes. “The Illuminate are now actively moving Meridia,” an in-game message informed players on February 8. “The Center of Science on Fenrir III can confirm: Meridia is in motion. The Dark Energy that the illuminate muster through their many invasions appears to be key. The Helldivers is [sic] now called upon to limit the Illuminate accumulation of this Dark Energy.”</p><p>It’s unclear how the black hole can be stopped but things will get very, very bad if it’s not. The anomaly is now on a collision course for Super Earth, with five other planets in the way. Plus, the more dark energy it accrues, the faster it moves. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1ii9dlw/dark_energy_accumulation/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1ii9dlw/dark_energy_accumulation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Players had been tracking</a></span> it via in-game tools over the past week. How many more planets will fall before the Illuminate’s plan can be unraveled and halted? Or is Arrowhead planning to celebrate <em>Helldivers 2</em>'s one-year anniversary with a Super Earth showdown players have been waiting for?</p><p>Either way, it’s a testament to the game’s one-of-a-kind evolving online world that it feels like it’s building toward something despite all of the repetition and incremental progress. Players of the original <em>Helldivers</em> have won the Galactic War multiple times at this point, with each victory clearing the board ahead of a new campaign. I’m excited to see what Arrowhead’s long-term plans are with this sequel. It feels like <em>Helldivers 2</em> has room to continuing evolving, both mechanically and narratively, for years to come. </p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation State of Play February 2025 Tier List]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-state-of-play-february-2025-tier-list</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-state-of-play-february-2025-tier-list.1109091/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-state-of-play-february-2025-tier-list<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">We just got our first PlayStation State of Play for 2025 with several big announcements from Metal Gear Solid Delta to a new game from developer Housemarque. While the best part of any new showcase is new game announcements, release dates, and trailers, we know some announcements are bigger than others.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s why we’re giving you a chance to rank your favorite announcements from the recent PlayStation State of Play. Was it the first look at Saros? Or the new game from the lead designer of Grand Theft Auto? With over 20 announcements from yesterday’s showcase, look back at our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-state-of-play-february-2025-everything-announced">Everything Announced post</a> and decide which big reveal made the most impact on you.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for me, the Metal Gear Solid Delta release date was probably my most anticipated announcement, but it was also really cool to finally get a look at the main character of Capcom’s upcoming Onimusha: Way of the Sword. And what’s more, it’s incredible that he’ll be modeled after one of my favorite actors, Toshiro Mifune.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So let us know how the State of Play news items ranked for you below.</p><div id="playstation-state-of-play-february-2025-announcements-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">PlayStation State of Play February 2025 Announcements Tier List</h3><h3>PlayStation State of Play February 2025 Announcements Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Matt Kim is IGN's Senior Features Editor.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No More Heroes Studio Asks For No More Fans To Randomly Appear At Office]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/no-more-heroes-studio-asks-for-no-more-fans-to-randomly-appear-at-office/1100-6529502/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-more-heroes-studio-asks-for-no-more-fans-to-randomly-appear-at-office.1109088/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/no-more-heroes-studio-asks-for-no-more-fans-to-randomly-appear-at-office/1100-6529502/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529502">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Grasshopper Manufacture is kindly asking for people to stop dropping by its Tokyo location unannounced. In fact, the developer--founded by Suda51 and behind the No More Heroes franchise--decided to can an episode of its <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@GhMChannel51" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dev Room series on YouTube</a> because it may have led to even more fans randomly appearing at its office.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/grasshopper-manufacture-asks-fans-not-to-visit-the-studio-unannounced/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Automaton</a> reported that Grasshopper Manufacture explained the situation last week <a href="https://x.com/Grasshopper_EN/status/1887772293226766715" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">on X</a>, noting "it simply isn't possible for us to receive sudden visitors during work so often." As such, the developer is calling on fans to "refrain from showing up at the studio without a business-related appointment."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/Grasshopper_EN/status/1887772293226766715" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Announcement Re: The Dev Room: Ep. 49<br>A few days ago we posted that the release of the 49th episode of The Dev Room would be delayed due to some last-minute editing issues. During editing, there was a lot of internal discussion regarding this particular episode, and we regret to…</p>  — Grasshopper Manufacture (@Grasshopper_EN) <a href="https://twitter.com/Grasshopper_EN/status/1887772293226766715?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 7, 2025</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">Founded in 1998, the studio is probably best known for No More Heroes, Killer7, and Lollipop Chainsaw. Last year, Grasshopper released <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/shinji-mikami-thinks-modern-games-are-too-serious-shadows-of-the-damned/1100-6526245/">Shadows of the Damned: Hella Remastered, which doesn't take itself too seriously</a>. Looking ahead, Suda51, whose actual name is Goichi Suda, has <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-legendary-game-dev-promises-to-cook-for-switch-2/1100-6524194/">stated that his company will "cook for" Switch 2</a>.</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/no-more-heroes-3-review-desperate-struggle/1900-6417721/">No More Heroes 3</a> was a Switch exclusive for basically a year before hitting PlayStation and Xbox platforms in 2022, including PC. While <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-parent-company-hints-at-plans-to-support-switch-2/1100-6529308/">third-party companies have voiced support</a> for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/">Switch 2</a>, no official game announcements have been made quite yet. That will most likely change during <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-revealed-launch-date/1100-6528762/">the Nintendo Direct focusing on Switch 2 in April</a>.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1777506620" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465596,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%202%20%E2%80%93%20Official%20First%20Look%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:141,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-2-official-first-look-reveal-trailer\/2300-6465596\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465596\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465596\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465596\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465596&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465596,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6529502&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;no-more-heroes-iii,shadows-of-the-damned&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch,playstation-5,playstation-4,pc,xbox-series-x,xbox-one,playstation-3,xbox-360&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;marvelous,pixn-love,grasshopper-manufacture,marvelous-inc,xseed-games&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;no-more-heroes&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;no-more-heroes&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465596},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465596\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4428695-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/LOUrtQRx.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1737037800,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="LOUrtQRx" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465596" data-src="/videos/nintendo-switch-2-official-first-look-reveal-trailer/2300-6465596/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Nintendo Switch 2 – Official First Look Reveal Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529362&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/rpg-fans-should-check-out-this-square-enix-game-sale-on-amazon\/1100-6529362\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529315&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/wonder-woman-game-has-reportedly-cost-warner-bros-100-million\/1100-6529315\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529314&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-batman-and-game-of-thrones-games-may-be-in-the-works\/1100-6529314\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529316&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gta-parent-company-boss-discusses-ai-and-how-machines-dont-learn\/1100-6529316\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529313&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-quality-of-life-fixes-are-inbound-starting-with-its-ui\/1100-6529313\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529311&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/football-manager-25-canceled-after-multiple-delays-dev-moves-on-to-next-game\/1100-6529311\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529308&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/gta-parent-company-hints-at-plans-to-support-switch-2\/1100-6529308\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529312&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/trumps-tariffs-may-impact-console-sales-says-ceo-of-gta-parent-company\/1100-6529312\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529309&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/smite-2-dev-lays-off-staff-apparently-ends-work-on-three-games-including-smite-1\/1100-6529309\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6528872&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-new-dungeon-sundered-doctrine-release-date-race-details-and-everything-to-know\/1100-6528872\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529065&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/summer-wars-amazon-exclusive-4k-steelbook-preorders-now-only-cost-30\/1100-6529065\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529322&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sea-of-thieves-season-15-will-excite-megalodon-hunters-and-fishing-lovers\/1100-6529322\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529325&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/avowed-dev-is-sick-of-dwarves-all-having-scottish-accents\/1100-6529325\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529328&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/kingdom-come-2-dev-on-denying-instant-gratification-elder-scrolls-morrowind-influence\/1100-6529328\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529324&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/civilization-7-players-hear-coughing-in-game-music-but-no-ones-choking\/1100-6529324\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529318&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/one-of-nintendos-weirder-games-is-coming-to-switch-online-this-month\/1100-6529318\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529319&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/pubg-spin-off-gets-a-new-name-and-more-details\/1100-6529319\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529317&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/where-is-xur-today-february-7-11-destiny-2-exotic-items-and-xur-location-guide\/1100-6529317\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6529335&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-this-24-inch-asus-gaming-monitor-for-only-79\/1100-6529335\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It Takes Two Boss Says Studio Will Never Make A Live-Service Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-takes-two-boss-says-studio-will-never-make-a-live-service-game/1100-6529501/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it-takes-two-boss-says-studio-will-never-make-a-live-service-game.1109064/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-takes-two-boss-says-studio-will-never-make-a-live-service-game/1100-6529501/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529501">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Josef Fares, the director of It Takes Two and the upcoming Split Fiction, said that Hazelight Studios will never make a live-service game.</p><p>"We will not have them, I do not believe in them," Fares said in an interview with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ea-will-never-convince-us-to-make-a-live-service-game-it-takes-two-developer-says-after-suggestion-biowares-dragon-age-the-veilguard-should-have-been" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>. "I think [live service] is not the right way to go. I hope more and more [developers] focus on their passion and what they believe in."</p><p>Fares explained that he understands the financial pressures of having to make live-service games, but emphasized the need to not lose all focus on creativity. He believes that there should be a balance between the financial and creative aspects, as developers can't just ask for $100 million in funding and do whatever they want.</p><p><span>He pointed to the success Hazelight has seen as evidence that "trust[ing] in your vision" can still lead to a "big audience." Last year, Hazelight revealed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-takes-two-crosses-20-million-copies-sold-developer-teases-title-of-next-game/1100-6527240/" data-ref-id="1100-6527240">It Takes Two had surpassed 20 million copies sold</a>.</span></p><p><span>Other studios have recently followed the live-service trend to varying success. PlayStation started its </span><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sony-is-planning-to-invest-heavily-into-live-service-games-with-bungie-buyout/1100-6500131/" data-ref-id="1100-6500131">live-service initiative</a><span> several years ago. While </span><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-is-fastest-selling-playstation-game-ever/1100-6523423/" data-ref-id="1100-6523423">Helldivers 2 exceeded expectations</a><span>, games like </span><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/concord-now-being-removed-from-psn-accounts/1100-6526385/" data-ref-id="1100-6526385">Concord failed to take off</a><span> and several games have been canceled, including </span><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-last-of-us-multiplayer-game-canceled-announces-naughty-dog/1100-6519973/" data-ref-id="1100-6519973">Naughty Dog's The Last of Us multiplayer</a><span> game and reportedly a </span><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-cancels-two-games-including-a-live-service-god-of-war-report/1100-6528869/" data-ref-id="1100-6528869">God of War live-service one</a><span>.</span></p><p>Bungie veteran Joe Tung said that the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/live-service-is-a-better-model-according-to-former-halo-and-destiny-developer/1100-6524513/" data-ref-id="1100-6524513">live-service model is better</a> than the traditional $60 box approach, as it helps developers consider what's best for players in the long-term. In a recent earnings call, Ubisoft said that it would <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-doubles-down-on-open-world-and-live-service-games/1100-6529497/" data-ref-id="1100-6529497">double down on both live-service games and open-world action adventure titles</a>.</p><p>Fares also recently discussed his thoughts about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/it-takes-two-and-split-fiction-director-shares-his-thoughts-on-ai/1100-6529493/" data-ref-id="1100-6529493">AI and its effects on the video game industry</a>, saying that it needs to learn how to work with AI and other emerging technologies.</p><p>Hazelight's previous game, It Takes Two, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-game-awards-2021-winners-revealed-it-takes-two-wins-game-of-the-year/1100-6498845/" data-ref-id="1100-6498845">won Game of the Year at The Game Awards 2021</a>. The studio's next game, Split Fiction, launches on March 6 for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. Like Hazelight's past projects, Split Fiction is a co-op adventure game and it follows two women named Zoe and Mio as they traverse through both fantasy and sci-fi-themed levels in order to survive.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft cost-cutting 'ahead of schedule' after studio closures, with plans to 'go beyond' goal in FY26]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-s-cost-cutting-ahead-of-schedule-after-studio-closures-plans-to-go-beyond-goal-in-fy26</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-cost-cutting-ahead-of-schedule-after-studio-closures-with-plans-to-go-beyond-goal-in-fy26.1109058/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-s-cost-cutting-ahead-of-schedule-after-studio-closures-plans-to-go-beyond-goal-in-fy26<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ubisoft's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://staticctf.ubisoft.com/8aefmxkxpxwl/2GbdOQTUuRZV3mqGXgTfeK/520f2262c4f60b4bc13f0f3a59ec37e7/Ubisoft_FY25_Q3_PR_English_vFinal.pdf">financial report</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for the nine month period ending December 31, 2024 is out, with the French developer and publisher shining a spotlight on its upcoming Assassin's Creed title as well as the state of the ongoing cost reduction drive that's seen several studio closures and restructurings already, with more changes seemingly still on the way.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These cost reductions build on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-taking-decisive-steps-to-reshape-company-and-renew-focus-on-gameplay-quality">plans and processes detailed earlier into 2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to "reshape the group" with the goal of improving Ubisoft's operational efficiency, value creation, and player experiences. According to today's press release detailing the Q3 results, those efforts are pacing "ahead of schedule" due in part to Ubisoft shuttering of its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/ubisoft-kills-xdefiant-and-closes-studios-in-san-franciso-and-osaka">San Francisco, Osaka teams,</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and "targeted restructurings" across its European offshoots in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-kicks-off-bid-to-maximize-value-creation-with-layoffs-and-studio-closure">Leavington, Stockholm, and Newcastle.</a></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Those layoffs and closures, in addition to other measures taken by the company, have put the company well on its way to hitting the €200 million fixed cost base reduction goal set forth , so much CEO Yves Guillemot now says the company plans to significantly surpass its original target and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>further</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> reduce costs into the 2025-2026 financial year kicking off this April.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"As a result of disciplined execution, we have announced further targeted restructurings, making difficult but necessary choices, and now expect to exceed our cost reduction objective by the end of FY25, ahead of schedule," reads a statement from Guillemot. "We plan to pursue our efforts in FY26, going beyond the initial target by a significant margin."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Ubisoft prepares for Assassin's Creed and an uncertain future">Ubisoft prepares for Assassin's Creed and an uncertain future</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Financially, Ubisoft's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://staticctf.ubisoft.com/8aefmxkxpxwl/2GbdOQTUuRZV3mqGXgTfeK/520f2262c4f60b4bc13f0f3a59ec37e7/Ubisoft_FY25_Q3_PR_English_vFinal.pdf">bookings</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for the third quarter of the 2024-2025 financial year are in line with its previously revised expectations. Quarterly bookings were €301.8 million, down 52 percent year-over-year and just €1.8 million over that revised target. Meanwhile, bookings for the full nine-month period were €944 million, down nearly 35 percent year-over-year.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Looking forward to the final quarter of the 2024-2025 year, Ubisoft expects those last few months to bring the full year's net bookings up to around €1.9 billion. Guillemot added that the developer is "fully focused" on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Assassin's Creed: Shadows </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">ahead of its March 20 release. The action-stealth game has been delayed twice and stands as Ubisoft's next core title following after 2024's launch of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Star Wars Outlaws</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I want to commend the incredible talent and dedication of the entire Assassin’s Creed’s team, who is working tirelessly to ensure that Shadows delivers on the promise of what is the franchise’s most ambitious entry yet," he said.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In January, Ubisoft told investors it would take "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-taking-decisive-steps-to-reshape-company-and-renew-focus-on-gameplay-quality">decisive steps</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" to change the company and put a focus on "delivering best-in-class player experiences, enhance operational efficiency and maximize value creation." The cost reduction programs are part of said efficiency, as is improving the quality of releases like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Outlaws </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">via post-launch updates.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Guillemot also touched on the review process of its "strategic options" discussed in January. The process, which came after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-tencent-and-the-guillemot-family-considering-ubisoft-buyout">reports</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> of the Guillemot family exploring a potential buyout with Tencent, remains "ongoing."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Ultimately, the objective is to unlock the best value from our assets for our stakeholders and to foster the best conditions to create great games in a fast-evolving market," he explained. "We are convinced there are different potential paths to achieve this ambition."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone Includes First-Person Combat, Customization & More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-includes-first-person-combat-customization-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-includes-first-person-combat-customization-more.1109046/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-includes-first-person-combat-customization-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Farm 51 has been working on Chernobylite 2 for over three years, and today, one of the most significant milestones for the team has been achieved. The Kickstarter campaign for this game has reached more than 200% of the initial funding goal. The team exceeded its campaign target with six stretch goals, which has allowed the team to secure additional expansion of the project beyond the original plans that were set in place. This includes extra locations to explore for both single-player and co-op missions, as well as a customizable interface. The Farm 51 has created an infographic that goes into detail about their Kickstarter, as well as the team's dedication to creating this new game.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>The developers have announced that the Kickstarter campaign will continue to be live thanks to the option of Late Pledges, where those who pledge can still support the team and get some of the rewards that are available.</p>
<p><iframe title="Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone Early Access Announcement CGI Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lEoeb1g88e0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>One of the most exciting parts of the team's news is that Early Access is just around the corner for Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone. The Farm 51 has confirmed today that Early Access on Steam will begin on March 6, where approximately one-third of the final game's content will be available for players to explore, as well as provide the team with valuable feedback while they continue their efforts in the development process.</p>
<p>For those just hearing about this game, Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone is a post-apocalyptic action RPG that combines free exploration in a realistic open world with challenging combat, base management, non-linear storytelling, and more.</p>
<p>Character creation is a huge main feature of this game, as you get to develop your hero exactly how you want them. Whether it's skillful combat, being a fantastic conversationalist, or someone who can charm their way out of sticky situations, it's entirely up to you.</p>
<p>You can also choose how you handle the combat in Chernobylite 2. Whether you decide to utilize the complex melee combat system or use a variety of firearms to take out your enemies, the choice is completely up to you.</p>
<p>Base building will also be a huge part of this game, where you can develop your base, create valuable items, and upgrade your weapons. Here, you can assign your people to tasks where they will continue to take care of your equipment and supplies while you are away.</p>
<p>You can play the game your way, whether it's playing solo, or experiencing and engaging in online co-op missions, the choice is yours.</p>
<p>Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone will be in <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2075100/Chernobylite_2_Exclusion_Zone/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Early Access on PC</a> on March 6, with it soon to follow on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S. For more information, check out <a href="https://wccftech.com/chernobylite-2-qa-20-times-bigger-world-2-3x-longer-playtime/">Alessio's Q&amp;A with the team</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Some Fans Are Cheering The Return Of Loot Boxes In Overwatch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-loot-boxes-season-15-skins-cosmetics-1851762971</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-some-fans-are-cheering-the-return-of-loot-boxes-in-overwatch-2.1109028/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-loot-boxes-season-15-skins-cosmetics-1851762971<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>One of the funny things about being entrenched in a game’s community for years is that you sometimes forget how it might look to someone on the outside. That happened to me this week when Blizzard announced it would be bringing loot boxes back to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-perks-stadium-season-15-spotlight-preview-1851761919&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-perks-stadium-season-15-spotlight-preview-1851761919"><em>Overwatch 2</em></a></span><em> </em>in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-showcase-perks-stadium-freja-aqua-season-15-1851761489&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-showcase-perks-stadium-freja-aqua-season-15-1851761489">Season 15</a></span><em> </em>after dropping the mystery cosmetic packs when the sequel launched in 2022. When I saw that, my immediate thought was “Oh, so the people who wanted those back finally got what they wanted,” and then I mentally moved on to the next thing. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195460" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="195460,196880,196049" data-current="195460"><div><p>Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20938.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>I forgot that if you hadn’t been paying attention to <em>Overwatch 2 </em>for several years, you might be confused as to why Blizzard would make this choice, much less <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/PlayOverwatch/status/1889741290394227102&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/PlayOverwatch/status/1889741290394227102" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">frame it as something worth celebrating</a></span>. It’s tied up in years of nostalgia toward the “way things used to be” in the original <em>Overwatch</em> and a dislike of <em>Overwatch 2</em>’s methods of monetization. The return of loot boxes doesn’t mean Blizzard is dismantling the expensive money dump entirely, but it is giving players a free option to <em>maybe</em> get the skins they want.</p><h3 id="h123016"><a id=""></a><strong>Why did people want loot boxes back in <em>Overwatch 2</em>?</strong></h3><p>When <em>Overwatch 2 </em>launched, it completely reorganized how you unlock and purchase cosmetics. Blizzard added an in-game shop that rotates cosmetics in and out weekly that can be purchased with in-game currency and real-world money. Compare this to how you would unlock most things in the original <em>Overwatch</em>; you’d unlock a loot box with each level you gained and would hope and pray the skin you wanted was inside. You couldn’t control what you got from them, but the trade-off was that everything from skins to victory poses was obtainable for free. However, if you’re not so patient, you could also buy loot boxes with real money, which is how they get you. So there was an element of gambling involved.</p><p>By the time the original <em>Overwatch </em>was replaced by the sequel, I had unlocked so many cosmetics that opening the free loot boxes I’d gotten was a waste of time because I was mostly finding duplicates. Sure, I probably spent a few bucks here and there trying to find something specific, but the monetary investment was nothing compared to what it’s cost me to buy new skins in <em>Overwatch 2</em>’s store.</p><p>That’s part of why fans have been asking for a return to loot boxes. They’re pretty much a gambling mechanic that incentivizes players to spend real money in hopes of finding their desired skin, but there was still an option to earn them for free. A dedicated player could get everything they wanted without paying a cent, but in <em>Overwatch 2</em> that Mercy or Kiriko skin you’ve been eyeing is locked behind a paywall, and probably costs a pretty penny.</p><p>It’s easy to see how someone might yearn for the days when <em>Overwatch </em>wasn’t such a huge money investment on top of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-prereview-roundup-free-hero-shooter-grind-1849601813&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-prereview-roundup-free-hero-shooter-grind-1849601813">being such a grind</a></span>, and it’s a pretty damning criticism of <em>Overwatch 2</em>’s expensive store that some people think gambling is the preferable approach. But looking at loot boxes in an <em>Overwatch</em>-shaped vacuum isn’t telling the whole story, which is why people who aren’t in the payload-pushing trenches are bewildered by the excitement.</p><h2 id="h123017"><a id=""></a><strong>Are <em>Overwatch 2</em>’s loot boxes exploitative or just another means of progression?</strong></h2><p>Loot boxes have always been a controversial form of microtransaction in video games. Most gacha games use them in an inherently <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/loot-boxes-are-designed-to-exploit-us-1819457592&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/loot-boxes-are-designed-to-exploit-us-1819457592">exploitative way</a></span> because they require significant monetary or time investment with only a chance of getting the rewards you want. Such mystery packs have also been a centerpiece in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-class-action-lawsuit-loot-box-mario-kart-tour-1850462828&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-class-action-lawsuit-loot-box-mario-kart-tour-1850462828">lawsuits</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/u-s-senator-introduces-bill-to-ban-loot-boxes-and-pay-1834612226&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/u-s-senator-introduces-bill-to-ban-loot-boxes-and-pay-1834612226">legislation</a></span> as parents and elected officials deem them a predatory business model. With all this baggage, it probably looks insane from the outside to see Blizzard tout their return and fans respond with excitement, eager to accept them with open arms. From the sound of it, however, Blizzard isn’t bringing them back in the same way, and the approach the team is taking this time around sounds less exploitative than what came before.</p><p>In an interview with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/some-overwatch-fans-are-thrilled-loot-boxes-are-coming-back-some-not-so-much&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/some-overwatch-fans-are-thrilled-loot-boxes-are-coming-back-some-not-so-much" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>IGN</em></a></span>, <em>Overwatch 2 </em>director Aaron Keller confirmed that Loot Boxes will only be available on the battle pass and completing challenges, with no option to purchase them with real money. Keller also confirmed in an <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xRoM9B6vmhw&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xRoM9B6vmhw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">interview with YouTuber emongg</a></span> that if you get a duplicate cosmetic, you can re-roll so you’re not wasting the limited loot boxes you can get per season. <em>Overwatch 2</em> has found so many ways to monetize things that were once free in the original that I’m surprised Blizzard didn’t try to monetize gambling on top of it, but considering the gambling aspect is so fraught that the U.S. government wants to get involved, this was probably the safer approach. Blizzard is also trying to be more transparent about what you might get by providing explicit drop rates so there’s less randomized mystery.</p><p>Ultimately, what Blizzard has described is less like the gambling we typically associate with loot boxes and more like a free form of progression that harkens back to the old days of <em>Overwatch</em>. As long as there isn’t any predatory option to pay for them with real cash, I don’t see the harm in giving people chance drops to earn old cosmetics that have rotated out of the shop. Reviving the little glowing chests that burst open with a celebratory fanfare is a nostalgia play just like the <em>Overwatch Classic </em>modes and bringing the old 6v6 format back. But in another timeline loot boxes could’ve been brought back exactly as they were, ready to rake in money from some poor Mercy main desperate to get the latest legendary skin.</p><p>Loot boxes will return in season 15 on February 18.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Full 2025 Steam Sales Schedule Revealed by Valve]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/full-2025-steam-sales-schedule-revealed-by-valve/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/full-2025-steam-sales-schedule-revealed-by-valve.1109025/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/full-2025-steam-sales-schedule-revealed-by-valve/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-90743">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Valve has officially <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/groups/steamworks/announcements/detail/497187349280587904" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a> the full schedule of Steam Sales and Festivals for the remainder of 2025. A full slate of Steam events have been announced for the entire year, guaranteeing that waves of discounts and bundles will never subside. The first half of 2025 sales events were <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/2025-steam-sales-revealed-for-first-half-of-the-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced in July 2024</a>.</p>



<p>The 2025 schedule features the major seasonal Sales, genre-specific Fests, and Next Fests highlighting upcoming titles. Valve has noted that this year’s Autumn Sale will be at “a different time frame compared to previous Autumn Sales.”</p>



<h2 id="h-all-2025-steam-sales-and-festivals">All 2025 Steam Sales and Festivals</h2>



<ul>
<li>Couch Co-Op Fest:&nbsp;February 10 – 17</li>



<li>Steam Next Fest – February 2025 Edition:&nbsp;February 24 – March 3</li>



<li>Visual Novel Fest:&nbsp;March 3 – 10</li>



<li>2025 Steam Spring Sale: March 13 – 20</li>



<li>City Builder &amp; Colony Sim Fest:&nbsp;March 24 – 31</li>



<li>Sokoban Fest:&nbsp;April 21 – 28</li>



<li>Wargames Fest:&nbsp;April 28 – May 5</li>



<li>Creature Collector Fest:&nbsp;May 12 – 19</li>



<li>Zombies vs. Vampires Fest:&nbsp;May 26 – June 2</li>



<li>Steam Next Fest – June 2025 Edition:&nbsp;June 9 – 16</li>



<li>Fishing Fest:&nbsp;June 16 – 23</li>



<li>Steam Summer Sale: June 26 – July 10</li>



<li>Automation Fest:&nbsp;July 14 – 21</li>



<li>Racing Fest:&nbsp;July 28 – August 4</li>



<li>4X Fest:&nbsp;August 11 – 18</li>



<li>Third Person Shooter (TPS) Fest:&nbsp;August 25 – September 1</li>



<li>Political Sim Fest:&nbsp;September 8 – 15</li>



<li>Steam Autumn Sale: September 29 – October 6&nbsp;</li>



<li>Steam Next Fest – October 2025 Edition:&nbsp;October 13 – 20</li>



<li>Steam Scream 4:&nbsp;October 27 – November 3</li>



<li>Animal Fest:&nbsp;November 10 – 17</li>



<li>Sports Fest:&nbsp;December 8 – December 15</li>



<li>Steam Winter Sale: December 18 – January 5</li>
</ul>



<p>Valve provided some insight on their scheduling via their 2025 second half announcement. The Fests are centered around “a rotating category of games,” with dates set well in advance for developers to have time to plan their participation. Back in 2021, Valve <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/groups/steamworks/announcements/detail/3002196778013479574" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote</a> that daily wishlist additions jumped 421% during the 2020 Next Fest, resulting in a an increase of 292% in “converting wishlists” sales. While gaming sales number in general were incredibly inflated during the first year of COVID, this still demonstrates how important Steam Sales and Fests are to selling games.</p>



<p>Which Steam Sale or Fest is of the most interest to you? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-preorders-in-line-with-odyssey/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin’s Creed Shadows preorder numbers</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-preorders-in-line-with-odyssey/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-preorders-in-line-with-odyssey/">Assassin’s Creed Shadows Preorders In Line With Odyssey</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to Ubisoft, Assassin’s Creed Shadows is having strong preorders, putting it in line with Assassin’s Creed Odyssey.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/maximum-football-updates-add-invite-multiplayer-and-multiple-new-features/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/maximum-football-updates-add-invite-multiplayer-and-multiple-new-features/">Maximum Football Updates Add Invite Multiplayer And Multiple New Features</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The latest Maximum Football updates have added a number of new features to the game, including invite multiplayer.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-receiving-yakuza-skins-soon-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-receiving-yakuza-skins-soon-its-claimed/">Fortnite is Receiving Yakuza Skins Soon, It’s Claimed&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to a new leak, Fortnite might receive Kazuma Kiryu and one more character from the Yakuza series. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-energy-supercross-25-release-date-announced/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/monster-energy-supercross-25-release-date-announced/">Monster Energy Supercross 25 Release Date Announced</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Milestone has announced the release date for Monster Energy Supercross 25, the first Supercross game in two years.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark Messiah of Might and Magic RTX Remix Mod Gets New Trailer; Online Co-Op Mod Now Available]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-rtx-remix-mod-gets-new-trailer-online-co-op-mod-now-available/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-rtx-remix-mod-gets-new-trailer-online-co-op-mod-now-available.1109013/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-rtx-remix-mod-gets-new-trailer-online-co-op-mod-now-available/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The cult classic Dark Messiah of Might and Magic is receiving a lot of attention in the modding community <a href="https://wccftech.com/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-modders-show-rtx-remix-upgrade-co-op-also-planned/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">thanks to wiltOS Technologies</a>, which is hard at work on three mods (plus a bonus one) to rejuvenate the 2006 game originally developed by Arkane and published by Ubisoft.</p>
<p>Firstly, there's the <a href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/dark-messiah-restoration-mod" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Restoration mod</a>, which brings back some cut content with the help of Ubisoft. The modders were provided with access to assets from Elements, the Xbox 360 version of the game. Thanks to this, the bonus missions and alternate levels that were featured in that version of the game can now be played on PC. Players can also experience The Caves, a cut level, and use cut weapons such as the Sword of Misery or the Necromancer's Staff.</p>
<p>WiltOS Technologies even introduced quality-of-life features such as the Bonus Maps system, which allows level loading without console commands, and a redesigned new game menu with chapter and class selection taken from the Elements. With the Bonus Maps menu, the madders also added a Challenge mode that uses the map add system.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Then there's the online co-op mod, which has just launched as a public test build downloadable <a href="https://github.com/KingDavidW/DarkMessiah-Coop-Mod-Files" target="_blank" rel="noopener">via GitHub</a>. This is still an early build, though, as evidenced by the fact that three major features are missing: the new player models, the refined revive mechanics, and the cutscenes.</p>
<p>Lastly, there's the Dark Messiah of Might and Magic graphics overhaul mod powered by NVIDIA RTX Remix. This mod just got a new trailer, which you can find embedded below.</p>
<p><iframe title="RTX Remix Project | Dark Messiah of Might and Magic | The City of Stonehelm" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kN347m66sgc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The team of asset makers for the RTX Remix mod has expanded from two to three, but these high-quality assets take a long time to complete. Because of that, wiltOS Technologies plans to first release a version with the original textures and the RTX Remix enhanced lighting and then slowly introduce the improved textures as they are ready.</p>
<p>The bonus mod mentioned earlier in the article is a proof-of-concept for random map generation based on certain rules. Called 'The Trials of Kha-Baleth', it's meant to be an unofficial continuation to the story that uses DungeonGen technology derived from Alien Swarm's TileGen technology. In addition, players have the option to simply start a randomized level or create their own campaign. You can follow the progress of this work <a href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/the-trials-of-kha-baleth" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on the dedicated page</a>.</p>
<p>Are you excited that Dark Messiah of Might and Magic is getting all this attention after nearly twenty years from its release?</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arcane Wonders Announces Onstage, A Trick-Taking Game About A Theater Troupe]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/arcane-wonders-announces-onstage-trick-taking-game-about-theater-troupe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arcane-wonders-announces-onstage-a-trick-taking-game-about-a-theater-troupe.1109010/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/arcane-wonders-announces-onstage-trick-taking-game-about-theater-troupe<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Arcane Wonders has announced a new board game is coming to GenCon. They have partnered with Rolling Wizards Games to produce <em>Onstage</em>, a trick-taking game that blends Vietnamese-inspired artwork with theater performances.</p>

<h2>The <em>Onstage</em> Board Game Announcement</h2>

<p>In an official press release, Arcane Wonders provides more details on the Onstage board game. Three to five players are part of a theater company competing for the best performers to join their troupe. It is a must-follow trick-taking game with a twist. The trump suit can (and often will) change mid-round, which will keep players on their toes. Each game takes 15-30 minutes to complete.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/onstage-board-game-set-up-artwork.jpg?itok=59QnLjls 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/onstage-board-game-set-up-artwork.jpg?itok=dr_PWMos 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>On top of this unique gameplay, Onstage features beautiful Vietnamese-inspired artwork. Everything from the cards to the meeples to the game's pop-up stage all showcases a distinct art style featuring rich pinks, greens, blues, and dark reds.</p>

<p><em>Onstage</em> is the latest board game to join the Dice Tower Essentials line. This is a list of prestigious board games curated and hand-picked by board game critic Tom Vasel. This list has included the English language release of the 90s nostalgia-fueled board game <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/video-game-champion-brings-retro-game-collecting-fun-to-gaming-tables" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Video Game Champion</em></a>, and Mitsuru Nakamura's cooperative number card game, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/ito-card-game-getting-western-localization" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Ito</em></a>.</p>

<p>Arcane Wonders has a similarly acclaimed body of work. Their past titles include the detective board game <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/sherlock-13-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Sherlock 13</em></a>, and the deep diving board game <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/aquatica-board-game-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Aquatica</em></a>. They also helped produce an officially licensed <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/call-of-duty-board-game-deploys-to-kickstarter-this-august" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Call of Duty</em> board game</a>. They partnered with Vasel in 2014 to expand its catalog with the curated Dice Tower Essentials line.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/onstage-stage-box-artwork.jpg?itok=EjXr1h7_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/onstage-stage-box-artwork.jpg?itok=SiY_l8z4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p><em>Onstage</em> is the second board game developed by Rolling Wizards Games. The Vietnam-based studio's first game, <em>Stem and Branch</em>, is a fast-paced card game based on animals and elements from the Eastern zodiac. Each game is represented as a 60-year calendar.</p>

<p>The game will be sold during GenCon 2025. At time of writing there is no word on a retail release or price.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Hope Every RPG Steals Avowed's Brilliant Inventory System]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/avowed-rpg-xbox-game-pass-inventory-review-skyrim-1851762830</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-hope-every-rpg-steals-avoweds-brilliant-inventory-system.1109004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/avowed-rpg-xbox-game-pass-inventory-review-skyrim-1851762830<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Obsidian’s latest RPG, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avowed-xbox-pc-rpg-game-pass-skyrim-review-kotaku-1851761525&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-xbox-pc-rpg-game-pass-skyrim-review-kotaku-1851761525"><em>Avowed</em></a></span>, is out now on Xbox and PC (f<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/paid-early-access-pre-order-madden-star-wars-outlaws-1851596675&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/paid-early-access-pre-order-madden-star-wars-outlaws-1851596675">or those who pre-ordered the expensive fancy version</a></span>) and it’s a really good game! But one key thing I wanted to highlight is the RPG’s inventory and item management system because it’s really good and I want more games to copy it.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196055" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="227" data-playlist="196055,196599,196029" data-current="196055"><div><p>6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21584.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Sure, I’ll freely admit that an RPG’s inventory system might not be the sexiest or coolest topic. But it is a very important part of any game that features loot, potions, food, weapons, and gear.</p><p>A bad inventory system can ruin a great game and make it a chore to play. Having to endlessly fiddle about with various bags or being forced to run back to a shop or town to offload crap isn’t my idea of fun. So I was happy to discover that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avowed-rpg-obsidian-hands-on-preview-xbox-pc-1851703825&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-rpg-obsidian-hands-on-preview-xbox-pc-1851703825"><em>Avowed</em></a></span><em> </em>avoids all that annoying busywork with its streamlined and smart inventory system. The result is a more enjoyable experience because you spend less time fussing about with 400 items and more time doing stuff you actually want to do in a big RPG. </p><figure id="" data-id="aa43aa999221dd18d33e6c22b884af59" data-recommend-id="image://aa43aa999221dd18d33e6c22b884af59" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="aa43aa999221dd18d33e6c22b884af59" data-recommend-id="image://aa43aa999221dd18d33e6c22b884af59" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Perhaps the biggest and smartest feature in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-avowed-rpg-tips-tricks-before-you-play-1851760887&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-avowed-rpg-tips-tricks-before-you-play-1851760887"><em>Avowed</em></a></span><em> </em>is the ability to instantly and easily transport items to your camp stash. Find a cool sword that doesn’t quite fit your current build, but you want to play around with it later? Send it back to camp with a single button press. Stumble upon some valuable armor that is really heavy and will make you overencumbered, but you want to sell it later?  Well, just hit a button and send it back to your camp. You can do this anywhere with no restrictions and it’s awesome. Does it make sense? No, but the fact that I can even hold 10 swords in the first place doesn’t make sense either, so who cares?</p><p>The thing is, though, you might not even need to use this feature all that much because a lot of loot you find in <em>Avowed </em>doesn’t weigh anything. Consumable items—foods, potions, lockpicks—don’t weight anything. Likewise, crafting and upgrade materials—iron, wood, furs—also weigh nothing. I never, in my 40 hours or so with <em>Avowed</em>, left a dungeon  desperate to sell stuff in order to free up some inventory space. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/starfield-overencumbered-contraband-ship-parts-how-to-1850815667?_gl=1*29yk13*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczOTQ2NjIwNS40NDMuMS4xNzM5NDY2ODM4LjU3LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/starfield-overencumbered-contraband-ship-parts-how-to-1850815667?_gl=1*29yk13*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczOTQ2NjIwNS40NDMuMS4xNzM5NDY2ODM4LjU3LjAuMA..">That’s a common occurrence in many RPGs</a></span>, but not <em>Avowed</em>. And even if you do pick up way too many swords and armor items, which <em>do</em> weigh you down, you can just teleport that stuff to camp.</p><p>But funnily enough, you often won’t even have to do  that because you can always break down any weapon or piece of gear you find at any time and get its resources. Then you can use those resources, which weigh nothing, to upgrade your equipped gear and make it better. It’s wonderful.</p><figure id="" data-id="cad8190ca65bfb41f76a32380ce16da7" data-recommend-id="image://cad8190ca65bfb41f76a32380ce16da7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="cad8190ca65bfb41f76a32380ce16da7" data-recommend-id="image://cad8190ca65bfb41f76a32380ce16da7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Some might argue that this is too convenient and easy. I disagree. I think Obsidian correctly realized that managing stacks of crappy swords and pieces of iron isn’t much fun, nor is it what people want out of a roleplaying game. I want to fight monsters, meet new characters, explore strange lands and save the day. And <em>Avowed </em>focuses on all that stuff and doesn’t let inventory management get in the way.</p><p> I think more games should do that. Figure out what you want your game to be and the experience you want players to have while playing it. Then, once you understand that, cut anything that doesn’t help achieve that desired experience. Ultimately, sorting through forty pieces of iron isn’t why people play games like <em>Avowed</em>, so why make them do it?</p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA College Football 26 Could Offer Bigger Payouts To Players]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-college-football-26-could-offer-bigger-payouts-to-players/1100-6529500/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-college-football-26-could-offer-bigger-payouts-to-players.1108995/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-college-football-26-could-offer-bigger-payouts-to-players/1100-6529500/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529500">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Earlier this year, EA officially announced that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-26-announced-launches-this-summer/1100-6528861/" data-ref-id="1100-6528861">EA College Football 26 was in development</a> for release this summer. Last year, EA offered high-profile college football players $600 each for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-offering-college-athletes-600-to-appear-in-new-football-game/1100-6521289/" data-ref-id="1100-6521289">the right to use their names, images, and likenesses</a> in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/ea-sports-college-football-25-review-university-of-madden/1900-6418261/" data-ref-id="1900-6418261">EA College Football 25</a>. But if a new sports representative company is successful, EA may have to pay a significantly higher amount to include those players in EA College Football 26.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://sports.yahoo.com/college-football-players-sign-agreement-to-be-paid-for-likeness-in-video-games-134529715.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yahoo Sports</a>, Pathway Sports and Entertainment is making aggressive inroads by pursuing the elite players in college football. The company has offered players $1,500 upfront for their NIL (Name, Image, Likeness) rights in addition to royalty pay that has yet to be fleshed out. Over 450 students at Alabama, Illinois, Georgia, Texas Tech, Wisconsin, and Oregon have already taken the deal, and Pathway has even grander ambitions.</p><p>Pathway is currently sending representatives to colleges across the nation with the desire to sign every football player who is on a scholarship program. There are approximately 11,000 players who have scholarships, and it would take more than $17 million to sign them all at the currently offered rate. However, the report suggests that the total payout may exceed $20 million when factoring in "ambassador payments" for certain students.</p><p>"The overall vision is for athletes to make more money than we saw in the first year of the video game," said Pathway co-founder Casey Schwab in a statement. "We are creating mutual value here. This is a good thing for athletic directors, coaches, and schools because they are trying to create legit opportunities for their players. These are legitimate."</p><p>EA doesn't have any involvement with Pathway at this point. But if Pathway can sign up all or most of the athletes that EA wants to get for EA College Football 26, then the video game publisher will either have to agree to a new deal or go without the star players who helped make the franchise into one of EA Sports' top-sellers. </p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>