<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:56:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suicide Squad left a $200 million hole in WBD’s video game division]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/6/24172905/suicide-squad-kill-justice-league-200-million-loss-wbd-rocksteady</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/suicide-squad-left-a-200-million-hole-in-wbd%E2%80%99s-video-game-division.891636/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/6/24172905/suicide-squad-kill-justice-league-200-million-loss-wbd-rocksteady<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Warner Bros. Discovery took a $200 million hit after the launch of <em>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice</em> <em>League</em>, the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24062243/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-review-ps5-xbox-pc">troubled looter shooter</a> released in February — and now we have a sense of what went wrong. A new <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-06-06/-suicide-squad-warner-bros-s-200-million-flop-haunts-the-gaming-industry">report from <em>Bloomberg</em></a> details some of the studio’s struggles behind the scenes, including inexperience with the multiplayer genre and a “constantly changing vision.”</p><p>Rocksteady, the UK-based studio owned by Warner Bros. Discovery, was tasked with developing a <em>Suicide Squad</em> game in 2016. At this time, new Rocksteady employees were reportedly unaware that the studio was developing a multiplayer game, as Rocksteady is known for its single-player action-adventure games like <em>Batman: Arkham Knight</em>. This caused many employees to leave, <em>Bloomberg</em> reports.</p><p>The game’s development didn’t go smoothly. Rocksteady’s leaders kept changing their ideas for the game, turning their focus from melee combat to heavy gunplay, <em>Bloomberg </em>reports. The studio struggled with making its battles, levels, and bosses feel less repetitive — one of the biggest issues for live-service titles, where players are asked to retread large parts of the game. The studio also wasn’t accustomed to the level of complexity required to develop such a massive map and the four playable characters, according to <em>Bloomberg</em>.</p><p>Rocksteady co-founders Sefton Hill and Jamie Walker <a href="https://www.rocksteadyltd.com/news/letter/">left the studio in 2022</a> to start a new endeavor, with continued setbacks like this pushing the game’s release date until this year. Warner Bros. Discovery revealed the game’s $200 million loss during the company’s earnings call in May, with CEO David Zaslav calling its release “disappointing.”</p><p>Financial pressure in the gaming industry only continues to mount as studios contend with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24009039/video-game-layoffs-2023">layoffs affecting thousands of workers</a>. Some major studios have <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24172733/summer-game-fest-video-game-announcements-layoffs-labor-live-service-fortnite">turned to live-service games</a>, like <em>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League</em>, in an attempt to strike a constant source of revenue. But in Warner Bros. Discovery’s case, this backfired. According to <em>Bloomberg</em>, Rocksteady has now turned its attention to a director’s cut version of <em>Hogwarts Legacy</em> and may even start working on another single-player game. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The next Helldivers 2 Warbond has new rewards — and some big changes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24172932/helldivers-2-viper-commandos-warbond-announcement</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-next-helldivers-2-warbond-has-new-rewards-%E2%80%94-and-some-big-changes.891633/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24172932/helldivers-2-viper-commandos-warbond-announcement<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="Au91OD">A new Warbond is on the way to <a href="https://www.polygon.com/gaming/24071317/helldivers-2-starship-troopers-video-game-great"><em>Helldivers 2</em></a>, and it’s the first step in Arrowhead shaking up the game’s update schedule. The Viper Commandos Warbond is themed after jungle combat — camo prints, red berets, bare arms, throwing knives, skull masks, and everything else you can equip while CCR’s “Fortunate Son” blasts over a speaker nearby.</p>
<p id="M4R79T">Warbonds can be unlocked with 1000 Super Credits, which can be purchased with real money or collected around minor points of interest on the map. Fans have criticized Warbonds for coming a little too frequently without enough unique items to justify them, and the Viper Commandos Warbond takes that feedback into account.</p>
<p id="0xFNRz">“Based on player input, we’re changing our approach to Warbonds moving forward in a couple of ways,” <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/06/06/helldivers-ii-enlists-the-viper-commandos-warbond-on-june-13/">wrote community manager Katherine Baskin on the official Sony site</a>. “Firstly, we’re slowing down the pace at which we release Warbonds to give us a little bit more time to polish these designs before they’re released. Secondly, we are changing the arrangement of items in each Warbond to make room for new item types. It’s time to focus on quality over quantity.”</p>
<div id="M1nw9x"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jbb5ngK36x4?rel=0" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="7Tw1aT">Players can unlock a new Liberator Carbine, designed for close quarters combat, as well as a new secondary weapon that packs a lot of punch in the SG-22 Bushwhacker triple-barrel sawed off shotgun. The PH-9 Predator armor is a clear reference to, well, <em>Predator</em> — and I’m tempted to unlock it just for the cute beret. For those who prefer heavy armor, the PH-202 Twigsnapper keeps similar aesthetics with a little more protection. Both armors feature bare arms and a new Peak Physique passive, which improves melee damage and weapon handling.</p>
<p id="JwtaMj">The most exciting weapon is a new utility item: a throwing knife. I’m not sure if throwing knives will pack the same punch as shotguns and orbital lasers, but it definitely scores points for being cool and stylish.</p>
<p id="1nWRyY">The Viper Commandos Warbond also features camo skins for the hellpods, Exosuits, and Pelican-1. It should be nice to be able to customize these things, adding a certain panache to the otherwise plain-looking mech suits and hellpods. A new booster, Experimental Infusion, makes stims even more of a life-saver by giving injections a boost to movement speed and damage reduction.</p>
<p id="Lqub3P">The Warbond also comes with the typical rewards of capes, player cards, and emotes.</p>
<p id="rP57DP">It’s interesting to see Arrowhead shake things up. There are some big narrative happenings right now, since players <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24170825/helldivers-2-meridia-system-major-order-black-hole">turned the super colony of Meridia into an ominous black hole</a>. If things escalate further, at least we’ll have these fun new toys to throw at our alien enemies. The Viper Commandos Warbond will release on all platforms on June 13. </p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If You've Got Game Pass, Please, You Have To Play This Wonderful RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-2-xbox-game-pass-rpg-1851523842</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/if-youve-got-game-pass-please-you-have-to-play-this-wonderful-rpg.891630/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-2-xbox-game-pass-rpg-1851523842<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In an age when so many new games are trying to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-ps1-retro-fps-nightmare-decay-horror-cree-1848907596&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-ps1-retro-fps-nightmare-decay-horror-cree-1848907596">recapture the greatness of old classics</a></span>, it’s hard to find the ones that actually live up to their inspirations. For RPG enjoyers it’s often about finding something as good as the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/japanese-games-jrpg-final-fantasy-castlevania-1850228235&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/japanese-games-jrpg-final-fantasy-castlevania-1850228235">90’s era</a></span> of Square Enix’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/best-final-fantasy-games-rpg-7-6-10-12-square-enix-ff-1850560934&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/best-final-fantasy-games-rpg-7-6-10-12-square-enix-ff-1850560934"><em>Final Fantasy</em> series</a></span>. However, in that case, the best imitation of those classics comes from none other than Square Enix itself in the form of the <em>Octopath Traveler</em> games. Now with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-xbox-game-pass-ps4-ps5-1851520559&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-xbox-game-pass-ps4-ps5-1851520559"><em>Octopath Traveler II</em> on Xbox Game Pass</a></span>, subscribers have no excuse not to play one of the best retro-inspired RPGs out there.<br></p><div data-video-id="196055" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="227" data-playlist="196055,196599,196411" data-current="196055"><div><p>6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21584.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-ii-impressions-rpg-partitio-osvald-1850179725&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-ii-impressions-rpg-partitio-osvald-1850179725"><em>Octopath Traveler II</em></a></span> is an expansive turn-based RPG with a fascinating cast of characters and world to explore. It almost feels like a game from an alternate timeline where Square Enix never progressed past the mechanics and visuals of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-vi-retrospective-simply-the-best-1792398695&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-vi-retrospective-simply-the-best-1792398695"><em>Final Fantasy VI</em></a></span> and just refined that formula, producing <em>Octopath Traveler II</em>. And to get it out of the way, no, you don’t need to play the first <em>Octopath Traveler</em>. You shouldn’t, despite it also being available on Xbox Game Pass. It’s not that it’s a bad game, it’s just that <em>Octopath Traveler II</em> is a more refined title that improves upon its predecessor in every way.</p><figure id="" data-id="8541303344c4ccd974785cf7c1e95002" data-recommend-id="image://8541303344c4ccd974785cf7c1e95002" data-format="jpg" data-width="1024" data-height="576" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Partitio saying &quot;*sniff* Mmm, the scent of commerce! I can smell it on the wind!&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Partitio saying &quot;*sniff* Mmm, the scent of commerce! I can smell it on the wind!&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8541303344c4ccd974785cf7c1e95002" data-recommend-id="image://8541303344c4ccd974785cf7c1e95002" data-format="jpg" data-width="1024" data-height="576" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Partitio saying &quot;*sniff* Mmm, the scent of commerce! I can smell it on the wind!&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The basic set-up is that you’re presented with a map of the game’s world, Solistia, which spans two major continents divided by a large ocean, with eight different characters placed on it (hence the “Octo” in the title). You choose one to begin the game as and quickly start unraveling each party member’s story till they eventually intertwine into a grand web.<br></p><p>Each of the eight protagonists falls into a traditional archetype defined by their job. There is Throne the thief, Agnea the dancer, Hikari the warrior, and on and on. Each one’s job defines the tone of their narrative, with Throne’s, for instance, involving heists, betrayal, and revenge in Solistia’s crime world. The ability to swap between characters and pursue their narratives however you see fit leads to a wonderful balance. Some stories may be emotionally and mechanically intensive, but you can always follow it up with something silly, such as Agnea’s charming journey to become a famous performer in the big city. All these clashing tones meld together remarkably well and evoke the tonal shifts of classic <em>Final Fantasy</em> adventures.</p><p>The job archetypes of each character also inform their mechanical abilities. Inside of combat, each character will have special attacks and skills you’d expect for a thief, a mage or whatever that character’s job happens to be. The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lets-analyze-a-typical-octopath-traveler-battle-1827526170&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lets-analyze-a-typical-octopath-traveler-battle-1827526170">turn-based system</a></span> of <em>Octopath Traveler II </em>is so much deeper than those in competing retro-inspired RPGs in recent memory (I’m looking at you,<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sea-of-stars-game-impressions-review-switch-jrpg-indie-1850854165&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sea-of-stars-game-impressions-review-switch-jrpg-indie-1850854165"><em>Sea of Stars</em></a></span>) and feels like the best evolution of the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/make-my-battles-active-time-5970349&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/make-my-battles-active-time-5970349">Active Time Battle system</a></span> I’ve ever played. It revolves around two specific features, boosting and breaking. Combat occurs in a turn order represented on the screen. By attacking an enemy’s weakness, they can be broken, pushing them to the back of the turn order. You can also use special attacks called boosts which can be done by spending boost points that accrue every turn. This boost and break system turns into a strategic game of knowing when to build up your boost and when to unleash a strong attack in tandem with breaking the enemy to keep them from attacking as much as possible. This is best shown off during the game’s intense boss battles that require you to be at your best at all times.</p><figure id="" data-id="0aba61d68a033e3444073403b9ff9ca8" data-recommend-id="image://0aba61d68a033e3444073403b9ff9ca8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1024" data-height="576" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A hunter breaks an enemy in combat " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A hunter breaks an enemy in combat " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0aba61d68a033e3444073403b9ff9ca8" data-recommend-id="image://0aba61d68a033e3444073403b9ff9ca8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1024" data-height="576" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A hunter breaks an enemy in combat " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>But the unique twist of <em>Octopath Traveler II </em>is that you can also use skills outside of combat. Many of the game’s quests require you to complete mechanical puzzles only specific characters can solve. That might involve using Throne’s steal ability to lift a key, or Hikari’s combat prowess to knock out guards and sneak past. With a day and night cycle, <em>Octopath Traveler II</em> also gives each character different skills for different times of day, so players need to experiment with not just their party makeup but also the time of day to solve specific problems.<br></p><p>As a vast, dozens-of-hours-long, retro-inspired RPG, there is a lot to see and get lost in while playing <em>Octopath Traveler II</em>. It’s a game best enjoyed at your own pace, which is why it’s so nice that the story is separated into chapters that are each just an hour or two long. All the while, the game’s gorgeous <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/live-a-live-switch-square-enix-dragon-quest-jrpg-1849341082&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/live-a-live-switch-square-enix-dragon-quest-jrpg-1849341082">HD-2D</a></span> visuals and phenomenal score are there to give your eyes and ears a feast. As far as nostalgia plays in gaming go, this is one of the finest.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Getting New Game Plus Would 'Break the Way the Game Is Constructed,' CD Projekt Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-getting-new-game-plus-would-break-the-way-the-game-is-constructed-cd-projekt-says</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-getting-new-game-plus-would-break-the-way-the-game-is-constructed-cd-projekt-says.891627/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-getting-new-game-plus-would-break-the-way-the-game-is-constructed-cd-projekt-says<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a> never received a New Game Plus mode like CD Projekt's predecessor The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt because it would "break the way the game is constructed."</p><p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.dualshockers.com/cyberpunk-2077-dev-explains-lack-of-new-game-plus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DualShockers</a>, Cyberpunk 2077 quest director and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-quest-director-emotional-about-resurgence">its sequel's associate game director Paweł Sasko</a> gave a somewhat vague explanation for why the now beloved role-playing game didn't receive New Game Plus in its more than three years of updates.</p><p>"For us, it’s really important that when you have components in a game, they all work together and they all work well and they all make sense," Sasko said. "The thing is, Cyberpunk is very specific when it comes to its construction.</p><p>"It’s incredibly difficult to figure out a way where New Game Plus could be done in a way that doesn’t completely break the way the game is constructed."</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>"It’s incredibly difficult to figure out a way where New Game Plus could be done in a way that doesn’t completely break the way the game is constructed.</p></div><p>Sasko referenced Bethesda's latest RPG <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/starfield-review">Starfield</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/starfields-new-game-plus-is-its-most-intriguing-concept-if-you-get-lucky">its New Game Plus system</a>, which actually ties into the overall story and has a logical explanation for how and why the entire world is resetting, and seemed to suggest this was the only option for incorporating the New Game Plus mechanic.</p><p>He didn't address why Cyberpunk 2077 couldn't have a more traditional means of New Game Plus, however, that simply sees the player restart the story while keeping abilities or experience. This is how <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2015/05/12/the-witcher-3-the-wild-hunt-review">The Witcher 3's</a> version of the system worked, as it had no story connection or explanation for the reset whatsoever and just allowed players to experience the game again with a few extras.</p><p>Sasko even admitted Cyberpunk 2077 was designed to be replayed, which would suggest this style of New Game Plus would work well.</p><p>"It’s to be replayed. It’s to try different life paths, try different romances, try different builds," he said. "There’s so many things that you can at least, twice or three times, have a very varied experience in 2077. So this is another answer, the game was built to be replayed that way."</p><p>Fans still holding out hope for a New Game Plus mode shouldn't hold their breath, as CD Projekt announced <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/finally-35-years-after-launch-no-one-is-working-on-cyberpunk-2077-at-cd-projekt">there is no longer a dedicated Cyberpunk 2077 team</a> working at the studio as employees instead <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-gets-last-big-update-tomorrow-as-cd-projekt-moves-on-to-cyberpunk-2-witcher-4">turned their attention to its sequel</a> and, predominantly, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nearly-half-of-cd-projekt-now-working-on-the-witcher-4">the next Witcher game</a>.</p><p>That's not to say it won't receive any support in the future, however, as CD Projekt confirmed to IGN that <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-will-get-fsr3-support-at-some-point">Cyberpunk 2077 will still get the long promised FidelityFX Super Resolution 3 (FSR3) support</a> at some point.</p><p>Development was wound down after the release of its first and only expansion, Phantom Liberty, in September 2023. It came after the game-changing Update 2.0, which <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/cyberpunk-2077/All_Cyberpunk_2077_2.0_Updates_and_Changes">completely revamped Cyberpunk 2077 with features such as a new perk system and improved AI</a>, and was followed by <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-update-21-patch-notes-include-metro-system-romantic-hangouts-and-new-vehicles">another big update in 2.1</a> but only minor changes afterwards.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-review">In our 9/10 review</a>, IGN said: "Cyberpunk 2077 throws you into a beautiful, dense cityscape and offers a staggering amount of flexibility in how you choose to take it from there."</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Alters: 14 Minutes of Exclusive Gameplay from the Upcoming Demo - IGN First]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-alters-14-minutes-of-exclusive-gameplay-from-the-upcoming-demo-ign-first</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-alters-14-minutes-of-exclusive-gameplay-from-the-upcoming-demo-ign-first.891621/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-alters-14-minutes-of-exclusive-gameplay-from-the-upcoming-demo-ign-first<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">An appetizer for the upcoming demo you can play for yourself.</h2></div><section><p>Yesterday, we exclusively announced that developer 11 Bit Studios will soon be dropping a playable demo of The Alters, the team's alluring and unique new survival game. Today you can check out 14 minutes of gameplay from that demo in the video above, and then play the demo for yourself on Steam on June 10 until June 17. </p><p>So what is The Alters? Well, we encourage you to watch our recent hands-on preview below, but in short, you play as Jans. But not just one Jans. Lots of Jans. See, you're a miner on a hostile planet who must pull in versions of yourself from other realities in order to survive. But they're not mere clones. Rather, they're you but they've lived their own completely unique lives, and as such they'll bring different looks, skills, and personalities to your tall task at hand. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Enjoy that demo gameplay video at the top of this page, and be sure to check back all June long for lots more coverage of The Alters as our June IGN First "cover story"! Check out more of The Alters on their <a href="https://re.11bits.com/chi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam page</a>.</p><p><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Killing Time: Resurrected announced for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/killing-time-resurrected-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/killing-time-resurrected-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc.891618/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/killing-time-resurrected-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Companies > Nightdive Studios [46 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/atari/nightdive-studios">Nightdive Studios</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Killing Time: Resurrected" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/killing-time-resurrected">Killing Time: Resurrected</a></em>, a remastered version of the 1995-released <a title="Genres > Horror [420 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,471 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a>. It will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,153 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,424 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,753 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,199 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,407 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,247 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1733170/Killing_Time_Resurrected" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, GOG, and Humble Store in 2024. <span id="more-887908"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Nightdive Studios:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Killing Time: Resurrected</em> is a high-definition edition of the humorous horror <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,781 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> once described as “the bastard child of <em>DOOM</em> and <em>The 7th Guest</em>.”</p><p>Nightdive Studios and <a title="Companies > Ziggurat Interactive [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ziggurat-interactive">Ziggurat Interactive</a> will bring this sophisticated shooter laced with gallows humor and visual violence back to bestow mayhem.</p><p>The original <em>Killing Time</em> quickly became a smash hit among fans of <a title="Genres > Action [1,875 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>, <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,513 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>, mystery, and puzzle games when it was released in 1995. <em>Killing Time: Resurrected</em> features toggleable high-resolution character artwork/<a title="Companies > sprite [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sprite">sprite</a>s from the original 3DO and PC versions of the game, upscaled environmental texturing, smoother gameplay, more responsive controls, and expanded control and key-bind settings.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Set in the early 1930s, <em>Killing Time</em> casts players as a former Egyptology student trapped in the estate of wealthy heiress Tess Conway. Ms. Conway’s ritual to bestow eternal life backfires, and her high-society friends vanish without a trace. It’s up to players to find and destroy the mystical Egyptian Water-Clock to undo its curse and face a legion of supernatural horrors.</p></blockquote><!-- zp_shiv error: no images in gallery! --><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Murder Around Every Corner</strong> – A fright-fest for the true aficionado of first-person corridor mayhem.</li><li><strong>Ghost Stories</strong> – Listen to the remembrances of the seven video-real apparitions and ghostly guests. They offer clues as to what past heinous acts actually transpired in the cursed mansion.</li><li><strong>Stunning Graphics</strong> – Look up and down and turn around with a complete 360-degree view. The three-dimensional mansion offers outdoor areas, staircases, and intricately detailed ceilings and floors.</li><li><strong>Keep Your Guard Up!</strong> – The original music makes this old haunt strongly inviting, eh? But beware. Every room, every passage in the estate holds dreadful dangers.</li><li><strong>Max Efficiency</strong> – Enjoy continuous gameplay with no load time between areas.</li><li><strong>Updated Controls</strong> – Redesigned controls to support <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [45,171 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox [24,127 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> gamepads.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/killing-time-resurrected/june-6-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Killing Time: Resurrected - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d9wRBAunbz0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Volgarr the Viking II announced for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/volgarr-the-viking-ii-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/volgarr-the-viking-ii-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc.891615/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/volgarr-the-viking-ii-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Digital Eclipse [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/digital-eclipse">Digital Eclipse</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Crazy Viking Studios" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crazy-viking-studios">Crazy Viking Studios</a> have announced <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [668 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> <a title="Genres > Action [1,875 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Volgarr the Viking II [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/volgarr-the-viking-ii">Volgarr the Viking II</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,153 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,424 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,753 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,199 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,407 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,247 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2195140/Volgarr_the_Viking_II/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/volgarr_the_viking_ii" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GOG</a>). It will launch on August 6. <span id="more-886683"></span></p><p>“One of our key pillars is making new games the old-fashioned way,” said Digital Eclipse head Mike Mika in a press release. “We love and celebrate games where every pixel is hand-crafted. <em>Volgarr</em> was one of those games we couldn’t put down, no matter how hard it was. Games like this are a rare breed, and we’re happy to play a role in seeing <em>Volgarr II</em> realized.”</p><p>Crazy Viking Studios CEO and creative director Kristofor Durrschmidt added, “<em>Volgarr</em> is known for being easy to learn, hard to master. For some, that might even be an understatement. But that design philosophy guided every aspect of development for <em>Volgarr II</em>. We learned a lot from launching the original, and even with some modern updates, fans are going to love the sequel. <em>Volgarr</em> is still a game where, if you want the ultimate experience, you’ll need to really master what it asks of you.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Digital Eclipse:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>More than a decade after <em>Volgarr the Viking</em>‘s bloodbath of a debut from Crazy Viking Studios, which sold more than one million copies across PC and consoles, the barbarian king’s <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,513 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> continues in an uncompromising new form. Set against the backdrop of new and bigger-than-ever Norse-inspired worlds, <em>Volgarr the Viking II</em> ups the ante on the original’s hardcore 2D side-scrolling action in an expanded odyssey where every playthrough is grislier than the last.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The reveal trailer teases a selection of levels and enemy encounters, underscoring just how many times you’ll die (and die again)—all while progressively learning and mastering movesets, level layouts, and enemy attacks. <em>Volgarr the Viking II</em>‘s satisfyingly punishing torment will forge you into a true warrior, demanding precision, strategy, and an indomitable spirit to conquer the unforgiving world.</p><p>As the great warrior Volgarr, choose your actions wisely when entering battle, as precision is everything. One false move can spell a one-way ticket to Valhalla. Jump, duck, slide, and dodge to avoid deadly enemies while remaining cognizant of the threats posed by your environment.</p><p>While the sequel delivers the same unforgiving 1980s-arcade level of difficulty as the original, Volgarr’s a little older now, his muscles have wizened, and he graciously welcomes some new features that won’t agitate the arthritis: a practice mode, checkpoints, save profiles, and unlimited continues—but at what cost? If you can survive without these modern comforts, you’ll unlock everything the game has to offer. If not… death comes knocking.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_886710"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features Include:</strong></p><ul><li>Stave off death with new power-ups and magic items.</li><li>A roster of ruthless bosses so big and so ugly, they’re just begging to have their heads chopped off.</li><li>An epic orchestral soundtrack to carry you through battle.</li><li>Handy speedrunning tools, including an on-screen timer and no-HUD mode.</li><li>Six distinct endings based on player performance—only the masterfully skilled will unlock a hidden level to battle a secret final boss!</li><li>Modern era upgrades include a practice mode and multiple profile save options.</li><li>Buckets of blood and bone explosions.</li><li>Loincloths.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/volgarr-the-viking-ii/june-6-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Volgarr the Viking II - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sfu8hBI5aDc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yooka-Laylee remake Yooka-Replaylee announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/yooka-laylee-remake-yooka-replaylee-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yooka-laylee-remake-yooka-replaylee-announced-for-pc.891609/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/yooka-laylee-remake-yooka-replaylee-announced-for-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>New art, animations, challenges, secrets, mechanics, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Playtonic Games [45 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playtonic-games">Playtonic Games</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > Yooka-Replaylee" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/yooka-replaylee">Yooka-Replaylee</a></em>, a remastered and enhanced version of the 2017-released collectathon <a title="Genres > Platformer [446 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em>Yooka-Laylee</em> for consoles and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,247 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2448020/YookaReplaylee/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>). Specific consoles and a release date were not announced. <span id="more-887702"></span></p><p>Get the first details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Meet the definitive remastered and enhanced version of the 3D indie platforming collectathon darling, <em>Yooka-Laylee</em> (2017), with the same key creative talent behind the <em>Banjo-Kazooie</em> and <em>Donkey Kong Country</em> games at the helm and self-published by <a title="Companies > Playtonic Friends [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playtonic-games/playtonic-friends">Playtonic Friends</a>.</p><p>Marking the culmination of almost 10 years of Playtonic <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> along with an exciting new beginning for our favorite buddy-duo, <em>Yooka-Replaylee</em> is the result of the growth of the company, the things we have learned while working on other projects as well as the feedback we have taken on board since the original release. Experience the wacky colorful adventure of Yooka and Laylee with an art and animations overhaul, all new challenges, secrets, mechanics, and accessibility options! Our favorite buddy duo has never looked or moved better!</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_887730"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><!-- AD: content -->
        <blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>More Beautiful Than Ever</strong> – With an art and animations overhaul and enhanced performance and resolution, the favorite buddy duo has never looked or moved better.</li><li><strong>New and Improved Challenges</strong> – Improvements to existing in-game challenges and many entirely new challenges to discover and undertake!</li><li><strong>New Collectible Currency</strong> – Capital B’s inept minions have dropped their hard-earned coins all over the place. Collect the official currency of the Hivory Towers to spend on video games’ most beloved sentient vending machine.</li><li><strong>Navigating the World</strong> – Now you can get lost in the game, not in the world! A brand-new world map and challenges tracker helps you know where you are and what needs to be done. Hooray!</li><li><strong>Vendi Has Plenty to Offer</strong> – Tonics are back with all new flavors! With the option to equip multiple game-changing enhancements, you can truly customize your playstyle. And as if that wasn’t enough, Vendi has new lines of merchandise for the modern fashionable <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,513 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>r.</li><li><strong>Revised Controls and Camera</strong> – A new tweaked move set allows you to combine moves more fluidly while the new camera controls makes framing the <a title="Genres > Action [1,875 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> a breeze.</li><li><strong>A Dreamy Orchestral Soundtrack</strong> – The original score from famed video game composers Grant Kirkhope (<em>Banjo-Kazooie</em>) and David Wise (<em>Donkey Kong Country</em>) returns but as a beautifully arranged orchestral score. Now seriously, clean out those ears.</li></ul><p><strong>Upcoming Q&amp;A <a title="Games > Session: Skate Sim [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/session-skate-sim">Session</a> with the Founders!</strong></p><p>Join us on Tuesday, June 11 for a sit-down Q&amp;A session between our senior community manager, Steve James, and some of the company founders to answer all your burning questions about <em>Yooka-Replaylee</em> and Playtonic. Be sure to follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/PlaytonicGames" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/playtonicgames" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@PlaytonicGamesltd" rel="noopener" target="_blank">YouTube</a> to be notified of the specific time!</p><p><strong>More to Come</strong></p><p>We hope you are as excited for more of Yooka and Laylee as we are! We’ll have lots more exciting announcements and updates to share about the project very soon, so stay tuned!</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/yooka-replaylee/june-6-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Yooka-Replaylee! | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hrXXbkP5HAc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony removes still-unmet “8K” promise from PS5 packaging]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2029499</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-removes-still-unmet-%E2%80%9C8k%E2%80%9D-promise-from-ps5-packaging.891606/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/?p=2029499<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <h4>
      8K? We never said 8K!    —
</h4>
            
            <h2 itemprop="description">Move could presage an expected resolution bump in the rumored PS5 Pro.</h2>
                    </div><div itemprop="articleBody">
                                    
  




<!-- cache hit 341:single/related:7ca6b384bebded945f772ccc2cac6789 --><!-- empty -->
  <div>
    <ul>
              <li data-thumb="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/ps5no8k-150x150.png" data-src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/ps5no8k.png" data-responsive="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/ps5no8k.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/ps5no8k.png 2560" data-sub-html="#caption-2029502">
          <figure>
            
                          <figcaption id="caption-2029502">
                <span></span>
                                  <p>
                    The new PS5 packaging, as seen on the PlayStation Direct online store, is missing the "8K" label in the corner.                  </p>
                                                  
                              </figcaption>
                      </figure>
        </li>
              <li data-thumb="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/ps58k-150x150.png" data-src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/ps58k.png" data-responsive="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/ps58k-980x980.png 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/ps58k.png 2560" data-sub-html="#caption-2029501">
          <figure>
            
                          <figcaption id="caption-2029501">
                <span></span>
                                  <p>
                    The original PS5 packaging with the 8K label, as still seen on the GameStop website.                  </p>
                                              </figcaption>
                      </figure>
        </li>
          </ul>
  </div>

<p>When we first received our PlayStation 5 review unit from Sony in 2020, we reacted with some bemusement to the "8K" logo on the box and its implied promise of full 7630×4320 resolution output. We then promptly forgot all about it since native 8K content <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1294400/8k-tv-shipments-worldwide/">and 8K compatible TVs</a> have remained a relative curiosity thus far in the PS5's lifespan.</p>
<p>But on Wednesday, Digital Foundry's John Linneman discovered that Sony has quietly removed that longstanding 8K label from the PS5 box. The ultra-high-resolution promise no longer appears on <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/buy-consoles/playstation5-console-model-group-slim">the packaging shown on Sony's official PlayStation Direct store</a>, a change that appears to have happened between <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20240121065345/https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/buy-consoles/playstation5-console-model-group-slim">late January</a> and <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20240220195209/https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/buy-consoles/playstation5-console-model-group-slim">mid-February</a>, according to Internet Archive captures of the store page (the old "8K" box can still be seen at <a href="https://www.gamestop.com/consoles-hardware/playstation-5/consoles/products/sony-playstation-5-console/11108140.html">other online retailers</a>, though).</p>
<h2>A promise deferred</h2>
<p>This packaging change has been a long time coming since the PS5 hasn't technically been living up to its 8K promise for years now. While Sony's Mark Cerny mentioned the then-upcoming hardware's 8K support <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2019/04/sonys-ps4-successor-sports-3d-audio-tech-faster-ssd-storage/">in a 2019 interview</a>, the system eventually launched with a pretty big "coming soon" caveat for that feature. "PS5 is compatible with 8K displays at launch, and after a future system software update will be able to output resolutions up to 8K when content is available, with supported software," the company <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2020/11/09/ps5-the-ultimate-faq/">said in an FAQ</a> surrounding the console's 2020 launch.</p>                                            
                                                        
<p>Well over three years later, that 8K-enabling software update has yet to appear, meaning the console's <em>technical</em> ability to push 8K graphics is still a <em>practical</em> impossibility for users. Until Sony's long-promised software patch hits, even PS5 games that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2021-the-touryst-8k-60fps-on-ps5">render frames internally at a full 8K resolution</a> are still pushing out a downscaled 4K framebuffer through that HDMI 2.1 cable.</p>
<figure><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/ppl.jpg" data-height="647" data-width="1200" alt="A slide from TV manufacturer TCL guesses at some details for the next micro-generation of high-end game consoles."></a><figcaption><p><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/ppl.jpg" data-height="647" data-width="1200">Enlarge</a> <span>/</span> A slide from TV manufacturer TCL guesses at some details for the next micro-generation of high-end game consoles.</p></figcaption></figure>
<p>At this point, though, there's some reason to expect that the promised patch may never come to the standard PS5. At the moment, the ever-churning rumor mill is expecting <a href="https://www.tomsguide.com/gaming/new-ps5-pro-rumors-point-to-a-monster-8k-gaming-console">an impending mid-generation PS5 Pro upgrade</a> that could offer true, native 8K resolution support right out of the box. If that comes to pass, removing the outdated "8K" promise from the original PS5 packaging could be a subtle way to highlight the additional power of the upcoming "Pro" upgrade.</p>
<figure><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/8k4k.jpg" data-height="735" data-width="2000" alt="A slight majority of participants in a double-blind study saw no discernible difference between a 4K and 8K image video clips."></a><figcaption><p><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/8k4k.jpg" data-height="735" data-width="2000">Enlarge</a> <span>/</span> A slight majority of participants in a double-blind study saw no discernible difference between a 4K and 8K image video clips.</p></figcaption></figure>
<p>So will console gamers be missing out if they don't upgrade to an 8K-compatible display? Probably not, as <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2022/05/does-the-world-really-need-8k-resolution-game-consoles/">studies show extremely diminishing returns</a> in the perceived quality jump from 4K to 8K visual content for most users and living room setups. Unless you are sitting extremely close to an extremely large display, it's pretty unlikely you'll even be able to tell the difference.

                                                </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny's First Behind-The-Scenes Art Book In Seven Years Releases This Holiday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destinys-first-behind-the-scenes-art-book-in-seven-years-releases-this-holiday/1100-6523978/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destinys-first-behind-the-scenes-art-book-in-seven-years-releases-this-holiday.891600/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destinys-first-behind-the-scenes-art-book-in-seven-years-releases-this-holiday/1100-6523978/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523978">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Destiny fans are eating well this year. Not only did the latest Destiny 2 expansion, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-the-final-shape-preorder-guide/1100-6517093/" data-ref-id="1100-6517093">The Final Shape</a>, launch for PC and consoles on June 4, but a new volume of The Art of Destiny art book series was also recently announced. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D1P5Q4CK?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Art of Destiny Volume 3</a> is set to drop on November 19, will pick up where Volume 2 left off in 2017, and will show off even more official art and behind-the-scenes development materials. While there are still several more months until launch, preorders for the new art book are now live.</p><div title="6523978 - The Art of Destiny Volume 3 preorders" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="2424" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6523978 - The Art of Destiny Volume 3 preorders" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D1P5Q4CK?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0D1P5Q4CK?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D1P5Q4CK?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">Preorder The Art of Destiny Volume 3</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D1P5Q4CK?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0D1P5Q4CK?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0D1P5Q4CK?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">$50</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <div><p>According to the official description, the 216-page Art of Destiny Volume 3 art book "features everything from early sketches and illustrations of characters, to paintings of sweeping vistas used to shape the in-game worlds." It will also include details on in-game characters, locations, and weapons, as well as interviews with the Destiny development team.</p><p>The Art of Destiny Volume 3 will launch on November 19 for $50. Preorders are available now at Amazon and Target.</p></div>                      </div><p dir="ltr">It's been seven years since the last The Art of Destiny book, so there's quite a bit of new material to cover in this new volume. However, if you haven't checked out the previous two releases, you can snag both The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Art-Destiny-Bungie/dp/1608874206?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Art of Destiny Volume 1</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Art-Destiny-2-Bungie/dp/168383111X?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Volume 2</a> for over 40% at Amazon. You can also pick up a few other official Destiny books, including the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Destiny-Exotic-Collection-Insight-Editions/dp/1647227127?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny: The Exotics Collection Volume 1</a> for just $12 (normally $35), the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Destiny-Comic-Collection-Bungie-Inc/dp/1957721081?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny Comic Collection Volume 1</a> for $17.69 (was $20), and six volumes of the Destiny Grimoire Anthology for up to 38% off.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Destiny book deals</h2><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Art-Destiny-Bungie/dp/1608874206?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Art of Destiny Volume 1</a> --$28.49 ($<del>50</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Art-Destiny-2-Bungie/dp/168383111X?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Art of Destiny Volume 2</a> -- $29.72 ($<del>50</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Destiny-Exotic-Collection-Insight-Editions/dp/1647227127?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny: The Exotics Collection Volume 1</a> -- $12 ($<del>35</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Destiny-Comic-Collection-Bungie-Inc/dp/1957721081?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny Comic Collection, Volume 1</a> -- $17.69 ($<del>20</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Destiny-Grimoire-I-Bungie-Inc/dp/1957721006?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny Grimoire Anthology, Volume I</a> -- $18.24 ($<del>25</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Destiny-Grimoire-Anthology-II-Kingdoms/dp/1957721014?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny Grimoire Anthology, Volume II: Fallen Kingdoms</a> -- $20.64 ($<del>25</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Destiny-Grimoire-III-War-Machines/dp/1957721022?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny Grimoire Anthology, Volume III: War Machines</a> -- $19.41 ($<del>25</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Destiny-Grimoire-IV-Royal-Will/dp/1957721030?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny Grimoire Anthology, Volume IV: The Royal Will</a> -- $23.54 ($<del>25</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Destiny-Grimoire-Anthology-Legions-Adrift/dp/195772109X?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny Grimoire Anthology, Volume V: Legions Adrift</a> -- $15.80 ($<del>25</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Destiny-Grimoire-Anthology-VI-Partners/dp/1957721111?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Destiny Grimoire Anthology, Volume VI: Partners in Light</a> -- $15.60 ($<del>25</del>)</li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mad-max-5-film-limited-edition-4k-collection-and-furiosa-steelbook-up-for-preorder/1100-6523703/">Mad Max 5-Film Limited Edition 4K Collection And Furiosa Steelbook Up For Preorder</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cuphead-delicious-last-course-art-book-has-never-before-seen-content-limited-edition-up-for-preorder/1100-6523733/">Cuphead Delicious Last Course Art Book Has Never-Before-Seen Content, Limited Edition Up For Preorder</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-preorder-guide-ps5-xbox-series-x/1100-6523506/">Walmart Has An Exclusive Edition For EA Sports College Football 25</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More Best Gaming &amp; Tech Deals This Week Links (4)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/paper-mario-thousand-year-door-nintendo-switch-preorder-guide/1100-6521751/">Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door Preorders - Release-Day Delivery Still Available</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-over-60-on-12-months-of-xbox-game-pass-ultimate-with-targets-limited-time-deal/1100-6523230/">Save Over $60 On 12 Months Of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate With Target's Limited-Time Deal</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-world-championships-nes-edition-preorder-guide-nintendo-switch/1100-6523267/">Nintendo World Championships Deluxe Set Preorders Are Only Available At Select Retailers</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-portal-restock-guide/1100-6520876/">PlayStation Portal Is Back In Stock At Multiple Major Retailers</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/104300651635509044736?rel=author">Brendan Hesse</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6515851&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/meta-quest-2-is-only-100-right-now-but-itll-sell-out-fast\/1100-6515851\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523969&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/sony-removes-8k-claim-from-playstation-5-boxes\/1100-6523969\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523871&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/test-drive-unlimited-solar-crown-preorders-are-already-discounted\/1100-6523871\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523894&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/google-employee-reportedly-leaked-nintendo-info-ahead-of-official-announcement\/1100-6523894\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-get-exotic-class-items-in-destiny-2-the-final-shape-and-how-they-work\/1100-6523922\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523911&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/aerith-actress-reveals-why-she-didnt-sing-in-final-fantasy-vii-rebirths-big-opera-scene\/1100-6523911\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523864&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/wild-bastards-is-an-acid-trippy-roguelite-western-that-goes-deeper-than-its-predecessor\/1100-6523864\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523925&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/star-wars-hunters-is-available-to-play-for-free-now\/1100-6523925\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523930&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-quickly-level-up-your-power-in-destiny-2-the-final-shape-and-how-it-works\/1100-6523930\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523972&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/is-the-acolyte-the-gayest-star-wars-ever-amanda-stenberg-and-creator-discuss\/1100-6523972\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523855&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hitman-3-is-reloading-for-another-run-at-vr-assassinations\/1100-6523855\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523973&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-boys-shares-a-closer-look-at-season-4s-new-supes\/1100-6523973\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523804&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-boss-reveals-why-sony-doesnt-release-most-ps5-games-on-pc-day-and-date\/1100-6523804\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523743&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-plus-essential-free-games-for-june-2024\/1100-6523743\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523875&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/godzilla-minus-one-is-streaming-now-including-special-black-and-white-version\/1100-6523875\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523936&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-the-final-shape-guides-hub\/1100-6523936\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6523879&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/beloved-manga-vagabond-is-getting-a-new-definitive-edition\/1100-6523879\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Halo Game Is Reportedly Being Considered For PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-first-halo-game-is-reportedly-being-considered-for-ps5/1100-6523999/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-halo-game-is-reportedly-being-considered-for-ps5.891597/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-first-halo-game-is-reportedly-being-considered-for-ps5/1100-6523999/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523999">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The first game in the Halo series, Halo: Combat Evolved, is reportedly being considered for a release on PlayStation 5.</p><p>According to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/6/24172684/microsoft-xbox-showcase-2024" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">The Verge</a>, Microsoft is working on some sort of remaster of Halo: Combat Evolved. It's reportedly part of Microsoft's multiplatform strategy, Project Latitude, and the company is considering placing it on rival platforms. PlayStation 5 is one obvious option here, but that could potentially mean Nintendo Switch as well.</p><p>If this remaster exists, however, it's also apparently not going to be announced at Microsoft's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-games-showcase-airs-june-9-followed-by-mystery-event/1100-6523072/" data-ref-id="1100-6523072">upcoming showcase on June 9</a>. Microsoft's showcase will also reportedly feature a new entry in the Doom series called <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/doom-the-dark-ages-will-be-revealed-at-xbox-showcase-according-to-report/1100-6523727/" data-ref-id="1100-6523727">Doom: The Dark Ages</a>, as well as a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gears-6-could-be-teased-this-summer-insider-claims/1100-6522398/" data-ref-id="1100-6522398">new entry in the Gears of War</a> franchise.</p><p>Microsoft has already brought some of its former <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/microsoft-confirms-plans-to-launch-these-four-games-on-rival-platforms/1100-6521266/" data-ref-id="1100-6521266">Xbox exclusives to PlayStation</a> and Nintendo Switch. The first four games were Pentiment, Sea of Thieves, Hi-Fi Rush, and Grounded.</p><p>Halo: Combat Evolved was first released for the original Xbox in 2001. It got a remaster in 2011 as Halo: Combat Evolved Anniversary for Xbox 360, and is part of the Halo: Master Chief Collection for Xbox One and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2 Prismatic Guide: Recommended Builds And How To Unlock Fragments, Aspects, Supers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-prismatic-guide-recommended-builds-and-how-to-unlock-fragments-aspects-supers/1100-6523998/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destiny-2-prismatic-guide-recommended-builds-and-how-to-unlock-fragments-aspects-supers.891594/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-prismatic-guide-recommended-builds-and-how-to-unlock-fragments-aspects-supers/1100-6523998/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523998">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Alongside a new location to explore, campaign to complete, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-the-final-shape-raid-launch-time-and-everything-we-know/1100-6522790/" data-ref-id="1100-6522790">raid</a> to take on, one of the key additions in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-the-final-shape-guides-hub/1100-6523936/" data-ref-id="1100-6523936">Destiny 2: The Final Shape</a> is Prismatic. This is a new subclass, of which we've only ever had five in Destiny's history, but this one is much different in that it blends together old and new options from the existing Light and Darkness subclasses to give you an interesting blend. With so many choices comes a lot of complexity, so we're here to guide you through everything there is to know about Prismatic, including how to unlock it and all of its Supers, Aspects, Fragments, and other options, as well as recommended builds as we start to wrap our heads around what's possible.</p><div data-embed-type="toc"><p><span><strong>Table of Contents</strong> [<a data-toggle="collapse" href="#toc_list">hide</a>]</span></p><ul id="toc_list"><li><a href="#How_to_unlock_Prismatic">How to unlock Prismatic</a></li><li><a href="#How_to_get_more_Prismatic_Supers__grenades__Aspects__and_Fragments">How to get more Prismatic Supers, grenades, Aspects, and Fragments</a></li><li><a href="#Transcendence">Transcendence</a></li><li><a href="#Prismatic_tips">Prismatic tips</a></li><li><a href="#Recommended_Prismatic_builds">Recommended Prismatic builds</a><ul><li><a href="#Titan">Titan</a></li><li><a href="#Hunter">Hunter</a></li><li><a href="#Warlock">Warlock</a></li></ul></li></ul></div><h2 dir="ltr" id="How_to_unlock_Prismatic">How to unlock Prismatic</h2><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-the-final-shapes-prismatic-subclass-avoids-the-mistakes-of-strand-in-lightfall/1100-6523730/" data-ref-id="1100-6523730">Unlike Strand or Stasis</a>, Prismatic is put into your hands early in the Final Shape campaign, and it isn't taken away. You'll have unrestricted access to it, although it takes time to unlock all of its customization options (more on that below). Simply fire up the campaign, and you'll be mixing Light and Darkness like never before on your path to confronting The Witness. Part of this involves unlocking an entirely new Super and Aspect, which will also be available when using the corresponding elemental's subclass, in addition to Prismatic.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="How_to_get_more_Prismatic_Supers__grenades__Aspects__and_Fragments">How to get more Prismatic Supers, grenades, Aspects, and Fragments</h2><p dir="ltr">What makes Prismatic so exciting and fun are all of the options you'll eventually have at your disposal. Playing through the campaign will get you a limited selection of Supers, grenades, Aspects, and Fragments, but as you can see on the customization screen, there are more that await you.</p><p dir="ltr">As soon as you're done with the campaign, you'll be able to start the <strong>Destined Heroes</strong> quest, which will eventually allow you to unlock the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-get-ergo-sum-the-new-exotic-sword-in-destiny-2-the-final-shape/1100-6523991/" data-ref-id="1100-6523991">Ergo Sum Exotic sword</a>. But part of that extended questline involves completing several other missions, which contain some great story content but also will fill in much of your Prismatic arsenal.</p><p dir="ltr">Ghost will offer you two Transcendence quests, each aligned with either the Light or Darkness. You can complete them in either order, but completing them and their associated Adventures will each provide an additional grenade option, Aspect, and Super. Once you're done with these, you should have all of your Prismatic unlocks available, except for Fragments.</p><p dir="ltr">New Prismatic Fragments are unlocked in a different way. <strong>Hidden Prismatic chests</strong> can be discovered throughout the Pale Heart, and it's by opening these that you'll be able to round out your arsenal. We're working on tracking all of these down, and we'll have a guide to help you find these soon.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Transcendence">Transcendence</h2><p dir="ltr">Aside from the interplay that opens up from being able to mix and match elements of the different subclasses, Transcendence is perhaps the most key element of Prismatic. Two new bars will be located under your Super meter when using Prismatic. The Light bar is filled by dealing damage with Void, Solar, or Arc ability or weapon damage, while the Darkness bar is filled by Stasis or Strand abilities and weapons. (Kinetic weapons slowly build up both bars.) Once both bars are filled, you can activate Transcendence. This does a few things:</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Increases weapon damage</li><li dir="ltr">Instantly refreshes grenade and melee abilities</li><li dir="ltr">Increases grenade energy regeneration when dealing melee damage</li><li dir="ltr">Increases melee ability energy regeneration when dealing grenade damage</li><li dir="ltr">Swaps your grenade to a special Prismatic version</li><li dir="ltr">Provides damage resistance</li></ul><p dir="ltr">This state only lasts for a limited time, although kills do refill your meter, allowing you to extend the duration. The meters can be filled more quickly by standing on glowing pink/purple patches on the ground, which you'll typically see in the campaign any time you encounter special types of enemies.</p><p dir="ltr">Being Transcendent is required in order to make certain foes--Bound enemies, those that you'll see with a similar sort of pinkish-purple coating around them--vulnerable to damage. Any damage dealt to these enemies while Transcendent allows you to start attacking them with any damage type, although if they're left alone for long enough, they'll become Bound again.</p><p dir="ltr">Prismatic synergizes well with the aforementioned Ergo Sum, which has a perk--Transcendent Duelist--that helps to speed up filling the Light and Darkness bars, deals increased damage while Transcendent, and further extends its duration when getting kills with the sword while Transcendent.</p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Prismatic_tips">Prismatic tips</h2><p dir="ltr">The nature of Prismatic means you really need to think through your build, perhaps more so than any other subclass. While you can have fun mixing any combination of abilities, Supers, Aspects, and Fragments, there are clear synergies to be had. It also opens up some other interesting possibilities that we're still discovering. Here are some tips based on our time with it so far:</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Equipping a reliable Strand or Stasis weapon in addition to a Void, Solar, or Arc one can make it easier to consistently build up your bars to activate Transcendence.</li><li dir="ltr">As noted above, Bound enemies are invincible until damaged by a Transcendent player, but if necessary, you can rapidly build up your Light and Darkness bars by firing at a Bound foe, allowing you to activate Transcendence.</li><li dir="ltr">Before activating Transcendence, be sure to use your grenade and melee charges. Because they'll be automatically refreshed (and your grenade replaced with a Prismatic one), you can deal some extra damage this way.</li><li dir="ltr">Keep alternating between your grenade and melee ability. Dealing damage with either one while Transcendent will rapidly speed up energy regeneration for the other, allowing you to jump back and forth between them.</li><li dir="ltr">Transcendence does not make you invincible. It's easy to feel empowered by its increased damage resistance, but don't mistake that power for invincibility--particularly if you're in a Darkness Zone where a death can be costly.</li></ul><h2 dir="ltr" id="Recommended_Prismatic_builds">Recommended Prismatic builds</h2><p dir="ltr">We're still digging our teeth into all of the possibilities that Prismatic allows, but here are some early suggestions for builds or combos to consider. We'll continue adding more as we spend more time with the subclass, but be sure to let us know what you like using in the comments below.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Titan">Titan</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4314062-titanprismatic.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4314062" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4314062-titanprismatic.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4314062"></a><figcaption>Prismatic Titan</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4314062-titanprismatic.jpg"></figure><p>An enticing combo comes with the Consecration Aspect. While sliding, this lets you use a melee charge to launch out Solar energy to scorch targets, and then slam down to ignite them. But while the Solar subclass would normally have just one melee charge, you can opt for Frenzied Blade, which can store up to three melee charges. This way, you can potentially use Consecration multiple times in a row, or just more often in general. To make this even more powerful, you can equip the Facet of Ruin Fragment, which (among other things) increases Solar ignitions' area of effect, making these even more devastating.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Hunter">Hunter</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4314061-hunterprismatic.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4314061" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4314061-hunterprismatic.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4314061"></a><figcaption>Prismatic Hunter</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4314061-hunterprismatic.jpg"></figure><p>As a Hunter, you can leverage the ability to go invisible with other subclass perks. The Void Aspect Stylish Executioner will give you Invisibility and Truesight whenever you defeat an enemy who is weakened, suppressed, or volatile; it also weakens a target when you melee attack an enemy while invisible. Combine that with Gambler's Dodge--the Arc subclass ability--which fully recharges your melee when you dodge near an enemy, and then you have access to a melee more often. Then, equip the Combination Blow melee, which buffs your melee damage as you get kills and recharges your class ability when you get a kill (in addition to giving you health), and you have an amazing loop:</p><p dir="ltr">Void debuff an enemy, kill them with your melee to go invisible, buffing your melee damage, dodge to restore your melee, and weaken an enemy by doing a melee attack while invisible, restarting the loop and providing that Void debuff.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Warlock">Warlock</h3><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4314060-warlockprismatic.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4314060" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4314060-warlockprismatic.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4314060"></a><figcaption>Prismatic Warlock</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/123/1239113/4314060-warlockprismatic.jpg"></figure><p>Prismatic pairs very nicely with the Getaway Artist Exotic gauntlets and Bleak Watcher Aspect. You're able to keep Radiant, Devour, and Amplified activated through most combat encounters and have both multiple Bleak Watchers deployed along with an Arc Soul.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Summer Games Fest trailers can cost devs up to $550K]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-summer-games-fest-trailers-can-cost-devs-up-to-550k</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-summer-games-fest-trailers-can-cost-devs-up-to-550k.891591/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-summer-games-fest-trailers-can-cost-devs-up-to-550k<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content"><p><span>Image via Summer Games Fest.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Making games is expensive, and that includes airing trailers for particular events. A new </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.esquire.com/entertainment/a61006534/summer-game-fest-explained/">Esquire</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> report on Summer Games Fest explores how much studios pay to bring a trailer for the now annual showcase run by Geoff Keighley.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On the low end, developers will pay $250,000 for a one-minute trailer. The price goes up depending on length, from $350,000 for 90 seconds to a high of $550,000 for two and a half minutes.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Previously, this information wasn't transparent, so this offers some interesting insight on what studios (or their publishers) are willing to pay to get eyes on their projects.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Esquire notes the 2023 Game Awards had a similar pricing structure. However, it's unclear how shorter trailers less than a minute are priced, or if there are additional costs if a game's actor or creative director comes onstage to talk up the project.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Regardless, it appears to be a quite a fruitful endeavor for Keighley. The outlet speculated for last year's showcase, the main show made $9.65 million just off the trailers, which included reveals for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mortal Kombat 1 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Prince of Persia: The Lost Crown.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">However, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://kotaku.com/summer-game-fest-sgf-prices-trailer-cost-e3-keighley-1851523472">Kotaku</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> added that some major publishers get "earned editorial placements" during the main show at no cost.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The costs of getting your game ready for Summer Games Fest">The costs of getting your game ready for Summer Games Fest</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Speaking to Esquire, an insider was blunt in saying the SGF is "really fucking expensive," which likely explains the trailer cost.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A separate source acknowledged those costs may be too much for smaller studios, calling the price structure "an unattainable goal for most indie developers and publishers."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Several PR professionals defended the price structure with the pros of getting coverage on a big stage Keighley provides. But they also admitted that could be dulled if the trailer is too short to make much of an impact with viewers.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Conversely, one of the marketing people talking to Esquire brought up ticket prices for this year's main SGF show. First-party tickets were reportedly still $41 earlier this week, and they noted how Geoff could lower trailer costs since he effectively has two concurrent revenue streams.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Earlier this week, Keighley said the 2024 Summer Games Fest would </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-expect-big-reveals-at-summer-games-fest-says-geoff-keighley">have fewer</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> brand new reveals. The statement vaguely speaks to the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/approximately-one-third-of-game-developers-were-affected-by-layoffs-last-year">industry's woes</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in recent years, and how those cutbacks have hit the marketing teams at various studios.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Esquire's full report can be read </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.esquire.com/entertainment/a61006534/summer-game-fest-explained/">here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yooka-Replaylee Is A Yooka-Laylee Remaster With Remixed Challenges, Improved Controls, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/06/yooka-replaylee-is-a-yooka-laylee-remaster-with-remixed-challenges-improved</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yooka-replaylee-is-a-yooka-laylee-remaster-with-remixed-challenges-improved-controls-and-more.891585/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/news/2024/06/06/yooka-replaylee-is-a-yooka-laylee-remaster-with-remixed-challenges-improved<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Developer Playtonic has revealed Yooka-Replaylee, a remaster of its 2017 platformer <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/product/yooka-laylee">Yooka-Laylee</a>. It revealed this during today's Guerrilla Collective 2024 Showcase with a new trailer that highlighted the game's new visuals, improved camera and gameplay controls, remixed challenges, and more.&nbsp;</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="03b44e49-bdf5-4593-82fc-09ef89b4e2b9" data-langcode="en" data-entity-embed-display-settings="[]">





</article><p>"Embark on an epic open-world 3D platforming collectathon adventure with Yooka and Laylee," the game's description reads. "The search for Pagies starts anew in Yooka-Replaylee, the enhanced definitive version of the beloved indie darling with all new challenges, secrets, mechanics, and accessibility options."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Check it out for yourself in the Yooka-Replaylee reveal trailer below</strong>:&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hrXXbkP5HAc" width="640"></iframe></p>

<p>Yooka-Laylee launched in 2017 on PlayStation 4, Xbox One, Switch, Wii U, and PC, and we had a great time with it – you can read why in&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/games/yooka-laylee/b/pc/archive/2017/04/04/yooka-laylee-game-informer-review.aspx"><em>Game Informer's&nbsp;</em>Yooka-Laylee review</a>. Though the game is a 3D collect-a-thon, it got a sequel in 2019 called <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/review/yooka-laylee-and-the-impossible-lair/yooka-laylee-and-the-impossible-lair-review-a-fresh">Yooka-Laylee and the Impossible Lair</a> that played more like Donkey Kong Country.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em>Are you excited for Yooka-Replaylee? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero to feature local multiplayer, suggests updated PS Store listing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-to-feature-local-multiplayer-suggests-updated-ps-store-listing/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=dragon-ball-sparking-zero-to-feature-local-multiplayer-suggests-updated-ps-store-listing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-to-feature-local-multiplayer-suggests-updated-ps-store-listing.891582/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-to-feature-local-multiplayer-suggests-updated-ps-store-listing/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=dragon-ball-sparking-zero-to-feature-local-multiplayer-suggests-updated-ps-store-listing<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="294" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">It was unclear whether <em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</em>, the upcoming fighting game, would include local multiplayer. Those rumors have now been seemingly laid to bed, as the local multiplayer gameplay functionality was spotted by Twitter/X user SLOplays on the updated PS Store listing of the game.</p> <p data-characters="336" data-current-count="336" data-injectable="false">The rumors about local multiplayer’s absence arose when the ​​PlayStation and Steam pages listed it as a single-player game only with no mention of offline multiplayer. It was also <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/dragon-ball-z-sparking-zero-reportedly-wont-launch-with-split-scree-mode-co-op-2-player/">reported</a> earlier that game producer Jun Furutani said that local split-screen will not be present due to “issues relating to Sony and Microsoft.”</p> <figure data-current-count="636" data-injectable="true"><div> <blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">MAJOR SPARKING ZERO NEWS! The PS store has updated to show that LOCAL MULTIPLAYER will be added! This is HUGE cuz it means they are listening to feedback. Splitscreen isn't confirmed, but we will see as more info develops! I'm so happy! <a href="https://t.co/gd1MkfTHLw">pic.twitter.com/gd1MkfTHLw</a></p>— SLO (@SLOplays) <a href="https://twitter.com/SLOplays/status/1798299849198379507?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 5, 2024</a></blockquote> </div></figure>
 <p data-characters="193" data-current-count="193" data-injectable="false">If the store page is believed, it looks like local multiplayer will be in the cards. Local multiplayer has been a staple mode in fighting games, and its absence would have been felt among fans.</p> <p data-characters="265" data-current-count="458" data-injectable="true"><em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero </em>is a highly anticipated title among fighting games and <em>Dragon Ball </em>fans. The game has a packed roster, with many already confirmed as playable characters. It’s even more exciting that many of the characters are yet to be announced.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bandai Namco</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="50" data-current-count="350" data-injectable="false">Here are the latest additions to the roster:&nbsp;</p> <ol data-found-items="21" data-items-injection="true" data-current-count="1190" data-injectable="true"> <li data-index="0">Trunks (Kid)</li> <li data-index="1">Trunks (Kid), Super Saiyan</li> <li data-index="2">Goten</li> <li data-index="3">Goten, Super Saiyan</li> <li data-index="4">Caulifla</li> <li data-index="5">Caulifla, Super Saiyan 2</li> <li data-index="6">Kale</li> <li data-index="7">Kale, Super Saiyan</li> <li data-index="8">Gotenks</li> <li data-index="9" data-injectable="true">Gotenks, Super Saiyan</li>
 <li data-index="10">Gotenks, Super Saiyan 3</li> <li data-index="11">Kefla</li> <li data-index="12">Kefla, Super Saiyan</li> <li data-index="13">Kefla, Super Saiyan 2</li> <li data-index="14">Vegito</li> <li data-index="15">Vegito, Super Saiyan God Super Saiyan</li> <li data-index="16">Gogeta (Super)</li> <li data-index="17">Gogeta (Super), Super Saiyan</li> <li data-index="18">Gogeta (Super), Super Saiyan God Super Saiyan</li> <li data-index="19">Fused Zamasu</li> <li data-index="20">Fused Zamasu, Half-Corrupted</li> </ol>
 <p data-characters="149" data-current-count="149" data-injectable="false">More information is expected to be revealed soon, as <em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</em> is set to make an appearance at the upcoming Summer Game Fest.&nbsp;</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Halo: Combat Evolved remaster is reportedly in the works, and it’s apparently being considered for PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/a-halo-combat-evolved-remaster-is-reportedly-in-the-works-and-its-apparently-being-considered-for-ps5/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=a-halo-combat-evolved-remaster-is-reportedly-in-the-works-and-its-apparently-being-considered-for-ps5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-halo-combat-evolved-remaster-is-reportedly-in-the-works-and-it%E2%80%99s-apparently-being-considered-for-ps5.891579/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/a-halo-combat-evolved-remaster-is-reportedly-in-the-works-and-its-apparently-being-considered-for-ps5/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=a-halo-combat-evolved-remaster-is-reportedly-in-the-works-and-its-apparently-being-considered-for-ps5<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="173" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Amid a wave of other titles losing Xbox exclusivity, reports suggest that Microsoft is working on a <em>Halo: Combat Evolved</em> remaster and is considering it for rival platforms. </p> <p data-characters="248" data-current-count="248" data-injectable="false">The Verge’s Tom Warren <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/6/24172684/microsoft-xbox-showcase-2024" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reported</a>, “One game that is being considered for release on PS5 is Halo. Sources tell me Microsoft is working on some form of <em>Halo: Combat Evolved</em> remaster that is also being considered for rival consoles.” </p> <p data-characters="274" data-current-count="522" data-injectable="true">A <em>Halo</em>-to-PS5 announcement at the upcoming <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/where-and-when-to-watch-the-xbox-games-showcase-2024-and-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-direct/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Games Showcase</a> on June 9 would steal the show, but that dream might not become a reality. “I don’t expect Microsoft to announce this during the showcase as it is early days for the remaster,” Warren claimed. </p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie </figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="285" data-current-count="585" data-injectable="true"><em>Halo: Combat Evolved </em>was first launched on Xbox in 2001 and served as the first title in what would become one of the most iconic franchises in history. The title would be a great entry point for new fans of the series on PlayStation and continues a trend of titles losing exclusivity.</p>
 <p data-characters="370" data-current-count="370" data-injectable="false">In February, Microsoft <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/xbox-is-bringing-four-games-to-other-platforms-and-teasing-hardware-news-to-come/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> that <em>Pentiment</em>, <em>Hi-Fi Rush</em>, <em>Grounded</em>, and <em>Sea of Thieves</em> would be leaping from Xbox to other platforms. Phil Spencer, Head of Xbox, saw this as a chance to create more revenue for the titles and open the door for future iterations and sequels. However, Microsoft’s new vision of creating more opportunities has also come at a cost.</p> <p data-characters="536" data-current-count="906" data-injectable="false">In January, <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/microsoft-lays-off-1900-employees-from-activision-blizzard-and-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft laid off 1,900 employees</a> from Activision Blizzard and Xbox. Then, in May, Xbox Games Studios <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/redfall-and-hi-fi-rush-developers-shut-down-in-another-awful-wave-of-microsoft-cuts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shut down</a> Arkane Austin, Tango Gameworks, and Alpha Dog Games and merged a fourth studio. PlayStation players should be excited that they might finally get to experience <em>Halo</em> and everything the iconic FPS franchise has to offer on their boxes. Yet at the same time, Microsoft’s recent string of decisions has raised eyebrows and scared some long-time Xbox players about the future of their platform moving forward. </p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater devs reveal 50-player skateboarding game Wrekless]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/former-tony-hawks-pro-skater-devs-reveal-50-player-skateboarding-game-wrekless/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=former-tony-hawks-pro-skater-devs-reveal-50-player-skateboarding-game-wrekless</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-tony-hawk%E2%80%99s-pro-skater-devs-reveal-50-player-skateboarding-game-wrekless.891576/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/former-tony-hawks-pro-skater-devs-reveal-50-player-skateboarding-game-wrekless/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=former-tony-hawks-pro-skater-devs-reveal-50-player-skateboarding-game-wrekless<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="315" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">If solo shredding isn’t enough for you, some of the former developers behind the <em>Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater </em>series are here to throw 49 other players in the mix. <em>Wrekless </em>has been revealed as a skateboarding game that supports up to 50 players online, and it’s heading to Early Access later this year.</p> <p data-characters="471" data-current-count="471" data-injectable="true"><em>Wrekless </em>currently has a Q3 2024 window penciled in for its Early Access debut on Steam. According to the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1931930/Wrekless/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam page</a>, the team at the California-based Free Range Games—which is also behind <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/lord-of-the-rings-return-to-moria-dated-for-ps5-and-pc-xbox-comes-later/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Lord of the Rings: Return to Moria</a></em>—was founded by folks who worked on <em>Pro Skater </em>and “other action sports games in the 2000s.” They describe <em>Wrekless </em>as the “massively multiplayer collaborative skateboarding game we’ve always wanted to make.”&nbsp;</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Wrekless Reveal Trailer" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nZfUiMJ03No?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="353" data-current-count="653" data-injectable="true">In addition to skating around, mastering combos, and pulling off increasingly elaborate tricks, <em>Wrekless </em>lets you construct skate parks in real time. You can team up with friends and skate and build at the same time, from familiar warehouse parks to city-sized constructions with massive ramps, bouncy floors, lava pits, and other novel additions.&nbsp;</p>
 <p data-characters="459" data-current-count="459" data-injectable="false">Once you’ve completed a park you’ll be able to share it online with the rest of the community, so it sounds like <em>Wrekless </em>is going all in on the creative aspect. As the “Why Early Access?” portion indicates, this is an ambitious effort that’s going to take a lot of work to get to the finish line, especially with all the user-generated content to consider. We’ll see how it pans out once the wheels hit the pavement.&nbsp;</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Warframe community is willing to risk it all for the new Ember Heirloom Skin]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/the-warframe-community-is-willing-to-risk-it-all-for-the-new-ember-heirloom-skin/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-warframe-community-is-willing-to-risk-it-all-for-the-new-ember-heirloom-skin</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-warframe-community-is-willing-to-risk-it-all-for-the-new-ember-heirloom-skin.891570/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/the-warframe-community-is-willing-to-risk-it-all-for-the-new-ember-heirloom-skin/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=the-warframe-community-is-willing-to-risk-it-all-for-the-new-ember-heirloom-skin<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="277" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><a href="https://www.warframe.com/news/coming-soon-ember-heirloom" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ember is going to be the third Warframe to receive a Heirloom skin</a>, gracing the Fashionframe community, Ember mains, and… certain types of internet dwellers. Fans, rejoice because so much has improved with the Heirloom Collection since it first started in the Winter of 2023.</p> <p data-characters="203" data-current-count="203" data-injectable="false">This skin was originally made as a concept by <a href="https://twitter.com/CleoNaturin" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Warframe</em> content creator Vik / Cleo Naturin</a>. Digital Extremes saw the art and immediately bought it soon after, making it a reality coming to the game.&nbsp;</p> <p data-characters="273" data-current-count="476" data-injectable="true">This is a huge win for everyone, because the Heirloom skin looks amazing. It was a huge letdown when the Frost and Mag skins from last year were literally paywalled. They had a steep price and came with stuff that many of us didn’t want just as a way to bloat the prices.</p>
 <p data-characters="98" data-current-count="98" data-injectable="false">Since then, Digital Extremes has learned how to make the upcoming Heirloom sets consumer-friendly.</p> <figure data-current-count="398" data-injectable="false"></figure> <h2 id="h-ember-heirloom-collection-details-revealed" data-injectable="false">Ember Heirloom Collection details revealed</h2> <p data-characters="190" data-current-count="588" data-injectable="true">Starting with the biggest W of them all, the Ember Heirloom collection will now be available for purchase for 24.99 USD or for 475 Platinum. Stay tuned for that when it comes out on July 20.</p>
 <p data-characters="46" data-current-count="46" data-injectable="false">Buying the collection gives you the following:</p> <ul data-found-items="6" data-current-count="286" data-injectable="false"> <li>Ember Heirloom Skin</li> <li>Ember Heirloom Signa</li> <li>Ember Heirloom Glyph</li> <li>Ember Heirloom Sigil</li> <li>Ember Heirloom Color Palette</li> <li>Ember Heirloom Prex Card</li> </ul> <p data-characters="139" data-current-count="425" data-injectable="true">If you buy the collection with real-world money, you will also receive 425 Platinum. You can also buy the parts individually if you choose.</p>
 <p data-characters="287" data-current-count="287" data-injectable="false">This will be applicable to Ember and Ember Prime, so all of us copping this on day one will be able to use this skin despite which variant we have. Also, the Ember Prime Resurgence event will happen exactly on July 20, lining up everything so you can get her if you don’t have her yet.</p> <p data-characters="212" data-current-count="499" data-injectable="true">And then the cherry on top is that moving forward, the Heirloom skins will not be leaving. There will be no FOMO. It’ll only go away for purchasing with real-world money once the next Heirloom bundle comes out.</p>
 <p data-characters="46" data-current-count="46" data-injectable="false">Now, for the other side of the fan response…</p> <h2 data-injectable="false">The Ember Heirloom Skin has people acting up</h2> <p data-characters="191" data-current-count="237" data-injectable="false"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/ovxaYxLbUNE?si=aqXUP7nXB767URu5" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Whether you were there during Devsteam 180</a>, saw the aftermath in the YouTube comments section, or on Reddit, there was a lot of praise about the Ember Heirloom skin because of her… looks.&nbsp;</p> <p data-characters="167" data-current-count="404" data-injectable="true">To put it bluntly, this Ember skin has a noticeable posterior. The live chat was flooded with “gyatt” responses and other meme quotes usually referring to butts.&nbsp;</p>
 <p data-characters="322" data-current-count="322" data-injectable="false">The dev team already knew what fan responses would be once the skin was shown, so they leaned in on Ember’s curvature and gave it a good inspection. In all good fun, they spun it around and danced over every possible word without outright mentioning the objectively “best” features of the frame in her Heirloom skin.</p> <p data-characters="313" data-current-count="635" data-injectable="true">It took a while to actually notice that there’s an actual skin attached to this feature, and it’s great. The energy details on the body, paired with the flames on her helmet, the back of her heels, and around her neck are impeccable. The steep price isn’t going to stop any Ember fan from getting this skin.</p>
 <h2 data-injectable="false">And finally, Ember’s viability</h2> <p data-characters="255" data-current-count="255" data-injectable="false">Butt jokes and appreciation aside, the skin is actually fantastic. This does raise another concern, though. It can be more of a hope, but with all the reworks and buffs done to other frames, it feels like Ember has sort of been left behind by power creep.</p> <figure data-current-count="555" data-injectable="true"></figure>
 <p data-characters="317" data-current-count="317" data-injectable="false">Laid out by Reddit user Leskendle45, they express a sentiment that resonates with many other people who play <em>Warframe</em>. She’s been given a lot of tweaks since her initial release, with her kit sounding good on paper. However, in later-game content, she starts to struggle in terms of survivability and damage output.</p> <p data-characters="308" data-current-count="625" data-injectable="false">Fire is one of the better elements in <em>Warframe</em>, but her abilities don’t have the output that really reflects that in the long run. Hopefully, with enough traction, she’ll get a revisit since her popularity is about to blow up with this skin. But still, we should bask in the glory that is Ember Heirloom.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nightdive and Ziggurat are restoring a cult classic with Killing Time: Resurrected]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/nightdive-and-ziggurat-are-restoring-a-cult-classic-with-killing-time-resurrected/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=nightdive-and-ziggurat-are-restoring-a-cult-classic-with-killing-time-resurrected</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nightdive-and-ziggurat-are-restoring-a-cult-classic-with-killing-time-resurrected.891561/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/nightdive-and-ziggurat-are-restoring-a-cult-classic-with-killing-time-resurrected/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=nightdive-and-ziggurat-are-restoring-a-cult-classic-with-killing-time-resurrected<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="297" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Nightdive Studios <a href="https://youtu.be/Zkvx_2g68n4?feature=shared" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced their</a> next remastering project at the Guerilla Collective today. This time, they’re teaming with their fellow retro enthusiasts at Ziggurat to put the polisher on 3DO’s 1995 cult-classic FPS, <em>Killing Time</em>. <em>Killing Time: Resurrected</em> will be released later this year.</p> <p data-characters="449" data-current-count="449" data-injectable="true"><em>Killing Time</em> is one of the few games I own for my 3DO Interactive Multiplayer, one of the doomed consoles of the ‘90s. While playing through the first area of the game, I stopped myself because, while the game is fine, it was obviously not the ideal way to play it. The 3DO version is rather choppy, and the controller affords little comfort. There was a PC port, and I already owned it on GOG, so I figured I might as well just play that version.</p>
 <p data-characters="16" data-current-count="16" data-injectable="false">But I never did.</p> <figure data-current-count="316" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Killing Time Announcement Trailer | Nightdive Studios" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zkvx_2g68n4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="261" data-current-count="577" data-injectable="true">Now, I definitely will. Nightdive is bringing us what will most likely be the definitive way of playing <em>Killing Time</em>. Beyond simply being ported to a modern engine, the trailer shows off completely updated sprites and textures, mouselook, and smoother movement.</p>
 <p data-characters="453" data-current-count="453" data-injectable="true">I spoke to Nightdive about the new sprites and textures. Some of the updates are drawn from original source photographs and models whereever they were able to find backups of them. Some, however, were exclusive to the PC version, and Nightdive artist Albert Marin Garau says that to remake them he “modeled, rigged, skinned and animated those exclusive PC enemies and render hi-res sprites that match the quality of the other hi-res assets.”</p>
 <p data-characters="46" data-current-count="46" data-injectable="false">I’ll write about it in more detail soon.</p> <p data-characters="366" data-current-count="412" data-injectable="true"><em>Killing Time</em> is a rather obscure FPS, but don’t get it <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-poed-definitive-edition/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">twisted with <em>PO’ed</em></a>. While both games were initially released on the 3DO Interactive Multiplayer and both games were ambitious for their time, <em>Killing Time</em> just stuck the landing better. Rather than a series of levels, the world was more open-ish. It told a story using digitized actors and was fully voiced.</p>
 <p data-characters="327" data-current-count="327" data-injectable="false">The story involves an island where an ancient Egyptian curse causes a number of high-society people to vanish. Your task is to undo that curse, but standing in your way is a number of sometimes bizarre enemies. One of the first types that you fight is ducks, which is sad. The only thing you should be firing at ducks is bread.</p> <p data-characters="116" data-current-count="443" data-injectable="false"><em>Killing Time: Resurrected</em> is coming to PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, Switch, and PC sometime later this year.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demonschool Hands On Preview – Persona of a Different Kind]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/demonschool-preview/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demonschool-hands-on-preview-%E2%80%93-persona-of-a-different-kind.891543/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/demonschool-preview/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/demonschool-announced-for-pc-and-consoles/">Demonschool</a> by Necrosoft Games made more than <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-indie-games-of-2024-great-months-ahead/">a few heads turn</a> when it was revealed in 2022, and for good reasons. Combining gorgeous old-school visuals with a unique atmosphere reminiscent of Italian horror movies and an evident classic Persona influence, the game looked like the one to keep track of for fans of the ATLUS series who prefer the classic first entry in the franchise as well as Persona 2 Innocent Sin and Eternal Punishment.</p>
<p>Following two years of almost complete silence, which made people fear the worst, a Demonschool playable demo is available as part of this year's Steam Next Fest, giving players the chance to experience a week in the life of Faye, the final heir of a legendary family of demon hunters, as she attempts to uncover the mystery of an island university together with some friends, an island where demons have started appearing, and the boundary between worlds, started getting thinner and thinner. While the demo drops players a few hours into the adventure and lacks all of the mechanics that will be available in the final release, I feel it does a great job showcasing some of the most unique features of the experience.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/20240601124113_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>The story of Demonschool is probably the hardest feature to evaluate from the demo. From what can be gleaned, Faye's investigation will go hand-in-hand with university life, and an occult theme seems to permeate everything. For example, the demo begins after Faye and her companions have successfully investigated some sort of possessed VHS tape and have been rewarded for it with school credits that can be used to learn new abilities. The week that can be experienced in the demo is centered around finding a demonic paintbrush, and during the investigation, the party will meet all sorts of wacky characters, such as an amnesiac woman who thinks random people are actually her husband who seems to be the main focus of a longer subquest. Thankfully, it seems like secondary quests will be hard to miss, as the quick travel interface highlights any important event that is about to take place in a certain location. Ultimately, the week available in the demo passes by rather quickly thanks to a gripping enough story that is possibly made more enjoyable by the game's beautiful and colorful 2D visuals and the atmospheric soundtrack that gives the experience a sort of horror-noir vibe. If the entirety of the story manages to do the same, it remains to be seen, but I'm definitely hopeful.</p>
<p>The real highlight of the Demonschool demo is the combat system, which is quite unique compared to most role-playing games on the market. After encountering an enemy, the party gets transported to a combat arena where both the player and the AI-controlled enemies take turns to move their units and take action. Actions play all together at the end of the Planning Phase, where the player can take all the time needed to move their units. A single unit can be moved and attack enemies as long as enough AP is available, though multiple actions from a single unit increase their AP cost.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/20240601124811_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>A few rather unique quirks make the Demonschool combat system intriguing. For starters, units can only move in straight lines and must use a special maneuver called Sidestep, which doesn't cost AP to adjust their movement range. Attacking enemies requires positioning characters in the correct range, and each attack also pushes the attacked unit, allowing the player to plan things out so that it will become possible to attack an enemy out of range at the start of the Planning Phase. Additionally, just defeating enemies is not enough to win, as not only players must defeat a required number of demons, but they also have to reach the opposite side of the combat arena with any character to seal a portal. Add in different roles for playable characters, frequent demon respawns, and special attacks with different properties, and you get a uniquely challenging battle system that could take some time to understand, but it offers a lot of strategic depth, making battles extremely fun.</p>
<p>As already mentioned, my in-game week in the Demonschool demo flew by, and it has definitely left me hungering for more, especially as the demo hints that there will be more to do than just fight demons and progress through the main adventure. Hopefully, the wait won't be much longer, and the game will indeed be released on PC and consoles in the second quarter of the year, as currently listed on the game's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1900250/Demonschool/">Steam Store page.</a></p>
<p><em>Demo early access provided by the publisher.</em></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA Online update for the week of June 6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/gta-online-guides/2024/6/6/24172841/june-6-weekly-update-events-ls-car-meet</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-online-update-for-the-week-of-june-6.891540/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/gta-online-guides/2024/6/6/24172841/june-6-weekly-update-events-ls-car-meet<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="PeFkMi">The weekly <a href="https://www.polygon.com/gta-online-guides"><em><strong>GTA Online</strong></em></a><strong> update for June 6, 2024</strong>, is live with reward events, discounts, prizes, and a lot of street racing.</p>
<p id="uEn69V">Our <em>GTA Online </em>weekly update guide will tell you everything happening in Los Santos this week.</p>

<hr id="8tvoPq">
<h2 id="tqxGpX"><strong>GTA Online special events</strong></h2>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480416/GTA_Online_20240606_1.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717693319_8642_23562" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480416,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EkwSlsjOd_1hfgv-l08GzuxbM0g=/0x0:3840x2160/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480416/GTA_Online_20240606_1.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0bB5O_DKT-G0PYQ8ICC22l2ojFM=/0x0:3840x2160/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480416/GTA_Online_20240606_1.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wvHWZLVX1377z-sMbZx5isYdi0k=/0x0:3840x2160/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480416/GTA_Online_20240606_1.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FbfUx1HRqpRumeK57uJaI8uMu2o=/0x0:3840x2160/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480416/GTA_Online_20240606_1.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j-PFtMrHW2JR_175J40l3CsheS0=/0x0:3840x2160/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480416/GTA_Online_20240606_1.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZlW57cfE_DW-95gm8KgHNbNn4yM=/0x0:3840x2160/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480416/GTA_Online_20240606_1.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3MCj2YToLteTjyAtPn-Ft_wxiiA=/0x0:3840x2160/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480416/GTA_Online_20240606_1.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aOHoC9Km2mSjzqpne22dWgcQjGE=/0x0:3840x2160/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480416/GTA_Online_20240606_1.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0DlFb_3t-br_1HHwTZboc6t27gk=/0x0:3840x2160/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480416/GTA_Online_20240606_1.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Rockstar Games</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="FV51PL">This week’s update is all about the <strong>LS Car Meet Series</strong>. You’ll get <strong>2x GTA$</strong>, <strong>RP</strong>, and <strong>LS Car Meet Rep</strong> all week when you take part in<strong> Street</strong>, <strong>Pursuit</strong>, <strong>Drift</strong>, and <strong>Drag Races</strong>.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480425/GTA_Online_20240606_5.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717693319_2494_23563" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480425,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t9heRzMRY9McMVgyyuIWk_rChqg=/0x0:3840x2160/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480425/GTA_Online_20240606_5.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o8WXx786BXf34Yx7NZicGcLjkrg=/0x0:3840x2160/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480425/GTA_Online_20240606_5.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d0JxLFwIL3DaElFXI1jGtCfLSAM=/0x0:3840x2160/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480425/GTA_Online_20240606_5.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zSlh6hPcQrGsySPmuX5sI31M3Lk=/0x0:3840x2160/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480425/GTA_Online_20240606_5.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4KGm3utjrd4OabvYeMfsVyPBt5I=/0x0:3840x2160/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480425/GTA_Online_20240606_5.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nz6CUi9fzE_QZzZqmxmi298vxPw=/0x0:3840x2160/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480425/GTA_Online_20240606_5.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vms4rz_OlZBaiNvxH_Bsnh7d9oQ=/0x0:3840x2160/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480425/GTA_Online_20240606_5.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TKptx1N9Y7SmrZxQHmGXOFTIeNA=/0x0:3840x2160/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480425/GTA_Online_20240606_5.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/d6yaHJ-E0rPou5ZGqFRbwQbjw1s=/0x0:3840x2160/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480425/GTA_Online_20240606_5.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Rockstar Games</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="JroI5a">Meanwhile, the <strong>Dinka Jester RR</strong>, <strong>Dinka RT3000</strong>, and <strong>Dinka Sugoi</strong> are all on sale at 30% off at Legendary Motorsport and Southern San Andreas Super Autos. Picking up one of them will get you the <strong>Dinka Tee</strong>.</p>
<hr id="L6qDfO">
<h2 id="6wJoWp"><strong>What are the 3x GTA$ and RP events in GTA Online this week?</strong></h2>
<p id="6LeGEG">There are no 3x GTA$ and RP events this week.</p>
<hr id="pSo3xi">
<h2 id="sPqNIN"><strong>What are the 2x GTA$ and RP events in GTA Online this week?</strong></h2>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480418/GTA_Online_20240606_4.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717693319_520_23564" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480418,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UfPXeaPHEkiXNE94YwCraFY_Tu8=/0x0:3840x2160/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480418/GTA_Online_20240606_4.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Te7ZuPA3KYY9Ah0y0kVSKnbsCVs=/0x0:3840x2160/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480418/GTA_Online_20240606_4.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VEGhDndicaj7U_SUPhh3z0fo_y8=/0x0:3840x2160/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480418/GTA_Online_20240606_4.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VwKq5JyhrncPPCc5Tk1ngcvbjJY=/0x0:3840x2160/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480418/GTA_Online_20240606_4.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LWFhfJ-NnLSZ0sO2BGXAJ63Q2TY=/0x0:3840x2160/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480418/GTA_Online_20240606_4.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-n8VBHP-3G2thavmLePJJD0ybfE=/0x0:3840x2160/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480418/GTA_Online_20240606_4.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZVM1qyDHyFBhredZJHP0j1ibSpc=/0x0:3840x2160/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480418/GTA_Online_20240606_4.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fQ_S0PWpY6FjGsVCF3r6blF0V_U=/0x0:3840x2160/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480418/GTA_Online_20240606_4.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ceuSQsXzYD2WhjwCnBF7zw9mHOw=/0x0:3840x2160/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480418/GTA_Online_20240606_4.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Rockstar Games</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="8EK3OP">If you’ve talked to <strong>Mimi </strong>at the LS Car Meet and you’ve bought yourself an <strong>Auto Shop</strong> from Maze Bank (40% off this week), you get <strong>2x GTA$</strong> this week for all <strong>Auto Shop Client Jobs</strong>. Complete three of those to complete the Weekly Challenge and you’ll get <strong>GTA$ 100,000 </strong>and the <strong>LS Customs Coveralls</strong>.</p>
<p id="iBcvhR">In your Auto Shop, you can also do <strong>Exotic Exports</strong> missions for <strong>2x GTA$ and RP</strong> all week.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480420/GTA_Online_20240606_2.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717693319_3459_23565" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480420,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-HTHmARlN7khteAxXF6p_OAF9vg=/0x0:3840x2160/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480420/GTA_Online_20240606_2.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gmviD5rwUm-ZYdYQrqbeSKCNH3I=/0x0:3840x2160/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480420/GTA_Online_20240606_2.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EJsJ8fm4vzVbUa_s3sN9dEzl1lA=/0x0:3840x2160/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480420/GTA_Online_20240606_2.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Rw6OWL1Hj-5ET-S53aeRDYE53iQ=/0x0:3840x2160/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480420/GTA_Online_20240606_2.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LQRdN8CUolmiNr2q1I9GpWy4Bec=/0x0:3840x2160/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480420/GTA_Online_20240606_2.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Un1DEfzIDQlpp7UsSOSXvTVMz6s=/0x0:3840x2160/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480420/GTA_Online_20240606_2.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B9NR4Bb3O3iyA9J6o__BPziJaFM=/0x0:3840x2160/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480420/GTA_Online_20240606_2.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KQIoFcSTxInk8EzyeKfjtTOlfX4=/0x0:3840x2160/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480420/GTA_Online_20240606_2.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jnThje0yoXW5UgK7LvPJbeV8LWM=/0x0:3840x2160/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480420/GTA_Online_20240606_2.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Rockstar Games</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="2aRvYj">You can also take part in the <strong>Offense Defense Adversary Mode events</strong> this week for <strong>2x GTA$ and RP</strong>.</p>
<hr id="28qOtm">
<h2 id="ponoAs"><strong>What vehicles are for sale in GTA Online this week?</strong></h2>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480422/GTA_Online_20240606_3.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717693319_842_23566" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480422,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C6-phcwr03mBz9L2Xq525DM29Wo=/0x0:3840x2160/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480422/GTA_Online_20240606_3.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oocyWUpGCVibBXEv8Iz9y1iZjHo=/0x0:3840x2160/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480422/GTA_Online_20240606_3.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ERBAqfb_4nXFuXE_ElB8F6Pc0lw=/0x0:3840x2160/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480422/GTA_Online_20240606_3.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/M1dqAbgEgkf0FOzFaPxM4DRNowc=/0x0:3840x2160/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480422/GTA_Online_20240606_3.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YfiG40EtrhZdZ7JiIRx5DbUNKqM=/0x0:3840x2160/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480422/GTA_Online_20240606_3.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qd7c1HJlbGsJsLtYG8g67vZDQFo=/0x0:3840x2160/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480422/GTA_Online_20240606_3.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wj-VuM81dWNOLAFEzHUQ5hPKMf4=/0x0:3840x2160/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480422/GTA_Online_20240606_3.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oYhw3HjWfV6qYnGa5r0ah2zRqks=/0x0:3840x2160/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480422/GTA_Online_20240606_3.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/O8ZMCgw9GUYiSPV46NffvZMtasY=/0x0:3840x2160/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480422/GTA_Online_20240606_3.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Rockstar Games</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<h3 id="Cxu1ev"><strong>What’s in Premium Deluxe Motorsports Showroom this week?</strong></h3>
<p id="UqsRkL">Head to Simeon’s Premium Deluxe Motorsports showroom for:</p>
<ul>
<li id="Pl8FgU">
<strong>Emperor ETR1</strong> (40% off)</li>
<li id="PgJq3j"><strong>Annis Savestra</strong></li>
<li id="IJHxZK"><strong>Karin 190z</strong></li>
<li id="YY4hPg"><strong>Shitzu Hakuchou</strong></li>
<li id="0YeXEd"><strong>Dinka Verus</strong></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="nlW30E"><strong>What’s in the Luxury Autos Showroom in GTA Online this week?</strong></h3>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480423/GTA_Online_20240606_7.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717693319_6261_23567" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480423,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5hycSJhQxl9bRJ-KSyadbo0DHsE=/0x0:3840x2160/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480423/GTA_Online_20240606_7.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ll5fAlHhtt6Fz51o-zhHNhIYe1g=/0x0:3840x2160/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480423/GTA_Online_20240606_7.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aezkJsVA_TPGwKoPqzvl8ZMsdNs=/0x0:3840x2160/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480423/GTA_Online_20240606_7.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pFUAPKqMwu1GqInJcfrMz3nQLlc=/0x0:3840x2160/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480423/GTA_Online_20240606_7.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hxMiJ3Dz8muju2_7ndzzj70p36Q=/0x0:3840x2160/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480423/GTA_Online_20240606_7.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SytMTlvPt0xJBiwUel5TguKT9wM=/0x0:3840x2160/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480423/GTA_Online_20240606_7.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lZ-0IKZbh-SqhcqPprgDag7bvTk=/0x0:3840x2160/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480423/GTA_Online_20240606_7.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3x-JFzgwqDLUvb2gGsj3nd7GG8o=/0x0:3840x2160/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480423/GTA_Online_20240606_7.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V_RH7oDIj4am06YcDeAvvbI9l2g=/0x0:3840x2160/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3840x2160):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480423/GTA_Online_20240606_7.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Rockstar Games</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="khmAQR">At Luxury Autos over in Rockford Hills, you can pick up the following:</p>
<ul>
<li id="Cl4lMU"><strong>Canis Terminus</strong></li>
<li id="hnxMuJ">
<strong>Karin Vivanite</strong> </li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2J1BMf"><strong>What’s the Lucky Wheel prize car in GTA Online this week?</strong></h3>
<p id="GroqOZ">At the Diamond Casino, spin the wheel to win the <strong>Karin Previon</strong>.</p>
<hr id="jsk18X">
<h2 id="6K5mvW"><strong>What are the Salvage Yard Robbery targets in GTA Online this week?</strong></h2>
<p id="jKUviG">If you’ve set up a <a href="https://www.polygon.com/gta-online-guides/24065112/how-to-make-money">Salvage Yard</a>, you’ll be looking for <strong>Dinka Blista Kanjo </strong>as part of <strong>The Podium Robbery</strong> at Diamond Casino.</p>
<hr id="Gmn3TP">
<h2 id="v2zY1l"><strong>Which properties are discounted in GTA Online this week?</strong></h2>
<p id="m71pbb">Auto Shop properties, upgrades, and modifications are all 40% off this week. Head to Maze Bank to pick one up.</p>
<hr id="Rw0MJt">
<h2 id="w0Y6ur"><strong>What is the Gun Van selling in GTA Online this week?</strong></h2>
<p id="NCWx6N">Track down the <strong>Gun Van</strong> this week to pick up:</p>
<ul>
<li id="Orpcn3"><strong>Military rifle</strong></li>
<li id="wA4HAD"><strong>Tactical SMG</strong></li>
<li id="ELiF9O">
<strong>Battle rifle</strong> (50% with GTA+)</li>
<li id="npP84V"><strong>Pistol .50</strong></li>
<li id="PouS8h">
<strong>Heavy revolver</strong> (30% off)</li>
<li id="zaCYR4"><strong>Machete</strong></li>
<li id="ko1q95"><strong>Grenades</strong></li>
<li id="0pYCgt"><strong>Pipe bombs</strong></li>
<li id="2ckb6o"><strong>Sticky bombs</strong></li>
<li id="Z5Uiq0"><strong>Armor</strong></li>
</ul>
<hr id="ALxKpv">
<p id="3DJaHV">And if you’re playing the main game, don’t miss our list of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/guides/24001098/gta-5-cheat-code-console-ps4-ps5-xbox-pc-phone-numbers"><em>GTA 5 </em>cheats</a>.</p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sweet Tooth’s post-apocalyptic plague required a pinkie-finger-wiggling machine]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24170739/sweet-tooth-netflix-pinkie-finger-shaking-machine</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sweet-tooth%E2%80%99s-post-apocalyptic-plague-required-a-pinkie-finger-wiggling-machine.891537/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24170739/sweet-tooth-netflix-pinkie-finger-shaking-machine<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="oOdKkc"><a href="https://www.polygon.com/22517814/sweet-tooth-review-netflix"><em>Sweet Tooth</em></a>, a loose adaptation of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/comics/22538573/sweet-tooth-comic-changes-creator-jeff-lemire-interview">Jeff Lemire’s comic series of the same name</a>, is an undersung treat of Netflix’s library. The post-apocalyptic coming-of-age quest mixes the dreamlike qualities of a fable with the factional drama of a <em>Walking Dead</em> story, in a world where all human children are born as animal hybrids and a deadly virus called the Sick whittles away at teens and adults. </p>
<p id="pvYcUe">But in filming for the final season of <em>Sweet Tooth</em>, premiering today, showrunner Jim Mickle says that if anything, his long-running actors were excited about the prospect of their characters contracting the Sick.</p>
<p id="RgXxRN">You know, because it meant they’d get to try out the pinkie-finger-wiggling machine. </p>
<p id="ZW24aD">In <em>Sweet Tooth</em>, the earliest symptom of the Sick is that the patient develops an uncontrollable twitch in their littlest fingers. It’s a great visual, a tiny detail that represents huge revelations. Characters conceal and reveal their hands depending on who they trust; other characters demand to see their hands before allowing them close. In <em>Sweet Tooth</em>, a money shot of a twitching pinkie finger can be a shocking twist. </p>
<p id="jI6uQm">But we wondered: Was shaking one’s pinkie finger in complete isolation to the rest of the hand difficult for the <em>Sweet Tooth</em> cast? </p>
<p id="6atlZZ">“Yes!” Mickle told Polygon over video chat. “But you could tell that they were excited, like, <em>I get to try</em> [the pinkie finger twitch]<em>!</em> They would always get kind of into it.”</p>
<p id="WnDZdj">Mickle’s goal for the finger shaking was to make it look like an involuntary movement. “You know sometimes your eyelid flutters, or something, you have a little movement? That was exactly what I wanted it to be: a weird, involuntary thing. [...] It has to be more than just you can do naturally or organically. It has to be a thing that feels like your body is reflexively doing that.” </p>
<p id="Ho8dFR">Achieving that effect unaided was not always easy, but for anyone who found it difficult, <em>Sweet Tooth</em>’s effects team developed a bespoke pinkie-wiggling machine using the spin of a laptop’s hard drive. “That was the motor,” Mickle said, “and they connected that, basically taped it to a wire that went up someone’s arm and they just animated the hard drive and it would actually [shake their finger].” </p>
<p id="DSc0iD">By season 3, the pinkie-wiggling machine had evolved to boast its own motor that would sit underneath the actor’s clothing on their back, “and it would run up a cable that would go on your [arm with a] bicycle brake cable, and we tape it to the pinkie.” </p>
<p id="8lHhF8">Still, the devices remained finicky and were prone to failing entirely if the actor bent their elbow. “We spent probably days of our lives on set just going, <em>OK, roll!</em> and you’d roll and be like, <em>OK, and pinkie!</em> and it would just...” Here Mickle raised his hand and twitched his pinkie a measly one time. “...do that and stop. And we would constantly do that.”</p>
<p id="I0rt7o">Despite the frustrations, Mickle said, the cast was gung-ho for the device. Without wanting to reveal too much, he did let on that with the Sick becoming a bigger threat, a number of characters “that we don’t think will ever die of that suddenly start shaking, and I think [the actors] really got into it, because they never thought they’d have to do it.” </p>
<p id="g2qOlv"><small><em>Sweet Tooth</em></small><small> season 3 is out now on Netflix. </small></p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Save 50% on some of our favorite dad-centric media at Barnes & Noble]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/deals/24172825/fathers-day-movies-kino-lorber-barnes-noble-deal-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/save-50-on-some-of-our-favorite-dad-centric-media-at-barnes-noble.891534/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/deals/24172825/fathers-day-movies-kino-lorber-barnes-noble-deal-sale<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="ui3VJA"><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/b/50-off-kino-lorber-videos/_/N-303xZ1z141sz" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/b/50-off-kino-lorber-videos/_/N-303xZ1z141sz&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">Barnes &amp; Noble</a> is currently discounting an awesome selection of classic 4K Blu-ray movies from the Kino Lorber collection. Typically $39.99, each of these films can be picked up for just $19.99, giving you the perfect excuse to build out a library of essential, dad-centric cinema. While there are dozens of excellent films to choose from, we’ve hand-picked some favorites that would make great <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24161974/best-fathers-day-gift-guide-ideas">gifts for Father’s Day</a>, or any day, really.</p>
<hr id="NVi9Qk">
<h3 id="w1wgQ7"><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-great-escape-john-sturges/3623934" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-great-escape-john-sturges/3623934&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><strong>The Great Escape</strong></a></h3>
<p id="pmuQVz">The only World War 2 escape movie worth watching, <em>The Great Escape </em>features an all-star cast that includes Steve McQueen, Charles Bronson, and James Garner. Just be prepared to whistle the main theme for at least a week after watching it. </p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480305/9vh9vmt8.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717692703_4491_298223" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480305,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/otgSHMeK66MOTo9G1LsfiaWLj2c=/0x0:2400x1340/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2400x1340):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480305/9vh9vmt8.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sew8ghZkmmiZ9fZw_vITyVBJFHQ=/0x0:2400x1340/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2400x1340):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480305/9vh9vmt8.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Nn5FXzuFaJ5gZQ398ZPzyubDyEA=/0x0:2400x1340/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2400x1340):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480305/9vh9vmt8.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JRrMtJKVhmH28xClj7FwydDOSOI=/0x0:2400x1340/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2400x1340):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480305/9vh9vmt8.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CawtdW7JSOvKkVAwyBOpIXbBeM0=/0x0:2400x1340/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2400x1340):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480305/9vh9vmt8.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s93Ypl-aqWAyohjxGHKhrsg7ZwM=/0x0:2400x1340/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2400x1340):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480305/9vh9vmt8.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mmZEThmjQGc2naAeDSnFTpXz4yA=/0x0:2400x1340/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2400x1340):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480305/9vh9vmt8.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/04IRY6vWuu1ng8KPRSY-5HxVKpE=/0x0:2400x1340/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2400x1340):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480305/9vh9vmt8.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XPTjAiptyjyWU6Ru8Ykl2hvxTB4=/0x0:2400x1340/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2400x1340):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480305/9vh9vmt8.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: United Artists</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<div id="YGFFW4">
    <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Barnes &amp; Noble         $20         (51% off)" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-great-escape-john-sturges/3623934" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-great-escape-john-sturges/3623934&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $20
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at Barnes &amp; Noble
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
    </ul>
  </div>
<hr id="yDMUxC">
<h3 id="tdTiyC"><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-sergio-leone/3624077" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-sergio-leone/3624077&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><strong>The Good, The Bad, and The Ugly</strong></a></h3>
<p id="vVwkKf">The final installment in Sergio Leone’s “Dollars” trilogy starring Clint Eastwood and scored by Ennio Morricone, <em>The Good, The Bad, and The Ugly</em> has inspired countless films and remains a testament to deliberate filmmaking. The other films in the trilogy, <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-a-fistful-of-dollars-sergio-leone/3624065" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-a-fistful-of-dollars-sergio-leone/3624065&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><em>A Fistful of Dollars</em></a> and <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-for-a-few-dollars-more-sergio-leone/3624073" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-for-a-few-dollars-more-sergio-leone/3624073&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><em>A Few Dollars More</em></a><em>,</em> are also on sale.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480304/h22hieka.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717692703_9862_298224" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480304,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1j_STH7XC4kYSH2WvtMBS1vmTU4=/0x0:1440x810/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1440x810):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480304/h22hieka.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Z2O0U96_qeHROqgO8xBL030SDSA=/0x0:1440x810/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1440x810):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480304/h22hieka.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RbkFTmQQ0iwJY2PYdCnFoYiyDw0=/0x0:1440x810/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1440x810):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480304/h22hieka.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UP0AFHxzhPtJr8bzsm9pNZl5d7w=/0x0:1440x810/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1440x810):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480304/h22hieka.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JgMy4nsrWFAwRKy2ovK6NAyFkcs=/0x0:1440x810/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1440x810):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480304/h22hieka.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ON0WcpQG-1KjxMLixrECcjrf0rg=/0x0:1440x810/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1440x810):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480304/h22hieka.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FbzP8fa8Vr3RKKt_T9gMysq1X34=/0x0:1440x810/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1440x810):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480304/h22hieka.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RW7_dPryZrZFthLlS3Vr_2sqEbA=/0x0:1440x810/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1440x810):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480304/h22hieka.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e7gFld8N46yyzIAKowKrP3D0hJQ=/0x0:1440x810/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1440x810):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480304/h22hieka.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: United Artists</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<div id="LqsVed">
    <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Barnes &amp; Noble         $20         (51% off)" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-sergio-leone/3624077" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-sergio-leone/3624077&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $20
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at Barnes &amp; Noble
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
    </ul>
  </div>
<hr id="YmV1Nv">
<h3 id="3urJDR"><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-silence-of-the-lambs-jonathan-demme/3620929" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-silence-of-the-lambs-jonathan-demme/3620929&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><strong>Silence of the Lambs</strong></a></h3>
<p id="NXRBbR">The film that inspired a million terrible impersonations of Anthony Hopkins, <em>Silence of the Lambs</em> is a terrifying and tense psychological thriller that introduced the world to Hannibal Lecter. The other films in the “trilogy,” <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-hannibal-ridley-scott/5115313" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-hannibal-ridley-scott/5115313&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><em>Hannibal</em></a> and <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-red-dragon-brett-ratner/40345617" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-red-dragon-brett-ratner/40345617&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><em>Red Dragon</em></a><em>,</em> are also featured in this sale.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480303/g2972dmf.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717692703_1091_298225" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480303,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ogSgR3adZQ-i8qFpUdFXjjSiOqo=/0x0:1500x844/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1500x844):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480303/g2972dmf.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jVRjfGJMSs1cUkLldZJ03eNvIsc=/0x0:1500x844/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1500x844):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480303/g2972dmf.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ah23wdsut5S7IoSEUX6Yy6eO5Mo=/0x0:1500x844/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1500x844):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480303/g2972dmf.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/54sFiMusxAsJceGrPZjPv59Hd9Y=/0x0:1500x844/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1500x844):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480303/g2972dmf.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vKktvkwJ5zKcRP2aNLG9vx_RbSw=/0x0:1500x844/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1500x844):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480303/g2972dmf.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WQ3op6K2y4iJdTTqW22ycqYS6Lk=/0x0:1500x844/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1500x844):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480303/g2972dmf.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MS1lTBBCQiBJZmMX_SC8i7wtEp8=/0x0:1500x844/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1500x844):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480303/g2972dmf.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ozn-9ipbDyGqraVUXp5gPEHGimM=/0x0:1500x844/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1500x844):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480303/g2972dmf.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZUiLF6itANm-k2vWNDPNa3hJQRY=/0x0:1500x844/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1500x844):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480303/g2972dmf.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Orion Pictures</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<div id="Mv2Vac">
    <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Barnes &amp; Noble         $20         (51% off)" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-silence-of-the-lambs-jonathan-demme/3620929" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-the-silence-of-the-lambs-jonathan-demme/3620929&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $20
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at Barnes &amp; Noble
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
    </ul>
  </div>
<hr id="ZroKuq">
<h3 id="4fYsQ7"><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-in-bruges-martin-mcdonagh/12002806" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-in-bruges-martin-mcdonagh/12002806&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><strong>In Bruges</strong></a></h3>
<p id="Tor9h7"><em>In Bruges</em> is a buddy comedy bookended by moments of occasional violence and crass humor. It stars a pair of hitmen seeking shelter in the sleepy Belgian town of Bruges, which inevitably forces them to reassess their choice of career.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480301/7uup0pah.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717692703_2188_298226" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480301,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oJ-8Z7vWUHThqkFg_CzqH52v6vQ=/0x0:1200x500/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x500):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480301/7uup0pah.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wMKB0o4Hb1kVECI9BnClltCTb6c=/0x0:1200x500/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x500):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480301/7uup0pah.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5-OC4WA9sVZQ1f_g9du1-TKBXpQ=/0x0:1200x500/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x500):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480301/7uup0pah.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y8DRdusE0vTglZ-ni_jcFCqnjRA=/0x0:1200x500/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x500):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480301/7uup0pah.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zYymAAOfMO7QEdzrznuNlunaJ-E=/0x0:1200x500/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x500):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480301/7uup0pah.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LmbStWY6cz0N_4-nA5SYmp_BNWU=/0x0:1200x500/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x500):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480301/7uup0pah.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WJL83CYyeYQ_LDxfPIYkfBvcVVo=/0x0:1200x500/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x500):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480301/7uup0pah.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QRfASihN49I_z2QqqtXt847ghYk=/0x0:1200x500/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x500):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480301/7uup0pah.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/s92x_S6eC_CjPE3VyRmqi0U3GrQ=/0x0:1200x500/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1200x500):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480301/7uup0pah.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Focus Features</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<div id="4EreWD">
    <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Barnes &amp; Noble         $20         (51% off)" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-in-bruges-martin-mcdonagh/12002806" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-in-bruges-martin-mcdonagh/12002806&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $20
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at Barnes &amp; Noble
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
    </ul>
  </div>
<hr id="dkUPVZ">
<h3 id="WouEmw"><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-tinker-tailor-soldier-spy-tomas-alfredson/22416047" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-tinker-tailor-soldier-spy-tomas-alfredson/22416047&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><strong>Tinker, Tailor, Soldier, Spy</strong></a></h3>
<p id="WcXVIL">An amazing Cold War-era spy thriller,<em> Tinker, Tailor, Soldier, Spy</em> feels like a collection of virtually every actor Britain has produced in the past decade. A short list of appearances includes Gary Oldman, Benedict Cumberbatch, Colin Firth, Tom Hardy, John Hurt, and Mark Strong.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480331/128k4p1b.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717692703_6171_298227" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480331,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vx98BhIT-aYndg9NCfyUpkdZv0s=/0x0:2000x1058/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1058):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480331/128k4p1b.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_Rm78pQNmeTU1MbnTUcaHw--OEM=/0x0:2000x1058/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1058):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480331/128k4p1b.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/GZ5_F6H2TrKv8hinmQIdIf8B5e4=/0x0:2000x1058/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1058):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480331/128k4p1b.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7Q16ZQpV3d0F1LbVTQ-eLjiDwxQ=/0x0:2000x1058/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1058):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480331/128k4p1b.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IHtanweMfPl8GukTJnT96gNtPmc=/0x0:2000x1058/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1058):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480331/128k4p1b.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xCahdx-IgDUO8hBDB-4ISTfAvM0=/0x0:2000x1058/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1058):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480331/128k4p1b.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jaqweB4ZVN6i_Bt0X5p0fE65UIM=/0x0:2000x1058/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1058):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480331/128k4p1b.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IwXeEK0P2a5fwebvEJtDC1p0FYQ=/0x0:2000x1058/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1058):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480331/128k4p1b.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vYcZH6dlD-8AZ9ez9NFTF_aNqik=/0x0:2000x1058/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2000x1058):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480331/128k4p1b.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: StudioCanal</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<div id="slMa67">
    <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Barnes &amp; Noble         $20         (51% off)" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-tinker-tailor-soldier-spy-tomas-alfredson/22416047" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-tinker-tailor-soldier-spy-tomas-alfredson/22416047&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $20
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at Barnes &amp; Noble
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
    </ul>
  </div>
<hr id="Wj3Gvn">
<h3 id="Plrkxk"><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-spaceballs-mel-brooks/3624030" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-spaceballs-mel-brooks/3624030&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><strong>Spaceballs</strong></a></h3>
<p id="gVv6SE">The original Star Wars parody, <em>Spaceballs</em> is arguably Mel Brooks’ best work and fits in countless jabs and subtle nods to the George Lucas franchise.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480298/hdshi3x9.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717692703_574_298228" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480298,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gpS6QPDFvm7YW5KpkmwRhRinGEk=/0x0:2556x1040/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2556x1040):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480298/hdshi3x9.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TBTqVceQms622PwyFqeSAhq2L6k=/0x0:2556x1040/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2556x1040):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480298/hdshi3x9.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/227cXIYBr8BjoIwL7hGHSQEbmaQ=/0x0:2556x1040/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2556x1040):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480298/hdshi3x9.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HoR6SAq3bXHLST_6TwTnT9vTti4=/0x0:2556x1040/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2556x1040):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480298/hdshi3x9.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p280EUaMM-QZ_cBkbmp4NzzuWe8=/0x0:2556x1040/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2556x1040):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480298/hdshi3x9.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HA_Yrtn3fsUS_GdyGxoZiK-eg5w=/0x0:2556x1040/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2556x1040):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480298/hdshi3x9.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ibkUbZrQTQAAQAfGpdTLo33zaUk=/0x0:2556x1040/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2556x1040):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480298/hdshi3x9.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NuSCoy44pPsDMuUHluT45o--H9c=/0x0:2556x1040/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2556x1040):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480298/hdshi3x9.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uZNvhBfSVw2a5nYsU134KYysoUI=/0x0:2556x1040/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2556x1040):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480298/hdshi3x9.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: MGM Studios</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<div id="ItH3IG">
    <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Barnes &amp; Noble         $20         (51% off)" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-spaceballs-mel-brooks/3624030" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-spaceballs-mel-brooks/3624030&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $20
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at Barnes &amp; Noble
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
    </ul>
  </div>
<hr id="iYJkBy">
<h3 id="74CTnD"><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-12-angry-men-sidney-lumet/3623177" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-12-angry-men-sidney-lumet/3623177&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}"><strong>12 Angry Men</strong></a></h3>
<p id="Dr5uMc"><em>12 Angry Men</em> hits just as hard now as it did back in 1957. A true pressure cooker of a film, this monochrome classic proves how much you can do with a cast of 12 dudes in a single room.</p>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480296/613g0zgd.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1717692703_4667_298229" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25480296,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/D1FKcYiOXgP4rG_lzH4UKTCeVVA=/0x0:1400x700/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1400x700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480296/613g0zgd.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vCE-N5zocQ6Nr9m02hq1kW688Rw=/0x0:1400x700/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1400x700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480296/613g0zgd.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hpZo19C15E3LywmlcgUP42iKwvg=/0x0:1400x700/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1400x700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480296/613g0zgd.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RJknC-AwBjRSgmwQWOANeGhNxGY=/0x0:1400x700/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1400x700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480296/613g0zgd.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dnep6ToK_LBxrwYLayh6L15zd-U=/0x0:1400x700/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1400x700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480296/613g0zgd.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sxUNlxKJMv9_5nIlkwxmKWhQ1lY=/0x0:1400x700/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1400x700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480296/613g0zgd.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FjjRx2HItuTyhk0SmjBQBTXP4xk=/0x0:1400x700/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1400x700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480296/613g0zgd.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6CBtAdB8qlqCCYzqEyCvtizKLuw=/0x0:1400x700/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1400x700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480296/613g0zgd.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Atjd9mxgnFVRrjBQd3l9bPp2nfk=/0x0:1400x700/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1400x700):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25480296/613g0zgd.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: United Artists</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<div id="SnTnV1">
    <ul>
    
      
        <li>
          <a data-analytics-link="product-card" data-analytics-viewport="product-card" data-vars-analytics-action="product-card" data-vars-analytics-link-title="Barnes &amp; Noble         $20         (51% off)" has-subtag="true" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/polygon/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-12-angry-men-sidney-lumet/3623177" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder/https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/dvd-12-angry-men-sidney-lumet/3623177&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:64,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;sid&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;sid&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23936866__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">
             
             <span>
               $20
             </span>
             
           <span>
              at Barnes &amp; Noble
           </span>
          </a>
        </li>
      
    
    </ul>
  </div>



  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After All These Years, I Still Wish Destiny Had An Offline Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-server-error-offline-1851523773</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-all-these-years-i-still-wish-destiny-had-an-offline-mode.891531/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-server-error-offline-1851523773<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>As I sit here, on June 6, 2024 at 11:45 a.m., two days after <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-impressions-1851521089&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-impressions-1851521089"><em>The Final Shape</em></a></span> launched—<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-final-shape-d3-witness-raid-1851504108&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-final-shape-d3-witness-raid-1851504108"><em>Destiny</em>’s last expansion in the story arc</a></span> it <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-messy-true-story-behind-the-making-of-destiny-1737556731&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-messy-true-story-behind-the-making-of-destiny-1737556731">clumsily started more than a decade ago</a></span>—I am notably <em>not</em> blasting aliens nor taking in sweeping sci-fi vistas. I am not playing at all.</p><div data-video-id="196923" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="355" data-playlist="196923,196922,196918" data-current="196923"><div><p>Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22494.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-servers-1851519144&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-servers-1851519144"><em>Destiny 2: The Final Shape</em>’s Campaign Is A Messy, Moving High School Reunion</a></span></p><p>Nope, I’ve been sitting here looking at the “One Moment Please” screen for about 15 minutes now, with repeated interruptions of “Destiny servers are not available” that take me back to the title screen, where I then need to hit Enter just to wait yet again. Well, at least there’s some nice music to listen to.</p><figure id="" data-id="9f96809e0f345f39422526f036aa3bcf" data-recommend-id="image://9f96809e0f345f39422526f036aa3bcf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An error screen in Destiny 2 prevents the player from playing the game." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An error screen in Destiny 2 prevents the player from playing the game." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bungie / Claire Jackson / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="9f96809e0f345f39422526f036aa3bcf" data-recommend-id="image://9f96809e0f345f39422526f036aa3bcf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An error screen in Destiny 2 prevents the player from playing the game." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-servers-1851519144&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-servers-1851519144">connectivity issue</a></span> speaks to a larger discomfort I’ve had with <em>Destiny</em> since 2013: its existence as an online-only game—one that not only requires an active internet connection, as well as multiple players to complete its bigger and more rewarding activities, but one that has removed, or “vaulted” earlier parts of the game. If this were an offline game, it would still be mine to play.</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-messy-true-story-behind-the-making-of-destiny-1737556731&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-messy-true-story-behind-the-making-of-destiny-1737556731">The Messy, True Story Behind The Making Of <em>Destiny</em></a></span></p><p>That last point has been exacerbated for me during my time spent playing <em>The Final Shape</em>, which sends players to an old location not seen since <em>Destiny 2</em> launched in 2017. If I wanted to remind myself of its consequence, to relive it in its original context, I simply cannot. I don’t like that I can’t go back and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/destiny-the-final-shape-ten-years-tiktok-1851518305&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-the-final-shape-ten-years-tiktok-1851518305">play all of this story</a></span> from <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-lore-catch-up-mynameisbyf-1851513216&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-lore-catch-up-mynameisbyf-1851513216">beginning to end</a></span> without massive gaps. </p><p>I get that <em>Destiny</em> didn’t have some sort of grand plan for its story to unfold over the course of a decade. You don’t need a degree in literature to see that recent developments weren’t in the minds of writers when the game first shipped in 2013. Hell, if you finished the first <em>Destiny</em> campaign, it was pretty obvious that there really wasn’t much of a story, beyond references to wizards on moons and characters literally saying they didn’t have time to explain why they didn’t have time to explain.</p><figure id="" data-id="03a95ba5f73a3d01b7e69ca1a5a8e3bc" data-recommend-id="image://03a95ba5f73a3d01b7e69ca1a5a8e3bc" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Guardian visits the old tower in Destiny 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Guardian visits the old tower in Destiny 2." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bungie / Claire Jackson / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="03a95ba5f73a3d01b7e69ca1a5a8e3bc" data-recommend-id="image://03a95ba5f73a3d01b7e69ca1a5a8e3bc" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Guardian visits the old tower in Destiny 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>But I would still like to be able to play this solar-system-spanning adventure from beginning to end. I want to see and hear the evolution of its world-class far-future sci-fi aesthetic shift and evolve over the course of a massive campaign. Heck, right now, I want to be able to play it <em>at all</em>. I want to play it like an offline, single-player game.</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/destiny-the-final-shape-ten-years-tiktok-1851518305&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/destiny-the-final-shape-ten-years-tiktok-1851518305"><em>Destiny 2: The Final Shape</em> Has Players Getting Emotional About The Last 10 Years</a></span></p><p>Alas, I can’t. The original <em>Destiny 2</em> campaign and the three expansions that followed are locked away. And several other events were temporary, ephemeral, only to be lived in and enjoyed in the moment. I can appreciate that conceptually, but I’m not sure if I like it in exchange for concrete experiences I can take in on my own, with the ability to go through a complete story arc, and see how this wild sci-fi story came to be what it is now.</p><p>There’s value in multiplayer experiences for sure. But as I sit here and am still looking at repeat “Error” screens that have persisted throughout my entire writing of this blog, I just really wish I could play the main story on my own, without an internet connection. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/redfall-final-update-arkane-austin-1851509877&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/redfall-final-update-arkane-austin-1851509877">Even <em>Redfall</em> now has that</a></span>. C’mon <em>Destiny</em>. <br></p><p>.<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will We See Dragon Age The Veilguard at Summer Game Fest? – Answered]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-veilguard-summer-game-fest-answered/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/will-we-see-dragon-age-the-veilguard-at-summer-game-fest-%E2%80%93-answered.891528/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-veilguard-summer-game-fest-answered/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Following the hunger for the genre after the release of Baldur’s Gate 3, we desperately need a big-name RPG to hit digital storefronts and sweep people off their feet. We might have that on the horizon with Dragon Age: The Veilguard, but only time will tell. For now, will we see Dragon Age: The Veilguard at Summer Game Fest?</p>



<h2 id="h-is-dragon-age-the-veilguard-coming-to-summer-game-fest">Is Dragon Age The Veilguard Coming to Summer Game Fest?</h2>



<p>Previously, we heard about a Dragon Age: Dreadwolf <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/will-we-see-dragon-age-dreadwolf-at-summer-game-fest-answered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reveal in the </a>Summer of 2024, indicating a Summer Game Fest showing. However, with the recent name change to Dragon Age: The Veilguard, we know for a fact that we’ll see a full reveal on June 11. That is, of course, following the conclusion of Summer Game Fest, which ends on June 10. It appears EA wants the spotlight to themselves, so they’re waiting until the show’s end.</p>







<h2 id="h-do-we-know-when-dragon-age-the-veilguard-releases">Do We Know When Dragon Age The Veilguard Releases?</h2>



<p>While the title of the upcoming RPG may have changed, the release window has not shifted. We previously reported on the game <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-dreadwolf-will-reportedly-launch-by-march-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launching by March 2025</a>. That’s still the most likely case, though we still have months to go.</p>



<p>Personally, I’m hoping for a fall or winter 2024 release, something I can play over an extended winter vacation. However, it appears early 2025 is the most likely timeframe we have!</p>



<hr>



<p>If you need something to play in the meantime, there are a bunch of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-reveals-new-game-pass-titles-for-june-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">upcoming games hitting Xbox Game Pass</a>! In the meantime, we’d love to have you join us by signing up for the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>!</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft is Going to Remaster Halo: Combat Evolved Again and is Considering a PS5 Release, Says New Report]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/halo-combat-evolved-remaster/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-is-going-to-remaster-halo-combat-evolved-again-and-is-considering-a-ps5-release-says-new-report.891525/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/halo-combat-evolved-remaster/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Microsoft is reportedly in the early stages of developing another remaster of Halo: Combat Evolved and is considering releasing it on PlayStation 5.</p>



<p>That’s according to Tom Warren at The Verge, who received the website’s new <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/6/24172684/microsoft-xbox-showcase-2024" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">‘Notepad’ newsletter</a> (subscription required, but the first 30 days are free). </p>



<p>The report outlines other details surrounding the upcoming Xbox Games Showcase, including the fact that Microsoft is going to port other games under “Project Latitude”. However, according to Warren, Fable, Gears 6 and South of Midnight are currently not planned for porting. The new Doom game, which will be called <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/doom-the-dark-ages/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Doom: The Dark Ages will be</a>. </p>



<p>Halo: Combat Evolved has already been remastered once before as part of the Halo: Combat Evolved Anniversary. The remaster included the game being remade with 343 Industries’ in-house game engine and would include achievements, Terminals, and Skulls. The game was originally released in November 2011 and re-released as part of the Halo: The Master Chief Collection. </p>



<p>What do you think of a Halo: Combat Evolved remaster coming to PlayStation 5? Let us know in the comments below.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, check out a new report that states that one minute of trailer runtime at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/summer-game-fest-trailer-price/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Summer Game Fest and The Game Awards will cost publishers $250,000</a>, and don’t forget to sign up to receive&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bungie continues to monitor Destiny 2 as servers undergo maintenance]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/bungie-continues-to-monitor-destiny-2-as-servers-undergo-maintenance/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=bungie-continues-to-monitor-destiny-2-as-servers-undergo-maintenance</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bungie-continues-to-monitor-destiny-2-as-servers-undergo-maintenance.891522/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/bungie-continues-to-monitor-destiny-2-as-servers-undergo-maintenance/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=bungie-continues-to-monitor-destiny-2-as-servers-undergo-maintenance<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="342" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Another day, another disastrous launch from a recognized brand. This time, Bungie was in the line of fire after launching the latest DLC for <em>Destiny 2</em>. While <em>The Final Shape</em> is “shaping up” (how do I come up with such quality gags?!) to be a great addition to the game, there have been some major teething problems from the start.</p> <p data-characters="200" data-current-count="200" data-injectable="false">After the new content was released, major connection problems were almost immediately noticed. As such, the developer has had to quickly step in with fixes and the promise of some much-needed patches.</p> <figure data-current-count="500" data-injectable="true"><div> <blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>DESTINY 2 MAINTENANCE<br>❖ Update 8.0.0.2</p><p>Maintenance has begun. Destiny 2 is being brought offline for expected maintenance.</p><p>REMAINING TIMELINE<br>❖ Downtime ends: 8 AM</p><p>More info: <a href="https://t.co/48Mjp1drx7">https://t.co/48Mjp1drx7</a></p></div>— Bungie Help (@BungieHelp) <a href="https://twitter.com/BungieHelp/status/1798697598381138332?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 6, 2024</a></blockquote> </div></figure>
 <p data-characters="297" data-current-count="297" data-injectable="false">A recent post on Twitter/X from the Bungie Help account says that, as of now, <em>Destiny 2</em> servers have been “brought offline for expected maintenance.” This period is expected to last until 8AM PDT, but you can keep an eye on things via the Twitter account and/or the <a href="https://help.bungie.net/hc/en-us/articles/360049199271-Destiny-Server-and-Update-Status" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">server status page</a>.</p> <h2 id="h-seems-to-be-good-otherwise" data-injectable="false">Seems to be good, otherwise</h2> <p data-characters="218" data-current-count="515" data-injectable="true">After the debacle that was <em>The Final Shape</em>‘s poor connectivity and general server issues, fans immediately took to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2336880/Destiny_2_The_Final_Shape/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a> to register their complaints, where the DLC was downvoted to “Mostly Negative.”</p>
 <p data-characters="273" data-current-count="273" data-injectable="false">Fortunately, some mends and quick fixes were implemented and things seem to be only getting better. In fact, at the time of writing, the expansion is now at “mixed” and a lot of recent feedback shows that it could well be one of the best DLCs <em>Destiny 2</em> has had.</p> <p data-characters="389" data-current-count="662" data-injectable="false">However, there’s that lingering metaphorical fart in the air once more, as we find ourselves enmeshed in the ongoing backlash against studios and publishers that are putting out content that’s clearly not fit for consumption. Sure, the developer is on the case – which is typically how these things go – but it’s a concern that day launch in this state to begin with.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monolith’s Wonder Woman game is reportedly ‘troubled’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/monoliths-wonder-woman-game-is-reportedly-troubled/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=monoliths-wonder-woman-game-is-reportedly-troubled</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monolith%E2%80%99s-wonder-woman-game-is-reportedly-%E2%80%98troubled%E2%80%99.891519/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/monoliths-wonder-woman-game-is-reportedly-troubled/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=monoliths-wonder-woman-game-is-reportedly-troubled<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="285" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">The <em>Wonder Woman</em> game in development at Monolith Productions is reportedly “going through a “troubled” phase. The claim comes from Kinda Funny Gamescast host Greg Miller, who also adds that he is not holding hope for the game to be showcased at the upcoming Summer Game Fest.</p> <p data-characters="402" data-current-count="402" data-injectable="true">Here’s Miller’s complete quote from the podcast: “Here you go, you want it? You want the exclusive? I’ll give you my ‘Jeff Grubb’ information. In the past year – cause I’ll leave it ambiguous – I have talked to an insider, who was like, ‘This game’s troubled.’ That’s it, that’s all I’ll say. So I don’t hold out hope that it’s in a place to show something.”</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Summer Game Fest 2024 Predictions - Kinda Funny Gamescast" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2kJQjUgT_QY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="379" data-current-count="679" data-injectable="true">Interestingly, the studio has announced it is <a href="https://x.com/MonolithDev/status/1798401921465921768?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">looking for a lead gameplay engineer</a>, and the announcement comes days after Miller’s comment during the podcast. While hiring for roles is not that big of a deal, the lead role hiring does raise eyebrows. Given that Monolith has been working on the title since 2021, it may take some more time before we learn more about this game.</p>
 <p data-characters="168" data-current-count="168" data-injectable="false">It remains to be seen if <em>Wonder Woman</em> will be showcased at the Summer Game Fest or not, but it sounds like all signs point towards its absence at this year’s SGF.</p> <figure data-current-count="468" data-injectable="true"><p> <iframe title="Wonder Woman - Official Game Announcement Teaser" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dyA8lnp9Tzg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure>
 <p data-characters="285" data-current-count="285" data-injectable="false">Back when the game was announced, Monolith Productions had released a short, cinematic trailer, which offered a first look at <em>Wonder Woman</em>. It was also revealed in 2021 that the game will be a single-player title with an open world, and will carry an original story in the DC Universe.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s why Jeremy Renner turned down a Mission: Impossible return]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/heres-why-jeremy-renner-turned-down-a-mission-impossible-return/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=heres-why-jeremy-renner-turned-down-a-mission-impossible-return</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here%E2%80%99s-why-jeremy-renner-turned-down-a-mission-impossible-return.891516/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/heres-why-jeremy-renner-turned-down-a-mission-impossible-return/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=heres-why-jeremy-renner-turned-down-a-mission-impossible-return<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="325" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Jeremy Renner, who played William Brandt in the <em>Mission: Impossible</em> movies, has now revealed why he turned down the opportunity to return to the franchise. Renner was offered a role in <em>Mission: Impossible – Fallout</em> but bowed out because he did not agree with the direction his character in the film was heading towards.</p> <p data-characters="275" data-current-count="275" data-injectable="false">Renner was recently on the Happy, Sad, Confused Podcast where he was asked to explain why Brandt was missing in <em>Mission: Impossible – Fallout</em>, which came out back in 2018. He said that he declined to return because his character was going to be killed off in the movie.</p> <p data-characters="115" data-current-count="390" data-injectable="false">“If you’re going to do this, and you’re going to use my character, you’re going to do it right,” he said.</p> <p data-characters="268" data-current-count="658" data-injectable="true">The actor further explained, “I remember they tried to bring me over[seas] for a week so they could kill my character, and I was like, ‘No, you don’t get to do that. You’re not going to drag me over there and just kill my character,’ like get out of here!”</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Jeremy Renner talks accident, AVENGERS return, MAYOR OF KINGSTOWN I Happy Sad Confused" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cn5a57rH2XI?feature=oembed&amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;origin=https://www.destructoid.com" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="145" data-current-count="445" data-injectable="true">Renner said he yelled at the director, telling him, “Dude, you’re not going to do this to me like that; you’re not going to do me wrong.”</p>
 <p data-characters="209" data-current-count="209" data-injectable="false">The actor also revealed that he had left the franchise because he wanted to focus on his responsibilities as a father, and it was hard to spend time with the family since the filming took place overseas.&nbsp;</p> <p data-characters="259" data-current-count="468" data-injectable="false">While this sounds like Renner is not going to make a return to the franchise, all hope is not lost. He said during the podcast that he is open to returning as William Brandt. However, it is clear that the role must have significance for Renner to consider it.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2: The Final Shape – Every team to watch for the Salvation’s Edge race to world first]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-teams-to-watch-salvations-edge-race-world-first/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=destiny-2-the-final-shape-teams-to-watch-salvations-edge-race-world-first</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destiny-2-the-final-shape-%E2%80%93-every-team-to-watch-for-the-salvation%E2%80%99s-edge-race-to-world-first.891513/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/destiny-2-the-final-shape-teams-to-watch-salvations-edge-race-world-first/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=destiny-2-the-final-shape-teams-to-watch-salvations-edge-race-world-first<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="283" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><em>Destiny 2: The Final Shape</em> brought with it a brand new raid for players to prepare for and race in just three days later. <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/destiny-2-salvations-edge-raid-schedule-and-details-for-the-final-shape-race/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Salvation’s Edge</a> sees Guardians confront The Witness, possibly the toughest monster the universe has ever seen, but only one fireteam can finish it first. </p> <p data-characters="463" data-current-count="463" data-injectable="true">Every time a new raid is added to <em>Destiny 2</em>, <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/power-level-requirements-to-raid-destiny-2-the-final-shape-salvations-edge/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">players prepare themselves</a> and their fireteams to take part in the race to finish it before anyone else. For the first 48 hours that Salvation’s Edge is live, it’ll be on Contest Mode, meaning Bungie is actively tracking those playing it to see who finishes it first. Content creators and hardcore fans alike will be getting in on this one because <em>The Final Shape</em> is the last major expansion for the game. </p>
 <h2 data-injectable="false">When does the Salvation’s Edge race for world first start in <em>Destiny 2: The Final Shape</em>?</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="347" data-current-count="647" data-injectable="true">The race for world first in Salvation’s Edge in <em>Destiny 2: The Final Shape</em> will start at <strong>1 PM ET on June 7, 2024</strong>. From that point, all teams will have 48 hours to complete the raid and claim the title of being first, for which they’ll all receive fabulous rewards like exclusive jackets, as has been the case with most previous raids. </p>
 <h2 id="h-all-teams-to-watch-for-the-salvation-s-edge-race-to-world-first-in-destiny-2-the-final-shape" data-injectable="false">All teams to watch for the Salvation’s Edge race to world first in <em>Destiny 2: The Final Shape</em></h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Bungie</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="379" data-current-count="679" data-injectable="true">We won’t know every team competing in the race for world first in Salvation’s Edge in <em>Destiny 2: The Final</em> <em>Shape</em> until the race begins. However, a few content creators always jump into the race when a new raid drops, so I’ve included links to their channels below so you can see what they’re up to and how far into the raid they are when the race begins. </p>
 <h3 data-injectable="false">Twitch Rivals</h3> <p data-characters="284" data-current-count="284" data-injectable="false">Bungie has teamed up with Twitch Rivals for the race to world first in Salvation’s Edge. Hundreds of streamers are participating, so it’s worth looking at the <a href="https://schedule.twitchrivals.com/events/destiny-2-the-final-shape-world-first-race-on-twitch-rivals-dB9PP?utm_source=%C3%9CberStrategist+PR+List+-+Leading+Gaming+and+Tech+News+%282023%29&amp;utm_campaign=29b315260d-EMAIL_CAMPAIGN_2024_06_05_02_09&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_term=0_-29b315260d-%5BLIST_EMAIL_ID%5D" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official website</a> to find one you like and watch them work their way through the raid during this contest period. </p> <h3 data-injectable="false">BobDuckNWeave</h3> <p data-characters="286" data-current-count="570" data-injectable="true">BobDuckNWeave is a talented streamer who has accepted the challenge to tackle the race for world first in Salvation’s Edge. He’s a good one to watch if you don’t know where to go but want to guarantee the stream will be a good time. <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/bobducknweave" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Check out his Twitch channel here</a>. </p>
 <h3 data-injectable="false">Gladd</h3> <p data-characters="213" data-current-count="213" data-injectable="false">Gladd has been playing <em>The Final Shape</em> since its launch and is one of the best <em>Destiny 2</em> content creators. Even if he doesn’t win, his stream will be a fantastic one to watch. <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/gladd" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Go to his Twitch channel here</a>. </p> <h3 data-injectable="false">Datto</h3> <p data-characters="183" data-current-count="396" data-injectable="false">Datto is well-known in the <em>Destiny 2 </em>community and is one of the most wholesome content creators in the space. His stream will likely be quite analytical. <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/datto" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">See his Twitch channel here</a>.</p> <h3 data-injectable="false">Saltagreppo</h3> <p data-characters="219" data-current-count="615" data-injectable="true">Saltagreppo is another content creator who has been keeping up with <em>The Final Shape</em> since launch and looks to be in a great place for streaming Salvation’s Edge when it goes live. <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/saltagreppo" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Visit their Twitch channel here</a>. </p>
 <h3 data-injectable="false">King Gothalion</h3> <p data-characters="212" data-current-count="212" data-injectable="false">King Gothalion is another name synonymous with <em>Destiny 2</em>. I’ve watched him every time a secret has been unlocked in the game because he just won’t stop until he finds it. <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/kinggothalion" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">See his Twitch channel here</a>. </p> <h3 data-injectable="false">Clan Elysium</h3> <p data-characters="338" data-current-count="550" data-injectable="true">Clan Elysium has world first titles for the second launch of Vault of Glass, King’s Fall, and Crota’s End, as well as Vow of the Disciple. They’ve got an excellent track record and are probably the best bet to win the race in Salvation’s Edge. See their <a href="https://x.com/clanelysiumd2" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Twitter profile here</a> to keep up to date with their streams. </p>
 <p data-characters="262" data-current-count="262" data-injectable="false">Note that this isn’t a comprehensive list of every competing team. We’ll add more as we discover them, but these are the most notable content creators who will almost certainly be competing, as well as those who have claimed they’ll be racing. </p> <h2 data-injectable="false">Who is winning the race for world first in Salvation’s Edge in <em>Destiny 2: The Final Shape</em>?</h2> <figure data-current-count="562" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="339" data-current-count="339" data-injectable="false">At the time of writing, the race for world first in Salvation’s Edge in <em>Destiny 2: The Final Shape</em> hasn’t started yet. As soon as it does, I’ll update this section of the article with the team that is furthest ahead of all the others. I expect this to be quite a close race, so the team in first could change frequently. </p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can you claim past season rewards in Destiny 2?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/can-you-claim-past-season-rewards-in-destiny-2/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=can-you-claim-past-season-rewards-in-destiny-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/can-you-claim-past-season-rewards-in-destiny-2.891507/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/can-you-claim-past-season-rewards-in-destiny-2/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=can-you-claim-past-season-rewards-in-destiny-2<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="468" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">A new season of <em>Destiny 2</em> means a lot of different things. Outside of all the new season-related content (known now as <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/how-power-works-in-destiny-2-the-final-shape/">Episode Acts</a>), much of the content from the previous season is now permanently gone. There may be the odd vendor to spend your old resources, but that’s as far as it goes. With that in mind, you might be wondering if you can claim the rewards you may have forgotten to snag. Here’s whether you can claim past season rewards in <em>Destiny 2</em>.</p> <h2 id="h-can-you-get-rewards-from-previous-seasons-in-destiny-2" data-injectable="false">Can you get rewards from previous seasons in Destiny 2?</h2> <p data-characters="458" data-current-count="458" data-injectable="true">You can still get rewards from previous seasons in Destiny 2. If you want to claim the rewards you’ve earned from the last season (at the time of writing, <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/how-to-complete-destiny-2s-constellation-wish-quest-for-a-wish-keeper-exotic-catalyst/">Season of the Wish</a>) this can be done by navigating through <strong>the official Companion app</strong>. It’s available for download on any Android or iOS phone from the Play Store or App Store respectively. If you’re talking about seasons before then, it’s almost impossible to get their rewards.</p>
 <p data-characters="575" data-current-count="575" data-injectable="false">There have been mentions of a Google Chrome or Firefox extension called Season Pass Pass that did let you claim these rewards, but details on it have been muddy over the years. As of June 2024, it appears that the extension <strong>either doesn’t work, or may be limited</strong> in how many seasons you can go back. You could also try contacting Bungie to see what they could do on their end, but it’s unlikely much can be done. If you want the rewards from the current Episode Act, you should claim them as soon as you get them rather than sitting on them until the last minute.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Do You Want From Me, Man]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/summer-game-fest-keighley-hype</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-do-you-want-from-me-man.891498/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/summer-game-fest-keighley-hype<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>E3 is officially dead, which means Geoff Keighley has won in his quest to supplant it and now gets to slap his branding on its <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/the-life-and-death-of-e3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">corpse</a>. He’s been cranking the Summer Game Fest hype engine for weeks now, only to tell us on Monday that we shouldn’t get <em>too</em> hyped. Weirdly, he does this a lot.&nbsp;</p><p>On a Twitch stream this week, Keighley <a href="https://kotaku.com/summer-game-fest-2024-geoff-keighley-sets-expectations-1851516386" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> Friday’s Summer Game Fest show will focus on “existing games that have new updates” and that, while there will be announcements, “this is not a show that has a lot of like ‘coming in 2026' or ‘2027', or teasers for games that are years and years out.”&nbsp;</p><p>It’s not the kind of thing you expect to hear from a man who seems intent on holding the copyright for the phrase “world premiere,” a man who looks both animated by and exhausted from hype about hype. He’s been <a href="https://x.com/summergamefest" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tweeting</a> about the show for weeks, announcing partners and counting down the days. This semi-reversal has felt so notable that it’s spawned a universe of headlines about “<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/heres-what-we-know-wont-be-at-summer-game-fest" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what we know won’t be</a>” at the show and “<a href="https://en.as.com/meristation/news/what-not-to-expect-at-summer-game-fest-live-according-to-geoff-keighley-n/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">what not to expect</a>,” alongside exhortations that we “<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-expect-big-reveals-at-summer-games-fest-says-geoff-keighley" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">don’t expect big reveals</a>” and “<a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/summer-game-fest-will-focus-on-existing-games-so-dont-hyper-yourself-up-for-games-that-are-years-and-years-out-says-geoff-keighley/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">don’t hype yourself up</a>.”&nbsp;</p><p>But a similar thing happened around Summer Game Fest 2022, when Keighley <a href="https://www.engadget.com/summer-game-fest-showcase-geoff-keighley-expectations-141656607.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said in a Twitter Spaces chat</a> a few days ahead of the show that “it definitely is a show that’s primarily focused on stuff that is announced” and warned viewers to "definitely manage your expectations in terms of the megaton shocks that you’re expecting." Previously, Keighley had hyped that show up all the way to <a href="https://x.com/geoffkeighley/status/1522237966902460417" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">IMAX screens</a>, and told <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/video-games/2022/05/20/summer-game-fest-geoff-keighley-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Washington Post</a> that “June is definitely a good time for people to ramp up, get people excited about things coming in the future.”&nbsp;</p><p>The next year, he burst his own hype bubble around <a href="https://gamerant.com/gamescom-opening-night-live-reveals-world-premieres-geoff-keighley/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gamescom Opening Night Live</a> 2023, telling <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/geoff-keighley-says-this-years-gamescom-onl-is-less-about-announcing-new-projects/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Video Game Chronicle</a>, “This year's ONL is less about announcing brand-new projects, and more about giving fans updates on some of the biggest games due out over the next year.” This was after <a href="https://x.com/geoffkeighley/status/1690832310411964416" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hype trailers</a> and teasers about <a href="https://x.com/gamescom/status/1686025743422119936" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">world premieres</a>, and stood in contrast to ONL 2022, which he touted as a “<a href="https://www.nme.com/news/gaming-news/geoff-keighley-says-gamescom-opening-night-live-will-be-a-big-spectacle-3288878" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">big spectacle</a>.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>What do you want from us, Geoff? Keighley's whole deal is setting viewer expectations sky-high, turning advertisements into news and <a href="https://aftermath.site/how-many-game-awards-acceptance-speeches-could-have-taken-place-while-kojima-was-talking" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">long-winded speeches by his friends</a> into a required-viewing awards show. He's skilled in finding ways to appear excited about whatever is put in front of him, an orientation toward the world that seems like it must be very comforting--asked to select from the smorgasbord of human emotions, I too would choose endless enthusiasm if I could--and which has forged him a <a href="https://www.theringer.com/video-games/2022/12/8/23498936/geoff-keighley-the-game-awards-video-games-oscars" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">long-running</a> and <a href="https://www.esquire.com/entertainment/a61006534/summer-game-fest-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">high-profile</a> career. But part of that schtick is getting us to be as excited as he is, or at least as he portrays himself as--and then telling us <em>not</em> to get excited at the last minute.&nbsp;<em>You're</em> the one who's doing this, buddy! You're the one who keeps having to correct the expectations <em>you</em> set us up for!</p><p>Covid’s effect on game development and the layoffs chewing their way through the industry have made reveal shows weird for a while now. It’s not Keighley’s fault that it’s harder to coordinate everyone having new stuff to show at the same time than it used to be. But it <em>is</em> his fault for continuously <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/stop-trying-to-make-fetch-happen" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trying to make Fetch happen</a>, pretending that everything is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23992402/geoff-keighley-the-game-awards-layoffs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">business as usual</a> and that the only emotion <a href="https://videogames.si.com/features/games-industry-deserves-better-than-geoff-keighley" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">worth having</a> about video games these days is excitement. He’s inflicting all this on us, but he’s also doing it to himself, shovelling coal into his own hype train and then dodging before it hits him.&nbsp;</p><p>E3 saw the way the winds were blowing and bowed out. I think there’s some value, or at least some pleasure to be had, in doing <em>something </em>in its absence. If Keighley is determined to corner the market on that, ditching his role as the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LI_Oe-jtgdI" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Harold Hill</a> of video game hype and just being <em>normal</em> could do him, and <a href="https://aftermath.site/only-you-can-prevent-the-game-awards-hype-cycle" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all of us</a>, a favor.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>