<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:47:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New 007 First Light Trailer Shows Off Bond’s Stylish Wheels]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-007-first-light-trailer-shows-off-bonds-stylish-wheels/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-007-first-light-trailer-shows-off-bond%E2%80%99s-stylish-wheels.1360000/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Today's <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-announces-xbox-partner-preview-thursday/">Xbox Partner Preview event</a> showcased 16 games and announcements, one of them being a new trailer for IO Interactive's upcoming James Bond game, 007 First Light. Though it wasn't a huge new showcase of gameplay, a deep dive into the game's mechanics, or even a behind-the-scenes look at the game's development, it did highlight a key element of any James Bond video game: the car that Bond drives.</p>



<p>The short, fifty-second trailer shows off Bond's Aston Martin Valhalla, a stunning car even without all of the special agent gadgetry that Q details in his narration of the trailer.</p>



<p>"<em>Inspired by the groundbreaking Aston Martin Valkyrie and infused with advanced Formula 1 technologies, the Valhalla showcases aerodynamic mastery, race-derived engineering, and exquisite craftsmanship</em>," writes IO Interactive senior global communications manager, Yann Roskell,<a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/11/20/007-first-light-xbox-partner-preview/"> in an Xbox Wire post</a>. "<em>Limited to just 999 units worldwide, this supercar sets the standard for automotive innovation, showcasing unparalleled speed and precision.</em>"</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="007 First Light - Aston Martin Valhalla Reveal | Xbox Partner Preview 2025" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L0wLsLm8OlY?start=1&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Okay, perhaps it would have been better to get a deeper look at gameplay or some more insight into how the game was made, <a href="https://wccftech.com/007-first-light-release-date-march-2026-james-bond/">similar to what we saw in September</a> during a State of Play presentation. But a James Bond game will live and die by how well it truly captures the allure of the character that has captivated fans for decades.</p>



<p>Bond's taste for gadgets, clothes, and of course, cars, are all mixed in with that allure, so it makes sense that IO Interactive would put something like this together to further display how it is trying to capture the essence of James Bond.</p>



<p>That said, hopefully we don't have to go too long before getting a more detailed dive into what we can expect from the game ahead of its release on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S on March 27, 2026.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/new-007-first-light-trailer-shows-off-bonds-stylish-wheels/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demeo x Dungeons & Dragons: Battlemarked Brings Simplified TTRPG Combat To The Forgotten Realms]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-brings-simplified-ttrpg-combat-to-forgotten</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-brings-simplified-ttrpg-combat-to-the-forgotten-realms.1359997/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I'm a big fan of <em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3579fb91-ffa9-4c99-a750-de9f92ba642f" href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="nofollow">Dungeons &amp; Dragons</a>,</em> and when I can't find the time to get a group of friends together, I'm always down to try different experiences that seek to recreate the experience. The latest of these is <em>Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked</em>. A tabletop experience where abilities are replaced by cards as you go dungeon crawling through the <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="9cb3f917-f831-4c81-8cb8-54e040b09040" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-forgotten-realms-heroes-of-faerun-and-adventures-in-faerun-review" rel="nofollow">Forgotten Realms</a>, but where does it successfully recreate the experience, and where does it falter?</p>

<p><em>Battlemarked </em>is, as the name would suggest, a new title in the <em>Demeo </em>series of turn-based RPGs that leans into recreating the feeling of moving miniatures around a board and taking on waves of enemies as you dive deeper into interesting dungeons. This time around, the game has received a <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> coat of paint with character classes reflecting those from the TTRPG, cards of popular abilities and spells, and the campaigns are now set in the Forgotten Realms.</p>

<p>At launch, the game will release with two Campaigns, <em>Embers of Chaos</em> and <em>Crown of Frost</em>. In my time previewing the game, I dove into Embers of Chaos. Here, the surrounding areas of Neverwinter are in turmoil, and stress is rising between groups of humans and elves as strange attacks are on the rise.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-world-map.jpg?itok=a9oxiU3r 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-world-map.jpg?itok=V46ssOAu 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Through the early moments of the campaign, you'll find yourself fighting off bandits, saving the town of Thundertree, enjoying a drink at a local tavern, and diving deep into a mushroom-infested cave system. While there's certainly a number of name drops and references, it's still very clear this is a combat and tactics forward game, and not as much into building any kind of vast story.</p>

<p>There's no worry with not creating that experience, it's just good to make sure you don't go in expecting that.</p>

<h2><em>Battlemarked </em>Gameplay Works Like A Board Game</h2>

<p><em>Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked </em>leans heavily into the turn-based combat and simplified action economy of <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>. Starting a new area, your party will appear on the edge of the map, and you'll move them one by one, each character being able to take two actions per turn.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-character.jpg?itok=4oVOoAe2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-character.jpg?itok=ywP2egoe 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>You can move, make a simple attack, or use any of the different items or ability cards at your disposal. With <em>Battlemarked</em>, all of the cards have a <em>D&amp;D</em> theme with simple tweaks like Fire Arrows, as well as Lay on Hands and Blinkstrike. Your hand is limited to 10 cards, but as you take out enemies, you'll slowly earn more cards. It's pretty unlikely you'll ever run out.</p>

<p>This action economy did take me a bit to work out, because moving took an action, but using an attack ability could also move you and let you do an attack. Trying to keep the party together, but also dealing damage efficiently was a bit of a puzzle in itself (and one that I definitely lost a few times.)</p>

<p>When you are ready to attack an opponent, you'll be presented with a die to roll. While it is a D20, the dice you roll is made up of a skull for a miss, a single sword for hit, and two swords for a Critical hit. I'm someone who likes seeing high numbers on dice, so it wasn't as appealing to see the attack dice symbol-based, but it definitely speeds up the game. What was incredibly satisfying in the diorama world of the game is that rolling the dice is physics-based, letting you grab and throw the dice, and watching it bounce all over the terrain.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-virtual-reality.jpg?itok=ia-Ep-V4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-virtual-reality.jpg?itok=8f2yNEWL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Playing on my PC was fun, but Battlemarked is way more engaging in the VR mode</figcaption></figure><p>There are skill checks where you use a D20, these pop up during conversation or when you stumble across random events in a map, that do rely on your character stats. For the most part, you'll be rolling the Attack Dice though.</p>

<p><em>Battlemarked </em>really has the visuals of <em>Dungons &amp; Dragons</em> down, as someone who plays (way too much) D&amp;D, though it felt like a lot of these systems were a bit too simplified for me. You have a good chance to hit, but you won't always, and your characters' attack stats are all static. It would have been awesome to see some varying damage stats to create more scenarios where you'd go for a risky attack to hope for a high damage roll to finish off an enemy.</p>

<h2>Randomization &amp; Replayability</h2>

<p>When combat is a bit too tough and you fall in battle, you'll get to restart from the beginning of the floor, but the enemies present and their locations will be randomized. This is a fun addition, meaning that no matter how much the environment you move through might be the same, the progression of combat will always be different.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-combat.jpg?itok=7wc3YswB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-combat.jpg?itok=FIHBmyfy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>There's further replayability to be had in the game in playing with different people, what class you choose, and how you choose to upgrade your character. Do you prefer that your Paladin takes less damage on low health, or that there is less chance for Poison damage?</p>

<h2><em>Battlemarked </em>Offers A <em>D&amp;D</em>-lite Combat Experience</h2>

<p>From my time with <em>Battlemarked </em>so far, I've enjoyed the story as it has been laid out, and the visual experience perfectly demonstrates a high-quality game with terrain and miniatures.</p>

<p>I do wish that the combat wasn't so dialed back, but there is a lot of replayability in the layout of enemies in a dungeon and how you best use the cards available to you. With how every part of the game is static numbers and grid-based movement, even when not in active combat, the experience honestly felt closer to my recent experiences with HeroQuest.</p>

<p>If you're interested in getting online with friends and throwing some dice in a strategic setting,&nbsp;<em>Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked</em> is a fun experience, even more so with the different references that you'll run into. If the simplified combat or very light storytelling isn't for you, then you might need to seek your adventure elsewhere.</p>

<hr><p><strong><em>Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons Battlemarked </em></strong><em>was previewed on PC via Steam and Quest 3 with a code provided by the publisher - All photos were taken during the review.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Andrew has written Video Game and Entertainment news, reviews, and guides for 10+ years. As Senior Content Manager, he assists in creating and editing… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-stretch">More about Andrew</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-brings-simplified-ttrpg-combat-to-forgotten]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Windows handhelds are getting the new Xbox Full Screen Experience tomorrow]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/825405/microsoft-xbox-full-screen-experience-available-windows-handhelds</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/windows-handhelds-are-getting-the-new-xbox-full-screen-experience-tomorrow.1359994/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior editor and author of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/notepad-microsoft-newsletter"><i>Notepad</i></a>, who has been covering all things Microsoft, PC, and tech for over 20 years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Microsoft will start rolling out its new Xbox Full Screen Experience (FSE) to Windows-based handhelds on November 21st. The full screen mode for the Xbox app originally shipped on the Xbox Ally devices last month, providing a more console-like navigation experience on top of Windows 11.</p><p>While Microsoft released a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/811826/microsoft-xbox-full-screen-experience-fse-msi-claw-windows-11-insider">preview to MSI Claw models</a> last month, it’s now making the Xbox Full Screen Experience generally available to all Windows-based handhelds. Microsoft is <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/11/20/xbox-partner-preview-november-2025-recap/">also expanding</a> Xbox FSE “to more Windows 11 PC form factors through the Xbox and Windows Insider programs.”</p><p>The Xbox FSE doesn’t load the full Windows desktop or a bunch of background processes, freeing up more memory for games. It’s essentially not loading the Explorer shell and saving around 2GB of memory by suppressing all the unnecessary parts of a typical Windows 11 installation.</p><p>If you decide to enable Xbox FSE on your handheld or PC, it will launch you straight into the Xbox PC app at boot, which includes all of your PC games from the Microsoft Store, Battle.net, Steam, and other storefronts. There’s also a Game Bar for navigating between games and launchers, and a task view that’s designed to be more handheld-friendly.</p><p>To turn on Xbox FSE on a compatible handheld, go to Settings &gt; Gaming &gt; Full screen experience, then select Xbox as your home app.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTY0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Tom Warren</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/825405/microsoft-xbox-full-screen-experience-available-windows-handhelds]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Handgun Wrecking Everyone In Arc Raiders Has Been Put In Nerf Jail]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-embark-studios-1-3-0-venerator-wall-key-2000645901</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-handgun-wrecking-everyone-in-arc-raiders-has-been-put-in-nerf-jail.1359985/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i>Arc Raiders</i> got a fresh set of <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/duck-update-patch-notes-1-3-0">patch notes</a> for its 1.3.0 update this morning. The update includes a variety of changes across the board, but perhaps most important are the changes to a two-shot pistol that’s been causing havoc and devastation for anyone on the receiving end of its twin barrels. Here are all the changes impacting in-game weapons and items:</p> <h2>The Venator gets ‘re-tuned’ and explosions are less explosive</h2> <p>A blue rare gun, the Venator is a girl’s best friend as a sidearm and a seriously reliable primary weapon if you like maining pistols. That might change a bit as the gun was previously “capable of outgunning full squads using close range weapons,” according to the patch notes.</p>

 <p>The other notable change here is that explosions have been tweaked. To be honest, I kinda saw this one coming as it’s been pretty damn easy lately to take out the larger Arc threats with things that go boom. The most significant of these changes sees the Hullcracker launcher, great for taking down Arc, requiring more accuracy, while explosions on large enemies “deal a bit less damage,” as Embark puts it.</p>

 <p>The cost of ammo for the Hullcracker has also shifted, and arguably not for the better. Whereas you could snag a pack of 10 from the in-game traders for 6,000 Coins, you’ll now get 6 launcher ammo for 4,500.</p> <p>As <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1p1z2on/comment/npu81ec/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">one comment thread on Reddit discusses</a>, this might have the run-on effect of seeing fewer people rushing the Arc Queen as they’ll be a little less equipped, and with weaponry that requires some more careful aiming.</p>

 <h2>Embark takes aim at bugs and wall-glitching, but some issues remain</h2> <p><i>Arc Raiders</i>’ performance is mostly reliable, but folks found some unfortunate bugs that affected bullet collision, as well as exploits that allow players to glitch into rooms that are otherwise locked.</p> <p>The update brings improvements to those bullet issues on the map Blue Gate. It’s a nice start, but I know I’ve seen similar issues elsewhere, too. The patch notes detail “railing props [that] mistakenly blocked bullets” but say that “shots now pass through as expected.” Across the other maps, some other player collision issues were touched up.</p>

 <p>Players have also been exploiting some wall-glitching, allowing them to enter locked rooms without keys or to hide in unreachable ambush spots. Dam Battlegrounds has had an exploit that allowed access to the Control Tower fixed, while a specific wall in Spaceport that players were glitching into to jump unsuspecting players will no longer allow for this.</p>

 <p>Still, I’ve seen all sorts of locked doors bypassed by folks, not just the ones addressed by this patch. Hopefully there’ll be less of this.</p> <p>But perhaps the most frustrating movement issue occurs when trying to access an escape hatch while in a downed-but-not-out status. Normally, until you’re fully knocked out, you can crawl your way to an escape as the game lets you activate the elevator or escape hatch terminals while you’re down. But as documented well in <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ArcRaiders/comments/1oxzevn/i_need_to_have_a_word_with_whoever_designed_this/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">this video on Reddit</a>, most hatches seem to sit atop a slope that can’t be climbed while crawling.</p>

   <p>It’s hard to tell if this is intentional or an oversight. But it’s clearly been a frustrating experience for those who’ve tried to make a daring last-minute escape via a hatch, only to find out they can’t crawl over a hump.</p> <h2>Good news (maybe) for duck fans</h2> <p>Lastly, update 1.3.0 will fill your Raider’s room with more rubber ducks, letting them spill over the floor if you have enough in your stash.</p> <p>It’s cute! But if you ask me, those ducks aren’t valuable enough to extract with and are otherwise too pointless for me to have them taking up room in my stash. So fear not, any rubber ducks I come across are deliberately left behind on the battlefield. You’re welcome.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-embark-studios-1-3-0-venerator-wall-key-2000645901]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Was Interested In ‘Furry May Cry’ Until I Found Out It Might Be Using AI]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/zoopunk-generative-ai-demo-trailer-xbox-showcase-2000645874</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-was-interested-in-%E2%80%98furry-may-cry%E2%80%99-until-i-found-out-it-might-be-using-ai.1359979/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Today’s Xbox Partner Preview had a bunch of big announcements and trailers like a new look at the upcoming <em>007 First Light </em>and the reveal of a <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-vampire-survivorssequel-was-just-revealed-and-its-a-dungeon-crawler-2000645860">follow-up to&nbsp;<em>Vampire Survivors</em></a>, but one of the surprise standouts for me was <em>Zoopunk</em>, a new action game by <em>F.I.S.T.: Forged In Shadow Torch&nbsp;</em>developer TiGames, starring a bunch of anthropomorphic animals in a sort of dark, science-fiction post-apocalypse. However, as more news is trickling out, it’s beginning to look like the game might be using AI generation tools, and that has deflated my interest.</p> <p><em>Zoopunk</em>‘s fast-paced combat looks slick and stylish, but maybe a little stiff at first glance. I’m curious to see how it feels when the controller’s in my hands. Growing up playing&nbsp;<em>Devil May Cry&nbsp;</em>made me very picky about character action games in the PS2 era, so if one doesn’t feel good to play, I tend to bounce off of it very quickly. But what TiGames showed in the first trailer has potential.</p>

  <p>However, what didn’t come up during the Xbox showcase was that <i>Zoopunk </i>was also used as part of a Stable Diffusion AI asset generation demo earlier this year. The video, which is currently “unlisted” on the game’s YouTube channel, shows a user drawing simplistic equipment designs, which are then used to generate an in-game model. At the moment, it’s unclear if this is integrated into the game itself, or if <em>Zoopunk&nbsp;</em>was just used as a demo for the AI model. An <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/geforce/news/nvidia-ace-autonomous-ai-companions-pubg-naraka-bladepoint/">NVIDIA announcement</a> from earlier this year also names the game as using AI-powered NPCs. We’ve reached out to TiGames for comment on the situation and will update this story if we hear back.</p>  <p>Generative AI is creeping into video games more and more over recent years, with several executives at big companies <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-gen-ai-nexon-eurogamer-voices-2000643436">insisting it should become the norm within the industry</a>. Despite this, generative AI <a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-ai-slop-regulation-2000644735">has become a legal battleground</a> as these models are being trained on copyrighted works.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/zoopunk-generative-ai-demo-trailer-xbox-showcase-2000645874]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Total Chaos now available for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/total-chaos-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/total-chaos-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.1359973/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Psychological horror game with music by Akira Yamaoka.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Apogee Entertainment [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/apogee-entertainment">Apogee Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Trigger Happy Interactive [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/trigger-happy-interactive">Trigger Happy Interactive</a> have released psychological survival <a title="Genres > Horror [767 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror game</a> <em><a title="Games > Total Chaos" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/total-chaos">Total Chaos</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,871 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,294 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,812 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2208350/Total_Chaos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/total-chaos/9phtx5qz035t" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a> for $24.99, the companies announced. <span id="more-1008380"></span></p><p>“<em>Total Chaos</em> began for me almost two decades ago when the original mod became my first real step into creating a world of my own,” said Trigger Happy Interactive head Sam Prebble in a press release. “I never imagined I’d return to Fort Oasis and rebuild it as a full standalone release on PC and consoles. I’m grateful to everyone who helped bring it to this moment, especially the teams at Apogee, <a title="Companies > Atari [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/atari">Atari</a>, and <a title="Companies > Infogrames [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/atari/infogrames">Infogrames</a>. See you on the island. Listen carefully to the voice you follow.”</p><p>Apogee Entertainment executive producer Jeron Moore added, “<em>Total Chaos</em> is Apogee’s first step into survival horror and a full-circle moment for Sam, whose early love for classics like <em>DOOM</em>, <em>Duke Nukem 3D</em>, <em>S.T.A.L.K.E.R.</em>, and the horror genre at large helped inspire this original vision. What began as a total conversion mod has grown into a faithful and expanded remake. Our creative bond from <em><a title="Games > Turbo Overkill [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/turbo-overkill">Turbo Overkill</a></em> made it a privilege to support him again and ensure <em>Total Chaos</em> delivers a truly landmark horror experience.”</p><p>Guest composer Akira Yamaoka said, “I am truly honored to have taken part in this collaboration with <em>Total Chaos</em>. Within the chaos lies a hidden silence—an invisible world that cannot be captured by words, but only expressed through sound. It is an experience like a journey where unseen landscapes are felt through the ears rather than seen by the eyes. I hope you enjoy it.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Apogee Entertainment:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Descend into <em>Total Chaos</em>, a gripping terrormare that blurs the line between reality and madness.</p><p>Once a bustling haven for coal miners, Fort Oasis is now a crumbling wasteland, its eerie silence broken only by a cryptic radio transmission beckoning you toward the island’s heart—the forsaken mines. But as you delve deeper into the island’s desolation, the path forward becomes twisted and uncertain, unraveling unsettling truths hidden in the encroaching darkness.</p><p>Scavenge for scraps and craft makeshift weapons to defend yourself against the horrors that lurk in the shadows. Unearth fragments of forgotten lives scattered across the island and piece together the chilling mystery of Fort Oasis’s demise. Every discovery brings you closer to a truth that threatens to shatter your sanity.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Immersive Atmosphere</strong> – Explore the decayed ruins of Fort Oasis across nine harrowing chapters, each drenched in dread, plunging you deeper into its oppressive, decaying world.</li><li><strong>Environmental Storytelling</strong> – Uncover the island’s darkest secrets and confront your own fractured past through cryptic notes, haunting visuals, and unsettling encounters.</li><li><strong><a title="Genres > Crafting [47 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/crafting">Crafting</a> for <a title="Genres > Survival [483 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a></strong> – Build and upgrade weapons using scavenged materials to stand a chance against the relentless terrors stalking you.</li><li><strong>Face Nightmarish Foes</strong> – Engage against horrific creatures, each with their own deadly behaviors and strategies.</li><li><strong>Resource <a title="Genres > Management [34 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">Management</a></strong> – Navigate a deep inventory system where every item matters—your survival hinges on careful choices, crafting the perfect weapon, and quick thinking on the fly.</li><li><strong>A Haunting Original Soundtrack</strong> – Total Chaos features a new original theme and end credits track by legendary <a title="Companies > Sile" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sile">Sile</a>nt Hill composer Akira Yamaoka, joined by original Total Chaos mod composers Jason Dagenet and William Braddell, and Apogee’s music team, Chipper Hammond, Tim Stoney, and Mathieu Hallouin. Together, they’ve crafted an ambient, nightmare-inducing soundscape that blurs the line between music and madness.</li></ul><p>Originally conceived as an award-winning total conversion mod, <em>Total Chaos</em> has been fully reimagined into a standalone terrormare, amplifying its chilling atmosphere and relentless tension for a new generation of players.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the launch trailer below.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Total Chaos | Extended Launch Trailer | Available Now on PC, Xbox Series X|S, and PS5" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eIz6v3-y7ug?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/11/total-chaos-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This New Game Looks Downright Bizarre, And It's Launching On Game Pass Thankfully]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-new-game-looks-downright-bizarre-and-its-launching-on-game-pass-thankfully/1100-6536399/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-new-game-looks-downright-bizarre-and-its-launching-on-game-pass-thankfully.1359970/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536399">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>As part of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/xbox-partner-preview-showcase-every-game-and-announcement/2900-7271/" data-ref-id="2900-7271">November Xbox Partner Preview</a>, developer <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/search/?developer=Cybernetic%20Walrus&amp;snr=1_5_9__2000" rel="nofollow ">Cybernetic Walrus</a> announced that Roadside Research is coming to Xbox and will be a day-one release for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/upcoming-game-pass-titles/1100-6534406/" data-ref-id="1100-6534406">Game Pass</a>. What is Roadside Research? Few things in life are certain, but I feel confident in saying you probably won't guess the hook for this game.</p><h2><strong>What even is Roadside Research?</strong></h2><p>Roadside Research is a 1-4 player co-op gas station simulator. Simulator-type games are everywhere these days, but this one differentiates itself because you play as an alien. More specifically, you're an undercover alien who tries to act like a human and do human-like things that a gas station attendant would do like stocking shelves and assisting customers. "Just don't get caught," reads a line from the description.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1719481839" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466543,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Roadside%20Research%20%7C%20Official%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:65,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/roadside-research-official-reveal-trailer\/2300-6466543\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466543\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466543\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466543\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466543&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466543,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536399&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;roadside-research&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;simulation&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;oro-interactive&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466543},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466543\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4607999-1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/bYB3GHCM.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1763665800,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="bYB3GHCM" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Roadside Research | Official Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yy3A4oxvKKg" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Yy3A4oxvKKg" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>All the while, players are trying to gather intelligence on humans in preparation for an upcoming alien invasion. "If you arouse too much suspicion, the government will show up, jeopardizing your Earthly mission," the description adds.</p><p>This is a comedic game, as you can immediately tell by watching the trailer. The aliens in the game are the classic <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Little_green_men" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">little green men</a>, and to blend in, you must create what you deem to be a human-looking face mask--but it doesn't have to be any good, really.</p><p>Game Pass gets a lot of big-name launches, and one of the perks of a subscription service is that you can sample titles you might not otherwise rush to buy outright. If you're curious about Roadside Research but not sure you want to buy it, Game Pass seems like a pretty good avenue.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4607998-screenshot2025-11-20at1.56.46%E2%80%AFpm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607998" data-ratio="0.54785894206549" data-width="1588" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4607998-screenshot2025-11-20at1.56.46%E2%80%AFpm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607998"></a><figcaption>Nailed it.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4607998-screenshot2025-11-20at1.56.46%E2%80%AFpm.png"></figure><p>During the daytime, players will work as gas station attendants and do their best to blend in and be "normal." At night, players will take what they learned about humans and use that information to upgrade the gas station to attract more humans, and thereby gather even more intelligence about them.</p><p>Roadside Research is set for release in Q1 2026 (January 1-March 31, 2026) and will come to Game Pass Ultimate at launch for Xbox and PC. It's not immediately clear if the game is also coming to PlayStation.</p><p>A <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3643170/Roadside_Research/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">free demo is available already on Steam</a>. It's attracted a lot of interest and attention on Steam, where it's landed on more than 300,000 user wishlists, with <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3643170/view/514096230384533700?l=english" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">more than 260,000 people playing the demo</a> as of early October.</p><h2><strong>What else has Cybernetic Walrus made?</strong></h2><p>Cybernetic Walrus is an independent developer that aims to "redefine how players connect with virtual worlds," and <a href="https://www.cyberneticwalrus.com/about-us/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">specifically mentions on its website </a>that it makes simulation-type games. Before Roadside Research, the studio made the horror game Order 13, in which players must navigate a dark and scary warehouse as they take on packing orders and try to keep their cat alive. The team also made Does It Stack, a physics-based mixed-reality puzzle game for Meta Quest VR. Additionally, Cybernetic Walrus developed the futuristic anti-gravity racing game Antigravitator.</p><h2><strong>You don't have to pay extra for Game Pass... for now</strong></h2><p>In October, Microsoft announced a dramatic Xbox Game Pass price increase for Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass, along with some changes to the other tiers. The new price for Game Pass Ultimate soared by 50% to $30/month. However, most major retailers are not going with the new price, at least not yet, so <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-sign-up-best-deal-available-now/1100-6535504/" data-ref-id="1100-6535504">you can still get Game Pass Ultimate for $20/month or $60 for three months on Amazon</a> and many other stores.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-new-game-looks-downright-bizarre-and-its-launching-on-game-pass-thankfully/1100-6536399/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[007 First Light's Bond will have an Aston Martin so exclusive, there are only 999 real world models]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/007-first-lights-bond-will-have-an-aston-martin-so-exclusive-there-are-only-999-real-world-models</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/007-first-lights-bond-will-have-an-aston-martin-so-exclusive-there-are-only-999-real-world-models.1359967/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Aston-Martin-Valkyrie-in-007-First-Light-with-Bond-overlaid-on-top.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Aston-Martin-Valkyrie-in-007-First-Light-with-Bond-overlaid-on-top.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Aston-Martin-Valkyrie-in-007-First-Light-with-Bond-overlaid-on-top.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Aston-Martin-Valkyrie-in-007-First-Light-with-Bond-overlaid-on-top.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Aston-Martin-Valkyrie-in-007-First-Light-with-Bond-overlaid-on-top.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Aston-Martin-Valkyrie-in-007-First-Light-with-Bond-overlaid-on-top.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Aston-Martin-Valkyrie-in-007-First-Light-with-Bond-overlaid-on-top.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Aston-Martin-Valkyrie-in-007-First-Light-with-Bond-overlaid-on-top.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Aston-Martin-Valkyrie-in-007-First-Light-with-Bond-overlaid-on-top.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer/IOI</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>James Bond is known for its cars, and 007 First Light from Hitman developer <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/io-interactive">IO Interactive</a> will be no exception.</p>
<p>As shared at this evening's Xbox Partner Preview showcase, the upcoming espionage caper will feature Aston Martin's Valhalla supercar, which is to say Aston Martin's first-ever mid-engine plug-in hypercar.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>The car itself was inspired by Aston Martin's Valkyrie, but this chap has been "infused" with advanced Formula 1 technologies. There are only going to be 999 units worldwide, so lucky ol' (actually, make that lucky young) Bond, eh?</p>
<p>"The reveal of Valhalla in 007 First Light marks one of the many steps our team is taking to honour the iconic cars that define the Bond legacy," said Hakan Abrak, CEO of IO Interactive. "Cars have always been at the core of the James Bond experience, reflecting his style, ingenuity, and daring personality.</p>
<p>"With the debut of Valhalla, players will encounter a machine that embodies that spirit, capturing the excitement of Bond’s world and the timeless elegance of his vehicles."</p>
<p>You can see its 007 First Light counterpart in the images below. Obviously, Bond's has a few modcons</p>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
 


</figure>
<figure>
 


</figure>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>IOI</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>007 First Light will launch for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platforms/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, and PC on 27th March next year. Elsewhere this evening we got a peep at the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tides-of-annihilation-continues-to-look-awesome-in-new-dimension-shattering-gameplay">awesome looking Tides of Annihilation</a> and more.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/007-first-lights-bond-will-have-an-aston-martin-so-exclusive-there-are-only-999-real-world-models]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rapper Eminem stars in the next Elusive Target mission coming to Hitman World of Assassination]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/rapper-eminem-stars-in-the-next-elusive-target-mission-coming-to-hitman-world-of-assassination</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rapper-eminem-stars-in-the-next-elusive-target-mission-coming-to-hitman-world-of-assassination.1359964/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>It felt so empty without him.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HITMAN-World-of-Assassination-%E2%80%93-Eminem-vs.-Slim-Shady-Elusive-Target-_-Xbox-Partner-Preview-2025-0-25-screenshot-(2).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HITMAN-World-of-Assassination-%E2%80%93-Eminem-vs.-Slim-Shady-Elusive-Target-_-Xbox-Partner-Preview-2025-0-25-screenshot-(2).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HITMAN-World-of-Assassination-%E2%80%93-Eminem-vs.-Slim-Shady-Elusive-Target-_-Xbox-Partner-Preview-2025-0-25-screenshot-(2).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HITMAN-World-of-Assassination-%E2%80%93-Eminem-vs.-Slim-Shady-Elusive-Target-_-Xbox-Partner-Preview-2025-0-25-screenshot-(2).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HITMAN-World-of-Assassination-%E2%80%93-Eminem-vs.-Slim-Shady-Elusive-Target-_-Xbox-Partner-Preview-2025-0-25-screenshot-(2).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HITMAN-World-of-Assassination-%E2%80%93-Eminem-vs.-Slim-Shady-Elusive-Target-_-Xbox-Partner-Preview-2025-0-25-screenshot-(2).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HITMAN-World-of-Assassination-%E2%80%93-Eminem-vs.-Slim-Shady-Elusive-Target-_-Xbox-Partner-Preview-2025-0-25-screenshot-(2).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HITMAN-World-of-Assassination-%E2%80%93-Eminem-vs.-Slim-Shady-Elusive-Target-_-Xbox-Partner-Preview-2025-0-25-screenshot-(2).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/HITMAN-World-of-Assassination-%E2%80%93-Eminem-vs.-Slim-Shady-Elusive-Target-_-Xbox-Partner-Preview-2025-0-25-screenshot-(2).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>IO Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Rapper Eminem will star in the next Elusive Target mission coming to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hitman-world-of-assassination">Hitman World of Assassination</a>, with players tasked with eliminating his alter ego Slim Shady.
</p>
<p>
As announced in tonight's Xbox Partner Preview, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/io-interactive">IO Interactive</a> is releasing a new free mission for Agent 47, along with the paid Eminem vs Slim Shady Pack containing various cosmetics.
</p>
<p>
In the mission, Agent 47 will team up with Eminem - a fellow operative, just like Bruce Lee was recently - in a mission to "untangle the twisted mind of Slim Shady".
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="HITMAN World of Assassination – Eminem vs. Slim Shady Elusive Target | Xbox Partner Preview 2025" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qk6wSOEqMHU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>HITMAN World of Assassination – Eminem vs. Slim Shady Elusive Target | Xbox Partner Preview 2025</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qk6wSOEqMHU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qk6wSOEqMHU?autoplay=1" title="HITMAN World of Assassination – Eminem vs. Slim Shady Elusive Target | Xbox Partner Preview 2025">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>HITMAN World of Assassination – Eminem vs. Slim Shady Elusive Target | Xbox Partner Preview 2025<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qk6wSOEqMHU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>
A medical facility in Hokkaido has been reconfigured into the "chaotic" Popsomp Hills Aslyum. It's full of both psychological twists and references to the rapper. Slim Shady is busy delivering erratic live performances to brainwish listeners and weaponise music - because of course.
</p>
<p>
Eminem follows the likes of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hitmans-next-elusive-target-is-jean-claude-the-splitter-van-damme">Jean-Claude Van Damme</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hitmans-agent-47-will-soon-be-able-to-assassinate-casino-royale-baddy-la-chiffre">Bond nemesis Le Chiffre</a> as recent famous faces joining the ongoing stealth action game.
</p>
<p>
The free mission will be available from 1st December on all platforms - that's Xbox Series X/S, PC (Xbox, Steam, Epic), PS4, PS5, and Switch consoles.
</p>
<p>
The Eminem vs Slim Shady Pack will be available from 1st - 31st December for £3.99.
</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/rapper-eminem-stars-in-the-next-elusive-target-mission-coming-to-hitman-world-of-assassination]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Next Picross Games Are Teaming Up With Capcom & SNK]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/the-next-picross-games-are-teaming-up-with-capcom-and-snk</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-next-picross-games-are-teaming-up-with-capcom-snk.1359946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>What a combo</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>If you're a long-time reader, then you know we love a bit of Jupiter's Picross series. And we're in for a treat on 27th November 2025, as we're getting two brand new Picross games on Switch.</p>
<p>Jupiter has announced <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/picross_s_capcom_classics_edition">Picross S Capcom Classics Edition</a> <em>and</em> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/picross_s_snk_classics_neogeo_edition">Picross S SNK Classics &amp; NEOGEO Edition</a>, with both games featuring tons of pixel art puzzles for you to solve from various Capcom and SNK properties. Both titles will cost <strong>$17.99 / €17.99 / £16.19</strong> each.</p>
<p>For Capcom, you've got some familiar favourites such as <strong>Street Fighter</strong>, <strong>Mega Man</strong>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/ghosts_n_goblins">Ghouls 'n Goblins</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/breath_of_fire">Breath of Fire</a>, <strong>Final Fight</strong>, and other classic Capcom franchises.</p>
<p>SNK's own Picross entry pulls from <strong>Metal Slug</strong>, <strong>Fatal Fury</strong>, <strong>King of Fighters</strong>, and many other titles from its illustrious fighting game history and NEOGEO catalogue.</p>

<p>Both games will include Picross, Mega Picross, Color Picross, Clip Picross, and Extra modes, as well as art galleries and grid guidelines. On Switch 2, both will be compatible with Mouse Mode too!</p>
<p>We've seen Picross team up with Mario, Zelda, Pokémon, Doraemon, Sanrio, Story of Seasons, and many more IPs. We'd love to see even more like Capcom and SNK, too. Spoil us!</p>

<hr>
<p><em>Let us know what you think of these games in the comments.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:179377 @ 1763667319 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/the-next-picross-games-are-teaming-up-with-capcom-and-snk]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Total Chaos is out now, the Doom mod rebuilt as a standalone survival horror]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/20/total-chaos-is-out-now-the-doom-mod-turned-standalone-survival-horror/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/total-chaos-is-out-now-the-doom-mod-rebuilt-as-a-standalone-survival-horror.1359943/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Coming from the creator of Turbo Overkill, the survival horror Total Chaos is no longer “coming soon”, it’s out now! Total Chaos is available for PS4, Xbox Series X|S and PC, and it’s a day one game for Xbox Game Pass as well. Steam VR support is expected to arrive in Q2 2026.</p>
<p><iframe title="Total Chaos | Available Now on PC, Xbox Series X|S, and PS5" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3oMPaRnaiig?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>It’s an impressive trailer for the game, with some deeply unsettling visuals and perspectives, playing out as a first person horror and lookin to blend both classic and modern horror sensibilities together. </p>
<p>Across the 9 chapters journey through to the heart of Fort Oasis, along the way you’ll be able to lean on both melee and ranged weapons, building new weapons from scrap and scavenging as you go. </p>
<p>Your journey will also be accompanied by a soundtrack that features a new original theme from Silent Hill composer Akira Yamaoka, and an ambient soundtrack from composers Jason Dagenet &amp; William Braddell, and Apogee’s Tim Stoney, Chipper Hammond, and Mathieu Hallouin.</p>

<p>Total Chaos has its roots in a modern Doom II total conversion. First conceptualised by Sam in 2008 and then developed from 2012 through 2018, Total Chaos has now been completely rebuilt as a fully standalone experience, and expanded from six chapters to nine.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/20/total-chaos-is-out-now-the-doom-mod-turned-standalone-survival-horror/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[See a spectacular boss battle from Tides of Annihilation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/20/see-a-spectacular-boss-battle-from-tides-of-annihilation/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/see-a-spectacular-boss-battle-from-tides-of-annihilation.1359940/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Eclipse Glow Games shared a big long look at their upcoming action-adventure game, a spectacular visual feast of a boss battle that’s inspired by Arthurian Legend. The game is coming to PC, PS5 and Xbox Series X|S, though there’s no date set just yet. </p>
<p><iframe title="Tides of Annihilation | &quot;Break the Mirror&quot; Gameplay Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VGOsH1Gp8SE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Players will step into the role of Gwendolyn, with this boss battle seeing her face off against the witch Tyronoe through multiple realms. This is a Dual Frontline battle, where you battle through a mirrored, folded realm as both Gwendolyn and the knight Sir Lamorak.</p>
<p>There’s a lot going on throughout, from shattering the divide between worlds, to fighting on a lake and within its reflective surface, and to a big fiery ball that you need to blow up before it’s too late. </p>
<p>It really is quite special as a visual showcase, built within Unreal Engine 5.</p>

<p>I also find that it’s quite a satisfying turnabout for the usual game creation tale of Western developers looking to Asian mythology and history for inspiration. Eclipse Glow Games is a Chinese studio that’s borrowed from British myths instead, setting Tides of Annihilation in a devastated and distorted version of London, following an Outworld invasion, and crossing over to the mythical realm of Avalon. </p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/11/20/see-a-spectacular-boss-battle-from-tides-of-annihilation/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Erosion Is an Open World Roguelite Spaghetti Western Shooter Where Your Deaths Advance Time and Bring Consequences]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/erosion-open-world-roguelite-spaghetti-western-shooter-deaths-advance-time/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/erosion-is-an-open-world-roguelite-spaghetti-western-shooter-where-your-deaths-advance-time-and-bring-consequences.1359937/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Polish indie developer Plot Twist has unveiled its new open world roguelite game, Erosion, at the Xbox Partner Preview, and it was certainly among the most interesting titles there.</p>



<p>In Erosion, players find themselves in a distant future where a mysterious, sentient rock formation known as the Pillar is consuming civilization, bit by bit. They must descend into the Pillar and battle through chaotic, fully destructible dungeons to get one step closer to saving the protagonist’s daughter or losing her to time itself forever. Every decision alters the course of the story, and every death reduces the time available.</p>



<p>The game can be roughly split into two parts: </p>



<ul>
<li>Dungeon runs, where the focus is on fast-paced, twin-stick roguelite combat in procedural dungeons.</li>



<li>The Overworld, a handcrafted, open world, spaghetti western environment dedicated to exploration, quests, and meta-progression.</li>
</ul>



<p>Erosion was built with a “low voxel” aesthetic, enabling full physics-driven environmental destructibility. Players will encounter a diverse range of biomes, both above ground (deserts, swamps, ancient cities) and below ground in dungeons, each presenting unique atmospheric and enemy challenges. The game features an extensive arsenal of weapons, active/passive skills, and "orbitals" that the player can equip to deal with enemies. Boss design draws inspiration from classic arcade games (Snake, DDR, Pong, Tetris), sometimes blending bullet hell and puzzle elements. Erosion even features side activities such as poker, racing, sand fishing, and hunting.</p>



<p>The game's defining feature, however, is undoubtedly the time jump mechanic. Dying advances time, irreversibly altering relationships and quest outcomes, with branching consequences. Decisions like which factions to help, quests to complete, or bosses to fight have persistent effects; some villages might be taken over by factions or descend into anarchy depending on player actions. Eventually, players can unlock the ability to travel backward in time, undo previous choices, and try alternative timelines, letting them explore different outcomes and ultimately fix eroding timelines.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="EROSION - Reveal Trailer | Time-looping Open-World Roguelike" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-LjJmCmI31k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Plot Twist is planning to kick off early access in Spring 2026 for PC (Steam, Xbox on PC, and Game Pass), with console versions to follow. The developer said the early access period is expected to be short but will include rolling content updates, such as new biomes, skills, and timelines. The devs also plan to explore two-person cooperative gameplay and robust post-launch content inspired by successful roguelites like Dead Cells.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/erosion-open-world-roguelite-spaghetti-western-shooter-deaths-advance-time/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Dominates With Seven Wins at Golden Joystick Awards 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/golden-joysticks-awards-2025-winners-full-list/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-dominates-with-seven-wins-at-golden-joystick-awards-2025.1359934/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The Golden Joystick Awards are consistently the awards show to kick off awards season for the video game industry, <a href="https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-leads-the-golden-joystick-awards-2025-nominations/">not just with how early the nominees are revealed</a>, but with how early the show is. It's not even December, and the popular annual awards show has named its Game of the Year winner, and winner of many more awards. This year, though, several of those awards, along with the Ultimate Game of the Year winner, all have the same recipient: Clair Obscur: Expedition 33.</p>



<p>Sandfall Interactive's debut title took home seven wins, including Sandfall being named the Studio of the Year, and Clair Obscur swept the performance-based awards as both Ben Starr and Jennifer English won for their performances of Verso and Maelle, respectively. It also won Best Storytelling, Best Visual Design, and Best Soundtrack, and was the only game to take home more than two awards, and it won in every category it was nominated for.</p>



<p>Though much of the night was focused on Clair Obscur, it wasn't the only game with a big win in the night. Ghost of Yotei took home two awards, including Console Game of the Year, while Hollow Knight Silksong took home PC Game of the Year and Best Indie Game (Self-Published).</p>



<p>You can check out the full list of winners form the Golden Joystick Awards 2025 for yourself, below.</p>



<h2 id="h-golden-joystick-awards-2025-winners-list">Golden Joystick Awards 2025 Winners List</h2>



<p id="1e6376d5-0121-4b67-882d-29e7ca313754"><strong>Best Storytelling</strong></p>



<ul id="582a4d95-b57d-4072-8199-641863d917d8">
<li><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>SILENT HILL f</li>



<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Mafia: The Old Country</li>



<li>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage</li>



<li>The Hundred Line - Last Defense Academy</li>
</ul>



<p id="9449115c-c94e-45ee-86c4-3f0bf0a774ad"><strong>Best Multiplayer Game</strong></p>



<ul id="8fafd3fb-980b-4bae-bd77-2d8aea3e7fd1">
<li>Battlefield 6</li>



<li><strong>PEAK</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>ELDEN RING NIGHTREIGN</li>



<li>Split Fiction</li>



<li>Mario Kart World</li>



<li>REMATCH</li>
</ul>



<p id="c5baa6b4-6685-4e6b-afff-18b356b5f688"><strong>Best Visual Design</strong></p>



<ul id="b314c166-4cc0-485e-844c-2aff80117a69">
<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>The Midnight Walk</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Sword of the Sea</li>



<li>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</li>
</ul>



<p id="efa92018-6391-442f-b3b8-ac232c4b8cdc"><strong>Best Indie Game</strong></p>



<ul id="42db1885-38ce-4fc3-8fcb-fa95af1f38d5">
<li><strong>Blue Prince</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector</li>



<li>Wanderstop</li>



<li>Skin Deep</li>



<li>despelote</li>



<li>Herdling</li>



<li>Abiotic Factor</li>



<li>Baby Steps</li>



<li>Caves of Qud</li>



<li>Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor</li>
</ul>



<p id="fe843425-05e2-418f-9185-419f7d9ac989"><strong>Best Indie Game - Self Published</strong></p>



<ul id="5f7b7ced-f229-4a51-a94f-d776120edb13">
<li><strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>Hades II</li>



<li>Sword of the Sea</li>



<li>PEAK</li>



<li>Keep Driving</li>



<li>Spilled!</li>



<li>Lonely Mountains: Snow Riders</li>



<li>DELTARUNE</li>



<li>Promise Mascot Agency</li>



<li>Consume Me</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Still Playing Award - PC and Console</strong></p>



<ul id="66949e47-6597-45ef-ba5f-c0fb63808c76">
<li><strong>Minecraft</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>Dead by Daylight</li>



<li>HELLDIVERS 2</li>



<li>NARAKA: BLADEPOINT</li>



<li>Satisfactory</li>



<li>Call of Duty: Warzone</li>



<li>Marvel Rivals</li>



<li>Fortnite</li>



<li>Apex Legends</li>



<li>Tom Clancy's Rainbow Six Siege X</li>



<li>GTA Online</li>



<li>Warframe</li>
</ul>



<p id="d2dedb65-3fd1-405c-b5fa-0176d9229625"><strong>Still Playing Award - Mobile</strong></p>



<ul id="f8f97c1a-9766-40fb-8b9c-b5ea89b9eedd">
<li>Call of Duty: Mobile</li>



<li><strong>Pokémon GO</strong> <strong>- Winner</strong></li>



<li>Subway Surfers</li>



<li>Clash Royale</li>



<li>Honkai: Star Rail</li>



<li>Genshin Impact</li>



<li>Zenless Zone Zero</li>



<li>Roblox</li>



<li>Free Fire</li>



<li>PUBG MOBILE</li>
</ul>



<p id="8dd77c40-0b9e-4d9f-9282-9e473befde37"><strong>Best Remake / Remaster</strong></p>



<ul id="6ef37325-8bcf-4690-898e-18f957274ef0">
<li>METAL GEAR SOLID Δ: SNAKE EATER</li>



<li><strong>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</strong> <strong>- Winner</strong></li>



<li>Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter</li>



<li>The Talos Principle: Reawakened</li>



<li>Gears of War: Reloaded</li>



<li>Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater 3 + 4</li>
</ul>



<p id="67b8a04f-726c-4d48-af5c-88129bd8cb86"><strong>Studio of the Year</strong></p>



<ul id="0846493c-08f5-4a4c-a718-e3bff4aace4e">
<li>Team Cherry</li>



<li><strong>Sandfall Interactive</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>Aggro Crab and Landfall</li>



<li>Bloober Team</li>



<li>Sloclap</li>



<li>Rebellion</li>
</ul>



<p id="6a7315c1-6a89-477b-bb7f-abbcd8b058ce"><strong>Best Game Expansion</strong></p>



<ul id="584a114d-1686-491c-a945-fc21ac9de428">
<li>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle: The Order of Giants</li>



<li><strong>Lies of P: Overture</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>No Man's Sky: Voyagers</li>



<li>Atomfall Story Expansion Pack: The Red Strain</li>



<li>Assassin's Creed Shadows - Claws of Awaji</li>



<li>Still Wakes the Deep: Siren's Rest</li>
</ul>



<p id="7dd762c6-02c4-440c-a5df-0dd9036f2569"><strong>Best Audio Design</strong></p>



<ul id="14a768c7-daff-4b0a-866c-860bea40f34c">
<li><strong>Ghost of Yōtei</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>Battlefield 6</li>



<li>Donkey Kong Bananza</li>



<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Two Point Museum</li>



<li>Cronos: The New Dawn</li>
</ul>



<p id="a936bc2e-e7c3-4052-a498-406ed9c7f457"><strong>Best Soundtrack</strong></p>



<ul id="ab0244c8-71c4-47fa-bae3-dda529332777">
<li><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>South of Midnight</li>



<li>SILENT HILL f</li>



<li>Eriksholm: The Stolen Dream</li>



<li>DELTARUNE</li>



<li>Sword of the Sea</li>
</ul>



<p id="da834f66-80b5-439d-bf75-8663773a9243"><strong>Best Lead Performer</strong></p>



<ul id="db81e39c-25d0-4b83-adbb-26b3f0ef0026">
<li><strong>Jennifer English - Maelle in Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>Troy Baker - Indiana Jones in Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</li>



<li>Tom McKay - Henry in Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li>



<li>Alex Jordan - Jan Dolski in The Alters</li>



<li>Erika Ishii - Atsu in Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Adriyan Rae - Hazel in South of Midnight</li>
</ul>



<p id="59b38754-642b-4e0f-8293-eed4724cfce1"><strong>Best Supporting Performer</strong></p>



<ul id="f92e20b1-0a9d-4b42-8ccf-f56f1d77e640">
<li>Troy Baker - Higgs Monaghan in Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Jim High - Erik in Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li>



<li><strong>Ben Starr - Verso in Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>Lucy Griffiths - Alva in Eriksholm: The Stolen Dream</li>



<li>Logan Cunningham - Hades II</li>



<li>Marios Gavrilis - Emmerich Voss in Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</li>
</ul>



<p id="77471778-f097-4812-8ce9-4e85b62ced52"><strong>PC Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul id="1e85de18-c50d-4760-b5de-e5528435b431">
<li><strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>The Alters</li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li>



<li>PEAK</li>



<li>Abiotic Factor</li>



<li>Dune: Awakening</li>
</ul>



<p id="d88e0192-3bcb-4819-acb9-03b6b6c8f007"><strong>Console Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul id="6da012ab-9528-43d6-838a-2f5406493c1c">
<li>Donkey Kong Bananza</li>



<li>Monster Hunter Wilds</li>



<li><strong>Ghost of Yōtei</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</li>



<li>Mario Kart World</li>
</ul>



<p id="ad58d2b0-f95d-491b-bda5-467febe27b75"><strong>Best Early Access Game</strong></p>



<ul id="a18acfe5-6bc5-47c1-ae38-71b7934a5dd9">
<li>Grounded 2</li>



<li>Schedule I</li>



<li>9 Kings</li>



<li><strong>R.E.P.O.</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>skate.</li>



<li>White Knuckle</li>
</ul>



<p id="7e51ceed-447a-49ad-96f4-1b6ef0e62ebc"><strong>Best Gaming Hardware</strong></p>



<ul id="7d4bf6ef-56d9-46d9-bea4-51be02f2bff7">
<li>Nintendo Switch 2</li>



<li>Nintendo Switch 2 Pro Controller</li>



<li>WD_BLACK SN8100 NVMe SSD</li>



<li>Elgato Facecam 4K</li>



<li>Razer Blade 16</li>



<li><strong>AMD Ryzen 9 9950X3D - Winner</strong></li>
</ul>



<p id="1f9cead8-4d16-41b8-b6d0-8a1d907356c3"><strong>Best Game Adaptation</strong></p>



<ul id="67b008b2-0c9f-4044-ab39-cc445c9416b8">
<li>Devil May Cry (Netflix)</li>



<li><strong>Arcane Season 2 (Netflix)</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>The Last of Us Season 2 (HBO)</li>



<li>A Minecraft Movie (Warner Bros. Pictures)</li>



<li>Secret Level (Prime Video)</li>



<li>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 (Paramount Pictures)</li>
</ul>



<p id="6c2cdd20-a67c-4f16-a93a-aedacd95b7ab"><strong>Best Game Trailer</strong></p>



<ul id="fb924a5b-c1fa-432e-b7fa-c2358fe836ad">
<li><strong>Grand Theft Auto VI Trailer 2</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>Battlefield 6: Official Launch Live Action Trailer</li>



<li>Rhythm Doctor - Official Release Date Trailer</li>



<li>The Expanse: Osiris Reborn - Announcement Trailer</li>



<li>ROMEO IS A DEAD MAN - Announcement Trailer</li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II Official CGI Trailer – Live a Life Medieval</li>
</ul>



<p id="4844ff0b-cd01-4806-ac7e-fac2f5172381"><strong>Most Wanted Game</strong></p>



<ul id="4dc8d434-74de-44f8-aa22-280bb984e7f1">
<li><strong>Grand Theft Auto VI</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>Resident Evil Requiem</li>



<li>The Witcher 4</li>



<li>Black Myth: Zhong Kui</li>



<li>LEGO Batman: Legacy of the Dark Night</li>



<li>007 First Light</li>



<li>EXODUS</li>



<li>Subnautica 2</li>



<li>Light No Fire</li>



<li>The Expanse: Osiris Reborn</li>



<li>Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</li>



<li>SAROS</li>



<li>The Blood of Dawnwalker</li>



<li>Crimson Desert</li>



<li>KINGDOM HEARTS IV</li>



<li>Marvel's Wolverine</li>



<li>Hell Let Loose: Vietnam</li>



<li>OD - KNOCK</li>



<li>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</li>



<li>Resonance: A Plague Tale Legacy</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Breakthrough Award</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Schedule I - Winner</strong></li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Streamer's Choice</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Peak - Winner</strong></li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Hall of Fame</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><strong>The Sims - Winner</strong></li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Critic's Choice</strong></p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Donkey Kong Bananza - Winner</strong></li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Ultimate Game of the Year Award</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Hollow Knight: Silksong</li>



<li><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong> - <strong>Winner</strong></li>



<li>Peak</li>



<li>Hades II</li>



<li>Split Fiction</li>



<li>Ghost of Yotei</li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li>



<li>Silent Hill f</li>



<li>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</li>



<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Donkey Kong Bananza</li>
</ul>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/golden-joysticks-awards-2025-winners-full-list/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's an unedited bossfight video from Tides Of Annihilation to sate your hunger for Arthurian witch murder]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-an-unedited-bossfight-video-from-tides-of-annihilation-to-sate-your-hunger-for-arthurian-witch-murder</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-an-unedited-bossfight-video-from-tides-of-annihilation-to-sate-your-hunger-for-arthurian-witch-murder.1359931/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Devil May Cry me a frozen river, Tyronoe</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tides-of-Annihilation-1.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tides-of-Annihilation-1.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tides-of-Annihilation-1.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tides-of-Annihilation-1.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tides-of-Annihilation-1.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tides-of-Annihilation-1.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tides-of-Annihilation-1.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tides-of-Annihilation-1.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tides-of-Annihilation-1.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eclipse Glow Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Biff! Smash! Spear to the groin! Asteroid to the jaw! It must be a new gameplay video for Tides Of Annihilation, the Arthurian fantasy action game from Eclipse Glow Games that's out to steal either <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/stellar-blade">Stellar Blade</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/final-fantasy-xvi">Final Fantasy XVI</a> or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/bayonetta">Bayonetta</a>'s lunch - do me a favour and pick one, because I can't decide. I can't stop comparing this game to things. I think there's something wrong with me. Help.</p>
<p>The hoity-toity Englishness of it all is somewhat Bayonetta (minus the humour), but the ally-summoning mechanics remind me more of FF16, while lead character Gwendolyn is from the same school of improbably clean-cut beauty as Stellar Blade's Eve. She's perhaps a bit more grizzled than Eve, possibly because she keeps letting witches hit her in the face with small planets.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Tides of Annihilation | &quot;Break the Mirror&quot; Gameplay Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VGOsH1Gp8SE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Tides of Annihilation | "Break the Mirror" Gameplay Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VGOsH1Gp8SE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VGOsH1Gp8SE?autoplay=1" title="Tides of Annihilation | &quot;Break the Mirror&quot; Gameplay Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VGOsH1Gp8SE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>The video shows us a boss battle against one of those witches, Tyronoe. It appears unedited, so we can get a sense of the ebb and flow of the game's fancier throwdowns. The boss alternates between human-scale punching, valkyrie bombardments from the other side of energy barriers, and a tricksy little moment where she warps through a frozen lake's mirrored surface and starts battering you from inside the reflection. Fortunately, Gwendolyn teams up mid-fight with a Knight of the Roundtable, Lamorak, whose twisty javelin proves super-effective against the hag.</p>
<p>A barrage of background trivia from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tides-of-annihilation-brings-devil-may-crys-speed-and-god-of-wars-scale-to-post-apocalyptic-arthurian-london">the announcement post</a>: based in China, Eclipse Glow number 100 developers and have people who've previously worked on Yakuza, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/for-honor">For Honor</a>, Assassin's Creed, Persona, and Prince of Persia.</p>
<p>Tides Of Annihilation will be 30 hours long, and will have around 30 bosses. Some of the enemies are big enough to be levels, a la Fumito Ueda. Yes, that <em>is</em> Jennifer English of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii">Baldur's Gate 3</a> fame voicing Gwendolyn. The game is set across post-apocalyptic London and mythical Avalon, and they may have <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/new-tides-of-annihilation-trailer-is-a-buttery-montage-of-bossfights">got the bus routes wrong</a>.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-an-unedited-bossfight-video-from-tides-of-annihilation-to-sate-your-hunger-for-arthurian-witch-murder]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Philips Hue 3-Bulb Pack Hits a New Record Low, Amazon Goes Nuts on Black Friday’s First Day]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-philips-hue-3-bulb-pack-hits-a-new-record-low-amazon-goes-nuts-on-black-fridays-first-day-2000645817</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-philips-hue-3-bulb-pack-hits-a-new-record-low-amazon-goes-nuts-on-black-friday%E2%80%99s-first-day.1359922/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Traditional light switches offer exactly two settings: on and off, which leaves you stuck with whatever harsh overhead lighting the previous homeowner installed. The Philips Hue 3-pack <em>White and Color Ambiance</em> bulbs <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5759/">just dropped to a record low of $69 for Black Friday on Amazon, down from the usual $109 price</a>.</p>
<p>Philips maintains strict pricing on Hue products throughout the year which makes Black Friday the only time these smart bulbs receive meaningful discounts. <strong>Smart lighting completely changes room ambiance</strong> by letting you tune color temperature, brightness and even hue to match your activity or mood rather than accepting whatever your builder-grade fixtures emit.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5759/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Millions of Colors</h2>
<p>The <em>White and Color Ambiance</em> range reproduces millions of distinct colors alongside the full spectrum of white light, <strong>from 2000K warm amber to 6500K cool daylight</strong>. You can bathe your living room in deep blue for movie nights, shift to energizing daylight white for morning routines or create warm orange tones for dinner ambiance. The color accuracy spans the entire visible spectrum, giving you precise control over the exact shade you want rather than cycling through preset options. Each bulb can display different colors simultaneously, so you might have blue accent lighting in one lamp while maintaining warm white in overhead fixtures. The 60W-<strong>equivalent brightness delivers 800 lumens at full power,</strong> and provides enough light for reading or detailed work rather than just mood lighting.</p>



<p>The<strong> bulbs connect directly to your home Wi-Fi network without needing a separate hub</strong>, but with the addition of a Hue Bridge come more advanced features: remote control from anywhere and more stable connections that don’t tax your router. Matter compatibility integrates Hue bulbs with other smart home devices across manufacturers, creating unified automation regardless of which ecosystem you’ve invested in. You can trigger lights based on motion sensors, door contacts, or time schedules without maintaining separate apps for each device brand. Secure connection protocols block unauthorized access to your lighting system while maintaining responsive control.</p>
<p><strong>Preset scenes</strong> offer one-touch lighting setups for frequent activities and times of day. The 24-hour natural light scene automatically adjusts color temperature throughout the day to simulate sunlight, gradually changing from warm tones at sunrise to bright daylight in the afternoon and back to amber hues at sunset. Such circadian lighting supports your body’s natural rhythm and could give you better sleep quality by reducing blue light exposure before going to bed.</p>



<p><strong>Voice control via Alexa, Google Assistant, and Apple HomeKit</strong> means you won’t have to reach for your phone every time you want to issue basic lighting commands. The voice commands work with individual bulbs, rooms or zones that group multiple lights together. This is pretty handy when you’ve got messy hands from cooking, are settling into bed, or trying to get through the door while carrying groceries.</p>
<p>The <strong>standard A19 form factor fits any fixture</strong> designed for traditional bulbs, from table lamps to ceiling fixtures to bathroom vanities. The bulb screws into E26 sockets designed for standard medium-base bulbs, requiring no special adapters or modifications. LED technology remains cool to the touch and uses a mere 9 watts while delivering <strong>brightness equivalent to 60-watt incandescent bulbs</strong>, and reduces electricity costs while lasting 25,000 hours or roughly 22 years at three hours daily use.</p>
<p>At $69 for three bulbs, this Black Friday deal brings the per-bulb cost down to $23, which undercuts Philips’s regular single-bulb pricing of $49. You’re getting full-color smart bulbs from the industry leader in smart lighting for less than many color-changing bulbs from unknown brands.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5759/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-philips-hue-3-bulb-pack-hits-a-new-record-low-amazon-goes-nuts-on-black-fridays-first-day-2000645817]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ugreen Dumps Its 65W USB-C Wall Charger With 4 Ports, Now Going for Pocket Change]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ugreen-dumps-its-65w-usb-c-wall-charger-with-4-ports-now-going-for-pocket-change-2000645791</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ugreen-dumps-its-65w-usb-c-wall-charger-with-4-ports-now-going-for-pocket-change.1359919/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Wall outlets disappear fast when every device needs its own charging brick cluttering power strips and blocking adjacent sockets. The <strong>Ugreen</strong> <em>Nexode</em> 65W GaN charger <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4472/">just hit a record low of $24 for Black Friday on Amazon, down from its usual $39 price</a>. This four-port charger consolidates multiple charging bricks into a single compact unit that occupies one outlet while powering your laptop, phone, tablet, and wireless earbuds simultaneously. When traveling, carrying four separate chargers involves dedicating a lot of valuable bag space to power adapters, whereas this single charger handles everything. GaN technology keeps the charger cool and efficient while intelligently outputting a total 65W across three USB-C ports and one USB-A port.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4472/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>65W Powers Your MacBook at Full Speed</h2>
<p>The<strong> 65W maximum output is enough to fast-charge a MacBook Air at its full charging rate,</strong> and reach 51% battery in just 30 minutes. This matches the charging speed you’d get from Apple’s own 61W charger, so you’re not settling with the Ugreen as some kind of compromise. Power delivery is via USB-C Power Delivery 3.0 protocol that negotiates optimal charging rates with compatible devices automatically.</p>



<p>The <strong>four-port configuration includes three USB-C ports and one USB-A port</strong> that can cover modern devices alongside legacy gadgets. That three-USB-C setup means you can charge your laptop, phone, and tablet simultaneously using the same type of cable without hunting for different connectors. This design leaves the USB-A port for older devices, wireless earbuds, smartwatches, and accessories that haven’t transitioned to USB-C yet. Dynamic distribution of the total 65W output by intelligent power distribution allows for the <strong>charger to adjust the output based on what devices you plug in</strong> and their power requirements.</p>
<p>Gallium nitride technology replaces traditional silicon components found in the charger with more efficient materials that conduct electricity much better while generating less heat. This efficiency enables Ugreen to pack 65W of charging power<strong> into a charger that is significantly smaller than older silicon-based 65W adapters</strong>.</p>



<p>At compact dimensions,<strong> it measures just 2.64 by 1.65 by 1.5 inches</strong> and this charger is smaller than Apple’s single-port 67W adapter despite offering four ports and comparable power. This reduction in size matters enormously for travel: the charger easily fits into laptop bags, toiletry pouches, or jacket pockets without consuming excessive space. The foldable prongs collapse flat against the charger body and prevents them from snagging on bag contents or poking holes in pouches.</p>
<p>Universal compatibility includes MacBook Pro and Air series, iPhone 17/16/… series, Samsung Galaxy S25/S24/…, Pixel 10/9/…, iPad Pro, Steam Deck, and quite basically everything that charges via USB. It’s compatible across manufacturers and platforms without the need for brand-specific adapters or configurations. Charge Apple devices from USB-C ports and charge Android devices from the same ports without any compatibility issues.</p>
<p>At $24, this Ugreen 65W charger is 39% off retail while bringing features and performance that are in line with chargers costing upwards of $60 from premium brands.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4472/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ugreen-dumps-its-65w-usb-c-wall-charger-with-4-ports-now-going-for-pocket-change-2000645791]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nuketown’s Most Popular Easter Egg Isn’t Working In Black Ops 7]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nuketowns-most-popular-easter-egg-isnt-working-in-black-ops-7/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nuketown%E2%80%99s-most-popular-easter-egg-isn%E2%80%99t-working-in-black-ops-7.1359916/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 7’s preseason content brings Nuketown. The camo grind really begins now, but there’s a distinct lack of Easter Eggs in Nuketown, including the legendary mannequin heads.</p>



<p>Black Ops 7 is about to really get going. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-season-1-release-maps-zombies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Season 1</a> is getting ready to get underway, and this will signal the long-awaited <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-black-ops-7-warzone-coming-out-black-ops-7-warzone-integration/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 7 &amp; Warzone Integration</a>. Before this, the preseason has started, which includes the debut (again) of Nuketown. This is the latest incarnation of the decade-old map.</p>



<p>But it’s missing one big thing at launch.</p>







<h2 id="h-black-ops-7-nuketown-mannequins-can-t-be-shot">Black Ops 7 Nuketown Mannequins Can’t Be Shot</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It’s a waiting game. Credit to Activision</figcaption></figure>



<p>The mannequin heads can’t be shot in Black Ops 7’s Nuketown right now. The map is live, it has its own playlist option, but the mannequin heads are very resolute, meaning no Nuketown Easter Egg.</p>







<p>Ordinarily, you can shoot the mannequin heads, and if you pop all of them off, a humorous Easter Egg plays out. It varies from game to game, but there’s no such thing in Black Ops 7 right now.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>If you’ve encountered this, don’t worry, it’s probably not permanent. This has happened before, and the mannequin Easter Egg—as well as any others—is usually activated once Season 1 begins.</p>



<p>No one knows why this is the case, but it’s usually what happens. So, be patient, and the time will come for you to furiously dislodge plastic heads from idle mannequin bodies.</p>



<p>Have you encountered any other weird occurrences in Black Ops 7? Bring it to everyone’s attention in the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Black Ops 7, check out the latest on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-double-xp-weekend/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Next Black Ops 7 Double XP Weekend</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-7-dark-ops-challenges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">All Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Dark Ops Challenges Being Listed</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nuketowns-most-popular-easter-egg-isnt-working-in-black-ops-7/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reanimal, the New Co-Op Horror From the Devs of Little Nightmares, Is Out in February]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/reanimal-the-new-co-op-horror-from-the-devs-of-little-nightmares-is-out-in-february</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reanimal-the-new-co-op-horror-from-the-devs-of-little-nightmares-is-out-in-february.1359913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Reanimal, the upcoming co-op horror game from the creators of Little Nightmares, now has a release date announced at the Xbox Partner Presents. It's coming out on February 13, 2026 for Xbox, PC, PS5, and Nintendo Switch 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We got a look at a new trailer today during the presentation, which showed off the pair of siblings you play as traveling through some new locations.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Reanimal is incredibly unsettling, as is fitting for the Little Nightmares folks. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/little-nightmares-developer-reveals-reanimal-with-super-creepy-trailer-gamescom-2024">First announced at Gamescom 2024</a>, you play as a brother and sister trying to rescue their missing friends. You'll solve environmental puzzles and travel both by land and boat on this quest, haunted by horrible monsters and pieces of the childrens' past.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The good news is, if you don't have a friend to play with, you can play Reanimal in single-player, as well as with both local and online co-op.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can catch up on everything announced at today's Partner Showcase <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-partner-preview-november-2025-everything-announced-updating-live">right here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/reanimal-the-new-co-op-horror-from-the-devs-of-little-nightmares-is-out-in-february]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dave the Diver Is Out Now on Xbox at Last]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dave-the-diver-is-out-now-on-xbox-at-last</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dave-the-diver-is-out-now-on-xbox-at-last.1359907/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Announced during today's Xbox Partner Showcase, Dave the Diver has plunged onto Xbox consoles at last.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Per the trailer, the Xbox version of the game is out now. Dave the Diver was originally only available on PC at its 2023 launch, followed by a Nintendo Switch version in 2024 and PlayStation releases in 2024. A Nintendo Switch 2 dedicated version just released earlier this month.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Dave the Diver follows Dave, who by day dives into the Blue Hole to catch fish with his harpoon gun in a survival adventure setting, and by night runs a sushi restaurant where he serves up his catching to hungry diners in a management sim. The game received wide acclaim at launch: <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dave-the-diver-review">we gave it a 9/10</a>, saying it's "wholesome, wonderfully complex, and delightfully hard to put down."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to the trailer, we also got a brief tease of some upcoming previously-announced DLC, called In the Jungle, which will feature the addition of freshwater fish and some amount of new story. This DLC was previously announced at The Game Awards last year for a late 2025 launch, but was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dave-the-diver-delays-in-the-jungle-dlc-but-sure-knows-how-to-soften-the-blow-with-these-other-announcements" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">later delayed to 2026</a>. Developer Mintrocket has now narrowed the window to "early 2026" with this trailer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can catch up on everything announced at today's Xbox Partner Showcase <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-partner-preview-november-2025-everything-announced-updating-live">right here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/dave-the-diver-is-out-now-on-xbox-at-last]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Godfall Developers Reveal New Game Armatus, a Third-Person Action Game Set in a Messed Up Paris]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/godfall-developers-reveal-new-game-armatus-a-third-person-action-game-set-in-a-messed-up-paris</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/godfall-developers-reveal-new-game-armatus-a-third-person-action-game-set-in-a-messed-up-paris.1359904/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Today's Xbox Partner Showcase opened with a brand new game reveal I certainly didn't see coming: it's called Armatus, and it's seemingly being made by the developers of Godfall.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Armatus is a new third-person roguelite shooter set in a fictionalized version of Paris that's looking...pretty messed up. An event called The Vanishing has effectively caused the end of the world, and you're some sort of masked warrior roaming around and fighting demons. That's really all we know for now: the trailer gave us a look at a lot of combat and some pretty cool monster designs.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In an <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2025/11/20/armatus-xbox-partner-preview/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Xbox Wire post</a>, we learned a little more: after the end of the world, four members of something called the Armatus meet and summon the player to fight on their behalf and get them sent to heaven. You're searching for something called The Sunless Gate along The Scoured Path, which is a constantly changing road through a broken Paris, with procedurally-spawned rooms, enemy compositions, and rewards. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you've forgotten everything about Counterplay's last game, Godfall, here's a refresh: Godfall was an action RPG that came out in 2020, initially just for PlayStation and PC but later for Xbox as well. It was described at the time as a "looter-slasher", heavily focused on finding and collecting better and better gear, and that admittedly had an awful lot of cool-looking weapons to collect. Unfortunately it received pretty mixed reviews, including from us, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/godfall-review">getting an IGN 6/10</a>. As our reviewer put it then: "Godfall can be an enjoyable and lovely gear-based action game while it lasts, but the repetition of its missions wears thin before the end of its campaign, and even thinner in the endgame afterward." Hopefully Armatus fairs better.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Armatus is coming out in 2026 for Xbox Series consoles, PS5, PC, and Nintendo Switch 2. You can catch up on everything announced at today's Partner Showcase <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-partner-preview-november-2025-everything-announced-updating-live">right here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/godfall-developers-reveal-new-game-armatus-a-third-person-action-game-set-in-a-messed-up-paris]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Buy Slashes $20 off Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater in Black Friday Sales]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-slashes-20-off-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-in-black-friday-sales</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-buy-slashes-20-off-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-in-black-friday-sales.1359901/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Scoop up this remake for $50 ahead of the holidays.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/events/black-friday">Black Friday</a> sales are officially kicking off. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-2025-black-friday-sale-is-now-live">Best Buy has dropped its selection of deals today</a>, and there's plenty of excellent offers to look through, including quite a few video game deals. Among them is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a>, which is currently $20 off at the retailer.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This Black Friday deal has dropped its price from $69.99 to $49.99, but what's even better is that it applies to both the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X versions of the game (<a href="https://zdcs.link/aN8kBE?object_uuid=89aa1a0f-3348-46d3-89e1-1e610d509601&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">see the deal here at Best Buy</a>). No matter the platform you prefer, you can score a sweet little deal on the game we said, "largely succeeds as a faithful, visually impressive remake of the 2004 classic."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater Down to $49.99 at Best Buy</h2><div catalogid="59ce092f-3a6b-4e70-bd00-36ce10ba573c" id="230935"><div id="230935" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Metal Gear Solid Δ: Snake Eater - Tactical Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Our 8/10 <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-review">review of Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a> from IGN's Michael Higham also said, "if I were to point someone to one of the many versions available, this is the one I'd recommend, whether they're revisiting or playing for the first time." It's also a game we consider to be one of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-video-game-remakes">best video game remakes</a> in general, so if you've been waiting for a good time to play it, now is the time to make your move.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alongside this deal on Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater, there's so much more to explore at Best Buy right now. They're not the only retailer to have started up their sales early, either. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-black-friday-sale-2025-early-deals">Amazon has even dropped their Black Friday deals today</a>, so there's plenty to look through. If you're curious what other deals we're expecting to see this year, and which retailers will also be participating in the sale event, check out our breakdown of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2025-predictions-and-latest-news">Black Friday 2025</a> for more information.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 20, 2025 6:00 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-buy-slashes-20-off-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-in-black-friday-sales]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Major Borderlands 4 Update Adds Smarter Loot Drops, a New Legendary Loot Indicator for the Radar, and a Lot More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/major-borderlands-4-update-adds-smarter-loot-drops-a-new-legendary-loot-indicator-for-the-radar-and-a-lot-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/major-borderlands-4-update-adds-smarter-loot-drops-a-new-legendary-loot-indicator-for-the-radar-and-a-lot-more.1359898/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Gearbox has released a significant patch for Borderlands 4 that makes some quality-of-life improvements such as smarter loot drops and a new Legendary Loot Indicator for your radar. These arrive alongside visual polish and stability updates for a “smoother” experience on Kairos, Gearbox said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Digging into the detail, Class Mods have been adjusted to drop more for your current character, which is a welcome change for those on the hunt for ever-improving builds. The loot feed is now updated to display total current currency after spending or receiving money, and the likelihood of unintended movements or knockbacks while reviving a teammate is reduced. And it's worth noting that the patch adds a new Legendary Loot Indicator to the combat radar for easier identification of high-rarity drops. given how busy with loot Borderlands 4 can get, this is also welcome.</p><div id="borderlands-4-all-vault-hunter-skill-trees-ranked" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Borderlands 4: All Vault Hunter Skill Trees Ranked</h3><h3>Borderlands 4: All Vault Hunter Skill Trees Ranked</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">In the <a href="https://borderlands.2k.com/borderlands-4/update-notes/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">patch notes</a>, below, Gearbox said it was wrapping up work on Photo Mode, while other updates like support for multiple active Big Encore Machines and more options for scaling difficulty are coming.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Further into the future, Gearbox said it’s looking at ways to improve shared character progression, add additional endgame-focused activities (Takedown), launch cross-save support, and more. Major Updates, which deliver larger-scale changes, are planned to deploy about a month apart.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Today’s update launches alongside Bounty Pack 1: How Rush Saved Mercenary Day, which is now free for all players. How Rush Saved Mercenary Day is the first of five post-launch DLC Bounty Packs coming to Borderlands 4. While How Rush Saved Mercenary Day is free for all players, Bounty Packs 2, 3, 4, and 5 are included with Borderlands 4 Deluxe Edition, Borderlands 4 Super Deluxe Edition, the Borderlands 4 Bounty Pack Bundle, and will be available for separate purchase.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Borderlands 4 November 20 Major Update Patch Notes:</h2><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Bounty Pack 1: How Rush Saved Mercenary Day</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph">We're stoked for you to team up with Rush and teach Minister Screw the true meaning of Mercenary Day! This being a holiday-themed Bounty Pack, we knew we had to deliver it to you by the end of the year. However, the team realized that there was more mayhem than time when it came to getting as much into Bounty Pack 1 as originally planned while never slowing down in their mission to improve the <em>Borderlands 4</em> player experience. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">So in the spirit of the season, we're giving a gift to all <em>Borderlands 4</em> players by making Bounty Pack 1 free! Thank you for all the passion and support you've given us as a community. We're hard at work making sure future Bounty Packs are more fully loaded with the compelling content players have been asking for. In addition, we're now adding a new Bounty Pack 5 (more on that in a bit); there's a lot of amazing stuff coming to <em>Borderlands 4</em>, so stay tuned!</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added support for How Rush Saved Mercenary Day content! Jump into this free content today by finding and interacting with the gift-wrapped present (marked on your map as a new mission) in any major hub, which will initiate the mission to assist Rush!</li><li>Added support for the Bounty Pack 1 Vault Card! Playing <em>Borderlands 4</em> with a Vault Card active gives you more loot and XP via Daily and Weekly challenges, and it can be leveled up at your own pace (no time limits or expiring rewards here). You can activate it via the Vault Card screen in your ECHO menu. Vault Card progression works just like leveling up: it's all driven by how much XP you're gaining. By exploring Kairos, killing enemies, and completing quests, you'll fill up your Vault Card progression in addition to your regular XP!<ul data-cy="list"><li>This includes 4 new pieces of rerollable gear and 24 new cosmetics to earn!</li></ul></li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Notable Changes</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>We wanted to pull these out specifically as they have been heavily mentioned in the community. </strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Updated the Weekly Wildcard Missions to set additional start points in missions</li><li>Dev Note: This feature will allow future Weekly Wildcard Missions to jump straight to the meat of a mission.</li><li>Class Mods have been adjusted to drop more for your current character</li><li>Converted the Phosphene weapon challenge from character-based to profile-wide progression<ul data-cy="list"><li>Dev Note: This long-term grind is aimed at our most dedicated community members who invest the most time in the game. Still, we agree that completing this collection is more a reflection of your dedication to the game and not to a specific Vault Hunter. This is the first example of allowing more progression to be shared between all characters on your account.</li></ul></li><li>Updated the loot feed to display total current currency after spending or receiving money</li><li>Reduced the likelihood of unintended movements or knockbacks while reviving a teammate<ul data-cy="list"><li>Dev Note: When reviving another player, the reviving player is temporarily given more mass, making enemy attacks less likely to bounce you away from your partner.</li></ul></li><li>Added a new Legendary Loot Indicator to the combat radar for easier identification of high-rarity drops</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Gameplay &amp; Mission Progression</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed an issue that could cause the loss of SDU Tokens or Specialization points; this also returns missing tokens and points to those impacted</li><li>Resolved an interaction where players could not repurchase a boss encounter after all party members were defeated and respawned in multiplayer</li><li>Slide-attacking lootable objects will now open or break them consistently</li><li>Resolved progression blockers for more intuitive gameplay during <em>Faction Survivalist</em>, <em>Wayward Gun</em>, <em>Another Day, Another Universe</em>, the Badass Phalanx bounty, and the Black Market Tutorial</li><li>Corrected behavior where mission items could disappear after replaying and exiting a mission, preventing completion</li><li>Prevented rare instances of some enemies turning into NPCs and becoming unkillable</li><li>Adjusted tracking on some challenges and achievements to award progress as intended</li><li>Dev Note: <em>The Professional</em> now only awards progress for designated challenge conditions, while <em>Private Reserve</em> and <em>What Have We Here?</em> will progress correctly when opening chests with melee attacks. The <em>Arena Grande</em> achievement should consistently unlock in multiplayer.</li><li>Mort will revive players more consistently during <em>Thresher Rancher</em> </li><li>Resolved a condition where vehicles could be instantly destroyed if summoned immediately after using a Repkit with the Splat trait</li><li>Adjusted object placement and pathing across multiple missions, ensuring proper enemy spawns, interactions, Echolocation, and waypoint alignment</li><li>Synchronized some mismatched animations and behaviors in multiplayer</li><li>Resolved a reported issue where players could become briefly suspended in midair when exiting mission replay while jumping or swimming</li><li>Addressed a bug causing the Chopper vehicles to remain in a falling state after performing a vertical jump or powerslide</li><li>Prevented vehicle summoning in restricted indoor areas such as the Umbral Foundry Fortress</li><li>Removed the penalty during <em>Scoundrel Roundup: Kilo</em> if the panel is shot twice</li><li>Updated Mimicron’s combat behavior so it can no longer be stun-locked by singularity effects in the Tipping Point Bunker</li><li>Updated Patrol Ripper contract to progress with intended sources</li><li>Updated the Order Bunker boss Fractis encounter to ensure the boss remains defeatable after entering its shielded phase in The Crawlfort</li><li>Adjusted behavior in <em>The Next Quest Thing</em> so the mission can consistently be accepted after saving and reloading</li><li>Improved enemy physics in <em>Gone Are My Leggies</em> to prevent The Beastie from being launched out of the playable area when hit with high-impact weapons</li><li>Restored ECHO Log rewards for completing optional objectives in three micro-missions when played solo</li><li>Adjusted Arjay’s resistances so status effect damage-over-time now applies correctly<ul data-cy="list"><li>Dev Note: Visual inconsistencies with Arjay’s wings might appear as a result of this change, but will not impact gameplay. </li></ul></li><li>Adjusted arena boundaries so Locust’s gas canisters now spawn correctly within the arena during the Idolator Sol encounter in Fortress Indomita</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Vault Hunters</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Amon, the Forgeknight</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Updated Forgeknight Forgedrone challenge so it unlocks properly upon meeting completion requirements</li><li>Corrected skill tree investment functionality to prevent Forgeknight from applying skill points out of order</li><li>Updated weapon input handling so Forgeknight can reliably swap weapons after using the whip attack</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Rafa, the Exo-Soldier</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Exo-Soldier's <strong>Soltado</strong> Kill Skill passive has been adjusted to function properly with two skill points</li><li>Improved <strong>PROJECT: Raiju</strong> capstone behavior so APOPHIS Lance consistently damages enemies during extended uptime</li><li>Adjusted <strong>Booming Business</strong> passive's functionality to prevent grenade spawns when the passive skill exceeds its intended level cap</li><li>Updated the <strong>Temerario</strong> passive skill so it provides the intended gun damage bonus rather than a general damage increase</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Vex, the Siren</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Updated challenge tracking so the <strong>Target Prescience</strong> passive only progresses when damaging valid targets</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Harlowe, the Gravitar</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Ensured that <strong>QED</strong> passive skill would remain functional in multiplayer</li><li>Updated Gravitar’s <strong>Zero-Point </strong>Action Skill so it now properly enters cooldown when used on enemies immune to Stasis. Previously, using the skill on a Stasis-immune target after affecting a normal enemy could cause it to remain active instead of triggering cooldown </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>All Vault Hunters</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted critical hit calculations so gun and enhancement damage now applies correctly to all valid hit regions</li><li>Adjusted Cryo resistance scaling so enemy resistances now correctly match each player’s level in multiplayer sessions</li><li>Prevented Action Skills from activating during the first loading screen before entering active gameplay</li><li>Updated kill volume logic to ensure Vault Hunters cannot cheat death while in FFYL and healing with the Legendary Shield <em>Guardian Angel</em></li><li>Ensured sniper ammo displays full capacity when creating a level 30 Vault Hunter</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Gear and Rewards</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted melee damage on Bayonet weapons so that melee damage increases with bayonet parts</li><li>Updated beam weapon behavior so they will deal proper damage when thrown</li><li>Addressed an interaction allowing players to infinitely scale the splash radius of homing sticky projectiles when using Torgue Legendary Pistol <em>Queen’s Rest</em> with certain builds and firmware combinations</li><li>Updated <em>Skully</em> grenade to adjust projectile damage for consistent output</li><li>Corrected boss health bar updates so sustained heavy Ordnance damage with Amon now displays correctly</li><li>Updated Torgue Heavy Weapon <em>Ravenfire</em> so it now correctly applies elemental damage when equipped with elemental parts</li><li>Adjusted Maliwan Heavy Weapon behavior so projectiles created from a hit don't detonate immediately after spawning</li><li>Corrected the explosion delay of <em>Fuel Rod Discharge</em> to match its description of 3 seconds when used on Ripper shotguns</li><li>Adjusted Rolling Thunder underbarrel grenades on Torgue shotguns to behave predictably on vertical surfaces instead of ricocheting excessively</li><li>Prevented bosses from floating when Exo-Soldier's <strong>Booming Business</strong> passive skill was triggered with Order Legendary Grenade <em>Skully</em></li><li>Addressed a condition where the Vladof Legendary Shield <em>Heavyweight</em> could lose functionality after activating Forgeknight <strong>Onslaughter</strong> skill</li><li>Adjusted projectile interaction during the fight with Vile Ripper so players can now destroy the homing “Unstable Ore” projectiles</li><li>Updated collision behavior so Jakobs Throwing Knife grenades correctly impact the orb surrounding Vile Ordonite of Corrupted enemies</li><li>Adjusted some gear that was behaving inconsistently in multiplayer, such as: the bounce-back force of The Order Legendary pistol <em>Noisy Cricket</em>, reload animation timing for the Jakobs shotgun <em>Hot Slugger</em>, and misaligned accuracy of the Daedalus pistol <em>Bonn-91</em></li><li>Standardized some instances of Firmware 3-piece bonus cooldowns to appear consistently. Visual cooldowns have been added for Oscar Mike, Ahoy, and Daed-dy O’</li><li>Drops are no longer kept in the air when lowering the platform in <em>All Charged Up</em> </li><li>Restored functionality allowing players to loot and preview weapons from red chests after completing the Blacklime Bunker</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Gear Balance:</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Darkbeast</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed a scaling issue</li><li>Explosion Chance increased from 5% to 20%</li><li>Damage increased by 15%</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Prince Harming</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed a scaling issue</li><li>Self Damage amount reduced from 5% to 1.5% of damage done</li><li>Damage increased by ~24%</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Onslaught:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Damage increased by 75% </li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ruby's Grasp:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Damage increased by ~40%</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Lucky Clover:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Damage increased by 37.5%</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Vamoose:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Damage increased by 20%</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Asher's Rise</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed a scaling issue</li><li>Damage increased by 5%</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Firmware Balance:</strong></h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Get Throwin':</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Ordnance Damage increased from 10% to 35%</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Daed-dy O':</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Damage increased from 20% to 35%</li><li>Mag Size increase from 15% to 20%</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Rubberband Man:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Damage Reduction increased from 5% to 10%</li><li>Lifesteal increased from 5% to 10%</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Jacked:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Zoom-in Speed bonus increased from 20% to 35%</li><li>Hyperion Shield Capacity bonus increased from 25% to 50%</li><li>Ricochet chance increased from 30% to 40%</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Atlas Ex:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Mode Swap Speed increased from 25% to 33%</li><li>Damage while locked increased from 10% to 25%</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Atlas Infinium:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fire Rate bonus increased from 5% to 12%</li><li>Damage bonus increased from 10% to 15%</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Reel Big Fist:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Explosion Radius slightly increased</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Airstrike:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Missile damage increased by 35%</li><li>Decreased Cooldown from 8s to 5s</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>UI, UX, &amp; Text</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Restored filter functionality to Lost Loot menus and addressed non-functional filter selections and sorting dropdowns  </li><li>Updated the Lost Loot menu so the selected sort option is retained after exiting and re-entering</li><li>Adjusted map icon layering so Main Mission icons no longer overlap Wildcard Mission <em>Giver</em></li><li>Adjusted scrolling behaviors in menus in splitscreen</li><li>Ensured the Transfer Machine remains open after exiting inspect mode</li><li>Added separate sensitivity sliders for mouse and controller inputs in the Controls (Basic) menu on PC</li><li>Corrected the buddy widget display so respawned characters no longer appear as “still respawning” </li><li>Updated item rarity displays to show the correct color and tier when playing in non-English languages</li><li>Removed extra ECHO Log slots </li><li>Restored missing item thumbnails in the bank menu and improved loading speed for equipped and backpack item thumbnails when large numbers of items are stored in the bank</li><li>Updated Explore Menu positioning so it displays correctly in front of the explored region during vertical split-screen</li><li>Adjusted layout so Item Cards no longer overlap when compared in horizontal split-screen</li><li>Addressed a reported issue where weapons could unequip and disappear when changing their customization in the Status menu</li><li>Corrected overshield coloration and behavior for pets and buddy widgets so that health, shield, and armor visuals now display properly</li><li>Adjusted Contract trackers to only appear when the Contract is active</li><li>Resolved a reported issue where mission-related celebratory notifications could display duplicate icons</li><li>Added the missing “Restart to Apply Changes” prompt when adjusting texture quality during gameplay</li><li>Updated option descriptions to be more intuitive and player-friendly</li><li>Addressed the chaos displayed by the “SHiFT code is valid” countdown in the SHiFT menu</li><li>Updated controller prompts so the correct input type displays when opening the SHiFT menu from the main men</li><li>Removed an extra scrollbar that could appear when Reporting Users</li><li>Addressed text inconsistencies in some side missions</li><li>Updated D-pad functionality on controller to behave as expected</li><li>Preserved key bindings that could be removed between sessions for non-English keys </li><li>Standardized ECHO Log tracking for the Kairos Speaks challenge to ensure totals display consistently between general and mission log views </li><li>Updated localization, mission naming, and various text descriptions across the game</li><li>Updated end credits</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Visuals</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed reported instances where players could become invisible when performing a Vault-level transition during a travel tunnel</li><li>Addressed an issue with missing parts and textures on gear</li><li>Updated ECHO-4 character model and digistruct to have lights, eyes, and thruster effects appear correctly</li><li>Adjusted fishing point visuals so markers no longer appear incorrectly on terrain near Sandytoes Villa</li><li>Updated level geometry and collision across multiple regions to prevent players from becoming stuck, falling out of bounds, or being blocked by invisible surfaces</li><li>Adjusted grappling points and traversal paths in multiple missions to prevent players from chaining grapples into unintended areas or losing functionality</li><li>Addressed misplaced or inaccessible loot containers, including strongboxes and vending-area chests in The Wireworks and Windspear</li><li>Addressed inaccurate rendering of water in some locations</li><li>Corrected lingering slide smoke effects that could appear when moving or jumping after performing a slide</li><li>Turned off the mining laser after shutting down the second Eridium generator in Terminus Range</li><li>Corrected visual stretching on character and NPC cloth when adjusting the FOV while the game is paused</li><li>Updated <em>Dark Subject</em> mission so Tim’s weapon now properly disappears with his model during the “Kill Tim”</li><li>Addressed multiple reported animation inconsistencies including gear, NPCs, hand stuttering, root-lock issues, and visual glitches during combat actions. These improvements remove visible sliding or snapping during melee or grapple sequences</li><li>Improved environmental synchronization in multiplayer</li><li>Adjusted mouth animation timing for Callis in <em>Another Day, Another Universe</em> and for Numba One in <em>Mob Mentality</em> so dialogue syncs correctly</li><li>Balanced underwater lighting and brightness near Belton’s Bore (The Low Leys, Mountains) for more consistent visual clarity when diving below the surface </li><li>Repaired a purple light texture that appeared after interacting with the Auger Shrine in Terminus Range</li><li>Optimized beam effects on some Order gear with lasers</li><li>Standardized bullet shell ejection visuals for Daedalus pistols</li><li>[SPOILER] The smoke during Sophia’s death wasn’t goth enough and was changed from orange to black </li><li>Updated the fade on digistruct to be less uniform</li><li>Resolved flickering from Exo-Soldier’s <strong>PROJECT: Raiju</strong> Capstone effect when used inside the Order Bunker</li><li>Updated vehicle materials to display correctly after applying paintjobs in the customization menu</li><li>Adjusted deployable barrier visuals on shields and <em>Shield Boi</em> </li><li>Faded the red light trails from Atlas underbarrel tracking Darts and Balls on Jakobs pistols</li><li>Tuned brightness of target marker visuals when using the Ripper Sniper Rifle tracking mode against certain bosses</li><li>Corrected firing animations for Vladof submachine guns with the Extra Barrel underbarrel and Torgue shotguns with Daedalus ammo switcher</li><li>Adjusted Order grenade to no longer slide across the ground when dropped from the inventory</li><li>Adjusted animation blending for Daedalus shotguns using Maliwan Element Switcher to eliminate abrupt snapping and to prevent the secondary magazine from appearing loaded when using the primary firing mode</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Audio</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Resolved a reported issue where the crowd could continue to make sounds after they stopped spawning during the <em>Null and Void</em> mission</li><li>Prevented host players from temporarily losing audio if another player joined their session while they were in an ECHO menu in multiplayer</li><li>Addressed missing or incomplete sound effects when looting in multiplayer sessions</li><li>Made the really loud bird in Grasslands quieter </li><li>Additional audio balance adjustments</li></ul><h2 data-cy="title2"><strong>Player Experience</strong></h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Improvements to stability and optimization<ul data-cy="list"><li>Dev Note: We are continuing to investigate and will make further improvements to stability and performance.</li></ul></li><li>Updated PS5 controller LEDs to change color based on the player’s active elemental type</li><li>Addressed unintended adaptive trigger feedback that occurred with Ripper weapons while reloading or firing without ammo</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/major-borderlands-4-update-adds-smarter-loot-drops-a-new-legendary-loot-indicator-for-the-radar-and-a-lot-more]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire Crawlers Emerged Out Of Multiple Different Prototypes That Were Totally Different]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-crawlers-emerged-out-of-multiple-different-prototypes-that-were-totally-different/1100-6536393/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-crawlers-emerged-out-of-multiple-different-prototypes-that-were-totally-different.1359892/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536393">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Vampire Survivors developer Poncle just announced a new game, Vampire Crawlers, and it emerged after the studio tinkered around with multiple different ideas.</p><p dir="ltr">Poncle's Luca Galante told GameSpot that making Vampire Crawlers, a deckbuilding game, was not the team's first choice for a follow-up to Vampire Survivors. "We actually started off with a set of five different projects. We worked with several indie teams, experimenting a little bit, and what happened is simply that Vampire Crawlers was the game that immediately jumped out at us," he explained.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1080101897" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466538,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Vampire%20Crawlers%20Is%20Ready%20To%20Become%20Your%20Next%20Obsession%20-%20Preview&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:354,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/vampire-crawlers-is-ready-to-become-your-next-obsession-preview\/2300-6466538\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466538\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466538\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466538\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466538&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466538,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536393&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466538},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466538\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4607806-vc_site_fin.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/iYPGJxwk.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1763664000,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="iYPGJxwk" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Vampire Crawlers Is Ready To Become Your Next Obsession - Preview</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">"From the initial prototype, the team just nailed it. It was great immediately. They immediately understood the idea, the concept, and so that's the one that progressed. It wasn't some kind of strategic decision; it's just the one that naturally, organically went faster than any other."</p><p dir="ltr">Poncle had numerous other ideas, too. The ideas were "literally all over the place," Galante said. "Definitely not a soccer game or something like that, but I'm a big fan of RPGs, so there were actually, a couple actually different RPGs in the works," he explained.</p><p dir="ltr">He went on to say that people who have played Vampire Survivors may see clues to some of the ideas that Poncle was thinking about. "If you think you've seen a reference [to] a particular game in Vampire Survivors, there's a pretty good chance that I'm working on a spin-off of the genre of that game," he said.</p><p dir="ltr">Galante went on to say that a metroidvania game would be a "perfect fit" for the studio, adding that this would "make so much sense" or even "too much sense."</p><p dir="ltr">"If we were to do something like that--which I would love to do something like that, by the way--but if I were to do it, I would just go to Konami and ask for permission to use Castlevania at that stage. It just makes too much sense," he said. "That or, honestly, if I were to do a metroidvania, I would probably do one with the Legacy of the Moonspell characters and setting. Or Tides of the Foscari. I would try to move a little bit away from Vampire Survivors."</p><p dir="ltr">For more, check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/im-making-this-for-me-not-to-make-everyone-happy-vampire-survivors-creator-on-his-next-game/1100-6536362/" data-ref-id="1100-6536362">GameSpot's full interview with Galante</a> and our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-crawlers-is-ready-to-become-your-next-obsession/1100-6536363/" data-ref-id="1100-6536363">hands-on preview of Vampire Crawlers.</a></p><p dir="ltr">Vampire Crawlers is set to release on Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch, PC, and mobile in 2026. Poncle also confirmed that the game will be coming to Xbox Game Pass day one.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-crawlers-emerged-out-of-multiple-different-prototypes-that-were-totally-different/1100-6536393/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Ancient Fort Guide - All Battery Locations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-ancient-fort-guide-all-battery-locations/1100-6536367/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-ancient-fort-guide-all-battery-locations.1359889/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536367">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Each <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/arc-raiders/" data-ref-id="5000-546105">Arc Raiders</a> map has a few intriguing puzzles to figure out, and they'll usually provide you with some nice loot for solving them. For instance, if you've come across the Ancient Fort POI on the Blue Gate map, you may have noticed a cellar door and some electrical boxes scattered around. This puzzle is easy to complete in theory, but the random battery locations add a sense of randomness to the equation. Luckily, we're here to fill you in on where to look for them.</p><p>Once you solve the puzzle and get the cellar door open, you'll gain access to a room filled with loot. Not every run will net you excellent stuff down here, but it's always worth checking out if you're in the area. So, with that said, here's how to complete the Ancient Fort puzzle and open the cellar door.</p><h2>How to open the cellar door at the Ancient Fort</h2><p>If you visit the Ancient Fort and poke around a bit, you'll notice a cellar door on an outside wall. It's likely to be closed when you arrive, but note the three lights above it, as they're a key to how you can pop this sucker open. You guessed it--you need to power up some electrical boxes.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607826-share_20251119_1052431.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4607826" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607826-share_20251119_1052431.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4607826"></a><figcaption>Ancient Fort cellar door</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607826-share_20251119_1052431.jpeg"></figure><p>There are three electrical boxes located around the fort. Each of these is in plain sight, as solving this puzzle is much more about <em>how</em> to power them up.</p><ul><li>The first electrical box is located on the southern outside wall.</li><li>The second electrical box is located upstairs inside the tower of the fort.</li><li>The third electrical box is located upstairs against a wall on the second floor.</li></ul><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607819-share_20251119_1052442.jpeg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607820-share_20251119_1052201.jpeg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607821-share_20251119_1052212.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4607819,1300-4607820,1300-4607821" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/679/6794662/4607819-share_20251119_1052442.jpeg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/679/6794662/4607820-share_20251119_1052201.jpeg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/679/6794662/4607821-share_20251119_1052212.jpeg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607819-share_20251119_1052442.jpeg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607820-share_20251119_1052201.jpeg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607821-share_20251119_1052212.jpeg"></figure><p>Each electrical box requires a battery to power up. When you power up all three of them, you'll unlock the cellar door. However, finding the batteries can be a matter of trial and error. There are a variety of spots in and around the Ancient Fort where batteries can spawn, so the locations of the three batteries will change from match to match.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607880-share_20251119_1052180.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4607880" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607880-share_20251119_1052180.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4607880"></a><figcaption>You're looking for these batteries all around the perimeter of the fort (and sometimes within it).</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607880-share_20251119_1052180.jpeg"></figure><p>The map below shows the locations where we--and the Arc Raiders community--have discovered the batteries most frequently.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607825-share_20251119_1052420.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4607825" data-ratio="0.56246838644411" data-width="1977" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607825-share_20251119_1052420.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4607825"></a><figcaption>Potential battery spawns</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607825-share_20251119_1052420.jpeg"></figure><p>The most common spots to find batteries are within or around the smaller structures on the perimeter of the fort, but we've also regularly found one resting at the very top of the fort, as shown in the photo below. So, if you're struggling to find the last one, head all the way up to the top to look for this one.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607827-share_20251119_1052453.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4607827" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607827-share_20251119_1052453.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4607827"></a><figcaption>We've often found a battery at the very top of the Ancient Fort.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/679/6794662/4607827-share_20251119_1052453.jpeg"></figure><p>When you've found and returned three batteries to the electrical boxes, you'll hear a distinct sound letting you know the cellar door has opened below. Head back there and climb down the ladder to find a room full of loot just for you--or any other raiders who are eager to reap the benefits of your hard work. Stay vigilant!</p><p>For more, check out our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-guides-hub/1100-6536157/" data-ref-id="1100-6536157">Arc Raiders guides hub</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/arc-raiders-ancient-fort-guide-all-battery-locations/1100-6536367/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I'm Making This For Me, Not To Make Everyone Happy": Vampire Survivors Creator On His Next Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/im-making-this-for-me-not-to-make-everyone-happy-vampire-survivors-creator-on-his-next-game/1100-6536362/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/im-making-this-for-me-not-to-make-everyone-happy-vampire-survivors-creator-on-his-next-game.1359883/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="">

            
          
  

<section><p>Vampire Survivors creator Luca Galante discusses new game Vampire Crawlers, leaving his solo-dev days behind, and his not-so-secret desire to make a Castlevania game.</p></section>
        
        
                    
              <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Much like Vampire Survivors' titular vampire, the game's creator, Luca Galante, is often nowhere to be found. When Vampire Survivors won a BAFTA for Game of the Year back in 2023, it was a handful of Galante's colleagues at Poncle who took to the stage to accept it. At convention panels, Galante is known for using screens and decoys rather than addressing the audience himself. In the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XQVdR8mJrds">NoClip documentary</a> chronicling the success of Vampire Survivors, Galante opted to have a Muppets-esque puppet resembling the game's iconic vampire mascot made so he wouldn't have to appear on camera himself. And it is a <em>very</em> cool puppet.</p><p dir="ltr">Even after I arrived in the small, walled city of Lucca, Italy to preview Poncle's new game, Vampire Crawlers, the myth-making of Luca Galante continued. Several Poncle devs I spoke to recounted, with sheer amusement, how they loved playing up Galante's mysterious persona. When fans asked if Galante was around, they'd sometimes remark, "He could be. He could be me." Matteo Sapio, the chief strategy officer at Poncle, laughed as he told me, "It's all very funny because honestly, yes, he is brilliant, but he's also a very kind and normal guy. He just really values his privacy."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="839495575" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466536,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Vampire%20Crawlers%20-%20Official%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:92,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/vampire-crawlers-official-reveal-trailer\/2300-6466536\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466536\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466536\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466536\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466536&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466536,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;feature_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536362&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;vampire-survivors&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;2d,action,fixed-screen,shooter,vr&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,macintosh,linux,xbox-series-x,xbox-one,ios-iphoneipad,android,nintendo-switch,playstation-4,playstation-5,meta-quest,mobile&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;poncle&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466536},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466536\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4607202-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/zoWVSkMr.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1763664000,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="zoWVSkMr" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Vampire Crawlers - Official Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Imagine my delight then, when an hour after meeting Luca, I found myself sitting beside him on an old couch, both of us chatting animatedly about our love of Final Fantasy while playing Vampire Survivors together on a hulking CRT TV.</p><p dir="ltr">Contrary to how he presents himself, Luca Galante is an eager conversationalist. Though he speaks calmly and thoughtfully, it is not without immense passion for his work, the community it has fostered, and video games as a whole. After playing around 30 minutes of Poncle's new game, Vampire Crawlers, I proceeded to spend nearly an hour talking to Galante about his work on the game, what it's been like leaving his solo-dev days behind, and, most importantly, when we'll be able to play Vampire Crawlers from the comfort of our homes.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>GameSpot: So, what inspired the decision to set Crawlers in the same universe?</strong></p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Luca Galante:</strong> That was something that we decided very early to do because the success of Vampire Survivors was so big that, among other things, I saw an opportunity in the name Vampire Survivors. It was somewhat of a business decision, to just keep working on that IP and idea. If I wanted to make a game like this, and make a new IP to go with it, it's just going to be one among the other hundreds of deckbuilders out there. The Vampire Survivors name gives us the strength and the ability to tell people, "This is a Vampire Survivors deckbuilder. You will find elements that you're already familiar with in this game, and it will capture the feeling of the original."</p><p dir="ltr">There is something of deeper reason as well though, which is that I wanted to keep bringing the core principles, the core ideas of Vampire Survivors, to other genres. I started Vampire Survivors for fun. It was something I was just doing for myself. And to me, what makes Vampire Survivors what it is is the fact that it's easy to play, makes you feel good, and tries to avoid frustration. I wanted to transfer all of that into this game.</p><p dir="ltr">It's also a massive relief not to have to come up with new settings, new characters, and new everything to make a new game. Because I don't like to sit down and create new things on purpose. I prefer for things to be intuitive. I like the creative process to be something that comes naturally. For this game, what matters to me most is the game's mechanics. The fact that I can use existing settings and characters gives me the freedom to focus on that.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>When you first started working on Survivors, it was essentially just you making that game. What has it been like working with a team?</strong></p><p dir="ltr">When I started Vampire Survivors, it was only for fun. It was only for myself. But already at that point, it wasn't only my own stuff that I was using. I had a Castlevania-themed asset pack, basically. Well, medieval gothic, really, but it was very obviously inspired by Castlevania. The music I was listening to was actually Castlevania music. And then when I commissioned musicians to do music, I was using that music to inspire me.</p><p dir="ltr">So even if, yeah, I developed the game as a solo developer, I always had the inputs of other people from the beginning. And now I need other people to be able to maintain Vampire Survivors. With so many platforms, it is actually very complex to handle releases and QA. Even just passing ideas with someone who knows the game just as well as me is very important. It's a process I really like.</p><p dir="ltr">There are a lot of details on the original characters and weapon icons--all sorts of stuff, that wasn't how I initially thought about it. I simply went to the pixel artist, Glauber Kotaki, who's incredible. I'm so happy working with Glauber; you have no idea. I would just give Glauber some ideas, and he would work on them and make them better; he'd add even more elements to it. We had this ping pong of ideas going back and forth, just trying to make something interesting, and do something that people will be able to appreciate.</p><p dir="ltr">It's a lot harder, of course, and it's a much slower process now. But it's a different kind of fun. And honestly, when I want to do something--especially over the weekends when I'm alone--I do not have to worry about actually running the companies or having meetings. I can still sit down with my machine, open the project, and do whatever I want. It's the best of both worlds.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607281-vc_screenshot_19.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607281" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607281-vc_screenshot_19.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607281"></a><figcaption>A look at Vampire Crawlers's combat</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607281-vc_screenshot_19.png"></figure><p dir="ltr"><strong>I'm glad that you brought up Glauber because it leads into my next question. I feel like there's always this natural urge to change so much of the original game with a sequel or spin-off to make it more "modern." But Crawlers still feels so quintessentially Vampire Survivors, especially visually. What was the reasoning for retaining that look?</strong></p><p dir="ltr">The idea was practical and technical. I thought, "Let's use the exact same assets. Because if we change them, people are going to complain. If we change them, it is going to increase the cost of this project." And I'm not an entrepreneur. I'm not a risk-taker. I don't want to end up having crazy budgets for games and putting the company at risk.</p><p dir="ltr">Actually, the initial idea was to run the marketing campaign of the game on the fact that it is recycled. Yes, it's super cheap. Yes, we are milking these pixels like there's no tomorrow, or something like that. But then as we actually started to work on the game, you start to fall in love with what you're doing. You start to want to do more.</p><p dir="ltr">So long story short, we ended up repurposing the old assets in the 3D settings, but we also got new icons. We got new animations. The only thing I think we're going to keep exactly as it is right now [are] the characters because I think that makes most sense. There isn't a strong reason to change the characters. Everyone has their own idea of what they look like, so I really do not want to change them. Even when we have to do drawings or animation for certain characters, we try to let whoever is drawing them interpret them and do not have very strict rules to adhere to.</p><p dir="ltr">Because it was so much fun for me to work with these things in this world, I just want that anyone else who works on this game to have the same experience--to put their own spin on things.</p><p dir="ltr">Also, the idea of keeping the same UI, or at least keeping it very close to the original, is that there is no need to reinvent everything. I really want the fog to be on the gameplay in the end. Everything else should be familiar, but at the same time feel fresh.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>That makes sense. You don't need to reinvent something that clearly works.</strong></p><p dir="ltr">I don't know if it works, honestly! Very often I ask myself if I was successful in spite of certain things being awful. I don't know. But the only thing I can do is just keep going with what I think is good, basically. And then I wait for the player's input, of course. If a lot of players tell me that the confirm button is in an awkward place, I'm going to reconsider the positioning of that button. But until I get that feedback, I'm just going with my gut.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Something I noticed when I first started playing Vampire Crawlers is that, to a certain extent, it's slower and more strategic. Which is interesting when we live in a time when I feel like everybody has a very short attention span--everything is compulsive, everyone just wants to tap on something. Are you nervous working on something a bit slower paced?</strong></p><p dir="ltr">As always, I use myself as a judge. When I was talking to the team, I told them that I'm making the game basically for me. I told them, "You're making this game for me. I am player number one. I have to love this game. This is the concept I really want to see executed." I always use myself as a way to decide if the game is going in the right direction or not. So I'm sure that there are other people, like me, that love Vampire Survivors and will love this game.</p><p dir="ltr">I have no idea if it's going to be as many players. Probably not. I don't care, honestly. Because if I start thinking about that, if I start thinking about what are players expecting or what will the majority of the players want or need, I just end up doing something average. Something that tries to make everyone happy. I'd rather try to be original and take a <em>little</em> bit of risk. But as long as I'm confident that the game works for me, I know I can push that idea.</p><p dir="ltr">So I'm not worried about that. I know that some people will not like it, some people will like it, and some people will love it. Some people will absolutely hate it at first, and then maybe try it later and go, "Hmm, maybe it's not that bad." That happens very often with Vampire Survivors. It's very easy to underestimate it because of the visuals, right?</p><p dir="ltr">But there is a bit of compulsion with the "Play All" button. It's very interesting because, often in these kinds of games, you end up being overpowered. And if you're overpowered and you get into a fight with, I don't know, five bats, you know you're going to kill them immediately but you still have to play cards. It gets a bit boring, because you already know the outcome. To fix that, I decided to try and put in a "Play All" button. If you press it, the game will just try and play all your cards immediately.</p><p dir="ltr">On top of that, the game accelerates. So you get this rush from completing the fight immediately and then it just moves very quickly after that, which I personally absolutely love. I find myself mashing the "Play All" button even after the fight has clearly finished.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>I genuinely appreciate that you center what you enjoy when making games. I feel like you can't make art when you're self-conscious or when you're overly concerned with what everybody else thinks. You're going to make something that's average, because you're considering the average.</strong></p><p dir="ltr">After the game is out, I'm definitely going to take into account player feedback in the community. Vampire Survivors is the perfect example of a game that got released in early access because I wanted player feedback. Back then, it was mostly a way to get in touch, somehow, with other fans of Castlevania, joke together, and say, "Yeah, I see this reference" or something like that. But then it became something more.</p><p dir="ltr">Then I started to plan the complete version of Vampire Survivors. I would use the community feedback and player feedback to choose what would be the next part of the roadmap to add to the game. I knew the steps, but not the order. So I would let the community dictate what would come next for the early-access version of Vampire Survivors. For this game, it's going to be very different though; this time I want to release a game that is whole to begin with.</p><p dir="ltr">That makes this game a bit riskier from the get-go, but the plan is already that, once we release it, we'll listen to player feedback. Once again, we'll use that to decide what should come next for this game--what features people want added or if they want to see DLC, for instance. If they want collaborations, or spin-offs of this game instead.</p><p dir="ltr">There are many conversations around player entitlement these days. My perspective is that, to an extent, players are entitled to certain things. They have invested money and time into this game and our studio. They directly contribute to my success and my livelihood. I think that entitles them to polish and responsiveness. I think that entitles players to a good game.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607282-vc_screenshot_20.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607282" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607282-vc_screenshot_20.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607282"></a><figcaption>A look at deckbuilding in Vampire Crawlers</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607282-vc_screenshot_20.png"></figure><p dir="ltr"><strong>Deckbuilders are obviously a popular genre right now, but what inspired the decision to say, "Okay, we're doing a deckbuilder next" when there were so many options for this spin-off?</strong></p><p dir="ltr">Honestly, it was not our first choice. We actually started off with a set of five different projects. We worked with several indie teams, experimenting a little bit, and what happened is simply that Vampire Crawlers was the game that immediately jumped out at us. From the initial prototype, the team just nailed it. It was great immediately. They immediately understood the idea, the concept, and so that's the one that progressed. It wasn't some kind of strategic decision; it's just the one that naturally, organically went faster than any other.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>What were some of the other ideas?</strong></p><p dir="ltr">Oh, they were literally all over the place. Definitely not a soccer game or something like that, but I'm a big fan of RPGs, so there were actually, a couple actually different RPGs in the works. If you play Vampire Survivors, you can find a lot of references to all sorts of other games. So if you think you've seen a reference of a particular game in Vampire Survivor, there's a pretty good chance that I'm working on a spin-off of the genre of that game.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>I was wondering, because I think the first thing that I went to was like, "Oh, this would work so well as a metroidvania."</strong></p><p dir="ltr">Exactly, that's just a perfect fit. I mean, it just makes so much sense. It makes <em>too</em> much sense. It would almost have to be called Castlevania, right? If we were to do something like that--which I would love to do something like that, by the way--but if I were to do it, I would just go to Konami and ask for permission to use Castlevania at that stage. It just makes too much sense.</p><p dir="ltr">That or, honestly, if I were to do a metroidvania, I would probably do one with the Legacy of the Moonspell characters and setting. Or Tides of the Foscari. I would try to move a little bit away from Vampire Survivors.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Another feature that really sets Crawlers apart from Survivors is the inclusion of this sort of hub. Are there plans to expand that more? Are there any other features you're excited for people to see?</strong></p><p dir="ltr">There are games that give you a little customizable village, but that, for me, is one step too far. If the core of the game is playing cards, and I also add a little strategy to the village, then I really start branching a bit too much. The village will most likely stay how it [is] right now, which is just this circle of buildings. However, it being a circle means that, once in a while, we can make a new building pop between others. So it is still expandable and any feature we come up with over time, we'll be able to fit it in there.</p><p dir="ltr">The combat system is the core experience. Everything else is an accessory; it's an excuse to justify the combat system. So I'm really curious to see how far we can push it and what people want to see from this.</p><p dir="ltr">However, I think Crawlers has a lot of potential because, even though the point of this game is not exploration, the fact that there is this exploration opens up a lot of doors. I'm really curious to see what people will think of the exploration. Will they want more? Will they want less? Will they want bigger dungeons?</p><p dir="ltr">There are also, of course, endless menus of unlocks and new stuff to try. I think we're putting together all these modular elements so that the game eventually could expand just as much as Vampire Survivors. We do need limits to ship the first version, so early on we said, "Okay, let's bring over X amount of characters." And then, per usual, we doubled that amount. That's a very common theme at Poncle. We start with a very low goal because we know what we're going to do twice as much anyway.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>How many characters did you end up bringing over?</strong></p><p dir="ltr">I think we are going to end up with 20 or 21 characters. And every character has a different passive ability, a different trigger ability, and a different starting deck. The characters here are a lot more complex than in Vampire Survivors. When Vampire Survivors first launched, characters were merely a way for players to choose their starting weapon. They weren't even supposed to have different stats. But once the game got released, it was a bit too flat, so I added a few bonuses to different characters.</p><p dir="ltr">And then the game got so big that it felt like it was cheap to make a new character just to offer a new starting weapon. Now every character has to bring something different to the game. But with Crawlers, from the very beginning we established that every character has to be different and viable. So 21 characters, 21 different starting decks. It's quite a lot.</p><p dir="ltr">That's not to mention that in the final version you can actually bring up to three characters with you, allowing you to mix and match their triggers and abilities. You might only play just one card, but because of all the triggers you have enabled, that one card will do 10 different things.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607284-vc_screenshot_2.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607284" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607284-vc_screenshot_2.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607284"></a><figcaption>Exploration in Vampire Crawlers</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607284-vc_screenshot_2.png"></figure><p dir="ltr"><strong>Are there plans to bring Vampire Crawlers to mobile?</strong></p><p dir="ltr">Yeah, this game I wanted to release globally on all platforms on the same day. It's super ambitious, it's a lot of stress for everyone, but I feel like we owe it to the community that has been so patient with Vampire Survivors. They've been so helpful and understanding that I feel like we have to try to put this game into everyone's hands immediately. Again, very difficult, but let's see if we can manage to do it.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Do you have a release date planned for the game?</strong></p><p dir="ltr">I actually wanted to release it this year, but there was a problem. The game was not exactly what I wanted. Originally, there was not as much of the deckbuilding element. There wasn't a lot of depth. I realized that once people started playing it, they were saying that they couldn't wait to see what's next and how they could customize their deck. But there wasn't that much of that on the roadmap.</p><p dir="ltr">I realized that there were expectations. When you're playing a card game, well, by now it's a genre that's so well-established that people have a lot of expectations. They immediately expect to have a deckbuilding element that has a lot of depth. And so that's the element I decided needed to be revamped--that needed to deliver from the get-go. It's something that should be at the core of the experience.</p><p dir="ltr">Adding that big feature pushed our release date to next year. I'm not 100% sure when. I'm trying to avoid the Grand Theft Auto VI window. Not because the game is competing with GTA VI, but because the whole world is going to compete against GTA VI.</p><p dir="ltr"><em>The above interview has been edited for clarity and brevity.</em></p>
  
                                                              </div>
    

              <div>
  <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>
  
    </div>
      
        
        
  
              


  

    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/im-making-this-for-me-not-to-make-everyone-happy-vampire-survivors-creator-on-his-next-game/1100-6536362/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire Crawlers Is Ready To Become Your Next Obsession]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-crawlers-is-ready-to-become-your-next-obsession/1100-6536363/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-crawlers-is-ready-to-become-your-next-obsession.1359880/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="">

            
          
  

<section><p>With Vampire Crawlers, Poncle Games is expanding the world of Vampire Survivors while also exploring a new genre: deckbuilders.</p></section>
        
        
                    
              <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In the years since <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/vampire-survivors/" data-ref-id="5000-544864">Vampire Survivors</a> first hit PC, Poncle Games has been busy. In addition to releasing numerous updates to its debut title, the company has expanded, entered into publishing, and paired up with other studios--including Vampire Survivors' biggest inspiration, Konami--to create a slew of fun collaborations. It's been an eventful few years for the BAFTA award-winning team and its simple-yet-utterly-engrossing "bullet heaven." And based on my time spent with Poncle a few weeks ago, that's just scratching the surface.</p><p dir="ltr">For the past year, Poncle Games has been hard at work on its next game, Vampire Crawlers. The dungeon-crawling deckbuilder is a notable departure from the simplistic gameplay of Vampire Survivors, and yet, after spending around half an hour playing the game, it's abundantly clear that it shares much of the same DNA and the same penchant for chaotic fun. Although Crawlers is, at least initially, slower-paced and less compulsive than its predecessor, it makes up for this with increased depth and strategy, all while incorporating elements that make the game delightfully unruly.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="478283862" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466536,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Vampire%20Crawlers%20-%20Official%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:92,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/vampire-crawlers-official-reveal-trailer\/2300-6466536\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466536\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466536\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466536\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466536&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466536,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;feature_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536363&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;vampire-survivors&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;2d,action,fixed-screen,shooter,vr&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,macintosh,linux,xbox-series-x,xbox-one,ios-iphoneipad,android,nintendo-switch,playstation-4,playstation-5,meta-quest,mobile&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;poncle&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466536},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466536\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4607202-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/zoWVSkMr.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1763664000,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="zoWVSkMr" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Vampire Crawlers - Official Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">My first taste of Vampire Crawlers began with a fun cutscene--the same one seen in the game's announcement trailer--in which Vampire Survivors is transformed into a 2.5D experience. It's an exciting way to kick things off and conveys an important message: Vampire Crawlers, at its core, largely feels like a new way of playing Survivors. Though Luca Galante, the creative director behind Vampire Crawlers, said the team ultimately did go through and update most of Survivors' original assets for Crawlers, much of the series' visual identity remains intact. A cynic might call this lazy, sure, but I'd argue it comes across more as respect for Survivors' initial vision, and it ultimately works within the context of Crawlers. Furthermore, Galante said this was a very intentional choice that placed the company's stability ahead of a need to "create new things on purpose."</p><p dir="ltr">"The idea was practical and technical. I thought, 'Let's use the exact same assets. Because if we change them, people are going to complain. If we change them, it is going to increase the cost of this project,'" Galante explained. "And I'm not an entrepreneur. I'm not a risk-taker. I don't want to end up having crazy budgets for games and putting the company at risk."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607290-ff%286%29.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607290" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607290-ff%286%29.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607290"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607290-ff%286%29.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">Following the cutscene, you are immediately thrust into familiar terrain: the Mad Forest. Crawlers seems to retain Survivors' fantastic soundtrack, and certainly leans into its predecessor's visuals, albeit with a slight '90s JRPG spin. Gameplay, however, is an entirely different story. Rather than using a mouse, joystick, or finger to traverse, automatically attacking as you do so, Crawlers implements arrow keys to navigate its environments with a first-person perspective. A map is displayed in the bottom-right corner, detailing the layout of the dungeon floor as well as where enemies lurk. You then decide if you want to take on every enemy, raking up experience as you do, or beeline straight to the map's elite enemy. This adds a bit of strategy in itself, as you must weigh if certain battles are worth the potential damage you'll take. Is it worth pushing your luck with a swarm of bats when a monstrous mantis lurks ahead?</p><p dir="ltr">More strategic are the battles themselves. Upon encountering an enemy, the game seamlessly enters into a turn-based combat mode, in which you use cards--all of which have set mana values--to take down monsters. Each of Crawlers' 20 or so characters, all of which are pulled directly from Survivors, comes with their very own deck of cards, making your character selection more important than ever. Just like Survivors, Crawlers sees you first play as the whip-wielding Antonio Belpaese. Antonio comes equipped with cards like a zero-mana-cost Whip and a one-mana-cost Spinach: both items that will be familiar to Survivors players but have slightly different effects in Crawlers.</p><p dir="ltr">You gain bonuses based on playing your cards in ascending mana-cost order, though sometimes that's not the most advantageous move. For example, playing a one-mana-cost Spinach, which boosts your attacks by 20%, <em>before</em> executing several zero-mana-cost attacks, is often the way to go. Additionally, there is also a "Play All" button, which allows you to play all your cards simultaneously for a healthy dose of chaotic fun. Galante explained this was partially added as a way to quickly get through battles you know you're going to win, which I appreciated.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607289-ff%285%29.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607289" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607289-ff%285%29.png" data-ref-id="1300-4607289"></a><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4607289-ff%285%29.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">As you level up, you'll get the opportunity to add new cards to your deck. Additionally, you can use gems found in treasure chests to upgrade cards; these upgrades can upgrade the damage the cards deal, reduce mana cost, and more. This adds another layer of decision-making, as you must weigh which card would be best to socket your newly found gem into. The seemingly final layer is that, later on in the game, you can bring up to three Survivors with you on an expedition, allowing you to mix together decks and their various playstyles.</p><p dir="ltr">After completing the Mad Forest dungeon, I was able to visit one of the game's more charming areas: the village. Presented as a circle of buildings you can cycle between, the village is essentially your base of operations. Though I wasn't able to check out all of what it offered, the most notable inclusion was the tavern, which serves as a more immersive way to select your character by wrangling away them from their designated drinking spot. Although the village was built with the intention of being expandable, Galante noted that it is not intended to act as a major component of the game. While the base-building sicko in me was a bit disheartened to hear that, the reasoning behind the decision makes sense.</p><p dir="ltr">"There are games that give you a little customizable village, but that, for me, is one step too far. If the core of the game is playing cards, and I also add a little strategy to the village, then I really start branching a bit too much," Galante explained. "The village will most likely stay how it [is] right now, which is just this circle of buildings. However, it being a circle means that, once in a while, we can make a new building pop between others. So it is still expandable and any feature we come up with over time, we'll be able to fit it in there."</p><p dir="ltr">It's hard to say if Crawlers will sink its fangs into me to the same degree that Survivors did, but it's worth admitting that I felt the same when I first started Survivors. Since then, I've racked up a frankly embarrassing amount of time in that game. Thirty minutes felt too short to form a strong opinion on Crawlers, but I enjoyed what I played and have faith (and perhaps a deep fear) that it will steal just as many hours away from me as Survivors did. Beyond that, I also feel that Crawlers has plenty of potential to grow in accordance with what Poncle's community ultimately wants. Studio head Luca Galante expressed an eagerness to expand the game, be it by leaning into exploration, adding more depth to the village, or increasing the options for card modifications. Vampire Crawlers is currently slated to release early next year, with the ultimate goal of avoiding any overlap with Grand Theft Auto VI.</p>
  
                                                              </div>
    

              <div>
  <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>
  
    </div>
      
        
        
  
              


  

    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/vampire-crawlers-is-ready-to-become-your-next-obsession/1100-6536363/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Gameplay Trailer For Arthurian Action Game Tides Of Annihilation Shows Off A Thrilling Boss Battle]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/xbox-partner-preview/2025/11/20/new-gameplay-trailer-for-arthurian-action-game-tides-of</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-gameplay-trailer-for-arthurian-action-game-tides-of-annihilation-shows-off-a-thrilling-boss-battle.1359871/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Tides of Annihilation raised a lot of eyebrows when it debuted during a PlayStation State of Play in February, and the promising dark fantasy action game got another showing today, this time on the Xbox side during its Partner Preview. Curious fans were treated to a four-minute gameplay trailer showing off a titanic boss fight that, frankly, looks awesome.&nbsp;</p><p>The adventure draws inspiration from Arthurian legend (as in the lore of King Arthur) and centers on an otherworldly invasion of a modernized London. This invasion has fractured the world into distorted mirror realities, and it’s up to protagonist Gwendolyn to travel between two worlds, London and the mythical Avalon, to save her family, the city, and existence itself.&nbsp;</p><p>Today’s trailer shows off an impressively flashy boss battle against Tyronoe, one of the eight sisters of Morgan le Fay. The video, which developer Eclipse Glow Games confirms is captured in-engine, shows how Gwendolyn will enlist the aid of legendary knights, of which there are 10 in total, to augment her abilities and turn the tide (pun intended) of battle. Today's trailer shows her tag-teaming with former rival Sir Lamorak.&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VGOsH1Gp8SE"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VGOsH1Gp8SE" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>Tides of Annihilation is coming to PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC, but it does not have a release window.&nbsp;</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/xbox-partner-preview/2025/11/20/new-gameplay-trailer-for-arthurian-action-game-tides-of]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>