<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 19:06:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Could Be It for The Last of Us, Says Series Creator Neil Druckmann]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/this-could-be-it-for-the-last-of-us-says-series-creator-neil-druckmann/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-could-be-it-for-the-last-of-us-says-series-creator-neil-druckmann.1126260/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/this-could-be-it-for-the-last-of-us-says-series-creator-neil-druckmann/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>There's a whole lot of The Last of Us coming your way next month. To begin with, PC players will finally be able to get their hands on the 2020 sequel thanks to <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-last-of-us-part-ii-remastered-pc-is-out-on-april-3-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Last of Us Part II Remastered</a>, which will be released on the platform on April 4 via Steam and the Epic Games Store. The port is being handled by Nixxes Software and Iron Galaxy.</p>
<p>Then there's the second season of the acclaimed HBO TV series featuring Pedro Pascal as Joel and Bella Ramsey as Ellie. This new season will include a portion of the story seen in Part II and start airing on April 13, giving you just enough time to experience the game's version of the story, which is said to be quite different.</p>
<p><a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/the-last-of-us-season-2-abby-video-game-changes-backlash-1236327786/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Speaking to Variety</a>, series creator Neil Druckmann explained:</p>
<p><em>I love the changes that we’ve made. It's a different version of that story, but its DNA is in there. Maybe more than excited, I’m really curious what their reaction will be.</em></p>
<p>Some of the changes include changing Abby's character to accommodate the difference between her character in the game, who's very powerful physically, and actress Kaitlyn Dever, who's far slimmer. On this subject, Druckmann said:</p>
<p><em>Kaitlyn Dever wanted to work with us; we wanted to work with her. It's not worth passing it up to continue a search that might never bear fruit to find someone that matches the physicality.</em></p>
<p>Truth be told, many fans had hoped to see Dever cast as Ellie before the creatives settled on Bella Ramsey. On the other hand, there was the matter of age, since Ramsey was much closer to the character than Dever. This might be why they settled on her instead but still wanted to work with an excellent actress like Dever, though that's speculation on our part.</p>
<p>There will be some additions to the plot of The Last of Us Part II. For example, the character Eugene is only named in the game, but he'll be seen (played by actor Joe Pantoliano) in this new season of the TV show. Druckmann commented:</p>
<p><em>I get excited when I see these opportunities. I'm like, ‘Oh, I don’t know Eugene that well!’ The story we told in the game was somewhat superficial. The way this character comes in really gets to the heart of Joel and Ellie and their relationship.</em></p>
<p>According to showrunner Craig Mazin, there may be space for one or two more seasons. But what about The Last of Us Part III? Well, Druckmann didn't give much hope to fans:</p>
<p><em>I was waiting for this question. I guess the only thing I would say is don't bet on there being more of ‘Last of Us.’ This could be it.</em></p>
<p>Looking at the history of Naughty Dog, it's entirely possible he's not lying. The Californian studio is known for abandoning its successful IPs over time, starting with Crash, then Jak and Daxter, and then Uncharted. At the latest The Game Awards, the studio <a href="https://wccftech.com/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-naughty-dog-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">unveiled</a> its new sci-fi franchise, Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet. If that game sells well enough, they might work on a sequel for it instead of going back to The Last of Us. We've prepared a little poll to gauge your opinion on what they should do. Let us know your take in the comments!</p>
<div id="democracy-1409" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1409,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Should Naughty Dog make The Last of Us Part III at some point?</strong></p></div>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Years Of Waiting, Suikoden Finally Gets The HD Glow-Up It Deserves]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/suikoden-1-2-hd-collection-review-rpg-features-ps1-1851767870</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-years-of-waiting-suikoden-finally-gets-the-hd-glow-up-it-deserves.1126251/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/suikoden-1-2-hd-collection-review-rpg-features-ps1-1851767870<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Almost every major Japanese publisher had to have a big RPG franchise in the PS1 era. Square Soft had <em>Final Fantasy</em>. Enix had <em>Dragon Quest</em>. Capcom had <em>Breath of Fire</em>. Bandai Namco had <em>Tales</em>. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/why-you-should-play-suikoden-ii-one-of-the-best-rpgs-e-1668857424?_gl=1*m34oo9*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MTE5ODM3OC4zMC4wLjE3NDExOTgzNzguNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/why-you-should-play-suikoden-ii-one-of-the-best-rpgs-e-1668857424?_gl=1*m34oo9*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MTE5ODM3OC4zMC4wLjE3NDExOTgzNzguNjAuMC4w">And so, Konami made <em>Suikoden</em></a></span>. Its innovation was trading a set party of heroes for a cast of 108 total characters who could be recruited on your adventure. Combined with a world of rune-based magic and political intrigue, <em>Suikoden I </em>and <em>II</em> managed to carve out a unique lane in a crowded field, and now both games have finally been updated with modern bells and whistles for current platforms. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196411" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="A Typical Day On Persona 3 Reload’s Tatsumi Port Island" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="378" data-playlist="196411,196766,196452" data-current="196411"><div><p>A Typical Day On Persona 3 Reload’s Tatsumi Port Island</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196411/196411_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21958.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>I’ve played around a bit with the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-direct-august-2024-everything-announced-1851632968/slides/24&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-direct-august-2024-everything-announced-1851632968/slides/24"><em>Suikoden I &amp; II HD Remaster</em> collection</a></span>, which technically includes the much longer subtitle “Gate Rune and Dunan Unification Wars,” and am pleased to report two main takeaways. First, these JRPGs still have the juice, especially <em>Suikoden II</em>. The snappy turn-based combat and open-ended collect-em-all-fest holds up 30 years later, with decent storytelling and even better character writing. </p><p>Second, both games have survived the journey from low-resolution 4:3 aspect ratio to 16:9 HD <em>mostly</em> intact and looking better than ever, especially in <em>Suikoden II</em>. The character sprites remain perfectly pixelated-looking without any smoothed-over upscaling effects or muddy silhouettes. The backgrounds, never a series highlight, look crisp and get the job done. The tiling of its top-down world can feel a bit bland and repetitive, but certain scenes with more detailed shadows and lighting really pop. Most importantly, the battles still look and feel great, at least to the eyes of someone who grew up with these games back in the ‘90s. Things are less great in <em>Suikoden I</em> where some environments look weirdly flat and empty.&nbsp;</p><figure id="" data-id="d7e22e5989ceecc9e18004a394b766ee" data-recommend-id="image://d7e22e5989ceecc9e18004a394b766ee" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Characters fight a bug in battle. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Characters fight a bug in battle. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Konami</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d7e22e5989ceecc9e18004a394b766ee" data-recommend-id="image://d7e22e5989ceecc9e18004a394b766ee" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Characters fight a bug in battle. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>For those unfamiliar, <em>Suikoden I</em> (1995) follows military nepo-baby Tir who comes into possession of a magical relic that jumpstarts a rebellion against the empire he had previously pledged to serve. <em>Suikoden II</em> (1998) follows childhood friends Riou, Jowy, and Nanami after a false-flag attack by their military unit leads them to be branded as traitors amid an invasion by a neighboring kingdom. The first game is about 20 hours long and focuses mainly on recruiting characters to aid you in your fight against the evil Scarlet Moon Empire, while the second is longer, much more narratively dense, and a bit more morally grey and complex. </p><p>Both are propelled along by random encounters and boss fights, toil made much better than in some other games thanks to <em>Suikoden</em>’s old-school but flashy turn-based formula and the fact that you’re always finding new characters with unique abilities, strengths, and weaknesses to fight alongside. Instead of just three or four characters, you get to fight with six, with front and back rows as well as synergistic combo attacks adding to the strategy. None of it felt  revolutionary at the time like the multi-cam cinematic quality of <em>Final Fantasy VII</em> battles, but it’s crunchy and well-balanced as far as conventional turn-based combat goes.</p><figure id="" data-id="ec7665b9604a75378ac2a78cc4160011" data-recommend-id="image://ec7665b9604a75378ac2a78cc4160011" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A character runs across a town. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A character runs across a town. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Konami</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ec7665b9604a75378ac2a78cc4160011" data-recommend-id="image://ec7665b9604a75378ac2a78cc4160011" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A character runs across a town. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>So what improvements and new quality-of-life features does the <em>Suikoden I &amp; II HD Remaster</em> collection bring to the party? Aside from the graphical overhaul and updated script (the original localized versions were far from perfect), there are standard additions like auto-saves and a menu log that keeps a record of what people have told you. There’s no mini-map but you can sprint from the start now. You can speed up fights to auto-battle through them quickly, though weirdly the music speeds up during this as well. Plus there are optional difficulty modes now. The ability to turn off timed events is coming in a day-one update (certain characters can’t be recruited if the in-game clock ticks past a certain point). </p><p>It’s unfortunate that you can’t speed up the game outside of battle, and it feels like a missed opportunity not to have the option to turn on the game’s old graphics and aspect ratio for enthusiasts who want to revisit the original experience on PS1. The inventory systems in both games are also still a pain (though not nearly as clunky as how they were left in the recent <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em>). An in-game gallery, museum, or other historical feature would have been a nice bonus as well, especially for the $50 price tag. The bar keeps rising for modern remasters of all-time classics, and it certainly feels like there was room for <em>Suikoden I &amp; II HD Remaster </em>to be a more comprehensive package. </p><p>It doesn’t make any major missteps, though, which can’t be said for every PS1 JRPG that gets an HD makeover. <em>Suikoden I &amp; II HD Remaster</em> presents one good game and one excellent one (it’s sacrilege to say but if you’re short on time I think you should just play<em> II</em>) with everything a modern player needs to enjoy two genre classics (well, except for maybe an option to turn off random encounters). Konami has already announced an anime adaptation of <em>Suikoden II </em>and a new <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/suikoden-star-leap-trailer-gacha-mobile-konami-date-1851767567&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/suikoden-star-leap-trailer-gacha-mobile-konami-date-1851767567">mobile spin-off called<em> Star Leap </em>that looks beautiful but has gacha microtransactions</a></span>. If this burgeoning <em>Suikoden</em> renaissance is successful, though, maybe we’ll finally get<em> Suikoden VI</em>, or at least <em>Suikoden III</em> as a PS2 classic on PlayStation 5.  </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed's Best Great Sword Boosts How Quickly You Can Attack]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/find-avowed-best-great-sword-philosophers-riddle-1851767785</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avoweds-best-great-sword-boosts-how-quickly-you-can-attack.1126245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/find-avowed-best-great-sword-philosophers-riddle-1851767785<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="eff997bcf09cf9e576df46a3ef953580" data-recommend-id="image://eff997bcf09cf9e576df46a3ef953580" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The gang poses on a clifftop to show off The Philosopher's Riddle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The gang poses on a clifftop to show off The Philosopher's Riddle." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian Entertainment / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="eff997bcf09cf9e576df46a3ef953580" data-recommend-id="image://eff997bcf09cf9e576df46a3ef953580" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The gang poses on a clifftop to show off The Philosopher's Riddle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Avowed</em> contains multiple fantastic two-handed Great Sword options, so it’s hard to specify which is the absolute best for <em>you</em> without knowing what type of build you’re going for. But one thing is for certain: Great Swords swing slow as hell. As such, more attack speed is never a bad thing. And that’s where <strong>The Philosopher’s Riddle</strong> Great Sword comes in, with its enchantment that can increase how quickly you attack. Here’s what you should know about this big-ass sword and where to find it.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h579101"><a id=""></a><strong>The Philosopher’s Riddle passive bonus and enchantments</strong></h2><p>The Philosopher’s Riddle comes with the Poison Lash passive bonus, which deals +10 percent bonus Poison damage. Unless you’re specifically going for a poison build, this won’t be the weapon’s make-or-break component, but the added damage over time can be helpful nonetheless.</p><p>The Philosopher’s Riddle comes with the Aggressive Debate enchantment, which increases your attack speed by 15 percent for 10 seconds after completing a full combo. You can choose one of two permanent upgrades to this enchantment:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>Overwhelming Argument</strong> - Increases the attack speed buff after a full combo to 25 percent.</li><li><strong>Cutting Retort</strong> - Causes your Power Attacks to deal high Stun and Bleed accumulation.</li></ul><h2 id="h579102"><a id=""></a><strong>Where to find The Philosopher’s Riddle</strong></h2><p>The Philosopher’s Riddle is pretty easy to find and can be snagged early in <em>Avowed</em> while exploring the game’s opening region of Dawnshore. You’ll need to head to Castol’s Folly, which is an island of ruins located southeast of Paradis.</p><figure id="" data-id="8a35ba3a06fa0fc6692af8df1de3b126" data-recommend-id="image://8a35ba3a06fa0fc6692af8df1de3b126" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1112" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image of a map showing the location of The Philosopher's Riddle Great Sword in Avowed." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image of a map showing the location of The Philosopher's Riddle Great Sword in Avowed." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian Entertainment / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8a35ba3a06fa0fc6692af8df1de3b126" data-recommend-id="image://8a35ba3a06fa0fc6692af8df1de3b126" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1112" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image of a map showing the location of The Philosopher's Riddle Great Sword in Avowed." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Castol’s Folly features a handful of fun diversions, but your goal is to reach the very top, achieved by simply following the path up various platforms. You’ll eventually wrap around toward the northwestern corner of the island after making some heartstopping leaps. Before reaching the very tip-top, you can find The Philosopher’s Riddle embedded in the ground beside some pink mushrooms.</p><p>I’ve already picked up the sword, so enjoy my detailed drawing below. I think I have a future in art, honestly.</p><figure id="" data-id="2f68e034aa33a9afd9daff8a8139e885" data-recommend-id="image://2f68e034aa33a9afd9daff8a8139e885" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1082" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image showing a poorly-drawn sword in place of where The Philosopher's Riddle Great Sword would normally be found in Avowed." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image showing a poorly-drawn sword in place of where The Philosopher's Riddle Great Sword would normally be found in Avowed." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian Entertainment / Kotaku / Billy Givens Art Studio</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2f68e034aa33a9afd9daff8a8139e885" data-recommend-id="image://2f68e034aa33a9afd9daff8a8139e885" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1082" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image showing a poorly-drawn sword in place of where The Philosopher's Riddle Great Sword would normally be found in Avowed." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>With The Philosopher’s Riddle in hand, you’re ready to head back into The Living Lands and start slicing and dicing your foes with faster attack speed. Godspeed.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Developer Of Until Dawn's PS5 Remake Is "Effectively Closed" - Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-developer-of-until-dawns-ps5-remake-is-effectively-closed-report/1100-6529926/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-developer-of-until-dawns-ps5-remake-is-effectively-closed-report.1126239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-developer-of-until-dawns-ps5-remake-is-effectively-closed-report/1100-6529926/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529926">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Ballistic Moon, the studio behind the PC and PS5 remake of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/until-dawn/" data-ref-id="5000-616356">Until Dawn</a> released last year, is now "effectively closed" after failing to find a publisher for its next game.</p><p>A new report from <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-remake-developer-ballistic-moon-effectively-closed/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Insider Gaming</a> reveals that only the studio founders and a handful of others potentially remain employed there at this point. The studio reportedly couldn't find funding for its next game, and Sony didn't give the studio any support for future work on the Until Dawn franchise. Ballistic Moon has yet to comment on this situation.</p><p>Ballistic Moon is a U.K. developer founded in 2020 by industry veterans from studios like EA and Supermassive Games. So far, Ballistic Moon's only game is 2024's remake of Until Dawn, which brought the beloved PS4 choose-your-own-adventure horror adventure game to Unreal Engine 5. It featured a recomposed musical score, changed the gameplay camera to a third-person perspective rather than a fixed-camera one, and added a post-credit scene teasing a sequel. It received a <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/until-dawn/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lukewarm reception</a> compared to the original.</p><p>It's unclear if there is a Until Dawn sequel in active development right now, but if one is, it seems that Ballistic Moon is not the studio working on it. Whatever Ballistic Moon's next project was, Insider Gaming explains that the studio couldn't find funding or an interested publisher for it. Ballistic Moon had actually <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/until-dawn-remake-developer-ballistic-moon-lays-off-several-staff" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">laid off some developers</a> prior to the Until Dawn remake's release last October, although this report explains that many of the 20 or so remaining developers were cut in December.</p><p>If you want to play Ballistic Moon's take on Until Dawn, it's available on PC and PS5. A <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-until-dawn-trailer-serves-up-fresh-nightmares/1100-6529477/" data-ref-id="1100-6529477">movie based on Until Dawn</a> also hits theaters next month.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There Might Not Be Another Last of Us Game, Druckmann Suggests Rather Ambiguously]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/not-another-last-of-us-game-druckmann-ambiguous-suggest/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/there-might-not-be-another-last-of-us-game-druckmann-suggests-rather-ambiguously.1126206/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/not-another-last-of-us-game-druckmann-ambiguous-suggest/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a recent interview with Variety, Neil Druckmann suggested that The Last of Us might be over and done with. He said, ‘Don’t bet on there being more Last of Us.’ It’s a rather ambiguous statement, as it’s not immediately clear if he’s saying there are no more Last of Us games coming <strong>now</strong> or if The Last of Us Part III will be the final game in the series.</p>



<p>In April, the second season of the award-winning HBO series will drop, more than two years after the first season arrived.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-this-could-be-it">‘This Could Be It’</h2>



<p>The Last of Us was released in 2013 and has since been remastered and re-released no fewer than 743 times across multiple platforms and generations. In 2020, the follow-up title – aptly named The Last of Us Part II – was released. It was a controversial title in many ways, but it was still a masterpiece of a game that turned heads worldwide.</p>



<p>On April 3, Part II’s newest iteration, The Last of Us Part II Remastered, will be released on PC.</p>



<p>In <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/the-last-of-us-season-2-abby-video-game-changes-backlash-1236327786/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">a recent segment with Variety</a>, Neil Druckmann talked about the second season of the Emmy Award-winning show. He sat down with Craig Mazin, with whom he has pioneered the creation of one of the best live-action adaptations in gaming history.</p>



<p>In one section, Druckmann answers the question about the existence of The Last of Us Part III, which has been rumoured on and off but never confirmed. When asked about the possibility of the game surfacing, he said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I was waiting for this question.</p>



<p>I guess the only thing I would say is don’t bet on there being more of ‘Last of Us’. This could be it.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s ever so slightly ambiguous. It could mean that there’s nothing more planned after a third game, or it could mean that we’re stuck with a two-game series that’ll never again see the light of day.</p>



<p>In December 2023, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-last-of-us-multiplayer-game-officially-cancelled/">an online multiplayer game</a> set in The Last of Us’ universe was cancelled, but in 2024, the studio ‘teased’ <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/naughty-dog-teases-new-chapter-for-the-last-of-us/">a new chapter</a> in the franchise. That was before Naughty Dog appeared at The Game Awards <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet/">to reveal Intergalactic</a>, an all-new IP that came completely out of left field.</p>



<p>Do you think The Last of Us should end on Part II? It’s no big secret that the team plans to drag out the television series and cover the second game across <strong>two </strong>seasons, so we’ve got Last of Us content in the pipeline for a while, but would you rather play it than watch it?</p>



<p>Let me know in the comments.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/esports-betting-players-bet-on-themselves-new-jersey/">controversial esports betting bill has surfaced in New Jersey</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel 1943: Rise of the Hydra Could Launch This Holiday, Says Voice Actor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/marvel-1943-rise-of-the-hydra-could-launch-this-holiday-says-voice-actor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-1943-rise-of-the-hydra-could-launch-this-holiday-says-voice-actor.1126185/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/marvel-1943-rise-of-the-hydra-could-launch-this-holiday-says-voice-actor/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been a while since we heard any news about Marvel 1943: Rise of the Hydra. The action/adventure game in development at Skydance New Media and <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-to-be-published-by-plaion/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">scheduled to be published by Plaion</a> should launch this year, but there have been no further details on the release timing, and some fans have been worried about a delay.</p>
<p>According to Black Panther voice actor Khary Payton, though, the team is still doing its best to release it this Holiday season. <a href="https://thedirect.com/article/marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-game-release-khary-payton-exclusive" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Speaking to The Direct</a>, he said:</p>
<p><em>We’re still working. We’re planning on 2025… We’re thinking like a Christmas situation. But I'm so excited. To be playing him in the video game, playing his grandfather, be playing a version of Black Panther, and looking on there and seeing that it's me… It's like the most photo realistic… We want people to play this game and have the entire family, sit on the sofa and watch it like they're watching 'Game of Thrones,' or 'The Walking Dead,' or something. We’re looking for just an incredible cinematic experience for everybody, and I pinch myself.</em></p>
<p>Payton is definitely right about the game's photorealism. The developers <a href="https://wccftech.com/1943-rise-of-hydra-amy-hennig-2025-unreal-engine-5-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">demonstrated</a> the impressive Unreal Engine 5-powered visuals during Epic's Unreal Engine GDC 2024 live stream.</p>
<p>The development team is helmed by none other than Amy Hennig, who's renowned in the industry for her work on Legacy of Kain, Soul Reaver, Uncharted, and Battlefield: Hardline. She was famously developing the Star Wars game codenamed Project Ragtag at Visceral Games before the studio was shut down and the project canceled.</p>
<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/captain-america-black-panther-wwii-amy-hennig-confirmed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Announced</a> in September 2022, Marvel 1943: Rise of the Hydra is set in Nazi-occupied Paris during World War II. It involves Steve Rogers (Captain America) forming an uneasy alliance with Azzuri (Black Panther), the king of Wakanda. Other playable characters include Howling Commandos member Gabriel Jones and Nanali, leader of the Wakandan Spy Network.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA's Overlooked Monster Hunter-Like And 7 Other Games On Sale For Just $12]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ea-monster-hunter-wild-hearts-pacific-drive-humble-12-1851767846</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eas-overlooked-monster-hunter-like-and-7-other-games-on-sale-for-just-12.1126170/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/ea-monster-hunter-wild-hearts-pacific-drive-humble-12-1851767846<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="04c583fd546515c5c1c706e55a94ce1b" data-recommend-id="image://04c583fd546515c5c1c706e55a94ce1b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Gearbox / EA / Kepler / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="04c583fd546515c5c1c706e55a94ce1b" data-recommend-id="image://04c583fd546515c5c1c706e55a94ce1b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Calling all fans of <em>Monster Hunter,</em> creepy forests, awesome 2D action games, and/or intergalactic warfare, this month’s Humble Choice selection is for you. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196406" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Why This Under-the-Radar AAA Title Is More Than Just A Far Cry Clone" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="102" data-playlist="196406,195805,196163" data-current="196406"><div><p>Why This Under-the-Radar AAA Title Is More Than Just A Far Cry Clone</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196406/196406_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21954.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>We are only a few days into a new month. That means all the various video game subscription services out there are refreshing their catalogs to offer some fresh options. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.humblebundle.com/membership?hmb_source=humble_home&amp;hmb_medium=takeover&amp;hmb_campaign=current_sub-non-sub&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.humblebundle.com/membership?hmb_source=humble_home&amp;hmb_medium=takeover&amp;hmb_campaign=current_sub-non-sub" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">And this month’s Humble Choice offerings</a></span> are especially good. For those unaware, Humble Choice is Humble Bundle’s $12 a month subscription service that grants you a selection of PC games every month while supporting charity, too. </p><p>Here are the eight PC games you get this month if you are Humble Choice subscriber:</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Pacific Drive</em></li><li><em>Homeworld 3</em></li><li><em>Wild Hearts</em></li><li><em>Tales of Kenzera: Zau</em></li><li><em>Gravity Circuit</em></li><li><em>Sir Whoopass</em></li><li><em>Racine</em></li><li><em>Cavern of Dreams</em></li></ul><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pacific-drive-steam-ps5-survival-crafting-sim-1851282916&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pacific-drive-steam-ps5-survival-crafting-sim-1851282916"><em>Pacific Drive</em></a></span> is a fantastic and creepy car-based survival roguelike game set in the rainy and dark forests of the northwest. Avoid the strange anomalies and get out alive while upgrading your car with supplies you scavenge. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/wild-hearts&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/wild-hearts"><em>Wild Hearts</em></a></span> is a underappreciated and overlooked<em> Monster Hunter</em> clone that streamlines parts of the genre while also introducing some original ideas, too. Released in 2023, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/koei-tecmo-ea-toukiden-monster-hunter-wild-hearts-1849593724?_gl=1*1jt4ab6*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MTE5MTIwNy4yMjguMS4xNzQxMTk0MjQ1LjI5LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/koei-tecmo-ea-toukiden-monster-hunter-wild-hearts-1849593724?_gl=1*1jt4ab6*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MTE5MTIwNy4yMjguMS4xNzQxMTk0MjQ1LjI5LjAuMA.."><em>Wild Hearts</em></a></span> was published by EA and developed by Omega Force, and while it has its fans, it’s always felt like this game didn’t get the love it deserved. Perhaps now that will change. But then, considering how everyone is playing <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-steam-framerate-1851766992&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-steam-framerate-1851766992">a new<em> Monster Hunter </em>game</a></span>, probably not. </p><p>The other game I want to highlight is <em>Homeworld 3</em>. We don’t get a lot of big budget RTS space games anymore, so it was nice to see this one from Blackbird and Gearbox last year. Sadly, the game isn’t great, but as a freebie included with a subscription it might be worth checking out to see if its take on space RTS combat clicks with you. </p><p>If you want to grab these games up, you can subscribe to Humble Choice right now and then cancel your subscription later and still keep all of these games.</p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 8 Sterling K. Brown Moments On Paradise That Made Him A Certified Badass]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sterling-k-brown-paradise-season-finale-hulu-season-2-1851767682</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-8-sterling-k-brown-moments-on-paradise-that-made-him-a-certified-badass.1126167/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/sterling-k-brown-paradise-season-finale-hulu-season-2-1851767682<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="539459a58f1600550c18c6da8f701cfb" data-recommend-id="image://539459a58f1600550c18c6da8f701cfb" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Agent Collins sitting patiently" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Agent Collins sitting patiently" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="539459a58f1600550c18c6da8f701cfb" data-recommend-id="image://539459a58f1600550c18c6da8f701cfb" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Agent Collins sitting patiently" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Paradise </em>is the type of show in which bravery is essential, and being a badass is survival. The remarkable Hulu series is set in a world where rich and powerful people designed a utopian city called Paradise inside of a Colorado mountain in order to survive an extinction-level event that has ravaged Earth. The illusion of safety is shattered when President of the United States Cal Bradford (James Marsden) is mysteriously murdered in a place where crime isn’t supposed to exist, and it’s up to his Secret Service bodyguard Xavier Collins (Sterling K. Brown) to find out who did it. Samantha “Sinatra” Redmon (Julianne Nicholson), the brains behind the entire Paradise project, turns out to be a worthy adversary who’s trying to do the right thing in the absolute worst possible ways.</p><p><em>Paradise</em> does a lot of things well, but its shining achievement is showing how much of a badass Sterling K. Brown can be.</p><p>Known for his portrayals of stern but loving parents on his breakout show <em>This Is Us</em> and in the severely underrated film <em>Waves</em>, the Emmy-winning actor finds himself in some of the most intense situations of his illustrious career thanks to the Hulu series. Without shooting that many bullets or killing that many people, Brown channels the same emotional control that made his earlier characters feel three-dimensional to perform a role at the intersection of grief and anger. He isn’t a badass just for the sake of being one. He’s a badass because it’s the right thing to do. And these are his most badass moments from the first season of <em>Paradise</em>. </p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="3a6d0f17ae4ec6447a44be6180ce5f94" data-recommend-id="image://3a6d0f17ae4ec6447a44be6180ce5f94" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="1687" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney/Ser Baffo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3a6d0f17ae4ec6447a44be6180ce5f94" data-recommend-id="image://3a6d0f17ae4ec6447a44be6180ce5f94" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="1687" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>As a testament to how wildly the show’s character dynamics shifted by the end of the season, Agent Collins risking his life to protect the president from an assassin’s bullet in the first episode isn’t even a Top 5 most badass moment by the end of the season. While speaking to the press, Collins shields the president from a crazed boom operator who slides a gun out of his boom mic in an inventive but unsuccessful assassination attempt. In the moment, it was incredible watching Collins’ super-secret agent senses slow down time, allowing him to effectively react to the shot before it happens, and seeing him so focused on doing his job that he doesn’t realize he’s been shot until the President tells him. Unfortunately, revelations from later in the season  knock this badass moment down a few pegs, and it also suffers from not being presented from the boom operator’s perspective, which would have placed it squarely in the top 3.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="1fbd8ec6ee6251e4be54a7b25d134347" data-recommend-id="image://1fbd8ec6ee6251e4be54a7b25d134347" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sterling K Brown standing guard" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Sterling K Brown standing guard" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney/Brian Roedel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1fbd8ec6ee6251e4be54a7b25d134347" data-recommend-id="image://1fbd8ec6ee6251e4be54a7b25d134347" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sterling K Brown standing guard" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>There was no sequence in <em>Paradise</em>, or arguably any other show so far this year, as nerve wracking and suffocatingly intense as the one in which everyone in the White House realizes the severity of the natural disaster they’ve been watching take out entire countries. The seventh episode is centered on the chaotic day when the president let’s everyone in America, including the shell-shocked politicians outside the Oval Office, know that he and a few others knew about the cataclysm they’ve been watching, essentially telling them that death is inevitable for most of them. A true badass can oscillate between emotions at the drop of a dime, and Brown exhibited some of his most emotionally visceral acting yet as he was frantically worrying about the safety of his wife in Atlanta while also being tasked with getting the president through the mob of his hostile colleagues ready to tear him apart for keeping them in the dark. </p><p> He runs back to grab the briefcase the president needs to launch a nuclear attack seconds after the last person holding it was shot in the back of the head, then scurries to the helicopter without a single blink, tear, or even dust from the propeller entering his eyes. That’s a stone cold badass who unfortunately did it in service of a plot he’d quickly learn may have cost him the love of his life. </p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="9720a6479c1934250612aa7a2110774f" data-recommend-id="image://9720a6479c1934250612aa7a2110774f" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="James Marsden (left) explaining something to Sterling K Brown (right)" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="James Marsden (left) explaining something to Sterling K Brown (right)" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney/Brian Roedel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="9720a6479c1934250612aa7a2110774f" data-recommend-id="image://9720a6479c1934250612aa7a2110774f" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="James Marsden (left) explaining something to Sterling K Brown (right)" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Verbally reprimanding your boss in front of his subordinates could get you fired from McDonald’s. Doing that to the President of the United States, and as a result delaying his evacuation from an extinction-level disaster, could (and probably should) get you shot before your lips formed an exclamation point. None of that matters to tearfully enraged Agent Collins after he finally realizes the President knew Collins’ wife was doomed from the beginning of the day. As he and the leader of the free world exchange barbs over the reality of the situation, Collins looks him dead in his dreamy blue eyes and mocks the president’s performative bravery for telling the American people the world was already ending before they had a chance to prepare like he did. He then makes the impossible choice to accept his wife’s death in order to be there for his children, etching this in the Sterling K. Brown badass hall of fame.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="03c8696cf74c033b884d8ac6c1b68fd3" data-recommend-id="image://03c8696cf74c033b884d8ac6c1b68fd3" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sterling K Brown holding a gun to Sinatra's head" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Sterling K Brown holding a gun to Sinatra's head" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney/Brian Roedel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="03c8696cf74c033b884d8ac6c1b68fd3" data-recommend-id="image://03c8696cf74c033b884d8ac6c1b68fd3" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Sterling K Brown holding a gun to Sinatra's head" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Yes, Samantha “Sinatra” Redmon was a grieving mother who turned the grief of her son’s death into her life’s purpose to protect the ones she loved from a dying world, but she’s deserved a bullet in the head since the second episode. That quick shift from distraught to dangerous that I mentioned earlier was at its peak in the 10 seconds Collins went from a puddle of tears to a gun-toting killer after Sinatra implied that she’d accidentally had his daughter killed. This would’ve been a little higher on the list if he put the megalomaniac out of her misery. Unfortunately all he did was distract her long enough with a gun to her head for Sinatra’s own assassin, Jane Driscoll (Nicole Brydon Bloom), to put a bullet in her chest to disable her without killing her. I guess you shouldn’t come between a psycho and their Nintendo Wii.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="8c2e887f44b4035a678801db1fc989b0" data-recommend-id="image://8c2e887f44b4035a678801db1fc989b0" data-format="jpg" data-width="1650" data-height="825" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Eerie message in the sky" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Eerie message in the sky" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Hulu</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8c2e887f44b4035a678801db1fc989b0" data-recommend-id="image://8c2e887f44b4035a678801db1fc989b0" data-format="jpg" data-width="1650" data-height="825" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Eerie message in the sky" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>There are certain things in life that are inherently badass simply because describing them sounds unbelievable. Once Collins was ready to finally come at Sinatra, he called in the craziest favor you can ever ask a neighbor: Leave digital messages in the sky for all to see. In episode six, Collins had the messages “THEY’RE LYING TO YOU,” “DO YOU WANT TO KNOW THE TRUTH?” and “WHO IS SINATRA?” displayed across the sky in crimson red. That alone was a badass move to destabilize Sinatra’s influence over the community. It became genius when the only way she could have it removed was by rebooting the sky. REBOOTING. THE. SKY. That alone accomplished everything he wanted, and she did it for him.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="dd1ddb951399f549e32d8555f180c622" data-recommend-id="image://dd1ddb951399f549e32d8555f180c622" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Xavier Collins having an intense conversation over lunch" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Xavier Collins having an intense conversation over lunch" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney/Brian Roedel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="dd1ddb951399f549e32d8555f180c622" data-recommend-id="image://dd1ddb951399f549e32d8555f180c622" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Xavier Collins having an intense conversation over lunch" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>This Is Us </em>fans are well aware that if you give Brown time to speak uninterrupted about death, he’s going to rip your heart out and wash it with your tears. In the middle of his silent uprising in the sixth episode, Collins cuts through Dr. Gabriela Torabi (Sarah Shahi) trying to talk him out of his dissention with her psychobabble bullshit by vividly comparing Sinatra bringing all of these people to this idyllic city inside a mountain to the way people corral cows  into increasingly smaller spaces until the fight in them is diminished so much that they  “line up single-file and march down a chute to their death.” His delivery is bone-chilling, the analogy is sobering, and the interspersed visuals of Agent Robinson (Krys Marshall) finding Sinatra’s hidden armory during his speech are devastating. Speaking the truth is usually the most badass thing you can do, especially when it’s a matter of life or death.</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="20f0901f5e8409a45215700e75c784bb" data-recommend-id="image://20f0901f5e8409a45215700e75c784bb" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Nicole Robinson (left) and Xavier Collins (right) taking out weapons" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Nicole Robinson (left) and Xavier Collins (right) taking out weapons" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney/Brian Roedell</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="20f0901f5e8409a45215700e75c784bb" data-recommend-id="image://20f0901f5e8409a45215700e75c784bb" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Nicole Robinson (left) and Xavier Collins (right) taking out weapons" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The #4 pick and #2 pick have some overlap, but they’re not quite the same. With the help of Agent Robinson and a bunch of disillusioned Secret Service colleagues, Collins organizes a multifaceted coup of the powers that be. He and his cohorts surreptitiously steal all of the guns the government said didn’t exist, and hack the sky to tell the people being governed that they’ve been lied to, leading Sinatra to initiate the shelter protocol that had all senior officials and their families corralled in a secure location like the cattle he mentioned earlier. While his ultimate plan of imprisoning Sinatra with the rest of the corrupt officials doesn’t succeed, bringing a government to its knees is A-1 badassery. </p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="7e5ee4c8f8da3d70685320cef0da2470" data-recommend-id="image://7e5ee4c8f8da3d70685320cef0da2470" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Xavier Collins looking at coordinates" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Xavier Collins looking at coordinates" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney/Brian Roedel</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7e5ee4c8f8da3d70685320cef0da2470" data-recommend-id="image://7e5ee4c8f8da3d70685320cef0da2470" data-format="jpg" data-width="3000" data-height="2000" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Xavier Collins looking at coordinates" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Guns, blood, and government destabilization require bravery, but nothing is more badass than flying a plane out of a mountain into potentially poisonous air to find your wife who may or may not be alive. After 8 episodes of Collins doing everything from organizing a coup to berating the President of the United States after taking a bullet for him,  Collins commandeered a plane and took off to find his wife based on the secret coordinates the late president left. Season 2 will undoubtedly have him venturing into the unknown while his kids and everyone else he cares for back at Paradise deal with the aftermath of his uprising. No matter where he is, you can count on Collins to be the biggest badass in the vicinity. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exclusive: Until Dawn Remake Developer Ballistic Moon “Effectively Closed”]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-remake-developer-ballistic-moon-effectively-closed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-until-dawn-remake-developer-ballistic-moon-%E2%80%9Ceffectively-closed%E2%80%9D.1126164/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/until-dawn-remake-developer-ballistic-moon-effectively-closed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Until Dawn Remake developer Ballistic Moon is “effectively closed”. That’s according to multiple sources with knowledge of the situation.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has learned that after the layoffs that were publicly <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ballistic-moon-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced in September 2024</a> took place, roughly 40 employees or so were let go. The remaining staff was kept to offer post-launch support and development on Until Dawn after its October release. In December 2024, however, the company quietly laid off that staff as well, resulting in around 20 more developers losing their job.</p>



<p>Sources say that only the studio’s founders remain and “possibly” a handful of employees “at most”. There are no employees in public relations, marketing, or development left.</p>



<p>“People are sharing bugs they’ve found in the game to make the team aware but there is no one working on patch support for the game anymore,” one source said. “The studio has effectively closed now.”</p>



<p>As far as what happened, those who spoke on the condition of anonymity made it clear that the owners attempted to keep things at Ballistic Moon moving forward. Many said that the owners were actively looking for funding and pitching projects, but couldn’t secure funding or a new publisher.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When asked about Sony publishing another game or future updates to Until Dawn Remake for the studio, one source said it was discussed but never came to fruition.</p>



<p>“Sony said after the game they might greenlight more funding for updates, but looks like they didn’t,” the source said.</p>



<p>Regarding working at the studio, most who spoke said that it was a generally good place to work. Many spoke highly of their teams and the work being done. What they didn’t like, though, were instances of unpaid overtime. One former employee equated it to “weeks” of unpaid work and that the internal announcement of redundancies came after the team had worked overtime.</p>



<p>“Nice reward for our hard work,” they said.</p>



<p>Ballistic Moon’s leadership has yet to put out an official statement on the status of the studio and whether or not it has been or will be closed. In technical terms, it’s remains active in name. Should a publisher sign on or funding come from elsewhere, the studio could start the hiring process again to bring in developers and other staff. Right now, however, there is no work being done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Insider Gaming has attempted multiple times to get in contact with Ballistic Moon’s co-founders and owners as well as Sony regarding the claims of additional funding for the studio, but no responses have been received. Should any come after the publishing of this story, it will be added in an update.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about when the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/battlefield-labs-playtest-this-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first Battlefield Labs playtest</a> is expected to start. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft Dungeons Sequel Is in Development, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/minecraft-dungeons-sequel-is-in-development-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecraft-dungeons-sequel-is-in-development-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.1126161/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/minecraft-dungeons-sequel-is-in-development-its-claimed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A new leak has revealed that Minecraft: Spicewood is seemingly the sequel to Minecraft Dungeons.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The leak arrives from X0X_LEAK on <a href="https://x.com/X0X_LEAK/status/1897050276374425705" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a>, who has stated that the upcoming Minecraft Dungeons sequel is being referred to internally as “Project Spicewood” and has “been in development for at least 2 years.” The post also reveals more details about the upcoming spinoff title, including the main areas and POIs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to X0X_LEAK, Minecraft has a set of new areas and POIs for the Dungeons sequel; we now know the 3 locations and their places of interest. First up is Honeycomb Fields, which features locations such as Undermill, Farm, Island, Lake, Fields, and Forest. Next is the Desert, which includes a Cliff, Fortress, Mountain, Village and Icelagoon. Last up is Forest, which will introduce a Deep Dark entrance, an Outpost Entrance, a Witchzone, and a Shady Forest Town.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What’s more, VISLOWERKEBAB on <a href="https://x.com/VISLOWERKEBAB/status/1897049464931803317" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> has also provided some work-in-progress images for the Minecraft Dungeon sequel. The first image could be the official artwork for “Project Spicewood,” and the second image is a gameplay screenshot for the upcoming title, featuring a perspective similar to that of the 2020 dungeon crawler.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, the Minecraft Triple Bundle <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/minecraft-triple-bundle-releases-tomorrow-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leak has been confirmed</a>, and the new bundle is now available on the Xbox Store. Also, check out A Minecraft Movie’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/a-minecraft-movie-gets-final-pre-release-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">final pre-release trailer</a>. What are your thoughts on the Minecraft Dungeons Sequel?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;the<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ps3-has-received-a-new-system-software-update-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> PS3 receiving a new software update in 2025</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cities: Skylines 2's troubled console release sounds like it's still some way off]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2s-troubled-console-release-sounds-like-its-still-some-way-off</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cities-skylines-2s-troubled-console-release-sounds-like-its-still-some-way-off.1126158/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2s-troubled-console-release-sounds-like-its-still-some-way-off<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>As dev admits it has "more things" to address.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/cities-skylines-2-consoles.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer/Paradox Interactive</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/cities-skylines">Cities: Skylines</a> 2 developer Colossal Order has shared an update on the city builder sequel's long-delayed console release - confirming it still has "more things we need to address" before it can launch, and that it won't be arriving before summer.
</p>
<p>
Cities: Skylines 2's Xbox Series X/S and PlayStation 5 versions were originally due to launch alongside the PC release back in October 2023, but Colossal Order and Paradox Interactive <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-console-release-gets-delayed">announced a last-minute delay</a> into 2024. Its release was then <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-console-launch-delayed-again">delayed indefinitely</a> following Cities: Skylines 2's disastrous launch on PC - which continues to attract <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-fans-complain-of-performance-woes-after-developer-admits-it-missed-target">complaints about poor performance and simulation issues</a>, despite multiple updates over the 18 months since then.
</p>
<p>
Colossal Order's most recent news on Cities: Skylines 2 console release came last November, when it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-studio-blames-ongoing-console-delay-on-hardware-limitations">admitted it was struggling to overcome "hardware limitations"</a> impacting performance on Xbox Series X/S and PlayStation 5. It noted it had managed to get the game "stable and playable" on consoles by "significantly lowering the graphics quality", but said it wasn't happy with the compromise and wanted to bring graphics quality up to an "acceptable level".
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Coming October 24th, 2023 I Pre-Order Now I Cities: Skylines II Official Gameplay Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MX9YWu5wkGg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Coming October 24th, 2023 I Pre-Order Now I Cities: Skylines II Official Gameplay Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MX9YWu5wkGg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/MX9YWu5wkGg?autoplay=1" title="Coming October 24th, 2023 I Pre-Order Now I Cities: Skylines II Official Gameplay Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Cities: Skylines 2 gameplay trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MX9YWu5wkGg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Skip ahead six months and Colossal Order has addressed Cities: Skylines 2's console release once more, and while progress is apparently being made, it sounds like there's still some way to go. "We continue to make steady progress on the console version," it <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/949230/view/542225339665875067?l=english">wrote in an update</a>, "and our core focus has been on further improving performance and stability. However, despite these advancements, we have more things we need to address before we reach the level of quality and the experience we want for you as our players."
</p>
<p>
"We know many of you are eagerly awaiting the console release," it continued, "but to set expectations clearly: we will not have a release before summer. We want to avoid any premature estimates and instead commit to providing you with reliable information when we're closer to a launch-ready state. Our goal remains unchanged: to bring Cities: Skylines 2 to console in the best possible shape."
</p>
<p>
News isn't entirely positive on the PC front, either. Colossal Order has also admitted it's struggling with Cities: Skylines 2's custom asset editor - a modding feature it called "crucial" last September, when it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cities-skylines-2-dlc-gets-further-delays-as-developer-priorities-assets-editor-for-mods">announced it was delaying its DLC plans</a> in order to get the asset editor finished and released. But in its latest update, the studio has said the feature is proving "more technically challenging than initially anticipated due to the hefty amounts of built-in assets affected by the changes, but it is moving forward."
</p>
<p>
"Rest assured that we're committed to solving these challenges," it wrote, "and our dedicated team is actively making progress to overcome them. We know how much custom assets mean to you and, honestly, to us, too, and we will continue to keep you informed of our progress as soon as we have something more concrete to share."
</p>
<p>
"We appreciate your patience and enthusiasm," the studio concluded, "and we will share more updates as we continue shaping the future of Cities: Skylines together." It added it'll be back next week when the original Cities: Skylines celebrates its 10th anniversary.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here are the 2025 Bafta nominees and our predictions who will win]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/05/2025-bafta-nominees-predictions/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here-are-the-2025-bafta-nominees-and-our-predictions-who-will-win.1126134/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/05/2025-bafta-nominees-predictions/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The 2025 Video Game Baftas will take placed on April 8th and will be streamed live at 7pm on BAFTA’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/bafta" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://u7061146.ct.sendgrid.net/ls/click?upn%3Du001.gqh-2BaxUzlo7XKIuSly0rC0sA2ifa1G8yJeuQZiZY9TpAFD0mFWvGTcWFDlYMEUdxDVsY_O4dl5MM-2FfV4gOMdkHDRNUITfCBMKY6aIh2nXbQ6u4ZYHWdJ2xs778pAclvwX8QY22Dv2tVR0ZaXQuhdlJFZEpBGzb3VTDM-2FxYSFm1TozUqinr0UQXa7uNcJFFtf4HK8YYFltgvPqFvjhXKHqtIEjT-2Fg3WN6toFUB-2Bb-2FWLdQ-2B6GBMs4V9MO09vBS1XdACd-2FsmNMDlZyt34x9PwpVdUkga-2BmmMmf1OuHCUNqgvpYWbztHTI-2BWTNNW33J7TiK9kaEkN-2Bcz-2ByGd5w8VfFmU50lQ-2BK-2FkKDWDqxX0U86jOrB4D7r4Yjhp6XXGgsxjByX-2Fs63ApcUeHKs1B5-2FdeHN7IVv-2FL6g-3D-3D&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1741184228679000&amp;usg=AOvVaw00FGbHF6Nlh6La0K0gUrWZ" data-vars-ga-outbound-link="https://www.youtube.com/bafta" data-vars-ga-ux-element="Hyperlink" data-vars-ga-call-to-action="YouTube">YouTube</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.twitch.tv/bafta" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://u7061146.ct.sendgrid.net/ls/click?upn%3Du001.gqh-2BaxUzlo7XKIuSly0rC5HK-2FZP1yjeGSnTjYJGRvL2FyA3PhaWNAKDN2ZECP2Th6zy9_O4dl5MM-2FfV4gOMdkHDRNUITfCBMKY6aIh2nXbQ6u4ZYHWdJ2xs778pAclvwX8QY22Dv2tVR0ZaXQuhdlJFZEpBGzb3VTDM-2FxYSFm1TozUqinr0UQXa7uNcJFFtf4HK8YYFltgvPqFvjhXKHqtIEjT-2Fg3WN6toFUB-2Bb-2FWLdQ-2B6GBMs4V9MO09vBS1XdACd-2FsmNMDlZyt34x9PwpVdUkga-2BhTzRAP5uav6t3YQCY1H-2BBcsqOy0f-2Bevnh9UGih5tNhKgBbqg-2FvKOEsw3CjglvMckms2xLDYBAZeiqLT71GFocbgZIWgfP1eJI4H0vl7bpfqm8UdRbe-2FqTYFFYgt193-2F3w-3D-3D&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1741184228679000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0YnGvp8uBUeGEk-qQ1EgDf" data-vars-ga-outbound-link="https://www.twitch.tv/bafta" data-vars-ga-ux-element="Hyperlink" data-vars-ga-call-to-action="Twitch">Twitch</a> channels, but who will be winning a famous trophy? Here are all the nominees… along with our predictions.</p>
<h2 data-node-id="6">Best Game</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="7">•&nbsp;<em>Astro Bot</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Balatro</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Thank Goodness You’re Here!</em></p>


<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="7"><strong>Prediction:</strong> A strong category, but it has to be <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/astro-bot">Astro Bot</a>, the plucky PlayStation mascot who has charmed the whole planet (and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/31/game-of-the-year-2024-overall-winner/">won our own Game of the Year award</a> in December)</p>
<h2 data-node-id="9">Animation</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="10">•&nbsp;<em>Astro Bot</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Thank Goodness You’re Here!</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="10"><strong>Prediction:</strong> Harder to call this one, as Hellblade 2 once again comes with excellent performance capture and animation… but it’s probably going to be Astro Bot again, if only for the huge amount of incidental animations that you can trigger.</p>

<h2 data-node-id="11">Artistic Achievement</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="12">•&nbsp;<em>Astro Bot</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Harold Halibut</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Neva</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Still Wakes the Deep</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="12"><strong>Prediction:</strong> <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/04/16/harold-halibut-review/">Harold Halibut’s</a> stop motion animation seems to be the perfect winner for this category. It took eleven years to complete so that must deserve an award and this is probably more fitting than lifetime achievement!</p>
<h2 data-node-id="13">Audio Achievement</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="14">•&nbsp;<em>Animal Well</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Astro Bot</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Still Wakes the Deep</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="14"><strong>Prediction:</strong> Hellblade 2’s binaural recording and mixing is going to win this, no question.</p>

<h2 data-node-id="16">British Game</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="17">•&nbsp;<em>A Highland Song</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Paper Trail</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Still Wakes the Deep</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Thank Goodness You’re Here!</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="17"><strong>Prediction:</strong> There are some <em>very</em> British games in this category, but the slapstick Yorkshire humour of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/29/thank-goodness-youre-here-review/">Thank Goodness You’re Here!</a> is probably going to win.</p>
<h2 data-node-id="18">Debut Game</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="19">•&nbsp;<em>Animal Well</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Balatro</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Pacific Drive</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Tales of Kenzera: Zau</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Thank Goodness You’re Here!</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>The Plucky Squire</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="19"><strong>Prediction:</strong> Another strong category, but you can’t ignore the behemoth that is Balatro.</p>
<h2 data-node-id="21">Evolving Game</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="22">•&nbsp;<em>Diablo 4</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy 14</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>No Man’s Sky</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Sea of Thieves</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Vampire Survivors</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>World of Warcraft</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="22"><strong>Prediction:</strong> This one could go anywhere, but Sea of Thieves, Final Fantasy 14 and No Man’s Sky have won this category before, so maybe it’s time for Diablo 4.</p>

<h2 data-node-id="23">Family</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="24">•&nbsp;<em>Astro Bot</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Cat Quest 3</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Little Kitty, Big City</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>The Plucky Squire</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Party Jamboree</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="17"><strong>Prediction:</strong> Astro Bot. 100%.</p>
<h2 data-node-id="25">Game Beyond Entertainment</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="26">•&nbsp;<em>Botany Manor</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Kind Words 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Tales of Kenzera: Zau</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Tetris Forever</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Vampire Therapist</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="26"><strong>Prediction:</strong> Another hard one to guess, but Bafta do go for some odd choices now and then, so and if Hellblade 2 is getting wins elsewhere it might be Vampire Therapist.</p>
<h2 data-node-id="28">Game Design</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="29">•&nbsp;<em>Animal Well</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Astro Bot</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Balatro</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Tactical Breach Wizards</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="14"><strong>Prediction:</strong> While none of these games bring anything particularly new to the table they all play exceptionally well. Let’s go with Astro Bot again.</p>
<h2 data-node-id="30">Multiplayer</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="31">•&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Lego Horizon Adventures</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Party Jamboree</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Tekken 8</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="31"><strong>Prediction:</strong> Well it won’t be Lego Horizon Adventures – it’s fun, but no – and I have a feeling this will either go to Warhammer or Helldivers. I am going with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2.</a></p>

<h2 data-node-id="33">Music</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="34">•&nbsp;<em>Astro Bot</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Helldivers 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="34"><strong>Prediction:</strong> A completely open field here, and it really depends on what sort of music you like really. It would be nice to see <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/16/black-myth-wukong-review/">Black Myth: Wukong</a> win something,</p>
<h2 data-node-id="35">Narrative</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="36">•&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Still Wakes the Deep</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="36"><strong>Prediction:</strong> I am going for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/17/still-wakes-the-deep-review/">Still Wakes The Deep</a> in this category. There’s some great games like Metaphor: ReFantazio, but Still Wakes The Deep is a British game which gives it the edge.</p>
<h2 data-node-id="37">New Intellectual Property</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="38">•&nbsp;<em>Animal Well</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Balatro</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Still Wakes the Deep</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Thank Goodness You’re Here!</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="38"><strong>Prediction:</strong> This is a bit of a weird category as Still Wakes the Deep and Thank Goodness You’re Here! really don’t need to become franchises in the way that IP implies, and Balatro might be novel, but it’s card game and – no offence to creators – they didn’t invent the standard card deck or the Poker hands it uses. We think this will go to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/metaphor-refantazio-review/">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a>.</p>

<h2 data-node-id="40">Performer in a Leading Role</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="41">• Alec Newman,&nbsp;<em>Still Wakes the Deep</em><br>
• Humberly González,&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws</em><br>
• Isabella Inchbald,&nbsp;<em>Indika</em><br>
• Luke Roberts,&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2</em><br>
• Melina Juergens,&nbsp;<em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em><br>
• Y’lan Noel,&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="41"><strong>Prediction:</strong> This is almost certainly a second BAFTA for Melina Juergens.</p>
<h2 data-node-id="42">Performer in a Supporting Role</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="43">• Abbi Greenland and Helen Goalen,&nbsp;<em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em><br>
• Aldís Amah Hamilton,&nbsp;<em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em><br>
• Jon Blyth,&nbsp;<em>Thank Goodness You’re Here!</em><br>
• Karen Dunbar,&nbsp;<em>Still Wakes the Deep</em><br>
• Matt Berry,&nbsp;<em>Thank Goodness You’re Here!</em><br>
• Michael Abubakar,&nbsp;<em>Still Wakes the Deep</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="43"><strong>Prediction:</strong> This could be anyone, but let us hope it’s Matt Berry just for the acceptance speech.</p>
<h2 data-node-id="45">Technical Achievement</h2>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="46">•&nbsp;<em>Astro Bot</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Black Myth: Wukong</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Tiny Glade</em><br>
•&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</em></p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="46"><strong>Prediction:</strong> Given that Ninja Theory went to a lot of trouble to tell everyone they had travelled to Iceland to scan every rock and blade of grass, it’s going to be Senua’s Saga: Hellblade 2. The game really does look incredible.</p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="46">Do you agree with our predictions? Let us know in the comments.</p>
<p data-journey-content="true" data-node-id="46"><em>Source:&nbsp; <a href="https://www.bafta.org/awards/games">BAFTA</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025's Latest Retro Surprise Looks Like A Mashup Of Hades And Golden Axe]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/absolum-golden-axe-beat-em-up-rpg-rogulike-fantasy-1851767831</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2025s-latest-retro-surprise-looks-like-a-mashup-of-hades-and-golden-axe.1126122/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/absolum-golden-axe-beat-em-up-rpg-rogulike-fantasy-1851767831<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="3341ed8515c89453b04b32a703fd2c78" data-recommend-id="image://3341ed8515c89453b04b32a703fd2c78" data-format="jpg" data-width="1602" data-height="900" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Warriors fight atop a pool of green. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Warriors fight atop a pool of green. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Guard Crush, Supamonks, Dotemu</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3341ed8515c89453b04b32a703fd2c78" data-recommend-id="image://3341ed8515c89453b04b32a703fd2c78" data-format="jpg" data-width="1602" data-height="900" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Warriors fight atop a pool of green. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>  <em>Absolum</em> is a just-revealed side-scrolling brawler from some of the best teams in the genre. It looks like the beautiful art of <em>Hades</em> mixed with the soul of <em>Golden Axe</em>. It’s the latest neat-looking retro surprise in a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/shinobi-ninja-gaiden-trailer-2d-retro-release-date-ps5-1851762438?_gl=1*u230hr*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MTE5MjQ1Mi43Mi4xLjE3NDExOTI4MzEuNDYuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/shinobi-ninja-gaiden-trailer-2d-retro-release-date-ps5-1851762438?_gl=1*u230hr*_ga*MTg4NjY0MzM1NS4xNzM5NDU1MDcz*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MTE5MjQ1Mi43Mi4xLjE3NDExOTI4MzEuNDYuMC4w">year shaping up to be full of them</a></span>. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196539" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Innovative Hades-Like Feels Built For Speedrunners" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="278" data-playlist="196539,196848,196086" data-current="196539"><div><p>This Innovative Hades-Like Feels Built For Speedrunners</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196539/196539_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196539/196539_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196539/196539_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196539/196539_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22094.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The “action-RPG ‘rogue-’em-up” is being made by Guard Crush and Dotemu, which both contributed to the excellent <em>Streets of Rage 4</em>, in partnership with Supamonk, assisting with the art and animation. Up to four players team up to wield forbidden magic and lead a rebellion against the Sun King Azra who’s ravaged the land following a mysterious cataclysm. It looks awesome, like an ‘80s fantasy cartoon transformed into a nifty arcade cabinet:</p><p>Like a <em>Golden Axe</em>, each character has different strengths and weaknesses and plays into traditional barbarian, dwarf, mage, and rogue archetypes. It sounds like there will still be a fair amount of customization though out the game. “Use magical counters and rare items to turn the tide in your favor and experience a combat system that demands skill and timing, pushing you to craft new strategies at every run to wreak havoc among the enemy ranks,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1904480/Absolum/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1904480/Absolum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reads the Steam page description</a></span>. </p><p>It also sounds like there will be some pretty cool music. Absolum sports music from Gareth Coker (<em>Ori</em>, <em>Halo Infinite</em>,<em> Prince of Persia</em>), with guest composer collaborations from Yuka Kitamura (<em>Dark Souls</em>, <em>Elden Ring)</em>, Mick Gordon (<em>Doom Eternal</em>, <em>Atomic Heart</em>), and others. If the music, art and combat all come together into a cool retro fantasy adventure, <em>Absolum </em>could be something special.</p><p>It’s slated to arrive sometime in 2025 on PC and console, making it the latest NES and Genesis-era-inspired action adventure coming this year on a growing list. We’re getting <em>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</em> and <em>Ninja Gaiden: Ragebound </em>as well, both of which also look amazing. Those are single-player games though. I’d love for<em> Absolum</em> to become my new couch co-op obsession. Though if it can’t, we’re also getting <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/castle-crashers-first-dlc-in-12-years-lets-you-make-you-1851606535&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/castle-crashers-first-dlc-in-12-years-lets-you-make-you-1851606535">new <em>Castle Crashers</em> DLC in 2025</a></span>. </p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yotei Release Period—When is Ghost of Tsushima 2 Coming Out? Confirmed Platforms]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-release-ghost-of-tsushima-2/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-yotei-release-period%E2%80%94when-is-ghost-of-tsushima-2-coming-out-confirmed-platforms.1126116/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-release-ghost-of-tsushima-2/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Sucker Punch has been tight-lipped about Ghost of Yotei so far, but we’re keeping an eye on the Ghost of Tsushima 2 sequel. The stealthy standalone follow-up has a few details out in the public already, and it’s looking promising.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ghost-of-yotei-reveal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghost of Yotei</a> was a fun surprise announcement during the Sept. 24, 2024, Sony State of Play. Ghost of Tsushima cemented Sucker Punch as a stalwart of a studio following years of success with Sly Cooper and inFamous. Now, it’s back with Ghost of Yotei, and a certain Ubisoft <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/when-is-the-assassins-creed-shadows-review-embargo-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a> is making Ghost of Yotei more intriguing by the day.</p>



<p>Let’s take a look at the latest Ghost of Yotei reveals and announcements.</p>



<h2 id="h-do-we-know-when-ghost-of-yotei-is-coming-out">Do we Know When Ghost of Yotei is Coming Out?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Expect Ghost of Yotei to be just as impactful. Credit to Sucker Punch</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Ghost of Yotei doesn’t have a release date yet, but its initial reveal trailer claimed a 2025 release is on the cards for the open-world game.</strong></p>



<p>The first trailer was stunning, it was captivating, and it shockingly had a release period. After nearly three minutes of eye-opening action and drama, Ghost of Yotei’s Announce Trailer had a simple message: “2025.”</p>



<p>As of writing, we’ve not heard too much about Ghost of Yotei since. The calendar year is stacked with new games, but Sony’s catalog of hardware-selling goliaths is probably a bit more barren than most would have thought. A delay or a development hiccup could scupper Ghost of Yotei’s 2025 release date, and we’ll update this guide if this is the case.</p>



<p>Also, I’d wager Sucker Punch wants breathing space between Ghost of Yotei and Ubisoft’s Assassin’s Creed Shadows. There are a lot of similarities between both titles, so waiting until Shadows releases is the prudent play.</p>



<p>You can check out the full announcement trailer below—thanks to the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@PlayStation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PlayStation YouTube account</a>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ghost of Yōtei - Announce Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7z7kqwuf0a8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-all-ghost-of-yotei-platforms">All Ghost of Yotei Platforms</h2>



<p><strong>Ghost of Yotei is currently only scheduled to release on PlayStation 5.</strong></p>



<p>There isn’t a PlayStation 4 port scheduled—which makes sense given the supposed scale of the title—but an eyebrow or two might be raised at a lack of a PC launch. Ghost of Tsushima eventually released on PC a few years after its initial debut.</p>



<p>With Sony’s continued philosophy to bring its exclusives to PC after a while, it’s likely Ghost of Yotei will follow in the footsteps of its predecessor and release on PC later on.</p>



<hr>



<p>More Ghost of Yotei information is sure to drop as 2025 progresses. Could the Ghost of Tsushima successor end up being PlayStation’s star attraction this year? Or does Sony need to deliver more exclusive news? </p>



<p>If you are a Ghost of Tsushima fan, check out the latest on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-announces-ghost-of-tsushima-anime/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghost of Tsushima Legends</a>—a fully fledged anime. Plus, look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-playstation-games-coming-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">biggest PlayStation games expected to come out in 2025</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Jersey Betting Bill Could Permit Esports Players to Wager on Themselves]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/esports-betting-players-bet-on-themselves-new-jersey/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-jersey-betting-bill-could-permit-esports-players-to-wager-on-themselves.1126110/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/esports-betting-players-bet-on-themselves-new-jersey/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It has been discovered that a newly proposed bill in the state of New Jersey could allow esports competitors to <strong>wager on themselves and their teams</strong> if successfully implemented. This bill would be integrated alongside new ‘esports-specific skins’ that would permit licensees to offer odds on esports betting markets in the state.</p>



<p>This news comes almost six years after the state’s first legal esports wager was placed at the Borgata Casino in Atlantic City. In 2021, the state opened its doors to esports betting as part of the legal sports betting portfolio in the region, but things are still developing.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-half-the-industry">Half the Industry</h2>



<p>In the most recent edition <a href="https://sharpr.substack.com/p/stake-strikes-viral-gold-with-drake?open=false#%C2%A7nj-bill-will-introduce-esports-specific-skins" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">of the Sharpr newsletter</a>, it was revealed that New Jersey lawmakers are working on a unique bill that would introduce something quite bizarre. If successfully passed, esports competitors (of legal betting age) could bet on (or against…) themselves or their teams.</p>



<p>It’s hard to see how that <strong>couldn’t </strong>go wrong – it’s a recipe for disaster, surely.</p>



<p>In the report from Sharpr, it was claimed that the New Jersey Division of Gaming Enforcement will have the power to authorise venues holding esports events to accept exclusive wagers on the <strong>outcome </strong>of said events.</p>



<p>The primary sponsor of the bill, William Moen, explained that this is a step to ‘capitalise on an emerging industry.’</p>



<p>It’s a relatively well-known fact that esports betting makes up around 50% of the industry’s overall revenue – a substantial sum. Behind esports betting sits merchandising, ticket sales, sponsorships, and broadcast rights, but the esports industry is still not entirely profitable.</p>



<p>Last September, at ESI Lisbon, an expert panel featuring representatives from GRID, Kambi Abios, and BETER expressed that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/growth-of-esports-betting/">billions are being made in wagers</a> and that the esports betting market is no longer ’emerging’, as Moen puts it.</p>



<p>This latest bill proposed in New Jersey seems like a wrong turn, but the state has been at the forefront of esports betting for a while, so there must be some method to the madness.</p>



<p>Admittedly, it’s not the first time something like this has existed. In the past, some sites have offered players the ability to place wagers on themselves in certain games, charging them with completing challenges to receive a payout. That’s entirely different to betting on yourself as a pro esports player in a competitive environment, though.</p>



<p>Have you ever placed a bet on an esports match? Let us know in the comments what the outcome was.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cache-is-returning-to-counter-strike-but-only-once-valve-approves-it-for-cs2/">Cache is coming back to CS2</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>