<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 14:44:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Persona director says making beautiful menus is ‘actually really annoying’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/7/24262357/persona-metaphor-menu-design</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/persona-director-says-making-beautiful-menus-is-%E2%80%98actually-really-annoying%E2%80%99.1002618/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/7/24262357/persona-metaphor-menu-design<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Persona</em> is one of the rare video game series where people actually talk about the menus. They’re functional, sure, but they’re also so incredibly stylish that you almost don’t mind constantly pausing to equip gear or heal your party. So when I had the chance to talk to longtime<em> Persona</em> director Katsura Hashino about his new game, <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em>, which continues this tradition of beautiful menus, I had to ask how they do it.</p><p>The answer, as Hashino explains it, is simply a lot of work:</p><div><blockquote><p>In general, the way most game developers make UI is very simple. That’s what we try to do as well — we try to keep things simple, practical, and usable. But maybe the reason that we’ve achieved both [functionality and beauty] is that we have unique designs that we make for each and every menu. This is actually really annoying to do. We have separate programs running for each of them as well. Whether it’s the shop menu or the main menu, when you open them up there’s a whole separate program running and a separate design that goes into making it. It takes a lot of time.</p></blockquote></div><p>There are elements of craft and experience to it as well. While games like <em>Persona 3</em> had stylish menus, there was a clear evolution in later games as the designs became more elaborate and animated. You can even see a difference between <em>Persona 5</em> and <em>Metaphor</em> (see above).</p><p>Hashino says this is simply a matter of building off of previous work. “How we achieve both of them together is by the know-how that we built up over years,” he says. As an example, <em>Persona 5</em>’s menus feature a lot of angular elements, which initially created issues with legibility. “It was impossible to read at first,” Hashino says, “so we did lots of tweaking and adjusting so it became legible.”</p><p>You can explore <em>Metaphor</em>’s menus — along with the rest of the game — yourself when it launches on October 11th.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Could Saudi Arabia PIF Want Larger Ownership In Nintendo?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/could-saudi-arabia-pif-want-larger-ownership-in-nintendo/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/could-saudi-arabia-pif-want-larger-ownership-in-nintendo.1002612/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/could-saudi-arabia-pif-want-larger-ownership-in-nintendo/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-59902">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Could the Saudi Arabia Public Investment Fund (PIF) buy a larger stake of Nintendo? The fund is certainly considering the possibilities.</p>



<p>In a recent interview with <a href="https://english.kyodonews.net/news/2024/10/71fd22ea510c-saudi-wealth-fund-eyes-raising-stakes-in-nintendo-other-game-firms.html?phrase=Nintendo&amp;words=Nintendo" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Kyodo News</a>, vice chairman Prince Faisal bin Bandar bin Sultan Al-Saud was asked about increasing the PIF’s investment in Japanese games companies, including Nintendo and others. While he said there’s “always a possibility” of it happening, the PIF wouldn’t do it without approval of their partners.</p>



<p>“It’s important to keep the communication going so you get there in the right way,” he told the outlet. “We don’t want to rush into anything.”</p>



<p>The PIF currently owns just under 9% of Nintendo, 8.58% to be exact. The fund also has ownership stake in Nexon, Koei Tecmo, and Capcom. </p>



<p>Insider Gaming has reached out to Nintendo for comment on a possible increase in PIF ownership. As of publishing, no response has been received.</p>



<p>Recently, Saudi Arabia funded the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/breaking-olympic-esports-games-saudi-arabia/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Olympic Esports Games</a> in partnership with the International Olympic Committee. The first of those games will take place in 2025, and is the beginning of a 12-year deal.</p>



<p>What do you think of the Saudi Arabia PIF being interested in increasing its ownership in Nintendo? Join the discussion in the official Insider Gaming Forums.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/undisputed-review-redefining-the-boxing-game-experience/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official review of Undisputed</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-buyouts-reports/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-buyouts-reports/">Ubisoft Acknowledges Recent Buyout Reports</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Ubisoft has acknowledged the recent buyout reports, saying it “regularly reviews options.”</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-moves-to-unreal-engine-5-with-multiple-games-in-development/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-moves-to-unreal-engine-5-with-multiple-games-in-development/">Halo Moves To Unreal Engine 5 With Multiple Games In Development</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Microsoft and Xbox have announced that Halo is moving to Unreal Engine 5 and that there are multiple Halo games in development.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/league-of-legends-smartest-fans-in-gaming/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/league-of-legends-smartest-fans-in-gaming/">League of Legends Has The Smartest Fans In the Industry, Study Reveals</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>In a study, it has been revealed that League of Legends has the most intelligent fans in the gaming industry, closely followed by Black Myth.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-doctor-doom-event-player-count/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-doctor-doom-event-player-count/">5.6 Million Fortnite Players Just Combined Forces to Defeat Doctor Doom</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Fortnite’s Doctor Doom event just pulled in 5.6 million concurrent users, all intent on destroying the Marvel bad guy once and for all.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Undisputed Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/undisputed-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/undisputed-review.1002609/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/undisputed-review<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Boxing fans have gone far too long without a serious contender stepping forward in video gaming. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2011/02/25/fight-night-champion-review">Fight Night Champion</a> is the last true heavyweight in the genre that Punch-Out started, setting the bar high with its weighty focus on realism over a decade ago in 2010. Developer Steel City Interactive's presumptively named Undisputed comes in as the plucky underdog looking to knock the king off its throne, but while it is a split decision in some areas, it is clear the newcomer still needs to put in a bit more time on the speed bag before it can end this particular dispute. </p><p>To its credit, Undisputed does an excellent job of capturing a convincing simulation of what it’s like to rise through the ranks of the boxing world via its Career Mode. As soon as I started, I was impressed by the character customization options. There are dozens of hairstyles, tattoos, and wardrobe options, giving free rein to make an imposing, serious character or try and recreate real-life fighters thanks to its in-depth character model system. You can even make a wacky monstrosity, similar to the WWE 2K series, as the creation center lets you stretch out faces, give big dumbo ears, or rock a green afro akin to a chia pet. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Undisputed - September 2024 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Alongside that visual creativity, Undisputed also features various fighting styles, both from a cosmetic animation and functional gameplay standpoint. Emulate Mike Tyson by creating an offensive-mind bruiser with a Swarmer who focuses on inside power punches, or float like Muhammed Ali by using reach as an Outside Fighter who wears an opponent's health down with speedy jabs while draining their stamina by dodging instead of blocking. </p><p>I created my character centering around defense, using The Wall archetype. While I may have sacrificed stamina and power, the benefit of an improved guard to reduce the damage of incoming blows and a boost to accuracy for landing punches was worth the trade-off. I found this worked out in the long run, but my lack of power and speed, combined with how slow Undisputed fights feel at the start of Career Mode when stats are lower, took some patience. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Fights feel slow at the start of Career Mode when stats are lower.</p></div><p>For my first four fights, my character's stamina was drained after just a few punches, leading to many matches ending by decision. This is the one area in Undisputed where realism can drain my gaming stamina just as fast as my character’s. After two or three matches, I was on the ropes and wishing for a more arcade approach to fights – I really just wanted to knock a fool out for a change. </p><p>Thankfully, Undisputed's approach to setting up each fight was enough to keep me entertained even when the fights themselves didn’t. It follows an RPG approach to negotiating and training for opponents, mirroring how the process occurs in real life. I had control over almost everything, including the challenger I selected (within reason of rankings), how much of the fight's earnings I received, and even the amount of time I was required to spend on social media promoting the bout. </p><p>Successfully negotiating before each contest results in buffs to important features like fame, attribute improvements, and the time you have to spend training. Improving fame means you fight better opponents; Fighting better opponents results in an increase in money you receive and improved stats. You'll need to improve your attributes before getting into these fights, so allocating resources and time is a delicate balance. </p><p>On top of that you have to juggle tasks during the weeks leading up to an event. They can be spent training to get into fight-ready shape, resting to improve stamina and ensure you’re injury-free, or going on social media to reach the required level of promotion needed to fight in the first place. Weight also plays a significant role: Spend too much time on training and resting and you can end up overweight, which would mean the fight won't count – not only will you get less fame and money, but also risk injury for no gain. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Finding the right combo of jabs and power punches was very satisfying. </p></div><p>Finally, managing the contracts of your Coach, Cutman, and Manager is also vital in Undisputed. Each staff member comes with abilities and perks that improve your fighter's attributes, and they grow alongside you with each win. At first, I set out to keep the same manager my whole career in the hopes of forming a bond similar to Rocky and Mickey. However, the further on into my career I got, the pros of sticking with the same team started to fall too far behind the cons. Yes, I lost a few buffs when I had to start with a new coach, but with the extra ability slots – combined with the similar base stats that came alongside the better staff members – I could recruit with my higher notoriety, and that made it easy to replace the original team as Career Mode went on. Being offered increasingly meaningful benefits to kick my loyal crew to the curb made that decision more of a chin-scratcher.</p><p>Back in the ring with those improved stats allowing me to be more active, it didn't take too many fights for me to appreciate the flow and rhythm of Undisputed's combat. Figuring out the right combination of quick jabs and power punches and the chess match of attacking the body or the head depending on the opponent's weaknesses and guard was very satisfying. Just like in real life, damage adds up and plays a vital role in fights. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Consistently aim for one side of the head with a solid combination of jabs or powerful hook shots, and nasty cuts or swollen eyes will appear. Not only do these affect stats like accuracy, but they can also lead to technical knockouts (TKOs), where the referee stops the fight. However, the more I played Undisputed, the more I found these mechanics lacking when directly compared to the 14-year-old Fight Night Champions. </p><p>In that game there are a handful of different types of cuts, bruises, and swelling. Between each round, there is also a cutman minigame that, when done successfully, gives an extra stat boost to the fighter's health and wear-and-tear. Comparatively, Undisputed's wear-down features are limited to the same three swelling, cuts, and bruises in every fight, which gets repetitive quickly. There's also no cutman minigame or interaction between each round to break up the routine.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The lack of minigames leading up to fights is a missed opportunity.</p></div><p>The lack of minigames in the lead-up to fights is also a missed opportunity. Instead of automating every training boost, adding an option to hit the speed bag or work on defensive skills manually that can be applied to in-ring action would have been a helpful way to prepare. That is a standard tutorial method in sports games like <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-fc-25-review">EA Sports FC 25</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nba-2k25-review">NBA 2K25</a>, so I was disappointed this wasn't in Undisputed. </p><p>In fact, the only minigame that Undisputed does include is ridiculously hard – though to be fair, it shouldn’t be too easy to get up when someone has knocked you on your back. When your fighter is down you have to press and focus the right and left triggers to line up with green bars to make the count. The issue is the bars are located in different spots, so it’s a little like trying to rub your head and belly simultaneously to make your fingers do different things with precision. Improving stats like Heart doesn’t do anything to make this minigame any easier, either. It’s mostly a problem on higher difficulties, especially after I struggled to get up after going down twice while my opponent got to his feet after being knocked down seven times. </p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><p><h3>Andrew's Favorite Boxing/Fighting Games</h3></p></div><p>While the gameplay is fast and fun when fighting with better boxers, it’s not all that pretty to watch in motion, and in these ways it’s still considerably behind where the Fight Night series left off. Knockdowns and rising animations are identical each time, featuring about as much personality and variation as its commentary team. While I appreciate that Steel City Interactive got pros like Todd Grisham and Johnny Nelson to comment on fights, their descriptions of the action rarely matched what was occurring in the ring. They also had terrible memories: One moment they’d call it an even-sided round, only to make a polar-opposite statement about how my character was dominating a few seconds later as the bell rang. It sounds like they’ve taken a few too many blows to the head. </p><p>Dizzying camera angles and cornermen standing at ringside popping into the frame and blocking the fight also made for some pretty frustrating moments. While those are minor, I certainly felt my immersion slipping away when I'd get near the ropes and end up feeling like I was stuck behind a tall guy in the movie theaters mid-match.</p><p>Multiplayer is enjoyable, but be ready to run into the usual players who won’t choose anyone but the most powerful characters, Muhammad Ali and Canelo Alvarez. With nothing to balance them out online, those fights don’t have the variety they should. Your best bet is to play with friends or hope to find an opponent that wants to fight with evenly matched fighters. Otherwise, you’ll end up frustrated facing The Great One every time – which feels like the modern-day equivalent of fighting OddJob in GoldenEye.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Great God Grove launches November 15 for Xbox Series, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/great-god-grove-launches-november-15-for-xbox-series-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/great-god-grove-launches-november-15-for-xbox-series-switch-and-pc.1002606/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/great-god-grove-launches-november-15-for-xbox-series-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>It's the end of the world as we know it.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Fellow Traveller [30 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/fellow-traveller">Fellow Traveller</a> and developer <a title="Companies > LimboLane [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/limbolane">LimboLane</a> will release <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,799 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Great God Grove [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/great-god-grove">Great God Grove</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,205 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,145 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,406 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2840190/Great_God_Grove/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on November 15, the companies <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2840190/view/4663005043150333910" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-919835"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of teh game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2840190/Great_God_Grove/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>It’s the end of the world, and everyone’s favorite god has gone crazy!</p><p>Once in a generation, the gods come together to postpone the apocalypse. But this time, it’s HEAVENLY CHAOS!! The once-beloved god of communication started a bunch of godly fights and then went awol. With King missing and the gods in disarray, who’s gonna save the world from A-POCKY-LIPS???</p><p><strong>Wield the Trusty Megapon</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>As the gods’ new mail-carrier, suck up lines of dialogue with your mail-cannon and launch them back to solve puzzles.</p><p><strong>Meet 60 Characters</strong></p><p>Listen to their woes and wonders, then deliver key messages to solve their problems—or just to see how they’ll react!</p><p><strong>Discover Bizarre Gods???</strong></p><p>The god of TEAMWORK? The god of LOVE SONGS? Jeez, who’s in charge around here…?</p><p>You may be ready for:</p><ul><li>A big colorful world with eight weird gods!</li><li>Third and first-person gameplay</li><li>Tons of areas to explore</li></ul><p>But are you also ready for:</p><ul><li>Godly crushes?</li><li>Pumpkin fights??</li><li>Puppets <a title="Genres > Cooking [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/cooking">cooking</a>???</li></ul><p>AND YOU’RE NOT READY FOR:</p><ul><li>Grovekeeping!</li><li>Godbossing!!</li><li>THE END OF THE WORLD AS WE KNOW IT!!!!!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="GREAT GOD GROVE Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fxYga_HqQis?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney Fans, Look Here: Lego Disney Camera Set Is On Sale Right Now For A Great Price]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-fans-look-here-lego-disney-camera-set-is-on-sale-right-now-for-a-great-price/1100-6526947/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-fans-look-here-lego-disney-camera-set-is-on-sale-right-now-for-a-great-price.1002600/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-fans-look-here-lego-disney-camera-set-is-on-sale-right-now-for-a-great-price/1100-6526947/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526947">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Amazon's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">Prime Big Deal Days</a> officially begins on October 8, but plenty of retailers have already rolled out their own counter-programming to compete with Amazon, including Target. The retailer is now selling the Lego Disney Walt Disney Tribute camera for a pretty sweet deal.</p><p>Target Circle members (<a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.target.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F81938%2F2092%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fl%2Ftarget-circle%2F-%2FN-pzno9&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdisney-fans-look-here-lego-disney-camera-set-is-on-sale-right-now-for-a-great-price%2F1100-6526947%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">sign up for free here</a>) can score the set for $69.59, which is a nice markdown from its normal $87 price point. For comparison, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Building-Celebrate-Collectible-Builders/dp/B0BXQ7LGB2?tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon still has it for the full price</a>.</p><p>The Lego Disney Walt Disney Tribute Camera set is aimed at adults and comes with 811 pieces that you'll assemble to create a vintage-style camera. It also has a hinged back panel with a film strip showcasing stills from 20 classic Disney movies. What's more, it comes with a director's clapperboard with space for three Lego Disney minifgures. The set also includes a working crank and multiple lenses.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379843-screenshot2024-10-07at10.22.15am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4379843" data-ratio="0.58179959100205" data-width="978" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379843-screenshot2024-10-07at10.22.15am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4379843"></a><figcaption>The Lego Disney Tribute Camera is a nice set for Disney fans</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379843-screenshot2024-10-07at10.22.15am.png"></figure><figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379845-screenshot2024-10-07at10.22.21am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379846-screenshot2024-10-07at10.22.26am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379847-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.03am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379848-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.12am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379849-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.24am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379850-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.30am.png" data-ref-id="1300-4379845,1300-4379846,1300-4379847,1300-4379848,1300-4379849,1300-4379850" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4379845-screenshot2024-10-07at10.22.21am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4379846-screenshot2024-10-07at10.22.26am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4379847-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.03am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4379848-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.12am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4379849-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.24am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/1179/11799911/4379850-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.30am.png"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379845-screenshot2024-10-07at10.22.21am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379846-screenshot2024-10-07at10.22.26am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379847-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.03am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379848-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.12am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379849-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.24am.png,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4379850-screenshot2024-10-07at10.23.30am.png"></figure><p>If Disney isn't your thing, Target is also offering<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/target-circle-week-includes-deals-on-rarely-discounted-lego-sets/1100-6526935/" data-ref-id="1100-6526935"> 30% off more rarely discounted Lego sets</a> from franchises like Mario, Star Wars, and Marvel. And if you're not a Lego person at all and prefer Mega Bloks, well, there are plenty of deals to be had this week, too, in the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/official-xbox-360-building-set-gets-substantial-discount-for-target-circle-week/1100-6526936/" data-ref-id="1100-6526936">Mega Blok Xbox 360 set</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/retro-pokemon-mega-bloks-target-circle-week/1100-6526933/" data-ref-id="1100-6526933">Pokemon retro sets.</a></p><p>For more on Target's big deals, check out <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.target.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F81938%2F2092%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fl%2Ftarget-circle-week%2F-%2FN-7196o&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdisney-fans-look-here-lego-disney-camera-set-is-on-sale-right-now-for-a-great-price%2F1100-6526947%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">all the deals</a>, including <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fhowl.me%2FcnffwAOPj4y%3Fu1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdisney-fans-look-here-lego-disney-camera-set-is-on-sale-right-now-for-a-great-price%2F1100-6526947%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">B2G1 free books</a> and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.target.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F81938%2F2092%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fpl%2F8675-843436260816795%3Fmarketing_id%3D8675-843436260816795&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Fdisney-fans-look-here-lego-disney-camera-set-is-on-sale-right-now-for-a-great-price%2F1100-6526947%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">deals on toys and games.</a> Keep checking back with GameSpot for more deals in the days ahead.</p><h3 dir="ltr"><strong>More Prime Big Deal Days Early Deals</strong></h3><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-ps5-prime-big-deal-days-deals/2900-5816/">PlayStation Deals - PS5 Games, Accessories, Books, and More</a></li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-nintendo-switch-prime-big-deal-days-deals/2900-5817/">Nintendo Switch Deals - Games, Collectibles, and More</a></li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/official-nintendo-hoodies-are-20-off-ahead-of-amazons-prime-big-deal-days-sale/2900-5838/">Retro Nintendo Hoodies</a></li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/super-mario-and-zelda-official-t-shirts-discounted-for-prime-big-deal-days/2900-5832/">Super Mario and The Legend of Zelda T-Shirts</a></li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/lego-set-prime-big-deal-days-amazon-deals/2900-5823/">Lego Set Deals - Super Mario, Batman, Marvel, and More</a></li></ul><h3 dir="ltr"><strong>More Prime Big Deal Days Nintendo Sales</strong></h3><ul><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-nintendo-switch-prime-big-deal-days-deals/2900-5817/">Nintendo Switch Game &amp; Accessory Deals</a></li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/official-nintendo-hoodies-are-20-off-ahead-of-amazons-prime-big-deal-days-sale/2900-5838/">Retro Nintendo Hoodies (Officially Licensed)</a></li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/super-mario-and-zelda-official-t-shirts-discounted-for-prime-big-deal-days/2900-5832/">The Legend of Zelda &amp; Super Mario T-Shirts</a></li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/animal-crossing-fans-can-get-cute-lego-playsets-for-lowest-prices-yet/1100-6524782/">Animal Crossing Lego Sets</a></li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-mighty-bowser-lego-super-mario-set-gets-very-rare-discount-at-amazon/1100-6526848/">Lego Super Mario - Bowser Sets</a></li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-super-mario-piranha-plant-drops-to-best-price-yet-at-amazon/1100-6526845/">Lego Super Mario Piranha Plant</a></li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/legos-nes-and-crt-tv-model-kit-discounted-alongside-even-better-lego-mario-deals/1100-6526872/">Lego Nintendo Entertainment System</a></li><li dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/lego-set-prime-big-deal-days-amazon-deals/2900-5823/">Lego Super Mario Playsets</a></li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526926&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-5440-page-complete-history-of-middle-earth-drops-to-best-price-of-the-year\/1100-6526926\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526917&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ps5-console-exclusive-game-deals-amazon-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526917\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526914&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/meet-the-halo-fan-who-built-a-life-size-warthog-in-his-garage\/1100-6526914\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-complete-calvin-and-hobbes-is-on-sale-for-best-price-in-years-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526922\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526930&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/marvels-spider-man-2-on-sale-for-big-discount-for-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526930\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526928&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dragon-ball-super-limited-edition-steelbook-collection-crunchyroll-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526928\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526936&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/official-xbox-360-building-set-gets-substantial-discount-for-target-circle-week\/1100-6526936\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526915&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dragon-age-the-veilguard-has-gone-gold\/1100-6526915\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526919&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/silent-hill-2-global-launch-times-revealed\/1100-6526919\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526921&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-long-is-silent-hill-2-remake-playthrough-times-for-all-play-styles\/1100-6526921\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526804&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/game-of-thrones-books-box-set-house-of-the-dragon-prime-big-deal-days\/1100-6526804\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526900&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ubisofts-effort-to-save-star-wars-outlaws-continues-with-huge-patch\/1100-6526900\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526851&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/baldurs-gate-3-best-characters-are-now-dungeons-dragons-miniatures\/1100-6526851\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526861&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/atlus-rpgs-get-massive-price-cuts-ahead-of-metaphor-refantazios-release\/1100-6526861\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526850&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-pokemon-squishmallow-plushes-are-now-available-including-a-holiday-pikachu\/1100-6526850\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526906&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/metal-gears-david-hayter-seemingly-teasing-new-performance-as-snake\/1100-6526906\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6516719&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/baldurs-gate-3-dribbles-the-clown-guide\/1100-6516719\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526901&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-halo-tabletop-wargame-is-up-for-preorder-at-amazon-releases-this-month\/1100-6526901\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/metaphor-refantazio-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-review.1002585/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/metaphor-refantazio-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/07/metaphor-refantazio-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Metaphor: ReFantazio Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Nic Bunce">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2024-10-07">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2024-10-07">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Imagine a world where their vision of a perfect society is actually what we have today. What kind of culture and history would such a society have? Taking a step further than that, what if we were playing out a fantasy that fantasises about our ‘utopia’? That is the self-eating serpent at the centre of Metaphor: ReFantazio.</p>
<p><iframe title="Metaphor: ReFantazio — Story Trailer | Xbox Series X|S, Windows PC" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f5IWiqGKcQg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Kingdom of Euchronia is a world of kings and magic, curses and dragons, all put together by a supergroup team of extremely talented designers and artists at Studio Zero. Having spun out from Atlus’ P-Studio with long-time Persona director Katsura Hashino at the helm, and bringing fresh influences like Koda Kazuma (NieR Automata) and Ikuto Yamashita (Neon Genesis Evangelion) into the fold, you know you’re in for a treat.</p>


<p>In terms of atmosphere, the team’s design pedigree absolutely shines. Euchronian society is split into eight main tribes plus your persecuted ninth tribe. The eight tribes have distinct features, from big ears or shiny eyes, to basically being a bat- or dog-person. The less ‘human’ tribes are at the bottom of a fierce hierarchy, put in place by a corrupt (and frankly evil) state church, and used for inhumane experiments for magical devices that prop up the kingdom’s economy. You are part of an exiled ninth tribe, persecuted by the church and such a rarity that most people thought you just a myth.</p>
<p>The king on the board is merely a puppet of the church until he is murdered in the intro by the game’s antagonist, Count Louis. That’s when all hell breaks loose.</p>


<p>The villain of the piece is exactly as evil as he sounds, and is hell-bent on releasing Humans into society to wreak havoc in his quest for the throne. In Metaphor, Humans are tremendously powerful beasts, lifted straight out of Hieronymus Bosch’s The Garden of Earthly Delights. Any semblance of humanity is long since gone, and they are now city-wrecking monsters. With Louis trying to burn down society with the help of the Humans, your mission is to create a utopia is one where all are born equal, there is no religious persecution and the church holds no sway over life and politics.</p>
<p>It’s never that simple though, is it? The game is incredibly nuanced in its themes, and explores the darker themes very well. It doesn’t hold back from bloodshed, gore or swearing for that matter — which makes sense considering that the vast majority of its population is seemingly British. God help anyone who doesn’t speak Scouse…</p>

<p>Metaphor: ReFantazio builds on the classic systems that you’d expect from a Persona-like, with some notable improvements. The friendship-simulator side of the game, where you need to become besties with all of your followers to unlock their ultimate powers, no longer relies on perfect answers and stalls progress if you get it wrong. Instead, a perfect answer simply nets you bonus magical currency.</p>
<p>Similarly, we have all the Virtue system, cooking, side quests, dungeon crawls and turn-based combat that you would expect from a game with the name Atlus slapped on the side of it. If anything, combat is tighter and more tactical than any of the Persona games, and Metaphor really shines for this.</p>
<p>A huge part of this brilliance is the Archetype system. Once each character awakens to their natural archetype (their Persona, basically), they can teach it to the rest of the team. This means that rather than swapping to Inari to use ice-based Magic as in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/11/01/persona-5-tactica-preview-phantom-thieving-the-strategy-rpg-genre/">Persona 5</a>, you can simply make anyone and everyone be a mage with ice-based attacks. On top of this, once a character learns an ability, each other archetype they have unlocked can ‘inherit’ this skill for a fee.</p>

<p>All of this costs resources, of course, but the versatility this brings to combat is exceptional. The Synthesis system, where multiple party members attack together, based on the archetypes they currently wield, makes this combat system all the deeper. This is genuinely a 10/10 game if gameplay were the only metric.</p>
<p>This brings us to the sound design, which is eerily Uematsu-y. Indeed, you could easily be forgiven for thinking the famed Final Fantasy composer worked on this game, with familiar sounding motifs cropping up throughout. Music that gives you existential dread? Very similar. Dungeon stuff? Very similar. Boss fights? Very similar. It’s not quite fair to say that homework has been borrowed, but they clearly sat in the same proverbial classroom, possibly right next to each other, when doing their assignment.</p>
<p>While Persona is praised for its sound design, Metaphor went in exact opposite thematic direction, but to equal success. It is an absolute treat to listen to and you will quickly find yourself humming the music long after you’ve turned the game off.</p>

<p>For all this praise, Metaphor is less than perfect, falling down in a couple of areas.</p>
<p>The main offender lies in explaining the game’s more complex systems. The aforementioned inheritance mechanic is poorly explained, and it’s not until you’re a dozen hours in that you start to actually make use of it. Similarly, by the third city I had maxed out one of my friendships, with a message saying Strohl (the character) is ready for a new Heroic Embodiment. I had to reach the endgame — another 30 or so hours — before I learned what that actually meant, an explainer seemingly failing to pop up for me.</p>
<p>There are also graphics and optimisation issues. The game looks stunning from afar, thanks in no small part to the character and world design, but if you look closely there are myriad issues, including textures and — in one case — a character’s teeth being outside their mouth. We’ve also experienced a couple of issues with the game slowing down and a single crash on PS5. While these parts of the game feel particularly rushed, they’re at least things that are fixable in a future patch.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Metaphor ReFantazio is sublime. Persona fans will have an absolute blast playing this, and hunting out the subtle (and not-so-subtle) nods to its franchise cousin. A couple of minor annoyances make it feel a little rough around the edges hold it back from an otherwise perfect score.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>The best Persona-like game on the market</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Incredible battle systems</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Gorgeous art and sound design</li>
														
								<li><i></i>A genuinely morish story that is hard to put down</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>A few quality-of-life issues are drastically needed</li>
														
								<li><i></i>A graphics and optimisation patch wouldn’t go amiss</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio Review – Persona Non Grata]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/metaphor-refantazio-persona-non-grata/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-review-%E2%80%93-persona-non-grata.1002582/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/metaphor-refantazio-persona-non-grata/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
				<main>

					

					<!--<div class="ads-container banner-ad floated p-0">
						<div data-pg-ad-spot='div-gpt-ad-wccftechcom38564' style="min-height: 280px;"></div>
					</div>-->
					
										<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>Metaphor: ReFantazio</h5><p><span>October 11th, 2024</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, PC</span>
						</p></div></div></div>
					<p><span>For most casual players of recent years, invoking the name Atlus has typically been synonymous with the Persona series. One of Director Katsura Hashino’s breakout series, this offshoot of the Shin Megami Tensei franchise has grown to be one of the most stylish and compelling Japanese RPGs of recent years. Has the team at Atlus finally broken out of their mold, or is Metaphor: ReFantazio just the same game with a new mask?</span></p>
<p><span>Metaphor: ReFantazio opens with a tease of modern-day life and settings before whisking the player away into an isekai, or alternative world, within a book written about conflict and subterfuge. None the wiser of the greater story, players assume the role of a blue-haired young chap whose end goal is to subvert the election process to install a new king and instead bring a young, cursed prince to power whom most assume to be dead. Along this journey, the prince’s proxy competes to determine the rightful heir to the throne through a popular vote. How might one determine their standing in a world without ballot boxes or broad communication? By way of a floating moon in the sky adorned with the king’s visage. One empty eye socket reveals a number of faces representing the twenty or so most qualified candidates; the larger their faces appear, the wider the margin of the vote they’ve captured. Monolithic statues also appear across the various cities in Metaphor: ReFantazio allowing those on the distant reaches of the continent to still be aware of who their next ruler may be.</span></p>
<p><span>While the latter Persona titles dealt more with the psyche of human nature and Jung’s theory, Metaphor: ReFantazio presents the problems in the world in a much more overt nature, with racism running rampant in a world filled with various races and castes. The player hero has the unfortunate curse of being born as an Elda, a subrace that’s ostracized for the powerful magic and heretical views they hold. Because of this, the player and main character alike suffer an uphill battle against the inherent racism of nearly every other race and character in the Kingdom of Euchronia. The word human itself is taboo, with those humans being presented as grotesque monsters that draw direct inspiration from Hieronymus Bosch’s paintings. Inspired by may be too light of a phrasing, as many of the bosses and larger foes are one-for-one copies of one fresco of the Garden of Earthly Delights. Shin Megami Tensei has largely revolved around the various mythologies and religions of the world, so it’s intriguing to see a monster designer draw upon works not often cited in gaming. If you long for the likes of Mothman and other common Shin Megami Tensei beasts, players can research the Summoner class, which can invoke them as combat spells.</span></p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Metaphor_Screen_Mage_Fire-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p><span>The combat to Metaphor: ReFantazio should be instantly familiar to those who have dipped their toes into at least one Shin Megami Tensei title in the past decade. Turns are taking one side at a time, with characters ranked by their Speed stat to determine order. Typically, one character on either side will provide the entire team with a Press Turn icon when it’s their turn to take action, so it’s important to dispatch weaker peons before tackling the main boss. As with Shin Megami Tensei V, the effectiveness of an attack determines how many Press Turn icons are used for a given attack. A basic attack consumes one turn, while striking an enemy’s weakness or inflicting a critical hit will consume half the amount of icons. Likewise, dodging, blocking, or repelling an attack will consume twice as many icons and this goes both ways. If you can predict what an enemy’s main element will be, players can change their given Archetype or equip an accessory that might nullify that particular element. Towards the end of Elda’s journey, players can find a unique hat for the protagonist that yields an additional Press Turn icon or purchase accessories that allow a player to dodge an attack and deplete all of the enemy’s icons at once, but these won’t be in players hands until approaching the finish line.</span></p>
<p><span>Social Links have been a core component of the modern Persona series, presenting a physical manifestation of the trust between the main character and a chosen ally, whether they’re actively in the combat party or merely an outside observer. These systems play out identically to their Persona counterparts, with spending time with a given supporter yielding an additional rank and typically some form of passive boon for the Archetype that they provide the player. The system at play here has been largely simplified, with no time spent with a Follower yielding anything less than a rank-up. Gone are the days of having to take someone out for a burger two or three times before their Social Link increases. Instead, players will routinely have to pass a passive skill check based on their Royal Virtues before they can spend time with a given supporter. There is a handy menu that players can bring up at any time to quickly see which supporters are ready to take things to the next level and selecting them will instantly teleport the player into speaking distance. Many of these events will require additional criteria, such as speaking to a party member while traveling to another city or speaking to them in the evening versus the day. At each passing phase of the day, Gallica, the fairy that follows the player around during their journey, will offer a hint and let players telepathically communicate and hear the wishes of one who wishes to confide in the player.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>To my chagrin, Metaphor: ReFantazio still features a limited window to proceed with the adventure through another calendar system. Players only have a limited number of days to seek the crown, and every action they do, whether it’s spending time with a confidant, reading a book, hitting the battle coliseum for fame and glory, and so on, consumes one-half of a given day. Suppose Morgana’s persistent nagging to go to sleep after exploring a Palace in Persona 5 annoyed you. In that case, you’ll have no quarter from Gallica doing the same thing after venturing into a dungeon in the daytime. Because of this, dungeons in Metaphor: ReFantazio are better suited to be tackled in a single day without taking return trips. MP is still a finite resource with very few ways to recover it outside of consumable items or leaving the dungeon to catch some shut-eye, but there are a few ways to exploit the system to the player’s benefit. The easiest is to convert the player back into a Mage Archetype and attack enemies on the open field or pass turns in combat, both provide a minimal (3-8 MP) recovery but enough to push forward if the player spends enough time grinding.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>I touched upon this briefly before, but the Archetype system sets Metaphor: ReFantazio apart from the Shin Megami Tensei counterparts despite both sharing similar DNA. Rather than being locked to a single arcana or Persona, each party member in Metaphor: ReFantazio draws from the same pool of Archetypes and can be equipped with a given class. These Archetypes change everything from the character’s weapon, elemental strengths/weaknesses, and even bonuses to core stats, both positive and negative. If you want to run a team of four Mages or Gunners in the back row, that’s entirely up to you. Each character levels up a given Archetype independently, and it’s almost always worth it to pick up as many levels as possible, as nearly every skill acquired in a given Archetype can be carried forward into another. This feeds into the Follower system, with advanced ranks of each Archetype being unlockable and increasing the number of skills that can be carried forward into a given class.</span></p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Metaphor_Screen_Boss_Homo_Fulquilo.jpg"></a></figure>

<p><span>If there’s one negative aspect to the Archetype system, it’s that it feels largely in line with the same trappings of characters in Final Fantasy VII. By giving every party member the same tools, it homogenizes the party with the only real difference between characters being their innate stats and growth. Given Archetypes dictate what type of weapon a given character can wield, that further reduces how much agency players have in creating distinctly different characters. As such, it comes down to the individual’s proclivity for role-playing and pushing characters into certain roles. If you want to turn the elven knight Hulkenberg into a glass cannon mage or give the main character a massive two-handed axe, that’s entirely your own story to write in Metaphor: ReFantazio.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>No matter how much I engaged with the core fundamentals of Metaphor: ReFantazio, I couldn’t escape the feeling that this was largely Persona 6 by another name rather than some new IP that could stand on its own merits. That isn’t to say that Hashino’s team hasn’t created another stylish JRPG with broad appeal, but the premise that Metaphor: ReFantazio is a brand-new fantasy is dead. If the Persona series left you wanting more, Metaphor: ReFantazio certainly is a tale worth experiencing for yourself.</span></p>
<p><em>Reviewed on PS5 (code provided by the publisher).</em></p>

					
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>


					

<p>Those who harbor an innate distaste for the social systems and time limits of modern Persona titles will find no solace here, but those who are willing to embrace what very well could be the sixth Persona title in all but name alone will experience one of the most stylish Japanese roleplaying games of 2024.</p>

<div>
		<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Pros</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>The main battle theme (and many other tracks) are certified bops
</li><li>Customize the Archetypes and roles of every party member, not just the protagonist
</li><li>Regicide difficulty yields new challenges and a very difficult New Game+ experience
</li><li>Akio Otsuka as a weird little bat guy
</li><li>More narrative twists than an M. Night Shyamalan film
</li><li>Players can rewind a fight back to its beginning if they get dealt a bad hand
</li><li>The Traveller's Voice system lets players see what other folks chose on a given day if they can't decide on how to spend an afternoon</li>		</ul>
	</div>
			<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Cons</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>The narrative does little to distance itself from being a high fantasy version of Persona
</li><li>Homogenization of the Archetype system
</li><li>Constrained calendar system means players need to finish dungeons in a single day in order to pass the deadline at times
</li><li>Ailments, such as Anxiety, can be debilitating
</li><li>Limited income for most of the adventure unless players can exploit certain abilities</li>		</ul>
	</div>
	</div>


<p>The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>
					
				</main>
			</article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio Review - The Persona Formula Perfected]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/metaphor-refantazio-review-persona-formula-perfected</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-review-the-persona-formula-perfected.1002579/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/metaphor-refantazio-review-persona-formula-perfected<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em><a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="b8a354ce-036e-42d0-8cec-f33b5c8c36f1" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/metaphor-refantazio-preview-worthy-of-atlus-35th-anniversary">Metaphor: ReFantazio</a> </em>is the latest RPG/life-simulation title from Atlus where the player takes on the role of a protagonist swept into a grand plot that could lead about to the end of the world. While <em>Metaphor </em>does share a lot of gameplay elements with titles like <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="83c1dc81-53b4-48e1-a653-843f76d41389" href="https://techraptor.net/games/shin-megami-tensei-v"><em>SMT </em></a>and <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="449301ab-37d8-4de3-90e4-ee04edbde40f" href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/persona-5-review-stylish-substance"><em>Persona </em></a>it's in the added scope of story and quality-of-life improvements that might make this the best of them all.</p>
<h2>The Tournament Of The Throne</h2>
<p>The story of <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> explodes out the gate. Within the first few hours, the protagonist finds himself in the capital city and enlisted into the army, has fought a demonic-looking 'Human' in a training fort, and has returned with plans to interrupt the funeral of the recently deceased king in a hope to flush out his murderer and bring the king killer to justice.&nbsp;</p>
<p>This plan is immediately thrown into chaos as the magic of the deceased King appears to inform the people of the country that the next king will be decided through what is essentially a popularity contest. With his magic protecting all major candidates from assassination for the integrity of the Tournament of the Throne the protagonist is forced to put his name into the ring and journey the world to compete.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-injustice-of-the-world.jpg?itok=oTL97-AW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-injustice-of-the-world.jpg?itok=cUzo2O_S 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>From the first moment you reach the capital you're made immediately aware of how grim many aspects of this world is</figcaption></figure><p>Starting off so strong <em>Metaphor </em>will immediately pull the players into the story, which is very important when they'll likely know they're staring down the barrel of an 80+ hour game. Once you're past that intro the Tournament continues to be an entertaining overarching story while the in-between moments are filled with location-specific plot lines and spending time with your Followers.</p>
<h2>Explore The World In Search Of Purpose</h2>
<p>Even while the deadline of the overarching plot was looming I was getting drawn into each of the different side-quests and stories. Whether that be something as simple as visiting a hot spring or needing to enter a nearby dungeon to stop the threat of an undead entity, you don't just get to learn how unique each location is, but also how unjust the world is.</p>
<p>The story structure of the Tournament, mixed with the day-to-day plot of the game, reminds me a lot of the story of <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ad74aac8-414b-4cf7-96b2-7e8a8f9cb11e" href="https://techraptor.net/games/persona-5-strikers"><em>Persona 5 Strikers</em></a>. Following the protagonist and his every growing party is a lot like the Phantom Thieves road trip. Where <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> perfects this process is through the incredible world-building of each stop along the journey.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-world-map.jpg?itok=CUrNNn8T 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-world-map.jpg?itok=fRDVOyO4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Instead of being based in a single city you'll find yourself travelling all across the world as part of the Tournament of the Throne</figcaption></figure><p>Each new town will offer insights into how the people live, the extremely complicated relationships that each of the races have with one another, and opportunities to learn about the history of the land. Even the little gameplay moments like ranking up your Tolerance stat would come in the form of a masked Mustari person teaching you their history and making the world feel more real.</p>
<p>New followers and party members being added as you visit these new regions also help to create interesting and grounded stories. Every person has their own tragedy that you get to work with as you grow closer to them, not only fleshing them out further as three-dimensional characters but also providing gameplay benefits in the form of new abilities.</p>
<h2>You Have Four Months, The Clock Is Ticking</h2>
<p><em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> uses a day system where each major event in the story will happen on a certain day. Each of these events will work as a deadline that you'll be constantly reminded of, but all of the time up to that point you have to spend doing what you want.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-calendar.jpg?itok=yEDzwrB_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-calendar.jpg?itok=4J87IdW- 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The five-day week calendar might be strange, but keeps you on pace for the four-month clock until the end of the game</figcaption></figure><p>Each day you can take two actions, in the afternoon or evening, or dive into any of the dungeons that are present in the world. On a day when you visit a dungeon or engage in combat, you won't be able to do something in the evening, but there's plenty to do while traveling on your Gauntlet Runner so you can still make progress.</p>
<p>Outside of spending time with your companions you can also go shopping, visit the other cities of the world, and pick up a variety of quests. There are also a variety of date-based shops to investigate including weekly deals and items that are exchanged daily.</p>
<h2>Overworld Dungeon Combat Adds Efficiency</h2>
<p>The meat of the gameplay is in dungeon exploration and combat. The world of <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> is filled with unique dungeons, each normally filled with two separate objectives tied to progressing your relationships with your Followers, or just completing a quest or hunt.</p>
<p>Combat can take place in two different scenarios. The first of which takes place in the overworld, approaching enemies you can slash at them with quick attacks. If you're a high enough level this can lead to you finishing combat before it even begins, if not though it's your chance to stun your opponents and enter turn-based combat with an advantage.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-dungeon-exploration.jpg?itok=prnPrVCi 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-dungeon-exploration.jpg?itok=7agNn5qj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Rush through dungeons and when you're strong enough smacking enemies is enough</figcaption></figure><p>Turn-based combat is as you'd expect. Taking it in turns you'll move through your party dealing out special attacks and elemental abilities. <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> uses the same turn counter system from Shin Megami Tensei, starting each round you'll have as many turns as you have characters. Dealing critical hits or exploiting weaknesses will add an additional turn counter while having an enemy dodge or repel your attack will lead you to lose additional turns.</p>
<p>This style of turn-based combat is still my favorite, pushing you to really exploit weaknesses and alter your setup as you enter new areas. It also means for any of the incredibly tough boss fights if you do fail you have nearly limitless potential to respec your team and reapproach the fight.</p>
<p>For a title as long as it is I thoroughly appreciated the ability to essentially 'skip' combat when you were powerful enough, I did feel like the threshold for when combat would occur on the overworld only was a bit tough to reach. I would appreciate when I could get through combat quickly and understand when combat was against a tough enemy, but there was a strange limbo period in the middle that would mean I'd get pulled into turn-based combat, but it would only take a round or so of combat to complete it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-turn-system.jpg?itok=_dH8PMC6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-turn-system.jpg?itok=QLC9OJWL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Plan your attacks wisely to be able to capitalize no only on damage, but earn more turns</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> Archetypes Allow Limitless Possibilities</h2>
<p>Each character's prowess in battle is based upon their stats along with what Archetype they have equipped to them. The Archetypes are this game's equivalent of the Demons or the Persona. Each Archetype has a different theme, such as Knight, Warrior, or Brawler, and with that comes access to a variety of different active and passive abilities.</p>
<p>With each battle won you'll not only be leveling up the party members, but also their Archetype. Leveling up Archetypes can then give you access to more powerful Archetypes, this can be in the form of a linear evolution or into a completely different Archetype Tree.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-archetype-map.jpg?itok=G7JUMTKk 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-archetype-map.jpg?itok=nU3B8DmC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Plenty of relationships to make and Archetypes to unlock</figcaption></figure><p>There is incredible freedom in the Archetype system because of two factors. The first of which is that each party member can use any Archetype as long as they have enough points in it, the second factor is that with each Archetype you have active you can also equip skills from any of the other Archetypes that the character has previously unlocked.</p>
<p>In a single character, you can choose between over thirty different Archetypes, with a core set of abilities, and abilities from other Archetypes giving you unique combinations, powerful damaging attacks, or passive buffs. Even while leveling up one Archetype path I was constantly considering the different ways that their abilities could synergize with another.</p>
<h2>Improving The Formula</h2>
<p>As you already know from my review if you're a long-time player of <em>SMT </em>or <em>Persona </em>titles there's a lot here that's going to be immediately understood by you. Spending time with Followers to improve their rankings, familiar combat system, leveling up stand-like abilities to unlock further powers, etc</p>
<p>What <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> does that's so amazing is add a wave of quality of life improvements to all of them to allow them to pack as much into this game as possible, but for it to never feel tedious.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-follower-level-up.jpg?itok=XMlrSW9P 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-follower-level-up.jpg?itok=m3GbDHFb 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>From this screen you can not only see what abilities your Followers will gain but leap to them immediately</figcaption></figure><p>Followers rank up based on your Protagonist's social stats and the timeline of the game and when they're ready to rank up there is a clear indication of it. If your Follower is ready to rank up but you don't have a skill the game will even let you know which one to work on. Once you're ready that same menu will take you right to the Follower.</p>
<p>This ease of movement also extends to the different quests you'll take on, getting to move from city to city with ease, and even navigating within the cities itself.</p>
<p>Overleveled combat occurring on the overworld is a reward to those who like to over-prepare, not punishing you for being powerful but instead giving you the fun sensation of showing off that power.</p>
<p>Each Archetype being unlockable to each party member also adds an insane variety of customization in a different way to unlock and fuse demons that you might be familiar with. Letting you tailor every last aspect of your team and their loadout allows for spectacular possibilities.</p>
<h2>The Look And Feel Of <em>Metaphor</em></h2>
<p>Stylistically, <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> sits somewhere between high fantasy merged with modern sensibilities. With the merge of fantasy and futuristic-looking technology, such as swords you can surfboard around on or the Gauntlet Runner literally running instead of driving, it creates an extremely distinct setting that's immediately recognizable as well as memorable.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-homan-combat.jpg?itok=APUeuWv4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metaphor_-refantazio-homan-combat.jpg?itok=0kzsL5Sh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>No one makes a horrific creature like Atlus does...</figcaption></figure><p>While in-game <em>Metaphor</em> looks on par with the majority of other Atlus titles, there's nothing inherently wrong with that. The animated cutscenes however did seem to have some very strange stuttering to them, whether that's just that they were at a lower framerate to the in-game moments or something more was happening under the hood I'm not too sure though. I did keep thinking while playing "I can't wait for a <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> anime to be released".</p>
<p>One core aspect that contributes to the look of this game is its incredibly flashy UI elements. While it was a treat to navigate the various menus and equipment screens there were some moments that the UI came across as a bit too flashy. Scene transitions into battles offering a wipe of color, fast effects, and bright lights did wear when near the end of my longer gameplay sessions.</p>
<p>The audio design was nailed perfectly from the vocal direction of the strong cast of main characters (I was impressed with just how much of the game was fully voiced), as well as the incredible background and combat music. Even fast-paced combat felt epic and important with the monastic chanting reverberating in the background.</p>
<h2><em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><em>Metaphor: ReFantazio </em>feels like an evolution of the <em>Persona </em>formula in every single way. The way it addresses the core themes of the story are better explored through the story from start to finish, the relationships with your Followers are grander in scale and really address relatable topics like shame and loss, and navigating this complicated world is the easiest it's ever been.</p>
<p>Somehow Metaphoe Re Fantazio manages to add so much more gameplay into the formula while covering far less 'in-universe' time providing more substance without taking away from the narrative weight of what's going on in the story.</p>
<p>Gamers who have been waiting to find a good entry point into titles like <em>Shin Megami Tensei</em> or <em>Persona </em>should know that this is the best place to climb aboard, and for the long-standing fans who are already aware of the high-quality work that Atlus puts out be excited because you're not ready for how great the adventure you're about to take is going to be.</p>
<hr><p><em><strong>Metaphor: ReFantazio&nbsp;</strong>was reviewed on Xbox Series X with a copy provided by the publisher over the course of 85 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero Review – Kamehameha x100]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-review-kamehameha-x100</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-review-%E2%80%93-kamehameha-x100.1002576/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-review-kamehameha-x100<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The long-awaited sequel to the <em>Budokai Tenkaichi</em> series has a lot of nostalgia to live up to. <em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</em> has more material to work with than ever, and making it a cohesive package is no easy feat.</p>
<p>For Shenron's sake, among the 182 characters, there are seven Gokus and six Vegetas, each with their own set of transformations and fusions (that doesn't even include Goku Black or Baby Vegeta!). There's a bunch of new material from <em>Dragon Ball Super</em> to cover, too.</p>
<p>For the most part, <em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</em> handles all of that and more with care and heart, all while lovingly bringing your favorite spikey-haired Saiyans to life in Unreal Engine 5. Even if you get tired of hearing Goku yell "Kamehameha" a hundred times, at least it'll look good.</p>

<h2>Watch Those Sparks Fly</h2>
<p>Above all, <em>Dragon Ball</em> is all about the fights, and <em>Sparking! Zero</em> takes that seriously. The fighting system here is very comparable to the old-school <em>Budokai Tenkaichi</em> games, meaning it's frantic, energetic, and fast. However, there's an order to the chaos, especially with the meaningful updates to the combat introduced here.</p>
<p>For example, Revenge Counters let you use a Skill Count to get a breather while your enemy is mid-combo, sort of like a burst in <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/guilty-gear-strive-changed-fighting-games-rollback-netcode"><em>Guilty Gear</em></a>. Short Dashes also give you more options for close-quarters maneuverability and mid-combo versatility.</p>
<p>The camera, often a source of frustration in arena fighters, follows the action fairly well, too. When there's a quick series of high-speed movements, the camera goes for a bird's-eye view, valuing clarity instead of staying locked over the shoulder. It's another welcome upgrade, though it still struggles once you're in a corner.</p>

<p>No matter whether you're on the offensive or the defensive, it never feels like you're short of options. If you're beating down the enemy, there are at least five ways to extend your combo at any given moment, and it's up to you to mix things up, whether it's for style points or to trip up your opponent.</p>
<p>Similarly, when you're being attacked, there are tight timing windows to execute counters, vanishes, and all manners of parries. It feels like a series of high-speed rock-paper-scissors matches, but only metaphorically—this isn't like <em>Ultimate Tenkaichi</em>, thankfully.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-gohan-v-cell.jpg?itok=WKR89Mlm 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-gohan-v-cell.jpg?itok=ujf5MOrM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Gohan's dodging Cell's attacks so fast that he's a literal blur.</figcaption></figure><p>Super attacks, of course, are the flashiest part of combat here. Every character gets three attack ones and two utility skills. These utility skills can instantly max your ki meter or give a mini power boost. For example, one of Super Saiyan Blue Goku's utility skills is a temporary Kaioken.</p>
<p>The attacks are exactly what you think: These are your Kamehamehas and Final Flashes. Some are just projectiles, while others are rush attacks where you have to make contact with the enemy.</p>
<p>I've found the tracking for these attacks to be more forgiving than what I remembered from the older <em>Budokai Tenkaichi </em>games. I pretty consistently could land long combos, launch the enemy across the map, and reliably add a super attack for that extra touch of damage and pizazz.</p>

<p>Once you're in the groove, it really does feel like playing an episode of <em>Dragon Ball</em>, where quick combos and tricky teleports are punctuated by trash talk and big blasts. The super attacks are also all choreographed very well, referencing specific frames from the anime while being snappy enough to not outstay their welcome.</p>
<p>To put it simply, <em>Sparking! Zero</em> is everything I wanted in a <em>Dragon Ball</em> arena fighter and more. However, if you're looking for a truly competitive multiplayer experience here, I'd temper your expectations. There's online play and ranked matches, but the game is also absolutely unbalanced—in a good way.</p>
<p>After all, Ultra Instinct Goku or Super Saiyan 4 Gogeta are absolute powerhouses in the story, and this game is all about fulfilling that power fantasy. Could Krillin beat them? Sure, anything is possible. But I don't think we're here to see an equal playing field; we're here to see that field demolished.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-broly-v-broly.jpg?itok=jU2N09BY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-broly-v-broly.jpg?itok=PQjaCbx7 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Which one's stronger?</figcaption></figure><h2>Next Time on <em>Dragon Ball Z</em></h2>
<p><em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</em> has lots of game modes, where you can play against friends on the couch or online. There are even tournament modes to check out. But the star of the show, and what you'll likely first check out, is the Episode Battle mode.</p>
<p>You get a total of eight characters to choose from, and you follow their stories throughout the entirety of <em>Dragon Ball</em>. Goku's story is the first one you'll have, but you'll unlock more like Vegeta, Gohan, Frieza, and even Goku Black.</p>
<p>The real question is, how many more times do we need to see Frieza blow up Krillin? If you're picking up this game, chances are you already know the canon decently. This game knows that and treats the story with brevity where it's due.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-goku-and-vegeta-v-buu.jpg?itok=2AMaX9MN 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-goku-and-vegeta-v-buu.jpg?itok=BNYvPsbZ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This is from Vegeta's perspective, right before they fight Kid Buu. It's perhaps the only instance of a literal rock-paper-scissors match.</figcaption></figure><p>For example, in Goku's story, the Android/Cell Saga is just three fights: one with Android 19, one with Cell, then one with Cell Jr. There's some storytelling to tie them all together, but it handles it quickly because you'll get more of the context in Vegeta's and Gohan's stories.</p>
<p>It was a bit of a weird choice at first, but I grew to appreciate it in the long run. It makes the story mode overall feel better-paced, even if you occasionally see repeats of the same scenes from slightly different angles.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-yamcha.jpg?itok=NLhLzwkM 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-yamcha.jpg?itok=RAD_noyG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Classic.</figcaption></figure><p>The way some scenes are presented can feel a little bit dry, with unvoiced text over essentially a slideshow. The choice is only made more jarring when certain endings have a narrator reading out the words. Regardless, despite the sometimes lacking presentation, the full-motion cutscenes make up for it.</p>
<p>Certain scenes from the anime are lovingly remade in Unreal Engine 5, and the particle effects and energy beams look wonderful in it. Even better, you can press a button to toggle between your character's perspective or the pre-determined camera angles of the scene.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-vegeta-final-flash-pov.jpg?itok=ffGj8Fby 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-vegeta-final-flash-pov.jpg?itok=0cjDtPoH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>POV: Vegeta saving the universe.</figcaption></figure><p>Sometimes, it's really cool to see a unique perspective in these vignettes. Watching Piccolo kill Raditz and Goku from Goku's view is equally wild and wonderful. There's another scene where one character runs distraction while yours flanks the opponent, and it's cool seeing the distraction from afar.</p>
<p>Other times though, the first-person perspective is kind of awkward and unnecessary. Simple discussions are just a little weird, especially when the other character is really far away.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-vegeta-death-pov.jpg?itok=-EIJlh1H 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-vegeta-death-pov.jpg?itok=HdHSh74l 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>POV: Sky green.</figcaption></figure><h2>A Love Letter to <em>Dragon Ball</em> Fans</h2>
<p>Some fights also come with unique finish conditions that open up new paths in the narrative. They can be as simple as Goku finishing off Cell before Gohan needs to join in, and it leads to a fun-yet-brief happily ever after. But others are entire mini sagas on their own.</p>
<p>These what-if scenarios in the story mode are some of the best parts of <em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</em>, especially the lengthier ones. They play with the canon in interesting, fun ways, and more importantly, they bring those fun hypotheticals to life.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-alt-saiyan-saga.jpg?itok=6XzUreAH 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-alt-saiyan-saga.jpg?itok=Rw5YT7c3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>"All of them?"</figcaption></figure><p>If you grew up on <em>Dragon Ball</em>, there's no doubt you've heard friends say stuff like, "What if Vegeta killed Krillin on Earth and Goku went Super Saiyan early?" Heck, you might have been that kid yourself.</p>
<p>This game lives out that scenario in an eight-fight long alternate story, and it even adds a fun little twist I wasn't expecting. And that's just one of many lengthy breakaways from the known canon.</p>

<p>If you initially thought that it was weird for Goku Black or Frieza to be the protagonists of their own story modes, rest assured, they're fleshed out by all sorts of interesting hypotheticals. Frieza and Gohan especially have some of the best alternate stories as you get into the <em>Super </em>sections of the narrative.</p>
<p>As a whole, these story modes feel like a celebration of <em>Dragon Ball</em>'s most iconic moments while sparking the fans' imaginations. The weakest stories might be Jiren's and Goku Black's, since they're both confined to one arc each. Their what-if scenarios didn't feel so excitingly different from one another, often presenting slightly different flavors of "but what if they defeated Goku?"</p>

<p>If your imagination goes wild, there's also the Custom Battle mode in <em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</em>, where you can play and create your own dream matchups. It comes preloaded with 37 custom fights that range from silly to dramatic.</p>
<p>For example, there's one where Ginyu turns against Frieza and body changes with him. In another, the Great Saiyaman saves the city from evil Kaiju, like Hirudegarn and Great Ape Vegeta.</p>
<p>To up the ante even more, the Custom Battle editor lets you create all sorts of scenarios yourself. The editor is a little bit tedious to use, and it could use better filters for finding names and pre-set sentences. But if you're determined, it's robust enough to make interesting cutscenes and fights.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-custom-video.jpg?itok=GJQqCMWi 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-custom-video.jpg?itok=4URFNbe4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>While there are&nbsp;<em>Dragon Ball GT</em>&nbsp;characters available here, there isn't official story content for them in Episode Battles. Nothing's stopping you from making them yourself here.</figcaption></figure><p>Within a fight itself, you can program if-then statements to alter the flow as the fight continues. You can really up the stakes, creating an enemy that feels nigh invincible, but then another hero comes in and saves the day after your character loses a percent of health.</p>
<p>I'm not sure how enamored I am by the editor itself, but I love the idea it presents, and for the mega fans out there, I'm sure the potential of making and publishing unique <em>Dragon Ball </em>fights will be a dream come true. I'm personally excited to explore the online library a couple of days after it fully launches.</p>

<p>And as a final note for all the major <em>Dragon Ball</em> fans out there, please check out the Encyclopedia. It gives you your usage stats for each character, but more importantly, while you're perusing, you'll be on a Zoom call with Chi-Chi, Bulma, and Videl. You can ask them to dish on literally any character, and it's as delightful as you can imagine.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-encyclopedia.jpg?itok=zAm70g2- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-encyclopedia.jpg?itok=rwAM1X2Y 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Videl also jokes about how we'll eventually see a Super Saiyan Green or even Super Saiyan Purple (could you imagine???).</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</em> is the <em>Dragon Ball</em> game I've waited years for. I sunk so much of my youth into the <em>Budokai Tenkaichi</em> series, and this game just breaks the limits of what I thought would be possible.</p>
<p>Its story mode alone delivers so much more than just the narrative you know. It's a treasure trove of easter eggs and winks to the audience, all wrapped up in a beautifully rendered package.</p>
<hr><p><em><strong>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</strong> was reviewed on PlayStation 5 with a copy provided by the publisher over the course of 24 hours of gameplay – all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take Part In A Kill Team Global Mission To Win A Years Worth Of Prizes]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/take-part-in-kill-team-global-mission-to-win-years-worth-of-prizes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-part-in-a-kill-team-global-mission-to-win-a-years-worth-of-prizes.1002573/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/take-part-in-kill-team-global-mission-to-win-years-worth-of-prizes<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>To celebrate the launch of the latest edition of <em>Kill Team</em> with the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/kill-team-hivestorm-review">Hivestorm</a> box, Games Workshop are celebrating by inviting players to join in a Global Campaign on the 12 Oct 2024, with the chance to win a years worth of <em>Kill Team</em> products, just for participating.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kill-team-hivestorm-5_0.jpg?itok=gsa0X1ye 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kill-team-hivestorm-5_0.jpg?itok=JrgstWQL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The latest edition of <em>Kill Team, </em>which was released over the weekend, sees an updated ruleset, and fully <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/new-warhammer-40000-kill-team-faction-rules-are-available-digitally">updated faction lists for all factions</a> launched during the <em>Kill Team</em> 2021 to 2024 seasons. This season of Kill Team takes place on the planet Volkus, which houses the Massif Ballistus, known as the Great Gun. A weapon so large and powerful, that it uses the rotation of the planet to aid slingshotting its munitions into orbit to target any invading force.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kill-team-global-mission-2.jpg?itok=4oP4ZZHy 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kill-team-global-mission-2.jpg?itok=BDwFKvqM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The Kill Team Global Mission takes place underneath the Great Gun, and players are attempting to retrieve crucial intelligence before the Great Gun fires and lay waste to the ground beneath it. During each turning point, a new rule comes into effect as the weapon moves through its firing cycle. In the first round, the great hymns of Adeptus Mechanicus join in with the millions who worship the Great Gun, and operatives get a bonus to their move allowance. In later rounds, the Great Gun fires and any operatives not in sufficient cover can take damage, with all operatives suffering penalties to their movement in the final round as the shockwave of the weapon verberates across the planet.</p>
<p>To take part in the Global Mission, players can access the Mission Brief by signing up to Games Workshop's newsletter <a href="https://warhammer.me/3XD2lnu">here</a>, and once the mission is played on the 12 Oct 24, players submit their results through the Command Center to be in with a chance of winning <a href="https://www.warhammer-community.com/en-gb/articles/0S0xtIit/hivestorm-operations-complete-a-top-secret-mission-and-win-every-kill-team-release-for-a-year/">all-new <em>Kill Team</em> products for a year</a>.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kill-team-hivestorm-3_0.jpg?itok=7vZ_fjVg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kill-team-hivestorm-3_0.jpg?itok=mAjdfTmx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>I'm going to be taking the new&nbsp;Astra Militarum Tempestus Aquilon to battle this weekend. Their drop insertion and rapid insertion rules mean that getting to objectives before your opponent, in order to initiate transmission to gain victory points during the scenario should be easier. Keeping them on objectives against the more heavily armed and armored kill teams may be a challenge though, and I'm looking forward to seeing how players use the variety of kill teams to tackle the mission.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Persona’s longtime director made an epic fantasy RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/7/24262346/metaphor-refantazio-katsura-hashino-interview-persona</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-persona%E2%80%99s-longtime-director-made-an-epic-fantasy-rpg.1002570/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/7/24262346/metaphor-refantazio-katsura-hashino-interview-persona<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Persona 5</em> helped the roleplaying franchise <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/29/15098458/persona-5-review-ps4-ps3">break out with mainstream audiences</a>, and it’s also a game that was in the works for a long time. Early work began in 2008, just after <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/5/20994037/playstation-jrpg-persona-series-atlus-final-fantasy-4-vii-xenogears-kingdom-hearts-25-anniversary"><em>Persona 4</em></a> came out, with full development kicking off three years later. So, just ahead of the game’s launch in 2016, director Katsura Hashino — steward of the franchise since <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/2/24058364/persona-3-reload-review-xbox-ps5-steam"><em>Persona 3</em></a> — asked the team what they wanted to do next. “Everyone said fantasy,” he tells <em>The Verge</em>.</p><p>That game would turn out to be <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em>, an epic RPG that launches on PlayStation, Xbox, and PC on October 11th. In a lot of ways, it’s reminiscent of <em>Persona</em>, with slick menus, turn-based combat, and gameplay systems forged through making meaningful connections with characters. But gone is the detailed rendition of modern-day Japan, which has been replaced by a high-fantasy realm full of fairies and kingdoms and terrible monsters called humans. The story kicks off when the king is killed and a tournament of sorts is put in place to find his successor.</p><p>For Hashino, fantasy was a chance to explore some ideas that weren’t possible in <em>Persona</em>’s modern-day setting. He really wanted a game that emphasized a long journey, for example, which is a common fantasy trope. That’s harder to do in a story about high school students. And so <em>Metaphor</em> has players traveling across a fantasy realm so large that you actually get a vehicle to help reach faraway towns and dungeons.</p><p>That’s not to say that all of the swords and sorcery mean that <em>Metaphor</em> doesn’t explore real-world issues. Instead, Hashino uses the fantasy setting as a way of broaching these topics in a different way. “Thematically, we put anxiety as the central focus of the game,” he explains. “In part because everyone has anxiety. But if we made a game focused on anxiety in the real world, we’d have to focus on really specific things about how it affects people in the modern world. And we’d drown in the specifics of it.”</p><div><p>“I thought: let’s try to make a fantasy game that only we can make”</p></div><p>In <em>Metaphor</em>, anxiety manifests not just as an emotion but also as something physical, an actual particle in the air that you can see. “That is something that we wouldn’t really be able to do in the real world,” Hashino says. “It’s more of an abstract kind of idea.”</p><p>But the shift to fantasy did have its own challenges: namely, coming up with a world from scratch. After so much time spent on games set in the modern day, Hashino gave himself a crash course in fantasy, reading books like <em>The</em> <em>Lord of the Rings</em> as a refresher. Whereas, with <em>Persona 5,</em> he could gather ideas simply by walking the streets around his office, here, inspiration wasn’t quite so simple. But he soon realized that simply imitating the existing fantasy canon wouldn’t work.</p><div><figcaption><em>Metaphor: ReFantazio.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Atlus</cite></p></div><p>“I realized that if we tried to imitate this in any way, in the characters or setting or world, it wouldn’t really reach the originals,” Hashino says. “If we tried to copy that it would just be a copy. So I thought: let’s try to make a fantasy game that only we can make.”</p><p>In the end, the game gave Hashino and the team exactly what they were looking for: a new experience. It forced the director to not only create a unique world but also imagine how the people in that world would act and live. If anxiety particles suddenly appeared in Tokyo, for instance, people would understandably be weirded out. But in <em>Metaphor,</em> they’re an everyday thing.</p><p>“Trying to put myself in the shoes of the people in this fantasy world, and how they would think, was a really interesting experience for me,” he says. “And something I’d never really done before with the <em>Persona</em> series.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Future Of Halo Is Coming And It Includes Multiple Games]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/halo-6-infinite-unreal-engine-ue5-ce-remake-343-1851666611</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-future-of-halo-is-coming-and-it-includes-multiple-games.1002564/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/halo-6-infinite-unreal-engine-ue5-ce-remake-343-1851666611<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ever since mass layoffs at<em> Halo</em> maker 343 Industries, fans have wondered what the future will hold <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/halo-infinite-season-5-armor-pc-xbox-campaign-1850960459&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/halo-infinite-season-5-armor-pc-xbox-campaign-1850960459">for the famed sci-fi shooter</a></span>. It turns out Microsoft still has big plans for Master Chief, and they involve multiple upcoming projects as well as the franchise making the jump to Epic Games’ Unreal Engine, the tech that powers <em>Fortnite</em> and a host of other Xbox first-party games. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196163" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Firefight’s Back In Halo! What Is Firefight?" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="106" data-playlist="196163,195371,196909" data-current="196163"><div><p>Firefight’s Back In Halo! What Is Firefight?</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196163/196163_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196163/196163_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196163/196163_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196163/196163_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21695.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>343 Industries revealed the news during the 2024<em> Halo</em> World Championship, including that the studio will be called Halo Studios going forward. Instead of continuing to use its current  Slipspace Engine, which was created from the ground up for <em>Halo Infinite</em>, the franchise will abandon it for Unreal Engine 5. An effort called “Project Foundry” is also currently underway to build a foundation for training and best practices for developing <em>Halo </em>with the new tech.</p><p>A mini-video documentary featuring studio head Pierre Hintze, COO Elizabeth van Wyck, and studio art director Chris Matthews, among others, laid out the company’s vision for the future of<em> Halo</em>. It revealed that multiple new <em>Halo </em>games are currently in development, and Halo Studios is changing more than just its name, with shifts to studio culture, workflow, and team organization as well. One hope for making the jump to UE 5 is that recruitment will become easier and development more streamlined when people don’t have to learn from, and adapt to, an entirely foreign proprietary engine on the fly. </p><p>While Hintze called this a new chapter for<em> Halo</em>, it’s hard not to see it as a clean break from and rebuke of the recent past. <em>Halo Infinite</em> went through a notoriously challenging development cycle, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/halo-infinite-delayed-to-2021-1844688959?_gl=1*14m4j5s*_ga*ODE3ODM5ODIyLjE3MjA0NjY0NTg.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODMwNTc2NS4xMzQuMS4xNzI4MzA4NTMxLjI0LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/halo-infinite-delayed-to-2021-1844688959?_gl=1*14m4j5s*_ga*ODE3ODM5ODIyLjE3MjA0NjY0NTg.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODMwNTc2NS4xMzQuMS4xNzI4MzA4NTMxLjI0LjAuMA..">including missing the launch window for Xbox Series X/S</a></span>, and came out the other side of that good but not great. Less than two years after it released, then-343 Industries suffered a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/microsoft-layoff-xbox-343-halo-bethesda-coalition-1850002600&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-layoff-xbox-343-halo-bethesda-coalition-1850002600">reported 95 layoffs amidst wider-scale cuts at Microsoft</a></span>. </p><p>Moving to Unreal Engine might not fix some of the deeper issues at play in that messy production process, but it does suggest Microsoft is pushing toward a much bigger focus on internal co-development resources. The Coalition, which is making <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-e-day-trailer-marcus-dom-xbox-sgf-showcase-1851528894&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/gears-of-war-e-day-trailer-marcus-dom-xbox-sgf-showcase-1851528894"><em>Gears of War: E-Day</em></a></span>, has always used Unreal Engine. A bunch of other Xbox game studios have also already made the jump, including Obsidian (<em>Avowed </em>and <em>Outer Worlds 2</em>), InXile Entertainment (<em>Clockwork Revolutions</em>), The Initiative (<em>Perfect Dark</em>), and Compulsion Games (<em>South of Midnight</em>). </p><p>Undead Labs’ <em>State of Decay 3 </em>is also using UE5, which is seemingly at least part of why <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/GroundedGame/comments/1de5ipj/state_of_decay_3_is_codeveloped_with_grounded/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GroundedGame/comments/1de5ipj/state_of_decay_3_is_codeveloped_with_grounded/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Obsidian Entertainment has been able to help out with the tech for its open world</a></span>. That’s just some of the co-development potential Microsoft teased earlier this year as part of its big summer showcase. Most of the fruits of this effort have yet to be seen in action, though. <em>Avowed</em> was previously set to arrive this fall but was pushed to February 2025. There are also still notable studios inside Microsoft that aren’t using Unreal, including Playground Games which is making <em>Fable</em> and almost all of the teams from the Bethesda acquisition. </p><p>As for <em>Halo</em>, we still don’t know when these new games will be revealed or what they are. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/halo-combat-evolved-remaster-remake-ps5-xbox-1851523975&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/halo-combat-evolved-remaster-remake-ps5-xbox-1851523975">Tom Warren at <em>The Verge</em> reported</a></span> not too long ago that a remake of <em>Halo: Combat Evolved</em> is in the works. For the studio to transition the franchise to new tech, it would certainly make sense to begin with a beloved, known entity like the first game and learn from there. <em>Halo Infinite</em>’s free-to-play multiplayer, meanwhile, continues <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.halowaypoint.com/news/one-shot-slayer&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.halowaypoint.com/news/one-shot-slayer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">to get new updates</a></span>, though with these new changes in place it no longer sounds like the platform for the future of <em>Halo</em> that it was once described as. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/metaphor-refantazio-review-pc-ps5-xbox-persona-atlus-1851665876</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-the-kotaku-review.1002561/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/metaphor-refantazio-review-pc-ps5-xbox-persona-atlus-1851665876<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Throughout <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio</em>’s roughly 80 hours, the RPG’s protagonist carries a novel with him as he travels through the fantastical world of the United Kingdom of Euchronia. The book depicts an idealized metropolis of skyscrapers where equality is written into law. It’s clear this story envisions a pristine vision of our own world, and as our hero reads through its pages, he’s filled with a drive to try and make his world a place that mirrors the fantasy the author created. I’m no stranger to throwing my heart and soul into the stories I devour in fiction, so <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio </em>had me by the throat in mere minutes.</p><p>The latest game from the minds behind the <em>Persona </em>series has a lot to say, and it does so in a way that’s refreshingly full-throated and without a modicum of subtlety. <em>Metaphor </em>takes the foundations of Atlus’ beloved life sim RPGs and manages to do and say almost everything it sets out to more eloquently than the games it builds upon. It’s not flawless like the utopia in the novel, but it’s a relief to get a game from Atlus that I can recommend without the same caveats I typically have to attach to <em>Persona </em>games, which gives me hope for the company’s future projects, both in and out of this new, rich world it’s created.</p><figure id="" data-id="44a997f2df533ac182c2951cb79d8b92" data-recommend-id="image://44a997f2df533ac182c2951cb79d8b92" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The prince says &quot;So I can't give up. In my ideal world, people can believe in their future. Their birth doesn't matter.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The prince says &quot;So I can't give up. In my ideal world, people can believe in their future. Their birth doesn't matter.&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Atlus / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="44a997f2df533ac182c2951cb79d8b92" data-recommend-id="image://44a997f2df533ac182c2951cb79d8b92" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The prince says &quot;So I can't give up. In my ideal world, people can believe in their future. Their birth doesn't matter.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Despite <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/metaphor-refantazio-preview-persona-atlus-political-1851633394&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/metaphor-refantazio-preview-persona-atlus-political-1851633394">what Atlus would like you to believe</a></span>, <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio </em>is a dense, overtly political tale, and the happenings within the United Kingdom of Euchronia serve as an allegory for the injustices and prejudices of the real world. This universe’s people are made up of eight “tribes,” each a different humanoid race with its own cultures, traditions, and stereotypes that play into their perceived roles in society. The protagonist, an Elda, is a perfect centerpiece for illustrating this, as his tribe is one that has historically been put down under the current world order.<br></p><p><em>Metaphor </em>is heavy-handed as it draws attention to the power dynamics of its world. As I enter the capital city of Grand Trad, I see a beast-like Paripus begging for their life as they’re executed on the town square without trial. No one believes a paripus when they say they didn’t commit a crime, and no one with the power to execute them cares enough to look a little harder when an easy scapegoat is right in front of them. To the horn-sporting Clemar and the elf-like Roussainte that watch, it’s merely entertainment. As an Elda, the most despised tribe in all the land and the one blamed for the monstrous “human” creatures that threaten the safety of their betters, it’s a reminder that one perceived step out of line could lead to a quick, uncaring end.</p><p>Atlus has never been one for mincing wor as it creates, well, metaphors for real-world plights. However, instead of using the supernatural as it does in <em>Persona</em>, in <em>Metaphor </em>it creates a dystopian fantasy that mirrors reality. A recurring motif throughout the game sees the protagonist reading the novel he carries with him, as it illustrates a vision of what the world <em>could</em> be, powerfully contrasted with the reality of how it is. Of course, moving closer to a utopian reality is hardly a simple matter, and anyone who lives in this hellscape we all share has probably considered that achieving lofty ideals of a world without prejudice and injustice, where humanity is “one tribe” truly devoid of discrimination and oppression, would likely also mean erasing foundational cultural history. <em>Metaphor </em>doesn’t seem blind to this, and characters sometimes point out this conundrum. When I showed the book to the Eugief Heismay, for instance, he pointed out that the novel’s vision of what a utopia would look like seemed doomed to fail and full of blind spots. But can we still aspire to it? That’s the goal.</p><figure id="" data-id="b2eac35025f6570f8d169b73add4bbb9" data-recommend-id="image://b2eac35025f6570f8d169b73add4bbb9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Heismay says &quot;Equal competition doesn't mean equal footing. Their very aims of freedom and balance could spell doom for the striving weak.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Heismay says &quot;Equal competition doesn't mean equal footing. Their very aims of freedom and balance could spell doom for the striving weak.&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Atlus / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b2eac35025f6570f8d169b73add4bbb9" data-recommend-id="image://b2eac35025f6570f8d169b73add4bbb9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Heismay says &quot;Equal competition doesn't mean equal footing. Their very aims of freedom and balance could spell doom for the striving weak.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Metaphor</em> is simultaneously a story about people who want to make their world a better place, and an ideological statement about the importance of such struggles, one that offers up more actionable ways to live by such an ethos than the similarly themed <em>Persona 5</em> did eight years ago. It has its fantastical elements, but the game’s tale of people banding together with anyone willing to stand up for what’s right feels remarkably grounded. At the core of <em>Metaphor </em>is an election, one not determined by checkmarks on a ballot, but by a magical force that sees into the heart of every citizen of Euchronia. The game opens with a bed-ridden king being assassinated by antagonist Louis Guiabern, a prominent member of the Euchronian military who seeks to ascend to the throne, unhappy with the royal family’s rule. However, his plan is derailed by a spell left behind by the king in the wake of his death. His magic covers the entirety of the country and ensures that the people will be led by someone they actually choose, so no one can take the throne by force. It prevents political assassinations, so the only way to win is to actually gain the favor of the public.<br></p><p>That’s where <em>Metaphor</em>’s spin on <em>Persona</em>’s social mechanics comes into play. The relationships I foster across the country help solidify my place in the election, and ensure Louis is unable to comfortably ascend the ranks despite all his underhanded schemes and efforts to secure victory. As a political drama, <em>Metaphor</em> understands that a path to political prominence starts at the ground level, and that those in power routinely forget those at the bottom. By the time those vying for Euchronia’s crown have ascended to the highest ranks in the election, they’ve already forgotten the average citizen who put them there.</p><figure id="" data-id="dad0a40a58237b8e5c3954c51a587ae4" data-recommend-id="image://dad0a40a58237b8e5c3954c51a587ae4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Strohl and the Protagonist talk on their ship." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Strohl and the Protagonist talk on their ship." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Atlus / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="dad0a40a58237b8e5c3954c51a587ae4" data-recommend-id="image://dad0a40a58237b8e5c3954c51a587ae4" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Strohl and the Protagonist talk on their ship." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>These political truths are driven home all the more effectively because <em>Metaphor</em>’s follower relationships are some of the best-written stories in Atlus’ catalog. In a way, the game<em> </em>feels like <em>Persona </em>with a more thorough editor. The social link-style relationship building brings down its conversations to a more brisk eight encounters rather than the bloated 10 of <em>Persona</em> games. Each follower I grew to know throughout <em>Metaphor</em> felt like they filled out the world and brought a new perspective I wouldn’t have considered without them. Also, there are only 14 of them, compared to the two dozen of <em>Persona 5 Royal</em>. The trade-off is that none of them felt like filler, and even the worst of them still felt like they had something to contribute to <em>Metaphor</em>’s themes. Maria, the young child of a soldier killed in action, brought the perspective of a child affected by this cruel world. Bardon, a local leader in the town of Martira, illustrated the challenges of working locally with people you know rather than having lofty goals of acquiring the crown.<br></p><p>The one dud I’d call out is Catherina, the Paripus bounty hunter who is also gunning for the throne. While I found her entertaining as a character, her arc takes a strange left turn that feels pretty at odds with the views <em>Metaphor</em> has expressed up to that point on how those in power have everyone else under their boot (and what ordinary people should do about it). For a game that doesn’t shy away from talking about how shitty things are for the poor and marginalized, <em>Metaphor</em>’s lapse in judgment on this storyline soured me on the relationship, even though it helped my place in the election.</p><figure id="" data-id="2afb050490acef915caef60923c75520" data-recommend-id="image://2afb050490acef915caef60923c75520" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Catherina says &quot;When I'm queen, all the land's corrupt upper classes will be wanted men! We have our guillotines sharpened, and our wallets open!&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Catherina says &quot;When I'm queen, all the land's corrupt upper classes will be wanted men! We have our guillotines sharpened, and our wallets open!&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Atlus / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="2afb050490acef915caef60923c75520" data-recommend-id="image://2afb050490acef915caef60923c75520" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Catherina says &quot;When I'm queen, all the land's corrupt upper classes will be wanted men! We have our guillotines sharpened, and our wallets open!&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Navigating the social sim elements also means juggling the day-to-day. I had opportunities to take on bounties in my free time, which generally led me to one of several indistinct dungeons with a challenging boss at the end. But more often than not I’d use that time to go talk to the citizens of Euchronia. <em>Metaphor </em>uses the same social stats mechanic from <em>Persona</em> that blocks off dialogue options and relationship progress behind things like “wisdom,” “tolerance,” or “eloquence,” which can be leveled up by meeting people around towns and reading books.<br></p><p><em>Metaphor</em> never passes up an opportunity to teach you more about its world by hearing from the people who have been most affected by it. Talking to a mask-wearing Mustari about their culture fills in gaps in my knowledge and also allows me to affect change for them in-game. Even when you’re doing actions just meant to pass the time, <em>Metaphor</em> takes <em>Persona</em>’s systems and fine-tunes them to build out its world, so that even on days where I didn’t feel like I was doing anything particularly productive or meaningful, I was still getting something significant out of spending my time talking to a guy I met on the street.<br></p><figure id="" data-id="cc0f23d81d2eedcaabb74e9a8262b071" data-recommend-id="image://cc0f23d81d2eedcaabb74e9a8262b071" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Strohl awakens to the Archetype power." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Strohl awakens to the Archetype power." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Atlus / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="cc0f23d81d2eedcaabb74e9a8262b071" data-recommend-id="image://cc0f23d81d2eedcaabb74e9a8262b071" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Strohl awakens to the Archetype power." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Winning the hearts and minds of the people is only half the battle, however. Though growing my relationships helps me build up my team into the best versions of themselves, my ascent to the throne is paved in monster blood. <em>Metaphor: ReFantazio </em>may not be explicitly a <em>Shin Megami Tensei </em>game (though there are references aplenty), but it’s got the same tough-as-nails DNA running through its veins. When I <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/metaphor-refantazio-awakening-archetype-action-rpg-1851634250?_gl=1*1wt1s8s*_ga*MTMxODc3NjkwMi4xNzI1Njc2NzM3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODA3MDA2MS44MS4xLjE3MjgwNzEyMjcuMzguMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/metaphor-refantazio-awakening-archetype-action-rpg-1851634250?_gl=1*1wt1s8s*_ga*MTMxODc3NjkwMi4xNzI1Njc2NzM3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODA3MDA2MS44MS4xLjE3MjgwNzEyMjcuMzguMC4w">first played <em>Metaphor</em></a></span>, I wasn’t sold on its turn-based battle system which felt overly simple, a rote affair in which you just strike a weakness to do big damage rather than having the energizing complexities of <em>Persona</em>’s combat. However, as I unlocked new abilities and my foes did in kind, its complexities grew and I found its systems even more engaging than those of its predecessors.<br></p><p>For all the ways <em>Metaphor </em>better utilizes some of <em>Persona</em>’s core elements, it also tends to feel formulaic in some ways. The Persona summoning mechanic has been replaced by Archetypes, which are essentially classes that you can swap between throughout your journey. The cast goes through “awakenings” that are, nearly beat for beat, <em>Persona 5</em> awakenings, complete with an emotional surge, a voice telling them they have found their true strength, and a gruesome scene of each hero ripping their heart out. Those scenes are sick, but it’s also pretty clear that this studio has a formula. That being said, Archetypes don’t operate the same way Personas do in combat, even if they come about through the same means. Anyone can be anything in <em>Metaphor</em>, even as some characters’ stats are clearly meant for specific roles. The Roussainte guardian Hulkenburg feels ripe for the tanky jobs, for instance, while the Mustari priestess Eupha is clearly meant for magic-based Archetypes. Throughout <em>Metaphor </em>I would keep characters in fairly adjacent roles to those they seemed designed for, but there’s freedom to branch out and spec characters into whatever role if you want to get your hands dirty and grind for it.</p><figure id="" data-id="65c17117eb841a9efd74b1dc4183e6d1" data-recommend-id="image://65c17117eb841a9efd74b1dc4183e6d1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The protagonist faces a Human enemy." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The protagonist faces a Human enemy." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Atlus</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="65c17117eb841a9efd74b1dc4183e6d1" data-recommend-id="image://65c17117eb841a9efd74b1dc4183e6d1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The protagonist faces a Human enemy." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The sheer breadth of utility between Archetypes means <em>Metaphor </em>offers more room for player expression than the games it’s building off of. Support roles like the Commander make use of the frontline and backline mechanic, which allows you to make a tactical decision to give up defense or melee damage as you distance yourself from an enemy. Some Archetypes, like the Summoner and the Masked Dancer, feel a bit more gimmicky with their unique mechanics, the former able to bring new creatures into battle and the latter with its spell-casting masks to don. But there are also a lot of RPG mainstays like Warrior and Healer here, that keep you from getting too overwhelmed too quickly. <em>Metaphor </em>does a decent job of not handing you too much before you’re ready, so by the time that you have access to most Archetypes, you’ve got a strong enough grasp of how it all works to build a team that synergizes around them. The game encourages experimentation, though I would have liked to have seen that taken a step further by allowing you to pivot between Archetypes mid-battle, similar to <em>Final Fantasy X-2</em>.<br></p><figure id="" data-id="8d660794e519b4b450bc60f90fa9b325" data-recommend-id="image://8d660794e519b4b450bc60f90fa9b325" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Heismay looking like a cool guy." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Heismay looking like a cool guy." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Atlus / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8d660794e519b4b450bc60f90fa9b325" data-recommend-id="image://8d660794e519b4b450bc60f90fa9b325" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Heismay looking like a cool guy." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>On its face, <em>Metaphor</em>’<em>s</em> turn-based battles may look simple. You look for an enemy’s weakness and exploit it, but unlike in <em>Persona</em>, the character who exploits that vulnerability doesn’t get an extra turn. Instead, doing so increases your team’s round of turns before you pass things over to your enemy. Managing your turns is the core mechanic that informs everything you do in a battle, as every action has a risk/reward to weigh, and you can lose actions for missing an attack, or have your round cut short if your attack is repelled back at your team. However, the same is true for your foes as well. Some of my favorite Archetypes and ability loadouts were focused on not only dealing damage to my enemies, but slicing their own action count in half. By the final stretch of the game, I had Heismay set up with a passive ability that would end my opponents’ turns if they missed an attack. When he started a fight with heightened evasion, I was handily beating some of the most powerful bosses in the game by denying them a chance to fight back. <em>Metaphor</em>’s Archetype system is full of exploits and strategies like this that only come if you take the time to find them.</p><figure id="" data-id="1c427b639ea43f9ffeee9bf102bf370b" data-recommend-id="image://1c427b639ea43f9ffeee9bf102bf370b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1600" data-height="900" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The protagonist strikes an enemy with his sword." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The protagonist strikes an enemy with his sword." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Atlus</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1c427b639ea43f9ffeee9bf102bf370b" data-recommend-id="image://1c427b639ea43f9ffeee9bf102bf370b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1600" data-height="900" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The protagonist strikes an enemy with his sword." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>One of the best iterations on those systems, however, is in how <em>Metaphor</em> lets you avoid turn-based battles entirely for whole swaths of the game. Atlus has added an action system that lets you slash away at weak foes in the overworld and still get all the experience and rewards. Depending on your protagonists’ equipped Archetype, this can be more challenging, as your equipped weapon will determine if you have to get close enough for an enemy to hit back. But if you’re strong enough to take out an enemy on the field, you’ll save so much time without having to load into a turn-based fight and consider your tactics. Between multiple party members and Archetypes, <em>Metaphor </em>could have been a monotonous grind, but this one change makes <em>Metaphor </em>so breezy that I can’t even fathom Atlus doing away with it. I spent nearly 80 hours in this game, and I can only imagine how many more hours of just pure grind it would have taken to see credits if it weren’t for this change.<br></p><p>I’ve spent a lot of time comparing <em>Metaphor </em>to other Atlus games, but I think it’s fair to do so both because it clearly builds off <em>Persona</em>’s systems, and because it’s the first new franchise we’ve gotten from this team in some time. Systemically, sure, it gave me a lot to chew on and its turn-based combat feels like a compelling evolution of that in <em>Shin Megami Tensei </em>and <em>Persona</em>. But most of all, I keep coming back to how it manages to subvert the typical stumbling blocks of the team’s past work. There’s a scene early on in which Neuras, an older gentleman and the pilot of the group’s ship, is shown getting noticeably excited in the background while a famous young woman is greeting the party. I braced myself, expecting <em>Metaphor </em>to delve into the skeevy old man trope, only for him to barrel past her and geek out about her ship instead. While <em>Persona 4 </em>and <em>5 </em>were about self acceptance and fighting for change, they still carved out time to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/persona-3-reload-gay-social-link-takaya-ryoji-akihiko-1851227577&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/persona-3-reload-gay-social-link-takaya-ryoji-akihiko-1851227577">belittle queer people</a></span> and be shitty to women. <em>Metaphor </em>feels like a more mature story for this team, not because of its <em>Game of Thrones</em>-style dark fantasy, but because it doesn’t fall back into the unnecessary punching down I’d come to expect from them. As a story about fighting against injustice, <em>Metaphor </em>is mostly consistent in its ethos, even if it’s using its own fantasy social dynamics to explore those topics.</p><figure id="" data-id="86be756e5bf1ca34a0eda632467e2e38" data-recommend-id="image://86be756e5bf1ca34a0eda632467e2e38" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Strohl, the protagonist, Gallica, and Hulkenburg look at the camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Strohl, the protagonist, Gallica, and Hulkenburg look at the camera." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Atlus / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="86be756e5bf1ca34a0eda632467e2e38" data-recommend-id="image://86be756e5bf1ca34a0eda632467e2e38" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Strohl, the protagonist, Gallica, and Hulkenburg look at the camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Those ideas are present in every scene and relationship, but they come up most pointedly every time the protagonist opens his fantasy novel. As he reads it alongside his newfound companions, each of them read aloud the ideals of the author. To most people who want to believe in a better world, nothing <em>Metaphor </em>has to say is necessarily surprising. It’s not groundbreaking for a story to show people who have been embedded in oppressive systems begin to crack when they’re shown a different way. It’s also nothing new for those who have been most affected by that oppression to point out that the idealized vision the most well-meaning people have about a better world is often naive. To those who have been fighting in one way or another, <em>Metaphor </em>will<em> </em>probably read like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2024/film/news/america-ferrera-barbie-feminism-criticism-1235859445/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2024/film/news/america-ferrera-barbie-feminism-criticism-1235859445/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the <em>Barbie</em> monologue of progressive ideals</a></span>. But it feels good to know that those values are still being touted when we need them most.</p><p><em>Metaphor</em> feels like the game of the moment. Atlus may not want to draw direct comparisons between its own tale of a nation in the midst of a high-stakes election and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/presidential-debate-kamala-harris-donald-trump-jokes-1851646179&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/presidential-debate-kamala-harris-donald-trump-jokes-1851646179">the current American contest</a></span>, but the way it shows how the average citizen experiences anxiety around the state of the world, believes their responsibility to address that state begins and ends with a vote, and then retreats into fiction while <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://slate.com/culture/2024/09/chappell-roan-kamala-harris-trump-politics-voting-election.html&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://slate.com/culture/2024/09/chappell-roan-kamala-harris-trump-politics-voting-election.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">holding public figures to a higher standard</a></span> than they hold themselves feels apt. These days, the moments in <em>Metaphor </em>that drive home our need to do more than blindly believe in those we put in power feel like the kind of wake-up call some people in the real-world need.<br></p><p>I don’t have any faith in politicians who prove time and time again they will default to the status quo, but then I look at how many people who claim to want change only care enough to do something every four years and my faith is once again dragged down. Those who would see injustice persist don’t rest, and it feels like even when the stakes are highest, so many people opt to simply drop their anxieties at the feet of a “good enough” politician and wash their hands of the world’s ills. </p><p>When the world seems overwhelmingly fucked, sometimes I look at <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/baldur-s-gate-3-cyberpunk-mass-effect-character-creator-1851422575&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/baldur-s-gate-3-cyberpunk-mass-effect-character-creator-1851422575">the fictional versions of myself</a></span> I’ve created in so many games, versions of me that had more power to bring about change in their worlds than I do in mine. Some days, I wish those visions of who I could be aligned with who I felt like I really am. As I’ve grown more disenfranchised with the world I live in, it’s become so much easier to turn to whatever hope fictional stories might offer rather than try to find any reason to hope things could get better in the world outside my window. Sometimes I find myself losing any optimism that the world can get better when the majority of people are either happy with the way things are or too apathetic to fight. That means it’s easier for me to just concern myself with the plight of fictional worlds, rather than dwelling on the problems facing this one. Sometimes I feel catharsis in stories like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty-update-review-idris-elba-1850852291&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty-update-review-idris-elba-1850852291"><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em></a></span> that acknowledge everything is fucked and we’ll just survive it together. On other days, I need a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dustborn-review-red-thread-games-quantic-dream-pax-ps5-1851636258&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dustborn-review-red-thread-games-quantic-dream-pax-ps5-1851636258">reminder that other people want the world to be better</a></span> and will fight for it, so I don’t fall into apathy myself.<br></p><figure id="" data-id="93c99f7cb1ccbe2c14095d938e08cb1e" data-recommend-id="image://93c99f7cb1ccbe2c14095d938e08cb1e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A scheming man says &quot;But consider: if fantasy is born from hope... a desire to make the world better than it is...&quot; to a backdrop of an illustration of a city." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A scheming man says &quot;But consider: if fantasy is born from hope... a desire to make the world better than it is...&quot; to a backdrop of an illustration of a city." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Atlus / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="93c99f7cb1ccbe2c14095d938e08cb1e" data-recommend-id="image://93c99f7cb1ccbe2c14095d938e08cb1e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A scheming man says &quot;But consider: if fantasy is born from hope... a desire to make the world better than it is...&quot; to a backdrop of an illustration of a city." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Metaphor</em> does a succinct job of illustrating that progress is slow but still demands we take action, but the struggle for a better world still feels insurmountable to me some days in the face of what feels like never-ending systemic failure. Reading fiction that believes in the possibility of a better world is not the same as fighting for one. Posting isn’t activism. Imagining a world where everything is different, with no consideration for how to actually get there, is meaningless. <em>Metaphor </em>knows that fiction can change the world, but it also knows that inspiring people isn’t enough if they don’t follow through. And if despite my deteriorating hope I’m thinking this way, maybe that’s a sign that even if <em>Metaphor </em>isn’t exactly revolutionary in its politics or worldview, it still must have done something right.<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All Fighter Types in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/all-fighter-types-in-dragon-ball-sparking-zero/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-fighter-types-in-dragon-ball-sparking-zero.1002558/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/all-fighter-types-in-dragon-ball-sparking-zero/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>As Dragon Ball Sparking Zero enters early access today, it’s crucial to understand the different types of fighters the game offers. This knowledge is critical when assembling your team for an online PvP battle, as each fighter type brings its unique strengths and weaknesses. Dive into this guide to better understand each fighter type in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-dragon-ball-sparking-zero-fighter-types">Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Fighter Types</h2>



<p>Dragon Ball Sparking Zero boasts a diverse roster of over 180 characters, each falling into one of seven unique fighter types: Strength, Speed, Ki-Blast, Giants, Androids, Grounded, and Sword. This variety ensures that every player can find a fighter that suits their preferred playstyle, adding an exciting layer of strategy to the game.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-strength">Strength</h3>



<p>Strength characters are the game’s heavy hitters, and their movements revolve around heavy strikes and powerful Blasts. These characters lack speed but more than makeup for it in terms of their strength. There are two types of Strength characters; one category is more melee-focused, whereas the other has superior Blast attacks. Characters like Broly, Jiren and more fall in the Strength Category of Dragon Ball Sparking Zero.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-speed-nbsp">Speed&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Unlike others, the next category is the opposite of the Strength type, as these fighters can zoom around the map. These fighters might lack the strength for individual strikes but have enough stamina and speed to unleash a flurry of long-lasting assaults. Speed-type characters are also suitable for evasion and rushing to enemy players. Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Fighters like Kakunsa, Dyspo, Hit and more from the Speed type.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-ki-blast-nbsp">Ki-Blast&nbsp;</h3>



<p>This category explains itself, and these fighters are known for releasing a barrage of small Ki-Blasts or a destructive beam against these opponents. However, being from the Ki-Blast type doesn’t mean they are limited, as they can get up close and personal, too. Fighters like Vegeta, Goku and Frieza fall in the Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Ki-Blast category.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="DRAGON BALL: Sparking! ZERO – IGNITE THE SPARK Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sKJ9LDfA3ks?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h3 id="h-giant">Giant</h3>



<p>Giants are characters that will boast a humongous size on the battlefield. These characters will simultaneously be super slow but powerful, capable of staggering and blowing enemies away with their attacks. At the same time, these fighters are indifferent to blast attacks and lighter melee attacks. Great Ape characters and other Giants like Anilaza fall in this Dragon Ball Sparking Zero category.&nbsp;</p>







<h3 id="h-androids">Androids</h3>



<p>Fans of the series and previous games will be well-versed in this fighter type. Androids are known not to have Ki; however, their Ki gauge charges itself over time. At the same time, they do not lose stamina, so Rush combos are your friend. Some Dragon Ball Sparking Zero Android fighters can also absorb Ki Blasts and Blast attacks, such as Android 19 and Dr. Gero. Android 13, 16, 17 and 18 charges Ki automatically over time.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-ground-characters">Ground Characters</h3>



<p>Dragon Ball Sparking Zero is known for its flashy fights across grand stages. However, some fighters in the game cannot fly at all. These include Master Roshi, Hercule, and more. Even if they cannot fly, these are the only characters that can run on the ground and have a jump ability that allows them some air time.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-sword-characters">Sword Characters</h3>



<p>Some characters in the original series are known for their sword skills, and these fighters will adopt swords in their play style in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero. Characters like Future Trunks will be able to perform many combos, rush attacks, and blasts while wielding a sword and will also recreate their popular moves from the series.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-other-unique-details-for-fighters-in-dragon-ball-sparking-zero">Other Unique Details for Fighters in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero</h2>



<h3 id="h-super-aura">Super Aura</h3>



<p>This is a more visual characteristic for certain Dragon Ball Sparking Zero fighters. Certain fighters in their strongest form will have an always-on aura. Their Ki will provide a visual representation of their power overflowing.&nbsp;These include but are not limited to Goku and Vegeta’s Super Saiyan God, as well as Blue transformations.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="h-scouter-nbsp">Scouter&nbsp;</h3>



<p>Certain fighters from the Frieza Force can equip Scouters as an accessory in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero. This accessory will offer players a boosted search radius, which can be increased depending on Scouter quality. However, remember that the Scouter can be destroyed if you take too many hits in the battle.&nbsp;This includes characters like Bardock, Nappa, Ginyu and more.</p>



<p>Learn more about the characters from&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-unveils-saiyan-namek-sagas-characters-in-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Saiyan, Namek</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-reveals-android-saga-characters/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Android</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-has-released-the-majin-buu-saga-character-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Buu</a><span><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-has-released-the-majin-buu-saga-character-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">,</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-confirms-gt-characters-in-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GT</a>&nbsp;Sagas her</span>e. These are all the fighter types in Dragon Ball Sparking Zero; which one is your favourite?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/guides/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Guides Hub</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bleach: Rebirth of Souls character trailer – Kaname Tosen]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-kaname-tosen</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-%E2%80%93-kaname-tosen.1002555/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-character-trailer-kaname-tosen<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>The captain of Squad 9 who despises the world.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,577 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Tamsoft [296 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tamsoft">Tamsoft</a> have released a new character trailer for fighting <a title="Genres > Action [2,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Bleach: Rebirth of Souls [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bleach-rebirth-of-souls">Bleach: Rebirth of Souls</a></em> highlighting playable fighter Kaname Tosen. <span id="more-919826"></span></p><p>“His lack of eyesight has led him to develop a unique form of vision and counterattacking,” reads Tosen’s character description.</p><p><em>Bleach: Rebirth of Souls</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,121 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,205 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,296 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,406 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1689620/BLEACH_Rebirth_of_Souls/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> in early 2025.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Character Trailer: Kaname Tosen</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="BLEACH Rebirth of Souls — Kaname Tosen Character Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/B6LO391TSdY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="「BLEACH Rebirth of Souls」キャラクタームービー #14｜東仙要" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bPRSt29aLG8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open-world survival game Retreat to Enen coming to PS5, Xbox Series on October 22]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/open-world-survival-game-retreat-to-enen-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-on-october-22</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/open-world-survival-game-retreat-to-enen-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-on-october-22.1002552/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/open-world-survival-game-retreat-to-enen-coming-to-ps5-xbox-series-on-october-22<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > indie.io [35 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/indieio">indie.io</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Head West" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/head-west">Head West</a> will release <a title="Genres > Open-World [495 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> <a title="Genres > Survival [331 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival game</a> <em><a title="Games > Retreat to Enen" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/retreat-to-enen">Retreat to Enen</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,121 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,205 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> on October 22, the companies announced. <span id="more-919821"></span></p><p><em>Retreat to Enen</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1556490/Retreat_To_Enen/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on August 1, 2022.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via indie.io:</p><blockquote><p><em>Retreat to Enen</em> is a base building simulator and survival game unlike any other. Rather than fight your way to prosperity, you’ll be living off the land in balance with nature. Three vast biomes await you. Explore, forage, hunt, craft, build, and meditate as you unlock the secrets of Enen and build the retreat of your dreams. Unlock and gather over 160 unique items as you explore.</p><p>Experience a relaxing and engaging survival game, where you can build a huge home with over 50 unique unlockable building modules and dozens of furniture pieces and decorative items.</p><p>Humanity is unrecognizable in the year 3600 CE. Centuries of war, socio-economic strife, and the impending climate catastrophe, put the apex species on the verge of extinction. Turning back from the brink, humans chose a different path, one of healing, peace, and reverence for the ecosystem they are a part of. As Earth heals, every human who reaches adulthood is now tasked with learning how to become one with Nature. Your tribe has chosen Enen for your adventure.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Watch an old gameplay video below.</p><h2><span>2024 Gameplay</span></h2><p><iframe title="Retreat To Enen 2024 Gameplay" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6H0r6XYPVU0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Horror Game Plays Like The World's Scariest Game Show, And It's Out Today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-horror-game-plays-like-the-worlds-scariest-game-show-and-its-out-today/1100-6526923/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-horror-game-plays-like-the-worlds-scariest-game-show-and-its-out-today.1002549/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-horror-game-plays-like-the-worlds-scariest-game-show-and-its-out-today/1100-6526923/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526923">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>October is the best month for horror games, as you can see in our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/october-is-thankfully-stacked-with-new-horror-games/2900-5825/" data-ref-id="2900-5825">October horror games roundup</a>, and today we're adding a new one to the long list: 7 Minutes in Hell. Developed by Gaggle Studios, the team behind the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/among-us/" data-ref-id="5000-488791">Among Us</a>-like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/goose-goose-duck/" data-ref-id="5000-530204">Goose Goose Duck</a>, 7 Minutes in Hell has a similarly obvious inspiration, though with an unexpected twist; it's like if <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/lethal-company/" data-ref-id="5000-566928">Lethal Company</a> was a twisted game show.</p><p>7 Minutes in Hell asks players to descend into some decrepit, monster-infested labyrinths, collect as much loot as they can, and get out before the timer is up. For players of a certain age, it could best be likened to Supermarket Sweep, only with worse lighting and less advertising for laundry detergent.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="803258763" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465284,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;7%20Minutes%20in%20Hell%20-%20Official%20Debut%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:81,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/7-minutes-in-hell-official-debut-trailer\/2300-6465284\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465284\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465284\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465284\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465284&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465284,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6526923&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465284},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465284\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4379262-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/Mzv5KT2y.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1728309600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="Mzv5KT2y" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> 7 Minutes in Hell - Official Debut Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>The game can be played alone, but also in co-op, and there's a strong emphasis on social elements, like deciding to ditch the group and escape with <em>your </em>earnings even if it means leaving everyone else in the (literal) dark. With only seven minutes per run, rounds are meant to unfold quickly and ramp up in difficulty with each passing minute.</p><p>Like in Lethal Company, you can spend your earnings on subsequent rounds on resources like flashlights, which ought to improve your chances of not just surviving, but thriving in later rounds.</p><p>With in-game "sponsors" contributing additional buffs, it seems the game has a satirical side to it, the same way Lethal Company depicts workplace class structure or, perhaps more closely, how Squid Game depicts the common person's chase for wealth in a system designed for them to lose.</p><p>7 Minutes in Hell launches today, October 7, on Steam, and debuts as an early access title with a roadmap already revealed. This year will see additional threats and items come to the game across multiple updates, as well a new arena in December. Updates into 2025 are set to include mod support, plus more items and monsters.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digital Eclipse's retro balancing act is about courting bigger partners]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/digital-eclipse-s-retro-balancing-act-is-about-courting-bigger-partners</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/digital-eclipses-retro-balancing-act-is-about-courting-bigger-partners.1002546/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/digital-eclipse-s-retro-balancing-act-is-about-courting-bigger-partners<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Digital Eclipse.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In TV, film, and video games, documentaries are a tough market to crack. They're increasingly popular on streaming services in series format, but it's been a long time since mass market films like Fahrenheit 911 and Supersize Me were hits at the box office. And films or series about the history of video games have either focused on hyper-niche subjects or been relatively light on detail. Is it possible to capture interest in video game history outside of academic settings or journalism?</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Developer Digital Eclipse is taking a swing at it. The Atari-owned retro studio has begun putting out original projects like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2236680/Llamasoft_The_Jeff_Minter_Story/">Llamasoft: The Jeff Minter Story</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> alongside conventional commercial games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2816870/Mighty_Morphin_Power_Rangers_Ritas_Rewind/">Mighty Morphin Power Rangers: Rita's Rewind</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The two games don't seem similar at first—one is part of the studio's new experiment in mixing documentary interviews with gameplay, and the other is a side-scrolling beat-em-up featuring the cast of the original Mighty Morphin Power Rangers TV show. Digital Eclipse editorial director Chris Kohler acknowledged in an interview with Game Developer that it might be surprising to see the two projects come from the same studio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He explained that they're both part of the same project: to turn the company into a workshop for reinventing retro games—and to sell themselves to prospective partners as a go-to source for connecting with players who want an honest-to-goodness blast to the past.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Documentaries and more 'commercial' projects go hand-in-hand">Documentaries and more 'commercial' projects go hand-in-hand</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Kohler said the studio is "energized" after the release of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Making of Karateka</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Llamasoft: The Jeff Minter Story</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The two projects target a smaller audience as the games at the heart of both interactive documentaries aren't as well-known to the public. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Karateka </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">creator Jordan Mechner became famous later for the Prince of Persia series, and Minter's ZX Spectrum, Atari, and Jaguar games aren't as widely mythologized as their peers.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We've got this hill to climb where essentially what happens is we're creating these for people who've never experienced these games before," said Kohler, explaining why Digital Eclipse took this route instead of just rereleasing the original games. "It's gonna be a niche of a niche. If we can try to expand the audience somehow, then we can sell more of these games and get recognition for them."</span></p><p>Image via Digital Eclipse.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He said he's sure rereleases of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Karateka</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> or Llamasoft's library wouldn't have sold as well on their own.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">There's another way to assess the commercial viability of these games: they're prototypes for bigger documentaries Digital Eclipse wants to pull off. "The idea is, 'we've got the foundation now, we've done two projects with games that are really interesting stories...can we do this interactive documentary format with something people are clamoring for?'"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That pitch implies a future where games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Astroids</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> or </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>SimCity 2000</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> can get the documentary treatment. Digital Eclipse's two documentary games are like a calling card for the license holders for older titles. And those companies aren't the only ones the studio wants to work with.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Digital Eclipse says retro games help companies like Hasbro connect with a new audience">Digital Eclipse says retro games help companies like Hasbro connect with a new audience</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Video game history doesn't just have to be about constantly resurrecting beloved classics. Many developers, inspired by the aesthetics or playstyles of older games will riff on them with modern titles.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Digital Eclipse is doing the same, but with an eye toward games made "in partnership" (re: licensed) with notable brands. That was part of the motivation for making </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Rita's Rewind</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, a riff on '90s co-op sidescrolling beat-em-ups like the arcade game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>X-Men </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">or </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Simpsons</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. It isn't a remake, but more of a "what if?" on the kind of game that could have been made in Power Rangers' explosive heyday.</span></p><p>Image via Digital Eclipse.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"You're gonna see other games that are [potentially] in partnership with other publishers," Kohler said. Digital Eclipse's parent company Atari apparently isn't fussed about binding the company to its own library, and wants the studio to bring in revenue by courting any business that wants to make a retro-themed game.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The studio organizes developers into two groups—ones working on the documentary games, and ones working on the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Rita's Revenge</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">-style games, though there's "plenty of overlap" between the two teams, Kohler said.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He said that Digital Eclipse is "very dedicated" to the interactive documentary concept—seeming to imply that the company doesn't want its more conventional projects to overtake the documentaries in terms of resources.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a unique strategy—and definitely a niche that few other studios will be able to pursue. Game studios looking to capitalize on interest in classic games face a unique host of challenges, and leaning into the fun of diving through history is a solid plan. "We really believe that video games are the best way to tell the stories of video games," Kohler said. "and we're still actively looking for [new] ways to do that."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horror fishing game Dredge coming to mobile later this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/horror-fishing-game-dredge-coming-to-mobile-later-this-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horror-fishing-game-dredge-coming-to-mobile-later-this-year.1002543/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/horror-fishing-game-dredge-coming-to-mobile-later-this-year<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Dredge-The-Iron-Rig-DLC-screenshot-showing-a-scientist.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Black Salt Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Mobile and Mac users will soon be able to reel in Dredge, the rather sinister <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-leads-bafta-games-awards-with-10-nominations">BAFTA-nominated</a> fishing RPG from Black Salt Games.</p>
<p>The news comes from Black Salt Games programmer and writer Joel Mason, who noted this was a "huge day for the steam forums bros who said Dredge looks like a mobile game".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="We've Played Dredge and it's Reely Scary - Let's Play Dredge on PC - new Dredge Gameplay" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rTSHCYdtu2U?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>We've Played Dredge and it's Reely Scary - Let's Play Dredge on PC - new Dredge Gameplay</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rTSHCYdtu2U?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rTSHCYdtu2U?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>We've Played Dredge and it's Reely Scary. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rTSHCYdtu2U" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The developer said both the Android and iOS versions of Dredge "will be premium purchases for the full game". In addition, there will be a demo on iOS and Mac.</p>
<p>Dredge isn't currently available for pre-registration on Android devices, however. This is because, in Mason's words, "Google doesn't believe we own the rights to our own game".</p>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Dredge-on-the-iPhone-app-store.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>This is the Dredge you are looking for.  | <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>If you are an iPhone user, though, you can search for the game now. As a heads-up, you will need to make sure you add the developer's name to get the right one (see image). Dredge will be heading to Android, iOS, and Mac on 18th December.</p>
<p>Since its initial release in 2023, the Dredge team has added some DLC to the base game. Most recently, it debuted The Iron Rig across platforms, which gives players the chance to revisit each of Dredge's main island clusters, while hunting for fresh fish in new micro-habitats created by pools of ooze that have sprung up from the fissures created by the rig's drill. You can read more in our Katharine's feature: <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dredges-the-iron-rig-dlc-holds-up-a-mirror-to-still-wakes-the-deep-and-comes-off-slightly-worse-for-wear">Dredge's The Iron Rig DLC holds up a mirror to Still Wakes the Deep, and comes off slightly worse for wear</a>.</p><p>At time of writing, it is a little unclear from Mason's posts if DLC will be included on Dredge's mobile debut, although he did say "full game", so maybe. Either way, I have sent him a message to check and will let you know if I hear more.</p>
<p>Also, did you hear <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cosmic-horror-fishing-game-dredge-gets-film-adaptation">Dredge was being made into a film</a>?</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill 2 Remake Wikipedia Page Locked to Prevent Review Edit Trolling]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-to-prevent-review-edit-trolling.1002522/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Wikipedia has locked down the&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>remake's page in order to stop trolls from editing the review section to make it look like the game is performing much worse than it actually is.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-wikipedia-page-locked-after-salty-fans-try-to-rewrite-its-critically-acclaimed-reception" rel="noopener" target="_blank">reported by Eurogamer</a>, the page was repeatedly vandalized over the weekend by editors whose motives are unclear, although some are <a href="https://x.com/airbagged/status/1842644442433700020" rel="noopener" target="_blank">speculating</a> that the page has become yet another theater in the tiresome culture war surrounding "wokeness", as arguably meaningless as that word has become.</p>
<p>Whatever the goal of the editors in question, however, the&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>Wikipedia&nbsp;page was being edited to change the review scores of publications like Eurogamer itself, as well as IGN, Digital Trends, and others, to laughably low scores.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/silent-hill-2-wikipedia-lock-street.jpg?itok=zHmGOtLc 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/silent-hill-2-wikipedia-lock-street.jpg?itok=7nr1lgqy 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>remake is getting pretty good reviews, and for some reason, some people aren't happy about that.</figcaption></figure><p>A quick glance at the reception section of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silent_Hill_2_(2024_video_game)" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Wikipedia page</a> as it currently stands shows that&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>is getting some pretty solid reviews; there are lots of four-star and five-star reviews, so it's clear the game is resonating with critics.</p>
<p>What's more, the <a href="https://opencritic.com/game/16791/silent-hill-2" rel="noopener" target="_blank">OpenCritic</a> and <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/silent-hill-2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Metacritic</a> pages for the game show high scores across the board, so I'm not sure what the aforementioned Wikipedia editors think they were achieving here. It's not like it's hard to disprove their edits.</p>
<p>In case you're wondering, the&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>remake launches tomorrow around the world. It's a hotly-anticipated remake of a 2001 survival horror classic, and if you want, you can <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/konami-silent-hill-2-remake-music">listen to around 100 minutes of music from the game</a> right now.</p>

<p>The remake is being handled by&nbsp;<em>The Medium&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Layers of Fear&nbsp;</em>studio Bloober Team, and enterprising fans have already discovered that it contains a rather amusing reference to the original.</p>
<p>As documented by <a href="https://x.com/GmanLives/status/1843114248958066831" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GmanLives on X (formerly Twitter)</a>, the infamous "Silent Hill Ranch" sign, which was written in Comic Sans in&nbsp;<em>Silent Hill HD Collection&nbsp;</em>for some reason, can be found in the remake as well, although you've got to jump through a couple of hoops to see it.</p>
<p><em>Silent Hill 2&nbsp;</em>launches tomorrow on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2124490/SILENT_HILL_2/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/silent-hill-2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft's Troubles Continue as Data Policy Lawsuit Looms]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-lawsuit-data-policy</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisofts-troubles-continue-as-data-policy-lawsuit-looms.1002519/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-lawsuit-data-policy<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Another plate has been added to the ones Ubisoft is already spinning, as the studio is now facing a lawsuit from disgruntled plaintiffs who claim that it shared their data with Facebook without their knowledge.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/ubisoft-facing-lawsuit-over-allegations-online-store-ubisoft-shared-customer-info-with-meta" rel="noopener" target="_blank">MP1st</a> (which cites a <a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/privacy-and-data-security/ubisoft-shared-gaming-data-with-meta-wiretap-lawsuit-claims?" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Bloomberg Law article</a> that requires a subscription), California resident Trevor Lakes and West Virginia resident Alex Rajjoub are suing the French studio over claims that it shared their info to Facebook via parent company Meta's <a href="https://developers.facebook.com/docs/meta-pixel/support/pixel-helper/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">pixel tracker</a>.</p>
<p>The two plaintiffs claim that while signed up to the Ubisoft+ subscription service, they "downloaded one game while they were logged into Facebook", in MP1st's words, and Ubisoft then gathered info from that download and shared it with Facebook.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ubisoft-lawsuit-valhalla.jpg?itok=bMRc0VUe 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ubisoft-lawsuit-valhalla.jpg?itok=ydt2l_nH 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ubisoft is in trouble for allegedly collecting users' data without their consent.</figcaption></figure><p>Lakes and Rajjoub contend that they weren't aware their data was being shared to Facebook. Presumably, because they weren't aware, they therefore also couldn't give consent.</p>
<p>As MP1st points out, the pixel tracker has also been the subject of <a href="https://www.bipc.com/meta-pixel-a-new-target-for-privacy-litigation" rel="noopener" target="_blank">several other class action lawsuits</a>, so it's not just Lakes and Rajjoub that are upset with its use.</p>
<p>To reiterate, though, it's specifically Ubisoft in the firing line here; as the original Bloomberg Law article points out, Ubisoft is being accused of sharing the data it collected with Meta, with the class action lawsuit alleging "wiretapping and other privacy violations" on the studio's part.</p>
<p>This lawsuit comes at what is probably one of the worst times it could possibly have arrived for Ubisoft, as the company is dealing with several other challenges at the moment.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-outlaws-ubisoft.jpg?itok=9loBHSr- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-outlaws-ubisoft.jpg?itok=YnMFZz00 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ubisoft is already dealing with several other problems, including the underperformance of&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Back in September, upcoming RPG&nbsp;<em>Assassin's Creed Shadows&nbsp;</em>was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-february">delayed until next year</a>, and alongside that delay, Ubisoft also revealed that open-world action-adventure game&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a>&nbsp;</em>had underperformed.</p>
<p>The company is also dealing with <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/activist-ubisoft-investor-open-letter-change">challenges</a> from some of its investors, as well as <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-strike-investor-letter">a three-day strike</a> that's expected to take place later this month over return-to-work policy and low salaries.</p>
<p>Amidst this turmoil, Ubisoft bosses the Guillemots, alongside investor Tencent, are <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ubisoft-bosses-tencent-private-buyout-report">reportedly considering taking the company private</a>, although nothing has been announced by the studio itself yet. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Disneyfication Of Fortnite Won't Let You Take Mickey Mouse On A Killing Spree]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-fortnite-project-mickey-mouse-1851666530</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-disneyfication-of-fortnite-wont-let-you-take-mickey-mouse-on-a-killing-spree.1002516/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-fortnite-project-mickey-mouse-1851666530<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Back in February, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-games-15-billion-fortnite-1851236865?_gl=1*1j8dzbm*_ga*MTM1ODc4MTMxOS4xNzIxMzEwNzc3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODA1NTA2Mi44Mi4xLjE3MjgwNTc0MzcuNTMuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-games-15-billion-fortnite-1851236865?_gl=1*1j8dzbm*_ga*MTM1ODc4MTMxOS4xNzIxMzEwNzc3*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTcyODA1NTA2Mi44Mi4xLjE3MjgwNTc0MzcuNTMuMC4w">we learned that Disney had invested an astonishing $1.5 billion in game developer Epic</a></span>, as the two companies set out to create what they called “a new persistent universe.” Little more was known how this integration would work, but now an interview with Epic management <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/4/24261555/epic-disney-fortnite-unreal-fest&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/4/24261555/epic-disney-fortnite-unreal-fest" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">by <em>The Verge</em></a></span> has made things a teeny bit more clear.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196395" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="80" data-playlist="196395,194440,195386" data-current="196395"><div><p>The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21945.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Obviously, Disney is already heavily interwoven with <em>Fortnite</em>. Just this last Saturday saw some 5.6 million people show up simultaneously—numbers not even the biggest games on Steam could dream of—to battle a colossal Doctor Doom, who appeared on the island following weeks of the battle royale foreshadowing Marvel-based storylines. That came a week after skins for Pixar’s <em>The Incredibles </em>characters were added to the game, alongside cosmetics for Deadpool and Wolverine. Let alone the years of <em>Star Wars</em>-related inclusions in the massive game.</p><p><strong>Read More:</strong> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-games-15-billion-fortnite-1851236865&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/disney-epic-games-15-billion-fortnite-1851236865">Disney Will Develop A ‘New Persistent Universe’ With Epic Games</a></span></p><p>However, what the two mega-corps have planned is something that builds on all of this, but in an overlapping space. <em>The Verge</em> spoke to Epic’s executive vice president, Saxs Persson, who told them, “Disney wants a persistent place where all things Disney can be there, but they want to be part of an ecosystem we’ve built.” The idea being, you can discover the Disney-focused aspect of this future project via <em>Fortnite</em>, or you can come into it through other portals, but it’ll all somehow integrate together.</p><p> “We see the power of ecosystems interoperating as being really the magic here, continued Persson. “From a player perspective, you want to be able to flow between a <em>Fortnite</em> experience, a Disney experience, or any experience really.” So all the skins and characters you may have collected in <em>Fortnite</em>, or in similarly overlapping survival crafting game, <em>Lego Fortnite</em>, or perhaps even <em>Rocket League</em>, will transfer to this Disney space. However, it’s looking unlikely this will be an entirely  two-way street.</p><p> “Not every outfit will be able to do everything,” Persson told <em>The Verge</em>. “A minifig doesn’t hold a gun...Some IPs are not teen IPs or mature IPs. They are E for everyone IPs.” Which is to say, there’s obviously no desire with Disney to see its beloved children’s characters making headshots with a bolt-action sniper rifle, and as such, devastatingly, we’re still a long way off getting to see Donald Duck finally take his rightful revenge against that smug, dumb-voiced mouse via the means of rapid fire SMG.</p><p>What Disney’s own space will entail is still under wraps, but my money would be on something adjacent to the enormously popular <em>Disney Dreamlight Valley</em>, but with more emphasis on multiplayer events and interaction. Then you’ll be able to bring in all your Disney IP-based <em>Fortnite-</em>accrued skins and items, albeit without their arsenal of weapons, in a festival of corporate joy.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Come True now available for Xbox One]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/death-come-true-now-available-for-xbox-one</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-come-true-now-available-for-xbox-one.1002510/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/10/death-come-true-now-available-for-xbox-one<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Kazutaka Kodaka's full-motion video game adds another platform.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > IzanagiGames [96 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/izanagigames">IzanagiGames</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Too Kyo Games [66 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/too-kyo-games">Too Kyo Games</a> have released and <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,547 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> version of <a title="Genres > FMV [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/fmv">full-motion video game</a> <em><a title="Games > Death Come True [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/death-come-true">Death Come True</a></em> via <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/death-come-true/9nn8j5bfpz6k" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> for $15.99. The PC version is also now available via Microsoft Store. <span id="more-919809"></span></p><p><em>Death Come True</em> first launched for Switch, iOS, and Android on June 25, 2020, followed by PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1321070/Death_Come_True/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on July 17, 2020, PlayStation 4 on October 15, 2020, and PlayStation 5 on September 19, 2024. A physical edition is also available for PlayStation 4 in Japan.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>“A new wave interactive movie game” where your <a title="Genres > Action [2,225 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s, and the ending of the story, are determined by your choices.</p><p>A completely new science fiction mystery, in full-length live-action movie format, from genius creator of the <em><a title="Series > Danganronpa [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/danganronpa">Danganronpa</a></em> series, Kazutaka Kodaka.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Player controls are simple and straightforward: just swipe to look around and tap to make a selection. Even if you are a beginner, you can enjoy the game as if you were watching a movie.</p><p>The protagonist acts as you make choices in each scene, moving the story forward. What ending awaits you after you’ve made your choices?</p><p><strong>Cast</strong></p><ul><li>Kanata Hongo as Makoto Karaki</li><li>Chiaki Kuriyama as <a title="Games > Aka [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/aka">Aka</a>ne Sachimura</li><li>Win Morisaki as Nozomu Kuji</li><li>Yuki Kaji as the Concierge</li><li>Chihiro Yamamoto as Nene Kurushima</li><li>Jiro Sato as Kenichi Mino</li></ul><p><strong>Theme Song</strong></p><p>“Inner Circle” by Kami-sama, I have noticed (Warner Music Japan)</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>In a hotel room, there is a man lying on the bed.</p><p>He wakes up to the piercing sound of the phone ringing.</p><p>Picking up the phone, he hears a message from the hotel concierge,</p><p>“If you have any trouble, please visit the front desk.”</p><p>He doesn’t even know why he is in the hotel.</p><p>In fact, he doesn’t remember anything at all.</p><p>As he begins to look around, he suddenly finds a woman tied up and unconscious.</p><p>The evening news on the TV shows the man himself, allegedly wanted as a serial killer.</p><p>Then comes the sound of knocking on the door.</p><p><strong>Collect “Death Medals”</strong></p><p>Each time the protagonist experiences a new “death,” you can collect “Death Medals” based on the way he died. Depending on the number of the medals you collect, special movies called “DeathTube” will become available. Try and collect them all!</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GreedFall 2: The Dying World Preview – A Dated Feel]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/greedfall-2-the-dying-world/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/greedfall-2-the-dying-world-preview-%E2%80%93-a-dated-feel.1002489/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/greedfall-2-the-dying-world/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Admittedly, GreedFall II: The Dying World was my first experience with <a href="https://wccftech.com/greedfall-2-the-dying-world-hands-on-preview-swapping-places-with-dragon-age/">the franchise</a>, and it really wasn't a good one. Even though the game is in Early Access, I don't think it's even ready for that. Within the first 30 minutes of the game, I was immediately aware of how janky this game was and how dated it felt despite being developed and released for a modern audience. Admittedly, after seeing the main menu, I was hopeful and thought that the game had a lot of potential, as it's very aesthetically pleasing. However, my feelings were in the wrong place.</p>
<p>I got into the opening cutscene, which then took me into character creation, and I was hugely disappointed. The character creation was severely lacking- with the only options that 'mattered' to change being the hair. The several face presets that were available didn't offer much variation, and most of them had no 'attractive' qualities. There was only one face preset that I found remotely tolerable with the wild, untamed curls I used. It has been confirmed that face sliders will be added in the future, which is at least an upcoming benefit to making pretty characters in the game. Overall, the character creation is severely lacking, and the physics of the hair reminded me of that from The Sims 3. It had a chunky choppiness to it and didn't really provide much realism.</p>
<p>GreedFall 2: The Dying World is my first introduction to this franchise, and I immediately struggled to get to grips with it. Perhaps if I had used a controller, I would not have struggled as much, but this was really tricky. While there were tutorials given to you, it didn't really feel as if they were beneficial in any way whatsoever. As someone who had never played a game with this kind of combat system, I immediately found myself struggling. I read the tutorials, but they did not really provide enough information about them. However, once the combat clicked, it really clicked. It became much easier to deal with battles once I understood the system. In the early stages, the combat is very samey, as you don't have many skills to use at this point. Once you get into the later game, there's more variety to it, and you can choose to use abilities or just auto-attack, depending on how many action slots you have.</p>
<p>Navigation can be a little bit tricky to get used to, especially when you're in the starting area and trying to navigate yourself out of the weaving city. To make matters worse, running is a toggle. While I'm very much used to pressing Shift for running, most games I've played typically have you holding the button down. Every time my character stopped moving to look around, I had to toggle it, and sometimes it would toggle by itself, and my character would walk instead of run. The animation of running and walking is very stop-and-start and could do with a bit of buffering.</p>
<p>However, one feature I did really like about GreedFall 2: The Dying World was exploring the environment. A lot of the areas were very aesthetically pleasing to look at, especially with large flora and fauna in the overworld. The sun shining through the leaves was a great touch, and it helped provide an element of realism to the game. it reminded me of a lot of other games I've played with Celtic influence.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/GreedFall2_Screenshot_07-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Questing is quite fun, but sometimes they take longer than they need to because of the markers on the map. If you are asked to look for something, the game sometimes highlights the area on the map and minimap to show you where you should be looking. However, when asked to look for clues near the river to find out what was poisoning people, the item I was looking for was way out of the area specified. I ended up scanning the area multiple times and searching absolutely everything, just for it to be nowhere near the river.</p>
<p>While exploration is a lot of fun, and there are items to be grabbed along the way, the transition between opening a door and stepping into a new area needs some work. Of course, at this point, I am fully aware the game is at the beginning of its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1997660/GreedFall_II_The_Dying_World/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Early Access</a>, and the team is already working diligently on adding fixes and making the game a smoother experience for all. Still, I couldn't help but laugh, noticing how doors would lose all graphical fidelity when opening them, and you and your party would clip through the doors into a blinding light if you stepped outside.</p>
<p>Overall, I had a lot of fun with GreedFall 2: The Dying World, and I'm eager to see what improvements are made during the Early Access period. However, in its current state, I don't think I'll be playing it much more - it needs a lot of improvements.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I really hope turn-based horror RPG Lurks Within Walls gets combat worthy of its lovely claustrophobia]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-really-hope-turn-based-horror-rpg-lurks-within-walls-gets-combat-worthy-of-its-lovely-claustrophobia</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-really-hope-turn-based-horror-rpg-lurks-within-walls-gets-combat-worthy-of-its-lovely-claustrophobia.1002486/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-really-hope-turn-based-horror-rpg-lurks-within-walls-gets-combat-worthy-of-its-lovely-claustrophobia<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Try the demo, beware the ball</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20241006193032_1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>2 Wedges</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
My default movement mode in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror</a> games that actually scare me is: meandering. I seek to approach without approaching, scooting back and forth across the path like a stray hamster, worrying at the corners and avoiding clear perspectives of the route ahead, while keeping the route behind me in my peripheral vision. I have been trained to do this especially by Amnesia, where tilting your gaze too decisively at anything nasty drives your character nuts.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/lurks-within-walls">Lurks Within Walls</a> has no time for my hamstery antics. Developed by Here Be Monsters, it's a grid- and turn-based first-person dungeon crawler - a long-lost cousin of Etrian Odyssey that has wound up in an asylum jammed with internet cryptids, reminiscent in cinematic texture of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fear">F.E.A.R.</a> In keeping with other grid-based dungeon crawlers, it only lets you turn the view by 90 degree angles and travel in straight lines. Going by the demo, it's a promising restraint for a horror game, though they really do need to expand on the combat, which is currently a slight waste of some terrific creature art. 
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="LURKS WITHIN WALLS | Official Annoucement Teaser" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VZTGC7kFWcc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>LURKS WITHIN WALLS | Official Annoucement Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VZTGC7kFWcc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VZTGC7kFWcc?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VZTGC7kFWcc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
In the demo, you wake up on a gurney in a curtained room full of boxes containing weapons and items, plus a medical report or two alluding to hellish goings-on in the recent past. You know the stuff: "Subject X should be kept under visual observation at all times. Do not feed Subject Y prune juice after midnight. Do not ask Subject Z about her exciting web3 start-up." The visuals are dingy and fish-eyed and creased by static. The found doc writing is terse and fairly evocative. Setting off down the corridor, you spy a huge, spinning ball of godflesh trapped inside a cage of spotlights.
</p><p>
The game's monsters are the work of Trevor Henderson, a Canadian artist of some repute, who has a lifelong passion for creepypasta photography. They're an unpleasant bunch, for sure, but what really gets me going about Lurks Within Walls is being confined to 90 degree turns while roaming a small maze of lock-and-key puzzles, awash with glitchy lighting and frankly unreasonable quantities of negative space. Every sharp turn is an opportunity for a scare - it's as though you were viewing one of those slidereel shows 80s horror movies love, waiting for the one that has the spook. </p>
<p>It is also pleasantly unpleasant to glimpse or hear something to your right or left, and not know whether it's sensible to pivot toward or away from it. This being a turn-based game, you can spend an eternity inside that feeling of uncertainty. I would expect the novelty of the format to wear off eventually, but perhaps the developers can keep the suspense up by doing creative things with the audio or monster behaviour.
</p>
<p>
Hopefully, they'll also pamper the combat a bit. Part of the problem is that the options on show in the demo aren't that extensive or imaginative - you pick a weapon, then pick a body part to target based on your hit percentage, chugging health consumables where necessary. The other part of problem is that while the monsters look great in screens, they are purposefully devoid of animations and effects, to preserve that looming creepypasta aesthetic. I'm not sure what to suggest, but the game as it stands squanders all terror during battle. It just feels like you're rolling dice to punch an imageboard post from 2007.
</p>
<p>
Here's a rundown of key features, from <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3197890/LURKS_WITHIN_WALLS/">the Steam page</a>:
</p>
<blockquote><p>
Survival Horror meets Modern Dungeon Crawling: Experience a unique blend of survival horror and dungeon-crawling RPG elements, where every decision could be your last.
</p>
<p>
Fast-Paced Turn-Based Combat: Engage in intense, tactical battles against a range of nightmarish creatures. Gather weapons and items, and confront threats that demand strategy and resource management.
</p>
<p>
Creatures by Trevor Henderson: Explore accursed buildings and haunted settings, encountering terrifying creatures brought to life by the distinctive style of Trevor Henderson, known for his iconic horror art such as Siren Head, Long Horse, Bridge Worm, and many others.
</p>
<p>
Choose your Path: Choose to play as surviving residents, armed with pipes and makeshift weapons, or police officers, striving to eliminate threats and save remaining survivors. Will you seek to escape or search for your lost loved ones?
</p>
<p>
Inspired by Horror Classics: Revive the atmosphere of legendary titles like Resident Evil, Parasite Eve, and Shin Megami Tensei, blending exploration with strategic combat and storytelling.
</p></blockquote>
<p>
And here's a release date: BOO, JUMPSCARE, there isn't one yet. Just the ominous refrain "coming soon". You can also find the demo on <a href="https://herebemonstersx.itch.io/lurks-within">Itch.io</a>, if you consider Steam the greatest horror of all.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[INTERVIEW – Undisputed Boxing With Steel City Interactive]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/interview-undisputed-boxing-with-steel-city-interactive/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/interview-%E2%80%93-undisputed-boxing-with-steel-city-interactive.1002477/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/interview-undisputed-boxing-with-steel-city-interactive/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>After four years since its development, Undisputed boxing is finally here with a full release on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S. Just ahead of its launch on <a href="http://playundisputed.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">October 11</a>, Insider Gaming’s Mike Straw sat down with Steel City Interactive Ash Habib and Director of Product and Authenticity Will Kinsler for an exclusive interview about all things Undisputed.</p>



<p>In this interview, Mike, Ash, and Will talk Undisputed’s full release on console, the updates since the game launched its career mode in beta, what is a success for the team, worries or stress with the game, future updates, and more.</p>



<p>You can watch the interview below. Timestamps are underneath as well as in the video description itself. After you listen to the interview, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/undisputed-review-redefining-the-boxing-game-experience/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">complete review of the game</a> where we tell you if you should buy, wait, or skip.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="INTERVIEW - Undisputed Boxing With Steel City Interactive" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cUg4V-rAt2I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-undisputed-interview-topics">Undisputed Interview Topics</h2>



<p><strong>0:00</strong> – Intro<br><strong>0:41</strong> – Getting Undisputed ready for console <br><strong>1:41</strong> – The biggest gameplay change from Undisputed Early Access to full launch <br><strong>4:40 </strong>– Pleasing boxing fans <br><strong>7:08</strong> – Feeling around what Steel City Interactive has with Undisputed <br><strong>11:22</strong> – Getting new players to try the game <br><strong>14:16</strong> – Any new fighters to announce? <br><strong>16:22</strong> – Any names? <br><strong>17:38</strong> – What would a successful launch look like for Undisputed? <br><strong>19:45</strong> – What part of what Undisputed became surprises Steel City Interactive the most? <br><strong>23:46</strong> – How difficult was it to not just release earlier?</p>



<p>Are you going to pick up Undisputed now that it’s available on console?  Let us know in the comments, and join the discussion in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-moves-to-unreal-engine-5-with-multiple-games-in-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Halo moving to Unreal Engine 5</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>