<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:34:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Round Up: The Reviews Are In For Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade On Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/round-up-the-reviews-are-in-for-final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-on-switch-2</link>
            <guid>1411846</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="b09d1b7326bff"><a title="Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/b09d1b7326bff/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>After being announced for Switch 2 way back in the console's reveal Direct, we are now just days away from the release of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade</a>.</p>
<p>We're so close, in fact, that the reviews have started rolling in, and it's a pretty positive picture. Here at Nintendo Life, we had a wonderful time with FFVII, calling it "one of the best Switch 2 ports so far" in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">our 9/10 review</a>. Here's a brief snippet, followed by the whole thing, so you can read Alana's thoughts in full:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Yes, there are caveats like 30fps, softer screen resolution, and some fuzzy textures. But Square Enix has clearly put the time and effort in here to ensure the best possible result, and with the Episode INTERMission DLC included as standard too, this might be the definitive way to play Remake on the go</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:196050 @ 1769004002 -->
<p>But we're not the only ones with thoughts on the latest Square Enix joint! Below, we have rounded up a handful of reviews from across the internet to try and give you a better idea of the full range of opinions on display. Spoilers, we were not alone in our admiration.</p>
<p>Right at the top of the pile is <a href="https://www.cgmagonline.com/review/game/final-fantasy-vii-remake-switch-2/">CGMagazine</a>, where the outlet scored FFVII a 9.5/10 on Switch 2, praising how the title showcases the console's technical chops:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you’ve been holding off from playing <em>Final Fantasy VII Remake</em> all this time because you don’t have a PS5 or gaming PC, the Switch 2 port is practically a must-play</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://rpgamer.com/review/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-switch-2-review/">RPGamer</a> came in with a 4.5/5 review, arguing that the title "fits wonderfully onto the Switch 2":</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There’s a huge amount to enjoy about the game, be it the exciting combat, impressive presentation, highly endearing cast, fascinating adjustments to the original tale, or detailed realisation of Midgar</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Staying in the same camp, <a href="https://comicbook.com/gaming/review/final-fantasy-7-remake-intergrade-switch-2-review/">Comicbook.com</a> gave the game a 4.5/5, particularly calling out the "absolute bargain" price as a major pro:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade</em> remains $39.99 on the Switch 2 as it has been for PS5 and PC. And for the hours of solid action RPG combat it offers, that’s an absolute bargain in today’s market</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.vooks.net/final-fantasy-7-remake-intergrade-switch-2-review/">Vooks</a> kept the good times going in its 4.5/5 review, praising the progression streamlining and Switch 2's HDR prowess:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Final Fantasy Remake 7 Intergrade is one of the best-looking games on the Switch 2 to date, with an incredible port that compromises on very little to deliver a fantastic version of an already stunning game</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Finally, things dropped <em>ever so slightly</em> for <a href="https://www.nintendo-insider.com/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-nintendo-switch-2-review/">Nintendo Insider</a>'s 8/10 review, which shared many of the positives outlined above, but still felt that the major story beats are a little lacking in this first part:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I can strongly recommend it, albeit with the caveat that you aren’t going to get any meaningful plot resolution within this part of the overall story. If you’re okay with that, then all I can say is… let’s mosey</p>
</blockquote>
<p>All seems very consistent (and rather unsurprising), right? At the time of writing, the Switch 2 version is sitting with a <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade/critic-reviews/?platform=nintendo-switch-2">Metacritic</a> score of 90 based on 24 reviews. We're sure more takes will roll in over the coming days, but for now, it seems, good game is still good.</p>
<p>Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade arrives on Switch 2 tomorrow, 22nd January 2025.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:196050,192951,194129 @ 1769004002 -->
<p><em>Are you excited for FFVII Remake on Switch 2 after reading these reviews? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/round-up-the-reviews-are-in-for-final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-on-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arknights: Endfield Gets a 3X Performance Boost from DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation, Says NVIDIA]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/arknights-endfields-gets-3x-performance-boost-dlss-4-multi-frame-gen/</link>
            <guid>1411843</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>With just a few hours left before the official launch of the game <strong>Arknights: Endfield</strong>, <strong>NVIDIA</strong> announced that the PC version will include support for <strong>DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation</strong>, as well as, of course, for all the linked technologies: Super Resolution, Frame Generation, and Reflex.</p>



<p>According to NVIDIA, owners of a <strong>GeForce RTX 50 Series</strong> graphics card can expect to see their frame rates boosted by an average of <strong>3X</strong> at <strong>4K</strong> with DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation enabled (and Super Resolution set to Performance Mode). At lower resolutions, DLSS 4 MFG <strong>enables most GeForce RTX GPUs to reach the in-game maximum threshold of 480 frames per second</strong>, though that's not particularly surprising given that the game is also made for mobile devices (and PlayStation 5). With all this performance headroom, it should be a no-brainer for everyone to activate the <strong>second-generation DLSS Super Resolution Transformer model</strong> that <a href="https://wccftech.com/ces-2026-demo-footage-nvidia-dlss-4-5-dynamic-multi-frame-generation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NVIDIA unveiled at <strong>CES 2026</strong></a> to obtain improved visual quality. For the time being, you'll have to do it via the NVIDIA app, though native in-game support is also in development by Arknights: Endfield developer <strong>HYPERGRYPH</strong>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Arknights: Endfield | 4K NVIDIA DLSS 4 Launch Trailer - Launching January 22!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SWLsEsTay_8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>The game is a <strong>free-to-play action RPG</strong> with some simulation features thrown in for good measure. You can read <a href="https://wccftech.com/arknights-endfield-beta-test-ii-pc-hands-on-impressions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wccftech's hands-on preview and bonus developer interview here</a>, while the system requirements are available below. The PC version isn't on Steam, by the way; you can only download the game via the official website's launcher or <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/arknightsendfield-f0f167" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">via the Epic Games Store</a>.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th><strong>Arknights: Endfield Specifications</strong></th><th><strong>Minimum</strong></th><th><strong>Recommended</strong></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>OS Version</strong></td><td>Windows 10 64-bit</td><td>Windows 10/11 64-bit</td></tr><tr><td><strong>CPU</strong></td><td>Intel Core i5-9400F or equivalent</td><td>Intel Core i7-10700K or equivalent or higher</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Memory</strong></td><td>16 GB</td><td>16 GB or higher</td></tr><tr><td><strong>GPU</strong></td><td>NVIDIA GeForce GTX 1060 or equivalent</td><td>NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2060 or equivalent or higher</td></tr><tr><td><strong>DirectX</strong></td><td>DirectX 11</td><td>DirectX 11</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Storage</strong></td><td>50 GB free space (+ 40 GB for unpacking)</td><td>SSD Recommended, 50 GB free space (+ 40 GB for unpacking)</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Beyond the Arknights: Endfield news, NVIDIA also shared that <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/styx-blades-of-greed-wont-be-for-everyone-but-thats-okay-hands-on-preview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Styx: Blades of Greed</a></strong> supports NVIDIA DLSS 4 Multi Frame Generation, too, both in the <a href="https://wccftech.com/styx-blades-of-greed-demo-out-now-on-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PC demo that's currently out</a> and in the full game, due on February 19. Once again, <a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-dlss-4-5-super-resolution-how-to-guide-image-quality-analysis-performance-impact/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NVIDIA DLSS 4.5 Super Resolution</a> can be enabled through the NVIDIA app.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, Moon Studios will release the much-anticipated <a href="https://wccftech.com/no-rest-for-the-wicked-together-co-op-update-gameplay-trailer-moon-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>No Rest for the Wicked Together</strong> co-op update</a>. The game already natively supports NVIDIA DLSS Super Resolution and DLAA, and now players can also upgrade to the second-gen Transformer model (DLSS 4.5) through the NVIDIA app for enhanced fidelity, especially when using the Performance and Ultra Performance modes.</p>



<p>Lastly, the indie open world co-op survival game <strong>The Gold River Project</strong>, due to launch <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1253220/The_Gold_River_Project/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on Steam Early Access</a> this Friday, will be released with day-one support for NVIDIA DLSS Super Resolution, with the option to enable DLSS 4.5 in the NVIDIA app.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/arknights-endfields-gets-3x-performance-boost-dlss-4-multi-frame-gen/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Detective games get extra cryptic with TR-49’s code-breaking mystery]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/864630/tr49-review-steam-iphone</link>
            <guid>1411840</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>We’re living in a pretty great time for detective games. Over the last few years, developers have been experimenting with all kinds of different ways of turning the act of investigation into a compelling game, which has led to the likes of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/6/24/8837815/her-story"><em>Her Story</em></a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/18/17993710/return-of-the-obra-dinn-review-lucas-pope-pc-mac"><em>Return of the Obra Dinn</em></a>, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24295956/the-rise-of-the-golden-idol-review-pc-playstation-xbox-netflix-mobile">the <em>Golden Idol</em> series</a>, to name just a few. Now you can add TR-49 to that list — a game that builds on the genre by introducing a bizarre code-breaking computer.</p><p>Developed by Inkle, the studio behind <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2014/7/31/5954611/inkle-80-days-ios-game"><em>80 Days</em></a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/19/18507503/heavens-vault-review-ps4-pc"><em>Heaven’s Vault</em></a>, <em>TR-49</em> is confounding from its very first moments. When you start the game you have no idea what’s going on — and neither does your character. You play as a woman who wakes up inside of a church basement with no memory of who she is or how she got down there. In front of you is a strange WWII-era computer. It has a big circular screen and you control it by using the kind of lever more closely associated with factory machinery than high-end computing. Soon, you hear the voice of a man who tells you what you need to do: find a missing book.</p><p>To tell you much more about the premise would be to spoil the <em>1984</em>-esque dystopia that unravels; not that my description would make much sense anyway. <em>TR-49</em> is a game where discovering the narrative is woven directly into the gameplay. The machine is the only thing you can interact with, and it’s a device packed with information, but the trick is finding it. Each file has an associated code which you have to input to open it. The idea is that by reading through the various files you uncover, you’ll learn new information, which will in turn help you learn new codes for more files.</p><p>I found myself poring over documents I didn’t really understand at first, seeking out names and dates that could be relevant, and then trying my luck coming up with a code. You also don’t really need to carry around a notebook as the game keeps track of important people, organizations, and books through a file system you can reference at any point.</p><p>Playing <em>TR-49 </em>reminded me a lot of <em>Her Story</em>, a game you interact with by searching for keywords in a police database. In this case, a story starts to reveal itself the more you read and start to piece things together. But there’s another side to <em>TR-49</em>, as it’s also part audio drama. While your character is alone down in the basement, you have a radio that lets you communicate with a man on the outside. It’s mostly one way, as the radio will light up when it’s time to talk. He gives you directions, answers questions, and occasionally gives subtle hints when you’re stuck.</p><p>It’s a well-acted drama, and this structure makes the big revelations feel a lot more important than just opening a new file on an ancient computer. It adds a real sense of urgency to a game that is otherwise just inputting numbers. And there’s something very organic and satisfying in the way you reveal the scope of the story bit by bit. It feels almost like you’re uncovering things, rather than them simply being told to you.</p><p>And while most of this unfolds naturally, <em>TR-49</em> does suffer from the same problem as most games in the genre: there’s a good chance you’re going to get stuck. I certainly did. Usually, I just had to take a break and re-read something with fresh eyes, and the clues would jump out at me on a second look. But I also resorted to guesswork a few times, plugging in codes that seemed maybe right, and then hoping for the best. I’m not ashamed to say this typically worked. It helps that it’s a fairly tactile experience, at least on mobile where you rotate dials and pull knobs, so there’s satisfaction in simply using the machine, even if you’re guessing.</p><p>Those roadblocks can be frustrating, but at least in my experience I always found a way to get past them, whether it was taking a breath or taking a guess. Either way, <em>TR-49 </em>managed to do what all the best detective games do: make me feel like I was part of the story, piecing it together as I progressed. You just have to be willing to be bewildered before it all pays off.</p><p><sub>TR-49 <em>launches January 21st on Steam and iOS.</em></sub></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTk3"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Webster</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/864630/tr49-review-steam-iphone]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Restocks Its 15.6″ Portable Gaming Monitor at an All-Time Low and Already Close to Selling Out Again]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-restocks-its-15-6-portable-gaming-monitor-at-an-all-time-low-and-already-close-to-selling-out-again-2000661448</link>
            <guid>1411837</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A multi-monitor setup can significantly boost your productivity, whether you’re working on a creative task, a work deadline, or a passion project. While most secondary monitors are often bulky, there are quite a few portable options around that let you hit all your goals on the go.</p>
<p>One such option is the 15.6-inch KYY portable monitor, which is designed to work with a range of devices, from laptops to PC, MacBooks, phones, and even consoles. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4216/">It usually goes for around $100 at Amazon, but it’s currently available in grey for just $66 at the retailer. That’s after a limited time, 34% discount</a>. Grab it before the offer expires or the stock runs out for good.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4216/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Multiple Viewing Modes</h2>
<p>What’s the picture your mind paints when you think of a dual-monitor workstation? It likely involves big screens taking over your entire desk. This portable monitor does the opposite by offering you extra screen space without the usual clutter. You’re getting a high-quality 15.6-inch advanced IPS screen that delivers a stunning 1920 x 1080 resolution for clear, bright visuals. HDR support offers exceptional color accuracy, while blue light reduction technology keeps the screen easy on your eyes, especially during those long work sessions.</p>
<p>You’ll appreciate the 178-degree viewing angle that keeps the visuals consistent from nearly every position. This means you don’t exactly have to sit right in front of the screen to see what’s going on, which makes the monitor great for sharing with multiple people at the same time. As for the screen size, it’s almost similar to what most standard laptops offer these days. You will be able to stream, work, and play comfortably without feeling cramped. Additionally, the monitor can be used in both landscape and portrait modes. The former is ideal for browsing, watching videos, and gaming, while the latter can be used for reading long documents and even going through social media feeds. Viewing modes include duplicating and extending your main screen.</p>



<p>The KYY portable monitor comes equipped with two fully-functional Type-C ports and a mini HDMI port. It’s made to work with a range of devices (tablets, laptops, consoles, PC), as long as they support Thunderbolt 3 or 3.1 USB-Type-C. There are two built-in speakers, plus a 3.5mm headphone jack for audio as well, so you won’t need to rely on external options with this one.</p>
<p>Durability comes from the attached scratch-proof smart cover that’s made of strong PU leather exterior. It doubles as a stand, so you can use it to prop the monitor anywhere you like. The two grooves in the cover let you adjust the viewing angle, too. Maybe use it upright when you’re working on an important task on your desk, and then tilt it back into a more relaxed position for streaming later at night!</p>
<p>At just 1.7lbs and 0.3 inches slim, the monitor is easy to carry on the go. It can easily slip into your laptop bag and won’t add unnecessary bulk to it.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4216/">To wrap it up, this portable monitor is great for anyone looking to enjoy additional screen space and be more productive. It’s now down to just $66, which is nothing considering the convenience it offers.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4216/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-restocks-its-15-6-portable-gaming-monitor-at-an-all-time-low-and-already-close-to-selling-out-again-2000661448]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Witcher 3 Online Mod Lets You Play the Entire Campaign With Friends]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/witcher-3-online-mod-lets-you-play-the-entire-campaign-with-friends/</link>
            <guid>1411831</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new multiplayer mod for The Witcher 3, called ‘Witcher Online’, lets players complete the entire campaign with their friends. </p>



<p>There appears to be a lot happening with the Witcher franchise. Reports suggest that a new DLC is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-3-will-receive-a-new-dlc-in-may-2026-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">set to arrive by May 2026</a>, and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cd-projekt-red-confirms-the-witcher-4-not-releasing-in-2026-new-trilogy-sticking-to-6-year-plan/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">next installment is also in development</a>. However, it seems we have a long wait ahead before these releases become available. In the meantime, players can explore a mod that significantly enhances the original game’s replayability. </p>







<h2 id="h-the-witcher-online-mod-features-customization-emotes-and-full-campaign-experience">The Witcher Online Mod Features Customization, Emotes, and Full Campaign Experience </h2>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt/multiplayer-mod" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PCGamesN</a>, a new mod for The Witcher 3 has surfaced on <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/witcher3/mods/11590" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">NexusMods</a> called Witcher Online. The mod adds multiplayer to the title, allowing players to play through the entire story with their friends. The mod features chat functionality for conversations with strangers, along with emotes to express yourself even more.</p>



<p>The Witcher Online Mode can be combined with the Custom Player Characters mod to add more customisation, and the Chill Out mod just to have a relaxing time in the taverns with your friends. Check out the The Witcher 3 multiplayer mod in action in the video below: </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Witcher Online Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/E36I77ardm4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Players will need a non-pirated next-gen version of The Witcher 3, version 4.04 or higher. It can be purchased through Steam or GOG. </p>



<p>The Witcher 3 is known for having some of the best choice-driven narrative campaigns, a wealth of high-quality side quests, and some of the most intriguing characters. It is a wonderful experience on your own, which will only be enhanced once your friends join in on the fun. </p>







<p>In other news, The Witcher 3’s rumoured expansion <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-3s-rumoured-expansion-could-take-players-to-a-new-region/">could take players to a new region</a>. Additionally, Netflix’s live-action series <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/netflixs-the-witcher-series-will-end-in-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">will end in 2026</a>. What are your thoughts on the Witcher Online mod? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-still-coming-to-xbox-in-2026-insider-reaffirms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">an insider reaffirming that Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth is still coming to Xbox in 2026</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/witcher-3-online-mod-lets-you-play-the-entire-campaign-with-friends/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pumuckl and the Crown of the Pirate King launches March 5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/pumuckl-and-the-crown-of-the-pirate-king-launches-march-5</link>
            <guid>1411828</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>3D puzzle adventure game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>3D puzzle <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,823 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Pumuckl and the Crown of the Pirate King [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/pumuckl-and-the-crown-of-the-pirate-king">Pumuckl and the Crown of the Pirate King</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,302 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3864960/Pumuckl_und_die_Krone_des_Piratenknigs/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 5 for $39.99 / €39.99, publisher <a title="Companies > THQ Nordic [551 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/thq-nordic">THQ Nordic</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Quantumfrog [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/quantumfrog">Quantumfrog</a> announced. <span id="more-1020349"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via THQ Nordic:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>The famous German kobold Pumuckl is back with a 3D puzzle adventure game <em>Pumuckl and the Crown of the Pirate King</em>. The player controls Pumuckl through 3D puzzle levels, plays mini-games, solves tricky challenges and has to defeat scary enemies.</p><p>There’s always a lot going on in <a title="Companies > Mas [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter Eder’s workshop—especially when the kobold Pumuckl has to tidy up. But while tidying up, he finds a strange bottle, a ship in a bottle, and something is moving inside! With nerve-racking curiosity, Pumuckl opens the bottle containing the ship. Before he can shout “Darn bottle thing!”, the kobold is sucked into a magical vortex—directly onto the ship inside the bottle!</p><p>He wakes up in a magical pirate world that is bigger than it could possibly fit inside any bottle.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Here he meets the quirky and forgetful Captain Krimskrams, who asks Pumuckl for help: the Pirate King has cursed the ship and hides behind a magical door. Only the golden doubloons can open the door so that Pumuckl and Captain Krimskrams can face the king and have him lift the curse.</p><p>In the pirate world, travel is possible through a magical structure with doors to other worlds: tropical islands, enchanted ruins and an ancient pirate castle. Tricky puzzles, skeleton pirates, kobold traps and mini-games await Pumuckl and Captain Krimskrams everywhere. They are accompanied by the cheeky parrot Krakula, who gives helpful tips—or is amused by their misadventures.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Puzzle Level</strong> – Pumuckl moves through isometric 3D levels.</li><li><strong>Mini-Games</strong> – Memory, collecting quests and tricky challenges.</li><li><strong>Couch Cooperative Play</strong>&nbsp;– Second player can help out as Capt’n Krimskrams (locally).</li><li><strong>Parrot Clues</strong> – Krakula gives clues or makes fun of Pumuckl’s misfortunes.</li><li><strong>Enemies</strong> – Ghosts and skeletons.</li><li><strong>Final Boss Fight</strong> – The Pirate King with multiple phases—puzzle, combat, reaction..</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Pumuckl und die Krone des Piratenkönigs - Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3PXeb7fM_rQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/pumuckl-and-the-crown-of-the-pirate-king-launches-march-5]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crimson Desert goes gold]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/crimson-desert-goes-gold</link>
            <guid>1411825</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out on March 19.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Open-world <a title="Genres > Action [3,334 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,823 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Crimson Desert [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/crimson-desert">Crimson Desert</a></em> has officially gone gold, developer <a title="Companies > Pearl Abyss [39 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pearl-abyss">Pearl Abyss</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/CrimsonDesert_/status/2013974920120987867" target="_blank">announced</a>. That means development is complete and the game is ready for mass production ahead of its global release. <span id="more-1020344"></span></p><p>“We sincerely thank our fans around the world for being with us on this meaningful journey,” said Pearl Abyss in a message. “Thanks to your support, we have reached this important milestone. We look forward to welcoming you to the continent of Pywel on March 19.”</p><p><em>Crimson Desert</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,224 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,592 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,302 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3321460/CRIMSON_DESERT/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on March 19.</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/crimson-desert-goes-gold]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roguelike deckbuilder MECHBORN announced for PS5, Xbox Series, Switch 2, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/roguelike-deckbuilder-mechborn-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-2-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>1411822</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Protect Earth and her colonies.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Curve Games [58 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/curve-games">Curve Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Turtle Juice" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/turtle-juice">Turtle Juice</a> have announced <a title="Genres > Roguelike [409 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> <a title="Genres > Deckbuilder [130 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/deckbuilder">deckbuilder</a> <em><a title="Games > MECHBORN" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mechborn">MECHBORN</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,224 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,592 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [882 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [18,212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,302 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3531220/MECHBORN/" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch in late 2026. A pre-alpha demo is available now via <a href="https://turtle-juice.itch.io/mechborn" target="_blank">itch.io</a>. <span id="more-1020336"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3531220/MECHBORN/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Protect Earth and her colonies in a fresh roguelike deckbuilder experience, infusing classic ’90s mech anime with Greek mythology. In <em>MECHBORN</em>, your mech is your deck. Unlock mech parts and pilots, craft custom decks, and unleash devastating combos as you fight to repel the Kaiju incursions!</p><p><strong>From the Chaos, MECHBORN Arise!</strong></p><p>Earth reels under an unrelenting Kaiju assault. In response, TITANCORE forges the “MECHBORN”—elite pilots strong enough to endure the brutal toll of ‘Mech-Synchronization’. Craft devastating decks by unlocking mech parts and pilots to carve your own path across three ever-changing worlds.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Every Card Shift Reshapes The Course Of Battle</strong></p><p><em>MECHBORN</em> doesn’t use a traditional hand of cards. Instead, players start with seven cards in their “Conveyor Belt.” With each card that’s played, a new one enters. Position support cards to unlock new abilities and combine with pilot skills to create combos that reshape the course of battle!</p><p><strong>Your Mech Is Your Deck</strong></p><p>Channel the power of three god-forged mechs, each with their own combat style. Your design determines your strategy in battle!</p><ul><li>Freely mix and match parts to add new cards to your deck.</li><li>Create custom builds or equip a matching set to gain a valuable HP boost.</li><li>Unlock new cards each run to forge deadly synergies and Kaiju-crushing-combos.</li></ul><p><strong>Unlock Pilots To Unleash Epic Skills In Battle</strong></p><p>From Earth to the stars, unlock 12 MECHBORN pilots each with unique skills and backstories. Power their abilities with each card you play, and uncover devastating mech—pilot synergies to unleash kaiju-crushing-combos run after run!</p><p><strong>Attack, Backtrack, and Explore An Ever Changing Map</strong></p><p>With “Adaptive Exploration,” there are no fixed routes. Move and fight freely in any direction as you explore three worlds where encounters will change with every run:</p><ul><li>Remove, purchase or upgrade exotic cards with vendors.</li><li><a title="Games > Clea [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/clea">Clea</a>r territories zone-by-zone to repel the Kaiju advance.</li><li>Discover new factions, influence events and uncover rewards.</li><li>Hunt down ancient research labs to unlock mech-enhancing Infusers.</li></ul><p>But watch your fuel—getting stranded could make you Kaiju bait!</p><p><strong>Give No Quarter, Kaiju Must Fall!</strong></p><p>Stand against a relentless force that shows no mercy! From Kaiju hordes to mech-crushing elites. Each fight is a gamble of risk and reward, earning powerful deck upgrades with each victory. Only then can you hope to withstand the world-shattering bosses, each with unique strategies to test your survival.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p>v</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/roguelike-deckbuilder-mechborn-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-2-switch-and-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders players who spawn late into matches profit more, senior lead confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-players-late-spawn-profit-more</link>
            <guid>1411816</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-man-in-orange-suit.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-man-in-orange-suit.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-man-in-orange-suit.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-man-in-orange-suit.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-man-in-orange-suit.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-man-in-orange-suit.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-man-in-orange-suit.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-man-in-orange-suit.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-man-in-orange-suit.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Embark.</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a> who spawn into maps late actually tend to profit more economically, according to a recent interview with design lead Virgil Watkins.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/third-person-shooter/that-really-sucks-arc-raiders-lead-responds-to-complaints-about-late-spawns-says-late-joiners-are-important-and-profit-way-more-but-embark-knows-its-annoying-to-have-no-time-for-objectives/">Published by GamesRadar</a>, the matter on delayed spawns was addressed head on, as well as whether or not it's good for the players who find themselves a bit late to the party. It turns out, based on the data Embark Studios can see, these players actually tend to extract with more cash in their pockets.</p>
<p>"But similar to the perception of free kits versus what they do, the perception around late joining and what it affords you has been quite interesting. Players are like, 'The loot's all gone,' or whatever else. But players who late join economically profit way more than people who aren't," Watkins said. "The session, when they are fresh, does eventually get quieter, and very often they come across the remnants of fights or can maybe take out bigger drones or hit high-ticket areas more readily than other players. So that's been a very interesting thing to look at."</p>

<figure>

</figure>


<p>Watkins elaborated, stating that the purpose of late spawns was to make sure that maps weren't largely barren of players after around 10 minutes, keeping games fresh throughout the entirety of the game. The team had hoped that players entering a match late would be happy to pivot to alternative goals if they didn't have time to achieve what they initially wanted.</p><p>However, in limited-time events or locked rooms, Embark does acknowledge that a genuine sense of frustration is present. Watkins would confirm that the matter of late spawns is being looked into, to try and find a balance between keeping maps populated and removing that feeling of missing out on stuff at no fault of your own.</p>
<p>"With things like trials, where that is the only objective, then fine, that's kind of off the table and that really sucks, because that was the time you had set aside for it. I think trying to do more on that side of things is where I want to look next. Coming in with a dedicated purpose and that's been undercut by the late join is where I'd want to remove the pain point first."</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-players-late-spawn-profit-more]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hell Hots Up as Doom Is Now Playable on a Pressure Cooker]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pressure-cooker-run-doom</link>
            <guid>1411789</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>There are many things that can currently run <em>Doom</em>; in fact, it might be quicker to list all of the devices that can't run the seminal 1993 FPS. Now, YouTuber Aaron Christophel has added one more item to the list of <em>Doom</em>-compatible appliances: a pressure cooker.</p><p>As spotted by the good folks at <a href="https://retrododo.com/modder-gets-doom-running-on-a-pressure-cooker/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Retrododo</a>, Christophel posted a video explaining how to "hack" the Krups Cook4Me pressure cooker in order to enable it to run a ROM of the original <em>Doom</em>. Do note that we're talking about the 1993 game here, not <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/doom-2016" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="6653da9e-4b23-41d4-a815-ae67196955eb" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">the 2016 reboot</a>.</p><p>It turns out that running <em>Doom </em>on the Cook4Me is actually relatively easy. Opening up the device reveals that it has a Wi-Fi module inside, as well as around 128MB of RAM and Flash memory. That's more than enough to get things cooking.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>The Krups Cook4Me may not look like anything special, but it can run <em>Doom</em>. Image courtesy of Aaron Christophel on YouTube.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I won't go into the technical details (you can watch Christophel's video for that!), but he uploads the ROM to the smart cooker's board, puts the machine back together, and within moments, he's slaying demons on the Cook4Me's tiny screen.</p><p>This is probably one of those situations wherein it's more impressive to watch <em>Doom </em>running on a pressure cooker than it actually is to play the thing. I'd imagine it's pretty cumbersome to try and navigate the game's labyrinthine levels using controls that just were not designed for that purpose.</p><p>Still, it's pretty cool to see id Software's contribution to gaming history still being honored (if that's the right word) by spreading its gospel to all devices and sundry.</p><p>You can check out Aaron Christophel's video to see how he managed to get <em>Doom </em>running on a pressure cooker right here. It's well worth a watch.</p>
<p>The Krups Cook4Me is far from the only place <em>Doom </em>is able to run (outside of the places it's meant to run, of course). The game has also been <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/doom-notepad-is-now-thing" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="615fd2d5-c7a1-4259-a8c0-3f30da3df802" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">modded into Windows Notepad</a> and ported to devices like fitness bands, oscilloscopes, and printers.</p><p>Of course, the <em>Doom </em>franchise is still alive and well, with last year's <em>Doom: The Dark Ages </em>ripping and tearing across PC and consoles (and getting itself a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/doom-dark-ages-chelsea-flower-show" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ad90df29-2a6c-48a6-9ef5-b0c7c81e1bd9" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">Chelsea Flower Show installation</a> into the bargain). Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pressure-cooker-run-doom]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon Sales Reach 1m]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tainted-grail-fall-of-avalon-sales-1m</link>
            <guid>1411786</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer Questline and publisher Awaken Realms have announced that their open-world RPG <em>Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon </em>has reached a big new sales milestone after launching in May last year.</p><p>As revealed in a <a href="https://x.com/TaintedGrail_AR/status/2013682512816402788" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">social media post</a>, (and an accompanying trailer), <em>Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon </em>sales have hit the million mark, which isn't too bad for what is essentially an indie RPG following in the footsteps of the likes of <em>Skyrim</em>.</p><p>Of course, this figure applies across all platforms on which the game is currently available, so it takes into account console sales as well as PC numbers, but even still, that's quite the achievement for Questline and Awaken Realms. I don't doubt they'll be over the moon with this milestone.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon </em>sales are looking pretty good.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>News of <em>Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon</em>'s new sales milestone follows on from the release of the game's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tainted-grail-fall-of-avalon-sanctuary-of-sarras-expansion" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="188bdde8-8def-4173-8507-b661b13feeb8" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">first major expansion</a>, <em>Sanctuary of Sarras</em>, back in May.</p><p>The expansion adds "around 15 hours" of new adventures to the game, according to Questline and Awaken Realms, and it also brings a whole new region to explore, a new progression system to experience, and more.</p><p>If you're unfamiliar with <em>Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon</em>, it's an open-world RPG that shares similarities with games like Bethesda's <em>Skyrim </em>and Obsidian's <em>Avowed</em>.</p><p>Described by its developers as a "dark reimagination of Arthurian legends", <em>The Fall of Avalon </em>promises 50-70 hours of adventuring spread across several regions, as well as "hundreds of side quests", lots of build options, and, of course, plenty of monsters to slay.</p>
<p>If you'd like to see what all the fuss is about and join the million people who've already picked the game up, you can check out <em>Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon </em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1466060/Tainted_Grail_The_Fall_of_Avalon/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/concept/10009530" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/tainted-grail-the-fall-of-avalon/9NNMH5ZRPQJZ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Series X|S</a>. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tainted-grail-fall-of-avalon-sales-1m]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ASUS Crashes Its CPU Liquid Cooler to Its Lowest Price Yet, Matching Black Friday Pricing]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/asus-crashes-its-cpu-liquid-cooler-to-its-lowest-price-yet-matching-black-friday-pricing-2000661442</link>
            <guid>1411780</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The Asus ProArt LC 360 AIO is a liquid-cooling solution that combines a 360 mm radiator with 3 Matte Black Fans and a ProArt aesthetic for systems that require style and thermal management. It’s designed as a fully-integrated liquid-cooling system for use with either an Intel LGA 1700, 1200, or 115X socketed system, or an AMD AM4 or AM5 socketed system, giving you the flexibility to easily move the cooling system from one socketed system to another. On the pump housing is an illuminated Status Meter that provides a quick view of the current system load, temperature, and fan speed.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6804/">You can purchase the Asus ProArt LC 360 AIO CPU Liquid Cooling System for $230 at Amazon, saving $60 and 21% off its regular retail price of $290.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6804/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>An efficient and aesthetically pleasing way to cool your PC</h2>
<p>With the 360mm radiator on the Asus ProArt LC 360 AIO CPU Liquid Cooling System, you have a much larger heat-dissipation area under high-load conditions. The radiator is approximately 15.5″ long and has a narrow profile to accommodate many mid-tower and larger cases that can accept a triple-fan radiator. In addition to the radiator, the overall design of the cooler is intended to provide a clean build experience, with the hardware taking center stage and not overwhelming the build with light effects.</p>
<p>The included AlphaCool Apex Stealth Metal Power fans are matte-black, capable of both airflow and pressure, which is important for pushing air through densely packed radiator fins. These fans can operate up to 3000 RPM, and your motherboard may control the fan speed to optimize performance versus noise level to meet your needs. The fans are daisy-chained together to simplify cable routing, allowing you to connect multiple fans and run a single set of cables to them; this can help declutter the interior of your case after everything is wired.</p>



<p>The pump uses a 3-phase electric motor that delivers adequate coolant flow while operating more quietly than simpler designs. When combined with the 450mm of tubing provided, you can route the tubes to the top or front of supported cases without stressing the fittings. The tubes themselves utilize a braided mesh sleeve to improve durability and create a more finished appearance. Together, these features aim to provide smooth coolant flow to your processor, even during heavy workloads.</p>
<p>The primary goal of the ProArt LC 360 AIO is to provide a balanced build experience, pairing a subtle ProArt aesthetic with higher-end cooling hardware. In addition to the 360mm radiator, the system includes metal-bodied fans, an illuminated status meter, and supports a wide array of socket types. If you’re building a PC that requires a clean build, quiet operation, and no flashing lights, the Asus ProArt LC 360 AIO CPU Liquid Cooling System could be an excellent choice. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6804/">At $230 on sale, down from its typical $290, you receive premium-quality components at a lower cost than you would if you invested in a more elaborate custom loop.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6804/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/asus-crashes-its-cpu-liquid-cooler-to-its-lowest-price-yet-matching-black-friday-pricing-2000661442]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cairn Release Date & Exact Start Time]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cairn-release-date-start-times/</link>
            <guid>1411777</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Cairn is set to be one of the biggest indie releases of 2026, with the title surging past 700,000 wishlists last year, and the wait for the release date is rapidly approaching a conclusion.</p>



<p>The climbing title has garnered plenty of interest already and is expected to surge in popularity to hit a fresh summit when it launches on PC and PlayStation 5.</p>



<p>If you’re counting down the hours until you can jump in, Insider Gaming has all the release date and start time details for Cairn.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-does-cairn-release">When Does Cairn Release?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Reaching new heights. Image via The Game Bakers</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Cairn has an official release date of January 29, but the exact date will vary depending on your platform and your location in the world.</strong></p>



<p>Some players will be able to play on the evening of January 28, while others will have to wait until the early hours of the morning on January 30, as developer The Game Bakers has opted for a simultaneous worldwide release. However, the release times are different on each platform.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-time-does-cairn-release">What Time Does Cairn Release?</h2>



<p><strong>Cairn will be available worldwide at 9 AM PT on January 29 on Steam, but players on PlayStation 5 look set to be able to jump in hours earlier.</strong></p>



<p>The start time details come from <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1588550/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>, showing that the exact time of day for the release with vary depending on where they are located in the world. As such, while the release date is officially January 29, players in some regions won’t be able to jump in until the early hours of the morning of January 30.</p>



<p>It’s a different story on PlayStation 5, however, as the <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/cairn/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PlayStation Store states</a> a release time of 9 PM PT on January 28 on the platform, 12 hours ahead of the Steam release. Should these times change, this article will be updated.</p>



<p>The table below shows the exact start time and release date for Ciarn in major time zones across the world.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Cairn Steam Start Time</th><th data-align="center">Cairn PS5 Start Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">9 AM – Jan. 29</td><td data-align="center">9 PM – Jan. 28</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">11 AM – Jan. 29</td><td data-align="center">11 PM – Jan. 28</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">12 PM – Jan. 29</td><td data-align="center">12 AM – Jan. 29</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)</td><td data-align="center">5 PM – Jan. 29</td><td data-align="center">5 AM – Jan. 29</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Time (AET)</td><td data-align="center">4 AM – Jan. 30</td><td data-align="center">4 PM – Jan. 29</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<hr>



<p>Are you excited for the release of Cairn? Share your thoughts on the game in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, find out all the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/echoes-of-elysium-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date details for Echoes of Elysium</a>, and take a look at all the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-active-codes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">active codes to redeem in Arknights: Enfield</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/cairn-release-date-start-times/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arknights: Endfield Preload Guide & File Sizes Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-preload-guide-file-sizes/</link>
            <guid>1411774</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The action is waiting for you in Arknights: Endfield. But you can’t prepare for it unless you preload Arknights: Endfield, and to do that, you also need to know its file sizes across PlayStation, PC, and more.</p>



<p>The End(field) wait is nigh. A new Arknights will burst onto the scene shortly, and it is a huge push in a different direction for the franchise. No longer is tower defense at the forefront of the core gameplay system, as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Endfield</a> has evolved and exploded into life with action and RPG flourishes. If you’re one of the many eager to dive, find out how to preload now.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-to-download-amp-preload-arknights-endfield">How To Download &amp; Preload Arknights: Endfield</h2>



<figure><figcaption>You can choose your Operator soon enough. Credit to Hypergryph</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>You can preload Arknights: Endfield across mobile, PlayStation, and PC, and it requires you to buy and download the game from the respective game storefronts.</strong></p>



<p>Here’s a quick rundown on how to download Endfield across its various platforms.</p>



<h3 id="h-how-to-preload-arknights-endfield-on-mobile-android-amp-apple">How To Preload Arknights: Endfield On Mobile (Android &amp; Apple)</h3>



<ol>
<li>Go to the&nbsp;Google Play page&nbsp;on Android or the App Store page on Apple.</li>



<li>Search for Arknights: Endfield.</li>



<li>Confirm your purchase. </li>



<li>Launch the Arknights: Endfield application once it’s installed.</li>



<li>Create or log in to your Gryphline account.</li>



<li>Now, you can predownload Arknights: Endfield!</li>
</ol>



<h3 id="h-how-to-preload-arknights-endfield-on-pc-windows-amp-epic-games-store">How To Preload Arknights: Endfield On PC (Windows &amp; Epic Games Store)</h3>



<ol>
<li>Visit the <a href="https://endfield.gryphline.com/en-us" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">official Arknights: Endfield website</a>.</li>



<li>Click on either <strong>Windows </strong>or the <strong>Epic Games Store</strong> in the bottom-right corner.</li>



<li>Download the Arknights: Endfield launcher.</li>



<li>Once it’s installed, you can preload the game.</li>



<li>When it’s ready, you can play Endfield the second it goes live—find out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arknights: Endfield’s release date and start times</a>.</li>
</ol>



<h3 id="h-how-to-preload-arknights-endfield-on-ps5">How To Preload Arknights: Endfield On PS5</h3>



<ol>
<li>Make your way to the PS5 store.</li>



<li>Use the search function to find <strong>Arknights: Endfield</strong>.</li>



<li>Click on the game.</li>



<li>Buy and download Arknights: Endfield.</li>



<li>Preload the game once it’s ready.</li>
</ol>







<h2 id="h-arknights-endfield-file-sizes-on-playstation-xbox-amp-pc-explained">Arknights: Endfield File Sizes on PlayStation, Xbox &amp; PC, Explained</h2>



<p><strong>The file sizes for Arknights: Endfield range from anywhere between 22 GB to 78 GB, depending on which platform you want to play on.</strong></p>



<p>Below, we’ve listed all four major platforms Arknights: Endfield is available on, and this will be updated if additional ports arrive on Xbox or Nintendo Switch after launch.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Platform</th><th data-align="center">Arknights: Endfield File Size</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Android</td><td data-align="center">22.07 GB</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">iOS</td><td data-align="center">23.78 GB</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">PC</td><td data-align="center">78.16 GB (Unpacking) / 33 GB (Actual size)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">PS5</td><td data-align="center">36 GB</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>These seem like reasonable enough download sizes. Aside from the ever-unpredictable PC unpacking size, it’s all between 20-40 GB for what looks like a fairly meaty game. Message the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a> with your thoughts on the game and if you’ve been able to play it already.</p>



<hr>



<p>We have plenty of other helpful tidbits answering top Endfield questions, such as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">is Arknights: Endfield on Xbox Game Pass</a>, and all <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-active-codes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arknights: Endfield Codes and how to redeem them</a></p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-preload-guide-file-sizes/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth Still Coming to Xbox in 2026, Insider Reaffirms]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-still-coming-to-xbox-in-2026-insider-reaffirms/</link>
            <guid>1411771</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A reliable insider has reaffirmed that Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth will release for Xbox in 2026. </p>



<p>For those unaware, back in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-will-release-for-xbox-and-switch-2-in-2026-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">September 2025</a>, it was claimed that Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth would release for Xbox and the Switch 2 in 2026. We have yet to receive any official confirmation from either Xbox or Square Enix, but the insider seems confident it will release this year. </p>







<h2 id="h-final-fantasy-7-rebirth-for-xbox-is-coming-this-year">Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth for Xbox is Coming this Year</h2>



<p>The insider who has reaffirmed the release for Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth on Xbox is none other than NateTheHate. Interestingly, the reconfirmation comes via the insider’s latest <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/2013705307499712834" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> post (formerly Twitter), where he thanked the community for dubbing him r/GamingLeaksAndRumour’s Leaker of the Year. </p>



<p>In one of the comments, NateTheHate was asked whether the plans for Rebirth coming to Xbox in 2026 are still the same, to which he <a href="https://x.com/NateTheHate2/status/2013710238508077359" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">responded</a>, “Yes.” NateTheHate also stated that leaking something about Half-Life 3 is something he will “try to achieve” this year. And, there’s a chance that we might get some new leaks on his next podcast. </p>



<p>Final Fantasy 7 Remake has already released for both Xbox consoles and the Switch 2 on January 22, 2026, and hopefully, the port for FF7 Rebirth should be next on the list. At the moment, all we can do is wait for an official confirmation, but we do know the entire trilogy is making its way to Switch 2; it is just a matter of when now. </p>







<p>In other news, the director of Final Fantasy 7 Remake has stated that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-6-remake-should-be-led-by-someone-else-says-ff7-director/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the FF6 Remake series should be led by someone else</a>. Additionally, the game experience for the third instalment in the FF7 Remake series is “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3s-game-experience-is-more-or-less-complete/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more or less complete</a>“. When do you think Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth will be officially announced for Xbox and Switch 2 in 2026? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-pimlico-leak-reveals-upcoming-fall-guys-crown-jam-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new leak revealing the Fortnite x Fall Guys Crown Jam mode</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-still-coming-to-xbox-in-2026-insider-reaffirms/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't expect the developers of this popular Fallout 3 and New Vegas crossover mod to rework it for potential remasters from Bethesda]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-3-and-new-vegas-crossover-mod-not-getting-remastered</link>
            <guid>1411768</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Fallout-3-Brotherhood-in-New-Vegas.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Fallout-3-Brotherhood-in-New-Vegas.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Fallout-3-Brotherhood-in-New-Vegas.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Fallout-3-Brotherhood-in-New-Vegas.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Fallout-3-Brotherhood-in-New-Vegas.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Fallout-3-Brotherhood-in-New-Vegas.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Fallout-3-Brotherhood-in-New-Vegas.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Fallout-3-Brotherhood-in-New-Vegas.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Fallout-3-Brotherhood-in-New-Vegas.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer/Bethesda Softworks</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Fallout games are enjoying <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-4-new-vegas-player-numbers-skyrocket-thanks-to-the-unavoidable-impact-of-fallout-season-2">yet another surge in popularity</a> following the release of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-season-2-streaming-ratings-down">Season 2</a> of the TV show. At the same time, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-76-gets-another-hefty-patch-complete-with-ghoulish-fixes-and-quest-improvements">Fallout 76 continues to evolve</a> as it approaches its eighth anniversary (haters in shambles). Diehard fans can't wait to learn about the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/locked-fallout-tv-show-countdown-timer-coincides-with-season-2-finale-but-fans-are-hoping-it-also-signals-a-fallout-3-or-new-vegas-remaster-shadowdrop">long-rumoured remasters</a> of 3 and Vegas, though.</p>
<p>After the massive success of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remake">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a> in 2025, everyone's assuming those are happening sooner rather than later, but no one wants a rush job, so we'll patiently wait for news. That's also giving both fans and renowned Fallout modders plenty of time to discuss what they'd like to see in potential remasters and what their plans would be. After all, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/bethesda-game-studios">Bethesda Game Studios</a>' games are traditionally enduring thanks to the community.</p>
<p>Many of those mods are remarkably ambitious, so it makes sense the people behind them are keeping close tabs on the latest regarding those remasters. Now, via <a href="https://www.gamespark.jp/article/2026/01/19/161756.html">Game*Spark</a> (hat tip to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/creators-of-beloved-fallout-mod-no-interest-remasters/">Insider Gaming</a>), we've learned about an important comment posted on the <a href="https://taleoftwowastelands.com/">Tale of Two Wastelands</a> mod's Discord by the creators on 16th January.</p>
<p>"For anyone wondering, if 3 and NV get the remaster treatment, the team will NOT be pursuing this for TTW. It would be a mammoth effort and would require an entire rebuild of the project," developer <a href="https://fallout.wiki/wiki/Mod:Kazopert">Kazopert</a> announced.</p>
<p>Though the news might be disappointing to hardcore Fallout fans wishing for extensive mod support of remastered Bethesda games, it's easy to understand why modders who already poured their hearts, souls, and time into massive efforts are passing on "round two" before such re-releases are even confirmed.</p><p>To this day, Tale of Two Wastelands remains one of the greatest <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout-3">Fallout 3</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout-new-vegas">New Vegas</a> mods released, as it seamlessly puts the 2008 and 2010 RPGs under a single roof, canon timeline be damned. It's a mod I heartily recommend if you're more of a veteran looking to spice things up, especially after the show's efforts to tie lore from different games together.</p>
<p>For now, we highly recommend focusing on the series' present and near future. Later this year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-4-walkthrough-and-guide-4019">Fallout 4</a> will be making its debut on Nintendo hardware with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesda-announces-fallout-4-anniversary-edition-confirms-nintendo-switch-2-version-for-2026">an ambitious Switch 2 port of 2025's Anniversary Edition</a>, so that's neat.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-3-and-new-vegas-crossover-mod-not-getting-remastered]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Surprise Donkey Kong Country Returns HD Update Adds Dixie Kong and More]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/donkey-kong-country-returns-hd-update-dixie</link>
            <guid>1411756</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new update has been released for remastered platformer <em>Donkey Kong Country Returns HD</em>, and it's bringing enhancements for the Switch 2, the ability to play as Dixie Kong, and more.</p><p>As revealed in a <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/2013781050707558700" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">social media post</a> by Nintendo, the update allows you to play as Dixie Kong instead of Diddy Kong in either single-player mode or co-op play, so if you prefer swinging through the air with your helicopter hair, this is the update for you.</p><p>Not only that, but there's a brand new mode available by the name of Turbo Attack, and, as the name suggests, it'll allow you to run through speedier versions of <em>Donkey Kong Country Returns HD</em>'s existing levels for an extra layer of challenge.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>You can now play as Dixie Kong in <em>Donkey Kong Country Returns HD</em>, should you wish to.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>If you happen to be playing the game on Switch 2, then this update will also introduce "enhanced resolution, higher-definition graphics, and quicker load times", and what's more, you're getting all of that for free, which is more than you can say for <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/animal-crossing-new-horizons-switch-2-edition-free-update" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="d3f0290f-c6b5-44ad-83e5-8a42cbb6e299" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">some</a> Switch 2 <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/fantasy-life-i-switch-2-500k-sales" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="91a21696-562a-4257-aaec-a7380b13a7fc" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">upgrades</a>.</p><p>In case you're unfamiliar with <em>Donkey Kong Country Returns HD</em>, it is, as the name implies, an "HD" remaster of Wii platformer <em>Donkey Kong Country Returns</em>, although it'd perhaps be more accurate to call it a remaster of the 3DS version.</p><p>The game packs in all of the levels from the original release, plus the extra content the 3DS version offered, including the extra difficulty modifiers and items offered by New Mode to make things just a little less tricky.</p><p>You can check out a trailer that shows off the new content in this <em>Donkey Kong Country Returns HD </em>update right here.</p>
<p><em>Donkey Kong Country Returns HD </em>is available right now on <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/en-gb/Games/Nintendo-Switch-games/Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns-HD-2590475.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Nintendo Switch</a> (there's no native Switch 2 version, so you'll still be buying the original then applying the update). Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/donkey-kong-country-returns-hd-update-dixie]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JBL Clears Out Tune 770NC Headphones at Nearly 50% Off, Now Almost 7× Cheaper Than AirPods Max]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/jbl-clears-out-tune-770nc-headphones-at-nearly-50-off-now-almost-7x-cheaper-than-airpods-max-2000661433</link>
            <guid>1411747</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>JBL Tune 770NC Headphones are wireless over-the-ear headphones featuring adaptive noise cancellation, smart ambient features, and a lightweight foldable design ideal for watching video, making phone calls, and listening to music. They provide an over-the-ear fit that encloses your ears, Bluetooth 5.3 for a steady wireless connection, and JBL Pure Bass sound that delivers much more bass to your music. Plus, with up to 70 hours of battery life, you can listen to music all day (or longer) without needing to find a power source.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6803/">Go to Amazon to purchase the JBL Tune 770NC Headphones for only $80, down from their retail price of $150. That’s a savings of $70 or 47% off.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6803/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Headphones that add a new dimension to your favorite music</h2>
<p>The JBL Tune 770NC Headphones feature an Adaptive Noise-Cancelling system that helps eliminate background noise and distractions in crowded areas, so your music or podcast is always at the forefront. The Smart Ambient system on the headphones lets you bring outside sounds back into the headphones without removing either ear cup, and the Ambient Aware and Talk Thru systems let you quickly receive information such as traffic updates and airport announcements, or engage in brief conversations. Both modes can be changed using the JBL Headphones App, and volume, skipping songs, etc., can be controlled with buttons on each ear cup.</p>
<p>When it comes to sound, the JBL Tune 770NC Headphones deliver JBL Pure Bass Sound with solid low-end response while maintaining clarity in both vocals and instruments. Bluetooth 5.3 with LE Audio enables seamless, consistent wireless audio streaming to any compatible device. Using the JBL Headphones App, you can select the Audio Mode to get richer music or Video Mode for better lip sync, and you can also choose one of several pre-set EQ options or create your own custom curve if you prefer to customize the sound.</p>



<p>A major benefit of the JBL Tune 770NC Headphones is their battery performance. They offer up to 70 hours of playtime per charge. In addition, a 5-minute charge via USB-C can add approximately 3 hours of listening time if you need to recharge quickly. Additionally, a full recharge typically takes approximately 2 hours. That combination of long battery life and rapid charging makes the JBL Tune 770NC Headphones reliable for extended listening.</p>
<p>The JBL Tune 770NC Headphones feature a lightweight, over-the-ear band-style design that fits securely and comfortably on your head. The headphones fold to minimize their size when not in use and can be easily stored in a drawer or backpack. The headphones also support multi-point Bluetooth pairing so that you can connect to two devices simultaneously, and the VoiceAware feature lets you adjust how much of your own voice you hear during phone calls. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6803/">The combination of comfort, foldability, and flexible connections makes the JBL Tune 770NC a good value for a pair of over-the-ear headphones, especially since they can be purchased today for $80</a>, $70 less than their typical retail price of $150.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6803/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/jbl-clears-out-tune-770nc-headphones-at-nearly-50-off-now-almost-7x-cheaper-than-airpods-max-2000661433]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 Best Games To Play If You Like Hytale]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/8-best-games-to-play-if-you-like-hytale/</link>
            <guid>1411744</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Hytale has recently launched in Early Access, and it’s fair to say it’s been a hit amongst fans and critics alike. Insider Gaming gave it a stellar <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-first-impressions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first impressions review</a>, and updates are already rolling out thick and fast.</p>



<p>However, as is the case with most Early Access titles, there’s only so much of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/where-to-find-thorium-ore-in-hytale-thorium-ingots-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale</a> to enjoy at the moment, with plenty of content gated behind ‘Work In Progress’ barriers. It’s no fault of the game itself, but if you’ve enjoyed your time in Hytale so far and are looking for something with a bit more meat on its bones, then you’re in luck. </p>







<p>Here are eight games that you should play if you like Hytale. </p>



<h2 id="h-minecraft">Minecraft</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Build awesome structures. Image by Mojang.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Let’s start with the obvious—Minecraft. It’s no secret that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/8-things-hytale-does-better-than-minecraft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale was heavily influenced by Minecraft</a>; in fact, the creators began their development journey making mini-games and servers for it!</p>



<p>With that in mind, if you’ve somehow played Hytale and not Minecraft, you should definitely give it a go. Aside from the obvious blocky nature, it has an incredible amount of similarities. From a dangerous night time to vast biomes to explore, Minecraft is the sandbox that started it all. </p>



<h2 id="h-terraria">Terraria</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A minor dimensional shift. Image by Steam.</figcaption></figure>



<p>From looking at the image above, you might look at Terraria’s 2D art-style and wonder how it is at all similar to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-repair-in-hytale/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale</a>? Well, despite their dimensional differences, the core gameplay loops actually have a lot of similarities. </p>



<p>Terraria is filled to the brim with various monsters and bosses to fight, and the constant cycle of mining and getting better gear from rarer resources never gets dull. The game’s progression is as deep as its caves, and if you haven’t played Terraria before, they’re very deep indeed. </p>



<h2 id="h-vintage-story">Vintage Story</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A more realistic take on survival. Image by Humble Store.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Vintage Story is an incredibly underrated survival game that also shares a blocky aesthetic, but don’t let the similarities to Minecraft or Hytale fool you. It is a much more brutal take on the survival formula, so if you felt Hytale was too bright and charming, Vintage Story might be the one for you. </p>



<h2 id="h-stardew-valley">Stardew Valley</h2>



<figure><figcaption>There’s a lot more to it than just tending crops. Image by Steam.</figcaption></figure>



<p>If you look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/first-stardew-valley-1-7-update-includes-new-farm-type-lots-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stardew Valley</a> for the first time, you might mistakenly take it for a simple farming simulator, but it’s so much more than that. Of course, the farming aspect does play a central role in the game, but there’s caving, fishing, romancing—it has it all!</p>



<p>There are hundreds of hours worth of content in Stardew Valley, so if you enjoyed the cosiness of Hytale but want something more long-term, then it might be time for you to open your first farm.</p>



<h2 id="h-valheim">Valheim</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Take to the open seas. Image by Steam.</figcaption></figure>



<p>If anything, despite its visual style, Hytale might just share the most in common with Valheim. Exploration is central to progression in Valheim, and you’ll need to travel across the world in search of more powerful resources, whilst also engaging with the various enemies and hazards that litter the land.</p>







<p>Although Valheim is also in Early Access, it’s much further along in development compared to Hytale, and there’s a ton of content to engage with. If you’re desperate to live out your Viking fantasies, then Valheim should be your next purchase.</p>



<h2 id="h-disney-dreamlight-valley">Disney Dreamlight Valley</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Meet tons of recognisable characters. Image by Steam.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Disney Dreamlight Valley is a deceptively content-rich game full of stuff for you to unpack. It’s described as a hybrid between a life-sim and adventure game, and there aren’t many better ways to put it.</p>



<p>Whilst it does lack the survival elements of Hytale, it does instead feature similar base-building and adventuring aspects. If those are what you love about Hytale, and if you’ve got a strong affinity for Disney characters, then don’t sleep on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/7-best-games-like-disney-dreamlight-valley/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Disney Dreamlight Valley</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-enshrouded">Enshrouded</h2>



<figure><figcaption>One of the best building systems around. Image by Steam.</figcaption></figure>



<p>It’s another Early Access title, but Enshrouded needs to be on this list for its building systems alone. Some truly wondrous creations can be built, and it’s all so incredibly simple, but there’s a lot more to Enshrouded than just building. </p>



<p>Explore and survive in a vast open world filled with secrets to uncover and enemies to fight. It’s a hostile world, but thankfully, there are plenty of items and gear ready to craft. It might share more similarities with Valheim than Hytale, but it’s a best-in-class survival game that’s worth checking out.</p>



<h2 id="h-modded-minecraft">Modded Minecraft</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It’s like a whole new game. Screenshot by Insider Gaming.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Okay, this final entry might be cheap, but give it a chance. If you’ve enjoyed <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-minecraft-crossplay-mod-has-been-created/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale</a> but feel that Minecraft doesn’t quite scratch the same itch, then try modding it! Minecraft is one of the most popular games to mod, and some of them can genuinely reshape the game. </p>



<p>From building factories to exploring new dimensions, the possibilities are truly endless with modded Minecraft. Best yet, if you’re confused or uninterested in debugging a compatible mod list, then there are thousands of pre-curated modpacks ready to be installed and played in moments.</p>



<hr>



<p>Do you have any other suggestions for similar games to Hytale? Share your thoughts in the official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Hytale content, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/where-to-find-dinosaurs-hytale-location/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">where you can find dinosaurs</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-mithril-ore-in-hytale-mithril-ingots-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to obtain Mithril Ingots</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/8-best-games-to-play-if-you-like-hytale/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Developer Behind Fallen Trailer Responds to AI Backlash]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/developer-behind-fallen-trailer-responds-to-ai-backlash</link>
            <guid>1411738</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">The founder, director, producer, and writer behind indie title <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fallen"><u>Fallen</u></a> has responded to claims its reveal trailer was built using generative AI, confirming that it was a "tone pitch" with AI "placeholders [that] briefly escaped the context [they were] meant to live in."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After the Fallen reveal teaser debuted on IGN, commenters were quick to critique it, with one writing: "Woof. Any way to unreveal it?" and another saying: "can't wait to not touch this with a 10-foot pole."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Are game companies even aware of how controversial using AI art is?" asked someone else in the comments. "Why can't [they] just read the room."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You can watch the trailer yourself below:</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, creator Brooke Burgess has clarified that while there are AI "placeholders" in the trailer, the gameplay, environments, cinematics, and combat is "real, in-engine UE5.4 work" and "all writing is mine (no LLMs), all audio is bespoke, VO is from my colleague Kasper Michaels, and all creative support [and] implementation was done in close collaboration with my lead."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I think most of the confusion boils down to context," Burgess told <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/fallen-gen-ai-real-in-engine-ue54-work/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>TheGamer</u></a>. "What ended up being shared as an 'official trailer' was actually our early dev 'tone pitch,' i.e., a work-in-progress UE5 teaser designed for funding discussions. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"There are [AI-generated] placeholders in there, specifically some 2D test assets used to explore mood and presentation (for example, how 'lost souls' and fallen angels in the game might react when spoken to and judged, along with [work-in-progress] HUD elements). That material was never intended as final content, nor as a statement on how the shipped game would be made."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a separate interview, Burgess told <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/fallen-creator-brooke-burgess-on-the-struggle-to-get-game-funding-above-1-million" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>GamesIndustry.biz</u></a> last week that he was not "waving the flag of AI by any stretch."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I'm not going to sell my soul and be like, 'Yeah, I'll do it by myself, let me prompt this whole game into existence'," Burgess said. "No, I want to work with really talented people and make something cool. But if integrating it in a way that doesn't affect creativity, but helps to save a little bit of money and gets the game out there to people, and gives us a chance to make something cool and memorable, and then make something else after that — it's something I have to factor in."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">He also revealed that "every" prospective publisher has asked how he intends to use AI to "save money."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Every publisher I've talked to has brought up: 'So, have you thought about how AI might be able to save money on this?'" he added. "Almost all of them. They want to know that you're thinking about it, that you understand the potential."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fallen is an "epic dark fantasy action adventure game" featuring an avenging angel sent to the depths of Hell for one purpose — "to judge every demon, lost soul, and fallen angel, and bring an end to the cycle of suffering once and for all!" We don't have a release date or even a release windows at this time, but it is expected to come to both PC and consoles.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Opinion on the use of AI in games continues to divide studios and their fans, with some vehemently against its use, while others claim it's an inevitable part of the future. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rockstar-co-founder-and-former-gta-writer-dan-houser-says-ai-is-like-when-we-fed-cows-with-cows-and-got-mad-cow-disease"><u>Rockstar co-founder and former Grand Theft Auto writer Dan Houser recently likened AI to mad cow disease</u></a>, but the CEO of Genvid — the company behind choose-your-own-adventure interactive series like Silent Hill Ascension — has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gen-z-loves-ai-slop-former-square-enix-exec-claims-a-lot-of-ai-sentiment-is-driven-by-emotion-rather-than-logic"><u>claimed "consumers generally do not care" about generative AI in games, and stated that: "Gen Z loves AI slop."</u></a></p><p data-cy="paragraph">EA CEO Andrew Wilson has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-says-ai-is-the-very-core-of-its-business-what-does-that-mean"><u>said AI is "the very core of our business,"</u></a> and Square Enix recently implemented mass layoffs and reorganized, saying it needed to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-undergoes-mass-layoffs-as-it-reorganizes-to-consolidate-development-in-japan"><u>be "aggressive in applying AI</u></a>." Dead Space creator Glen Schofield also recently detailed <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dead-space-creator-glen-schofield-thinks-the-games-industry-is-broken-beaten-and-battered"><u>his plans to “fix” the industry in part via the use of generative AI in game development</u></a>, and former God of War dev Meghan Morgan Juinio said: "... if we don’t embrace [AI], <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/former-god-of-war-dev-on-the-use-of-ai-in-games-development-if-we-dont-embrace-it-were-selling-ourselves-short"><u>I think we’re selling ourselves short</u></a>.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/developer-behind-fallen-trailer-responds-to-ai-backlash]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Yakuza Kiwami 3 demo is rolling out today!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/21/a-yakuza-kiwami-3-demo-is-rolling-out-today/</link>
            <guid>1411729</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Sega has announced that a free demo for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/yakuza-kiwami-3">Yakuza Kiwami 3</a> &amp; Dark Ties is rolling out this week, starting today on PC and going live on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PS5</a>, Xbox Series X|S and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Switch 2</a> tomorrow. The full release is coming on 12th February in just a few weeks.</p>
<p>The demo will be live on Steam from 3PM GMT today, 21st January, but console players will have to wait 14 hours until 5AM GMT on 22nd January for the demo to arrive there.</p>


<p>This free demo will give a preview of both sides of this expanded remake. Here’s how Sega breaks down the two experiences:</p>
<ul>
<li>In Yakuza Kiwami 3, players can explore Ryukyu, Okinawa as Kazuma Kiryu, beating down bad guys while dynamically switching between Kiryu’s brutal Dragon of Dojima: Kiwami and weapon-based Ryukyu styles and indulging in immersive side experiences like karaoke, sub-stories, outfit customisation and more.</li>
<li>In Dark Ties, players can enjoy a slice of the all-new story featuring Yoshitaka Mine, exploring Kamurocho and variety of side experiences while also sinking their teeth into Mine’s shoot-boxing combat to stylishly dispose of foes.</li>
</ul>
<p>Yakuza Kiwami 3 is a remake of the third game in the popular crime drama series, recreating the PS3 original with some modernisation and new additions. As Kiryu has to save Okinawa’s Morning Glory Orphanage from those looking to force him and the children out of their home, he’ll be able to jump into a new <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/23/yakuza-kiwami-3-dark-ties-adds-a-new-bad-boy-dragon-mode/">Bad Boy Dragon mode that was revealed in December</a>.</p>
<p>So, what do you do in Bad Boy Dragon? Well, basically, Kiryu joins and leads the Haisai Girls gang to dominance. You’ll gather allies and train them up until they can take on the toughest gangs in the country, fighting in turf wars for territory, jumping into Baddies Battles with a small party of five, or going for a 20-member battle in Rumbles. You can also hop onto your motorbikes and raid enemy bases. There’s a ton of customisation here that looks like it could be &nbsp;a fun timesink.</p>

<p>Then there’s Dark Ties, which sees Yoshitaka Mine trying to bolster his reputation and rise through the ranks. This is a fresh side-story to the main Yakuza 3 tale, but RGG has now revealed the Hell’s Arena underground fight club that you can dive into. Your goal is to dive into 1v1 Hellish Brawls and perilous races to avoid hunters through a treasure-filled dungeon in Survival Hell.</p>



<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/21/a-yakuza-kiwami-3-demo-is-rolling-out-today/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Elite Series 2 Core Wireless Gaming Controller Drops to an All-Time Low While PlayStation DualSense Stays Full Price]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-elite-series-2-core-wireless-gaming-controller-drops-to-an-all-time-low-while-playstation-dualsense-stays-full-price-2000661439</link>
            <guid>1411726</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The Xbox Elite Series 2 Core Controller works with Xbox consoles and PC and emphasizes comfort, control, and customization. The controller itself is white and features a wraparound grip covered in soft rubber. With support for Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, Windows PC, Android, and iOS, one controller can accompany you from the couch to your computer desk, or even to your mobile device.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6519/">You may purchase the Xbox Elite Series 2 Core Controller on Amazon for just $110, a $40 discount and 27% off its regular price of $150.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6519/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>The perfect controller for hardcore Xbox players</h2>
<p>The Xbox Elite Series 2 Core Controller contains adjustable-tension thumbsticks. These allow you to adjust the tension to either loose or tight, based on what feels best for you. Shorter hair-trigger locks allow less travel, reducing the time it takes for actions to register. The wraparound rubberized grip covers the back and sides of the controller, providing additional grip during longer gaming sessions.</p>
<p>You can create up to three custom profiles and switch between them with a single button. Button remapping in the Xbox Accessories app lets you place actions wherever it makes sense for your gaming experience and save each profile for future use.</p>
<p>Connectivity options include connecting to Xbox Series X|S and Xbox One consoles via Xbox Wireless, Bluetooth, or the included USB-C cable. Once connected to one of these console types, you can pair your controller with their Windows PC, Android smartphone, or iOS device to enable gameplay and/or other compatible services. You can also use the included 3.5mm stereo headset jack to connect a wired headset to the controller instead of using an available headset port on their system.</p>



<p>When you buy the controller, you’ll get all the necessary accessories to get started using the upgraded controls right away. Included with the controller are the USB-C cable, a D-pad, two standard thumbsticks, and a thumbstick adjustment tool used to adjust the tension system of the thumbsticks. Additional optional parts to further customize the controller are also available for purchase.</p>
<p>The Xbox Elite Series 2 Core Controller combines improved comfort, additional control options, and greater flexibility in how many devices it can connect to, offering users an upgrade. You can expect up to 40 hours of battery life from the controller, reducing the need to recharge it during extended gaming sessions. When taking into account the adjustable hardware, custom profiles, compatibility with multiple devices, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6519/">and the sale price of $110 versus the regular retail price of $150, the Xbox Elite Series 2 Core Controller is a great way to enhance your gaming experience while continuing to utilize the same systems you have been using.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6519/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/xbox-elite-series-2-core-wireless-gaming-controller-drops-to-an-all-time-low-while-playstation-dualsense-stays-full-price-2000661439]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Random: YouTuber Combines Switch 2, PS5, And Xbox Series X Into One Huge Machine]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/random-youtuber-combines-switch-2-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-into-one-huge-machine</link>
            <guid>1411720</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>It's a beast</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>If you happen to be lucky enough to own a Switch 2, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X, then chances are you've had to do a little rearranging just to get them all to fit correctly underneath (or to the side of) your TV.</p>
<p>Well, YouTuber <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@xnzxnz">Xiao Ningzi</a> has come up with a rather novel – and surprisingly elegant – solution, by combining all three consoles into one giant machine. The result is pretty cool, albeit not one that we'd be in a rush to emulate anytime soon.</p>
<p>Essentially, with a simple press of a button, the 'Ningtendo PXbox 5', as it's been christened, can switch between all three consoles at will. You might be wondering how it works with docking the Switch 2, and this is done by sliding the console into the side of the device, with a red eject button used to pop it back out. The downside to this is that it has to go in sideways, which is a little concerning, but if the vents are kept clear, that's the main thing, right?</p>
<p>Switching between each console takes mere seconds, though we remain unconvinced that it would stay cool enough to keep everything safe and in good working order. Still, it's a fun little experiment, and we applaud the process Ningzi went through to get everything done.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:185726 @ 1769004918 -->
<p><em>What do you make of this Frankenstein console creation? Let us know with a comment down below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FAIqzpbv9Xw" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FAIqzpbv9Xw">youtube.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1769003906 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/random-youtuber-combines-switch-2-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-into-one-huge-machine]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Did You Like Frontiers?’ Leaker Teases Next Sonic Game as Community Pleads for More Than Just ‘Sonic On Generic UE5 Terrain’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/did-you-like-frontiers-leaker-teases-next-sonic-game-as-community-pleads-for-more-than-just-sonic-on-generic-ue5-terrain/</link>
            <guid>1411717</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><em>Sonic the Hedgehog</em> went through a <strong>deep identity crisis</strong> following the glorious 16-bit entries in the series. The transition to <strong>3D gameplay</strong> wasn't smooth at all, and the <strong>many experiments conducted by Team Sonic weren't always successful.</strong> </p>



<p>2022's <a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" href="https://wccftech.com/review/sonic-frontiers-review-wheres-the-fun-in-being-careful/"><strong><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Sonic Frontier</em> is, in my opinion, among those experiments that</strong> <strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">succeeded,</strong></a> as, even with some issues, the game did a great job <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">capturing the spirit of the franchise</strong> while trying to <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">push the formula in a new direction</strong>. SEGA and Team Sonic, apparently, share my sentiment.</p>



<p><strong>Known and reliable insider Nate the Hate</strong>, who has an <strong>excellent track record</strong> with many early reveals (<strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-revealed-january-16th/">including the Switch 2 official announcement date last year</a></strong>) <strong><a href="https://xcancel.com/NateTheHate2/status/2013707082789237065#m">replied to an X user question</a></strong> regarding the <strong>next entry in the Sonic the Hedgehog series</strong>. </p>



<p><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">"Did you like Frontiers?</em>" the leaker replied, leaving <strong>little doubt about the direction of the yet-to-be-announced game.</strong></p>



<p>While the game is generally regarded as a solid entry in the series, the community seems divided on a hypothetical <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Sonic Frontiers 2</em>. </p>



<p><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">"Hopefully the artstyle is more cartoonish. Frontiers felt too much like one of those "Mario in UE5" type videos,"</em> said Reddit user KittenDecomposer96 on the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1qif3a7/natethehate_seemingly_says_the_next_sonic_game/">Gaming Leaks and Rumors subreddit</a></strong>. <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">"I really felt like they dropped Sonic on a generic UE5 terrain and randomly sprinkled some Sonic elements over the place,"</em> agreed Phos-Lux, echoing the wider community sentiment.</p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">The evolution of Sonic Frontiers' open-world gameplay</strong>, however, is making other fans <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">excited</strong> about the possibilities. <em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)">"They could make it open world and connect the areas, let us actually see Sonic's world properly,</em>" said Phos-Lux, highlighting well what Team Sonic could do for the next entry in the series.</p>



<p>As the identity crisis I mentioned above often led Team Sonic to almost completely discard gameplay formulas in favor of others, I would definitely welcome the developer <strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)">iterating on and improving the Frontiers open-world formula</strong>. While the game's plot justified the generic visual identity of the open world, I couldn't help by wonder how much better the game would have been if it had the colorful cartoonish visuals that have defined the series, no matter the quality of each game.</p>



<p>Regardless of how the next Sonic the Hedgehog game will play, it hopefully won't take much longer to know <strong>what's next for the franchise. </strong>2026 marks the series' <strong>35th Anniversary</strong>, and its celebrations would be perfect to unveil what's next for it.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/did-you-like-frontiers-leaker-teases-next-sonic-game-as-community-pleads-for-more-than-just-sonic-on-generic-ue5-terrain/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathon Steam pre-orders no longer automatically try to install Destiny 2, as Bungie fix Freudian slip/bug]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marathon-steam-pre-orders-no-longer-automatically-try-to-install-destiny-2-as-bungie-fix-freudian-slipbug</link>
            <guid>1411714</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Somehow ending up with Destiny back on their hard drives is no longer the destiny of Marathon purchasers</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marathon-pre-order-destiny-install-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marathon-pre-order-destiny-install-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marathon-pre-order-destiny-install-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marathon-pre-order-destiny-install-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marathon-pre-order-destiny-install-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marathon-pre-order-destiny-install-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marathon-pre-order-destiny-install-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marathon-pre-order-destiny-install-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/marathon-pre-order-destiny-install-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bungie</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Ah, no, not that one. That, I assume, has been the reaction of folks who've gone to pre-order the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/marathon-2025">Marathon</a> reboot on Steam, and immediately been informed that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/destiny-2">Destiny 2</a> is sneaking its way back onto their machines. Thankfully, Bungie have now fixed whatever issue was causing the latter to take pre-purchases of the former as a cue to re-install itself.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Yep, ahead of its <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marathons-final-release-date-locked-in-by-bungie-with-the-shooter-finally-set-to-run-out-of-cover-soon">arrival on March 5th</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/marathon">Marathon</a>'s been trying to do its mate and the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sony-are-still-fully-dedicated-to-releasing-marathon-by-march-as-they-sigh-in-disappointment-at-bungies-money-numbers">higher-ups at Sony</a> a solid by persuading folks they might as well fire up the MMO.</p>
<p>Hence the following post from Bungie early this morning: "We've resolved an issue where Destiny 2 would begin installing after pre-ordering Marathon on Steam. We have also resolved an issue where Collector's Edition owners would receive an error when attempting to activate their game code on Steam."</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">We've resolved an issue where Destiny 2 would begin installing after pre-ordering Marathon on Steam. We have also resolved an issue where Collector's Edition owners would receive an error when attempting to activate their game code on Steam.</p>— Marathon Development Team (@MarathonDevTeam) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarathonDevTeam/status/2013752445231305147?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 20, 2026</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Given PC Destiny 2's file size can balloon up to around 170 GB, that's certainly a relief. I'd liken it to suddenly having a piano dropped on your hard drive, but I reckon Destiny 2 would want to be classed as some sort of weird futuristic instrument with a name like 'The Keypresser'. As opposed to Marathon, which would almost certainly insist that whatever the instrument's name was, it must be painted lime green and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nobodys-reinventing-the-wheel-with-marathons-mechanics-says-former-art-boss-so-the-visual-design-needed-to-take-risks">vaguely remind you of plastic IKEA furniture</a>.</p><p>Then again, the Destiny 2 side of the fence has had its own Marathon pre-order problem. Bungie have also <a href="https://x.com/Destiny2Team/status/2013356027261935971">fixed an issue</a> which was leading Marathon-themed gear for the MMO, which is included as part of a Marathon pre-order, from showing up for collection at Destiny 2's special deliveries kiosk. So, people who wanted Marathon got an extra Destiny 2, and people who wanted Destiny 2 with a bit of Marathon in it just got Destiny 2.</p>
<p>If only I was as good at self-promo as the shooter about running around with a wee robot eye. I'd probably be ruling the galaxy by now.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marathon-steam-pre-orders-no-longer-automatically-try-to-install-destiny-2-as-bungie-fix-freudian-slipbug]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JBL Boombox 4 Drops Below Black Friday Prices as the Latest Portable Speaker Hits a New Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/jbl-boombox-4-drops-below-black-friday-prices-as-the-latest-portable-speaker-hits-a-new-low-2000661377</link>
            <guid>1411708</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p data-start="0" data-end="585">A dependable portable Bluetooth speaker is one of those essentials you don’t realize you need until the moment music is missing. Whether you’re hosting friends in your living room, hanging out in the backyard, spending a day at the beach, or heading off on a weekend camping trip, good sound can completely define the mood. Phone speakers sitting in red cups simply don’t cut it, and that’s where a powerful option like the JBL Boombox 4 earns its place. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6802/">Right now, it’s even more appealing thanks to its first big price drop that brings it down to $450 — an 18% discount and its lowest prices to date.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6802/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2 data-start="734" data-end="777">Big, Powerful Sound That Fills Any Space</h2>
<p data-start="587" data-end="1128">The JBL Boombox 4 is built to make a statement, both visually and sonically. Weighing in at about 13 pounds and stretching nearly 20 inches wide, it’s unapologetically large. That size translates directly into sound performance. This speaker delivers room-filling volume with deep, punchy bass that small portable speakers simply can’t match. From blasting music outdoors to filling a large indoor space at a house party, the JBL&nbsp; Boombox 4 creates an immersive, high-energy atmosphere.</p>
<p data-start="1130" data-end="1626">Despite its size, JBL designed the Boombox 4 with portability in mind. A sturdy integrated handle makes it easy to carry from place to place, so moving the party from indoors to outdoors is effortless. It’s also built to handle the elements. With an IP68 waterproof and dustproof rating, the speaker can survive splashes, rain, sand, and poolside accidents without skipping a beat. Durability like that means you can just sit back and enjoy the music instead of worrying about protecting your gear.</p>


<h2 data-start="1805" data-end="1850">All-Day Listening</h2>
<p data-start="1628" data-end="2130">Battery life is another standout. On a full charge, the JBL Boombox 4 can deliver up to 28 hours of continuous playback. That’s more than enough to last through an all-day event and well into the night. If you need even more time, JBL’s Playtime Boost mode can extend listening by up to an additional six hours, bringing it to a maximum of 34 hours of playtime. There’s also a built-in power bank, allowing you to charge your phone or other devices directly from the speaker—super useful when outlets are nowhere to be found.</p>
<p data-start="2132" data-end="2576" data-is-last-node="" data-is-only-node="">Bluetooth connectivity keeps things simple, letting you stream music from phones, tablets, laptops, or TVs. With Auracast support, you can even link multiple compatible speakers together for synchronized audio throughout a larger space.</p>
<p data-start="2132" data-end="2576" data-is-last-node="" data-is-only-node=""><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6802/">The JBL Boombox 4 comes in your choice of three colors.</a> There’s the standard black, a stylish blue, and “Squad” which is a camo pattern. All three options are on sale for the same discounted price of just $450.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6802/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/jbl-boombox-4-drops-below-black-friday-prices-as-the-latest-portable-speaker-hits-a-new-low-2000661377]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Echoes of Elysium Release Date & Exact Start Times]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/echoes-of-elysium-release-date/</link>
            <guid>1411705</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>After a lengthy wait and a last-minute delay last month, Echoes of Elysium is finally poised to release in early access, with the release date and exact start times now confirmed.</p>



<p>The action-adventure RPG hands players their very own airship to customize and expand with crafting, weapons, and more, as you explore the world of Elysium, an environment full of mysteries to uncover.</p>



<p>If you’ve been anxiously waiting for the Echoes of Elysium release date, Insider Gaming has all the details on the exact start time, so you can work out exactly how many hours there are to wait.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-does-echoes-of-elysium-release">When Does Echoes of Elysium Release?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Skybound. Image via Loric Games Inc.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Echoes of Elysium is set for release on Tuesday, January 27, bringing an end to the long wait fans have had to endure.</strong></p>



<p>An initial early access release date was slated for December 4, before a last-minute announcement pushed the release date back to the above date.</p>



<p>The delay allowed the team to be “deeply focused on improving stability and overall game feel,” and was about “addressing real issues” so that when players jump in, the “experience is solid, reliable, and ready to grow.”</p>



<p>Tweaks include crash resolving and smoothing out rough systems, as well as porting the game entirely to a new version of Unity. The result is a build that is “significantly more stable” and “in a far better position,” so the delay has been worth the wait.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-time-does-echoes-of-elysium-release">What Time Does Echoes of Elysium Release?</h2>



<p><strong>Echoes of Elysium will be available worldwide from 10 AM PT on January 27, with a simultaneous release for players across the world.</strong></p>



<p>Details of the start time come from <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2644050/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a> and show that the time of day will vary depending on where you are in the world, with players in some regions only seeing the doors open for them to play in the early hours of January 28.</p>



<p>The table below shows the exact start time and release date for major time zones across the world.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Echoes of Elysium Start Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">10 AM – Jan. 27</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">12 PM – Jan. 27</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">1 PM – Jan. 27</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)</td><td data-align="center">6 PM – Jan. 27</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Time (AET)</td><td data-align="center">5 AM – Jan. 28</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<hr>



<p>Are you excited for the launch of Echoes of Elysium? Share your thoughts on the game in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, find out all the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-platforms-ps5-xbox-series-x-s/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">platform details for Arknights: Endfield</a>, and check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-battlefield-6-season-1-january-27-bonus-content-frostfire-bonus-path-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">everything coming to Battlefield 6 in the January 27 update</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/echoes-of-elysium-release-date/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Arknights: Endfield on Xbox Game Pass?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-game-pass/</link>
            <guid>1411702</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new gacha-RPG title is spinning onto the scene with the release of Arknights: Endfield, and a customary question to ask with every release is whether the title will be available with an Xbox Game Pass subscription.</p>



<p>Arknights: Endfield releases on January 22, expanding the Arknights universe on the back of the original game, which was released in China in May 2019 and in other countries in January 2020.</p>



<p>If you were a fan of that title and are keen to jump into Arknights: Endfield, Insider Gaming has all the details on whether the title is available with a Game Pass subscription.</p>







<h2 id="h-is-arknights-endfield-on-xbox-game-pass">Is Arknights: Endfield on Xbox Game Pass?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>New journey. Image via GRYPHLINE</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>No, Arknights: Endfield is not available on Xbox Game Pass, and it isn’t available on Xbox Series X|S at all.</strong></p>



<p>However, that doesn’t close the door entirely to Game Pass fans as, while it isn’t available on the service, Arknights: Endfield is available on PC, and it’s a free-to-play game, so you don’t need to splash out any additional funds to enjoy it.</p>



<p>While it won’t be available through Game Pass specifically, PC players can still enjoy it. Unfortunately, there’s no similar news for Xbox Series X|S players, as there is no indication the game will arrive on the console.</p>



<p>That might be frustrating for Xbox Series X|S players, particularly as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-platforms-ps5-xbox-series-x-s/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Arknights: Endfield is available on PlayStation 5</a>. </p>



<h2 id="h-will-arknights-endfield-be-added-to-xbox-game-pass">Will Arknights: Endfield be Added to Xbox Game Pass?</h2>



<p><strong>It is unlikely that Arknights: Endfield will be added to the Xbox Game Pass service, as the free-to-play approach means it’s not necessary.</strong></p>



<p>Recent updates to the Xbox app on PC make it easy to launch games across different launchers, so putting the title on Game Pass wouldn’t make much difference, and, due to the free-to-play nature, there’s no need to add Arknights: Endfield to the service if a console release on Xbox Series X|S occurs later down the line.</p>



<p>Free games have been added to Game Pass in the past, however, often providing additional in-game bonuses, so this is a route that could appear in the future. For now, though, there is no indication that Arknights: Endfield will be available on Game Pass anytime soon.</p>







<hr>



<p>What platform will you be playing Arknights: Endfield on? Share your plans in the Insider Gaming Discord.</p>



<p>For more Arknights: Endfield, check out all of the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-active-codes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">active codes to redeem for free rewards</a>, and find out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-release-date-start-times/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exact start time for the title</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arknights-endfield-game-pass/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders Dev Says Players Who Spawn Late Don't Realize They 'Economically Profit Way More' Than Players Who Don't]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-dev-says-players-who-spawn-late-dont-realize-they-economically-profit-way-more-than-players-who-dont</link>
            <guid>1411699</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a> developer Embark Studios has said players who spawn late don’t realize they “economically profit way more” than players who don’t.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview with <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/third-person-shooter/that-really-sucks-arc-raiders-lead-responds-to-complaints-about-late-spawns-says-late-joiners-are-important-and-profit-way-more-but-embark-knows-its-annoying-to-have-no-time-for-objectives/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GamesRadar</a>, design lead Virgil Watkins discussed the extraction shooter’s divisive late spawn system, which can see players join games with around 20 minutes left to go. The feeling from some is that this can be a frustrating experience because it gives late joiners less time to complete objectives, and there isn’t as much loot around. But Watkins suggested the data tells a different story.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We 100% acknowledge the whole thing of, 'Man, I came in to do that trial and now I clearly don't have enough time to do that, and that sucks, so I'm just going to leave,' or whatever. That aspect is definitely not great,” Watkins admitted.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"But similar to the perception of free kits versus what they do, the perception around late joining and what it affords you has been quite interesting. Players are like, 'The loot's all gone,' or whatever else. But players who late join economically profit way more than people who aren't. The session, when they are fresh, does eventually get quieter, and very often they come across the remnants of fights or can maybe take out bigger drones or hit high-ticket areas more readily than other players. So that's been a very interesting thing to look at."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So what is the goal behind the late join system? According to Watkins, it helps mitigate deserted raids. Indeed, Embark distributes loot in such a way so “there should be plenty of stuff for players to do” even if they join late.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It will be interesting to see if Watkins’ explanation here turns sentiment on late spawns around. Since Arc Raiders’ explosive launch, its late spawn system has come under fire from some who feel it needs to be overhauled. There’s frustration on both sides, with those who have to face late spawns having been in a game from the start also expressing concern.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Best Game of 2025</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">“It's crazy that my team can clear a section of Stella Montis, place traps near the popular entrances, and start looting... only to have a full team of three, heavy shield, volcano running players spawn 50 FEET AWAY from us in a random room in the corner of the area... spawning basically on top of us, at 15 MINUTES REMAINING,” said one fan last month. “There is no counter, there is no chance of winning, they bypassed our traps as they spawned in the room next to me.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The ONLY players who should be spawning in five minutes into the raid or later are FREE LOADOUTS. Tarkov got that system down with the player Scavs, and it works very well. The initial spawn should be player loadouts only, then free loadouts come in at 25, 20, and 15 minutes remaining. Does that sound reasonable?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I'm not crazy right? I've spawned literally on top of players who were looting and have gotten extremely unfair free kills because of it. Even reworking the spawning mechanic wont fix it, as you shouldn't have to worry about a random full geared 3-man at 15 minutes remaining after 5 minutes of silence after your team wiped out 12 players.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Spawning in a 20 with gear sucks. Most of the PVP is gone, half the loot is already extracted. It sucks for everyone else too, they are low on meds, shields are nearly broken, and now 3-9 completely fresh, geared players have arrived at unexpected locations you just cleared.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-update-targets-infamous-stella-montis-glitch-but-some-say-rats-are-still-in-the-walls">Embark released a new patch for Arc Raiders</a> that stamped out some infamous out-of-bounds exploits – but players said "rats" still live in the walls of Stella Montis. If this has tempted you into giving Arc Raiders a try, check out our guide to the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/arc-raiders/Best_ARC_Raiders_Settings"><u>best settings</u></a>, find out what <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/arc-raiders/Skill_Tree_and_Best_Abilities"><u>skills we recommend unlocking</u></a> first, and see <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/arc-raiders/How_to_Deliver_Field_Depot_Crates"><u>how to earn loot by delivering field depot crates</u></a>... or you can just wait for the inevitable TV show or movie adaptation, although the team says <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-arc-raiders-movie-and-tv-show-offers-are-already-coming-in-and-the-boss-of-embark-studios-sounds-up-for-it"><u>it hasn't been swayed just yet</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/arc-raiders-dev-says-players-who-spawn-late-dont-realize-they-economically-profit-way-more-than-players-who-dont]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>