<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:22:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Big Hops Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/12/big-hops-review/</link>
            <guid>1403305</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/12/big-hops-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Big Hops Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Aran Suddi">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2026-01-12">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2026-01-12">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>It is about time some fresh 3D platformers to turn up, bringing with them fresh ideas and new ways to enjoy the genre. Big Hops is a game that comes with some big and fun new ideas, like using a frog tongue as a grapple to latch onto points and to grab items from the environment, and using different plants for fun ways to get around the world. But as it’s leaping from platform to plant, jumping through the world, can it stick the landing?</p>
<p><iframe title="BIG HOPS - Announce Trailer | A new kind of 3D platformer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bd7WIf1peRA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Big Hops follows the story of a young frog called Hop who lives his simple, quiet life in the forest with his sister and mum. However, he soon hears a voice calling to him away from his usual stomping grounds to a shrine where he is asked to bring some things to fix the altar. Unfortunately, the voice belongs to the being known as Diss who whisks Hop away to different worlds where he must find Dark Drips to assist Diss, as well as Airship Parts to get back home. The lesson here is that you shouldn’t listen to disembodied voices promising a good time – embodied voices can also be pretty problematic.</p>


<p>Hop visits three very different worlds from his home, including a desert inhabited by rabbit people, an island chain inhabited by otters, and a mountain inhabited by bats. Diss brings Hop to each of these places because there is conflict at each one which draws in the Dark Drips. In the desert, the regular townsfolk are in conflict with a gang, in the islands it is a between one person and the oil company DrillCo, and in the mountains it is punks railing against authority. Three very different conflicts and each one is presented decently, with a wide cast of characters that are brought to life by good voice performances. Each of the locations also look great, filled with vibrant colour and well mapped environments that show where you need to go, but letting you test different ways of getting to points of interest.</p>


<p>Big Hops gameplay has the classic hallmarks of 3D platformers providing open spaces to explore to find collectables, solve puzzles, and assist people in their endeavours. Where Big Hops differs is through its traversal and puzzle solving. As Hop is a frog he has a long and powerful tongue that can latch onto surfaces allowing him to swing across gaps, pull levers from a distance, pick locks, and even engage in a bit of light graffiti.</p>
<p>As if his tongue wasn’t enough, Hops can also make use of a number of plants and vegetables, each of which has its own properties and affect the way you can navigate the world. Mushrooms can be used as bounce pad, a cacti plant can create rope crossings, and the flux plant creates zones of low gravity. These are just three of a wider number of plants that can be used to solve puzzles and find different ways of getting around, though some are exclusive to each area. Hop does get a backpack to store these items in, but space is limited so you won’t be able to carry every plant with you.</p>

<p>In each area, Hop has to try to resolve the local conflict to find the airship parts he needs and to move on to the next world. Much of the gameplay consists of solving big puzzles, usually three, to unlock the path to move forward. There are also secondary tasks available to tackle, but they are not required to move on. Your focus is looking for Dark Drips and solving the issues of the region.</p>
<p>Dark Drips are needed to unlock additional bonuses for Hop, be it additional stamina for climbing, more health, or compasses to locate more Drips in the world. Every time you find a Dark Drip you can take it back to Diss and choose between two bonuses. I wouldn’t agonise too much over the choice as you will eventually get all of them. The worlds also contain hidden challenge rooms where you have to use what you have learned in that world to navigate treacherous paths to grab a Dark Drip.</p>

<p>I initially really enjoyed my time with Big Hops and there are some really fun moments, but through the review period we did run into a number of issues on PS5. One area had stuttering performance, there was some clipping through the environment, skipping music, and more significantly some game crashes and progression-blocking issues. Patches arrived before launch to address most of these, allowing me to finish the game, though I wasn’t able to return to previous areas and did still run into a glitch that locked me into a first person view – this resolved itself when I failed the level. Hopefully remaining issues at launch are patched quickly, because they did detract from my experience of an otherwise charming game.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Big Hops is a good new 3D platformer that will draw plenty of fans with its fun abilities and locations to explore. My playthrough was affected by bugs, with patches coming to address some of these issues in the run up to launch, but there seem to be some teething issues that remain.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Some genuinely good ideas for traversal</li>
														
								<li><i></i>The worlds are well designed with puzzles to overcome</li>
														
								<li><i></i>The cast of characters is nicely varied</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>The story could have been stronger</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Some bugs remain through pre-release patches</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/12/big-hops-review/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘We Must Monitor The Situation Closely’: Current High RAM Prices Won’t Immediately Impact The Nintendo Switch 2, But For How Long?]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/we-must-monitor-the-situation-closely-current-high-ram-prices-wont-immediately-impact-the-nintendo-switch-2/</link>
            <guid>1403302</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>A few weeks after <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">RAM prices</strong> started spiking due to increased demand from <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">AI data centers</strong> which will take some time to normalize, the critical situation for consumers (<strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/micron-exclusive-why-consumers-have-gotten-the-memory-shortage-narrative-all-wrong/">who apparently have gotten the narrative wrong</a></strong>) has now become evident, as prices for some devices have already been increased, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/no-one-can-escape-memory-shortages-says-samsungs-co-ceo/"><strong>more are set to follow.</strong></a></p>



<p>Obviously, video game consoles will also be impacted by the current RAM prices and shortages, and another price increase will make the current console generation even more unusual, as it is the first one to date where console prices increased instead of dropping in the years following their launch. For the time being, however, the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Nintendo Switch 2</strong> may not be impacted by the current unprecedented situation.</p>



<p>Speaking with <strong data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a href="https://www.kyoto-np.co.jp/articles/print/1631945">Kyoto Shimbun</a></em> in a new interview</strong> summarized by <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://bsky.app/profile/ninpatentswatch.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Patents Watch</a></em></strong>, president <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Shuntaro Furukawa</strong> commented on the impact the current high RAM prices could have on the new generation Nintendo system, saying that components are <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">"procured from suppliers based on Nintendo's medium to long term business plan,"</em> and, as such, the current memory price has no immediate impact on their financial performance and the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Nintendo Switch 2</strong> price should remain stable for the near future.</p>



<p>However, given the magnitude of the situation, no one can rest easy. <em>"We must monitor the situation closely,"</em> said <strong>Furukawa-san</strong> before refusing to <em>"comment on hypotheticals"</em> regarding a possible price increase for the <strong>Nintendo Switch 2</strong>.</p>



<p>Although high RAM prices make any new hardware launch challenging, <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Nintendo</strong> could be planning a <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Nintendo Switch 2 Lite</strong> model. During the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Kyoto Shimbun</em></strong> interview, <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Furukawa-san</strong> mentioned that the company wants to make the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Switch 2</strong> accessible to people <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">"who pick up their first console when reaching a certain age."</em> A cheaper <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Switch 2 Lite</strong> model would definitely appeal to a younger crowd but it remains to be seen how affordable such a system would be in the current landscape.</p>



<p>With no slowdown in sight for the AI boom, purchasing a <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Nintendo Switch 2</strong> in the near future seems to be the safest choice for those still looking to get the system. In the future, Nintendo may eventually face a difficult choice: take a hit to its margins to protect the current price point, or <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-price-increased/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">follow </strong></a><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-price-increased/">Sony</a></strong> and <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-series-xs-price-increase-europe/">Microsoft</a></strong> in increasing the system's price after its launch.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/we-must-monitor-the-situation-closely-current-high-ram-prices-wont-immediately-impact-the-nintendo-switch-2/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This week in PC games: Hytale, Quarantine Zone, a weird Batman sim, and a fresh batch of RPGs and shooters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-week-in-pc-games-hytale-quarantine-zone-a-weird-batman-sim-and-a-fresh-batch-of-rpgs-and-shooters</link>
            <guid>1403299</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>What we're feeding the Maw</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hank-drowning-on-dry-land.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hank-drowning-on-dry-land.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hank-drowning-on-dry-land.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hank-drowning-on-dry-land.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hank-drowning-on-dry-land.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hank-drowning-on-dry-land.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hank-drowning-on-dry-land.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hank-drowning-on-dry-land.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hank-drowning-on-dry-land.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>My Next Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Happy Mawday all! This week, I'm thinking about how we can expand our bestiary of Maw manifestations. When describing the beast, we often resort to stock Lovecraftian imagery of a kaleidoscopic kerfuffle of teeth and tentacles, but the Maw’s appearances aren’t always so pulpy and cinematic. Sometimes, it just looks like a blinking cursor, or an expectant child, or a feeling of guilt about not returning a text message from an old friend. Sometimes, it looks like an audience of people who want to read about new PC games. 
</p>
<p>Come, depress yourself with me as we tot up possible indicators of Maw activity. Alternatively, read about some of those aforesaid new PC games. Thanks very much to Editor King Julian for suggesting the majority of titles on this list, which he has been doing with disturbing efficiency of late. 
</p><!--more-->
<h2>Monday 12th January</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1221480/Big_Hops/">Big Hops</a> is a 3D platformer featuring a frog who is given to both the titular big hops and also, tongue-based gymnastics. I guess Big Tongue would have sent the wrong signals as a title.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2797960/Confidential_Killings__A_Detective_Game/">Confidential Killings - A Detective Game</a> is definitely a game that could have done with a better title. You might as well call Mass Effect “Space Shootings &amp; Shaggings – An RPG”. Oh no, I think I’ve just talked myself into this.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/quarantine-zone-the-last-check">Quarantine Zone: The Last Check</a> is a game about playing a border guard during a zombie apocalypse that has the strong potential to be either a Papers, Please-style moral experiment or a crass and gaudy fantasy about brutalising migrants, and is perhaps worth us writing about in either case.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Tuesday 13th January</h2>
<ul>
<li>Out this week in early access, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hytale">Hytale</a> is the previously Riot Games-published sandbox building RPG, now in the hands of the Minecraft Hypixel server founders at Hypixel Studios. This could be Big, though I’m not sure the world needs another cousin of Minecraft with Robloxy game creation platform aspirations.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1937880/Hank_Drowning_On_Dry_Land/">Hank: Drowning on Dry Land</a> (pictured) is a caped debacle in which you play drunk, time-travelling pseudo-Batman trying to escape from a comicbook world. Julian picked this one out in our morning meeting for being a budget experimental immersive sim, akin to Blendo’s recent <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/skin-deep">Skin Deep</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Wednesday 14th January</h2>
<ul>
<li>Fez fans ahoy! <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cassette-boy">Cassette Boy</a> is an action RPG puzzler in which you can spin the world to reveal things or remove them from existence. I like the old school Nintendo handheld visuals and the guiding meditation on object permanence.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2707870/Streetdog_BMX/">Streetdog BMX</a> is six colourful 3D maps' worth of kids doing frightfully Tony Hawkish things on bicycles. Seriously, how do any of these mad children still have groins.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Thursday 15th January</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3316940/The_Legend_of_Heroes_Trails_beyond_the_Horizon/">The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon</a> is the thirteenth instalment in an apparently brilliant RPG series I am resigned to never being able to play before the sun implodes.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3538860/Tabulo/">Tabulo</a> is the latest Balatro-like, which is to say, the latest snazzy application of roguelite mechanics to a concept that was getting on quite well enough without - in this case, chess</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1771110/Craftlings/">Craftlings</a> is… Lemmings, the ancient Psygnosis game in which you try stop critters walking off clifftops, but it’s also a colony building sim, with mines and airships and monsters? This is a truly terrifying piece of retro alchemy.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Friday 16th January</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3459150/The_Fortress/">The Fortress</a> is a first-person turn-based dungeon-crawling RPG in the tradition of Eye of the Beholder and Legend of Grimrock. You’ve been locked up by the Sorceror King. Please attempt to get out.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3973060/NEUROXUS/">NEUROXUS</a> is a dizzy third-person mech shooter that looks like Armored Core 6 but more neon.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3525060/Moving_Simulator/">Moving Simulator</a> is, as you may deduce, a moving house simulator, though I guess that could also be “moving” as in emotive. Perhaps it’s both? Moving house tends to be pretty moving.</li>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2547090/Lunar_Ascendant/">Lunar Ascendant</a> is about playing politics as the very first mayor of the Moon. You will monitor social media, bandy words with representatives of various factions, and figure out your relationship to an Earth now run by super-advanced AI.</li>
</ul>
<p>Other things afoot this week: James and Julian have some preview events to attend. Mark and Ollie are gunning for a bit of that Hytale launch excitement, among other things, and I’m trying to turn around a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/pathologic-3">Pathologic 3</a> review, after only getting code on Friday.</p><p>The Maw’s manifestations may diversify and fracture into ubiquity but we Leech Wizards of games journalism will always be here to intercept its dreadful advance and woo the creature with some absolute gibberish about, I don’t know, overpowered shoes in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-best-guns-tier-list">Arc Raiders</a> or something. Let the cry ring forth once again from the battlements: FEED THE MAW!</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-week-in-pc-games-hytale-quarantine-zone-a-weird-batman-sim-and-a-fresh-batch-of-rpgs-and-shooters]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jackery Is Offloading the Explorer 300 Portable Power Station at an All-Time Low, Priced Like Small Power Banks]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/jackery-is-offloading-the-explorer-300-portable-power-station-at-an-all-time-low-priced-like-small-power-banks-2000658283</link>
            <guid>1403293</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p data-start="0" data-end="547">As the calendar flips to a brand-new year and the rush of holiday shopping fades into the background, many people find themselves holding onto gift cards or leftover holiday cash, wondering what worthwhile purchase to make next. If you’re looking to invest in something practical, versatile, and genuinely useful year-round, a portable power station is an excellent place to start. One standout option right now is the Jackery Explorer 300, a compact yet capable power solution that is now part of a limited-time Amazon discount.</p>
<p data-start="549" data-end="829"><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5851/">Normally priced at $259, the Jackery Explorer 300 is currently available for just $179, marking a 31% price drop and a solid $80 in savings</a>. For anyone who’s been on the fence about adding a portable power station to their gear collection, this deal might just push you onto the buying side.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5851/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>
<p data-start="831" data-end="1327">A portable power station is one of those items you might not realize you need until you really need it. Whether you’re planning outdoor adventures or simply want peace of mind at home, something like the the Jackery Explorer 300 is a must in both scenarios. It’s ideal for camping trips, road travel, tailgating, or even backyard gatherings where access to outlets is limited. At the same time, it’s a smart emergency backup to keep in your car or garage for unexpected power outages or roadside situations.</p>

<p data-start="1329" data-end="1670">Weighing just 7.1 pounds, the Explorer 300 is super lightweight for the power it delivers. The integrated top handle makes it easy to grab and go, whether you’re heading into the wilderness or pulling it out during a blackout. Despite its compact size, it packs enough energy to keep essential devices running when you need them most.</p>
<h2 data-start="1329" data-end="1670">Universal Connectivity</h2>
<p data-start="1672" data-end="2128">The Jackery Explorer 300 can power up to six devices at once, making it a great option for families or group trips. It includes two AC outlets for larger electronics, a 60W Power Delivery USB-C port for fast-charging modern laptops and phones, a USB 3.0 fast-charge port, a standard USB-A port, and a DC car port. This variety ensures that nearly any device you own can be powered or recharged without hassle.</p>


<p data-start="2130" data-end="2530">In terms of performance, the Explorer 300 delivers reliable results. On a full charge, it can run a mini cooler or a television for approximately 4.5 hours. It can recharge smaller devices multiple times over, including about 31 phone charges, four laptop charges, 15 camera recharges, or around five and a half drone recharges.</p>
<p data-start="2532" data-end="2871">Recharging the power station itself is quick and convenient. Using a standard wall outlet or the USB-C Power Delivery port with an AC adapter, it can reach 80% capacity in just two hours. For those who prefer renewable energy or off-grid use, it’s also compatible with solar charging when paired with panels like the Jackery SolarSaga 100 (sold separately).</p>
<p data-start="2873" data-end="3054">Safety and reliability is important. The Jackery Explorer 300 uses pure sine wave technology, ensuring a stable and clean power supply that protects sensitive electronics.</p>
<p data-start="3056" data-end="3327" data-is-last-node="" data-is-only-node=""><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5851/">At $179 for a limited time, the Jackery Explorer 300 is a pretty sweet deal.</a> Whether for outdoor adventures, emergency preparedness, or everyday convenience, it’s a smart way to start the new year with a purchase you’ll actually use.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5851/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/jackery-is-offloading-the-explorer-300-portable-power-station-at-an-all-time-low-priced-like-small-power-banks-2000658283]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Quarantine Zone: The Last Check on Xbox Game Pass?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/quarantine-zone-the-last-check-xbox-game-pass/</link>
            <guid>1403290</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Xbox Game Pass continues to add new games to expand your gaming library, but keeping track of which games are on the service can be tricky, but Insider Gaming is here to help with the details on Quarantine Zone: The Last Check’s Game Pass status.</p>



<p>Launching January 12, Quarantine Zone: The Last Check puts players in control of a crucial checkpoint separating the zombie horde from survivors, tasking you with deciding who gains entry and who is denied, and the choices you make can have serious consequences.</p>



<p>Here’s all the important information on whether Quarantine Zone: The Last Check is on Xbox Game Pass.</p>







<h2 id="h-is-quarantine-zone-the-last-check-on-pc-game-pass">Is Quarantine Zone: The Last Check on PC Game Pass?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Key step. Image via Brigada Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Yes, Quarantine: The Last Check is available on PC Game Pass through subscription from day one of the launch on January 12, 2026.</strong></p>



<p>Quarantine: The Last Check was a late addition to the Game Pass service for January, having not been listed in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-wave-xbox-game-pass-games-january/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">11 games revealed</a> to be coming to the service this month, despite the release window aligning with the announcements.</p>



<p>Instead, the official Xbox social media account teased the <a href="https://x.com/XboxGamePass/status/2009788572078137696" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">reveal of a new game</a> launching onto PC Game Pass imminently, then later revealed that the game in question is Quarantine: The Last Check, meaning PC players have a new game to enjoy as part of their subscription.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-quarantine-zone-the-last-check-on-xbox-game-pass-for-consoles">Is Quarantine Zone: The Last Check on Xbox Game Pass For Consoles?</h2>



<p><strong>No, Quarantine: The Last Check will not be available to Xbox Game Pass subscribers on Xbox One and Xbox Series X|S. Instead, only those with PC Game Pass will be able to play.</strong></p>



<p>Quarantine: The Last Check launches as a PC exclusive and is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/quarantine-zone-the-last-check-playstation-xbox-all-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">not available on other </a>platforms, such as PlayStation and the Xbox family of consoles. Therefore, you need a PC to play the game.</p>



<p>The good news is that Microsoft’s many tiers of Game Pass subscriptions include a host of PC games, though you will, of course, require a platform to play them on, and, at the time of writing, it has not been confirmed which level of Game Pass is required to access Quarantine: The Last Check on PC.</p>



<p>It’s likely an Ultimate subscription will be required, however, as this is the tier that features day one releases across both platforms, whereas the Premium subscription brings new Xbox-published games to the service within 12 months of launch.</p>







<hr>



<p>Are you jumping into Quarantine Zone: The Last Check as soon as it is released? Share your plans in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-release-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed release time for Hytale</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/biggest-games-releasing-this-week-you-should-check-out-january-12-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">take a look at the biggest games releasing this week</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/quarantine-zone-the-last-check-xbox-game-pass/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five-Year-Old Survival Game Icarus Just Sold Nearly 1 Million Copies In Three Weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/five-year-old-survival-game-icarus-just-sold-nearly-1-million-copies-in-three-weeks/1100-6537322/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1403287</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537322">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Steam sales are always a great opportunity to pick up some bargains, and the recent <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-steam-winter-sale-2025-game-deals/2900-7360/" data-ref-id="2900-7360">Steam Winter Sale</a>, which ran from December 18, 2025 until January 5, 2026, was no exception. While many games typically see a spike in sales and players during these periods, one multiplayer game saw a particularly huge surge in sales following an enormous discount.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/icarus/" data-ref-id="5000-513911">Icarus</a>, a PvE survival game from New Zealand studio RocketWerkz that was first released in December 2021, was reduced from its usual $35 price to a mere $3.50 during the Steam Winter Sale - an enormous 90% saving.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="425390967" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6456821,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Icarus%20First%20Cohort%20Launch%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:60,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/icarus-first-cohort-launch-trailer\/2300-6456821\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6456821\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6456821\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6456821\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6456821&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6456821,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6537322&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;icarus&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,adventure,survival&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;rocketwerkz,grip-studios&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6456821},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6456821\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1352\/13527689\/3913164-icarusss.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/12\/01\/icarus_launch_trailer_700,1000,1800,2500,3200,5000,8000,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_dash&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/12\/01\/icarus_launch_trailer_700,1000,1800,2500,3200,5000,8000,master.mpd&quot;,&quot;adaptive_hd&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/12\/01\/icarus_launch_trailer_8000,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_high&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/12\/01\/icarus_launch_trailer_2500,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_low&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/12\/01\/icarus_launch_trailer_700,master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;adaptive_restricted&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/mt-rv-v1.gamespot.com\/vr\/2021\/12\/01\/icarus_launch_trailer_700,1000,1800,2500,master.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1638406980,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="7oz0rHqb" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Icarus First Cohort Launch Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Now, RocketWerkz founder Dean Hall has revealed just how many copies of Icarus were sold during the sale. In a post on <a href="https://x.com/rocket2guns/status/2010559063088934997?s=46" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">X</a>, Hall shared that that an enormous 984,000 copies were during this sales period. On top of that, the game's DLC, which includes two expansions and a "pets" bundle, moved a further 243,000 units.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/rocket2guns/status/2010559063088934997?s=46" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Over the steam winter sale, ICARUS sold just under a million new base game units during the sale (984k). We also did quarter of a million DLC units (243k).</p>  — Dean Hall (@rocket2guns) <a href="https://twitter.com/rocket2guns/status/2010559063088934997?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 12, 2026</a></blockquote>              </div><p>These sales also led to a huge increase in the game's active player base. According to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1149460/charts/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>, the game enjoyed a massive spike in players during December 2025, with a peak concurrent player count of 44,120 (compared to 9076 in November). This is the highest concurrent player count the game has had since its launch month, December 2021.</p><p>Dean Hall is no stranger to hugely popular online games - he was the developer of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/dayz/" data-ref-id="5000-146913">DayZ</a>, a 2012 zombie survival game that tasked players with surviving in a post-apocalyptic, zombie-filled world where other players were just as dangerous as the undead. The game started life as a mod for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/arma-ii/" data-ref-id="5000-38942">Arma 2</a> before eventually receiving a standalone release.</p><p>Steam has already announced dates for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/when-is-the-next-steam-sale-date/1100-6532422/" data-ref-id="1100-6532422">next few rounds of sales</a>, through to May 2026. Coming up in January are the Detective Fest from January 12 -19 and the Board Game Fest from January 26 - February 2.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/five-year-old-survival-game-icarus-just-sold-nearly-1-million-copies-in-three-weeks/1100-6537322/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Splatoon 3 Ver. 11.0.0 Update Launches Later This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/splatoon-3-ver-11-0-0-update-launches-later-this-month</link>
            <guid>1403269</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Here's what you can expect</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="748ac964687af"><a title="Splatoon 3" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/748ac964687af/splatoon-3.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Nintendo has announced that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/splatoon_3">Splatoon 3</a>'s next update is expected to launch later this month, bringing a fresh dose of battle balances to the Splatlands.</p>
<p>As revealed by the official <a href="https://x.com/SplatoonJP" tabindex="-1">@SplatoonJP</a> Twitter account, the update is currently planned for a <strong>29th January</strong> arrival, with "balance changes to battles and changes to some battle-related systems" (translated via Google) being the main attraction this time.</p>
<p>The tweet clarifies that more detailed information about the update's contents will be revealed as launch day approaches, so keep an eye out over the coming weeks.</p><div><figure data-videoid="Z3qjATCE2dk" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z3qjATCE2dk?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytZ3qjATCE2dk" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Z3qjATCE2dk?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z3qjATCE2dk?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed38f12eozxylp&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>841k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>

<p>We still don't know exactly what 2026 will hold for Splatoon 3. 2024's 'Grand Festival' brought regular updates and Splatfests to an end, though the game stayed alive and kicking throughout 2025 with continuing seasonal events and the surprise release of a free Switch 2 update.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the game received a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/splatoon-3-has-now-been-rated-for-the-switch-2">PEGI rating for a Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a>, though Nintendo has yet to confirm anything just yet.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:196081,195801 @ 1768223805 -->
<p><em>What do you hope to see from Splatoon 3's next update? let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://x.com/SplatoonJP/status/2010637877496127698" rel="noopener" href="https://x.com/SplatoonJP/status/2010637877496127698">x.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/ae46e9ebb3f4ea1153dd4043e3880d36 @ 1768222933 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/splatoon-3-ver-11-0-0-update-launches-later-this-month]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's Doom running in Hytale before it's even out, thanks to modders]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-doom-running-in-hytale-before-its-even-out-thanks-to-modders</link>
            <guid>1403266</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-doom-running-mod-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-doom-running-mod-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-doom-running-mod-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-doom-running-mod-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-doom-running-mod-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-doom-running-mod-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-doom-running-mod-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-doom-running-mod-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-doom-running-mod-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Hypixel / Tr7zw</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Well, it was inevitable really. Here I sit, a day before <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hytale">Hytale</a>'s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/with-hytale-early-access-imminent-lead-dev-urges-folks-to-take-a-couple-steps-to-significantly-reduce-launch-day-stress">early access release</a>, to tell you that a modder has already managed to get a blocky version of classic <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/doom">Doom</a> running in it.</p>
<p>Add it to the list of weird places to play the shooter, which already included (inhales) <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-on-a-captcha-is-the-most-frustrating-though-admittedly-raddest-way-to-prove-your-humanity-to-an-algorithm">human test</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-next-weird-device-to-run-doom-your-lawnmower">lawnmower</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/before-you-brush-your-teeth-tonight-remember-to-install-doom-on-your-electric-toothbrush">electric toothbrush</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/doom-can-now-run-on-a-jailbroken-tractor">tractor</a>, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/tweet2doom-lets-you-play-doom-via-twitter">bad social media place</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/yup-a-pregnancy-test-is-the-weirdest-device-ive-seen-running-doom">pregancy test</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-play-doom-using-gut-bacteria-but-the-framerate-is-atrocious">gut bacteria</a>.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Playable Doom in Hytale" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RxVj6_NKRDY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Playable Doom in Hytale</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RxVj6_NKRDY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RxVj6_NKRDY?autoplay=1" title="Playable Doom in Hytale">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RxVj6_NKRDY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>According to modder Tr7zw, getting a version of Vanilla Mocha Doom running in Hytale before it's even out took two or three relatively sleepless nights of work. For that sacrifice, their character can stand in the sky above the landscape and Doom away on a monitor made of blocks. </p><p>As with a lot of the more wacky places to play Doom, I'm not sure it's one I'd pick for an extended shooty run, since its visuals do a bit of a number on your eyes at times. Its creator's endorsement comes with some extra caveats, with them noting: "[It] controls a bit like a broken keyboard, the code doesn't follow best practice at all, but it works enough to play the game somewhat." That said, as weird Doom ports always are, it's undeniably impressive.</p>
<p>This showcase has Doom running on an 80x60 block screen at 20 frames per second, with Tr7zw explaining that the Doom port runs in its own thread, generating a screenshot per frame. "I take the screenshot, downsample it to a size Hytale can handle 20 times per second to place, convert it to blocks with the nearest colour, place them," the modder continued. "And the other way, check for player movement/item interactions to provide input into the engine. Basically the same way logic-wise as you would do it in Minecraft. Just that the code works a lot [differently]."</p>
<p>They're hardly the only modder set loose in Hytale to show its modding potential ahead of early access release. Thus far, Hypixel co-founder Simon Collins-Laflamme and co have shown off in-house creations which let you <a href="https://x.com/Simon_Hypixel/status/2010372558198018181">command a skeleton army</a>, be <a href="https://x.com/Hytale/status/2010098788229361925">followed by a floating lantern</a>, and build a <a href="https://x.com/Simon_Hypixel/status/2009579590713549287">claw-based factory conveyor belt</a>. That's in addition to one of team's devs putting togther a prototype of a <a href="https://x.com/Simon_Hypixel/status/2010412549486063673">custom side-scrolling adventure</a> using Hytale's toolset.</p>
<p>With mod site <a href="https://x.com/CurseForge/status/2008177774255636830">CurseForge</a><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/"></a> set to support Hytale works from day one and Collins-Laflamme having already announced plans to deliver an <a href="https://x.com/Simon_Hypixel/status/2008226527436304682">in-game mod browser</a> at some point down the line, it's looking like there'll at least be the means for the game to hit the sorts of modding heights enjoyed by Minecraft over the years. That's assuming mod-makers settle in for the long run and don't run into too many technical hurdles.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-doom-running-in-hytale-before-its-even-out-thanks-to-modders]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Fire TV Soundbar Plus Hits New Record Low After Two Price Cuts in One Week (Newest Model With Built-in Subwoofer, 3.1 Channel, Dolby Atmos)]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-fire-tv-soundbar-plus-hits-new-record-low-after-two-price-cuts-in-one-week-newest-model-with-built-in-subwoofer-3-1-channel-dolby-atmos-2000658522</link>
            <guid>1403263</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div dir="auto" data-message-author-role="assistant" data-message-id="120afa3f-762d-4d99-b75c-184290b96084" data-message-model-slug="gpt-5-2">
<p data-start="0" data-end="488">If you’ve ever splurged on a new TV only to feel underwhelmed once you hit play, the problem probably isn’t the picture—it’s the sound. Modern televisions are thinner than ever, and while that sleek design looks great on the wall, it leaves very little room for quality speakers. As a result, dialogue can sound flat, action scenes lack punch, and music loses its emotional impact. The good news is that dramatically improving your home entertainment audio doesn’t have to cost a fortune.</p>
<p data-start="490" data-end="768"><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4053/">Right now, Amazon’s Fire TV Soundbar Plus is discounted by 30%, bringing the price down from its usual $250 to just $175.</a> For anyone looking to elevate their viewing experience without diving into an expensive, complicated surround sound setup, this deal is well worth a closer look.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4053/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2 data-start="770" data-end="816">Why a Soundbar Makes Such a Big Difference</h2>
<p data-start="818" data-end="1209">Audio accounts for a huge portion of how we experience movies, sports, and TV shows. Crisp dialogue helps you follow the story, while powerful bass and immersive effects pull you into the action. Relying on your TV’s built-in speakers means missing out on much of what creators intended you to hear. A soundbar is one of the simplest and most cost-effective ways to fix that problem.</p>
<p data-start="1211" data-end="1493">The Fire TV Soundbar features a 3.1 channel configuration with a built-in subwoofer, delivering noticeably richer and deeper bass than standard TV speakers. Explosions feel more impactful, crowd noise during sports broadcasts sounds more realistic, and music gains warmth and depth.</p>
<p data-start="1495" data-end="1787">It’s worth it alone for the dedicated center channel, which focuses specifically on dialogue. This means voices are clearer and more distinct, even during busy or loud scenes. You can finally stop riding the volume button or turning on subtitles just to understand what characters are saying.</p>
<h2 data-start="1789" data-end="1839">Designed for Small Spaces, Built for Big Sound</h2>
<p data-start="1841" data-end="2165">Not everyone has room for a full home theater system, and that’s where this soundbar really shines. Measuring just 37 inches wide, it’s compact enough to fit comfortably in apartments, bedrooms, dorm rooms, or smaller living rooms. You can place it neatly on a TV stand or mount it on the wall for a clean, minimalist setup.</p>
<p data-start="2167" data-end="2522">Despite its modest size, the soundbar delivers an expansive audio experience thanks to DTS Virtual:X technology. This feature creates the illusion of surround sound, making audio feel like it’s coming from all around you—even without rear speakers. Dolby Atmos support further enhances compatible content, adding clarity and dimension to movies and shows.</p>


<h2 data-start="2524" data-end="2563">Easy Setup and Everyday Versatility</h2>
<p data-start="2565" data-end="2784">The Fire TV Soundbar is designed to be plug-and-play. Simply connect it to your TV using HDMI ARC, and your TV should automatically route audio through the soundbar. No complicated menus or technical expertise required.</p>
<p data-start="2786" data-end="3024">Beyond TV viewing, the soundbar also doubles as a wireless speaker. With Bluetooth and USB connectivity, you can stream music, podcasts, or audiobooks directly from your phone or other devices, making it a versatile addition to your home.</p>
<p data-start="3026" data-end="3233">If you already use a Fire TV smart TV or Fire TV streaming device, integration is seamless. You can control both your TV and the soundbar with a single Fire TV remote, keeping things simple and clutter-free.</p>
<p data-start="3273" data-end="3681" data-is-last-node="" data-is-only-node="">For $175, the Fire TV Soundbar offers a noticeable upgrade over built-in TV speakers, combining clear dialogue, enhanced bass, and immersive sound in a compact, affordable package. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4053/">With its current 30% discount, it’s an ideal opportunity to transform your home viewing experience without overspending</a>. If you’re ready to leave tinny TV audio behind, this soundbar is an easy and budget-friendly step forward.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4053/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-fire-tv-soundbar-plus-hits-new-record-low-after-two-price-cuts-in-one-week-newest-model-with-built-in-subwoofer-3-1-channel-dolby-atmos-2000658522]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hytale Expects One Million Players at Early Access Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-expects-one-million-players-at-early-access-launch/</link>
            <guid>1403260</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The founder of Hypixel Studios has stated that they expect more than one million players during the early access launch. </p>



<p>For those unaware, after being shut down by Riot Games, Hytale was reacquired by Hypixel Studios and is now scheduled to release in early access tomorrow, January 13, 2026. Ahead of this launch, we already knew some details, such as the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-price-revealed-ahead-of-early-access-release/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">price</a><span>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-early-access-coming-soonand-shows-off-16-minutes-of-minecraft-like-gameplay/" target="_blank">16 minutes of gameplay</a>, along with plans to add</span><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-reveals-plans-for-proximity-chat-multiplayer-portals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> proximity chat and the potential of multiplayer portals</a>.</p>







<h2 id="h-hypixel-founder-asks-players-to-download-launcher-and-login-beforehand-due-to-expected-influx-of-over-1-million-players">Hypixel Founder Asks Players to Download Launcher and Login Beforehand Due to Expected Influx of Over 1 Million Players</h2>



<p>As revealed in a new post on <a href="https://x.com/Simon_Hypixel/status/2010458001455640636" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter), the founder of Hypixel Studios has asked players to download the launcher a day prior and log in to help reduce launch-day stress, as they expect “over 1 million players on the early access release day” for Hytale. If you are wondering about the launcher, the developers have confirmed they’ll skip Steam to avoid negative reviews during the early access stage. Interested readers can learn <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/download-hytale-launcher/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to download the launcher</a> through Insider Gaming’s guide. </p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>IMPORTANT</p><p>We expect over 1 million players on the early access release day for Hytale (January 13). Please download the launcher today and log in now to help us significantly reduce launch-day stress. Let us know if you are having any issues.</p><p>Download now:… <a href="https://t.co/kiMYIkKmJI">pic.twitter.com/kiMYIkKmJI</a></p></div>— Simon (@Simon_Hypixel) <a href="https://twitter.com/Simon_Hypixel/status/2010458001455640636?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 11, 2026</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>For those unaware, Hytale is a title that blends sandbox creativity with RPG action, where players can “explore a procedurally generated world full of dungeons, secrets, and a variety of creatures, then shape it block by block.” As the game is launching in early access, players should expect bugs and other changes, as it is still in active development. However, the developers have polished the core systems for launch, including exploration, responsive combat, and robust building, along with creator‑first tools for creating unique content, minigames, and running community servers. </p>







<p>In other news, Hytale developers have received the blessing to include a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-receives-blessing-to-include-technoblade-tribute/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Technoblade tribute</a>. Additionally, here are the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-system-requirements/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PC performance and system requirements</a> for the upcoming title. Do you think Hytale will attract more than 1 million players at launch? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-definitive-edition-could-be-coming-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a banner for The Division: Definitive Edition surfacing online, hinting at an upcoming announcement</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-expects-one-million-players-at-early-access-launch/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Detroit: Become Human tops 15 million sales worldwide]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/detroit-become-human-tops-15-million-sales-worldwide</link>
            <guid>1403257</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-template="layout" data-theme="theme2"><nav data-module="navigation" aria-label="navigation"><div data-testid="header" data-component="informa-bar"><div data-testid="informa-bar-left-section"><p>Together, we power an unparalleled network of 220+ online properties covering 10,000+ granular topics, serving an audience of 50+ million professionals with original, objective content from trusted sources. We help you gain critical insights and make more informed decisions across your business priorities.</p></div><p>This site is operated by a business or businesses owned by Informa PLC and all copyright resides with them. Informa PLC's registered office is 5 Howick Place, London SW1P 1WG. Registered in England and Wales. Number 8860726.</p></div></nav><div data-testid="article-base-body" data-template="article"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">January 12, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>1 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Newsbrief:</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Detroit: Become Human</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has surpassed 15 million sales worldwide to cement its position as Quantic Dream's best-selling title to date.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The French studio </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/quantic-dream_we-are-proud-to-announce-that-detroit-become-activity-7415059736594812929-6PG-?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&amp;rcm=ACoAAAoO_OkB-VfPR7dhiZ-PZ-9sf_EfWliEy1k">shared the news on LinkedIn</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and said the milestone reflects the dedication of its development team.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The sci-fi adventure launched in 2018 for PlayStation 4 before eventually debuting on Windows PC in 2019.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div><div data-module="newsletter-signup-promo"><p>Daily news, dev blogs, and stories from Game Developer straight to your inbox</p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/detroit-become-human-tops-15-million-sales-worldwide]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld is getting an official card game this summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/palworld-is-getting-an-official-card-game-this-summer</link>
            <guid>1403254</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Promo-image-for-Palworld-Official-Card-Game-showing-a-number-of-Pals-around-a-playing-card.jfif?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Promo-image-for-Palworld-Official-Card-Game-showing-a-number-of-Pals-around-a-playing-card.jfif?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Promo-image-for-Palworld-Official-Card-Game-showing-a-number-of-Pals-around-a-playing-card.jfif?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Promo-image-for-Palworld-Official-Card-Game-showing-a-number-of-Pals-around-a-playing-card.jfif?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Promo-image-for-Palworld-Official-Card-Game-showing-a-number-of-Pals-around-a-playing-card.jfif?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Promo-image-for-Palworld-Official-Card-Game-showing-a-number-of-Pals-around-a-playing-card.jfif?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Promo-image-for-Palworld-Official-Card-Game-showing-a-number-of-Pals-around-a-playing-card.jfif?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Promo-image-for-Palworld-Official-Card-Game-showing-a-number-of-Pals-around-a-playing-card.jfif?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Promo-image-for-Palworld-Official-Card-Game-showing-a-number-of-Pals-around-a-playing-card.jfif?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Pocketpair</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Pocketpair has announced <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/palworld-beginner-tips-tricks-9409">Palworld</a> Official Card Game, which is, yes, an official card game based on the developer's monster catching survival game, Palworld.</p>
<p>It's coming on 30th July in collaboration with Bushiroad, and has been designed as a two-player competitive card game.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>As you would expect, Palworld Official Card Game has been created with many of the core ideas which made Palworld so popular on its debut (remember, this <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/palworld-becomes-second-game-to-pass-2m-concurrent-steam-players">chap managed to become only the second game to pass two million concurrent Steam players on its release in 2024</a>). Players will be able to "enjoy strategic and tactical battles" in the upcoming card game, and this will be done by deploying Pals.</p>
<p>According to the <a href="https://en.palworld-official-cardgame.com/news/post-1">official website</a>, those who take Palworld Official Card Game for a spin will have to fight alongside the Pal companions while also gathering resources and building up their bases. The Pals, meanwhile, will have "unique traits" which will help lead players to victory.</p><p>"Team up with your trusty Pals and experience the thrill of overcoming formidable enemies through this exciting trading card game," the site reads. At the time of writing, the team hasn't yet released any pricing or specific card details, though on the Palworld Discord server, Pocketpair has said to stay tuned for more updates.</p>
<p>You can check out a short teaser for Palworld Official Card Game below.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Palworld OFFICIAL CARD GAME Teaser PV" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1haeLlUTq2s?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Palworld OFFICIAL CARD GAME Teaser PV</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1haeLlUTq2s?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1haeLlUTq2s?autoplay=1" title="Palworld OFFICIAL CARD GAME Teaser PV">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Palworld OFFICIAL CARD GAME Teaser PV. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1haeLlUTq2s" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>So, as you can see, Palworld and Pocketpair continue to march along all this time after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/palworld-xbox-us-player-numbers-briefly-surpass-fortnite-as-steam-sales-hit-8m-in-six-days">the game's explosive release almost two years ago</a>. Not all headlines have been positive, though, and the developer has been in the midst of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-sues-palworld-developer-for-infringement-of-multiple-patents">a legal battle with Nintendo over alleged patent infringement</a>.</p>
<p>More recently, this has actually been leaning in Pocketpair's favour, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/could-palworld-triumph-over-pokemon-in-lawsuit-japans-rejection-of-nintendo-patent-might-make-things-more-interesting">with a rejection of Nintendo's patent</a> in October throwing a spanner in the works for Nintendo.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  <div>
      <p>
        <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/palworld">Palworld</a>
      </p>

      <p>
            <span>PS4</span>, 
            <span>PS5</span>, 
            <span>Xbox One</span>, 
            <span>Xbox Series X/S</span>, 
            <span>PC</span>
      </p>





</div>

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/palworld-is-getting-an-official-card-game-this-summer]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RAM may be abominably expensive, but hey, at least SSD prices are also exploding]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ram-may-be-abominably-expensive-but-hey-at-least-ssd-prices-are-also-exploding</link>
            <guid>1403248</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>PC hardware's winter of discontent gets worse</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/WD-Black-SN850X-SSD_5rmoNZy.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/WD-Black-SN850X-SSD_5rmoNZy.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/WD-Black-SN850X-SSD_5rmoNZy.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/WD-Black-SN850X-SSD_5rmoNZy.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/WD-Black-SN850X-SSD_5rmoNZy.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/WD-Black-SN850X-SSD_5rmoNZy.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/WD-Black-SN850X-SSD_5rmoNZy.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/WD-Black-SN850X-SSD_5rmoNZy.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/WD-Black-SN850X-SSD_5rmoNZy.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>As we stumble into what increasingly looks like a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/for-its-gaming-hardware-contingent-ces-2026-was-a-good-week-to-bury-good-news">hardware-unfriendly</a> 2026, RAMnarök shows no signs of petering out. As tech giants continue hoarding memory chips to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genai-users-larian-forced-to-build-divinity-around-ram-shortage-caused-by-genai">build their AI farms</a>, and suppliers gleefully <a href="https://www.techspot.com/news/110871-samsung-sk-hynix-jacking-up-dram-prices-much.html">jack up their prices</a> in turn, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/predicting-steam-machine-prices-would-be-a-lot-easier-if-ram-costs-hadnt-gone-horribly-wrong">consumer-grade RAM is still laughably expensive</a> – and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-ssd-for-gaming">SSDs</a>, most of which also need these in-demand chips, are seeing some nasty inflation as well.</p>
<p>I bring this up now, when storage prices began climbing back in November, because the past week has been <em>particularly</em> fucked, vis-à-vis the kind of SSDs you’d want in a modern games PC. <a href="https://keepa.com/#!">Keepa</a>, Amazon-tracking the browser extension I’ve long used to gauge the honesty of Prime Day and Black Friday deals, makes for grim reading: the <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0B7CKVCCV/?th=1">1TB WD Black SN850X</a> currently sits at £162, having been £116 on January 5th, and £85 on November 5th. Nearly double the price, in barely two months.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0CK2TC9XQ/">Crucial T500</a>, another "recommendable in other circumstances" PCIe 4.0 drive, offered its 2TB version for £140 across most of November. Now it’s £240, having climbed even further from the £193 it cost earlier in January. The closest thing to an upside here is that the T500 will shortly be put out of its misery, the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/one-of-pc-gamings-key-ram-manufacturers-arent-selling-to-regular-humans-anymore-so-they-can-peddle-more-kit-to-ai-companies">entire Crucial brand being sacrificed</a> to help expand the AI bubble that made its storage and RAM so unaffordable in the first place.</p>
<p>And it’s not just NVMe SSDs, as the ol' SATA-based <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B08PC5DKZQ/">Samsung 870 Evo 1TB</a> has climbed from £83 in November, to £110 in December, to £140 right now. You know something’s gone wrong when you can’t even turn to outmoded tech like SATA drives to avoid the bite. DRAMless SSDs aren’t reliable alternatives either, despite their defining omission – a DRAM (Dynamic Random Access Memory) cache, built using the very memory chips that are in such short supply – logically making them more resistant to supply issues. Yet the DRAMless <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0CP42QVT8">Samsung 990 Evo</a>, in its 2TB capacity, is going for £233, almost a hundred quid more than its December price of £144.</p><p>Again, there’s no indication that prices will self-right any time soon; even if the supply of DRAM chips increases, they’re more likely to end up in another Big Tech warehouse than in your home desktop. Not counting <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-microsd-cards-for-steam-deck">microSD cards</a> for handhelds, that only leaves – urgh – mechanical hard drives as the economically sensible choice for upgrading your PC’s storage. And, as anyone who’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/for-the-love-of-all-things-good-do-not-install-starfield-on-a-hard-drive">tried to run Starfield on one</a> will tell you, they’re not much of an upgrade at all.</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ram-may-be-abominably-expensive-but-hey-at-least-ssd-prices-are-also-exploding]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple MacBook Air (2025 13-inch, M4) Drops to Its Lowest Price Ever in a New Year Laptop Clearance]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-macbook-air-2025-13-inch-m4-hits-its-lowest-price-ever-in-a-new-year-laptop-clearance-2000658785</link>
            <guid>1403242</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>You gotta love it when an elite-level laptop processor takes a serious price dive because a new version hits the market. That’s what’s happened with Apple’s M4-powered laptops since the M5 chip dropped last October, and while the M5 models are truly incredible, the M4s still pack a powerful punch, and <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6716/">you can score a 13-inch 2025 M4 MacBook Air for just $799 at Amazon right now</a>.</p>
<p>Apple’s most recent features and innovations are all packed into the M4 MacBook Air, from Apple Intelligence AI, an 18-hour battery life, and some of the absolute best visuals and sound of any laptop. The M4 MacBooks are a great opportunity for creative pros, Apple fans, and anyone wanting to score a truly great laptop that’s marked down by hundreds of dollars from its original price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6716/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Still Fresh</h2>
<p>Apple’s rapid upgrade schedule from the M2 chip to the M5 — a trek that took only two years — means that the “previous model” MacBooks are actually very,&nbsp;<em>very</em> recent. This 13-inch M4 MacBook Air is less than a year old, which means you won’t have to worry about OS compatibility or falling behind on the latest Apple goodies for years to come, most likely. Since the jump from the M4 to the M5 is a 20% gain in CPU speed and quicker Apple Intelligence, you might not notice the performance difference at all, but you’ll definitely notice the $200 that’s staying in your wallet when you go with the M4 MacBook Air.</p>
<p>The first thing you’ll notice when you fire up the M4 MacBook Air is, of course, Apple’s legendary Liquid Retina display. A billion colors are packed into the 13.6-inch screen to make any picture or static image truly pop, and with a great refresh rate, your videos and streaming will be absolutely peak. The MacBook Air’s 12MP Center Stage camera combines with three built-in mics and four speakers with Spatial Audio to create a perfect multimedia machine for video calls.</p>



<h2>All-Day Intelligence</h2>
<p>Once you dig into the latest iteration of Apple Intelligence, you’ll want to play with it all day. Apple’s AI model is a true boon to anyone needing a hand with writing, creating, research, or anything else you ask of it. Apple’s built market-best privacy protection features into Apple Intelligence, making your searches and activity so secure that even Apple can’t see them. You can indulge in that all-day dive into Apple Intelligence with the 13-inch M4 MacBook Air, because it comes with a robust 18-hour battery life.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6716/">The 20%-off Amazon deal that cuts the price of the 13-inch 2025 M4 MacBook Air by a full $200</a>, down to just $799, is especially noteworthy since Apple’s been historically a little spare with their sale prices. But it’s real, and it’s still live right now for anyone looking to score a top-of-the-line MacBook at a terrific price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6716/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-macbook-air-2025-13-inch-m4-hits-its-lowest-price-ever-in-a-new-year-laptop-clearance-2000658785]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Division: Definitive Edition Could Be Coming Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-definitive-edition-could-be-coming-soon/</link>
            <guid>1403239</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It seems Ubisoft could be gearing up for an announcement of The Division: Definitive Edition, as a banner has surfaced in Japan. </p>



<p>The Division franchise seems to be progressing well, with Ubisoft’s Julian Gerighty stating that The Division 3 is “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-3-shaping-up-to-be-monster-dev/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shaping up to be a monster</a>” and thinks it could have as significant an impact as the first game in the series. Talking about the first game, it seems there still might be something in store for us for Division 1 in 2026. </p>











<p><span>Spotted by&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/domen0204" target="_blank">domen0204</a>&nbsp;on X (formerly Twitter), a banner for The Division: Definitive Edition was spotted at the FPS Day X event in Japan recently, with many hoping that the developers will finally provide an official announcement during its 10th Anniversary celebrations.</span> Additionally, we received some new announcements for The Division 2, with the developers confirming a ‘Realism mode’ coming in March 2026. </p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-the-division-2-s-realism-mode">The Division 2’s Realism Mode</h2>



<p>The Division 2’s ‘Realism mode’ will feature action-focused gameplay, reduced time-to-kill, and realistic weapon damage based on bullet caliber, allowing players to immerse themselves in the game in a brand-new way. Additionally, the mode will also introduce reduced UI, limited HUD, no health regeneration, reduced cool-down, and more. The devs also confirmed this is only the “first glimpses of the celebrations ahead,” with “more surprises” to come. </p>



<figure></figure>







<p>In other news, Tom Clancy’s The Division received a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-receives-60-fps-update-for-ps5-in-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">60 FPS update for the PlayStation 5</a> in 2025. Additionally, The Division 2 was ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-2-saved-by-team-five-developers-ubisoft/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">saved’ by a team of five developers.</a> What are your thoughts on The Division: Definitive Edition’s banner surfacing online? Do you think an announcement is around the corner? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-devs-receive-4000-in-new-years-bonus/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stellar Blade developers receiving over $3,000 in cash and Apple Products as a New Year’s bonus</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-definitive-edition-could-be-coming-soon/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG: Top 10 Most Valuable Cards From Last Year (2025)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-top-10-most-valuable-cards-from-last-year-2025</link>
            <guid>1403230</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-tabletop"><u>Pokémon Trading Card Game</u></a> had a defining year in 2025, with not only the return of Mega Evolutions, the bold visual direction of Black and White Rares, and jaw-dropping Special Illustration Rares from Prismatic Evolutions and Phantasmal Flames pushing artistic ambition to new heights. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Altogether, the market for singles in the Pokémon TCG has been skyrocketing, with the game’s continued short supply escalating the values of stunning chase cards even further</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Altogether, there have been ten cards that have stood above the rest. The ten most valuable cards brought by the Pokémon TCG are not only more expensive due to their amazing potential for competitive play, but also because of rare and exclusive artwork that makes them worthy of a museum, rather than a deck box. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Using prices determined by the dedicated TCG marketplace <a href="https://zdcs.link/9ZAenv?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>TCGPlayer</u></a>, ranked below from cheapest to most expensive, these ten cards represent the pinnacle of what <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/pokemon"><u>Pokémon</u></a> card collectors and players were chasing throughout 2025.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">10. Mega Gardevoir ex – 187/132 (ME01: Mega Evolution)</h2><div catalogid="144124ae-cbf5-456f-8b82-b94a616ad49b" id="234322"><div id="234322" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mega Gardevoir ex – 187/132 (ME01: Mega Evolution)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Although only the tenth most valuable Pokémon card released in 2025, the golden Mega Hyper Rare of Mega Gardevoir has artwork that presents Ralt’s final evolution in an elegant, almost celestial pose, reinforcing its identity as a Pokémon of grace rather than brute force.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the table, however, <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qm8xkJ?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Mega Gardevoir ex</u></a> is anything but gentle. Overflowing Wishes accelerates Psychic Energy across your bench, setting up devastating turns where Mega Symphonia scales damage based on total attached Energy. In slower, resource-heavy metas, Gardevoir decks flourished, making this card both well-sought after for its design and respected on a strategic level.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">9. Mega Lucario ex – 188/132 (ME01: Mega Evolution)</h2></div><div catalogid="144124ae-cbf5-456f-8b82-b94a616ad49b" id="234323"><div id="234323" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mega Lucario ex – 188/132 (ME01: Mega Evolution)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Mega Lucario ex’s gold Mega Hyper Rare treatment instantly upped its value with some added prestige. With an almost ceremonial design that belongs in a chapel window, Lucario is framed as a focal icon, with metallic finishes that catch the light far more dramatically than standard illustration cards.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Competitively, all versions of <a href="https://zdcs.link/Q45BLA?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Mega Lucario ex</u></a> earn their place in decks through sheer efficiency. Aura Jab accelerates Fighting Energy across the board, enabling rapid board development, while Mega Brave offers an explosive 270-damage swing capable of ending games outright. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Though the attack’s drawback limits consecutive use, Lucario’s consistency kept it relevant in Fighting-based archetypes. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">8. Sylveon ex – 156/131 (SV: Prismatic Evolutions)</h2></div><div catalogid="144124ae-cbf5-456f-8b82-b94a616ad49b" id="234324"><div id="234324" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Sylveon ex – 156/131 (SV: Prismatic Evolutions)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Sylveon ex sits at number eight with its pastel-heavy Special Illustration Rare artwork that’s immediately striking, leaning fully into the Eeveelution’s fairy-like charm with crystalline motifs and soft colours that bring a nice brighter contrast with the darker chase cards of the year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In gameplay terms, <a href="https://zdcs.link/QOjKqM?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Sylveon ex</u></a> carved out a niche as a control-leaning option. Magical Charm dampens opposing damage output, while Angelite provides rare bench disruption by shuffling opposing Pokémon back into the deck. In a 2025 meta increasingly defined by set-up reliant strategies, that kind of interference could carry some real value. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">7. Mega Charizard X ex – 130/094 (ME02: Phantasmal Flames)</h2></div><div catalogid="144124ae-cbf5-456f-8b82-b94a616ad49b" id="234328"><div id="234328" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mega Charizard X ex – 130/094 (ME02: Phantasmal Flames)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The golden ticket equivalent of the Phantasmal Flames expansion, the <a href="https://zdcs.link/z7RwdP?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Mega Hyper Rare version of Charizard X ex</u></a> is a pure spectacle that never gets old when staring at it in your binder. The gold silhouette treatment transforms Charizard into a mythic emblem rather than one of the best Pocket Monsters, but with even more mystique than Mega Lucario and Mega Gardevoir’s.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite the minimalist look, the card’s competitiveness is a joy to play with, too. Inferno X allows players to convert excess Fire Energy into overwhelming damage, making Mega Charizard X ex one of the most feared closers of the year. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">6. Reshiram ex – 173/086 (SV: White Flare)</h2></div><div catalogid="144124ae-cbf5-456f-8b82-b94a616ad49b" id="234325"><div id="234325" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Reshiram ex – 173/086 (SV: White Flare)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Reshiram ex’s Black White Rare treatment strips colour almost entirely, rendering the Legendary Pokémon in stark monochrome light that makes it look like a beautiful marble slab; it’s without a doubt one of the most unique prints we’ve seen recently in the TCG — all the more reason it’s a top contender among the most expensive Pokemon cards last year. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Functionally, <a href="https://zdcs.link/z7RyJn?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Reshiram ex</u></a> thrives as a comeback threat. Blaze Burst scales damage with the opponent’s Prize count, punishing aggressive decks that take early leads. Fire decks in 2025 often leaned on this mechanic to flip matches late, and combined with the card’s minimalist aesthetic, made Reshiram ex a standout collector piece.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">5. Zekrom ex – 172/086 (SV: Black Bolt)</h2></div><div catalogid="144124ae-cbf5-456f-8b82-b94a616ad49b" id="234326"><div id="234326" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Zekrom ex – 172/086 (SV: Black Bolt)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Following Reshiram’s lead, <a href="https://zdcs.link/QK8x1y?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Zekrom ex’s</u></a> own Black White Rare follows the same style design, but is stunning in its own way: using the Black White Rare format to emphasise raw power and silhouette. In fact, the sculpted look almost gives the Gen-5 Legendary a statue-like depiction, giving the card itself a sense of weight rarely seen in modern artwork in the TCG lately.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In gameplay, Voltage Burst rewards aggressive opponents by scaling damage as Prize cards are taken. While the self-damage drawback keeps it balanced, Lightning decks capable of managing recoil found Zekrom ex to be a reliable late-game finisher. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">4. Victini – 171/086 &amp; 172/086 (SV: Black Bolt / White Flare)</h2></div><div catalogid="144124ae-cbf5-456f-8b82-b94a616ad49b" id="234327"><div id="234327" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Victini – 171/086 &amp; 172/086 (SV: Black Bolt / White Flare)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Victini earns its place here as a paired phenomenon among the Pokémon TCG’s most valuable 2025 cards. Both Black White Rare versions (<a href="https://www.tcgplayer.com/product/644350/pokemon-sv-white-flare-victini-172-086?page=1&amp;Language=English" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>#172 in White Flare</u></a>, <a href="https://zdcs.link/a56EZx?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>#171 in Black Bolt</u></a>) share a vivid red presentation, creating an instantly recognisable aesthetic unlike anything else released.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">When played with in decks, Victini is deceptively simple. V-Force delivers efficient damage under specific bench conditions, rewarding precise board management. While not a format-defining attacker, Victini’s consistency and iconic status have pushed collector interest sky-high in the last 12 months.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">3. Team Rocket’s Mewtwo ex – 231/182 (SV: Destined Rivals)</h2></div><div catalogid="144124ae-cbf5-456f-8b82-b94a616ad49b" id="234329"><div id="234329" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Team Rocket’s Mewtwo ex – 231/182 (SV: Destined Rivals)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Few cards in 2025 carried as much narrative weight as <a href="https://zdcs.link/zj8JLy?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Team Rocket’s Mewtwo ex</u></a>. The Special Illustration Rare artwork places Mewtwo front and centre, with Giovanni placed directly in front — almost like it’s a special edition print of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/pokemon-the-first-movie"><u>Pokémon: The First Movie</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Mechanically, Mewtwo ex can be powerful, but it demands a lot of commitment. Power Saver restricts its use unless your board is fully aligned with Team Rocket Pokémon, but the payoff is substantial in terms of damage. Meanwhile, Erasure Ball scales aggressively with Energy discard, enabling devastating one-hit knockouts. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">2. Mega Charizard X ex – 125/094 (ME02: Phantasmal Flames)</h2></div><div catalogid="144124ae-cbf5-456f-8b82-b94a616ad49b" id="234330"><div id="234330" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Mega Charizard X ex – 125/094 (ME02: Phantasmal Flames)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Mega Hyper Rare was the golden ticket of Phantasmal Flames, but this <a href="https://zdcs.link/QpBbOZ?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Mega Charizard X ex</u></a> is the crown jewel and the must-have expensive Pokémon card of late last year. This Special Illustration Rare treatment is breathtaking: with Mega Charizard X’s blue flames crashing above the cards, followed by masterfully added silhouettes of Charmander, Charmeleon, and base Charizard underneath. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the battlefield, this version shares the same destructive Inferno X attack, but its scarcity and artwork elevate it far beyond its gold counterpart. For many players, this was the definitive Charizard of 2025</p><h2 data-cy="title2">1. Umbreon ex – 161/131 (SV: Prismatic Evolutions)</h2></div><div catalogid="144124ae-cbf5-456f-8b82-b94a616ad49b" id="234331"><div id="234331" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3> Umbreon ex – 161/131 (SV: Prismatic Evolutions)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">At the summit stands the most valuable Pokémon card of them all: <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qb8VdE?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>Prismatic Evolution’s Umbreon ex</u></a>, the undisputed chase card of 2025. Its Special Illustration Rare artwork is dazzling and surreal, blending gemstone motifs with cosmic patterns that frame Umbreon as something almost otherworldly. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">When Prismatic Evolutions launched in January 2025, packs were in short supply from the get-go (even compared to other expansions that were hard to buy already). SIR Umbreon was a rare card to begin with, but that double scarcity, and being arguably one of the most beautiful modern cards released, is the reason why this card is currently worth just under $1000.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Beyond those bank account-draining factors, Umbreon ex delivers meaningful utility in gameplay, if anyone is brave enough to put on in their deck. Moon Mirage disrupts opposing attackers with confusion, while Onyx introduces rare Prize-taking mechanics that can swing games unexpectedly. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">That said, you can get a <a href="https://zdcs.link/9yP0gO?object_uuid=c694fa85-b62f-4489-8a8a-73285ed6f490&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow"><u>‘lightly played’ Double Rare version for around $6</u></a>, so we’d recommend that if you’re just looking to use one in tournaments. If you’re after a new family heirloom, though, SIR Umbreon’s for you. <br>
</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Ben Williams</strong> – IGN freelance contributor with over 10 years of experience covering gaming, tech, film, TV, and anime. Follow him on Twitter/X <a href="https://x.com/BenLevelTen" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@BenLevelTen</a>.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jan 12, 2026 9:55 am</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-top-10-most-valuable-cards-from-last-year-2025]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As roughly one-in-ten Arc Raiders players reset their characters, Embark Studios is looking for new ways to incentivise expeditions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-expeditions-one-in-ten</link>
            <guid>1403227</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pre-Order-Trailer-_-ARC-Raiders-1-0-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pre-Order-Trailer-_-ARC-Raiders-1-0-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pre-Order-Trailer-_-ARC-Raiders-1-0-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pre-Order-Trailer-_-ARC-Raiders-1-0-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pre-Order-Trailer-_-ARC-Raiders-1-0-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pre-Order-Trailer-_-ARC-Raiders-1-0-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pre-Order-Trailer-_-ARC-Raiders-1-0-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pre-Order-Trailer-_-ARC-Raiders-1-0-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Pre-Order-Trailer-_-ARC-Raiders-1-0-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Embark</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>With the first expedition window for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a> concluded in December, Embark Studios has revealed that just over a million players opted in to reset their characters in exchange for various rewards. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-12-million-sales">Having sold over 12m copies according to analyst estimates</a>, that's under 10 percent of all players.</p>
<p>Expeditions, for those unaware, allow players to send off their levelled up character (alongside all the goodies stored in their stash) off on a grand adventure. In return your account gets cosmetics, an XP boost on your next character, expanded stash space, and for those able to gather up to five million credits additional skill points above the cap on their next character. A powerful boon!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/arc-raiders/first-expedition-wipe-statistics">In an interview with PCGamesN</a>, design director Virgil Watkins stated that of that roughly one million players, around 35-40 percent of them managed to scrape together the five million credits required for the full spread of skill point boosts during the expedition window.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Watch Eurogamer's Arc Raiders review here!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oXigyRsVeB0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Watkins also shared learnings from the game's first expedition window, stating: "One of the bigger topics [of feedback] was the requirements for the final stage to get the skill points, and probably going out a bit too late with that information, because we wanted to hold off until we could calibrate it around the actual economy of the player base, rather than trying to guess really early on.</p><p>"So then, when we chose the number, which was the five million credits for the full thing, [we set] that as an aspirational goal that some players might achieve. But then I think a lot of players took that as like, 'Well, now I have to do that to get it.'"</p>
<p>With just over a month until the next expedition window, it looks like the next opportunity for a reset will work largely in the same fashion as this initial run, though as PCGamesN points out changes to the final rush for credits can absolutely change. Watkins said that the team is looking at ways to "bring a little more variety" to the system, poring over player data.</p>
<p>Arc Raiders, unlike many other extraction games, have an opt-in reset mechanic rather than a forced progression wipe. As such, those not especially concerned with extra stash space or a few extra skill points don't <em>have</em> to worry about it too much. Given how hard it can be to build up a hoard of loot, one wanders if casual Arc Raiders players will be inclined to cash it all in for such bonuses.</p>
<p>Arc Raiders itself appears to be maintaining momentum going into 2026, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hollywood-sure-sounds-keen-to-make-an-arc-raiders-film">with Hollywood seemingly keen to chat about a theatrical adaptation of some sort</a>. Thanks to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/why-is-arc-raiders-cheaper-than-most-triple-a-games-thanks-to-helldivers-2-mostly">its cheaper price point</a>, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-was-steams-best-selling-game-over-the-holiday-period">some well-timed holiday discounts</a>, it doesn't appear to be going anywhere anytime soon.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-expeditions-one-in-ten]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Awesome Games Done Quick 2026' Raises $2.44 Million For Charity]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/awesome-games-done-quick-2026-raises-usd2-44-million-for-charity</link>
            <guid>1403221</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Final stream was a speedrun of Pokémon Emerald</p>
</section></header><div><section>

<p>The <strong>Awesome Games Done Quick 2026</strong> event has now closed with a total of <strong>$2.443.554</strong> raised for the <a href="https://preventcancer.org/">Prevent Cancer Foundation</a>.</p>
<p>The week-long fundraiser ended with a speedrun for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/pokemon_emerald">Pokémon Emerald</a> by streamer adef, who managed to beat it in 3 hours and 13 minutes. Other highlights from the event include a 70-Star, 70-Player relay for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/super_mario_64">Super Mario 64</a> and an any% speedrun for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> from streamer Ceen, who stormed through the game to beat the final boss in 54 minutes and 55 seconds.</p>
<p>The next major event, Summer Games Done Quick 2026, will take place later this year from <strong>5th - 11th July</strong>, with donations going to <a href="https://www.msf.org/">Médecins Sans Frontières</a> (Doctors Without Borders).</p>
<p>The charity events have not been without controversy, with the 2022 Summer Games Done Quick fundraiser seeing the <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/metal-gear-rising-revengeance/sgdq-fake">complete ban of speedrunner Mekarazium</a> for faking a run of the <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-360/metal_gear_rising_revengeance">Metal Gear Rising: Revengeance</a> DLC. The player had shown a segmented, pre-recorded video of the run rather than playing it live, later admitting to this and receiving a ban from future GDQ events.</p>

<p><em>Did you watch any of the Awesome Games Done Quick event this year? What was your personal highlight from the schedule? Let us know.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mxV-3XJy2WI" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mxV-3XJy2WI">youtube.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-info/072c40af84b20220d67b130a7d6bbfa1 @ 1768222916 --></div></article></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/awesome-games-done-quick-2026-raises-usd2-44-million-for-charity]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft once toyed with a "hidden" Assassin's Creed character creator that let you pick your ancestor from "millions"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-once-toyed-with-a-hidden-assassins-creed-character-creator-that-let-you-pick-your-ancestor-from-millions</link>
            <guid>1403218</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Former AC Unity creative director still wishes they'd brought it to life</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/acunity.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/acunity.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/acunity.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/acunity.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/acunity.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/acunity.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/acunity.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/acunity.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/acunity.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Ubisoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Ubisoft's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/assassins-creed-unity">Assassin's Creed Unity</a> almost had a 'character creator' system that would have seen you choosing an ancestor from a database of millions of people, rather than being thrust into the riding boots of Scarlet Pimple-esque nobleman Arno Dorian. The idea was broadly to give each player a unique perspective on the complexities of the French Revolution. According to former creative director Alexandre Amancio, this character creation system dates back to a time when the developers were weighing up two versions of the game, one of them far more co-op focussed. 
</p>
<p>
Ultimately, they rolled with a more familiar flavour of Assassin's Creed, but Amancio - who was also creative director for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/assassins-creed-revelations">Assassin's Creed: Revelations</a> - still wishes they'd committed to the riskier option for Unity. Our original reviewer Alec Meer might have agreed. Back in 2014, he <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-unity-review-pc">criticised</a> the game for "reverting to type despite its glitzy surface", and knocked the four-player co-op specifically for simply duplicating Arno: "it is simply boring for everyone to be the same (not particularly interesting) character".
</p>
<p>
All this comes from <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/former-assassins-creed-director-alexandre-amancio-explains-how-to-fix-aaa-development">a recent interview</a> with the chino-wearing, pipe-smoking sophisticates of GamesIndustry.biz. "When we began making Unity, two games started emerging," Amancio told the site's features editor Lewis Packwood following a talk at DevGAMM Lisbon... last November??? Fine, I guess we'll file this under 'news to me'. 
</p>
<p>
"One game was a traditional Assassin's Creed game, with the main protagonist carving his path through the French Revolution, but we also wanted to make a co-op game," Amancio went on. "We found a clever way of hiding a character creation system within Assassin's Creed. Instead of having just one blood ancestor in the Animus, it's a database of millions of people, and you're searching for an ancestor. So the more you describe that ancestor, the more it reduces the search until you find a match.
</p><p>
"The French Revolution is such a complex mishmash of different events and different perspectives that it would have been a more accurate portrayal if, instead of having a linear adventure through the lens of one character, you got your own perspective of the revolution," he continued. "So everyone's experience through the game is their own path through a complex event.
</p>
<p>
"At one point, we needed to choose to make one game or the other. Obviously these are huge investments with huge teams, so we made the decision to make the title that people would most recognize. But somewhere inside of me, I still wish we would've gone for that other one."
</p>
<p>
To play both sides, I can well imagine the hypothetical database-searching feature panning out badly, though it's hard to comment at length based on these crumbs of insight. Creating a repository of millions of potentially playable NPCs so that the player can refine the selection down to one protagonist sounds like a massive expense, needless to say, requiring steep compromises or supernatural forbearance from management on par with that shown to, say, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/beyond-good-and-evil-2">Beyond Good and Evil 2</a>.</p>
<p>It also would have required a different approach to narrative - something closer to an MMO or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-origins">Dragon Age: Origins</a>, with its selection of protagonist backstories. Hence the "hidden" character creation system being one component of a wholly different Unity concept. As Amancio notes, Unity was the first Assassin's Creed to allow co-op multiplayer within the open world, so even the more conventional version they shipped was a bit of a gamble, despite the well-worn mechanics and framing.
</p><p>
Still, character creation as population database refinement is a cool idea in general, not least because it suggests a period portrayal in which your assassin could be a heroic latrine digger, rather than some lukewarm blueblood adventurer. It makes me think of the collective storytelling of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/velvet-89-is-a-free-hidden-object-game-that-tells-the-story-of-the-czechoslovakian-revolution">Velvet 89</a>.
</p>
<p>
Amancio attributes a little of the Unity database idea's inception to his time working on <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/far-cry">Far Cry</a>, a series he feels has more appetite for unscripted upheaval. "I started my career at Ubisoft on Far Cry, not on Assassin's Creed, and I'm a huge fan of systemic games. I like simple, small systems that interact to create emergence. And Assassin's Creed was always open world, but very much a directed game. I've always had this desire to inject a little bit more of that chaos into the game.
</p>
<p>
"For example, adding the bomb system to Revelations was a way of exposing systems to the audience, because you could attract and disperse the crowd. It was a way of giving tools to players. These are the kinds of decisions that I think would have made - and still could make - Assassin's Creed into a more, in my opinion, modern game."
</p>
<p>
It's strange to compare Unity, let alone Revelations to the more recent Creed outings, post Assassin's Creed Odyssey. The series is now far more of an open world RPG and an exercise in pillaging the past. Brendy <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-shadows-review">summarised</a> the most recent Assassin's Creed Shadows as "a marathon of distraction" and "a reliably Ubisoftian tourist trap that sequesters you in a hedge maze of history with a packed itinerary and a disregard for the time constraints of adult life". I'd like to hear more from Amancio about how they could shake things up. Then again, given that Unity and Revelations are among the less-good Creeds, it's perhaps better that he's no longer part of the picture.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-once-toyed-with-a-hidden-assassins-creed-character-creator-that-let-you-pick-your-ancestor-from-millions]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With Hytale early access imminent, lead dev urges folks to take a couple of steps to "significantly reduce launch-day stress"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/with-hytale-early-access-imminent-lead-dev-urges-folks-to-take-a-couple-steps-to-significantly-reduce-launch-day-stress</link>
            <guid>1403215</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Hypixel say they expect over a million people to queue up right out of the gate</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-lead-urges-players-log-in-early-to-avoid-launch-issues-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-lead-urges-players-log-in-early-to-avoid-launch-issues-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-lead-urges-players-log-in-early-to-avoid-launch-issues-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-lead-urges-players-log-in-early-to-avoid-launch-issues-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-lead-urges-players-log-in-early-to-avoid-launch-issues-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-lead-urges-players-log-in-early-to-avoid-launch-issues-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-lead-urges-players-log-in-early-to-avoid-launch-issues-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-lead-urges-players-log-in-early-to-avoid-launch-issues-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/hytale-lead-urges-players-log-in-early-to-avoid-launch-issues-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Hypixel</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>It's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hytale">Hytale</a> early access release week, with the recently <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/in-a-rare-bit-of-good-news-hytale-lives-on-with-its-original-devs-buying-the-rights-off-of-riot">resurrected via purchase from Riot</a> blocky sandbox set to ruck up tomorrow, January 13th. Ahead of the big day the Hypixel co-founder who's currently spearheading the game has asked prospective players to download and log into its launcher nice and early, with the hopes this can help keep launch day disruption to a minimum.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Said co-founder, Simon Collins-Laflamme, outlined in a tweet over the weekend that the Hytale team are anticipating having a stampede of "over 1 million players" to descend on the game over the course of launch day.  As outlined in our handy <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hytale-release-time-and-date">Hytale release times guide</a>, the game'll be emerging from its square cave in the middle of the afternoon UK and European time, with US folks seeing it launch in the morning their time. </p>
<p>Ahead of that, Collins-Laflamme has a couple of steps he's urged prospective players to take. "Please <a href="https://hytale.com/download">download the launcher</a> today and log in now to help us significantly reduce launch-day stress," he wrote. "Let us know if you are having any issues."</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>IMPORTANT</p><p>We expect over 1 million players on the early access release day for Hytale (January 13). Please download the launcher today and log in now to help us significantly reduce launch-day stress. Let us know if you are having any issues.</p><p>Download now:… <a href="https://t.co/kiMYIkKmJI">pic.twitter.com/kiMYIkKmJI</a></p></div>— Simon (@Simon_Hypixel) <a href="https://twitter.com/Simon_Hypixel/status/2010458001455640636?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 11, 2026</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Provided plenty of folks take those steps, here's hoping Hytale's launch'll avoid serious issues or hugely lengthy queues, though such things are obviously never totally inevitable possibilities when any game goes live. In this case, the fact Hytale's launcher'll be the sole way to access it early doors - with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hytale-wont-be-on-steam-right-away-as-its-devs-want-to-avoid-overindexing-on-negative-reviews-from-players-who-arent-as-well-informed-yet">no versions on Steam</a> or other storefronts at this point - is likely part of what's got the devs concerned about getting everyone in quickly.</p><p>Once you've done the reccomended admin, maybe take a second to make sure you're all caught up on the myriad of things the devs of the rapidly resurrected sandbox have said about what you can expect it to offer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hytales-early-access-release-date-set-in-stone-for-january-2026-but-its-devs-admit-the-first-impression-will-be-rough">right out of the box</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hytales-devs-hope-to-redefine-the-block-game-genre-with-their-world-generation-and-theyve-now-explained-how-it-works">further down the line</a>.</p>
<p>It's also worth being aware that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hytale-will-launch-with-native-linux-support-though-the-steam-deck-is-not-officially-recommended">native Linux support</a> will be available for Hytale right from the get go, but it isn't guarunteed to work seamlessly on the Steam Deck right away.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/with-hytale-early-access-imminent-lead-dev-urges-folks-to-take-a-couple-steps-to-significantly-reduce-launch-day-stress]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stellar Blade Devs Receive $4,000+ in New Year’s Bonus]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-devs-receive-4000-in-new-years-bonus/</link>
            <guid>1403212</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Stellar Blade developers seem to be living the life we all want, as they have been given over $3,000 in cash and Apple products as a New Year’s Bonus. </p>



<p>Shift Up knows how to treat its employees and keep them motivated through frequent bonuses awarded on major milestones and other occasions. For last year’s New Year’s Eve, the developers were given <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-employees-receive-ps5-pros-and-a-cash-bonus/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PlayStation 5 Pros</a> and a cash bonus. This time, Shift Up has returned with another set of goodies for the employees. </p>







<h2 id="h-stellar-blade-devs-were-gifted-cash-and-apple-products-for-new-year-s">Stellar Blade Devs Were Gifted Cash and Apple Products for New Year’s </h2>



<p>According to a report by South Korean outlet <a href="https://www.sedaily.com/NewsView/2K773GI6BZ">Seoul Economic Daily</a> (via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/stellar-blade-studio-shift-up-has-gifted-all-its-staff-3500-airpods-max-and-an-apple-watch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">VGC</a>), Shift Up has gifted 300 employees a 5 million won cash bonus ($3400 USD), Apple AirPods Max, and Apple Watches for this New Year’s. As mentioned above, Shift Up is known to shower their employees with gifts; they have previously received items such as iPhone 14s, credit cards loaded with 10 million won ($6,800 USD), PlayStation 5 Pros, and Switch 2s. Don’t you wish you were working at Shift Up as well? </p>



<p>Currently, the dev team is working on the Stellar Blade sequel and other projects, and this could be the best way to motivate them and keep their interests aligned. The dev team is also working on a cross-platform title called <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-devs-upcoming-title-will-be-published-by-tencent/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Project Spirits</a>, which will be created through “a strategic partnership to include both publishing and joint development,” with Tencent’s Level Infinite. </p>







<p>In other news, Stellar Blade devs are considering additional platform expansions, which could mean <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-could-come-to-xbox-and-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Switch 2 and Xbox ports</a> are on the way. Additionally, Shift Up is planning a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-2-multiplatform-shift-up/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">multi-platform release</a> for the sequel. What are your thoughts on Stellar Blade employees receiving over $3,000 in cash and Apple Products as a New Year’s bonus? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/one-million-arc-raiders-players-wiped-accounts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Embark Studios revealing that one million ARC Raiders players completed their first Expedition Project</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-devs-receive-4000-in-new-years-bonus/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Time Does Hytale Release? Hytale Release Time, Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-release-time/</link>
            <guid>1403209</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The countdown until the release of Hytale is rapidly approaching the end, and as players across the world gear up for the release of the title, questions have naturally emerged about the Hytale release time.</p>



<p>Hytale releases on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-early-access-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">January 13</a> as a PC exclusive, though it is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-steam-how-to-buy-hytale/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">not available on Steam</a> at launch, after a rollercoaster ride through development that saw the title cancelled by Riot Games last year, before then being re-acquired by the original creators.</p>



<p>There’s still a long development journey ahead until a full 1.0 release, but players will finally be able to sink their teeth into Hytale imminently, and Insider Gaming has the release time details.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-time-does-hytale-release">What Time Does Hytale Release?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Go time. Image via Hypixel Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Hytale has a confirmed release time of 10 AM ET/3 PM GMT on PC, as revealed by a countdown timer on the official Hytale website.</strong></p>



<p>The official countdown on the <a href="https://hytale.com/countdown" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Hytale website</a> has been running for a while, counting down exactly how many days, hours, minutes, and seconds are left before players can dive into the game.</p>



<p>Hytale devs are expecting around one million players on launch day, so there could be some server issues to iron out early on, but the hope is that when the doors open, players will be able to flock in.</p>



<p>If you are having issues launching the game when the release time has passed, you may have to wait and try again, and make sure to keep an eye on the official Hytale social media accounts for any news and updates on ongoing problems.</p>



<p>The table below shows the exact release time for Hytale in major time zones across the world.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Hytale Release Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">7 AM – Jan. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">9 AM – Jan. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">10 AM – Jan. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)</td><td data-align="center">3 PM – Jan. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Time (AET)</td><td data-align="center">2 AM – Jan. 14</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<hr>



<p>Are you planning to dive into Hytale immediately? Share your plans for the game in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Hytale, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/does-hytale-have-multiplayer-co-op-multiplayer-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all the multiplayer details</a> for the game, and take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-hytale-editions-bonuses/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all the editions available to purchase</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-release-time/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["A sad end to a sad story" - fond Anthem farewells begin as BioWare's Destiny-like game reaches last day of operation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fond-anthem-farewells-begin-as-biowares-destiny-like-game-reaches-last-day-of-operation</link>
            <guid>1403203</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Exactly when it'll be switched off remains unclear.</p>

    </div>


  

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>At some point today, EA will turn the Anthem servers off, rendering BioWare's multiplayer online shooter inaccessible and unplayable, presumably forever. And fond farewells have already started to pour in.</p>
<p>Incidentally, the exact end-time is unclear. All we have officially to go by is today's date, 12th January, and as of this morning, the game's servers were still active for me. Presumably that means they'll remain up until the end of the day, until the clock strikes midnight - but midnight in which timezone? My best guess would be Pacific Time, as that's the timezone EA's Redwood City, California headquarters is located in. 12am midnight PT is 8am tomorrow morning GMT.</p>
<p>But I've also seen suggestions the Anthem servers could come down in line with the game's maintenance window, which was apparently 8am Eastern Time or thereabouts, which is 1pm GMT. I'll keep an eye on it and keep trying to clarify with EA.</p>
<p>Perhaps fuelled by this uncertainty, players have already begun saying their goodbyes to the game. The Anthem subreddit right now is filled with them; it makes for quite touching reading, actually. The general format seems to be people sharing a picture or short clip of their Javelin-suited Freelancer character, while sharing a word or two about the game.</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="546"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnthemTheGame/comments/1qaltf1/it_has_been_an_honor_freelancers/">It has been an honor, freelancers.</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Zephyr2209/">u/Zephyr2209</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnthemTheGame/">AnthemTheGame</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><ul>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnthemTheGame/comments/1qaltf1/it_has_been_an_honor_freelancers/">"It has been an honor, freelancers."</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnthemTheGame/comments/1qa7810/all_those_moments_will_be_lost_in_time_like_tears/">"All those moments will be lost in time, like tears in rain."</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnthemTheGame/comments/1qafb0x/rip_anthem_2026/">RIP anthem 2026</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnthemTheGame/comments/1qa9kpr/my_humble_anthem_collection_rip/">My humble Anthem collection. R.I.P. 😢</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnthemTheGame/comments/1qagzrt/whatever_happens_to_bastion_after_all_we_have/">Whatever happens to Bastion, after all we have done, we are stronger now, and at our strongest together.</a></li>
</ul>
<p>There are lots of variations of the "strongest together" sentiment.</p>
<p>The posts highlight what a startlingly attractive game Anthem can be, particularly as you fly around the often stormy jungle world of Coda, through enormous crumbling ruins and alongside flocks of strange birds. I've been playing Anthem this past week in the hope of seeing a community come together one final time and I've been struck again by the beauty of it. Even the streets of your home base in Tarsis are beautiful to wander around - that crumbled, almost Persian-style architectural fortress.</p><p>There has been increased activity in the game, too, as people return for a final fly-around, or as they - as in many cases - finish the game's achievements while they still can. To think that characters they've poured hundreds hours into - and that they're proudly parading around the game's social Launch Bay space - will cease to exist is a sobering reminder of the temporary nature of our virtual, server-based heroes.</p>
<p>Whether anything will happen in Anthem to mark its last moments is also unclear, but I expect it won't, as there appears to be no change anywhere else in the game - the shop still charges for items, and XP and currency is all still awarded in the same way. For all intents and purposes, the game seems untouched. Again, I'll keep an eye out.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/biowares-beleaguered-multiplayer-shooter-anthem-shutting-down-next-year">Anthem was earmarked for closure in July last year</a>, at which point EA removed the game from digital sale. EA thanked people for their "dedication, passion and support" and confirmed that you won't be able to play Anthem offline. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioware-very-disappointed-in-anthem-launch-issues">Anthem was originally released in 2019 but failed to catch on in the way EA BioWare hoped</a>. There were plans for a big overhaul - a 2.0 - but they were eventually abandoned, as, it seems, the game was.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/fond-anthem-farewells-begin-as-biowares-destiny-like-game-reaches-last-day-of-operation]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why don't we see male V in post-launch Cyberpunk 2077 marketing? The Cyberpunk 2 creative director has a very simple explanation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/why-dont-we-see-male-v-in-post-launch-cyberpunk-2077-marketing-the-cyberpunk-2-creative-director-has-a-very-simple-explanation</link>
            <guid>1403200</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Male-V-cyberpunk.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Male-V-cyberpunk.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Male-V-cyberpunk.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Male-V-cyberpunk.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Male-V-cyberpunk.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Male-V-cyberpunk.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Male-V-cyberpunk.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Male-V-cyberpunk.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Male-V-cyberpunk.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>When <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a> was sort of relaunched with its 2.0 update and the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/phantom-liberty-is-a-remarkable-expansion-and-a-bittersweet-end-for-cyberpunk-2077">Phantom Liberty</a> expansion, female V took over as the face of the game. More than two years later, and with the RPG still selling well and attracting new players, that hasn't changed.</p>
<p>At some point, fans of the game started to wonder what happened with male V, who had spearheaded all of the game's pre-launch marketing efforts. If you own a physical copy as released in 2020, he’s on the cover by default. As the game fixed what was broken and evolved into one of the best games in recent memory, he became a relic of sorts. Now, the short-haired bloke is nowhere to be found in official promotional materials. This has raised some eyebrows across the internet and given conspiracy theorists a couple of inventive reasons for the change, but the truth is far more simple than simply some market research saying folks preferred female V, or something more sinister.</p>
<p>"Male V had whole base game marketing for himself", stated Cyberpunk 2 creative director Igor Sarzynski when asked <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/srznsk.bsky.social/post/3mbrejiy3ok2w">via BlueSky</a> last week. The team simply decided to go 50/50 for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty">Phantom Liberty</a>. "One game for each V."</p>
<p>Of course, such a huge change to the initially-troubled game's promotion as it relaunched probably went through deeper discussions than what Sarzynski is saying here. While we don't have the data on the percentage of male and female V runs of the game, the consensus among the most dedicated players is that people enjoy both versions of the character equally. This isn't a clear <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-odyssey-review-a-vast-and-generous-voyage">Assassin’s Creed Odyssey</a> situation where most folks ultimately agreed Kassandra was far superior to Alexios as a main character.</p><p>The thing is that going with male or female V isn't just a matter of who you prefer for purely aesthetic and voice acting reasons, as the pick also enables or disables certain romantic relationships. Most veterans agree doing at least two runs of the game is recommended to experience its branching narratives and different partners worth meeting (and smooching) while you try to save the character's life.</p>
<p>We're inclined to say female V is ultimately the more substantial choice since it has access to the Judy romance, which adds to the main storyline in ways the other relationships don't, but either way, you're getting excellent opportunities and voice acting across the board. We definitely are curious about actual data behind Cyberpunk 2077's protagonist pick (and life paths for that matter), but if we take Sarzynski at his word, CD Projekt Red didn't give the official swap much thought.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/why-dont-we-see-male-v-in-post-launch-cyberpunk-2077-marketing-the-cyberpunk-2-creative-director-has-a-very-simple-explanation]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameStop Kicks Off 2026 By Reportedly Shutting "Hundreds" Of Stores]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/gamestop-kicks-off-2026-by-reportedly-shutting-hundreds-of-stores</link>
            <guid>1403194</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>While CEO Ryan Rohen eyes up $35 billion pay packet</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="7b93f790bb70d"><a title="GameStop" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/7b93f790bb70d/gamestop.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>The coming of the new year is a good time to take stock and look at the 12 months ahead with a sense of optimism. According to a new report from <a href="https://www.polygon.com/gamestop-closing-stores-as-ceo-payday/">Polygon</a>, however, GameStop has instead decided to kick off 2026 by shutting hundreds of its stores in the US.</p>
<p>News of such closures apparently came as quite the shock to employees, with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GameStop/comments/1q2h1j2/gamestop_really_put_a_trade_coupon_on_my_local/">signs being hastily pasted to storefronts confirming the news</a>. To add insult to injury, the same signs offered up an extra 20% on trade-ins if customers head to alternative GameStop locations.</p>
<p>Many customers have reportedly noted that some store closures have left them with few alternatives, with one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GameStop/comments/1q4vm6i/comment/ny0n4bi/">Reddit commenter</a> stating that their nearest store is now "1.5 hours away".</p>

<p>It's estimated that <a href="https://gsclosing.blogspot.com/2025/12/january-2026-reported-closings.html">up to 296 stores closed in the first week of 2026</a>, with even well-performing locations being given the chop. It seems likely that such drastic action is somewhat linked to the <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1326380/000132638026000004/pressrelease-rclti.htm">recent announcement</a> that CEO Ryan Cohen could bag a pay packet worth an astonishing $35 billion, but only if the retailer is able to reach a market cap of $100 billion.</p>
<p>This is roughly ten times its current value at $9.3 billion, so it's a pretty wild target. The announcement clarifies that Cohen "receives no guaranteed pay—no salary, no cash bonuses, and no stock that vests simply over time", with the compensation being entirely "at-risk".</p>
<p>It's not a case of "all or nothing", mind you, with Cohen's compensation available in nine tranches (or 'portions'). The first is available if GameStop achieves a market cap of $20 million, with each subsequent tranche requiring an addition $10 billion in value all the way up to £100 billion. So even if GameStop only manages to reach £20 million, Cohen will still earn billions in shares.</p>
<p>According to a report from <a href="https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/business/583322/eb-games-proposes-closing-all-new-zealand-stores">RNZ</a>, GameStop is also considering ending its EB Games business in New Zealand, which would mean the closure of 38 stores in the region. According to the notice sent to employees, the proposal is "not final, and no decision will be made until we have completed a full consultation process in good faith with affected team members."</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:195105,181590 @ 1768221971 -->
<p><em>What a way to kick off the year, huh? Let us know your thoughts on GameStop's store closures with a comment down below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1326380/000132638026000004/pressrelease-rclti.htm" rel="noopener" href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1326380/000132638026000004/pressrelease-rclti.htm">sec.gov</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://www.polygon.com/gamestop-closing-stores-as-ceo-payday/" rel="noopener" href="https://www.polygon.com/gamestop-closing-stores-as-ceo-payday/">polygon.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e @ 1768222450 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/gamestop-kicks-off-2026-by-reportedly-shutting-hundreds-of-stores]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Divinity Team Says Character Creation Will Be "Even Better" Than Baldur’s Gate 3]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/divinity-team-says-character-creation-will-be-even-better-than-baldurs-gate-3/1100-6537321/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1403191</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537321">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Baldur's Gate 3 was the kind of game that could take hours to get started, thanks in part to a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-character-creators/2900-7236/">rich character customization suite</a> that allowed players to fine-tune everything from their race to several minute details. For the upcoming <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/divinity/">Divinity</a>, developer Larian Studios says that players can expect "even better" options for fine-tuning their character when the game eventually launches.</p><p>"We are planning to have an even better one! More colors, more options, more control," Divinity art director Alena Dubrovina wrote in a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1q870w5/comment/nyl8jff/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Reddit AMA session</a>.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="309843665" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466601,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Divinity%20Will%20Be%20Better%20Than%20Baldur%E2%80%99s%20Gate%203%20%E2%80%9COn%20All%20Fronts%E2%80%9D%20Says%20Larian%20CEO&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:310,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/divinity-will-be-better-than-baldurs-gate-3-on-all-fronts-says-larian-ceo\/2300-6466601\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466601\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466601\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466601\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466601&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466601,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6537321&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;divinity&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;larian-studios&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;divinity&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;divinity&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466601},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466601\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1862\/18620770\/4623391-interview_divinity_20251215v2.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/Y9NU7GCb.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1765893600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="Y9NU7GCb" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Divinity Will Be Better Than Baldur’s Gate 3 “On All Fronts” Says Larian CEO</p>
      </div>
<p>That's a high bar for the studio to set, considering just how detailed the Baldur's Gate 3 character customization system is. Beyond the standard options, players can also tinker with unique biological traits depending on the race they choose, fiddle around with facial features, and much more. Just when you think you've got your character nailed down, the game also offers you a chance to design a Spirit Guardian for your adventurer, a character who will appear in your dreams.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-mystery-of-the-game-awards-monolith-appears-to-have-been-spoiled-by-a-trademark-filing/1100-6536822/">Divinity was unveiled at The Game Awards</a> last year, and since then, a few more details on the game have been revealed. You can expect co-op play when the RPG launches, and in response to the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-divinity-dev-reveals-how-it-uses-generative-ai/1100-6537001/">backlash about the use of generative AI</a>, studio CEO Swen Vincke confirmed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/larian-studios-draws-harder-line-on-ai-clarifies-stance-in-reddit-ama/1100-6537296/">Divinity won't feature "any GenAI art."</a></p><p>Following the massive success of Baldur's Gate 3, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/divinity-devs-feel-more-pressure-after-baldurs-gate-3s-massive-success/1100-6537029/">Vincke admitted that there's "more pressure"</a> now on Larian, but he believes that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/divinity-better-than-baldurs-gate-3-larian-ceo-swen-vincke/1100-6536981/">Divinity will be better than Baldur's Gate 3 "on all fronts."</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/divinity-team-says-character-creation-will-be-even-better-than-baldurs-gate-3/1100-6537321/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Division appears to be getting the "definitive edition" treatment soon, but we don’t know yet quite what that means]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-division-definitive-edition</link>
            <guid>1403188</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/TheDivision_prZlgEz.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/TheDivision_prZlgEz.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/TheDivision_prZlgEz.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/TheDivision_prZlgEz.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/TheDivision_prZlgEz.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/TheDivision_prZlgEz.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/TheDivision_prZlgEz.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/TheDivision_prZlgEz.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/TheDivision_prZlgEz.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Tom Clancy's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tom-clancys-the-division-2-review-an-accomplished-sequel-with-an-awful-story">The Division 2</a> is still trucking along, and with an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-division-2-kicks-off-10th-anniversary-year-with-the-division-2-survivors-an-updated-take-on-the-survival-extraction-experience">ambitious 2026 roadmap</a> to boot, while development on <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-division-3-will-have-as-big-an-impact-as-the-division-1-ubisoft-dev-says">the third game</a> continues. More shocking, though, is the apparent tease that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-division-review">The Division 1</a> is making a return for its 10th anniversary.</p>
<p>We've had no shortage of leaks on Ubisoft’s upcoming releases, including the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/raid-shadow-legends-collaboration-assassins-creed-black-flag-remake">Assassin's Creed: Black Flag</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/five-years-later-ubisofts-much-delayed-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-gets-the-closest-thing-to-a-release-date-yet">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time</a>'s remakes (the latter of which was announced ages ago), but we hadn't heard a peep regarding a remaster or re-release of the first Division game. On 11th January, the noise began when users on X/Twitter like <a href="https://x.com/domen0204">Domen Gaming</a> started sharing a photo of a banner taken at the grand finale of the <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/esports/rainbow-six/siege/news-updates/5JKjM9XlbV6Lyd2xNYzkIf/apac-cup-at-fps-day-details">APAC Cup of R6 Siege</a> currently taking place in Tokyo, Japan:</p>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p><a href="https://x.com/Okami13_/status/2010471227387740286?s=20">KAMI</a> on X/Twitter adds folks at the event heard Ubisoft is holding a "10th anniversary commemorative premiere" this weekend, which we assume is later this week unless something was lost in translation. Technically, The Division 1 launched on March 8, 2016, so we're still a ways off from the actual anniversary, but if a re-release of sorts is happening, it makes sense Ubisoft would move it forward a bit to boost its Q1 2026 numbers as much as possible (and we're not ruling out Assassin's Creed or Prince of Persia shadow drops, either).</p><p>Anniversary aside, the timing of the news is odd, as the game <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/19/the-division-yes-the-first-one-gets-a-ps5-update/">finally received a 60 FPS patch on current-gen consoles last month</a>. Moreover, most of the series' community is playing The Division 2 instead, which is the meatier game that will seemingly be supported until the threequel arrives. On the other hand, The Division’s snowy New York City setting remains one of the most captivating and moodiest modern open worlds to the point much of The Division 2's DLC efforts has catered to players who preferred that location over the less inspired Washington DC map.</p>
<p>Unless substantial graphical updates taken from Massive's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/avatar-frontiers-of-pandora-fire-and-ash-player-boost">Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora</a> are coming as part of this Definitive Edition, we're only expecting a repackaged and complete edition for newcomers looking to go back to the beginning. We wouldn't rule out a surprise <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platforms/switch-2">Switch 2</a> port of the game, though, especially since Ubisoft has been keen to support the young console so far. It would explain this marketing push in Japan and would continue Ubisoft's trend of supporting Nintendo’s hybrid hardware, which has been off to a great start this generation with the excellent Star Wars Outlaws and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/want-to-know-how-assassins-creed-shadows-works-on-switch-2-ubisoft-details-console-specific-features-and-more">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a> ports.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-division-definitive-edition]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 3 HDRP NextGen Edition 2026 Will Feature Wind Simulation and More Detailed Characters]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-3-hdrp-nextgen-edition-2026-wind-simulation-more-detailed-characters/</link>
            <guid>1403182</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Yesterday, modder <strong>Halk Hogan</strong> shared the second video preview of his <strong>The Witcher 3 HDRP NextGen Edition 2026</strong> mod. This new version of the popular visual remastering mod, which enhances thousands of the original game's assets, including textures, models, materials, and more, <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-3-hd-reworked-project-nextgen-edition-2026-announced-with-new-trailer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was first announced two months ago</a>. </p>



<p>As usual, Halk Hogan also shared a brief message with the community, revealing what he'll be focusing on for this new version:</p>



<p><em>I'm back to share some fresh progress on the HDRP NextGen Edition. As you can see in the video, many objects will no longer be static and will now have wind simulation. All characters will also be reworked, along with all armor and equipment for Geralt and Roach; everything will now be much more detailed. Of course, this is just a small part of all the changes that will be included in The Witcher 3 HDRP NextGen Edition 2026, which will be available later this year.</em></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="The Witcher 3 HD Reworked Project NextGen Edition 2026 - Preview 2" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sEGB_5GQ1AI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>It might just be a very timely release. <a href="https://wccftech.com/third-the-witcher-3-dlc-rumors-intensify-more-polish-websites-confirm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">According to growing rumors</a>, <strong>CD Projekt RED is secretly preparing a new DLC</strong> for The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt, ten years after the release of <strong>Blood and Wine</strong>. Speculation is that it will somehow bridge the previous game with the upcoming The Witcher 4. IGN Poland previously heard that the studio was interested in introducing the Eastern realm of Zerrikania, though they acknowledged that the Northern kingdom of Kovir and Poviss might also be an option for the DLC.</p>



<p>If you just can't wait for either thing to release and want to play the game now, you can find the current The Witcher 3 HDRP NextGen Edition <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/witcher3/mods/9963" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>. Warning: the download is around 12GB.  </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-3-hdrp-nextgen-edition-2026-wind-simulation-more-detailed-characters/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Download The Hytale Launcher Now, As Hypixel Estimates "Over 1 Million" Players At Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/download-the-hytale-launcher-now-as-hypixel-estimates-over-1-million-players-at-launch/1100-6537319/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1403173</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537319">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/hytale/" data-ref-id="5000-507834">Hytale</a> has been on quite a development journey. After being acquired and subsequently shuttered by Riot Games, the original development team bought the Minecraft rival back and recommenced development in November 2025. On January 13, the title goes into early access, which the team acknowledges will be unpolished and full of bugs. Still, Hypixel--the developer behind one of the most popular Minecraft servers of all time--is expecting mammoth launch-day numbers, estimating "over 1 million" players. To that end, the studio is encouraging users to download the game's launcher ahead of time in order.</p><p>Hypixel's CEO, Simon Collins-Laflamme, <a href="https://x.com/Simon_Hypixel/status/2010458001455640636?s=20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">posted on X</a> stating, "We expect over 1 million players on the early access release day for Hytale ... Please download the launcher today and log in now to help us significantly reduce launch-day stress." Hypixel's preorders have been open since early December, so the team has had around a month to gauge interest, meaning this player estimate is based on those figures and not just speculation.</p><p>Hypixel has already allowed mod creators early access to the game so they can research and develop the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-hytale-mods/2900-7397/" data-ref-id="2900-7397">best Hytale mods</a> for the early access release. Modders are adding new game modes, cosmetics, items, and quality-of-life improvements to the game, with more being added daily. When the game launches tomorrow, January 13, all of those mods will be available via Curseforge thanks to an agreement between the modding platform and Hypixel Studios.</p><p>You can learn more about the game, including registrations and preorders, on the <a href="https://store.hytale.com/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Hytale website</a>. If you've already purchased Hytale, you can also download the launcher there.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/download-the-hytale-launcher-now-as-hypixel-estimates-over-1-million-players-at-launch/1100-6537319/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Following its cancellation by Riot, Hytale devs anticipate over a million players in Early Access alone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/hytale-launch-million-players</link>
            <guid>1403170</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Hytale_System_Requirements_3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Hytale_System_Requirements_3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Hytale_System_Requirements_3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Hytale_System_Requirements_3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Hytale_System_Requirements_3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Hytale_System_Requirements_3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Hytale_System_Requirements_3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Hytale_System_Requirements_3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Hytale_System_Requirements_3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Hypixel Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Hytale's founder Simon Collins-Laflamme has revealed the team expects over a million players on the game's Early Access launch day on the 13th January.</p>
<p>This statement, <a href="https://x.com/Simon_Hypixel/status/2010458001455640636">posted on Laflamme's personal Twitter account</a>, came alongside a call-to-action for players to download the game's launcher today to help reduce development-side stress on the day of release.</p>
<p>Hytale, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hytale-is-saved-riot-sells-cancelled-minecraft-like-game-back-to-its-original-co-founder">a game revived by Laflamme</a> following its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/promising-minecraft-like-hytale-cancelled-after-ten-years-in-development">cancellation by Riot Games last year</a>, has seen a surge in interest since the unexpected return. Shortly after switching hands from the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/league-of-legends">League of Legends</a> creator to Laflamme and co, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hytale-will-finally-be-launching-early-next-year-after-years-of-development-woes">Early Access plans for the game were revealed back in a matter of months</a>. This, after the game had been in development for roughly ten years.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Hytale Animation | In-Game Machinima Experimentation" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/emNCLx_WCTo?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Hytale Animation | In-Game Machinima Experimentation</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/emNCLx_WCTo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/emNCLx_WCTo?autoplay=1" title="Hytale Animation | In-Game Machinima Experimentation">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Hytale team has been releasing plenty of videos ahead of release, including this cool in-engine animation!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=emNCLx_WCTo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hytale-release-date-time">In terms of release time</a>, the game is set to launch early morning on Tuesday morning in the Americas, and early evening in Europe, so one would expect it'll steadily gain momentum throughout the week once it launches. Not that we'll be able to track it live, as the game is not releasing to Steam during its initial Early Access period.</p><p>The game<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hytale-price-where-to-buy"> is being sold at three price points via the official Hytale website</a>, starting off at a pretty cheap $19.99 for the standard version. The creator has warned folks ahead of time that this is an Early Access game in the truest sense of the word, so given the shaky history of Hytale expect a few bumps when it first launches.</p>
<p>Will you be playing Hytale when it finally comes out later this week? Let us know below!</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/hytale-launch-million-players]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Larian wanted a Baldur's Gate 3 Switch 2 release, but that decision apparently wasn't in the studio's hands]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/larian-wanted-a-baldurs-gate-3-switch-2-release-but-that-decision-apparently-wasnt-in-the-studios-hands</link>
            <guid>1403167</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Baldur's-Gate-3-characters-including-Karlach-and-Astarian-holding-up-torches.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Baldur's-Gate-3-characters-including-Karlach-and-Astarian-holding-up-torches.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Baldur's-Gate-3-characters-including-Karlach-and-Astarian-holding-up-torches.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Baldur's-Gate-3-characters-including-Karlach-and-Astarian-holding-up-torches.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Baldur's-Gate-3-characters-including-Karlach-and-Astarian-holding-up-torches.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Baldur's-Gate-3-characters-including-Karlach-and-Astarian-holding-up-torches.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Baldur's-Gate-3-characters-including-Karlach-and-Astarian-holding-up-torches.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Baldur's-Gate-3-characters-including-Karlach-and-Astarian-holding-up-torches.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Baldur's-Gate-3-characters-including-Karlach-and-Astarian-holding-up-torches.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Larian</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>It wasn't Larian's choice to not release <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-a-critical-success-with-critical-failures">Baldur's Gate 3</a> on <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platforms/switch-2">Switch 2</a>.</p>
<p>That's coming from studio head Swen Vincke, who shared this titbit during an AMA which Larian hosted on Reddit towards the end of last week.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>Here, the team was asked about potentially getting the critically acclaimed and award winning Baldur's Gate 3 onto Switch 2.</p>
<p>"We would have loved to but it wasn't our decision to make," came Vincke's reply. This was met with a number of disappointed community comments, such as "super bummed by this decision especially if you wanted to do it but somehow were not green lit by [the] publisher…" and "I'm shattered to read this news".</p>
<p>While Vincke did not go into further details about the lack of a Baldur's Gate 3 Switch 2 release, many have surmised it was probably due to licensing issues.</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="219"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1q870w5/comment/nymeyhg/">Comment</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Wombat_Medic/">u/Wombat_Medic</a> from discussion<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/comments/1q870w5/larian_studios_divinity_ama/"></a><br> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Games/">Games</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>But, while it doesn't sound like we will be getting Baldur's Gate 3 on Switch 2 any time soon, if ever, there is a little bit more hope that Larian's next game - Divinity - may release on Nintendo's hybrid console. During the same AMA, the studio's technical director noted Larian had just recently released <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/days-after-larians-big-the-game-awards-announcement-2017s-divinity-original-sin-2-receives-current-gen-upgrade-for-switch-2-ps5-and-xbox-series-xs">Divinity Original Sin 2 on Nintendo's latest console</a>, saying: "We love the platform." They then assured the community that Larian would of course also keep the Switch 2 in mind for Divinity, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/larian-announces-new-game-takes-ownership-of-desert-statue">which it announced during The Game Awards last month</a>, with a rather horrifying trailer.</p><p>At this time, Larian's technical director also said <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/larian-will-certainly-consider-a-divinity-switch-2-release">the team was keen to ensure Divinity was playable on Steam Deck when it releases</a> (whenever that may be). The developer remarked that Baldur's Gate 3 was one of the Steam Deck's most played games, and so the studio would do its "best" to get Divinity on there as well.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/larian-wanted-a-baldurs-gate-3-switch-2-release-but-that-decision-apparently-wasnt-in-the-studios-hands]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Our Most Wanted Games of 2026 – #5 Resident Evil Requiem]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/12/our-most-wanted-games-of-2026-5-resident-evil-requiem/</link>
            <guid>1403164</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Any game series is going to need to adapt and reinvent itself after a few entries, but few have been quite so transformative as Resident Evil. Through its many sequels and spin-offs, this horror series always keeps you on your toes and the edge of your seat.</p>
<p>A big part of horror is building up the anticipation and the scares, to not reveal everything about the monstrosities that are terrifying our protagonists. Capcom took that to heart for the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/resident-evil-9-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem’s</a> announcement as well.</p>
<p><iframe title="Resident Evil Requiem - Reveal Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/POz1-EmLsTY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>At its reveal, there was plenty of mystery about the new leading lady that Capcom had featured. Grace Ashcroft might be an FBI agent, but she’s more of a desk-bound analyst than a field agent. A cruel twist of fate sees her assigned to investigate the Renwood Hotel, the same hotel in which her mother was murdered, dragging her back to Resident Evil’s original stomping ground of Raccoon City.</p>
<p>There’s good reason for this, because<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/26/leon-was-considered-for-resident-evil-requiem-lead-heres-why-capcom-created-grace-instead/"> as Director Koshi Nakanishi said</a>, “We always thought about making Leon the protagonist, but making a horror game based around him is difficult. He wouldn’t jump at something like a bucket falling. No one wants to see Leon scared by every little thing, so he’s actually quite a bad match for horror.”</p>

<p>So Grace is put front and centre, facing off against horrors and monstrosities that she’s got no chance of overcoming, forcing her to evade and hide instead. This was the scene for our hands on preview in the middle of last year, as I guided Grace through dark hallways, looking to reach puddles of light, to keep my noise to a minimum for fear of the hulking beast that was stalking me.</p>
<h3>Further Reading: <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/20/resident-evil-requiem-preview-first-person-frights-third-person-delights/">RE Requiem Preview – first person frights, third person delights</a></h3>
<p>But then comes the twist because… well, why not have Leon in the game too?</p>
<p><iframe title="Resident Evil Requiem - 3rd Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T54OWinnymM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Leon will be featured in Resident Evil Requiem, his story intertwined with Grace’s, letting her handle all the tense psychological horror, while Leon will be handling all the gory action. How nice of him.</p>
<p>One of the great things for Resident Evil Requiem is that, where previous games have made the choice for you, Requiem can be played in both first person and third person from day one –&nbsp;Village added this choice through DLC. The game also looks to push a new generation of the RE Engine that has powered so many of Capcom’s games over the past decade.</p>
<p>Thankfully the wait for this one isn’t too long. Resident Evil Requiem is launching on 27th February 2026 for PS5, Xbox Series X|S and PC.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/12/our-most-wanted-games-of-2026-5-resident-evil-requiem/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>