<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 16:47:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Internet Reacts To The Minecraft Movie’s Divisive Teaser Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-trailer-internet-reacts-jack-black-1851640832</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-internet-reacts-to-the-minecraft-movie%E2%80%99s-divisive-teaser-trailer.973161/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-trailer-internet-reacts-jack-black-1851640832<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-jack-black-steve-jason-momoa-trailer-1851639338&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-movie-jack-black-steve-jason-momoa-trailer-1851639338">first official trailer</a></span> for the live-action <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-jason-momoa-movie-adaptation-jared-hess-warne-1848808544&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-jason-momoa-movie-adaptation-jared-hess-warne-1848808544"><em>Minecraft </em>movie</a></span>—which is annoyingly titled <em>A Minecraft Movie</em>—has finally been released. On September 4, Warner Bros. posted what it called a teaser for the movie to social media and the film distributor’s YouTube channel. Starring <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/tenacious-d-trump-joke-jack-black-kyle-gass-cancel-1851594630&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/tenacious-d-trump-joke-jack-black-kyle-gass-cancel-1851594630">Jack Black</a></span> and Jason Momoa, the film is set to bring the best-selling video game of all time to the big screen, but this first look has made fans less than excited about what’s in store.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="193831" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Octopath Dreamland Deluxe" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="226" data-playlist="193831,195410,196299" data-current="193831"><div><p>The Week In Games: Octopath Dreamland Deluxe</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/193831/193831_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/19283.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The trailer, set to the Beatles’ “Magical Mystery Tour,” introduces audiences to the film’s cast and the blocky world in which their adventure will take place. Fans of the game will catch a lot of familiar items and creatures, such as the iconic green creeper, a tree floating with a block of wood missing from its trunk, and many weird looking animals.</p><p>One of the biggest initial reactions to the teaser trailer from fans is dissatisfaction over the film’s look, which brings a strange CGI aesthetic to the iconic blocky textures of <em>Minecraft</em>. Many have taken to social media to voice their concerns over the visual style of the movie, with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/death444star/status/1831694473115443360&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/death444star/status/1831694473115443360" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one poster</a></span> on X (formerly Twitter) saying that, “we gotta give the <em>Minecraft </em>movie the sonic treatment bc it’s looking buns rn,” referring to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/sonic-movie-first-trailer-ugly-design-delay-redesign-1851446390&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/sonic-movie-first-trailer-ugly-design-delay-redesign-1851446390">the debacle surrounding Sonic’s original trailer design for his 2020 film</a></span>, a look that would be completely redone before the movie’s release. Other criticisms of the movie’s aesthetic call it worse than AI, or just as bad as crappy renderings of what “realistic <em>Minecraft</em>” would be like.</p><p>To make matters worse, audiences are also bringing up <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/minecraft-story-mode-works-surprisingly-well-1736251691&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-story-mode-works-surprisingly-well-1736251691"><em>Minecraft: Story Mode</em></a></span>, the 2015 game from Telltale that took a more narrative approach to the sandbox title. While it had its problems, <em>Story Mode</em> retained the iconic style of the original game, with blocky textures and characters throughout that made it feel like it was set in true <em>Minecraft</em>. Almost a decade since its release, and with the trailer for the movie not satisfying a lot of fans, some are seeing <em>Story Mode</em> in a new light.</p><p>Yet, beyond all the hate on how the<em> Minecraft Movie</em> looks, there are some acknowledging what the film actually is: a fun, if silly, movie aimed towards kids. <em>Kotaku</em>’s own John Walker said as much in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/a-minecraft-movie-trailer-jack-black-kids-1851640395&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/a-minecraft-movie-trailer-jack-black-kids-1851640395">his post</a></span> on the internet backlash to the movie, succinctly telling adults complaining on the internet that the movie just isn’t for them. He’s not wrong! This movie is absolutely trying to be just fun enough to make kids happy. </p><p>I think there’s a world in which a <em>Minecraft </em>movie could have served old and young fans, without being what looks to me like the most boring drivel imaginable. But clearly, this version of the film is doing exactly what it aims to, whether we like it or not.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 Patch 7 With Mod Support Is Live On PC]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-with-mod-support-is-live-on-pc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-patch-7-with-mod-support-is-live-on-pc.973158/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-with-mod-support-is-live-on-pc/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Larian Studios has finally released <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-patch-7-coming/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the highly-anticipated</a> Patch 7 for Baldur’s Gate 3 on PC. </p>



<p>The <a href="https://baldursgate3.game/news/patch-7-now-live_121">new patch adds a number of features</a> to the game. From new evil ending cinematics to Honor Mode improvements to new Legendary Actions, there’s a lot for players in this update. Of course, there’s no bigger addition than official mod support for Baldur’s Gate 3.</p>



<p>“We’re also bringing you another way to mod your Baldur’s Gate 3 saves, with Patch 7 introducing our very own in-game Mod Manager and modding Toolkit,” Larian Studios said. “With this new and supported way to create and install mods, you should see improvements in compatibility and accessibility, and can rest more assured that your supported mods work wherever you’re playing Baldur’s Gate 3.”</p>



<p>With the mod support and the new Toolkit along with the rest of the update, there is the potential for third-party modes to become incompatible. </p>



<p>“Please try uninstalling your mods and confirm whether the issue persists without them installed,” Larian says.</p>



<p>While Baldur’s Gate Patch 7 is available now on PC, those on Mac and console will have to wait a little longer. Larian says that the update will come to those platforms sometime in October.</p>



<p>The patch comes in at 11.6GB on PC and requires 160GB of free space to install on your machine. Should you not have the space to install the update, Larian suggest uninstalling the game and then re-downloading the patched version of the game.</p>



<p>While Patch 7 is going to be the last major update to the game, Larian isn’t done support Baldur’s Gate 3 just yet. The studio is still working on full crossplay and a photo mode along with various other fixes. Once those are out the door, however, Larian will then pivot fully to its next,  unannounced project.</p>



<p>Full notes for Patch 7, which includes hundreds of fixes and updates, can be found via <a href="https://baldursgate3.game/news/patch-7-now-live_121" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the game’s official website</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Are you going to check out Baldur’s Gate Patch 7 now that its out on PC? For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-will-get-post-launch-dlc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">current plans for Astro Bot post launch</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Members Get 28 Free Games In September]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-members-get-28-free-games-in-september/1100-6526296/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-prime-members-get-28-free-games-in-september.973155/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-members-get-28-free-games-in-september/1100-6526296/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526296">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Amazon has revealed the next batch of games that'll be available through its Prime Gaming service, and in a month that's already <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/the-biggest-game-releases-of-september-2024/2900-5729/" data-ref-id="2900-5729">crowded with high-profile new releases</a>, subscribers can get a pretty good selection of freebies. The first wave of games are now available, and in addition to the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/prime-gaming-is-giving-away-two-lord-of-the-rings-games-to-celebrate-rings-of-power-season-2/1100-6526141/" data-ref-id="1100-6526141">Lord of the Rings games that were previously announced</a>--Shadow of Mordor and Lego Lord of the Rings--you can also grab some Borderlands and Tomb Raider games.</p><p>As a reminder, once you claim the free games from Prime Gaming, they are yours to keep forever--even if your subscription expires. If you aren't a member, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/prime/pipeline/signup?tag=gamespot-promos-20&amp;tag=gamespot-buybutton-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">you can sign up for Amazon Prime</a> for as little as one month to take advantage of the subscription and score some great freebies.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/borderlands-2/" data-ref-id="5000-112742">Borderlands 2</a> put the franchise on the map with its polished gunplay, weird sense of humor, and one of the all-time best villains in video games, and while it wasn't as warmly received, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/borderlands-the-pre-sequel/" data-ref-id="5000-264457">Borderlands: The Pre-Sequel</a> is still a solid chapter in the series that filled in several gaps in the story. If you like collecting a bajillion guns and dubstep, you'll want to grab these. Don't forget to redeem the<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-players-have-cracked-the-code-for-the-most-valuable-shift-key-ever-made/1100-6526259/" data-ref-id="1100-6526259"> most-valuable Shift key of all time</a>, as you can give yourself an advantage in combat with some of the best loot in those games.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/shadow-of-the-tomb-raider/" data-ref-id="5000-479759">Shadow of the Tomb Raider</a> is also available this week, and this is the final chapter in Lara Croft's origin story. This is the definitive edition of the 2018 game, so you're getting a ton of extra content and DLC to play with. You can also check out <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/greedfall/" data-ref-id="5000-462064">Greedfall</a>--an RPG about magic, exploration, and colonialism--and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/eternights/" data-ref-id="5000-565527">Eternights</a> is a dating action game where you try to make the most out of life during the apocalypse.</p><p>The next batch of games will be available starting September 12, and one of the highlights here is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/tales-from-the-borderlands-a-telltale-game-series/" data-ref-id="5000-404835">Tales from the Borderlands</a>. A five-part episodic game set on Pandora between the events of Borderlands 2 and Borderlands 3, this was a well-received change of pace from the loot-centric games in the main series. Another game to check out is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/cursed-to-golf/" data-ref-id="5000-537207">Cursed to Golf</a>, a weird and wild story about being trapped in Golf Purgatory after a freak accident takes you out of action--and life. You can also download <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/showgunners/" data-ref-id="5000-569582">Showgunners</a>, a game about a brutal reality show where you're playing as a contestant out for revenge.</p><p>September 26 adds several more games, but the big one here is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/thronebreaker-the-witcher-tales/" data-ref-id="5000-487270">Thronebreaker: The Witcher Tales</a>. This is a single-player role-playing game set in the world of The Witcher and it combines narrative-driven exploration with unique puzzles and card-battle mechanics. The final batch of games will be released on September 26, and includes Ghost Song, Mystery Case Files: Black Crown, Ynglet, Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams, and Black Desert.</p><h2>Prime Gaming free games for September 2024</h2><h3>Now available</h3><ul><li>Middle-earth: Shadow of Mordor Game of the Year Edition</li><li>Lego The Lord of the Rings</li><li>Borderlands 2</li><li>Shadow of the Tomb Raider: Definitive Edition</li><li>GreedFall: Gold Edition</li><li>Eternights</li><li>Borderlands: The Pre-Sequel</li><li>Whispered Secrets: Everburning Candle Collector's Edition</li><li>Minabo - A Walk through Life</li><li>Lego Indiana Jones: The Original Adventures</li></ul><h3>September 12</h3><ul><li>Tales from the Borderlands</li><li>9 Years of Shadows</li><li>Moonlighter</li><li>Cursed to Golf</li><li>Hell Pie</li><li>Showgunners</li><li>Arcadegeddon</li><li>Golfie</li></ul><h3>September 19</h3><ul><li>Thronebreaker: The Witcher Tales</li><li>The Falconeer</li><li>Lego The Hobbit</li><li>I Love Finding Cats &amp; Pups: Collector’s Edition</li><li>Kerbal Space Program</li></ul><h3>September 26</h3><ul><li>Ghost Song</li><li>Black Desert</li><li>Mystery Case Files: Black Crown - Collector's Edition</li><li>Ynglet</li><li>Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams</li></ul><p>Prime subscribers will also be able to the following games in September via the Prime Gaming Luna channel:</p><ul><li>Middle-earth: Shadow of War</li><li>Whisker Waters</li><li>Super Meat Boy Forever</li><li>CleM</li><li>XDefiant</li><li>Fortnite Battle Royale</li><li>Fortnite Festival</li><li>Fallout New Vegas: Ultimate Edition</li><li>Fallout 3: Game of the Year Edition</li><li>Lego Fortnite</li><li>Rocket Racing</li><li>Fortnite</li><li>Trackmania</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Be Cool And Don't Spoil The Story, Says Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Publisher]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/be-cool-and-dont-spoil-the-story-says-warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-publisher/1100-6526297/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/be-cool-and-dont-spoil-the-story-says-warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-publisher.973152/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/be-cool-and-dont-spoil-the-story-says-warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-publisher/1100-6526297/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526297">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 is now out in the wild for people who ponied up the cash for the Gold or Ultra editions of the sequel. As such, publisher Focus Entertainment wants these early-access players to "share the glory, not the story."</p><p dir="ltr"><a href="https://x.com/Focus_entmt/status/1831373193593995643" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">On X</a>, Focus posted a graphic asking Space Marine 2 players to be mindful of others out there who won't get to play the third-person shooter until next week. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-when-youll-be-able-to-play-warhammer-40000-space-marines-2/1100-6526244/" data-ref-id="1100-6526244">Early access begins today for the sequel</a>, while the standard release is September 9. With that in mind, the image states: "No spoilers! Every space marine out there deserves the thrill of discovering the game's story on their own."</p><p dir="ltr">The story does sound pretty captivating. GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-review/1900-6418276/" data-ref-id="1900-6418276">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 review</a> highlights how "the sense of scale is tremendous, both in terms of your enemy and the world around you," for instance.</p><p dir="ltr">Players can also squad up together in Space Marine 2's campaign, with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/does-warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-have-cross-play-and-cross-save/1100-6526283/" data-ref-id="1100-6526283">the sequel offering cross-play and cross-save options</a>. However, in PvP, PC and console players will be separated for competitive reasons.</p><p dir="ltr">Looking ahead, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-will-have-no-microtransactions/1100-6523722/" data-ref-id="1100-6523722">don't expect any microtransactions for Space Marine 2</a>. Instead, "any paid DLCs will be cosmetic only," according to developer Saber Interactive.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astro Bot DLC Revealed, Adding Speedrun Mode & Challenge Levels]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/astro-bot-dlc-revealed-adding-speedrun-mode-challenge-levels/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/astro-bot-dlc-revealed-adding-speedrun-mode-challenge-levels.973119/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/astro-bot-dlc-revealed-adding-speedrun-mode-challenge-levels/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A recent trip to the Team Asobi studio <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/astro-bot-dlc-will-include-challenge-and-speedrun-levels/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">made by VGC</a> revealed upcoming plans for a DLC for Astro Bot, a game that will be released on September 6. Reviews have already started pouring in, and you can read our <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/astro-bot-celebrated-platformer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">review written by Kai here</a>. For those who have already played it, the game is highly revered and scored 94 on Metacritic, making it Universally Acclaimed. When people get around to playing it, they may want more from Astro Bot. With the trip that VGC made to Team Asobi, it has been confirmed that there is a DLC coming, which adds to Speedrun mode and challenge levels for those who want to push themselves to the limit.</p>
<p><iframe title="Astro Bot - Launch Trailer | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/unYFdcEjV9k?start=40&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>To prepare for the upcoming release of Astro Bot, Team Asobi has been adding plenty of content to Astro's Playroom, the predecessor to Astro Bot. This includes new trophies for players, such as collecting all four Special Bots and trophies for collecting them individually from their dedicated area. It also includes gatchas, where players can use their in-game currencies to collect the special rewards.</p>
<p>According to the report made by VGC, Team Asobi is planning on adding new content over the coming weeks and months, with an estimate of ten challenge levels and five speedrun-focused levels. However, it isn't fully confirmed whether that will be everything that is added, and it will most likely revolve around the success of Astro Bot.</p>
<p>With how well it's currently doing in the critics' eyes, likely, the game will also be universally liked by those who purchase it. Additionally, Team Asobi have expressed interest that they want to know whether those on PC would be interested in being able to access Astro Bot, with Team Asobi saying in <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/features/astro-bot-how-team-asobi-has-turned-playroom-into-a-galaxy-sized-sequel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an interview with VGC</a>, Nicolas Doucet, the Creative Director of Team Asobi noted that he believes it wouldn't be an issue if there were an Astro Bot game released in the future that didn't rely on PlayStation theming. Before the pack-in Astro Bot game for PlayStation 5 was released, it was a point of contention whether they would rely on PlayStation's theming for the game, but so far it seems to be a nostalgic success.</p>
<p>Even with the free pack-in software alone for PlayStation 5, Astro Bot has provided fun and nostalgia to those who grew up with the consoles, and the possibility of an Astro Bot DLC gives the game and franchise even more room to grow and to stand on its own two feet.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heed the Dark Urge and check out Baldur's Gate 3's Patch 7, which adds 13 new evil endings plus official mod tools]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heed-the-dark-urge-and-check-out-baldurs-gate-3s-patch-7-which-adds-13-new-evil-endings-plus-official-mod-tools</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heed-the-dark-urge-and-check-out-baldurs-gate-3s-patch-7-which-adds-13-new-evil-endings-plus-official-mod-tools.973116/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heed-the-dark-urge-and-check-out-baldurs-gate-3s-patch-7-which-adds-13-new-evil-endings-plus-official-mod-tools<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Long-awaited patch leaves beta with revamped splitscreen and bug fixes</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Baldur's-Gate-Dark-Urge-1.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Larian Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Did you forget about <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-class-list">Baldur's Gate 3</a>? Because Baldur's Gate 3 did not forget about you. Specifically, it did not forget about the incorrigible evil-doers amongst you who've been gunning for some additional plot catharsis. Larian's very bestest <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> has been biding its time in the shadows while you've been busy with other games. It has lingered silently while you occupy yourself heisting on Tatooine or messing up Golden-Eyed Beasts, waiting and waiting for the perfect moment - and now, it has finally struck with an unholy new patch, which adds 13 new Evil Endings, revamped splitscreen and an official modding toolkit. Foolish summer child! It is too late to flee.</p><!--more-->
<p>We last heard about Patch 7 back in July, in the shape of a blog post <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-will-add-dynamic-splitscreen-new-evil-endings-dark-urge-fixes-and-lots-more-kissing">that contained no less than 10 mentions of kissing</a>. Subsequently, there was a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/delayed-baldurs-gate-3-patch-notes-reckon-youve-all-been-eating-too-much-delicious-irresistible-soap">stern memo about players eating soap</a>. The full changelog eases off on both the soap and the sauce, with just five kisses to unearth and minimal discussion of cleansing products. It also details revisions to the game's "Show Cinematic Nudity" option, which is now "Show Sexual and Violent Cinematics" and has a more extensive description. </p>
<p>I highlight the Show Sexual And Violent Cinematics setting because you'll need to disable it if you want to view the aforesaid new evil endings in their entirety. They are, after all, <em>very</em> evil. "This setting does not affect your adventure, your choices, or your access to romance options," the changelog reassures. "However, it does block sexual content with nudity and particularly violent scenes with gore."</p>
<p>If you're playing as a Dark Urge character, the update also makes it possible to add a particular Tiefing bard to your party as a controllable character at camp, given an empty slot. This is very much a "one-night kinda thing", however. "There are no new companions," the developers note. "There is only death." If you were hoping for a surprise deluge of permanent full-time party members, you'll have to console yourself with new Honour Mode features instead. These include new Legendary Actions - Dror Ragzlin will now be able to befriend pit spiders, while local physician Malus Thorm has a new trick called Grasping Appendage.</p>
<p>And then there's the official in-game mod manager and accompanying toolkit, available via Steam, which are far too <a href="https://baldursgate3.game/news/community-update-27-official-modding-support_118?mc_cid=62c7d6b649&amp;mc_eid=e6ec8a7074">voluminous</a> to summarise. "With this new and supported way to create and install mods, you should see improvements in compatibility and accessibility, and can rest more assured that your supported mods work wherever you're playing Baldur's Gate 3, which will include consoles a little down the line," the devs note.</p>
<p>Patch 7 weighs approximately 11.6GB on PC, and will require 160GB of free space to install - the devs suggest uninstalling and reinstalling the patched version as a single download if you don't have room.</p>
<p>Larian are still working on crossplay and photo mode, but this will be one of the last significant Baldur's Gate 3 patches, as the developers bid the Sword Coast goodbye and commence work on no less than <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/larian-have-two-new-games-in-the-works-fueled-by-the-very-same-fire-as-baldurs-gate-3">two new games</a>. As the patch notes conclude, "it's time for the team to go back to our cave and hang the armour on the wall while we focus on bringing you our next project."</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Disclosure: Former RPS deputy editor Adam Smith (RPS in peace) now works at Larian and is the lead writer for Baldur's Gate 3. Former contributor Emily Gera also works on it.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Can Finally Unlock The Doom Skin In Fortnite]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fortnite-unlock-doom-skin-guide-1851640774</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-finally-unlock-the-doom-skin-in-fortnite.973110/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/fortnite-unlock-doom-skin-guide-1851640774<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><figure id="" data-id="14b2f7af0b55766da2bf462a557d5156" data-recommend-id="image://14b2f7af0b55766da2bf462a557d5156" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="It's the comic cover for Dr Doom's latest quests. He's all green and lightningy." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="It's the comic cover for Dr Doom's latest quests. He's all green and lightningy." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Epic / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="14b2f7af0b55766da2bf462a557d5156" data-recommend-id="image://14b2f7af0b55766da2bf462a557d5156" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="It's the comic cover for Dr Doom's latest quests. He's all green and lightningy." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>If you purchased the Chapter 5, Season 4 battle pass, you can now unlock the Doom skin. But you’ll need to complete a series of quests before you can rock it around the island. Read on to learn every detail you’ll need to know about unlocking the elusive Doom skin.</p><h2 id="h27015"><a id=""></a><strong><em>Page 1</em></strong></h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>The strongest metals are forged in the hottest flames - Loading screen</li><li>No unseen defense can stand against my power - Doom’s Cloak (Back Bling)</li><li>No man, monster, or monument may stand before Doom. - Weapon Wrap</li><li>4… I am not overly fond of the number. - The Doomblade (Pickaxe)</li><li>Her shadow is my place of peace in this world of torment - Fist of Doom (Glider)</li><li>Stark thinks himself a genius investor. I beg to differ. - Doom (skin)</li></ul><h2 id="h27016"><a id=""></a><strong><em>Page 2</em></strong></h2><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>This chest is now property of Latveria - Pandora Doomblade</li><li>Insolence must be punished - Latverian Monarch Decor</li><li>There is triumph, even in torment - Doom’s Pandora Cloak (Back Bling)</li><li>Doom masters all that lies before - Pandora’s Fist Of Doom</li><li>Defend Latveria. At all costs. - Doom’s Domain (Emote)</li><li>Success of the strong demands sacrifice of the weak - Pandora’s Armor Doom (Skin)</li></ul><p>On the next two pages, we break down each of these stages.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="3dbe1500f044bc8538f6eebc47bfb1c6" data-recommend-id="image://3dbe1500f044bc8538f6eebc47bfb1c6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Standing in a fire for fun and profit." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Standing in a fire for fun and profit." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Epic / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="3dbe1500f044bc8538f6eebc47bfb1c6" data-recommend-id="image://3dbe1500f044bc8538f6eebc47bfb1c6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Standing in a fire for fun and profit." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><h3 id="h27017"><a id=""></a><strong>The strongest metals are forged in the hottest flames</strong></h3><p>To complete this quest, you’ll need to take some fire damage. This is easily done by landing on the mini-island on the northmost side and starting the campfire. As soon as the fire starts stand in the flame, and you’ll be done.</p><h3 id="h27018"><a id=""></a><strong>No unseen defense can stand against my power</strong></h3><p>For this quest, we recommend landing at one of the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dr-doom-fortnite-marvel-locations-guide-1851625368&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dr-doom-fortnite-marvel-locations-guide-1851625368">Marvel-themed areas with a boss</a></span>. When you get there, begin shooting the AIs. After you crack five of their shields, you’ll finish this quest.</p><h3 id="h27019"><a id=""></a><strong>No man, monster, or monument may stand before Doom</strong></h3><figure id="" data-id="36f17b812ab065f4df9112aae6c1cfa8" data-recommend-id="image://36f17b812ab065f4df9112aae6c1cfa8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Defeating Doom's Doombot." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Defeating Doom's Doombot." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Epic / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="36f17b812ab065f4df9112aae6c1cfa8" data-recommend-id="image://36f17b812ab065f4df9112aae6c1cfa8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Defeating Doom's Doombot." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This is another quest you can complete by naturally playing the game. All you need to do for this is hit 51 rocks or structures. If you’re looking to finish this fast, we suggest landing at Restored Reels because most of the buildings there are made of stone.</p><h3 id="h27020"><a id=""></a><strong>4… I am not overly fond of the number</strong></h3><figure id="" data-id="c95f4a9324bb2f4baeff17a2cb73ae51" data-recommend-id="image://c95f4a9324bb2f4baeff17a2cb73ae51" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shooting someone from more than 44 meters away." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Shooting someone from more than 44 meters away." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Epic / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c95f4a9324bb2f4baeff17a2cb73ae51" data-recommend-id="image://c95f4a9324bb2f4baeff17a2cb73ae51" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Shooting someone from more than 44 meters away." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>For this quest, you’ll be tasked with inflicting a total of 200 damage to opponents that are beyond 44 meters away from you. This can be a bit challenging, but we once again recommend going to one of the Marvel-themed areas with a boss and shooting the AIs. Just make sure there is some good distance between you and them.</p><h3 id="h27021"><a id=""></a><strong>Her shadow is my place of peace in this world of torment</strong></h3><p>This is straightforward. You only need to reach the statue near Rebel’s Roost and crouch. Once you pay your respects, you’ll complete this portion of the quest.</p><h3 id="h27022"><a id=""></a><strong>Stark thinks himself a genius investor. I beg to differ</strong></h3><figure id="" data-id="ca08e9dcc9602cf3ea016e9053efa141" data-recommend-id="image://ca08e9dcc9602cf3ea016e9053efa141" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Holding War Machine's stuff, only to drop it." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Holding War Machine's stuff, only to drop it." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Epic / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ca08e9dcc9602cf3ea016e9053efa141" data-recommend-id="image://ca08e9dcc9602cf3ea016e9053efa141" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Holding War Machine's stuff, only to drop it." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>For this quest, you’ll need to collect all of War Machine’s weapons and gear, and drop them. These can be a bit challenging to obtain. We suggest landing either at Restored Reels or Rebel’s Roost. The reason is that these areas always spawn Avenger chests, increasing the odds of finding the gear you need. Oh, and then pick it all back up again as it’s super-useful.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="a9e0bddcea1d1b10164bf5776aaca1f2" data-recommend-id="image://a9e0bddcea1d1b10164bf5776aaca1f2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A Latverian chest." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Latverian chest." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Epic / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a9e0bddcea1d1b10164bf5776aaca1f2" data-recommend-id="image://a9e0bddcea1d1b10164bf5776aaca1f2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A Latverian chest." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><h3 id="h27023"><a id=""></a><strong>This chest is now property of Latveria</strong></h3><p>For this quest, you’ll need to open five rare chests. These commonly spawn in named areas, especially if they’re highlighted gold. You’ll know you found one when you spot a giant blue chest. After you open five, you’ll complete this quest.</p><h3 id="h27024"><a id=""></a><strong>Insolence must be punished</strong></h3><p>This quest is easier said than done. For this, we recommend playing with friends because you’ll need to kill either the Doombot or someone carrying the Arcane Gauntlets. Once you’ve obtained them, you’ll need to be smart and use them wisely in combat because they’re not the best weapons. To complete this quest, you must hit four players with Doom’s Arcane Gauntlets.</p><h3 id="h27025"><a id=""></a><strong>There is triumph, even in torment</strong></h3><p>This is another quest that may take a little while to complete. What you need to do is place first or second in a match. Depending on how sweaty your lobbies are, this may take a while to complete.</p><h3 id="h27026"><a id=""></a><strong>Doom masters all that lies before</strong></h3><p>Here you’ll need to pick up Captain America’s Shield or Shuri’s Black Panther Claws from a fallen enemy. It’s important to mention that you don’t need to be the one that kills them. The quest will be completed as long as another dead player has them before you.</p><h3 id="h27027"><a id=""></a><strong>Defend Latveria. At all costs</strong></h3><figure id="" data-id="dc9bc8d109da5aa6d2159a6f0d8cff06" data-recommend-id="image://dc9bc8d109da5aa6d2159a6f0d8cff06" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Attacking other players in Doom-themed areas." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Attacking other players in Doom-themed areas." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Epic / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="dc9bc8d109da5aa6d2159a6f0d8cff06" data-recommend-id="image://dc9bc8d109da5aa6d2159a6f0d8cff06" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Attacking other players in Doom-themed areas." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>To complete this quest, you’ll be tasked with killing ten players in any of the Doom-themed areas on the map. We recommend landing at either Doom Castle or Doomstadt because those are the two most popular areas out of the three.</p><h3 id="h27028"><a id=""></a><strong>Success of the strong demands sacrifice of the weak</strong></h3><figure id="" data-id="6a8755be1bddc700b69347c9ca017759" data-recommend-id="image://6a8755be1bddc700b69347c9ca017759" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Defeating AIs on a stairwell." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Defeating AIs on a stairwell." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Epic / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="6a8755be1bddc700b69347c9ca017759" data-recommend-id="image://6a8755be1bddc700b69347c9ca017759" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Defeating AIs on a stairwell." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This quest is fairly easy to complete. All you have to do is defeat five AIs in any of the Marvel-themed areas or dig sites. Once you’ve done that, you’ll finish the quest.</p><hr><p>Congratulations, you’ve just unlocked both Doom skins! Now go terrorize the island and have fun.<br></p><p>.</p></div></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Interactive Entertainment shares early glimpse at PlayStation 30th anniversary plans]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/sony-interactive-entertainment-shares-early-glimpse-at-playstation-30th-anniversary-plans</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-interactive-entertainment-shares-early-glimpse-at-playstation-30th-anniversary-plans.973104/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/sony-interactive-entertainment-shares-early-glimpse-at-playstation-30th-anniversary-plans<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,880 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/09/05/celebrating-30-years-of-playstation-my-first-gt-digital-soundtracks-shapes-of-play-collection-and-theres-more-to-come/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">shared</a> an early glimpse at some of its plans for <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [45,919 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a>‘s 30th anniversary, which it will celebrate on December 3. Today’s reveals include a free trial version of <em><a title="Games > Gran Turismo 7 [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/gran-turismo-7">Gran Turismo 7</a></em> called <em>My First Gran Turismo</em>, digital game soundtracks, a “Shapes of Play” product collection, a free multiplayer online weekend, and esports tournaments. According to Sony Interactive Entertainment, these activities and releases are “just a taste of what’s to come” as it approaches the 30th anniversary later this year. <span id="more-912836"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><div><p><strong>■ <em><a title="Games > ASTRO BOT [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/astro-bot">ASTRO BOT</a></em> – <a title="Platforms > PS3 [15,621 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps3">PlayStation 3</a>0th Anniversary Photo Opportunity</strong></p><p>We’re pleased to share a first look at a 30th anniversary photo opportunity located in <em>ASTRO BOT</em>‘s central hub, where Bots you’ve saved throughout your spacefaring <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,740 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>s will hang out, ready to dance along with your stylish moves.</p><p><iframe title="Astrobot - PlayStation 30th Anniversary" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jwut96VGuM4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>■ An Early Look at What’s Ahead</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong><em>My First Gran Turismo</em></strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/PS-30th_09-05-24_001.jpeg"></a></figure><p>This holiday, look forward to <em>My First Gran Turismo</em>—a free trial version designed to attract a diverse players of all skill levels to the globally acclaimed <em>Gran Turismo 7</em>. This upcoming release will include some of the favorite cars, tracks, and race events that evoke the nostalgia and excitement of the very first <em>Gran Turismo</em> experience. Look out for more details on <em>My First Gran Turismo</em>, available to all <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,866 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,156 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> players this holiday.</p><p><strong>Digital Game Soundtracks</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/PS-30th_09-05-24_002.jpg"></a></figure><p>In collaboration with Sony Music, each month from October through January, we’ll release for the first time on Spotify a set of digital soundtracks from fan-favorite PlayStation franchises. You’ll be able to stream the following game soundtracks on Spotify or purchase them on various digital music storefronts, including Amazon Music, Apple Music, and participating music retailers:</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > God of War (2018) [175 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/god-of-war-2018">God of War</a>​</em></li><li><em>God of War II​</em></li><li><em>God of War: Ghost of Sparta</em></li><li><em>Twisted <a title="Platforms > Meta [120 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta">Meta</a>l​</em></li><li><em>Starhawk​</em></li><li><em>Warhawk</em></li><li><em>Unit 13</em></li></ul><p>You can also vibe to our specially curated PlayStation 30th Anniversary playlist on Spotify, available to stream today. We’ll have more to share on the upcoming digital soundtrack releases, which will be added to this playlist over time, so stay tuned!</p><p><strong>Shapes of Play</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/PS-30th_09-05-24_003.jpg"></a></figure><p>A new collection of products called “Shapes of Play,” crafted by the team behind the design of PlayStation consoles, gives you opportunities to create fun moments with our iconic shapes:</p><ul><li><a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/buy-accessories/shapes-of-play-battle" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Shapes of Play: Battle</strong></a> – A <a title="Genres > Board Game [45 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/board-game">board game</a> where you can challenge a friend to line up four different shapes of the same color on the board to win.</li><li><a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/buy-accessories/shapes-of-play-create" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Shapes of Play: Create</strong></a> – A set of magnetic blocks that you can position in any direction to create fun shapes.</li><li><a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/buy-accessories/shapes-of-play-recharge" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Shapes of Play: Recharge</strong></a> – Lets you experience a new way to recharge between games, especially after that tough boss battle.</li></ul><p>Shapes of Play will launch in December 2024, exclusively through direct.playstation.com in the United States, United Kingdom, France, Germany, Austria, Spain, Portugal, Italy and Benelux. Preorders start today exclusively through <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-us/collections/shapes-of-play" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Direct</a>.</p><p><strong>Free Online <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [378 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">Multiplayer</a> Weekend and Esports Tournaments</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/PS-30th_09-05-24_004.jpg"></a></figure><p>Join us later this month for a free online multiplayer weekend and exciting esports tournaments! To celebrate the fantastic online games and communities on PlayStation, we’re hosting a free online multiplayer weekend on September 21 and 22. During those days, you can enjoy online multiplayer for games you own without having a PlayStation Plus membership, on PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 4 consoles.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/PS-30th_09-05-24_005.jpg"></a></figure><p>During the same weekend, we’ll host a series of PlayStation 5 esports tournaments, featuring titles like <em><a title="Games > NBA 2K24 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/nba-2k24">NBA 2K24</a></em>, <em><a title="Games > NBA 2K25 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/nba-2k25">NBA 2K25</a></em>, <em>Madden NFL 24</em>, <em><a title="Games > MLB The Show 24 [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mlb-the-show-24">MLB The Show 24</a></em>, <em><a title="Companies > Electronic Arts [1,750 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/electronic-arts">EA</a> UFC 5</em>, <em><a title="Games > Tekken 8 [50 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tekken-8">Tekken 8</a></em>, and <em><a title="Games > Guilty Gear: Strive [88 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/guilty-gear-strive">Guilty Gear: Strive</a></em>. If you own any of these games and qualify, you can compete on September 21 and 22 to win a special 30th anniversary-themed avatar and other game-specific prizes. Players on PlayStation 5 can sign up via the Game Hub or the in-game PlayStation Tournaments button. Keep an eye on compete.playstation.com for all the upcoming tournament details.</p><p><em>—Image of the PlayStation avatars players will receive for participating in any of the September 21 to 22 esports tournaments.</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/PS-30th_09-05-24_006.jpg"></a></figure><p>As we celebrate 30 years of play, these upcoming activities and releases are just a taste of what’s to come. Be on the lookout for more announcements in the near future!</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madden 25 Is Free To Play This Weekend On PS5 And Xbox Series X|S]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-25-is-free-to-play-this-weekend-on-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s/1100-6526295/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/madden-25-is-free-to-play-this-weekend-on-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s.973101/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/madden-25-is-free-to-play-this-weekend-on-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s/1100-6526295/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526295">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Just in time for the start of the new NFL season, EA Sports has announced that Madden NFL 25 is free on all platforms now through September 8. You can follow the links below to download the game now on your preferred platform.</p><ul><li><a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP0006-PPSA18888_00-MADDENNFL25GAME0/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/ea-sports-madden-nfl-25/9p1rkdk0r4cm?rtc=1" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xbox Series X|S</a></li></ul><p>The 2024 NFL season begins today, September 5, with a matchup between the Kansas City Chiefs and the Baltimore Ravens. That's right, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ryan-murphys-grotesquerie-trailer-reveals-travis-kelces-first-acting-role/1100-6526266/" data-ref-id="1100-6526266">the actor Travis Kelce</a> also plays football.</p><p>If football is not your thing, TopSpin 2K25 is free on Xbox for Game Pass Core and Game Pass Ultimate members now through Sunday, September 8. The timing here is not random, either, as the promotion is no doubt tied to the US Open women's and men's finals taking place this coming weekend in New York.</p><p>For more on these games, be sure to read GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/madden-nfl-25-review-gridiron-grates/1900-6418271/" data-ref-id="1900-6418271">Madden NFL 25</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/top-spin-2k25-review-painting-the-lines/1900-6418222/" data-ref-id="1900-6418222">TopSpin 2K25 reviews.</a></p><p>In other sports game news, EA Sports FC releases on September 27, while NHL 25 launches on October 4. One sports game that isn't launching on time is Football Manager 25, which has been delayed to the end of November.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Prime September games include several Borderlands titles and more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/amazon-prime-september-games-include-several-borderlands-titles-and-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-prime-september-games-include-several-borderlands-titles-and-more.973098/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/amazon-prime-september-games-include-several-borderlands-titles-and-more<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Handsome Jack of all trades.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/tales-from-the-borderlands-screenshot.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Telltale</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Amazon is offering its Prime members over 20 games throughout September, which can be scooped up at no additional cost.</p>
<p>These games include a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/three-games-from-lord-of-the-rings-universe-currently-available-to-claim-for-amazon-prime-members">number of Lord of the Rings-themed entries</a>, as well as <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/shadow-of-the-tomb-raider">Shadow of the Tomb Raider</a>, GreedFall: Gold Edition and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/kerbal-space-program">Kerbal Space Program</a>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, if you were <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/borderlands-movie-earned-4m-on-its-opening-day">one of the admittedly few people who went to see the Borderlands movie</a> last month and thought a trip to Pandora looked up your street, Amazon also has a selection of Borderlands games on the way.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="7 Ways Shadow of the Tomb Raider is the Deadliest Lara Yet: New Shadow of the Tomb Raider Gameplay" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F5EfMWhWTog?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>7 Ways Shadow of the Tomb Raider is the Deadliest Lara Yet: New Shadow of the Tomb Raider Gameplay</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F5EfMWhWTog?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/F5EfMWhWTog?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>7 Ways Shadow of the Tomb Raider is the Deadliest Lara Yet. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F5EfMWhWTog" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Here's everything Amazon Prime members will be able to claim over the coming weeks.</p>
<p><strong>Available now:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shadow of Mordor Game of the Year Edition (GOG code)</li>
<li>Lego The Lord of the Rings (GOG code)</li>
<li>Borderlands 2 (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>Shadow of the Tomb Raider: Definitive Edition (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>GreedFall: Gold Edition (GOG code)</li>
<li>Whispered Secrets: Everburning Candle Collector’s Edition (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Minabo - A Walk through Life (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Eternights (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>Lego Indiana Jones: The Original Adventures (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Borderlands: The Pre-Sequel (Epic Games Store)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>12th September: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Tales from the Borderlands (Epic Games Store)</li>
<li>9 Years of Shadows (GOG code)</li>
<li>Moonlighter (GOG code)</li>
<li>Golfie (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Cursed to Golf (GOG code)</li>
<li>Hell Pie (GOG code)</li>
<li>Showgunners (GOG code)</li>
<li>Arcadegeddon (Epic Games Store)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>19th September:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Thronebreaker: The Witcher Tales (GOG code)</li>
<li>The Falconeer (GOG code)</li>
<li>Lego The Hobbit (GOG code)</li>
<li>I Love Finding Cats &amp; Pups - Collector’s Edition (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Kerbal Space Program (GOG code)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>26th September: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Mystery Case Files: Black Crown - Collector’s Edition (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Ghost Song (GOG code)</li>
<li>Ynglet (Amazon Games App)</li>
<li>Black Desert (Pearl Abyss Code)</li>
<li>Giana Sisters: Twisted Dreams (Amazon Games App)</li>
</ul>
<p>You can find more information about <a href="https://primegaming.blog/prime-gaming-september-content-update-lego-the-hobbit-borderlands-2-shadow-of-the-tomb-raider-59a7ce4a4a05">Amazon's September game offerings here</a>. Has anything taken your fancy?</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/0_QnUq1Fv3AyHPGB4F.webp?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Amazon</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>While admitting there were some issues, we were quite taken with GreedFall on its initial release.</p>
<p>"GreedFall has more than its fair share of faults, and its curious mix of the sweet and the sour is far from a roleplaying revelation. But the elements that matter have been imbued with such love and care - so much so that I quickly forgave this ambitious RPG its shortcomings," reads <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/greedfall-review-technical-shortcomings-are-overcome-by-an-abundance-of-heart">Eurogamer's GreedFall review from 2019</a>.</p>
<p>We were less enamoured with Shadow of the Tomb Raider, however. "This Tomb Raider may have motivation and purpose and a vague semblance of an emotional arc but it all rings hollow, particularly when elsewhere there's repetition and an overall lack of new ideas," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/shadow-of-the-tomb-raider-review">Shadow of the Tomb Raider review</a>. "This Lara has forgotten herself and forgotten the joy and the thrill."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Great Graphic Novel About Riding Your Bike]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/bike-road-davis-comic</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-great-graphic-novel-about-riding-your-bike.973089/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/bike-road-davis-comic<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Eleanor Davis’ graphic novel <a href="https://www.fantagraphics.com/products/you-a-bike-a-road" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>You and a Bike and a Road</em></a> came out in 2017, but was reprinted this summer by Fantagraphics. I heard about it from a very cool artist I met on my <a href="https://aftermath.site/failing-on-a-bike-trip-taught-me-too-much-about-myself" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">failed bike trip</a> last spring; I’m not sure if she recommended it to me just because it’s about bikes, or because she knew how much of its story would resonate with me in that moment. Either way, I’ve read it twice since I picked it up at the bookstore this week.</p><p>The autobiographical book tells the story of Davis’ attempt to bike from her parents’ home in Tucson, Arizona, to her home in Athens, Georgia. She illustrates each day of the trip in a diary style, with pencil drawings that range from simple lines to busy sketches of countryside and towns. Along the way, she meets cool people, sees beautiful sights, and grapples with the self-doubt and intense introspection that comes with biking long distances by yourself.</p><p>I love the vulnerability in the book; while my own bike trips have been blessedly free of bros and bravado, narratives about distance cycling often skip over the moment-to-moment in favor of grand narratives of achievement. The book inspired me to look back at photos of my own bike trips last night, and so many of my pictures brought back memories that aren’t entirely good: blurry photos when my hands were shaking with exhaustion, the last picture before a flat tire stranded me on a 90-degree day in the middle of nowhere, stretches of farmland highway that managed to be both boring and stressful. Something I love about bike travelling is that, because you’re going so far, a day can contain so many different sights and emotions; in one moment, you’re picking through city traffic cursing the world, and in the next you’re all alone atop a beautiful vista awed by how much it rules to be alive. Davis’ book captures all of that variety, without making the trip seem better or worse than it is.</p><figure><figcaption>Davis/Fantagraphics</figcaption></figure><p>Because much of her trip takes place along the border, <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20190317110332/https://slate.com/culture/2017/05/comics-dispatch-from-the-mexico-border-by-eleanor-davis.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">immigration features heavily</a>, with Davis encountering Border Patrol and people worrying about her safety alone in the desert. This brings up some of the ways privilege plays into bike touring; as the US more and more aggressively <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/06/28/nx-s1-4992010/supreme-court-homeless-punish-sleeping-encampments" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">criminalizes</a> homelessness, what does it mean that some of us can, in a way, become temporarily homeless for fun? On trips, I’m often aware of how my camping or loitering would be met with very different reactions if I weren’t so obviously a guy on a bike, or if I weren’t in areas bike travellers frequent. I’m aware of how willing strangers are to help me, and how willing I am to trust them, in ways that everyone doesn’t experience, and I appreciated this playing into Davis’ narrative.</p><p><em>You and a Bike and a Road</em> doesn’t come to any grand conclusions about any of this, or about bike travelling in general; in its messy, big-but-also-small story, it captures the variety and realities of bike touring in a way that made me even more desperate to get back on the road before the winter comes on, to remind myself that the world is so much bigger than I often let it be. I’ve only done <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_Oc6k9yxOn/?hl=en&amp;img_index=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a little exploring</a> since moving back to New York, feeling intimidated by how much logistically harder it feels than it did in DC, where the woods were right outside my front door. But there’s still time if I just tell myself I can do it and get back out there.&nbsp;</p><p>(Also, it’s frankly amazing that Davis can consistently draw a bike, which I am convinced is impossible. Seriously: before you scroll down, try to draw a bike from memory. So hard!)&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption>Davis/Fantagraphics</figcaption></figure></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pathfinder: Wrath of the Righteous Gets Surprise Children of Morta DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pathfinder-wrath-of-righteous-children-of-morta-dlc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pathfinder-wrath-of-the-righteous-gets-surprise-children-of-morta-dlc.973077/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/pathfinder-wrath-of-righteous-children-of-morta-dlc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Surprise! A brand new&nbsp;<em>Pathfinder: Wrath of the Righteous&nbsp;</em>DLC pack has been revealed, and it's bringing a crossover with a major indie roguelite. What's more, it's free for everyone!</p>
<p>The DLC is called&nbsp;<em>Visitors from Morta</em>, and as you've probably guessed, it's a crossover with pixel-art roguelite&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/children-of-morta"><em>Children of Morta</em></a>. Download this one and you're getting a new area, new unique opponents, and more.</p>
<p>Developer and publisher Owlcat says it "tried to capture the mood of&nbsp;<em>Children of Morta</em>" with this DLC, as well as preserving the characters' unique personalities while still making sure they're integrated well into the world of&nbsp;<em>Wrath of the Righteous</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/pathfinder-wrath-of-the-righteous-children-of-morta-dlc-characters.jpg?itok=uSCZpI7B 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/pathfinder-wrath-of-the-righteous-children-of-morta-dlc-characters.jpg?itok=fzzficv3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Pathfinder: Wrath of the Righteous&nbsp;</em>has some new free DLC for you to enjoy.</figcaption></figure><p>If you download and check out this DLC, you'll get a new location to enjoy, plus two new archetypes that are designed around&nbsp;<em>Children of Morta&nbsp;</em>heroes John and Lucy. You'll also be able to use those archetypes when creating your own character.</p>
<p>Additionally, you'll get a new female hairstyle based on Lucy's do, as well as a new quest involving John and Lucy, whom you must rescue and guide home.</p>
<p>If you want to access the DLC, you can do so either at the start of&nbsp;<em>Wrath of the Righteous</em>' second chapter, or at any stage in chapters three or five. Either Anevia or Arsinoe will bring you the quest, and you'll need to visit the new location on your map to start it.</p>

<p>This DLC comes as a surprise given that back in May, Owlcat <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/final-pathfinder-wrath-of-righteous-dlc-release-date">announced</a> that the then-upcoming DLC pack&nbsp;<em>A Dance of Masks&nbsp;</em>would serve as the game's final expansion.</p>
<p>Still, I suppose a little freebie doesn't count as a "full" DLC pack, so Owlcat can still claim it's done with making major&nbsp;<em>Pathfinder: Wrath of the Righteous&nbsp;</em>content. Well played, Owlcat.</p>
<p><em>Pathfinder: Wrath of the Righteous</em>'&nbsp;<em>Children of Morta&nbsp;</em>DLC is available right now on PC, PlayStation, and Xbox. A Switch version of the DLC is also in the works and will arrive "soon". You can check out our&nbsp;<em>Wrath of the Righteous&nbsp;</em>review <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/pathfinder-wrath-of-righteous-review">here</a>, and you can read our&nbsp;<em>Children of Morta&nbsp;</em>review <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/children-of-morta-review-appealing-action-rpg">right here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro Mobile Release Date Revealed in Funny, Yet Terrifying Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-mobile-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-mobile-release-date-revealed-in-funny-yet-terrifying-trailer.973074/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-mobile-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Playstack and developer LocalThunk have revealed the&nbsp;<em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>mobile release date, and the information comes alongside a trailer that's sure to contribute to your insomnia.</p>
<p>The addictive poker roguelike lands on iOS and Google Play, as well as Apple Arcade, on September 26th, so if you've already been enjoying its endlessly absorbing gameplay on PC or consoles, well, now you've got an excuse to play it on the go as well.</p>
<p>News of the&nbsp;<em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>mobile release date comes alongside a trailer that features a joker card by the name of Jimbo, as well as some surreal imagery and&nbsp;<em>Inscryption</em>-style creepy energy. I don't want to overexplain it, but you can check the trailer out here.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>(and the above trailer didn't put you off), it's a poker-based roguelike in which the goal is to "play illegal poker hands, discover game-changing jokers, and trigger adrenaline-pumping, outrageous combos".</p>
<p>The game features a campaign mode with eight difficulty levels, as well as plenty of different cards, decks, and synergies to discover. In short, if you're a roguelike fan, then you're likely going to love this one.</p>
<p>You wouldn't be alone if you did, either; within its first two weeks,&nbsp;<em>Balatro&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-sales-half-million">crossed the 500,000 sales mark</a>, going on to sell <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-sales-one-million">a million copies in its first month</a>&nbsp;and to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/balatro-sales-reach-2-million-as-devs-promise-first-major-update-soon">cross the two million barrier last month</a>.</p>
<p>More content is on the way to&nbsp;<em>Balatro</em>, too; LocalThunk and Playstack have confirmed that a major update is on the way next year, and it's set to bring "new ideas and strategies" to the game.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/balatro-mobile-release-date-gameplay.jpg?itok=uzbfzQDE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/balatro-mobile-release-date-gameplay.jpg?itok=Em34-22_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>is set to come to mobile later this month.</figcaption></figure><p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>Balatro&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2379780/Balatro/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/balatro/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/balatro/9pk087lngjc5" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Xbox</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/balatro-switch/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Nintendo Switch</a>. It's coming to Android and iOS via the Play Store and the App Store on September 26th, so you might want to think about booking that day off.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 patch adds official in-game mod support]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/5/24236649/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-now-live-evil-endings-mod-support</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldur%E2%80%99s-gate-3-patch-adds-official-in-game-mod-support.973071/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/5/24236649/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-now-live-evil-endings-mod-support<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The long-awaited <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/16/24199957/baldurs-gate-3-patch-7-coming-soon">Patch 7 for <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em></a> is now live. The update adds new, gruesome cinematics for some of the game’s evil endings, new legendary actions for Honor Mode encounters, and official in-game mod support.</p><p>However, with Patch 7 comes a big ole asterisk from the game’s maker, Larian Studios. The patch is currently only available for PC, meaning that players will be unable to load cross-platform save files from PC on their console versions. PC / Mac multiplayer is also disabled. Larian says that it intends to launch Patch 7 on consoles and Mac sometime in October, so <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/10/23827343/baldurs-gate-3-reactivates-ps5-cross-saves">if you like to hop between desktop and console to play <em>BG3</em></a>, you’ll have to wait about a month. The compatibility issues can be avoided by simply declining to update the game on PC, but with all the other Patch 7 improvements, that might prove a difficult choice.</p><p>The official mod support will allow players to browse, download, and manage user-made mods directly in the game. Enterprising players will also be able to use the new toolkit to create their own mods that will work across PC and console (once Patch 7 is available on consoles).</p><p>Patch 7 also includes the requisite host of tweaks, improvements, and bug fixes. You can check out all the specifics <a href="https://baldursgate3.game/news/patch-7-now-live_121">here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In space sim Tin Can, you are a janitor in an escape pod and all the red lights are flashing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/in-space-sim-tin-can-you-are-a-janitor-in-an-escape-pod-and-all-the-red-lights-are-flashing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/in-space-sim-tin-can-you-are-a-janitor-in-an-escape-pod-and-all-the-red-lights-are-flashing.973068/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/in-space-sim-tin-can-you-are-a-janitor-in-an-escape-pod-and-all-the-red-lights-are-flashing<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/tin-can-space-sim-1.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / Tin Can Studio</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p> "Do not forget to turn the system off before touching anything," says my astronaut colleague over the radio. I grab the faulty power transformer without listening, and am immediately electrocuted. Worse still, I have to hammer a quick-time button to recover. This is what it is like to be Jerry, the janitor of a cheap and poorly maintained space station. Jerry is being tasked with repair work beyond his job description, learning the ins and outs of an escape pod's machinery from his co-worker via radio. This may come in handy, as the station is about to explode. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/tin-can">Tin Can</a> is not a new game (it came out in 2022) but it is on sale as part of <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/category/space_exploration">Steam's space exploration fest</a>. And I enjoy a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-space-games-on-pc">space game</a> that makes me panic while alarms go off everywhere.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Tin Can Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/USumDp1boe0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Tin Can Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/USumDp1boe0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/USumDp1boe0?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=USumDp1boe0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>We haven't covered it before, but it's basically <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/my-summer-car">My Summer Car</a> in space. Or perhaps Gravity starring Sandra Bullock, but funnier. The escape pod is notoriously troublesome. During the tutorial your colleague jokes that it is barely worth the effort of keeping the heap of junk maintained. "I would rather die than have to escape in this thing," he says. Well.</p>
<p>It is full of small moments of comic misjudgement. My fellow space employee asks me to install some components back into the oxygen generator, slotting circuit boards and pumps into an intimidating drawer full of machinery. "You can't get it wrong," he says. </p>
<p>I fumble with the loose switch and drop it on the floor. I don't know what I'm doing. I'm a janitor. </p>
<p>But it's possible the game is stealthily teaching me science. The engineer colleague talks all about the correct ratios of oxygen to nitrogen in breathable air, for example. But it's the tension of needing to survive that really hammers home the knowledge about pressure bars or nuclear decay. You learn a lot quicker when faced with the practical concern of, you know, not dying. </p>
<p>The requirements soon stack up. When the main computer is down there's no way of knowing which exact component is faulty within the pod. So you have to glance at a bunch of little monitors for cryptic four-letter codes, then resort to flipping through a clipboard manual to identify those error codes and understand which do-hickey is causing trouble. It is hugely cumbersome. I love it.</p>
<p>Like I say, it's on sale, so you can suffocate for half price. But there's also <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1315980/Tin_Can/">a demo on Steam</a> that will take you through all the basics I describe here, and have you switching little buttons on and off with the reckless abandon of a toddler in the front seat of a station wagon. Go on, embrace a few mistakes. If you don't accidentally turn off the gravity at least once, how will you know to avoid it in the future?</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gimmick! 2 is out now, which is great news for fans of difficult platformers starring fun lil' green guys]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gimmick-2-is-out-now-which-is-great-news-for-fans-of-difficult-platformers-starring-fun-lil-green-guys</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gimmick-2-is-out-now-which-is-great-news-for-fans-of-difficult-platformers-starring-fun-lil-green-guys.973065/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gimmick-2-is-out-now-which-is-great-news-for-fans-of-difficult-platformers-starring-fun-lil-green-guys<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gimmick2header.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sunsoft/Clear River Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Pssst. You into hardcore 2D platformers? And do you like lil' green guys, just like, gooby wooby lookin' orbs of green? Then I present to you <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/gimmick-2">Gimmick! 2</a>, which has an unexpected exclamation point before the "2" and all of the above. It's out now and will no doubt please fans who've been waiting <em>years</em> for a sequel to the original Gimmick!, and possibly other platform enthusiasts who are after a decidedly different style of gap-hopper.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>For a brief nugget of context, the original Gimmick! was a Famicom <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-platform-games-on-pc">platformer</a> developed by Sunsoft and released in 1992. Funnily enough, at the time it only ever got localised for Scandinavia, where it was called Mr. Gimmick (what all of the Demon Souls bosses should've been named… ahem, anyway). It starred a green yokai called Yumetaro, who embarked on a quest to save a young girl from evil toys. And it has since been re-released a bunch of times, most recently getting a 2023 remaster called Gimmick! Special Edition. </p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Gimmick! 2 - Launch Trailer - Nintendo Switch | Steam" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-QqtRjEhf2s?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Gimmick! 2 - Launch Trailer - Nintendo Switch | Steam</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-QqtRjEhf2s?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-QqtRjEhf2s?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-QqtRjEhf2s" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>And so Swedish dev Bitwave and publisher Sunsoft have come together to release Gimmick! 2, many years later. It stars the same Yumetaro who embarks on a different quest, all in an updated aesthetic that has a Spelunky sheen. In it you'll hop and avoid spikes and do puzzles, like almost all other platformers. But what sets it apart is Yumetaro's ability to summon and throw a powerful star - his gimmick, you could say - that not only bounces, but <em>also</em> retains momentum from his movement. You can use it to activate switches, bonk enemies, and eliminate chunks of the map to reveal secret spots. Oh and you can trick enemies so that their heads form helpful platforms as they fall to their deaths, too.</p>
<p>Honestly, Gimmick! 2 looks like a tricky platformer, owing to the physics-y interactions between your little green goob, his bouncy star, and the obstacles you're trying to bonk or cross or flip. I imagine it requires a lot of precise movement and a lot of risk-taking, especially when it comes to surfing on that star in critical moments. But I also imagine it makes for some fun problem solving that doesn't just require some carefully timed air-dashes. There's an assisted mode if you want an easier time, otherwise you've got the Gimmick! mode for the "true-to-the-original" challenge.</p>
<p>You can find the game over on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2994880/Gimmick_2/">Steam</a> if you're interested. Cheers to RPS commenter treelo for giving us the heads-up.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NHL 25 Gameplay Deep Dive Released]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nhl-25-gameplay-deep-dive-released/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nhl-25-gameplay-deep-dive-released.973056/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nhl-25-gameplay-deep-dive-released/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>EA Sports <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/nhl/nhl-25/news/gameplay-blog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">has released the deep dive</a> for NHL 25 gameplay ahead of its October release. The deep dive was originally set to be released on August 30, but was postponed due to the tragic deaths of Johnny and Matthew Gaudreau.</p>



<p>In the NHL 25 gameplay deep dive, EA Sports gives insight into its new Ice-Q technology for this year’s game. From new vision control to updated AI to more reactive actions, EA Sports is hoping that the gameplay updates will help make the on-ice action more authentic than ever before.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="NHL 25 Official Gameplay Trailer | Deep Dive" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hw0APrAqgDs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-nhl-25-gameplay-features">NHL 25 Gameplay Features</h2>



<p>All of the below information comes directly from EA Sports itself.</p>



<h3 id="h-next-gen-vision-control">Next-Gen Vision Control</h3>



<p><em>“Next-Gen Vision Control is an evolution of Chel’s skating system that allows you to create more time and space on the ice by providing fresh abilities, improvements, and a user-initiated skating mode that ups the responsiveness, explosiveness, and expression on the ice for human and AI players alike.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><em>“For example, when Next-Gen Vision Control is active and the player has the puck in the offensive zone, they now skate with the net as the target. This opens up the player’s body creating the ability to skate and attack the net, shoot the puck, or pass from anywhere in the offensive zone in a contextually more authentic way.”</em></p>



<h3 id="h-empowered-ai">Empowered AI</h3>



<p>“<em>Empowered AI is a complete overhaul of our AI player system, heightening CPU skaters’ awareness of other players and positioning on the ice, giving them more fluid and helpful reads to execute in a true-to-life fashion.</em></p>



<p><em>“On top of that, all of Chel’s In Zone strategies — including Behind the Net, Overload and Crash the Net — have been rebuilt from the ground up to allow skaters to better utilize open space and position themselves to be bigger offensive threats.”</em></p>



<h3 id="h-reactive-actions">Reactive Actions</h3>



<p>“<em>New to NHL 25, Reactive Actions like collision avoidance animations allow players to swim past one another and into position smoothly like the pros, no longer running into and getting tangled up with each other.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p><em>“Plus, all-new panic turns let players quickly change direction and use their stick to take away space if they are beaten on the ice, making defensive players more athletic and dynamic. Players will also stick out their legs to try and block a shot or pass and offensive teammates will lower their sticks into passing lanes if they feel they’re in a good spot.”</em></p>



<h3 id="h-skill-based-one-timers">Skill-based One-timers</h3>



<p><em>“Anchored by a new in-game visual indicator that identifies a teammate as a target for a Skill Based One-Timer, when passing to a teammate you’ll need to input the shot control as the puck arrives. The timing window to nail a Skill Based One-Timer is dynamic and takes into account how fast the pass is traveling, as well as the shooter’s abilities like the One T X-Factor.</em></p>



<p><em>“If timed correctly you’ll unleash the Skill Based One-Timer, which is more powerful and accurate. If your timing is off, the shot’s accuracy drops, raising the stakes and making the action all the more exciting.”</em></p>



<figure></figure>



<h3 id="h-other-new-nhl-25-gameplay-features">Other New NHL 25 Gameplay Features</h3>



<h4>Goalies</h4>



<ul>
<li>General Improvements preemptive save decisions &amp; animations.</li>



<li>Improved poke check &amp; puck cover responsiveness and situation-solving.</li>



<li>Improvements to save motion coming onto the goalposts.</li>



<li>Increased save range including better solving for lacrosse goals.</li>



<li>Goalies stay on their feet longer, and won’t drop to or stay in butterfly if they have time to get back up.</li>



<li>Tweaks to save and capability models
<ul>
<li>Improved readiness for controlled and redirected saves</li>



<li>Rebalanced goalie precision</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Improved decision-making for positioning
<ul>
<li>One timers</li>



<li>Facing in-tight shots</li>



<li>Challenge distances</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>New Actions Added
<ul>
<li>AI goalies will use the spread-v</li>



<li>User goalies can saucer pass</li>



<li>Goalies can cover the puck off of teammate’s stick to better protect their own goals</li>



<li>Post-goal emotional reactions</li>



<li>Pad stack and desperation side poses are now merged</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<h4>Hitting System</h4>



<ul>
<li>Improvements to hit alignment to ensure more consistent outcomes</li>



<li>New shoulder check animations from back-skating</li>



<li>Improvements to shove and hit conflicts with shooting controls</li>



<li>Get-up time is scaled based on player fatigue and the level of hits taken</li>



<li>Fatigue drain varies based on the size of the hit delivered
<ul>
<li>The bigger the hit the larger the stamina loss</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>AI will now use the hip check&nbsp;</li>



<li>Player sizes factor more into hit outcomes</li>
</ul>



<h4>Sustained Pressure System</h4>



<ul>
<li>A team that activates pressure will receive 20% increase to their on-ice player stamina meters</li>
</ul>



<p>NHL 25, available only on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S, launches on September 27 for those who buy the Deluxe Edition of the game. Those who buy the Standard Edition get access on October 4. </p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the NHL 25 gameplay trailer and deep dive? For more Insider Gaming, check out what <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hogwarts-legacy-2-a-priority-for-warner-bros-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Warner Bros. Discovery had to say about Hogwarts Legacy 2</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astro Bot Will Get Post-Launch DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-will-get-post-launch-dlc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/astro-bot-will-get-post-launch-dlc.973053/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-will-get-post-launch-dlc/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-55870">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Astro Bot’s release is here, but people are already wondering about DLC plans for the future. Luckily, the base game doesn’t appear to be all that developer Team Asobi has planned.</p>



<p>During a special pre-release presentation for select invitees, Team Asobi talked about plans for Astro Bot. According to the developer, the plan is to add 10 challenge levels as well as five speed run levels for players.</p>







<p>So far, no release window or actual public confirmation from the developers have been announced.</p>



<p>In the base game, Astro Bot will have 300 bots to rescue. Half of them will be call backs to various PlayStation characters and games of the past. Astro himself will also have abilities and skills that will remind players of classic characters.</p>



<p>Astro Bot is available starting September 6 exclusively on PlayStation 5.</p>



<hr>



<p>Do you think Astro Bot needs DLC, or should it stand on its own? For more Insider Gaming, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/squirrel-with-a-gun-is-the-obnoxious-game-we-needed-it-to-be/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">read our review of Squirrel With A Gun</a> to help you decide whether its a game you should buy, wait on, or skip. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming Wrap Up</a>, a once-a-week newsletter with exclusive columns, interviews, and more.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-mobile-launching-in-september/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/balatro-mobile-launching-in-september/">Balatro Mobile Launching In September</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Developer LocalThunk has announced that Balatro Mobile is launching this September for Android and iOS with preorders now open.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/maximum-football-enters-early-access-in-november/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/maximum-football-enters-early-access-in-november/">Maximum Football Enters Early Access In November</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Maximum Entertainment has announced that Maximum Football will release in Early Access on PC starting in November.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-new-ip-forgotten-franchise/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-new-ip-forgotten-franchise/">Does Sony Need New IP, Or Can It Just Revive a Forgotten Franchise?</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>With Sony’s CFO saying the company doesn’t have enough new IP, perhaps it should look backwards instead of forwards.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/state-of-decay-2-end-support-undead/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/state-of-decay-2-end-support-undead/">Undead Labs Ending Support For State of Decay 2 To Focus on Sequel</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Undead Labs has confirmed it’s ending developer support for State of Decay 2 as it pivots to focus full-time on State of Decay 3</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Looney Tunes: Wacky World of Sports launches September 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/looney-tunes-wacky-world-of-sports-launches-september-27</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/looney-tunes-wacky-world-of-sports-launches-september-27.973047/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/09/looney-tunes-wacky-world-of-sports-launches-september-27<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Basketball featurette trailer released.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Looney Tunes: Wacky World of Sports [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/looney-tunes-wacky-world-of-sports">Looney Tunes: Wacky World of Sports</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,866 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,031 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,156 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,464 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,969 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,160 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2330430/Looney_Tunes_Wacky_World_of_Sports/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on September 27, publisher <a title="Companies > GameMill Entertainment [40 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gamemill-entertainment">GameMill Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Bamtang Games [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bamtang-games">Bamtang Games</a> announced. <span id="more-912814"></span></p><p>The standard edition is available to pre-order today for $49.99. The Deluxe Edition is also available for $59.99, featuring the exclusive Yosemite Sam character to use in-game, Golden Outlaws uniforms, and the “Wild West <a title="Genres > Sports [564 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/sports">Sports</a> Pack,” which includes a western-themed basketball, soccer ball, tennis ball, and golf clubs.</p><p>Pre-orders for either edition of the game will include the “Sweet Deal Sports Pack,” which features candy-themed equipment for each sport.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via GameMill Entertainment:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Compete against friends and family with the Looney Tunes squad in basketball, soccer, golf and tennis. Play your way solo or in four-player local co-op and choose the characters that best suit your play style. Avoid wacky obstacles and gain power-ups to incite chaos as you control your favorite Looney Tunes all-stars!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Four <a title="Genres > Action [2,142 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a>-Packed Sports</strong> – Take on all rivals in two-versus-two <a title="Genres > Arcade [61 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a> basketball, one-versus-one or two-versus-two arcade tennis, four-player golf, and three-versus-three arcade soccer!</li><li><strong>Squad Up With Your Favorite Toons</strong> – Choose from nine iconic playable characters each with their own specialties, including Bugs Bunny, Lola Bunny, Daffy Duck, Porky Pig, Elmer Fudd, Sylvester, Taz, Wile E. Coyote and the Road Runner.</li><li><strong>Compete With Friends</strong> – Enjoy arcade sports action solo or with up to four players in local <a title="Genres > Co-Op [199 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> play.</li><li><strong>Travel the Toon-iverse</strong> – Play across iconic worlds like Galactic Outpost Delta, Porky’s Barn, Foghorn’s Farm, Road Runner’s Canyon, Whispering Woods, Martian Command Center, Granny’s House, and many more!</li><li><strong>Unleash the Full Acme Arsenal</strong> – Disrupt your opponents in the wackiest ways possible, but watch out for that anvil!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Basketball Featurette</span></h2><p><iframe title="Looney Tunes Wacky World of Sports - Basketball Featurette" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ei9x1lIENLE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro Is Coming To Mobile Devices, So Get Your Important Tasks Done Now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/balatro-is-coming-to-mobile-devices-so-get-your-important-tasks-done-now/1100-6526293/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-is-coming-to-mobile-devices-so-get-your-important-tasks-done-now.973041/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/balatro-is-coming-to-mobile-devices-so-get-your-important-tasks-done-now/1100-6526293/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6526293">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Since its launch on PC and consoles in February, Balatro has become one of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-reviewed-games-2024/2900-5065/" data-ref-id="2900-5065">surprise hits of 2024</a>. Jimbo The Joker's influence will soon be moving on to another platform, as publisher PlayStack has confirmed the game will be ported to mobile devices on September 26.</p><p dir="ltr">The game will be available on both the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/balatro/id6502453075" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Apple App Store</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.playstack.balatro.android" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Play Store</a> for $10, while a free <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/balatro/id6502451661" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Balatro+ version</a> will be available to those who have an Apple Arcade subscription. The announcement did not confirm whether a free version will also be offered on Android devices via Google Play.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="2022965998" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465068,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Balatro%20Mobile%20-%20Official%20Release%20Date%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:51,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/balatro-mobile-official-release-date-trailer\/2300-6465068\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465068\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465068\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465068\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465068&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4362409-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/aggThdwd.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1725546120,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="aggThdwd" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Balatro Mobile - Official Release Date Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Balatro is a card-based puzzle game which sees players use traditional playing cards to battle against "Blinds," as playing cards from their hand earns them points--think poker, but with rules you can mess with. Multiple types of special cards--Jokers, Tarot cards, cards with special treatments, and more--add points or multipliers to each hand, and once a certain score is reached, the Blind is defeated. </p><p dir="ltr">The indie hit first launched on PC back on February to massive critical acclaim, which included an average score of 90 on <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/balatro/">GameSpot's sister site Metacritic</a>. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/balatro-review-one-more-blind/1900-6418192/" data-ref-id="1900-6418192">GameSpot's 9/10 review</a> said that Balatro "injects new life into the fundamental rules of poker without requiring any previous knowledge of the game, feeling deftly balanced for both newcomers and experts of the card game alike."</p><p dir="ltr">Balatro+ will join over 200 games on the Apple Arcade subscription service, which recently added another indie darling in Vampire Survivors last month. Other games coming to the service soon include NFL Retro Bowl+ 25, a modern spin on the classic Tecmo Bowl style of football game that launches today, as well as NBA 2K25 Arcade Edition in early October.</p><p dir="ltr">Balatro will launch on the Apple App Store and Google Play Store on September 26, with pre-registrations on both platforms beginning today. The free Balatro+ version for Apple Arcade will be available to subscribers on the same day.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Twenty-Sided Tavern Welcomes Aabria Iyengar, Felicia Day and Erika Ishii As Guest Cast Members]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/twenty-sided-tavern-welcomes-aabria-iyengar-felicia-day-and-erika-ishii-as-guest-cast</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-twenty-sided-tavern-welcomes-aabria-iyengar-felicia-day-and-erika-ishii-as-guest-cast-members.973008/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/twenty-sided-tavern-welcomes-aabria-iyengar-felicia-day-and-erika-ishii-as-guest-cast<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Back in February, Showpath Entertainment and Wizards of the Coast announced an official theatrical production set in the world of <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a>. Now, that show, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/official-dungeons-dragons-theatrical-production-is-coming" rel="noopener" target="_blank">The Twenty-Sided Tavern</a>, has announced several beloved celebrity guest cast members attached to the production.</p>
<h2>The Twenty-Sided Tavern Guest Member Announcement</h2>
<p>According to an official press release, three special guest cast members will be joining The Twenty-Sided Tavern production this fall an winter.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/felicia-day-geek-and-sundry-image.jpg?itok=mpQg5N4r 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/felicia-day-geek-and-sundry-image.jpg?itok=PI07KgC_ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The first guest member is award-winning actress Felicia Day. Her acting credits include <em>The Guild</em>, <em>Supernatural</em>, and the Netflix revival of <em>Mystery Science Theater 3000</em>. She was also the mind behind <em>Geek and Sundry</em>, the YouTube channel that hosted the early days of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/among-us-x-critical-role-crossover-has-crewmates-rolling-for-insight" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Critical Role</em></a>.</p>
<p>The second guest is Aabria Iyengar. Iyengar is prolific within the tabletop and actual play community. Her work includes DMing the first season of <em>Critical Role's</em> <em>Exandria Unlimited</em>, the actual play <em>Worlds Beyond Number</em>, and helming <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/aabria-iyengar-discusses-burrows-end-finale-dice-telling-story-and-what-happens" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Dimension20 Burrow's End</em></a>.</p>
<p>Last but not least, The Twenty-Sided Tavern's third guest member will be <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/we-chat-dimension-20-burrows-end-generational-trauma-and-environmental" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Erika Ishii</a>. Ishii is a prolific videogame voice-actor. Their credits include Valkyrie in <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/apex-legends" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Apex Legends</em></a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/opinions/destiny-2-final-shape-end-to-light-and-darkness" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Destiny 2's</em></a> Ana Bray, and the upcoming <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-age-veilguard-release-date-leaked-trailer" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Dragon Age: Veilguard</em></a>.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dimension20-aabria-iyengar-and-erika-ishii-profile-image.jpg?itok=jJ9Fj3qO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dimension20-aabria-iyengar-and-erika-ishii-profile-image.jpg?itok=EYjMyENG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Ishii has also has appeared in several actual play productions. Ishii was a player in several seasons of <em>Dimension20</em>, including <em>Misfits and Magic</em> and <em>Escape From The Bloodkeep</em>, and the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/vampire-masquerade-5th-edition-review-front-loaded-lore" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Vampire: The Masquerade</em></a> actual play, <em>LA By Night</em>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We are honored that these two massively talented performers have accepted our invitation to come play with us this fall,” says Executive Producer and Co-Creator David Carpenter. “It’s been our dream from the beginning that we would be able to invite friends from across the country to share the stage with us and these two brave adventurers have accepted the call. Audiences are going to get to see two of their favorite performers do a whole new style of D&amp;D live on stage. It’s going to be absolutely magical.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Felicia Day will be joining the production from September 19 to September 24. Aabria Iyengar will join September 26 to October 7. Erika Ishii will join December 5 to December 17.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google’s Nest floodlight camera is a solid $70 off right now]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/5/24236581/google-nest-cam-floodlight-marvel-capcom-collection-deal-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/google%E2%80%99s-nest-floodlight-camera-is-a-solid-70-off-right-now.973005/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/5/24236581/google-nest-cam-floodlight-marvel-capcom-collection-deal-sale<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If you’re looking for a nice discount on a great outdoor smart home camera right now (and you don’t mind Google’s ecosystem), look no further than the <strong>Google Nest Cam with floodlight</strong>. It’s on sale for $209 ($70 off) at <a href="http://amazon.com/dp/B09J9ZWZ9Q?tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a> or $209.99 at <a href="https://howl.me/cm1WzZGEU0e">Best Buy</a>. It’s possible that it may dip to an even lower price during Black Friday / Amazon Prime Day, but today’s deal is a good value if you’re currently sprucing up the homestead with a bit of security in mind.</p><p>The Nest floodlight brightly illuminates your yard, driveway, or walk-up when it detects motion and syncs up with the Google Home app to show captured clips of the activity. It supports 1080p video with night vision, two-way audio for communicating with people outside, and IP54-rated weather resistance. Its fanciest features — like recognizing familiar faces or 24/7 recording — are locked behind subscription tiers, but even if you don’t pay a monthly fee, you can get notifications to your phone when it sees a person, vehicle, or animal and save any clip logged within the last three hours. You can even set up designated zones to trigger your notifications and recordings, so you’re not pestered every time a car passes by.</p><div><p>A Google Nest Cam attached to two bright, adjustable floodlights, this camera has free video recording, powerful lights, and on-device processing of smart alerts for people, vehicles, and animals. There’s no siren, but there is 24/7 recording and facial recognition. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22776184/google-nest-cam-floodlight-review-smart-security-camera">Read our review</a>.</p></div><div><div><h2>Verge Deals on X<!-- --> <!-- --> / </h2><p>Join nearly 50,000 followers and keep up with the best daily tech deals with @vergedeals</p></div><p><a href="http://bit.ly/2JzR5Ud">Follow us!</a></p></div><p><h3>I wanna take you for a ride (to more deals)</h3></p><div><ul><li><a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/https://www.fanatical.com/en/game/marvel-vs-capcom-fighting-collection-arcade-classics?v=5299">Fanatical</a> is offering a preorder discount for the digital version of <em><strong>Marvel vs. Capcom Fighting Collection: Arcade Classics</strong></em> on Steam — offering the game for $40.99 ($9 off). If you’re interested in the remasters of iconic 2D fighting games like <em>X-Men vs. Street Fighter</em> and <em>Marvel vs. Capcom 2: New Age of Heroes,</em> this is a nice value that allows you to jump in at launch on September 12th. The collection also includes five other Capcom-made Marvel titles of the ’90s and 2000s, with added online play.</li><li>A couple of <strong>Anker Qi2 multi-chargers</strong> are discounted to their second-best prices to date, each available at Amazon. You can get the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0D2XYS4QC?th=1&amp;tag=theverge02-20">Anker MagGo 2-in-1 15W Qi2 magnetic charging stand</a> (for compatible iPhones and AirPods) for just $37.49 when you click the on-page coupon or opt for the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Anker-Wireless-Charging-Station-%C3%AF%C2%BC%C5%92Cable/dp/B0CFXLVY1V?th=1&amp;tag=theverge02-20">3-in-1 version</a> (which adds Apple Watch charging) for $74.99 when you click the coupon for $25 off.</li><li>The USB-C version of the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23191199/razer-kishi-v2-mobile-game-controller-android-review"><strong>Razer Kishi V2</strong></a> mobile game controller is $59.99 ($40 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0B16NGTCT?th=1&amp;tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a>, while the Lightning version for older iPhones is $69.99 (around $30 off) at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0B16PJ31L/ref=ewc_pr_img_1?smid=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;th=1&amp;tag=theverge02-20">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://howl.me/cm1XgizM5o1">Best Buy</a>. The clamp-style controller may be slightly rougher around the edges compared to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/8/23945850/backbone-is-making-some-tweaks-to-its-excellent-mobile-game-controller">latest Backbone One</a>, but it’s a great value for playing mobile and streaming games with console-like controls (especially when on a sale like this one). Plus, Razer added some nifty functionality allowing you to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/1/23/23567901/razer-kishi-v2-update-mobile-gaming-controller-touchscreen-android">map touchscreen-only game controls to its physical buttons and sticks</a>.</li></ul></div><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p> / <span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we've tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Myth: Wukong's first DLC is aiming for a Shadow Of The Erdtree-style second wave of popularity]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukongs-first-dlc-is-aiming-for-a-shadow-of-the-erdtree-style-second-wave-of-popularity</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-myth-wukongs-first-dlc-is-aiming-for-a-shadow-of-the-erdtree-style-second-wave-of-popularity.973002/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukongs-first-dlc-is-aiming-for-a-shadow-of-the-erdtree-style-second-wave-of-popularity<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Game Science to work on expansions before any sequels</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/black-myth-wukong-hundred-eyed-daoist-master.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/Game Science</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Not very shockingly for a game that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukongs-record-setting-launch-popularity-soured-by-co-publisher-request-to-avoid-feminist-propaganda-in-streams">set Steam records</a> within hours of release, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukong-release-date-details-everything-we-know">Black Myth: Wukong</a> is getting DLC, the first in a series of follow-up projects that continue the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-action-games">action</a> epic's explorations of Chinese mythology. 
</p><!--more-->
<p>
That's from <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-09-05/investor-who-risked-it-all-on-wukong-scores-another-sales-win?leadSource=uverify%20wall">a new Bloomberg interview</a> with Daniel Wu, co-founder of Hero Games, the largest external shareholder in Wukong developers Game Science. What the DLC actually consists of and when it'll launch remain to be seen, but the article compares it to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-how-to-start">Shadow Of The Erdtree</a>, which has demonstrated how a timely and substantial expansion "can spur a fresh flurry of sales for the original."</p>
<p>I imagine there will be new <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukong-bosses">bosses</a> and a few more <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/all-black-myth-wukong-meditation-spots">meditation spots</a>, but perhaps they'll flesh out the setting in less combative or progression-driven ways. Edders, who authored our <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukong-review">Black Myth: Wukong review</a>, is hoping for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/black-myth-wukong-needs-an-assassins-creed-style-discovery-mode">some kind of Discovery Mode</a>.
</p>
<p>
DLC aside, the Bloomberg piece dips into the backstory of both companies: a much-publicised 2017 meeting between Wu and Apple bigwig Tim Cook, which didn't really go anywhere; Game Science's "four failures in a row", including several free-to-play mobile games, prior to releasing Wukong; and the fact that even following Wukong's success, with Game Science now worth "several billion yuan", the 2000-person Hero Games team aren't making a profit. 
</p>
<p>
Hero Games sunk 60 million yuan ($8.5 million) into Game Science back in 2017. They aren't profitable, it seems, partly because they're still making their money back from previous Game Science flops, but Wu also notes that "this is the most gruesome year for China's games industry ever," with wider economic difficulties leading to cuts in entertainment spending and a number of cancellations.
</p>
<p>One way to keep growing Wukong's audience could be to make more of an appeal to overseas players - according to Game Developer, the <a href="https://x.com/simoncarless/status/1825818693751779449">vast majority of the launch sales came from China</a>.</p>
<p>
As ever with Hero Games, Wu declined to answer questions from Bloomberg about a notorious guidance document asking English-language Wukong streamers and video makers to avoid discussing "feminist propaganda", Covid prevention measures, or Chinese government policy. In what a less generous soul might read as an exercise in telling on your creepy self, the (not legally binding) caution about "feminist propaganda" came in the wake of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-black-myth-wukong-developers-history-of-sexism-is-complicating-its-journey-to-the-west">an extensive IGN report from last year that Game Science have a culture of sexism</a>.
</p>
<p>
The developers and their partners have staunchly avoided the subject ever since. I asked a PR representative for Black Myth: Wukong about the streamer "Do's and Don'ts" in August, and was told a week or two later that "unfortunately, we cannot provide a comment at this time".
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>