<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:11:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AC League, A Co-Op Assassin’s Creed Game, Has Reportedly Been Canceled]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ac-league-co-op-assassins-creed-game-canceled/</link>
            <guid>1427917</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div data-nosnippet="">
		
		<ul>
			<li>0-20%: Unlikely - Lacks credible sources</li>
			<li>21-40%: Questionable - Some concerns remain</li>
			<li>41-60%: Plausible - Reasonable evidence</li>
			<li>61-80%: Probable - Strong evidence</li>
			<li>81-100%: Highly Likely - Multiple reliable sources</li>
		</ul>
	</div>


			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://www.origami.ng/ubisoft-vantage-cancel-league-assassins-creed-multiplayer/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">According to the French website Origami</a>, <strong>Ubisoft</strong> has canceled a <strong>secret Assassin's Creed co-op game</strong> codenamed <strong>AC League</strong>. Origami, which has a solid track record, claims to have verified the information with six current Ubisoft employees before publishing the story.</p>



<p>First and foremost, it should be clarified that <strong>this is not <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-invictus-an-arcade-multiplayer-game-rumored-to-launch-this-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Assassin's Creed Invictus</a></strong>, the arcade Fall Guys-inspired PvP multiplayer game that was previously leaked to be in development. AC League was originally meant to be the <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-is-reportedly-getting-a-co-op-mode-post-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>rumored Assassin's Creed Shadows co-op mode</strong></a>, which later morphed into a standalone title. It was in development at <strong>Ubisoft Annecy</strong>, the studio that led development on <strong><a href="http://wccftech.com/review/steep-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steep</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/riders-republic-beautiful-rocky-road/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Riders Republic</a>,</strong> and also contributed to several Assassin's Creed games, including the multiplayer modes featured in Assassin’s Creed: Brotherhood, Revelations, AC III, AC IV: Black Flag, and AC Unity.</p>



<p>According to the report, over the last year, the developer <strong>began questioning whether to keep League as a Shadows expansion: the DLC was seen as too long and costly to produce for the quality bar they wanted</strong>. They had two options on the table: either attach the co‑op framework onto another, more traditional Assassin's Creed game already in development elsewhere in the group, or shrink AC League's narrative and scope and pitch it as a small, standalone co‑op Assassin's Creed game built from the base of Assassin's Creed Shadows.</p>



<p>Ubisoft Annecy pursued the second option, <strong>aiming to kick off invite‑only alpha sessions around May</strong> to test the game, refine it, and then get a formal greenlight. In the game, parties of up to four assassins would tackle missions together, presumably in a similar fashion to <strong>Assassin's Creed Unity</strong>, the last title to support online cooperative multiplayer.</p>



<p>As to the circumstances of the game's cancellation, Origami reports that <strong>executives from the newly created <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-tencent-new-subsidiary-far-cry-rainbow-six-assassins-creed-vantage-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vantage Studios</a> subsidiary have been carefully reviewing each and every internal project</strong> (<a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-major-reset-cancels-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">and canceling plenty of them</a>). Just last week, after an internal play session, <strong>the project leads behind AC League were informed that the decision had been made to shut down the project</strong>. Annecy had put around 85 of its roughly 270 employees on this project.</p>



<p>While AC League is effectively dead, <strong>the co-op tech base developed by Ubisoft Annecy is reportedly being salvaged</strong> for potential new pitches to be attached to future Assassin's Creed games. Those co-op modes will have to be much cheaper to make than AC League was shaping up to be, though, which led to its cancellation.</p>



<p>Do you miss co-op Assassin's Creed? Let us know in the comments.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/ac-league-co-op-assassins-creed-game-canceled/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders Expedition 2—Release Date, Requirements, & Rewards, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-expedition-2-release-date-requirements-rewards-explained/</link>
            <guid>1427911</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s almost time for another progression wipe in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/arc-raiders/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/games/arc-raiders/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders</a>, as the next Expedition Project deadline is fast-approaching. This mechanic allows you to reset your account, go back to square one, whilst earning some exclusive rewards, bonuses, and temporary buffs.</p>



<p>Of course, you don’t have to reset, but Embark Studios has updated the rewards and requirements, and it seems much more worthwhile when compared to the first one. It’s a big decision to make, so you’ll want to be well-informed.</p>







<p>Luckily for you, Insider Gaming has all the information you’ll need for ARC Raiders’ Expedition <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-trophy-display-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-trophy-display-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Project</a>, including the requirements, rewards, and when you’ll need to complete it.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-arc-raiders-second-expedition">When Is ARC Raiders’ Second Expedition?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Time to get packing. Image by Embark Studios.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The Expedition window opens on February 25, and departures take place on March 1, meaning you’ve got until the end of February to complete the Expedition Project.</strong></p>



<p>It might seem like you still have a good amount of time to complete the Project, but be warned, you’ll need a lot of different resources if you want to finish it. It’s best to start sooner rather than later, as you might wind up missing the wipe and regretting it.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-are-the-requirements-for-the-second-expedition">What Are The Requirements For The Second Expedition?</h2>



<p><strong>There are six stages to the Expedition Project in ARC Raiders, with each one having four requirements each.</strong></p>



<p>The items vary from materials to ARC parts, but the toughest stage is bound to be the fifth one, which requires you to sell 800,000 Coins’ worth of supplies! The Expedition won’t come cheap, but if you want to complete it, here are all of the Project’s stages:</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Expedition Project Stage</th><th data-align="center">Expedition Project Requirements</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 1: Foundation</td><td data-align="center">– 150 Metal Parts<br>– 200 Plastic Parts<br>– 80 ARC Alloy<br>– 15 Steel Springs</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 2: Core Systems</td><td data-align="center">– 35 Durable Cloth<br>– 25 Wires<br>– 20 Electrical Components<br>– 4 Cooling Coils</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 3: Framework</td><td data-align="center">– 4 Light Bulbs<br>– 30 Batteries<br>– 10 Shredder Gyros<br>– 1 Exodus Modules</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 4: Outfitting</td><td data-align="center">– 5 Frequency Modulation Boxes<br>– 5 Advanced Electrical Components<br>– 3 Ion Sputters<br>– 3 Leaper Pulse Units</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 5: Load Stage</td><td data-align="center">– 250,000 Coins worth of Combat Items<br>– 100,000 Coins worth of Survival Items<br>– 150,000 Coins worth of Provisions<br>– 300,000 Coins worth of Materials</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 6: Departure</td><td data-align="center">No donations needed, you’re ready for the Expedition</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-what-are-the-rewards-for-the-second-expedition">What Are The Rewards For The Second Expedition?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Is it worth it? Image by Embark Studios.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>You don’t get direct rewards from the Expedition Project like you would from other Projects, as you’ll instead be rewarded with permanent and consecutive bonuses for your character.</strong></p>



<p>However, your rewards will vary depending on whether you completed the first expedition or not, as well as how many Coins you have when you depart, which can all seem a bit confusing. Luckily for you, Insider Gaming has broken it down in the table below, splitting the rewards into two tiers:</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Rewards If It’s Your First Expedition</th><th data-align="center">Rewards If It’s Your Second Expedition</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">The Patchwork Outfit (Permanent)</td><td data-align="center">The Patchwork Outfit—Evolved (Permanent)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Scrappy Cosmetics (Permanent)</td><td data-align="center">Scrappy Cosmetics (Permanent)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">The Expedition Indicator Icon (Permanent)</td><td data-align="center">The Expedition Indicator Icon (Permanent)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">+ 12 Stash Spaces (Permanent)</td><td data-align="center">+ 24 Stash Spaces (Permanent)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">+ 0-5 Skill Points (Permanent, dependent on player wealth)</td><td data-align="center">+ 0-5 Skill Points (Permanent, dependent on player wealth)<br>+ Catch up on missed Skill Points (Permanent, dependent on player wealth)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">+ 5% XP Boost (Consecutive Buff)</td><td data-align="center">+ 10% XP Boost (Consecutive Buff)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">+ 6% Scrappy Materials Boost (Consecutive Buff)</td><td data-align="center">+ 12% Scrappy Materials Boost (Consecutive Buff)</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">+ 60% Repair Value Increase (Consecutive Buff)</td><td data-align="center">+ 70% Repair Value Increase (Consecutive Buff)</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>The key thing to note regarding the Expedition rewards is the extra Skill Points, as they’re dependent on your Coin total when you depart on the Expedition. Each extra Skill Point is worth <strong>600,000 Coins</strong>, meaning you’ll need to have <strong>3,000,000 Coins</strong> to your name if you want all five Skill Points on offer. </p>







<p>If it’s your second Expedition, and you didn’t manage to claim all of the Skill Points from the first one, then you’re in luck, as there’s a way to make up for lost time. Those now have a value, too, as they’re worth <strong>300,000 Coins</strong> per Skill Point. If you want to claim all five of them, you’ll need an extra <strong>1,500,000 Coins</strong>; add that onto the original five Skill Points, and that totals a whopping <strong>4,500,000 Coins</strong>!</p>



<hr>



<p>Will you be embarking on ARC Raiders’ next Expedition? Share your thoughts in the official <a href="https://discord.gg/vwj7zdWxaW" id="https://discord.gg/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<p>For more ARC Raiders content, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/7-secret-loot-spots-you-need-to-know-in-arc-raiders/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/7-secret-loot-spots-you-need-to-know-in-arc-raiders/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the 7 secret loot spots you need to know</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-event-tracker-every-map-condition-schedule/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-event-tracker-every-map-condition-schedule/">Insider Gaming’s Map Condition Tracker</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-expedition-2-release-date-requirements-rewards-explained/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Larian Isn’t Involved in the Baldur’s Gate TV Show, and They’re Not Happy]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/larian-not-involved-baldurs-gate-tv-show-not-happy/</link>
            <guid>1427908</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It was recently revealed that HBO plans to produce a Baldur’s Gate live-action adaptation, helmed by Craig Mazin, one of the leads who has brought The Last of Us to life over the last few years. It has been confirmed that the show will continue after the events of Baldur’s Gate 3 and will feature the characters from the smash-hit 2023 game.</p>



<p>However, shortly after the news dropped regarding the show, it was confirmed that Larian Studios, the <strong>developer </strong>behind Baldur’s Gate 3, will have <strong>no involvement in the series</strong>.</p>







<h2 id="h-bucking-the-trend-and-not-involving-the-developer">Bucking the Trend and Not Involving the Developer</h2>



<p>Larian having zero involvement in a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hbo-developing-baldurs-gate-series-from-the-last-of-us-showrunner/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Baldur’s Gate 3 television series</a> is a bold move. From what we’ve seen already, developers of these popular games have had a direct input in the production of their live-action adaptations. For instance, Neil Druckmann is a writer and executive producer on The Last of Us, which surfaced in 2013 from Naughty Dog.</p>



<p>Similarly, the likes of Todd Howard (Bethesda Game Studios) have executive producer credits and deep involvement in the creation of Fallout, another <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-tv-show-could-run-more-than-a-decade/">award-winning adaptation</a> that just wrapped its second season this week.</p>



<p>In recent years, one of the only examples of a developer <strong>not </strong>being involved in a live-action adaptation would be the Borderlands movie. Randy Pitchford, of Gearbox, revealed to Insider Gaming at Gamescom 2025 that he didn’t have any input in the movie and would have felt uncomfortable if he had.</p>



<p>On social media, the Director of Publishing at Larian Studios, Michael Douse, <a href="https://x.com/Cromwelp/status/2019571113345396945" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">wrote</a>:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Except that we made it popular enough for it to be referred to as Baldur’s Gate 3.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>When prompted in the comments to confirm if Larian would ‘sue or something’, he simply said, ‘Not really.’</p>



<p>He then wrote a lengthy series of posts talking about Larian having some of the best video game writers in the world, explaining, ‘I genuinely don’t think anyone can trump our writers.’ He wrapped by saying, ‘Don’t abandon hope, but do expect the world. That’s the job.’</p>







<p>Do you think it’s a huge concern that Larian won’t be invested in the creation of a Baldur’s Gate 3 television show? Let us know your thoughts on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/machinegames-still-plans-to-finish-the-wolfenstein-trilogy/">MachineGames wants to make more Wolfenstein</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/larian-not-involved-baldurs-gate-tv-show-not-happy/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard workers ratify union contract, Ghost of Yotei soars, and has Yves Guillemot outstayed his welcome at Ubisoft? - Patch Notes #39]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blizzard-workers-ratify-union-contract-ghost-of-yotei-soars-and-has-yves-guillemot-outstayed-his-welcome-at-ubisoft-patch-notes-39</link>
            <guid>1427905</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">February 6, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>5 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Artwork via Blizzard / Logo via Patch Notes</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Wouldn't you know it? There is a maelstrom of news to sift through this week, but before we plunge into the headlines I wanted to take a moment to GUSH about </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cairn</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, a new video game from indie studio The Game Bakers (of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Furi</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Haven</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> fame) that might be one of this year's very best.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a bold statement to make this early on, but I'm going to stand by it. I sat down with the survival climber at 8pm on Saturday thinking I'd stick with it for an hour or two before slapping on a movie and munching my way through a bag of delectable crisps (chips, for our American readers) I had saved for such an occasion.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Hard cut to 2am and there I am still glued to the screen. Palms sweaty. Eyes blurring. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cairn's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">protagonist, Aava, straining every sinew in her body as she clings to a sheer face on the side of Mount Kami. It has been minutes since I secured my last piton—the only thing standing between Aava and oblivion.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/four-tips-for-pitching-your-game-to-investors-and-publishers" target="_self" data-discover="true">Four tips for pitching your game to investors and publishers</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It might as well have been a lifetime. Any false move now would almost certainly result in death, sending Aava crashing into the mountain below at breakneck pace. The only way is up. This struggle is my salvation.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The higher you climb, the more </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cairn</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> turns into a brilliantly tense battle of wills. The question 'why am I doing this?' might cross your mind on more than one occasion, but therein lies the magic. There is victory in conquering even the smallest peak. Imagine what awaits at the summit.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Okay, okay. I'll rein myself in before this becomes a full-blown review. Did I mention we have some news to get through?</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="MachineGames asking more staff to move to full-time office work"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/machinegames-asking-more-staff-to-move-to-full-time-office-work">MachineGames asking more staff to move to full-time office work</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via GamesIndustry.biz // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">MachineGames, the Microsoft subsidiary behind Wolfenstein and Indiana Jones, is pulling employees back into the office. According to studio director Jerk Gustafsson, leadership is now required to be on-site five days per week to drive efficiency and collaboration. The hope is that will set a precedent for others to follow. "We are moving more and more towards five days a week," added Gustafsson. Given Ubisoft's recently-announced RTO mandate has seemingly gone down like a lead balloon internally, you have to wonder what MachineGames staffers make of the shift.&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Ghost of Yotei outperforms Ghost of Tsushima to bolster Sony financials"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ghost-of-yotei-outperforms-ghost-of-tsushima-to-bolster-sony-financials">Ghost of Yotei outperforms Ghost of Tsushima to bolster Sony financials</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via Game Developer // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Sucker Punch's soaring sequel </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ghost of Yotei</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> exceeded the expectations of Sony after outperforming its predecessor </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ghost of Tsushuma</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> during its first three months on shelves. The PlayStation maker shared the news in its latest fiscal report, where it also confirmed the PlayStation 5 has now sold-in over 92 million units worldwide.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-probablymonsters-lays-off-devs-while-unveiling-nazi-hunting-game" target="_self" data-discover="true">Report: ProbablyMonsters lays off devs while unveiling Nazi hunting game</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="No, NetEase isn't suddenly ditching generative AI"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/kerrblimey.bsky.social/post/3mdzzmptmy22c">No, NetEase isn't suddenly ditching generative AI</a></h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via NetEase //</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> File this one under 'news that didn't really happen.' Earlier this week, NetEase described widespread reports that it had shuttered a generative AI research division and told staff to abandon the tech as "false." The rumor spread after veteran designer Goichi Suda told Eurogamer the company was ditching generative AI altogether. Suda's studio, Grasshopper Manufacture, is currently owned by Netease. That claim was quickly quashed by multiple Netease representatives. "The situation described did not occur, and we have not published any related policies," said one spokesperson.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Steam Machine pricing and shipping details delayed due to RAM shortage"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/valve-delays-steam-machine-and-steam-frame-due-to-ram-shortage">Steam Machine pricing and shipping details delayed due to RAM shortage</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via Game Developer // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Do you remember what life was like before the RAM wars? That's a sentence our descendants might one day utter as they scamper through the apocalypse. Until then, we have to contend with the fact that the ongoing memory and storage shortage—driven by rampant investments into generative AI—might force us to pay more and wait longer for Valve's upcoming hardware slate. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://aftermath.site/steam-machine-frame-delayed-ai-data/">Oh, and shout out to Aftermath for this whopper of a headline when covering the news</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/us-based-tariffs-impact-38-of-business-leaders" target="_self" data-discover="true">38 percent of game industry leaders are feeling the impact of U.S. tariffs</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Games for Change is coming to London"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.videogamesindustrymemo.com/p/games-for-change-is-coming-to-london">Games for Change is coming to London</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via VGIM // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Games for Change is heading to the Big Smoke for a one-day event on April 15, 2026, dedicated to interrogating how video games can be a powerful force for good. The London event will unite 150 people from the world of video games, business, and politics. There'll be talks, panels, roundtables, workshops, and more. Could be worth a look if that sounds like your cup of tea.&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Ubisoft union representatives call for resignation of CEO Yves Guillemot"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-union-representatives-call-for-resignation-of-ceo-yves-guillemot">Ubisoft union representatives call for resignation of CEO Yves Guillemot</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via Game Developer // </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Ubisoft is (still) in revolt. Ahead of an impending international strike called by five unions across France, two union representatives have implored long-serving CEO Yves Guillemot to head for the exit in order to restore an ounce of trust between workers and management. They feel it might be impossible for Ubisoft, which recently announced more layoffs and studio closures, to regain the trust of its employees without a change in personnel at the very top.&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="UK co-development house Sumo Digital announces redundancies"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/uk-co-development-house-sumo-digital-announces-redundancies">UK co-development house Sumo Digital announces redundancies</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via GamesIndustry.biz //</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> UK co-development specialist Sumo Digital has confirmed yet another round of redundancies. The Tencent-owned company said it must adapt its business to remain "resilient" amid ongoing instability across the video game industry. The news came around 18 months after the company laid off 15 percent of its workforce.&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="QA workers at Blizzard ratify union contract with Microsoft"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/qa-workers-at-blizzard-ratify-union-contract-with-microsoft">QA workers at Blizzard ratify union contract with Microsoft</a>&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>via Game Developer //</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> After years of negotiations, a group of QA workers at Blizzard Albany and Austin rated a union contract with Microsoft that delivers wage increases, generative AI protections, crediting provisions, disability accommodations, and much more. One union member said the contract makes it easier to see a "real, long-term career" at the company.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blizzard-workers-ratify-union-contract-ghost-of-yotei-soars-and-has-yves-guillemot-outstayed-his-welcome-at-ubisoft-patch-notes-39]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Planet of Lana 2 is launching in March, and a demo is coming next week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/06/planet-of-lana-2-is-launching-in-march-and-a-demo-is-coming-next-week/</link>
            <guid>1427887</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Wishfully and Thunderful Games has announced the release date for <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/planet-of-lana-2">Planet of Lana II: Children of the Leaf</a>, launching on 5th March 2026. There’s further surprises, though, as the game is also coming to Switch and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Switch 2</a>, in addition to PS5, PS4, Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One and PC (and with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-game-pass">Game Pass</a> on day one), and there’s also a demo coming out next week!</p>
<p><iframe title="Planet of Lana II: Children of the Leaf - Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NksRtFjpYGI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The playable demo will be going live on 11th February for all platforms, giving a first hands-on opportunity for Lana and Mui’s continuing adventure.</p>
<p>This next chapter in their tale will look to build on the strengths of the original. The story promises to be more ambitious, there’s new puzzles, and evolved companion mechanics for Lana to work with Mui. Lana is older, bigger and stronger, able to get around the world more readily, and there’s screenshots that show off swimming, which I believe is new for this game as well. Planet of Lana 2 still retains the delightful hand-painted visuals and the orchestral score.</p>
<p>Here’s Wishfully’s synopsis:</p>

<p>As greed and power divide the tribes of their home planet, Lana and her loyal companion Mui must stand together against the forces reshaping their world – struggling not just for survival, but for the very soul of their home. Embark on an unforgettable cinematic puzzle journey across Novo, where ancient mysteries and new threats will test your wits, challenge Lana’s unbreakable bond with Mui, and guide her toward her destiny.</p>
<p>I really enjoyed the original game, saying in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/05/22/planet-of-lana-review/">our review</a>, “Planet of Lana looks and sounds as wonderful as its original reveal promised. While it doesn’t redefine the adventure platformer, the adorable partnership between Lana and Mui, the gorgeous art direction and sweeping soundtrack make this well worth experiencing.”</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/06/planet-of-lana-2-is-launching-in-march-and-a-demo-is-coming-next-week/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japanese Charts: Mario Kart World Can't Keep Code Vein II From The Top Spot]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/japanese-charts-mario-kart-world-cant-keep-code-vein-ii-from-the-top-spot</link>
            <guid>1427884</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="9ed7e9492fc64"><a title="Code Vein 2 / Mario Kart World" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/9ed7e9492fc64/code-vein-2-mario-kart-world.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Yesterday's Direct shenanigans meant that we were a little too busy to get to the Japanese charts, but worry not, we've got them for you now!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202602/65215">Famitsu</a>'s latest numbers paint another picture of sleepy sales numbers this week, with nothing exceeding 15,000 copies sold. Bandai Namco's <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/code_vein_2">Code Vein II</a> on PS5 emerged at the top of the pile with 14,452 debut sales to its name, narrowly beating <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a>, which still hangs around in second.</p>
<p>Much like we saw in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/uk-charts-final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-plummets-as-familiar-faces-retake-the-podium">UK charts</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade">Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade</a> has taken a bit of a tumble since grabbing the gold medal last week, and now finds itself in ninth. Meanwhile, three titles take up a whopping six spots in the top ten, with both their Switch 1 and Switch 2 editions making it into the upper reaches of the charts.</p>
<p>Here's the latest top ten physical sales in Japan:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Position</th>
<th>Game</th>
<th>Platform</th>
<th><strong>Unit Sales</strong> <strong>(26th Jan - 1st Feb)</strong></th>
<th>Total Unit Sales</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>
<p>Code Vein II</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>PS5</p>
</td>
<td>14,452</td>
<td>NEW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2<a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/shin_megami_tensei_v_vengeance"><br></a></td>
<td>
<p>Mario Kart World</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>12,445</td>
<td>
<p>2,805,146</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>
<p>Animal Crossing: New Horizons - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>9,941</td>
<td>52,918</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>
<p>Animal Crossing: New Horizons</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>9,042</p>
</td>
<td>8,362,221</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td>
<p>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>6,744</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>1,601,782</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6</td>
<td>
<p>Momotaro Dentetsu 2: Anata no Machi mo Kitto Aru – Higashi Nihon Hen + Nishi Nihon Hen - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>6,203</td>
<td>262,314</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7</td>
<td>
<p>Pokémon Legends: Z-A - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>5,875</td>
<td>1,078,445</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8</td>
<td>
<p>Kirby Air Riders</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>5,324</td>
<td>491,424</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9</td>
<td>
<p>Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch 2</p>
</td>
<td>5,289</td>
<td>
<p>28,717</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10</td>
<td>
<p>Momotaro Dentetsu 2: Anata no Machi mo Kitto Aru – Higashi Nihon Hen + Nishi Nihon Hen</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>5,243</td>
<td>
<p>313,300</p>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<p>Things were similarly sluggish on the hardware side of things. Switch 2 continued to put up some solid numbers, with an additional ~69,000 units to its name, but it was ghostly quiet from everything else across the board.</p>
<p>Combining the three SKUs for Switch and PS5 leans things in Sony's favour this week, with the Switch 1 models totalling in at 10,678, and the PS5 trio reaching 10,949.</p>
<p>Here's a look at the week's full hardware charts:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Position</th>
<th>Console</th>
<th><strong>Unit Sales</strong> <strong>(</strong><strong>26th Jan - 1st Feb</strong>)</th>
<th>Lifetime Unit Sales</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>Switch 2</td>
<td>69,586</td>
<td>4,307,086</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td>
<p>PlayStation 5 Digital Edition</p>
</td>
<td>5,803</td>
<td>
<p>1,172,069</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>
<p>Switch OLED</p>
</td>
<td>4,526</td>
<td>9,431,437</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>Switch Lite</td>
<td>4,462</td>
<td>6,848,650</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td>
<p>PlayStation 5</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>3,575</p>
</td>
<td>5,884,066</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6</td>
<td>
<p>Switch</p>
</td>
<td>1,690</td>
<td>20,237,843</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7</td>
<td>
<p>PlayStation 5 Pro</p>
</td>
<td>1,571</td>
<td>319,526</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8</td>
<td>
<p>Xbox Series X Digital Edition</p>
</td>
<td>389</td>
<td>26,110</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9</td>
<td>
<p>Xbox Series S</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>119</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>340,676</p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10<br></td>
<td>
<p>Xbox Series X</p>
</td>
<td>
<p>19</p>
</td>
<td>323,926<br></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>11<br></td>
<td>PlayStation 4<br></td>
<td>
<p>13</p>
</td>
<td>7,930,217</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/japanese-charts-final-fantasy-vii-remake-intergrade-emerges-victorious-in-a-quiet-week">&lt; Previous charts</a></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:196050,197125,197097 @ 1770376503 -->
<p><em>What are your thoughts on this week's Japanese charts? Let us know down below.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.famitsu.com/article/202602/65215" rel="noopener" href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202602/65215">famitsu.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/69b1d31e4a00cdde809c26b29239ba08 @ 1770377919 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/japanese-charts-mario-kart-world-cant-keep-code-vein-ii-from-the-top-spot]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones developer MachineGames still plans to finish its Wolfenstein trilogy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-developer-machinegames-still-plans-to-finish-its-wolfenstein-trilogy</link>
            <guid>1427869</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>The Wolfenstein among us.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-grey-haired-man-in-unifrom-in-Wolfenstein-2-The-New-Colossus.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-grey-haired-man-in-unifrom-in-Wolfenstein-2-The-New-Colossus.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-grey-haired-man-in-unifrom-in-Wolfenstein-2-The-New-Colossus.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-grey-haired-man-in-unifrom-in-Wolfenstein-2-The-New-Colossus.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-grey-haired-man-in-unifrom-in-Wolfenstein-2-The-New-Colossus.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-grey-haired-man-in-unifrom-in-Wolfenstein-2-The-New-Colossus.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-grey-haired-man-in-unifrom-in-Wolfenstein-2-The-New-Colossus.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-grey-haired-man-in-unifrom-in-Wolfenstein-2-The-New-Colossus.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-grey-haired-man-in-unifrom-in-Wolfenstein-2-The-New-Colossus.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>MachineGames</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>MachineGames' most recent release may be the brilliant Indiana Jones and the Great Circle, but the studio is of course also known for its Wolfenstein games. And, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/it-doesnt-sound-like-weve-heard-the-last-from-machinegames-wolfenstein-series">following an earlier hint that the studio wasn't finished with its nazi-busting series</a>, we now have more concrete word on the fate of MachineGames' Wolfenstein trilogy.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>This word comes from studio director Jerk Gustafsson, who was chatting with Eurogamer's sister site <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/machinegames-on-being-part-of-microsoft-going-back-to-the-office-and-wolfenstein-3">GamesIndustry</a> about MachineGames' 15 year legacy. During this conversation, Gustafsson admitted that because of the time it takes to make a video game in this day and age, he may only have a few more projects left in him before the end of his career.</p>
<p>"There's so many things that I would like to do, but I'm also getting a bit older, so I don't have that many games left in me," he said. "It takes a long time to make a game now, and let's say that we release one every four years, then maybe two more, maybe three if I'm lucky."</p>
<p>So, could one of these hypothetical projects be Wolfenstein 3? While Gustafsson was careful with his answer, he did say this:</p>
<p>"Our intention has always been to go back to Wolfenstein. We wanted to finish the trilogy. And when we do that, that is something that I don't want to comment on. It can be now, it can be later, but we're not done with it. That's what I can say."</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>MachineGames</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for the more immediate future, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-4-and-indiana-jones-switch-2-release-dates-leak-ahead-of-nintendo-direct">MachineGames is set to release Indiana Jones and the Great Circle on Switch 2 later this year</a>. Like I have said, this game is brilliant, and I loved being able to whip crack my way across the globe with Indy.</p>
<p>"Smart, fun and so very Indiana Jones, The Great Circle is a stealth action tour de force that marks a bold new era for MachineGames," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review">original five star Indiana Jones and the Great Circle review from 2024</a>.</p>
<p>There's also a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/wolfenstein-is-the-next-game-series-to-get-an-adaptation-for-tv">Wolfenstein TV series in the works</a>, though <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/an-elder-scrolls-tv-series-cant-be-ruled-out-todd-howard-teases-but-remains-tight-lipped-on-the-status-of-the-wolfenstein-adaptation">Bethesda's Todd Howard is staying tight-lipped on how things are progressing</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-developer-machinegames-still-plans-to-finish-its-wolfenstein-trilogy]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BAFTA Games in Concert – Opening Night in Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/06/bafta-games-in-concert-opening-night-in-review/</link>
            <guid>1427860</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>What is your favourite piece of video game music? If we started humming the opening theme to Halo, how many of you would join in? What about if it was Tifa’s Theme or the theme to Assassin’s Creed? All of these live rent-free in our heads, and no doubt yours too.</p>
<p>This is something that the British Academy of Film and Television Arts, or BAFTA as we all know it, is keenly aware of, and it is to their immense credit that they realised this more than 20 years ago when they held the inaugural British Academy Games Award for Music in 2002, celebrating “excellence in composition for a game music score, through original music and/or creative use of licensed track”.</p>
<p>To put that in perspective, composer Jeremy Soule won for his work on Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets, beating the other nominees: Command &amp; Conquer: Generals, Primal, Republic: The Revolution, TimeSplitters 2 and Return to Castle Wolfenstein. If, like us, you remember playing these games at launch, we can recommend good deals on walking sticks.</p>


<div id="attachment_468569"><p id="caption-attachment-468569">Austin Wintory conducting at BAFTA Games in Concert 2026 –&nbsp;Image Credit: Andy Paradise</p></div>
<p>It’s with this rich catalogue of exceptional music in mind that BAFTA Games in Concert was produced. Its world premiere at the Royal Festival Hall on Saturday 31 January certainly felt celebratory. Conducted by BAFTA-winning composer Austin Wintory, and backed up by the 65-piece BBC Concert Orchestra and London Voices, attendees were met with iconic video game soundtracks from over the past two decades.</p>

<p>As the ensemble did what they do best, starting with Baldur’s Gate 3, a screen behind them played excerpts from the games they were celebrating. The thing that differentiates this from your average performance, however, is the game footage being cut with real-life singers, placed into a setting that reflects the game — in this case, a red-head in a green dress with Celtic jewellery singing opera.</p>

<p>What followed was a night of fantastic music. Wintory introduced Jessica Curry’s Everybody’s Gone to the Rapture before ploughing straight into Inon Zur’s Fallout 4, followed by Jesper Kyd’s Assassin’s Creed.</p>
<div id="attachment_468571"><p id="caption-attachment-468571">BAFTA Games in Concert features Helldivers 2 –&nbsp;Image Credit: Andy Paradise</p></div>
<p>As excellent as these pieces are — and they are truly excellent, the choir singing the theme to Assassin’s Creed gave me goosebumps — this is where the issues with this performance came to the fore. It could be opening night tech issues, but the human performer intercut with the footage on the screen was playing a wooden flute-like instrument. However, despite seeing his fingers moving, I couldn’t hear him playing over what was in the room. Perhaps the AV team knocked the slider by mistake, but it felt a little off.</p>
<p>The other thing that was obviously missing after Wintory introduced Curry’s phenomenal score was any sort of intro or anecdote about what was to come. This is where real value could have been given to the paying audience — small insights into what each composer thought, liked or was inspired by as they crafted the melodies that have stayed with us for decades. They were in the room, it wouldn’t have been hard to pick their brains.</p>
<div id="attachment_468574"><p id="caption-attachment-468574">Baldur’s Gate 3 Composer Borislav Slavov &amp; Performers Mariya Anastasova and Andrew Wincott –&nbsp;Image Credit: Andy Paradise</p></div>
<p>The best video game music concerts I’ve seen all have insights and trivia from the composer or lead musician to hang the performances on. It’s never for every piece, and it doesn’t have to be, but it provides not only a structure for the performance, but also a frame of reference for those who haven’t played every game that’s being showcased that evening.</p>
<p>Absent such a narrative, the BAFTA Games in Concert felt a lot more like a greatest hits compilation than a celebration, especially in the second half. Hopefully this was just the opening-night settling into a format and future audiences will get to hear why Disco Elysium has the tone they’re hearing, which instrument you see played on the screens during Far Cry 4 and what inspired the music behind Returnal.</p>
<p>Still, it was a night of phenomenal music, played beautifully by some truly expert musicians. You really can’t beat live music, especially when a full orchestra is on stage.</p>
<hr>
<p>If you’re keen to reminisce about how far video game music has come and celebrate it as an art form in its own right, check out the tour dates below:</p>
<ul>
<li>Saturday 23 May 2026 – The Glasshouse, Gateshead</li>
<li>Sunday 31 May 2026 – Bristol Beacon, Bristol</li>
<li>Thursday 04 June 2026 – Usher Hall, Edinburgh</li>
<li>Friday 05 June 2026 – Royal Concert Hall, Glasgow</li>
<li>Saturday 06 June 2026 – Symphony Hall, Birmingham</li>
<li>Sunday 07 June 2026 – Aviva Studios, Manchester</li>
</ul>
<p>Tickets are available now at <a href="https://www.liveconcert.games/">https://www.liveconcert.games</a></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/06/bafta-games-in-concert-opening-night-in-review/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization 8 could be a proper early access game - "never say never", comment Firaxis]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/civilization-8-could-be-a-proper-early-access-game-never-say-never-comment-firaxis</link>
            <guid>1427857</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Firaxis are somewhat "jealous" of devs taking this route</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civ5.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civ5.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civ5.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civ5.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civ5.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civ5.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civ5.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civ5.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civ5.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>RPS / Firaxis</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii">Civilization 7</a> has been through a sizeable array of changes since launch in February next year, amid some very uncivilised reactions to boat-rocking features like the new age format. The next update, Test Of Time, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/civilization-7s-big-test-of-time-update-thatll-bring-back-playing-as-one-civ-for-the-whole-game-is-set-to-drop-this-spring">will restore the ability to play as one civilization through the whole game</a>, while making changes to how victories are earned in the hope of creating some lategame variety.</p>
<p>All these tweaks and rejigs invite a more fundamental question. “Why didn’t they just launch it as an early access game?” I remember moaning to another journalist last year. I should have directed my moaning at executive producer Dennis Shirk, who says that Firaxis are tentatively open to the idea and, indeed, “jealous” of developers taking this approach.
</p><!--more-->
<p>
That’s a snippet from <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2026/02/interview-civilization-viis-devs-on-the-big-update-meant-to-win-critics-back/">an Ars Technica interview</a> this week in which Shirk and franchise creative director Ed Beach look back on the transition from <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vi">Civilization VI</a> to Civilization VII, and what they might try with the hypothetical Civilization 8.</p>
<p>One of the major changes with Civilization VI was that Firaxis had access to lot more player telemetry, compared to Civilisation V, rather than monitoring the feedback on Reddit and fansites like CivFanatics. Amongst other things, they discovered that most players don’t finish a single game, which is part of the reason for Civ 7’s more broken-up, modular historical progression.
</p><p>
Based on the reaction to Civ 7, the devs are trying to get hold of that feedback earlier in development of new mechanics or systems. “It’s the worst-kept secret in the world that we’ve had this external test team for quite a few years called our Frankenstein Group,” Beach told the site.</p>
<p>With publisher 2K’s input, the Frankenstein Group is being expanded into <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/civilization-7-will-bring-back-the-ability-to-play-as-one-civ-for-the-whole-game-bypassing-the-divisive-age-system">a larger and more structured playtesting program, the Firaxis Feature Workshop</a>. (I enjoy the implication that a bunch of mad scientists have gone mainstream – I’m picturing Doc Brown, Doctor Octopus and Doctor Eggman at an investor fare, explaining the nutritional benefits of formaldehyde to passing soccer moms.)
</p>
<p>
Officially embracing full early access development (not just preorder-baiting ‘advanced access’) would surely make a lot of sense for Civ, even discounting the ire aimed at Civ 7. After all, even the best 4X strategy games tend to evolve a lot throughout their shelf lives. Ars Technica popped the question, and Shirk had this to say: “It’s one of those things that you can never say never. As developers, we’re always looking at that jealously because we see that it’s a great opportunity.” 
</p>
<p>
Even so, I doubt it’ll ever happen, because when you present yourself as selling an unfinished game, it’s harder to charge $70 or more for it upfront. Still, perhaps the wilting fortunes of Civ 7 will persuade 2K and Take-Two Interactive to be more calculating with the game's development process.</p><p>Civ 7 set a series record for preorders, but has struggled to match its predecessors in terms of Steam concurrent users. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-ceo-strauss-zelnick-insists-projections-for-the-lifetime-value-of-civilization-7-are-very-consistent-with-our-initial-expectations-for-the-title-despite-slow-start">Speaking in August last year</a>, Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick confessed that the game had gotten off to a “slow start” with the caveat that “Civ has always been a slow burn” and “right now our projections for the lifetime value of the title are very consistent with our initial expectations for the title.” The publishers have yet to share any total sales figures.
</p>
<p>
The broader question around Civ going early access is whether “early access” really means anything, any more, inasmuch as “early access” has sort of bled into “live service". Most games of a certain scale receive a number of updates post-launch, and players have come to expect them, with a vocal minority pillorying games as “dead” if too many months go past without substantial changes. I think there’s probably a longer feature to write there – do you have any thoughts?
</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/civilization-8-could-be-a-proper-early-access-game-never-say-never-comment-firaxis]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite February 2026 Roadmap: Love Legends Event, Collabs & More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-february-2026-roadmap/</link>
            <guid>1427854</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Regular new content drops continue to take place in Fortnite, and February 2026 is stacked, with Epic Games dropping a big teaser roadmap of what to expect.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/genres/battle-royale/">Battle Royale</a> behemoth is in the latter stages of the current season, but a new Fortnite Festival season has only just begun. Additionally, updates are also coming to other modes, including Reload and Fortnite OG.</p>



<p>If you’re looking for all of the dates and new content coming in the Fortnite Roadmap for February 2026, Insider Gaming has you covered.</p>







<h2 id="h-complete-fortnite-february-2026-roadmap">Complete Fortnite February 2026 Roadmap</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Lots to come. Image via Epic Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Fortnite has plenty to add in February with the month-long Love Legends event, featuring new collabs, free rewards, and more.</strong></p>



<p>The Love Legends event kicked off immediately after the update on February 5, with the first major content coming the following day with the second wave of KPop Demon Hunter Skins. </p>



<p>Later in the month, players can expect new weapons and items in Battle Royale, along with the long-awaited return of The Seven.</p>



<p>The table below shows all of the major additions coming to Fortnite in February 2026, as revealed by Epic Games. New announcements will be added regularly.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Fortnite Addition</th><th data-align="center">Date</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">February 6</td><td data-align="center">– KPop Demon Hunters Wave 2</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">February 7</td><td data-align="center">– Battle Royale Power Hour<br>– Pink Storm Shield</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">February 13</td><td data-align="center">– Nitemare Island Returns<br>– Cupid’s Crossbow</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">February 14</td><td data-align="center">– Battle Royale Power Hour</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">February 15</td><td data-align="center">– Fortnite OG Ice Storm Live Event</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">February 19</td><td data-align="center">– DeLorean Return<br>– Lantern Fest Reload Map</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">February 21</td><td data-align="center">– Battle Royale Power Hour</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">February 23</td><td data-align="center">– Return of The Seven<br>– New Item</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-is-there-more-coming-in-february-2026">Is There More Coming in February 2026?</h2>



<p><strong>Yes, Fortnite will definitely have plenty more to add in February 2026, including content added beyond February 23.</strong></p>



<p>Epic Games’ reveal teaser only covered up until February 23 and the additions beyond that date will likely center around the long-awaited return of The Seven.</p>



<p>There will also be a significant build-up to the first seasonal change of 2026, with Chapter 7, Season 2 kicking off in early March.</p>



<p>Players should also expect further collab skins to drop in the Item Shop, as Epic Games is on a roll of major additions so far this year.</p>







<hr>



<p>What do you want to see added to Fortnite before the end of the season? Share your ideas in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, find out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/where-is-zero-build-fortnite/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">where to find Zero Build</a> in the new update, and take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-direct-february-2026-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">everything announced in February’s Nintendo Direct</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-february-2026-roadmap/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where is Zero Build in Fortnite? Zero Build Removed Rumors, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/where-is-zero-build-fortnite/</link>
            <guid>1427851</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Fortnite continues to drop regular updates, but the latest has caused some confusion, with some questioning whether the popular Zero Build modes have been removed.</p>



<p>Zero Build is a more accessible version of Fortnite’s popular <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/genres/battle-royale/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Battle Royale</a> mode, removing all of the complicated build mechanics from the game, and it regularly attracts hundreds of thousands of players.</p>



<p>Tweaks in Fortnite’s February 5 update have raised some questions for Zero Build, but Insider Gaming is here to clear the air.</p>







<h2 id="h-where-is-zero-build-in-fortnite">Where is Zero Build in Fortnite?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Settings. Screenshot by FGZ</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Zero Build is found in the lobby settings for the mode,  the same area where options for Team Size and Squad Fill are located.</strong></p>



<p>Once the game mode you want to play has been selected, the option for Zero Build can then be toggled. Here’s a step-by-step approach to the full process.</p>



<ol>
<li>Log in to Fortnite as you normally would.</li>



<li>Choose a game mode with Zero Build available (Battle Royale, OG, Reload, Blitz).</li>



<li>In the lobby screen, select the options found above the yellow Play button, where it should currently say: Build, Solo.</li>



<li>In the pop-up screen, click where it says ‘Zero Build.’</li>



<li>Select any other options as you desire, including Ranked and Team Size.</li>



<li>Hit ‘Close’ to return to the lobby, with your changes saved, or press ‘Play’ to begin searching for a match.</li>
</ol>



<h2 id="h-did-fortnite-remove-zero-build">Did Fortnite Remove Zero Build?</h2>



<p><strong>No, Fortnite has not removed Zero Build from the game, but there have</strong> <strong>been some changes to tidy up the lobby and mode selection screen.</strong></p>



<p>Fortnite has evolved significantly since Epic Games initially released the title, regularly adding new game modes for players to enjoy.</p>



<p>Additionally, there’s far too much to keep track of when all the popular Creative modes are taken into account.</p>



<p>In the update on February 5, Epic Games made a big change to the mode select screen. However, Zero Build is still available across all major modes, including Fortnite OG, Reload, and Blitz.</p>







<hr>



<p>What do you think about the UI changes introduced by Fortnite in the latest update? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-direct-february-2026-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">everything announced in February’s Nintendo Direct</a>, and check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/reviews/nioh-3-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full review of Nioh 3</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/where-is-zero-build-fortnite/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox is planning a summer release for Halo remake and a late 2026 launch for Gears of War E-Day according to a new report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-is-planning-a-summer-release-for-halo-remake-and-a-late-2026-launch-for-gears-of-war-e-day-according-to-a-new-report</link>
            <guid>1427848</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gears-of-War-E-Day_bwkbGlD.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gears-of-War-E-Day_bwkbGlD.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gears-of-War-E-Day_bwkbGlD.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gears-of-War-E-Day_bwkbGlD.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gears-of-War-E-Day_bwkbGlD.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gears-of-War-E-Day_bwkbGlD.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gears-of-War-E-Day_bwkbGlD.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gears-of-War-E-Day_bwkbGlD.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gears-of-War-E-Day_bwkbGlD.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Xbox Game Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A new report has claimed that Gears of War E-Day is eyeing a release window in the second half of 2026, with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/halo-combat-evolved">Halo: Combat Evolved</a> tentatively targeting a launch some time this Summer.</p>
<p>This report, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/874303/microsoft-xbox-roadmap-2026-notepad">written by The Verge's Tom Warren</a>, claims that Microsoft wants both Gears of War E-Day and Fable to dodge the launch of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gta-6-everything-we-know-so-far-9357">Grand Theft Auto 6</a>, with Tom Warren writing: "I understand Microsoft has a good idea of when both should launch, but it's also keen to avoid being too close to Grand Theft Auto VI's November 19th date."</p>
<p>The report also touches on the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout-3">Fallout 3</a> Remake, which The Verge reports is in "active development". The article also states that Bethesda wants the game to reach a similar bar of quality as the Oblivion Remake, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/even-in-the-shadow-of-skyrims-mountains-the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-still-matters">which was well-received in part due to its faithfulness and level of polish</a>.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Here's a big gameplay breakdown for the recentl Fable gameplay showcase!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UMS-xSNNeX4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Finally, The Verge reports that Double Fine's The Kiln is aiming for an April release, and new <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/starfield-main-story-walkthrough-9352">Starfield</a> content is due for a reveal soon. All of this comes with a caveat, with Warren sensibly writing: "Don't be surprised if any of these game dates slip or change -- such is the reality of video game development."</p><p>If these release windows are accurate, which they may very well be (The Verge has a solid track record with this stuff), then Microsoft certainly has a packed 2026. Fable, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fable-finally-gets-a-release-window-following-xbox-developer-direct-will-launch-in-autumn-2026">which we already know is due to launch some time this Autumn</a>, recently got a dedicated showcase in an Xbox Developer Direct. There's also <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/forza-horizon-6">Forza Horizon 6</a>, set in Japan and landing on the 19th May.</p>
<p>If these dates and release windows are accurate, what do you reckon of Xbox line-up this year? Let us know in the comments!</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-is-planning-a-summer-release-for-halo-remake-and-a-late-2026-launch-for-gears-of-war-e-day-according-to-a-new-report]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate 3 HBO Series Announced, with Craig Mazin (Chernobyl, The Last of Us) Creating]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-hbo-series-announced-craig-mazin-creating/</link>
            <guid>1427842</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://deadline.com/2026/02/baldurs-gate-3-tv-show-craig-mazin-hbo-1236710583/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Deadline reports</a> that <span><strong>a Baldur's Gate 3 HBO series is now underway</strong>, with&nbsp;<strong>Craig Mazin</strong>&nbsp;attached as&nbsp;</span>creator, writer, showrunner, and executive producer. Mazin is primarily known for his acclaimed work on the TV shows <strong>Chernobyl</strong> and <strong>The Last of Us</strong>, the latter of which is particularly relevant because it's also an adaptation of a game. Previously in his career, he also co-wrote the screenplays for movies like Scary Movie 3 and 4, The Hangover Part II and III, and The Huntsman: Winter's War.</p>



<p>The big difference compared to the adaptation of Naughty Dog's The Last of Us is that the Baldur's Gate 3 HBO series will pick up from the end of the game made by <strong>Larian Studios</strong> and continue from there. On the one hand, this is perfect because Larian famously <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-no-sequel-dlc-larian-dropping-dungeons-and-dragons/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">decided against doing Baldur's Gate 3 DLCs or even a sequel</a></strong>, opting to <a href="https://wccftech.com/divinity-is-a-turn-based-rpg-will-be-way-better-than-baldurs-gate-3-says-larian/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">make a new game based on its own <strong>Divinity IP</strong></a>. Many fans who loved characters like <strong>Astarion, Shadowheart, Gale, Karlach, Lae'zel, Wyll</strong>, and <strong>Halsin</strong> were eager to learn what would happen to them next. </p>



<p>On the other hand, <strong>there's the little issue that one of the game's main features is the ability for players to influence the events in major ways</strong>. For instance, in my playthrough, I killed both Lae'zel and Astarion. Even setting aside such extreme measures, the creators of the Baldur's Gate 3 HBO series will inevitably have to choose a specific thread for each character from among the various choices originally available in the cRPG.</p>



<p>Anyway, Mazin will be helped by executive producers <strong>Jacqueline Lesko</strong>, <strong>Cecil O’Connor</strong>, and <strong>Hasbro Entertainment's Gabriel Marano</strong>. Moreover, <strong>Chris Perkins</strong>, the former Head of Story at <strong>Wizards of the Coast</strong>, will be involved as a consultant. Craig Mazin shared the following statement to go along with the news:</p>



<p><em>After putting nearly 1000 hours into the incredible world of Baldur’s Gate 3, it is a dream come true to be able to continue the story that Larian and Wizards of The Coast created. I am a devoted fan of D&amp;D and the brilliant way that Swen Vincke and his gifted team adapted it. I can’t wait to help bring Baldur’s Gate and all of its incredible characters to life with as much respect and love as we can, and I’m deeply grateful to Gabe Marano and his team at Hasbro for entrusting me with this incredibly important property.</em></p>



<p>Deadline's report adds that alongside characters from the game, the Baldur's Gate 3 HBO series will also feature some new ones. Indeed, it does sound like the new characters could be the main protagonists, though that remains unclear at the time being. By the way, <strong>Mazin has reportedly reached out to some of the game's excellent voice cast to participate in the adaptation in some capacity</strong>. There are no dates yet, but we know Mazin is preparing to shoot <a href="https://wccftech.com/hbos-the-last-of-us-may-wrap-up-in-three-seasons-not-four-it-certainly-seems-that-way-says-hbo-boss/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the third and final season of The Last of Us adaptation</a>. Presumably, his next project will be Baldur's Gate 3.</p>



<p>Lastly, if you were wondering whether game developer Larian would be involved in any way, <strong>CEO Swen Vincke</strong> <a href="https://x.com/LarAtLarian/status/2019646146587525143" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote on X</a> that the endings were written specifically to serve as the base for new adventures, and added that <strong>Mazin has already reached out to them to have a chat about the TV show</strong>, so there's a chance Larian might pass on some of their ideas.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/baldurs-gate-3-hbo-series-announced-craig-mazin-creating/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Baldur’s Gate TV series is set to follow on from Baldur’s Gate 3, though Larian don't look to be involved beyond a casual chat]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-baldurs-gate-tv-series-is-set-to-follow-on-from-baldurs-gate-3s-story-though-larian-dont-look-to-be-involved-beyond-a-casual-chat</link>
            <guid>1427839</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>The Last Of Us show co-creator Craig Mazin is set to helm the new series</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gaye-3-tv-show-in-works-larian-not-involved-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gaye-3-tv-show-in-works-larian-not-involved-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gaye-3-tv-show-in-works-larian-not-involved-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gaye-3-tv-show-in-works-larian-not-involved-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gaye-3-tv-show-in-works-larian-not-involved-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gaye-3-tv-show-in-works-larian-not-involved-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gaye-3-tv-show-in-works-larian-not-involved-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gaye-3-tv-show-in-works-larian-not-involved-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/baldurs-gaye-3-tv-show-in-works-larian-not-involved-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Larian</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Everything's a show! <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JoAhmWlS8sY">Everything's a show</a>! Everything's a show! Everything's a show! Did you know <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/baldurs-gate">Baldur's Gate</a> is a show? Well, it will be soon. One that'll carry on from the events of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii">Baldur's Gate 3</a> and star characters both old and new. Baldur's Gate 3 developers Larian, though, don't seem to be directly involved outside of the show's boss asking if he can pop into their studio for a chat.</p>
<!--more-->
<p><a href="https://deadline.com/2026/02/baldurs-gate-3-tv-show-craig-mazin-hbo-1236710583/">Deadline</a> report that this Baldur’s Gate HBO drama is set to be helmed by Craig Mazin, co-creator of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-last-of-us">The Last of Us</a>' TV adaptation, who'll write, executive produce and showrun it. As you might expect, a bunch of executive producing chairs have also been assigned to bigwigs at Hasbro and subsidiary Wizards of the Coast, the current owners of the Baldur's Gate series/name/all of its various bits.</p>
<p>According to Deadline, the BG show won't be a relatively straightforward adaption of tales the games have already told, instead aiming to be a "continuation to the games, telling a story that takes place immediately after the events of Baldur’s Gate 3, as the characters — old and new — are dealing with the ramifications of the events in the third game".</p>
<p>The site add that the show, which isn't tied to meshing with any new Baldur's Gate games in development, "draws deeply" from BG3 and "not so much from the first two games which are not official source material". From the sounds of it, the older entries' influence might be limited to wider themes/bits which form part of all three games and are key aspects of wider DnD lore. Mazin also reportedly plans to reach out to some of Baldur's Gate 3's voice actors in the hopes of potentially getting them involved in the show.</p><p>Despite the Baldur's Gate 3 emphasis here, that game's devs Larian don't look to be directly involved in crafting the show, at least in terms of having full hands-on roles like Bethesda have with Amazon's Fallout adaptation. That arguably isn't entirely surprising, given they've moved back to working on their own games post-BG3 with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/larian-will-no-longer-use-genai-for-divinity-concept-art-and-any-genai-used-for-other-games-will-be-trained-on-data-we-own">Divinity</a>, rather than agreeing to make a Baldur's Gate 4 with Hasbro's blessing.</p>
<p>Larian boss Swen Vincke's opted to take the <a href="https://x.com/LarAtLarian/status/2019646146587525143">diplomatic approach</a> to news of the show. "The endings of BG3 were created so they could serve as narrative soil for new adventures," he wrote, adding that to his knowledge none of Larian's writers are consulting on the show. "There's plenty of directions they could go. I'm eager to find out which ones Craig and his team will pick. He's reached out for a chat so we'll have the opportunity to tell him our thoughts."</p>
<p>Larian publishing head Michael Douse, meanwhile, has opted to take a slightly less diplomatic approach. Going on a lengthy <a href="https://x.com/Cromwelp">retweeting spree </a>of random folks' posts about not watching the show now they've learned Larian won't be crafting it directly. He also had a <a href="https://x.com/Cromwelp/status/2019586400476164184">wee shout at Deadline</a> for not asking Larian about the show prior to publishing their article and responded to a Geoff Keighley post about Larian not being involved in the series by writing: "except that we made it popular enough for it to be referred to as Baldur's Gate 3". Finally, he's gathered some thoughts into <a href="https://x.com/Cromwelp/status/2019572415878070680">a thread</a> that's rather less unhinged and essentially boils down to hoping the show does the work of Baldur's Gate 3's writers justice.</p>
<p>We'll see if it does, but there's no timeline been given as of yet for when the show'll arrive.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-baldurs-gate-tv-series-is-set-to-follow-on-from-baldurs-gate-3s-story-though-larian-dont-look-to-be-involved-beyond-a-casual-chat]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur’s Gate television series confirmed by HBO]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/06/baldurs-gate-television-series-confirmed-by-hbo/</link>
            <guid>1427818</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It is reported that<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/baldurs-gate-3/"> Baldur’s Gate</a> will be coming to television screens, with the show following on from the end of the third game.&nbsp; <a href="https://deadline.com/2026/02/baldurs-gate-3-tv-show-craig-mazin-hbo-1236710583/">Deadline</a> reports that HBO have secured the rights to make the show and also the talents of Craig Mazin, co-creator of The Last of Us television series and the fantastic Chernobyl.</p>
<p>Mazin is a big gamer and has completed Baldur’s Gate 3 on Honor mode, a single-save difficulty setting featuring smarter enemies, higher enemy health, and punishing ‘Legendary Actions’ for bosses. It is reported that the series will include existing and new characters, and Mazin will be reaching out to the voice actors from the game to try to get them into the television series.</p>


<p>“After putting nearly 1000 hours into the incredible world of&nbsp;Baldur’s Gate 3, it is a dream come true to be able to continue the story that Larian and Wizards of The Coast created,” Mazin said. “I am a devoted fan of D&amp;D and the brilliant way that Swen Vincke and his gifted team adapted it. I can’t wait to help bring&nbsp;Baldur’s Gate&nbsp;and all of its incredible characters to life with as much respect and love as we can, and I’m deeply grateful to Gabe Marano and his team at Hasbro for entrusting me with this incredibly important property.”</p>
<p>Mazin is also a long-time fan of Dungeons &amp; Dragons and has been running games as a Dungeon Master for fifteen years.&nbsp; HBO have <a href="https://deadline.com/2026/01/hbo-casey-bloys-the-pitt-heated-rivalry-euphoria-interview-1236700801/">strongly hinted</a> that the third season of The Last of Us will be the final season, so it would be logical that Baldur’s Gate would be Mazin’s next project.</p>
<p>In an interesting twist, the Baldur’s Gate series will “co-exist” alongside another Dungeons and Dragons show that is coming to Netflix, The Forgotten Realms.</p>

<p>“We’re thrilled to continue our partnership with Craig Mazin on&nbsp;Baldur’s Gate,” Francesca Orsi, EVP, Head of HBO Drama Programming said. “His deep and long-standing passion for the source material paired with his remarkable talent for building immersive worlds filled with rich, compelling characters, promises ground-breaking results.”</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://deadline.com/2026/02/baldurs-gate-3-tv-show-craig-mazin-hbo-1236710583/">Deadline</a>&nbsp;</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/06/baldurs-gate-television-series-confirmed-by-hbo/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 is getting the TV treatment from HBO's The Last of Us showrunner but Larian won't be directly involved]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-is-getting-tv-treatment-from-hbos-the-last-of-us-showrunner</link>
            <guid>1427815</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"It is a dream come true to be able to continue the story."</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-last-of-us-bg3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-last-of-us-bg3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-last-of-us-bg3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-last-of-us-bg3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-last-of-us-bg3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-last-of-us-bg3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-last-of-us-bg3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-last-of-us-bg3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-last-of-us-bg3.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Craig Mazin, showrunner on HBO's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-season-two-wins-series-another-emmy">award-winning The Last of Us adaptation</a>, has confirmed he's giving <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-a-critical-success-with-critical-failures">Baldur's Gate 3</a> the TV treatment next, with the new show set to continue the story of the acclaimed fantasy RPG - although developer Larian seemingly won't be directly involved.
</p>
<p>
As per <a href="https://variety.com/2026/tv/news/baldurs-gate-hbo-craig-mazin-1236654094/">Variety</a>, HBO is developing the Baldur's Gate 3 TV adaptation, hot of the success of its live-action The Last of Us series, with Mazin serving as both as showrunner and executive producer on the new project.
</p>
<p>
In a statement accompanying the news, Mazin claimed he'd put "nearly 1000 hours" into the video game version of Baldur's Gate 3. "It is a dream come true to be able to continue the story that Larian and Wizards of The Coast created," he said. "I am a devoted fan of D&amp;D and the brilliant way that Swen Vincke and his gifted team adapted it. I can't wait to help bring <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/baldurs-gate">Baldur's Gate</a> and all of its incredible characters to life with as much respect and love as we can."
</p>
<p>
Francesca Orsi, HBO's executive vice president and head of drama, added that Mazin's "deep and long-standing passion for the source material paired with his remarkable talent for building immersive worlds filled with rich, compelling characters promises groundbreaking results."
</p>
<p>
After news of the adaptation broken, The Games Awards' <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/geoff-keighley">Geoff Keighley</a> <a href="https://x.com/geoffkeighley/status/2019563522339082576?s=20">took to social media</a>, claiming Larian had told him directly the studio - which officially <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-developer-bids-final-farewell-for-real-this-time">wrapped up work</a> on Baldur's Gate 3 last year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/larians-next-game-wont-be-a-baldurs-gate-3-sequel-dlc-or-anything-with-dungeons-dragons">moving away from D&amp;D</a> - has "no involvement in the series." Larian boss Swen Vincke <a href="https://x.com/LarAtLarian/status/2019648134645957061?s=20">later confirmed</a> no Larian writers were consulting on the adaptation 'to his knowledge', but did note Mazin had reached out "to ask if he could come over to the studio to speak with us. From the conversation we had, I think he truly is a big fan which gives me hope."
</p><p>
"We worked incredibly hard on making Baldur's Gate 3 worthy of its legacy," Vincke wrote in a <a href="https://x.com/LarAtLarian/status/2019646146587525143?s=20">separate social media post</a>. "Its characters and narratives are the result of many teams working together and I think I can speak for them all in saying that they'll think this is cool and hope that what comes next will enjoy the same level of passion."
</p>
<p>
"The endings of BG3 were created so they could serve as narrative soil for new adventure," he continued. "There's plenty of directions they could go. I'm eager to find out which ones Craig and his team will pick. He's reached out for a chat so we'll have the opportunity to tell him our thoughts."
</p>
<p>
Larian director of publishing Michael Douse also <a href="https://x.com/Cromwelp/status/2019572415878070680?s=20">shared his thoughts</a>, writing, "I've spent the last eight to 10 years of my life with the writers and creators of Baldur's Gate 3 and they're the most incredible storytellers and creators in the space. Only hope is that they get both the credit deserved and the characters are represented at the same level as the game.
</p>
<p>
"Our stories are built by fierce comeraderie and resolve," Douse added. "I have watched them write and write and write and through respect for audience and material come up with some of the finest shit I have ever played. I hope TV allows for the same thoroughness."
</p><p>
There's no word on when HBO might be looking to bring its Baldur's Gate 3 adaptation to air, but Mazin will be tied up with his The Last of Us show for a little while longer at least. While Mazin had <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-tv-showrunner-confirms-four-season-plan-says-no-way-to-wrap-things-up-in-three">previously confirmed a four-season plan</a> for his post-apocalyptic series, insisting there was "no way" its story could be wrapped up sooner, HBO boss Casey Bloys <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/despite-previously-insisting-there-was-no-way-hbos-the-last-of-us-show-could-be-wrapped-up-in-3-seasons-it-looks-like-itll-be-wrapped-up-in-3-seasons">recently indicated season three will be its last</a>. "It certainly seems that way," he told Deadline, "but on decisions like that, we will defer to the showrunners."
</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-is-getting-tv-treatment-from-hbos-the-last-of-us-showrunner]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["A lot of survival games are really boring": Abiotic Factor developer says many game makers are too focused on mechanics and not enough on vibes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-lot-of-survival-games-are-really-boring-abiotic-factor-developer-says-many-game-makers-are-too-focused-on-mechanics-and-not-enough-on-vibes</link>
            <guid>1427809</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>You should hear the wind in the trees, and see the fear in the scientist's eyes</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/abiotic-factor-header.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/abiotic-factor-header.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/abiotic-factor-header.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/abiotic-factor-header.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/abiotic-factor-header.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/abiotic-factor-header.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/abiotic-factor-header.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/abiotic-factor-header.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/abiotic-factor-header.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>PlayStack / Deep Field Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>"I think a lot of survival games are really boring," Geoff 'Zag' Keene, founder of Deep Field Games, developers of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/half-life">Half-Life</a> adjacent co-op survival game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/abiotic-factor">Abiotic Factor</a>, said in a recent interview. However, despite these strong words, please hold onto your spit take for just a moment.</p>
<p>It's not the first time Keene's said something like it and, in fact, in <a href="https://gamemakersnotebook.libsyn.com/abiotic-factor-with-geoff-zag-keene-and-henry-feltham">the episode of The AIAS Game Maker's Notebook</a>, he's responding to a question about when he said it to <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/survival-crafting/abiotic-factor-interview-survival-immersive-sim/">cheery RPS fanzine PC Gamer back in 2024</a>. So, please, calmly swallow your spit take liquid of choice, so I can explain why I'm reporting on something Keene originally said two years ago.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Abiotic Factor is a survival game that throws out a lot of what you find in stalwarts of the genre. Rather than building a life on an abandoned island by cutting down trees, planting crops, and using crafting benches to expand your toolbox until you've built a somewhat secure life for yourself in a virtual wilderness, you put on the pocket-protector-fitted lab coat of a scientist having a hell of a day in an underground facility going through a containment breach.</p>
<p>If you've played through Half-Life, the set up, at least, is a lot like the beginning of Gordon Freeman's adventure in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/black-mesa">Black Mesa</a>. There's been an incident, everything is on fire, and it's up to you to explore the facility and try to put things right. Scavenging resources from the environment to cobble together weapons and equipment as you go.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>PlayStack / Deep Field Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>While Keene starts from the same place in the podcast, that original quote from 2024, he takes his answer in a different direction, reflecting on a game that only came out at the end of last year. Perhaps you can guess what it is…</p><p>"I find a lot of survival games very boring," Keene continued, ignoring the future RPS writers who would need to provide context for why they're writing a news article about previously said words. "I find a lot of them... just ticking off boxes, and going through the motions. They have hunger, thirst, and all this other stuff, but they don't have anything of substance."</p>
<p><em>[If you're listening along, I'll let you in on a secret. I'm actually skipping ahead in the interview a bit here, so I can create a structural coherence to his answer that will have a more dramatic payoff.]</em></p>
<p>"I find a lot of survival games are just doing mechanics, flooding content in, and it's so meaningless," Keene continued, definitely not skipping anything out in between. "It's iterations of the same thing. I play one game and I play another and it looks different but it's got the same mechanics that I just played and no story to set it apart. I'll try out a survival game on Next Fest, my timer is 10 minutes per game before I'm like 'Eh, not interested.'"</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>PlayStack / Deep Field Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>While loaded up with <em>stuff</em> to do, what's missing, Keene says, is attention paid to the world. "We've all played Early Access survival game #27. [It's] in the forest with trees chopping, picking up rocks, but there's no wind or ambience in the air because it's not finished yet," Keene said. "If you're going to ship the game to the public, make sure it has some of the mood and the atmosphere. I don't know if I'm that good of a game developer, I don't think we've turned the survival genre on its head or anything, but we know how to [establish] our tone right, our mood, and the atmosphere of the game. Look at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-best-guns-tier-list">Arc Raiders</a>, that's like 90% of the battle, getting a place that people want to exist in."</p><p>Coming from a different place, I arrived at a similar conclusion when writing about Arc Raiders for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-is-a-good-shooter-but-its-also-where-i-go-for-a-walk-and-relax">last year's Advent Calendar</a>. Its take on a ruined Earth is somewhere I play, but often it's just a world I like to spend time in. Even with all the killer robots. There is a sometimes beautiful, sometimes mournful peace that hangs over the landscape. While there are many other extraction shooters, and several big names in the space before Arc Raiders came along, I've not found that peace playing the others. There is always a tension in the air, and, while there is a lot of fun to be had, I won't say <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/escape-from-tarkov">Escape from Tarkov</a> or Hunt: Showdown are chill games.</p>
<p>Also being interviewed was Henry Feltham, Abiotic factor's producer and narrative designer. He says how the team landed on two of the game's defining qualities: "The obvious ones we inverted. Being inside rather than outside, and being smart rather than strong. It doesn't take a lot to give the whole thing a completely different vibe."</p>
<p>I'd recommend listening to the whole interview. Not only do the developers dive into their many attempts to make the game without guns, there's also a story about DayZ creator Dean Hall pitching his game Icarus for Google Stadia while he snowboarded down a mountain.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-lot-of-survival-games-are-really-boring-abiotic-factor-developer-says-many-game-makers-are-too-focused-on-mechanics-and-not-enough-on-vibes]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>