<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:54:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wccftech’s Most Anticipated Strategy and Simulation Games of 2026 – The Year of Warhammer?]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-strategy-and-simulation-games-of-2026-the-year-of-warhammer/</link>
            <guid>1401064</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>2025 saw the return of one of the biggest strategy franchises in the genre, a spiritual successor to a series that fans are dying to see make a comeback, and a beloved game get its long-awaited remake. There was plenty to fill our pick of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-strategy-and-simulation-games-of-2025/">Best Strategy and Simulation Games of 2025</a>, and if everything on our list below makes it out before the end of 2026, putting together 2026's list of the best strategy games and best simulation games shouldn't be an issue either.</p>



<p><em>Other Wccftech's Most Anticipated 2026 Games per genre:</em>&nbsp;<em><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-role-playing-games-of-2026-legends-and-legacies/">Role-Playing Games</a></strong></em>,&nbsp;<strong><em><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-indie-games-of-2026/">Indie Games</a></em></strong>,&nbsp;<strong><em><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-platformers-of-2026-new-adventures-in-familiar-worlds/">Platformers</a></em></strong>,&nbsp;<strong><em><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-dlc-expansion-of-2026/">DLC/Expansion</a></em></strong>, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-action-games-of-2026-martial-artists-spies-super-heroes-and-criminals/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Action</em></a></strong>, <strong><em><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-shooter-games-2026-the-year-of-xbox-studios/">Shooters</a></em></strong>, <strong><em><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-horror-games-of-2026-a-new-era-of-dread/">Horror</a></em></strong>, <strong><em><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-sports-racing-games-of-2026-from-japan-to-a-galaxy-far-far-away/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sports/Racing</a></em></strong>, <strong><em><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-fighting-games-of-2026-tag-fighters-dominance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fighting</a></em></strong>, <strong><em><a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftech-most-anticipated-adventure-games-of-2026-against-fire-air-water-mind/">Adventure Games</a></em></strong></p>



<h2 id="h-star-wars-zero-company-tbc-2026-pc-ps5-xbox-series-x-s">Star Wars Zero Company (TBC 2026 - PC, PS5, Xbox Series X/S)</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Star-Wars-Zero-Company-Key-Art.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: Bit Reactor</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>If you wanted to give someone the elevator pitch for Star Wars: Zero Company, telling them 'It's XCOM but make it Star Wars,' would be enough to get any strategy game player with a mild love for Star Wars through the door.</p>



<p>We can't be sure if it'll be that exact of a match-up whenever Star Wars: Zero Company does arrive on PC and current-gen consoles sometime in 2026, but it has the precedent to be. Bit Reactor was founded by former XCOM developers, with the studio led by Greg Foerstch, former art director at Firaxis on XCOM and Marvel's Midnight Suns. With so much XCOM blood in the studio, it's exciting to think of the kind of gameplay and storytelling we'll get, all set within the Star Wars universe. Hopefully, it makes its proposed 2026 window, and we're playing it before the end of the year.</p>



<h2 id="h-ace-combat-8-wings-of-theve-tbc-2026-pc-ps5-xbox-series-x-s">Ace Combat 8: Wings of Theve (TBC 2026 - PC, PS5, Xbox Series X/S)</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Ace-Combat-8-Wings-of-Theve.png"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: Bandai Namco</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/ace-combat-8-wings-of-theve-announced-2026-launch-multiplayer-modes/">One of the bigger announcements of The Game Awards,</a> Bandai Namco's Ace Combat series is returning with Ace Combat 8: Wings of Theve. It's not necessarily a jet flying simulator, but its simulation-style approach is what has it in our picks for what we're looking forward to from simulation games this year.</p>



<p>It's the first mainline entry in the series in seven years, after <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ace-combat-7-skies-unknown/">2019's Ace Combat 7: Skies Unknown</a>, which has <a href="https://wccftech.com/ace-combat-7-3-million-copies-sequel-in-development/">gone on to sell over 3 million copies since then</a>. It may not be the best-selling series in Bandai Namco's portfolio, but there's a clear hunger for more Ace Combat and millions of players who will happily buy this new entry when it arrives. Hopefully, we'll know more about the game and its release soon.</p>



<h2 id="h-total-war-warhammer-40-000-tbc-2026-pc-ps5-xbox-series-x-s">Total War: Warhammer 40,000 (TBC 2026 - PC, PS5, Xbox Series X/S)</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Total-War-Warhammer-40K.png"></a><figcaption><em>Image credit: SEGA</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The Total War series is hitting a couple of 'firsts' with the coming release of Total War: Warhammer 40,000. It'll be the first time the Total War series makes the trip to the Warhammer 40,000 franchise, but perhaps more importantly for the series, Total War: Warhammer 40,000 will be the first time the Total War series makes its way to consoles, as it is also set to arrive on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X/S.</p>



<p>Announced at <a href="https://wccftech.com/total-war-warhammer-40000-announced-the-game-awards/">The Game Awards 2025</a> with the help of David Harbour from Stranger Things, the coming game will feature the Space Marines, Orks, Aeldari, and Astra Militarum as its four factions, and while it doesn't have an official release window yet, the announcement did include gameplay footage which hopefully means its far enough along that we could see it arrive in 2026.</p>



<h2 id="h-warhammer-40-000-dawn-of-war-iv-tbc-2026-pc">Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War IV (TBC 2026 - PC)</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Warhammer-40K-Dawn-of-War-IV.png"></a><figcaption><em>Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War IV. Image credit: Deep Silver</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>A second appearance from the Warhammer 40,000 franchise, though this time it's coming from its own series of RTS games instead of a different franchise making its first foray into the Warhammer 40,000 universe. The long-awaited Warhammer 40,000: Dawn of War IV was shown off multiple times in 2025, including with <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40000-dawn-of-war-iv-stunning-in-engine-trailer/">an incredible-looking in-engine gameplay trailer</a> that made the game look like it was ready for release very soon.</p>



<p>It doesn't have an official release date or release window yet, but we'll hopefully be hearing more about it soon.</p>



<h2 id="h-nova-roma-march-26-2026-pc">Nova Roma (March 26, 2026 - PC)</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Nova-Roma.png"></a><figcaption><em>Nova Roma. Image credit: Lion Shield</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Last on our main picks is Nova Roma, a new upcoming title from developer Lion Shield and publisher Hooded Horse, the latter of whom has made a name for themselves as having a keen eye for upcoming strategy titles. </p>



<p>This city builder asks you to appease the Roman gods and create a successful and thriving Ancient Roman empire, and if you feel like <a href="https://wccftech.com/anno-117-pax-romana-breaks-franchise-sales-records-outsells-call-of-duty/">Anno 117: Pax Romana</a> didn't scratch the Ancient Roman itch you have, then Nova Roma could be the game to do it. </p>


<div id="democracy-1517" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1517,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Most Anticipated Strategy and Simulation Game of 2026</strong></p></div>



<h2 id="h-honorable-mentions">Honorable Mentions</h2>



<p>Of course, we can't have every upcoming game in our main picks, but the following games are still worth paying attention to.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2838950/Game_of_Thrones_War_for_Westeros/">Game of Thrones: War for Westeros</a></li>



<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2956040/PVKK_Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant/">PVKK: Planetenverteidigungskanonenkommandant</a></li>



<li><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2432860/MENACE/">Menace</a></li>
</ul>





			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-strategy-and-simulation-games-of-2026-the-year-of-warhammer/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[César-Winning Composer Amine Bouhafa Used an “Alien Instrument” To Help Capture the Frozen World of DON’T NOD’s Aphelion]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cesar-winning-composer-amine-bouhafa-used-an-alien-instrument-to-help-capture-the-frozen-world-of-dont-nods-aphelion/</link>
            <guid>1401061</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>DON'T NOD has unveiled a new trailer for its upcoming game, <strong>Aphelion</strong>, at today's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dA4J6ByZPR0">New Game Plus Showcase,</a> which focused on the game's music and featured an interview with its award-winning composer, Amine Bouhafa.</p>



<p>You may have already heard Bouhafa's work in the 2021 short film <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5030456/?ref_=fn_t_1">The Summit of the Gods</a> or in 2025's <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt28326501/">The Little Sister</a>, though this is the first time the <strong>César-winning</strong> composer is working on a video game. "<em>This is my first time working on a video game, and I loved the way that [the Aphelion team] thought about the music and about the game. I'm enjoying the experience</em>," Bouhafa said in a press release.</p>



<p>Bouhafa narrates the trailer while gameplay from Aphelion is shown, as he describes how he approached writing the score for his first video game and how he used what he described as an "<em>alien instrument</em>" called a Cristal Baschet to capture the cold and frozen world of the game. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Aphelion | A Musical Journey - Amine Bouhafa" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GkTMEg1x6Qc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>"<em>It is an instrument that had been invented by the Baschet brothers in the mid-20th century. For me, it looks like an alien instrument. When you see it, you cannot even predict that it's a musical instrument</em>," Bouhafa says. Playing the Cristal Baschet involves dipping your hands in water and then running them along several crystal batons to create its sound. For Bouhafa, it was the perfect element to "<em>convey the frozen identity of the score</em>."</p>



<p>Bouhafa also talks about using the grand organ at the Saint-Eustache Church in Paris, which helped convey the bigger, grander, and sacred moments in Aphelion's narrative. It's all together an interesting behind-the-scenes look at how a major aspect of Aphelion is coming together. </p>



<p>DON'T NOD has suffered a string of commercial misses lately, with <a href="https://wccftech.com/lost-records-bloom-and-rage-missed-expectations-dont-nod-signs-deal-with-netflix/">last year's Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage missing expectations</a>, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/banishers-and-jusant-underperformed-dont-nod-admits/">Banishers: Ghosts of New Eden and Jusant both underperforming before that</a>. The studio does have a new game in the works with Netflix on top of Aphelion, which could prove fruitful, as it is based on "<em>a major IP</em>" within Netflix, but it'll be some time before that materializes into a full release - if Netflix even lets it get that far, since <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/806303/netflix-squid-game-unleashed-boss-fight-entertainment-studio-shut-down">its willing involvement in video games seems iffy</a>, at best.</p>



<p>Aphelion is currently set to arrive sometime in 2026 on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S. It'll also be available on Xbox Game Pass on day one.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/cesar-winning-composer-amine-bouhafa-used-an-alien-instrument-to-help-capture-the-frozen-world-of-dont-nods-aphelion/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Faces Fresh Labor Complaints Three Years After Union-Busting Settlement]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-union-complaint-switch-2-2000658263</link>
            <guid>1401055</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-christmas-holiday-sales-down-europe-uk-us-nintendo-2000658223">Nintendo of America</a> is once again facing labor complaints from one or more of its workers. <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/nintendo-teksystems-labor-complaints"><em>Game File</em> reports</a> that new charges accuse the Switch 2 manufacturer of violating sections of the National Labor Relations Act dealing with worker organizing and related union activities. These come just a few years after the company settled <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-splatoon-3-mario-strikers-working-conditions-u-1848918777">a previous labor charge</a> with a former tester for $26,000.</p> <p>The charges were filed on December 17 and January 6 against both Nintendo and tech contracting services firm Teksystems. They both list the following alleged violations of the NLRA: “8(a)(4) Discharge (including Layoff and Refusal to Hire)” and “8(a)(1) Concerted Activities (Retaliation, Discharge, Discipline).” Here’s an explanation of section 8(a)(1) in more detail from <em>Game File</em>:</p>

 <blockquote><p>8(a)(1) bars employers from interfering with or restraining employees from their right to self-organize, “to form, join, or assist labor organizations, to bargain collectively through representatives of their own choosing, and to engage in other concerted activities for the purpose of collective bargaining or other mutual aid or protection.”</p></blockquote> <p>While it’s unclear exactly what the nature of this particular labor dispute is over, it’s not the first time a Nintendo worker has taken the company to task over its labor practices with the NLRB. MacKenzie Clifton, who tested <em>Smash Bros. Ultimate</em> and other games at the company’s North American Headquarters, <a href="https://www.axios.com/2022/09/29/nintendo-tester-union-busting-whistleblower">told <em>Game File</em></a> in 2022 they believed their contract was cut short for <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-smash-bros-ultimate-union-busting-1849652308">mentioning unionization</a> to ex-President Doug Bowser during an online meeting.</p>

 <p>Nintendo ultimately settled that case for damages and back-pay that amounted to $26,000, but it led many then-current and former contractors at the company <a href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-america-switch-employee-treatment-unionize-nlr-1848828975">to speak out about feeling underpaid and exploited</a>. The company has since shifted some of its contractors to full-time roles while cutting others. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-customer-support-concern-following-outsourcing-decision-ahead-of-switch-2s-first-holiday-season"><em>IGN</em> reported</a> last fall that there were concerns among some at the company that Nintendo would be outsourcing more of its customer service work to overseas partners ahead of the Switch 2 holiday season.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-union-complaint-switch-2-2000658263]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aphelion composed by Amine Bouhafa; PS5 physical edition announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/aphelion-composed-by-amine-bouhafa-ps5-physical-edition-announced</link>
            <guid>1401052</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The soundtrack for cinematic science-fiction third-person <a title="Genres > Action [3,318 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,808 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Aphelion [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/aphelion">Aphelion</a></em> will be composed by Cesar award-winning French-Tunisian composer Amine Bouhafa, developer <a title="Companies > DON'T NOD [125 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dont-nod">DON’T NOD</a> announced. A physical edition of the game will also be distributed by <a title="Companies > Maximum Entertainment [252 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/maximum-entertainment">Maximum Entertainment</a> across North America, Europe, and Australia. <span id="more-1018338"></span></p><p>“This is my first time working on a video game, and I loved the way that [the <em>Aphelion</em> team] thought about the music and about the game,” Bouhafa said in a press release. “I’m enjoying the experience.”</p><p>DON’T NOD creative director Florent Guillaume added, “It has been a real pleasure to collaborate with Amine on Aphelion. We discovered his work through his composition for The Summit of the Gods and were immediately captivated by his talent for portraying the intimacy of characters caught up in a grand, epic adventure. Amine is a person with great emotional intelligence and sincere humanity. I hope that players will feel that connection and will be moved by their experience.”</p><p>Here are the latest details, via DON’T NOD:</p><blockquote><p>Amine Bouhafa is a Cesar award-winning French-Tunisian composer known for his scores on <em>Timbuktu</em> (2015), <em>The Summit of the Gods</em> (2021), and <em>The Little Sister</em> (2025). </p><p>Players will be able to experience Bouhafa’s unique blend of epic and intimate as it gives life to planet Persephone and supports Ariane and Thomas’s journeys in the game. His work easily and beautifully conveys the atmosphere and mood of the planet, the tension of the Nemesis, and the emotions between the characters. The video explores the ways in which Amine uses instruments such as the pipe organ and the unique cristal baschet in order to reflect the sacred feeling of the adventure, and to bring to life the frozen identity of Persephone</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>Aphelion</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,158 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,537 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,211 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1966410/Aphelion/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/aphelion/9nk8947z28xl" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> in 2026. It will also be available via Game Pass.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>A Musical Journey: Amine Bouhafa</span></h2><p><iframe title="Aphelion | A Musical Journey - Amine Bouhafa" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GkTMEg1x6Qc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/aphelion-composed-by-amine-bouhafa-ps5-physical-edition-announced]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Holy Crap, Look At This Freaking Game About Giant Fantasy Mechs]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/vampire-survivors-armored-core-vital-shell-mechs-2000658252</link>
            <guid>1401031</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Have you ever wondered what might happen if you put </span><i><span>Armored Core</span></i><span> and </span><i><span><a href="https://kotaku.com/castlevania-roguelike-vampire-survivors-steam-itch-io-1848402308">Vampire Survivors</a></span></i><span> into opposite ends of the teleporter from </span><i><span>The Fly</span></i><span> and flipped the switch? The resulting mash-up would probably look a lot like </span><i><span>Vital Shell</span></i><span>, a game by solo developer Marvin Wizard released to Steam on January 8.</span></p> <p><i><span>Vital Shell</span></i><span>, fortunately, is less a monstrous example of scientific hubris and more a competent, top-down arena shooter that combines fantasy mechs with automatic battling mechanics and adds an aesthetic splash of PlayStation 1 visuals and ambient jungle music for good vibes. I spent a few rounds running the game through its paces after noticing its launch this morning and, folks, it’s pretty dang fun.</span></p>

  <p><span>If you’ve played </span><i><span>Vampire Survivors</span></i><span>, you should mostly know what to expect here. </span><i><span>Vital Shell</span></i><span> places players in control of a giant robot and tasks them with destroying everything in their wake. What this looks like in practice is kiting waves of enemy hordes around a nondescript battlefield, persisting long enough to level up, and building an ever-improving kit of weaponry and upgrades for tackling the challenges ahead.</span></p>

 <p><span>As fun as </span><i><span>Vital Shell</span></i><span> is gameplay-wise, it really excels in presentation. The level-up screen looks like something out of early installments of </span><i><span>Armored Core</span></i><span>, and the clean 3D graphics make it easy to distinguish friend from foe during raucous battles. Marvin Wizard also developed the game</span> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3741860/view/506206686159048296"><span>with a “console-first approach” from the beginning</span></a><span>, which means the menus are snappy and easy to navigate via controller. I first tried playing </span><i><span>Vital Shell</span></i><span> with mouse and keyboard but quickly switched to my trusty DualSense and haven’t looked back.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000658254" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000658254"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000658254">MarvinWizard</figcaption></figure> <p><i><span>Vital Shell</span></i><span> is now available on Steam for $4.79 (the price goes up to $5.99 after January 21), alongside</span> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3928280/Vital_Shell_Demo_Disc/"><span>a demo-disc-style preview</span></a><span> if you want to try before you buy. It’s a solo affair at the moment, but Marvin Wizard is exploring the addition of co-op in a future update.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/vampire-survivors-armored-core-vital-shell-mechs-2000658252]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DICE Awards 2026—All Award Nominees]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dice-awards-2026-all-award-nominees/</link>
            <guid>1401028</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Academy of Interactive Arts &amp; Sciences (AIAS) has announced the full list of nominees for the 2026 DICE Awards.</p>



<p>This year’s awards feature 65 games across 23 awards. Of the nominees, Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 and Ghost of Yotei lead the way with eight nominations each. Other games receiving multiple nominations include Dispatch (6), ARC Raiders (6), Blue Prince (5), and Death Stranding: On the Beach (4).</p>







<p>As far as the big award of the night, Game of the Year, five games are up for it. Those games are Clair Obscur: Expedition 33, Dispatch, ARC Raiders, Blue Prince, and Ghost of Yotei.</p>



<h6>MORE DICE: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-wins-game-of-the-year-at-dice-awards-all-winners-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Astro Bot Wins Game of the Year at DICE Awards – All Winners Revealed</a></h6>



<p>The 29th Annual DICE Awards <a href="https://www.interactive.org/awards/29th_dice_awards_finalists_93k3p1.asp" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">take place on Thursday, February 12</a> at 11pm ET/8pm PT from Las Vegas, Nevada. It will be hosted by Kind Funny founder Greg Miller and Stella Chung, and air on YouTube.</p>



<p>You can check out the full list of nominees below, and leave your thoughts on what games you feel deserve the recognition as the best of 2025 down in the comments and over in the official <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming will have full coverage of the awards as well as be live in Las Vegas for the annual DICE Summit. </p>







<h2 id="h-dice-awards-2026-nominees">DICE Awards 2026 Nominees</h2>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Animation</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Monster Hunter Wilds</li>



<li>South of Midnight</li>



<li>The Midnight Walk</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Art Direction</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Dispatch</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>The Midnight Walk</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Character</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 – Esquie</li>



<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 – Maelle</li>



<li>Dispatch – Courtney/Invisigal</li>



<li>Dispatch – Robert Robertson III/Mecha Man</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei – Atsu&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Original Music Composition</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Herdling</li>



<li>Mario Kart World</li>



<li>Sword of the Sea</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Audio Design</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Arc Raiders</li>



<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Lumines Arise</li>



<li>Split Fiction</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Story</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Consume Me</li>



<li>despelote</li>



<li>South of Midnight</li>



<li>The Drifter</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Technical Achievement</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Arc Raiders</li>



<li>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</li>



<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Donkey Kong Bananza</li>



<li>DOOM: The Dark Ages</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Action Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Absolum</li>



<li>Arc Raiders</li>



<li>DOOM: The Dark Ages</li>



<li>Hades II</li>



<li>Ninja Gaiden 4</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Adventure Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Dispatch</li>



<li>Donkey Kong Bananza</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Hollow Knight: Silksong</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Family Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>LEGO® Party!</li>



<li>LEGO® Voyagers</li>



<li>Lumines Arise</li>



<li>MARVEL Cosmic Invasion</li>



<li>POPUCOM</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Fighting Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>2XKO</li>



<li>Capcom Fighting Collection 2</li>



<li>FATAL FURY: City of the Wolves</li>



<li>Mortal Kombat: Legacy Kollection</li>



<li>WWE 2K25</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Racing Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>EA SPORTS F1® 25</li>



<li>Kirby Air Riders</li>



<li>Mario Kart World</li>



<li>Wheel World</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Role-Playing Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector</li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li>



<li>Monster Hunter Wilds</li>



<li>The Outer Worlds 2</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Sports Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>EA SPORTS FC™ 26</li>



<li>PGA Tour 2k25</li>



<li>MLB® The Show™ 25</li>



<li>NBA 2k26</li>



<li>Rematch</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Strategy/Simulation Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>The Alters</li>



<li>Drop Duchy</li>



<li>Europa Universalis V</li>



<li>The King is Watching</li>



<li>StarVaders</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Immersive Reality Technical Achievement</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Ghost Town</li>



<li>Hotel Infinity</li>



<li>Marvel’s Deadpool VR</li>



<li>Star Wars: Beyond Victory – A Mixed Reality Playset</li>



<li>Unloop</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Immersive Reality Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked</li>



<li>Ghost Town</li>



<li>Marvel’s Deadpool VR</li>



<li>The Midnight Walk</li>



<li>Thief VR: Legacy of Shadow</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement for an Independent Game</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Baby Steps</li>



<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Consume Me</li>



<li>despelote</li>



<li>Dispatch</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Mobile Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Persona5: The Phantom X&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</li>



<li>Umamusume: Pretty Derby</li>



<li>WHAT THE CLASH?</li>



<li>Where Winds Meet</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Online Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Arc Raiders</li>



<li>Battlefield 6</li>



<li>Mario Kart World</li>



<li>Marvel Rivals</li>



<li>Split Fiction</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Game Design</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Arc Raiders</li>



<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Hades II</li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li>



<li>Öoo</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Game Direction</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Hades II</li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Arc Raiders</li>



<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Dispatch</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>
</ul>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/dice-awards-2026-all-award-nominees/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Towerborne launches February 26 for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/towerborne-launches-february-26-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>1401025</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Side-scrolling action RPG brawler leaving Early Access.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Side-scrolling <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,921 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> brawler <em><a title="Games > Towerborne [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/towerborne">Towerborne</a></em> will leave Early Access and launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,158 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,537 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,211 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2458830/Towerborne/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/p/towerborne/9p7tlx79s7n7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a> on February 26, publisher <a title="Companies > Xbox Game Studios [959 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/xbox-game-studios">Xbox Game Studios</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Stoic [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/stoic">Stoic</a> <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2026/01/08/towerborne-launches-february-26-with-massive-full-game-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a>. It will cost $24.99 for the standard edition and $29.99 for the Deluxe Edition. It will also be available via Game Pass. <span id="more-1018230"></span></p><p><em>Towerborne</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2458830/Towerborne/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on September 10, 2024, followed by Game Preview for Xbox Series and PC via <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/store/p/towerborne/9p7tlx79s7n7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a> on April 29, 2025. The PlayStation 5 version is newly announced.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Microsoft:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About the Game</strong></p><p><em>Towerborne</em> is an exciting <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [1,193 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> action RPG brawler. Rise again as an Ace, an immortal warrior reborn to defend the Belfry against the darkness beyond its walls. Journey across a crumbling world, uncover the mystery of the fallen City of Numbers, and push back the corruption threatening humanity’s <a title="Genres > Survival [499 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a>.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong><a title="Companies > Mas [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>ter the Mayhem</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> classic combo-based brawler combat combined with a modern <a title="Genres > RPG [17,925 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a>. Customize your Ace with powerful gear, experiment with diverse combat styles, and refine your skills through relentless battles. Every fight makes you stronger, every victory opens new strategies, and every weapon reshapes your journey.</li><li><strong>Fight Your Way</strong> – Whether you want quick pick-up-and-play sessions or intricate systems to master, <em>Towerborne</em> lets you choose your play style. Its fast-paced, responsive combat rewards timing and creativity, making every encounter feel fresh and challenging as you grow stronger.</li><li><strong>Grow Stronger Together</strong> – Join forces with up to three other Aces* or venture solo with Umbra lending unique abilities to your side. Teamwork amplifies the chaos and the thrill, where synergy and strategy make the difference between victory and defeat. Rally together to fight as one.</li><li><strong>Take an Unforgettable Journey</strong> – <em>Towerborne</em> expands beyond combat with a compelling Story Campaign designed to spark excitement and fuel unstoppable <a title="Genres > Action [3,318 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>. For players who crave more than battles, <em>Towerborne</em>‘s full story campaign brings to life the lore, characters, and stakes of the Belfry’s survival. Explore, progress, and uncover the world at your own pace and take your Ace’s journey offline then reconnect online to fight alongside friends without missing a beat.</li></ul><p><strong>Version 1.0 Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>A Complete Story and Final Showdown</strong> – We have an updated and complete story, a full narrative arc featuring a major antagonist, new side quests, and an overhauled Bounty Board.</li><li><strong>Who’s the Boss?</strong> – We’ve added two new bosses, including the big bad boss (that would be the antagonist we mentioned), lieutenants, and umbra enemies.</li><li><strong>Fully Reworked Difficulty System</strong> – We’ve added an entirely new difficulty system, a complete rebalance of the game, and a new ‘Brutal’ difficulty for those who enjoy breaking controllers and swearing at their screens.</li><li><strong>Map It Out</strong> – we’ve reworked and reimagined the World Map and added a new coastal biome.</li><li><strong>New Encounters and Combat Challenges</strong> – We’ve added new gear and player abilities, a new Forge system with the ability to modify, upgrade, and re-roll stats</li><li><strong>Is there more?</strong> – Yes, there’s more! We have new music from the man/myth/maestro Austin Wintory, a bunch of quality of life and bug fixes, no more cosmetic purchasing—you can acquire all cosmetics free through gameplay, we added a TON of new cosmetics, and we’ve included multiple save slots and the ability to import your current character and associated loot.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/towerborne-launches-february-26-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rockstar's Battle With Union Over Fired Devs Goes To Court]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rockstars-battle-with-union-over-fired-devs-goes-to-court/1100-6537286/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1401022</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537286">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Near the end of October 2025, Rockstar fired over thirty devs in the United Kingdom and Canada over what it called "gross misconduct." The Independent Workers' Union of Great Britain <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rockstar-accused-of-firing-grand-theft-auto-devs-over-union-organization/1100-6535862/" data-ref-id="1100-6535862">accused Rockstar of union busting</a> for laying off workers who were organizing with the union. Both sides have held firm since the initial accusations, and now the battle has gone to court in the UK.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/fired-rockstar-games-developers-fight-for-payroll-relief-at-employment-tribunal-hearing/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Video Games Chronicle</a>, Rockstar and the IWGB went before the court earlier this week, where the latter requested that the fired workers be given "interim relief" while the legal drama plays out. If granted, that would place the affected workers back on Rockstar's payroll and allow some to keep their visas that were reliant on their jobs. The court will reportedly decide on the matter before the end of the week.</p><p>The IWGB pledged to continue fighting for the workers regardless of the court's decision, while Rockstar reiterated its position that the workers broke the company's policy.</p><p>"We have consistently made clear that we took necessary action against a group of individuals across the UK and Canada who discussed highly confidential information, including relating to game features from upcoming and unannounced titles, in an insecure and public social channel," a Rockstar spokesperson told <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/union-asks-judge-to-grant-fired-gta-6-devs-interim-relief-at-preliminary-tribunal-hearing-rockstar-denies-claims" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IGN</a>. "This was a breach of long-standing and well-understood confidentiality policies. This channel contained at least 25 non-Rockstar employees, including employees of competitor game developers, a video games industry journalist, as well as dozens of anonymous, unidentifiable members. Meanwhile, employees who posted union-supportive messages, but who did not breach confidentiality policies, were not dismissed."</p><p>There is some question as to whether the alleged break of confidentiality had anything to do with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/union-asks-judge-to-grant-fired-gta-6-devs-interim-relief-at-preliminary-tribunal-hearing-rockstar-denies-claims" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Grand Theft Auto 6</a>. A report from November 2025 noted that the employees in question shared details about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-details-emerge-about-fired-rockstar-devs-and-the-messages-they-shared/1100-6536482/" data-ref-id="1100-6536482">Rockstar's rule changes for Slack</a>, which eliminated most of the personal and non-work channels. That story also stated that Rockstar's internal security is so tight that employees can't even check their work emails unless they are in the office.</p><p>This case may boil down to whether Rockstar can prove that the employees shared sensitive details that violated their terms of employment. The case has drawn a considerable amount of attention worldwide. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/united-kingdoms-ministers-will-look-into-rockstars-dev-firings-says-prime-minister/1100-6536840/" data-ref-id="1100-6536840">UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer and MP Chris Murray</a> have both pledged to look into it, but the legal battle may take a long time to play out.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rockstars-battle-with-union-over-fired-devs-goes-to-court/1100-6537286/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[13 Years Later, Hot Toys Finally Gives Arkham Origins' Batman the Figure He Deserves]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/13-years-later-hot-toys-finally-gives-arkham-origins-batman-the-figure-he-deserves</link>
            <guid>1401007</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">2013's Batman: Arkham Origins may not be the most critically beloved entry in the series, but many fans would argue it's the game with the best Batman costume design. Now Hot Toys is finally giving that costume its due with a truly stunning 1/6 scale figure. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Check out the slideshow gallery below for an early look at Hot Toys' Batman: Arkham Origins figure:</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Hot Toys Batman: Arkham Origins 1/6 Scale Figure Gallery</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This figure stands an impressive 12.7 inches tall and features a detailed recreation of the character model from the game. The head boasts individually rotating eyeballs and interchangeable faceplates that allow for different expressions.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The figure also includes various other accessories you'd expect, including Batman's various gadgets and weapons, electric gauntlets, and interchangeable hands. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">This is hardly Hot Toys' first time exploring the Arkham universe. In the past, they've released figures based on Batman's Arkham City and Arkham Knight designs, along with several of the alternate suits from those games and villains like Joker and Harley Quinn.  As for Arkham Origins specifically, Hot Toys previously tackled Deathstroke (who makes a cameo appearance in the photos above) and Batman's armored XE Suit.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Batman: Arkham Origins figure is priced at $300 and is available to <a href="https://zdcs.link/a56E3L?object_uuid=ad4192bd-15a0-404c-b164-40246c1dbabd&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">preorder on Sideshow Collectibles</a>. The figure is expected to release between January and June of 2027.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more Hot Toys fun, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/this-stunning-hot-toys-figure-recreates-dcs-most-iconic-joker-cover">their Killing Joke-inspired Joker figure</a> and their massive <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-fantastic-four-first-steps-galactus-finally-revealed-thanks-to-new-hot-toys-figure">The Fantastic Four: First Steps Galactus figure</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Jesse is a mild-mannered staff writer for IGN. Allow him to lend a machete to your intellectual thicket by</em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jschedeen.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em> </em><u><em>following @jschedeen on BlueSky</em></u></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/13-years-later-hot-toys-finally-gives-arkham-origins-batman-the-figure-he-deserves]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Detroit: Become Human sales top 15 million]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/detroit-become-human-sales-top-15-million</link>
            <guid>1401004</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Cinematic adventure game achieves new milestone.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Total sales for <em>Detroit: Become Human</em> have surpassed 15 million units across <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,633 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,211 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, developer <a title="Companies > Quantic Dream [112 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/quantic-dream">Quantic Dream</a> <a href="https://pressreleases.triplepointpr.com/2026/01/08/detroit-become-human-surpasses-15-million-units-sold-worldwide/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-1018309"></span></p><p><em>Detroit: Become Human</em> first launched for PlayStation 4 in May 2018, followed by PC via the <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/product/detroit-become-human/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Epic Games Store</a> in December 2019 and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/960990/Beyond_Two_Souls/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Steam</a> in June 2020. <!--more--></p><p>“More than seven years after its release, <em>Detroit: Become Human</em> continues to resonate with audiences, bringing always more players together around the world,” said Quantic Dream president, writer, and director David Cage in a press release. “What began as a reflection on choice, empathy, and humanity has become a shared journey for tens of millions of players. This milestone belongs to the community that believed in its story and carried it forward, and everyone at the studio is deeply grateful for their continued support.”</p><p>Quantic Dream CEO and head of publishing Guillaume de Fondaumiere added, “This new milestone highlights the emotional resonance and lasting cultural impact of <em>Detroit: Become Human</em>. The game’s continued success across platforms, generations and continents speaks to the power of stories that place players at the heart of the experience, inviting them not only to play, but to reflect, question, and engage long after the credits roll.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>Detroit: Become Human</em>, the award-winning video game production from Quantic Dream, is finally available on Steam! Featuring world-renowned actors including Jesse Williams (<em>Grey’s Anatomy</em>), Clancy Brown (<em>Carnivale</em>), Lance Henriksen (<em>Aliens</em>), Bryan Dechart (<em>True Blood</em>) and Valorie Curry (<em>Twilight</em>).</p><p>What makes us human?</p><p>Detroit 2038. Technology has evolved to a point where human like androids are everywhere. They speak, move and behave like human beings, but they are only machines serving humans.</p><p>Play three distinct androids and see a world at the brink of chaos—perhaps our future—through their eyes. Your very decisions will dramatically alter how the game’s intense, branching narrative plays out.</p><p>You will face moral dilemmas and decide who lives or dies. With thousands of choices and dozens of possible endings, how will you affect the future of Detroit and humanity’s destiny?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Play Your Part in a Gripping Narrative</strong> – Enter a world where moral dilemmas and difficult decisions can turn android slaves into world-changing revolutionaries. Discover what it means to be human from the perspective of an outsider—and see the world through the eyes of a machine.</li><li><strong>Their Lives, Your Choices</strong> – Shape an ambitious branching narrative, where your decisions not only determine the fate of the three main characters, but that of the entire city of Detroit. How you control Kara, Connor and Markus can mean life or death—and if one of them pays the ultimate price, the story still continues…</li><li><strong>Countless Paths, Countless Endings</strong> – Every decision you make, no matter how minute, affects the outcome of the story. No playthrough will be exactly the same: replay again and again to discover a totally different conclusion.</li><li><strong>Fully Optimized for PC</strong> – <em>Detroit: Become Human</em> is brought to PC with stunning graphics, 4K resolution, 60 frames per second framerate and full integration of both mouse/keyboard and gamepad controls for the most complete <em>Detroit: Become Human</em> experience to date.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/detroit-become-human-sales-top-15-million]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Switch 2 Joy-Cons Are Here And They're Extremely Underwhelming]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-switch-2-joy-cons-are-here-and-theyre-extremely-underwhelming/1100-6537284/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1401001</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537284">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nintendo has revealed its first set of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-joy-con-2-light-purple-light-green-preorder-roundup/1100-6537276/" data-ref-id="1100-6537276">new Joy-Con controllers</a> for the Nintendo Switch 2 and I'll be honest, I'm a bit disappointed.</p><p>To be clear, I'm not disappointed (or surprised) by the $100 price tag, as the original Switch Joy-Cons are still $90, the standard Switch 2 Joy-Cons are $100, and all gaming hardware is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-much-will-steam-machine-cost-heres-what-valve-had-to-say-about-pricing/1100-6536161/" data-ref-id="1100-6536161">pretty expensive</a> right now. No, it's not the cost that bothers me, but rather how little these new Joy-Cons differentiate themselves from the pair that already exist.</p><p>Similar to the original Switch's Joy-Cons, it appears that the various colorways for the Switch 2 versions will feature two different colors; in the case of these newly announced Joy-Cons, those colors are a bright, pastel purple and a vibrant aqua that the company refers to as "Light Green." Despite not fully agreeing with Nintendo on what constitutes light green, I actually really like these new colors. It took a long time for me to care for any of the original Switch's Joy-Con colorways enough to purchase them, as the vast majority are extremely saturated and don't feature color combinations that I feel pair well together. I was so starved for options, in fact, that I purchased the Animal Crossing: New Horizons Switch largely because I thought it featured the best Joy-Con colors available. In that sense, these new Joy-Cons definitely feel like an improvement.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4632816-switch2newjoycons.png" data-ref-id="1300-4632816" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4632816-switch2newjoycons.png" data-ref-id="1300-4632816"></a><figcaption>The new Switch 2 Joy-Cons.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4632816-switch2newjoycons.png"></figure><p>However, the problem with these new Joy-Cons is that, for the most part, you won't actually <em>see</em> these colors. When using your Switch 2 in handheld mode or with the Joy-Con grip, the strips of color on the inner portion of the controllers are entirely hidden. So while these colors might be pretty, it's a bit disappointing that they are essentially relegated to two small rings around the thumbsticks.</p><p>So sure, if you are just looking to pick up a second pair of Joy-Cons simply to have a second pair of Joy-Cons you might as well grab these; there's at least a <em>small </em>difference between them and the standard red and blue controllers that come with the console. That said, it's just a bummer that they lack the same level of whimsy, creativity, and variation as the original Switch's Joy-Cons.</p><p>The good news is you can (kinda) remedy this issue so long as you're willing to spend an extra $20. Shortly after the Joy-Cons were revealed, gaming accessories company Dbrand announced it had already created a <a href="https://dbrand.com/shop/skins/nintendo-switch-2-skins#/customizer/details" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Joy-Con skin</a> that perfectly matches the new colorway. It's not an official fix, sure, but to <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/wario64.bsky.social/post/3mbwuee3lgt2p" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">quote the brand</a>, it "does what Nintendon't."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-switch-2-joy-cons-are-here-and-theyre-extremely-underwhelming/1100-6537284/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega Sues Guy Who Uploaded Game Soundtracks To Spotify Before They Did]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/sega-persona-3-reload-soundtrack-lawsuit/</link>
            <guid>1400995</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
      <p>A couple years ago, the <em>Persona 3 Reload</em> soundtrack <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/OkBuddyPersona/comments/1aoluhb/comment/kq0edbv/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>was uploaded to Spotify</u></a>. The issue? Developer Atlus hadn't released the album digitally. That album, and <em>Shin Megami Tensei: Strange Journey</em>'s soundtrack, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PERSoNA/comments/1avlnqj/why_the_heck_did_they_take_the_reloaded_ost_off/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>were uploaded by a random guy and quickly removed</u></a>—likely from a DMCA request—in 2024. Now, Sega is suing over it.</p><p><a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/978185320/Sega-suing-over-unauthorized-music-uploads?ref=aftermath.site"><u>In a lawsuit filed Thursday in Florida</u></a>, Sega said it discovered in March 2024 that a person with the username Ziodyne (<a href="https://megamitensei.fandom.com/wiki/Ziodyne?ref=aftermath.site"><u>a reference to a skill in Shin Megami Tensei</u></a>) <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/OkBuddyPersona/comments/1b4zbvx/fatlus_hit_ziodyne_with_demonic_decree/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>uploaded the two soundtracks</u></a> to different music platforms, like Apple Music, Spotify, and Amazon. That person used a music distribution service called DistroKid to get the soundtracks on the platforms, offering them for sale and streaming. Sega says the person "received significant revenue and profits from the unauthorized sales," and that the person used the <em>Persona 3 Reload</em> logo to "deceive or mislead consumers concerning the source of the sound recordings."</p><p>DistroKid is a distribution service that advertises itself as an easy way to get music on all different platforms—Instagram, Spotify, Amazon, Tidal, and more. It charges a yearly fee, collects payments from streaming and sales, then pays out the artist. The company has been <a href="https://www.musicbusinessworldwide.com/distrokid-faces-potential-class-action-lawsuit-over-how-it-handles-takedown-requests/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>sued at least nine times for how it handles DMCA takedown requests</u></a>, failing to pay out artists, and other reasons. Many of these cases are pendings, but a few have been dismissed.</p><p>Sega wasn't offering these soundtracks digitally yet, but people were looking for them. People immediately noticed them, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/OkBuddyPersona/comments/1aoluhb/comment/kq0edbv/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>according to several different Reddit posts</u></a>, which showed the <em>Persona 3 Reload</em> soundtrack as having more than 26,000 monthly listens on Spotify. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/OkBuddyPersona/comments/1bpxur5/ziodyne_has_burning_mans_soul_as_a_song_on/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>On Reddit</u></a>, another screenshot of Ziodyne's page showed more than 134,000 monthly listens, including the popular <em>Burning Men's Soul</em> from the <em>Persona Trinity Soul</em> anime. Sega says in its lawsuit that it subpoenaed Apple, Spotify, and DistroKid to determine Ziodyne’s identity.&nbsp;</p><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PERSoNA/comments/1boozwb/first_part_of_the_persona_3_reload_ost_is_now/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Commenters on Reddit</u></a> called Ziodyne an "unsung hero" for getting the music out there: "They reuploaded it like 3 times despite it getting taken down each time what a legend," one person wrote. <a href="https://megamitensei.fandom.com/wiki/Burning_Men%27s_Soul?ref=aftermath.site"><u>Ziodyne appears to have been beloved by the Reddit community</u></a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/OkBuddyPersona/comments/1bhcwy5/they_took_my_baby_boy_ziodyne_again/?ref=aftermath.site"><u>for his perseverance</u></a> in uploading Atlus' music, which was often otherwise hard to find online.</p><p>"Defendant has taken advantage of a set of circumstances, including the anonymity and mass reach afforded by the Internet and social media, coupled with the cover afforded by international borders, to violate Sega’s intellectual property rights with impunity," Sega's lawyers wrote in the complaint.</p><p>Sega is looking for "at least $60,000" in monetary damages, according to the complaint. The counts listed in the complaint include copyright infringement, trademark infringement, false designation of origin, and unfair competition.</p><p>Since the unauthorized version was removed, Sega and Atlus have uploaded their own digital version of the <em>Persona 3 Reload</em> soundtrack to music platforms. <em>Strange Journey</em>'s soundtrack doesn't appear to be available digitally.</p><p>Aftermath has reached out to Sega of America and Ziodyne for comment.</p>
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/sega-persona-3-reload-soundtrack-lawsuit/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Falcom Reiterates Support For Switch 2, Currently Working On New Port]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/falcom-reiterates-support-for-switch-2-currently-working-on-new-port</link>
            <guid>1400983</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="6cf4017f02177"><a title="Trails Beyond the Horizon opening movie" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/6cf4017f02177/trails-beyond-the-horizon-opening-movie.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: NIS America</em></figcaption></figure><p>Nihon Falcom has reiterated its support for the Nintendo Switch 2 today, and it plans to self-publish more major titles on the newest Nintendo console in the coming years.</p>
<p>That's according to a report from <a href="https://gamebiz.jp/news/418652">GameBiz</a> (translated by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/trails-developer-nihon-falcom-to-shift-focus-on-increasing-number-of-released-titles-per-year-and-publishing-more-switch-2-ports-six-unannounced-titles-currently-in-development/">Automaton Media</a>), where the creator of the <strong>Ys</strong> and <strong>Trails</strong> series has also teased that its currently working on a brand new Nintendo Switch 2 port of one of their existing titles. What that is, we don't know yet, but we'll likely find out at some point this year.</p>
<p>Sales for the company increased by 3.5% year on year, which works out to around $16.7 million USD, in 2025. Operating profit is up 8.1%, while net profit has increased by 6.0%. These successes include the international launches for titles such as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_heroes_trails_through_daybreak_ii">Trails through Daybreak II</a>, the worldwide release of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/trails-in-the-sky-1st-chapter-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter</a>, and the Japanese release of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/ys-x-proud-nordics">Ys X: Proud Nordics</a>.</p>
<p>Another big goal for the company is to broaden the company's reach, and while the Switch 2 will certainly help with that, it's also looking to do that with more multiplatform releases and multi-language support — for the latter, both Ys X: Proud Nordics' international release and the upcoming <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/trails-in-the-sky-2nd-chapter-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Trails in the Sky 2nd Chapter</a> will include English, French, German, and Spanish subtitles.</p>
<p>While Falcom has been pretty busy in recent years, much of its focus has been on ports, which it says "had a limited impact on business performance."</p>

<p>Now the company aims to release two new titles per year over the next three years, and it's currently working on six unannounced titles; two of these are new ports (including the Switch 2 one), and three are brand new games, which includes a new <strong>Trails</strong>, a new <strong>Ys</strong>, and a new <strong>Tokyo Xanadu</strong> game.</p>
<p>Yes, 2025 was a particularly big year for the legendary Japanese developer, 2026 doesn't look to be any slower. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-heroes-trails-beyond-the-horizon">The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon</a> launches just next week (and psst, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/the-legend-of-heroes-trails-beyond-the-horizon">it's pretty darn good on Switch 2</a>), and we have Ys X: Proud Nordics' international release on 20th February.</p>
<p>Then, later in the year, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/ys_memoire_revelations_in_celceta">Ys Memoire: Revelations in Celceta</a> launches in English, with Trails in the Sky 2nd Chapter launching in the Fall. <em>Phew</em>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Are you excited to see more Falcom titles on Switch 2? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:195674,195408 @ 1767908835 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/falcom-reiterates-support-for-switch-2-currently-working-on-new-port]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ed Greenwood's RealmsBound Project Brings New Depth to Dungeons & Dragons' Forgotten Realms]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/ed-greenwoods-realmsbound-project-brings-new-depth-to-dungeons-dragons-forgotten</link>
            <guid>1400980</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The creator of the most popular <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a> setting has announced a new project. Ed Greenwood, the creator of the Forgotten Realms, has announced Realmsbound, a series of books designed to flesh out the iconic setting further.</p><p>According to its official <a href="https://mythmakers.com/realmsbound/dalelands" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">web page</a>, Realmsbound is a project intended to bring new lore, stories, and adventures to the land of the Forgotten Realms. These books will be available on DMs Guild both as PDFs and in physical copies through print-on-demand.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/realmsbound-ed-greenwood-promo-banner.jpg?itok=UKDj-1q4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="700" height="394">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/realmsbound-ed-greenwood-promo-banner.jpg?itok=bUtSP3G5 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="700" height="394">
                  

  </picture><p>The books in question will flesh out certain locations in the setting and highlight areas that have never been seen before. As the page itself states, this is not a journey into uncharted lands, but a deepening of what was always there, waiting to be found.</p><p>This is an admirable project given the current state of the Forgotten Realms in <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>. Despite decades of supplements, &nbsp;prewritten adventure modules like <em>Waterdeep: Dragon Heist</em>, award-winning video games like <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/baldurs-gate-3" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Baldur's Gate 3</em></a>, and one <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-honor-among-thieves-review-adaptation-that-understands-its-roots" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">feature film</a>, the worldbuilding and lore are centered on one small part: the Sword Coast. Even the new <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/dungeons-dragons-forgotten-realms-heroes-of-faerun-and-adventures-in-faerun-review" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">2024 supplements</a> stay within this region of the land of Faerun.</p><p>This is where the Realmsbound project comes in. The first region getting the long-awaited glow-up is the Dalelands. The first book, <em>Guide to the Dalelands</em>, expands upon the material in the <em>Adventures in Faerun</em> book, adding more texture and history to the region. This will include detailed maps of regions like Cormanthor, as well as information on local economies, secretive factions, and echoes of long-lost power.</p><p>The second supplement, included in this book, is a Player's Guide meant to help ground players in the setting. The three remaining supplements focus on other aspects of play. <em>Inn Sites of the Dalelands</em> focuses on social encounters, local holidays and regional events, fleshed out NPCs and inns, and casual mini-games. <em>Delves of the Dalelands</em> focuses on areas of interest full of legendary danger.</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dungeons-dragons-dalelands-promo-art.jpg?itok=qKqFs3gT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="660">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dungeons-dragons-dalelands-promo-art.jpg?itok=pqQ3i1OK 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="1200" height="660">
                  

  </picture><p>Lastly, <em>Adventures in the Dalelands</em> is an anthology book. It will contain several prewritten adventures up to level 12. All of these books will be released over the course of a year. Guide to the Dalelands will release in Q1 2026, Inn Sites releases in Q2 2026, Delves releases in Q3 2026, and Adventures will release in Q4 2026.</p><p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.polygon.com/dnd-realmsbound-forgotten-realms-2026/" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">Polygon</a>, Greenwood spoke more about the Realmsbound project. He states that, much like the original creation of the Forgotten Realms, the project is a collaborative effort. The team includes creative director Eric Menge, who produced the Moonshae campaign for Adventurer's League, and senior designer Savannah Houston McIntyre (<em>City of Greyhawk</em>).</p><p>Ed Greenwood returning to expand on a setting he helped create isn't unheard of for a <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> setting. The creator of Eberron, Keith Baker, has published multiple supplements as well on DMs Guild for the game's latest edition. His latest book, <em>Frontiers of Eberron: Quickstone</em>, expands upon the latest 2024 <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/eberron-forge-of-artificer-review-minor-tweaks-overall-but-fun-new-subclass" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow"><em>Forge of the Artificer</em></a> supplement, adding new player options and more history to the setting's Western Frontier.</p><p>At the time of writing, it is unclear how much the Realmsbound supplements will be sold for. It can be speculated that, based on the current prices of theEberron books, they may be sold for around $35 for PDFs and $75 for physical copies.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/ed-greenwoods-realmsbound-project-brings-new-depth-to-dungeons-dragons-forgotten]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[For Wolfenstein 3 To Be Good, It Needs To Punch Nazis Even Harder]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/wolfenstein-3-sequel-nazis-trump-ice-machinegames-2000658228</link>
            <guid>1400974</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>The news that </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/wolfenstein-3-in-development-machinegames-bethesda-2000657758"><i><span>Wolfenstein 3</span></i></a><span> is in the works is music to my ears. I’ve long been a fan of Sweden-based MachineGames’ take on </span><i><span>Wolfenstein</span></i><span>, which transforms B.J. Blazkowicz’s one-man war on occult-powered Nazis into a grisly and moving narrative about the strength of family and communities while finding oneself amidst endless conflict. </span><i><span>Wolfenstein 2</span></i><span> showed the importance of resisting the narrative that fascism can and will win. If I have one concrete hope for a potential sequel, it’s that it doesn’t ease up on the gas.</span></p> <p><span>The first of these games, </span><i><span>Wolfenstein: The New Order</span></i><span> is</span><span> really good, as is its prequel, <em>The Old Blood</em>. Their shooting chops have always been up to snuff and their unflinching narratives were a breath of fresh air at a time when FPS fare was beginning to feel a little same-y. They had a stylish verve that was becoming all-too uncommon and paired B.J. with the likes of alt-history takes on Jimi Hendrix and Nikola Tesla. Besides that, it was also refreshingly novel to play an FPS about Nazis at a time where it seemed like most of the genre was ditching the past in favor of modern and future conflicts. It was 2014, and we couldn’t have known what was to come.</span></p> <p><i><span>Wolfenstein: The New Colossu</span></i><span>s was an entirely different story. Arriving in the fall of 2017, </span><i><span>The New Colossus</span></i><span> struck like lightning. Its unveiling and marketing beats reveled in the joy of ripping fascists to shreds, while </span><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/fps/8-years-after-wolfenstein-2-vowed-to-make-america-nazi-free-again-multiple-reports-suggest-wolfenstein-3-is-finally-in-development/"><span>leaning into the dystopic headlines</span></a><span> Americans increasingly became inundated with. It adopted the “punch Nazis now, ask questions later” ideology that emerged amid Donald Trump’s first presidency and the rise of the alt-right. More specifically, it leaned into that time that Richard Spencer–a Neo-Nazi and early figurehead of the alt-right movement–got </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aFh08JEKDYk"><span>decked</span></a><span> by an unknown assailant on camera.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>At the time, many criticized publisher Bethesda’s decision to appropriate some of this language and rhetoric throughout </span><i><span>The New Colossus’</span></i><span> marketing cycle. Fans of the games and companies involved openly protested against the game on social media, and even threatened to boycott it.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>During an interview with </span><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Wolfenstein/comments/7ap3n8/hey_bethseda_youre_game_is_making_people_mad/"><i><span>Vice News</span></i></a><span> which centered on this outrage, Bethesda’s then-director of PR, Pete Hines, told the outlet, “Unless you’re a Nazi, there should be nobody who’s opposed to the idea of being against Nazis.” When told that the game’s aggressive marketing tone might be poking the hornet’s nest, Hines even doubled down, saying, “Maybe a little bit, but the hornet’s nest is full of Nazis so…fuck those guys. I’ll poke a Nazi hornet’s nest.”</span></p>  <p><i><span>The New Colossus</span></i><span>‘ narrative was as brazen as its marketing campaign and bold in a way few games have managed since, focusing on a Nazi-occupied America and how B.J. and his allies, the Kreisau Circle, begin fomenting rebellion at home. It is filled with sights that are still hard to shake, like KKK members in full Klan garb chumming it up with Nazi shocktroopers on the streets of Roswell, New Mexico. And it is filled with characters and pulse-pounding dialogue exchanges that interrogate whether America has ever really been the virtuous home of freedom its most patriotic defendants claim it to be. After all, America under Nazi rule in <em>The New Colossus </em>looks a lot like America always has</span><span>.</span></p> <p><span>Maybe the root of evil wasn’t abroad all along. Maybe it’s been in us the whole time. And maybe we never really stamped it out because the blood and cruelty which it produces has always greased the wheels of this </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/no-games-for-genocide-xbox-microsoft-boycott-palestine-2000650175"><span>damnable, infernal machine</span></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>And yet B.J. and his allies fight like hell to dismantle it. They take on impossible odds, which manifest in </span><i><span>The New Colossus</span></i><span>‘ difficulty spikes and often brutal gauntlets and level design. B.J. himself even takes a detour into his past and confronts the earliest source of evil in his life: his racist, abusive father, Rip. And you know what he does? He exorcizes his demons. It is cathartic to be in B.J.’s shoes at that crucial moment when he takes back his life from Rip, who dies at the hands of his own son in defense of an America that, in his own words, has become “a white man’s world now.” And it is cathartic to take that rage and rip into Nazis for several more hours afterwards.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><i><span>Wolfenstein: The New Colossus</span></i><span> could not have more perfectly matched the moment it emerged into. Its European developers definitely seem like they were tuned into the national conversation overseas and the growing political divide in America, but I don’t believe any of them would go so far as to say they predicted the exact descent into fascism which the game’s development and release would parallel. </span><i><span>Wolfenstein 3</span></i><span>, however, could be an entirely different story.</span></p> <p><span>Even if </span><i><span>Wolfenstein 3</span></i><span> is only in the earliest stages of production right now, it could still arrive near the end of Trump’s second presidency. And lord knows the material that MachineGames has to work with nowadays. That loser notion that Rip died defending? Well, that seems like the primary ambition of the current U.S. administration, which continues to stoke fires both abroad and at home in pursuit of this goal. Look no further than the way that the administration has continually sicced ICE–the </span><a href="https://www.404media.co/inside-ices-tool-to-monitor-phones-in-entire-neighborhoods/"><span>president’s own secret police</span></a><span> at this point–on American citizens in a manufactured war on immigrants, rounded people up into camps, and even claimed the lives of innocents, as many saw with the </span><a href="https://defector.com/ice-agent-kills-woman-dhs-tells-obvious-insane-lies-about-it"><span>murder of Renee Nicole Good</span></a><span> in Minneapolis on January 7.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>If </span><i><span>The New Colossus</span></i><span> felt like a heightened, yet prescient take on the politics of the 2010s, what might a follow-up in the wake of the declining American empire under a second Trump administration look like? Neither you nor I can really say, but if it’s anything like its predecessors, it will be abrasive, unhinged, and rightfully angry at the rot we’ve observed in the time since </span><i><span>Wolfenstein </span></i><span>was last in the limelight. At the naked abuses of power which dominate our timelines and drive our seemingly routine descents into madness. At the normalization of Nazi shit and cruelty. I could use a place to vent all that frustration. Maybe, just maybe, </span><i><span>Wolfenstein 3 </span></i><span>will fill that role perfectly whenever it arrives.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/wolfenstein-3-sequel-nazis-trump-ice-machinegames-2000658228]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33, Ghost of Yotei, ARC Raiders and Dispatch Lead 29th DICE Awards Nominations]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/29th-annual-dice-awards-nominees-full-list-clair-obscur-ghost-of-yotei-arc-raiders-dispatch/</link>
            <guid>1400959</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The <strong>29th annual DICE Awards</strong> are set for <strong>February 12, 2026</strong>, and the <a href="https://www.interactive.org/awards/29th_dice_awards_finalists_93k3p1.asp">full list of nominees has been revealed</a>, with an unsurprising list of games leading the way in nominations. <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/clair-obscur-expedition-33-dont-fear-the-paintress/">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ghost-of-yotei-exploring-the-price-of-vengeance-in-17th-century-ezo/">Ghost of Yotei</a></strong> lead the pack with <strong>eight nominations each,</strong> while <strong>Dispatch</strong> and <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/arc-raiders-review-speak-softly-and-carry-a-wolfpack/">ARC Raiders</a></strong> tie for second place with <strong>six nominations each</strong>. All four titles are also nominated for the big prize, <strong>Game of the Year</strong>.</p>



<p>The DICE Awards are hosted every year by the Academy of Interactive Arts and Sciences, with the nominees and winners picked by an academy of more than 30,000 members of the video game industry. Similar to the GDC Awards, this is an awards show that is chosen by the developers, and made for developers to celebrate each other's work and lift up the latest and greatest in the video game industry.</p>



<p>Basically, if you think that <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-where-to-watch-all-nominations-what-to-expect/">The Game Awards</a> are nothing but a popularity contest and that the games' media critics who make up the judging panel don't know what they're talking about and/or you think they're only focused on trailers for new games and not focused enough on the actual awards themselves, then the DICE Awards are what you'll want to pay attention to.</p>



<p>Coincidentally, four out of the five choices for DICE's Game of the Year appear on <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-games-of-2025-year-of-the-indie-ish/">Wccftech's Best of 2025 list.</a> </p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Other notable nominees include Blue Prince, which has five nominations, including one for Game of the Year, and Death Stranding 2: On the Beach, which has four nominations. </p>



<p>Some of the major differences between the DICE Awards and the <a href="https://wccftech.com/golden-joysticks-awards-2025-winners-full-list/">other major awards shows</a> that've already passed are the fact that Hollow Knight Silksong and Hades 2 are left off the Game of the Year list, with the former getting only one nomination and the latter getting three. Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 also came up short with only three nominations, and Donkey Kong Bananza got two.</p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/astro-bot-wins-game-of-the-year-at-dice-awards-2025/">Last year's big winner was Astro Bot</a>, which took home five wins, including Game of the Year. Helldivers 2, Balatro, and Indiana Jones and the Great Circle also came up with multiple wins, with four, three, and three awards each, respectively. </p>



<p>You can check out the full list of nominations below.</p>



<h2 id="h-29th-annual-dice-awards-nominations">29th Annual DICE Awards Nominations</h2>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Animation</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Monster Hunter Wilds</li>



<li>South of Midnight</li>



<li>The Midnight Walk</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Art Direction</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Dispatch</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>The Midnight Walk</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Character</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - Esquie</li>



<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 - Maelle</li>



<li>Dispatch - Courtney/Invisigal</li>



<li>Dispatch - Robert Robertson III/Mecha Man</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei - Atsu</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Original Music Composition</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Herdling</li>



<li>Mario Kart World</li>



<li>Sword of the Sea</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Audio Design</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>ARC Raiders</li>



<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Lumines Arise</li>



<li>Split Fiction</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Story</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Consume Me</li>



<li>Despelote</li>



<li>South of Midnight</li>



<li>The Drifter</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Technical Achievement</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>ARC Raiders</li>



<li>Assassin's Creed Shadows</li>



<li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li>



<li>Donkey Kong Bananza</li>



<li>DOOM: The Dark Ages</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Action Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Absolum</li>



<li>ARC Raiders</li>



<li>DOOM: The Dark Ages</li>



<li>Hades II</li>



<li>Ninja Gaiden 4</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Adventure Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Dispatch</li>



<li>Donkey Kong Bananza</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Hollow Knight: Silksong</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Family Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>LEGO Party!</li>



<li>LEGO Voyagers</li>



<li>Lumines Arise</li>



<li>MARVEL Cosmic Invasion</li>



<li>POPUCOM</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Fighting Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>2XKO</li>



<li>Capcom Fighting Collection 2</li>



<li>FATAL FURY: City of the Wolves</li>



<li>Mortal Kombat: Legacy Kollection</li>



<li>WWE 2K25</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Racing Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>EA SPORTS F1 25</li>



<li>Kirby Air Riders</li>



<li>Mario Kart World</li>



<li>Wheel World</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Role-Playing Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector</li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li>



<li>Monster Hunter Wilds</li>



<li>The Outer Worlds 2</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Sports Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>EA SPORTS FC™ 26</li>



<li>PGA Tour 2k25</li>



<li>MLB® The Show™ 25</li>



<li>NBA 2k26</li>



<li>Rematch</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Strategy/Simulation Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>The Alters</li>



<li>Drop Duchy</li>



<li>Europa Universalis V</li>



<li>The King is Watching</li>



<li>StarVaders</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Immersive Reality Technical Achievement</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Ghost Town</li>



<li>Hotel Infinity</li>



<li>Marvel's Deadpool VR</li>



<li>Star Wars: Beyond Victory - A Mixed Reality Playset</li>



<li>Unloop</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Immersive Reality Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked</li>



<li>Ghost Town</li>



<li>Marvel's Deadpool VR</li>



<li>The Midnight Walk</li>



<li>Thief VR: Legacy of Shadow</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement for an Independent Game</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Baby Steps</li>



<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Consume Me</li>



<li>Despelote</li>



<li>Dispatch</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Mobile Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Persona5: The Phantom X&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</li>



<li>Umamusume: Pretty Derby</li>



<li>WHAT THE CLASH?</li>



<li>Where Winds Meet</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Online Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>ARC Raiders</li>



<li>Battlefield 6</li>



<li>Mario Kart World</li>



<li>Marvel Rivals</li>



<li>Split Fiction</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Game Design</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>ARC Raiders</li>



<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Hades II</li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li>



<li>Öoo</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Game Direction</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Ghost of Yōtei</li>



<li>Hades II</li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Game of the Year</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>ARC Raiders</li>



<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Dispatch</li>



<li>Ghost of Yotei</li>
</ul>





			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/29th-annual-dice-awards-nominees-full-list-clair-obscur-ghost-of-yotei-arc-raiders-dispatch/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FF7 Rebirth Director Explains The Mini-Game Bloat]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-minigames-remake-trilogy-3-game-2000658234</link>
            <guid>1400953</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i><span>Final Fantasy VII Remake</span></i><span>’s third and final entry is still years away, but Square Enix is actively developing whatever comes after 2024’s </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>. The sequel was notoriously </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-mini-games-best-worst-ranked-1851340606"><span>minigame heavy</span></a><span>, and while the </span><i><span>Remake </span></i><span>trilogy already felt like it was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-remake-mini-games-third-game-1851272221"><span>straining to make three games out of one</span></a><span>, </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>’s reliance on minigames to pad the length really pushed things past the limit. Other than </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-ending-cloud-aerith-sephiroth-1851374178"><span>its divisive ending</span></a><span>, it’s probably the most widely derided part of the game, but it doesn’t sound like this criticism has deterred Square from this approach.</span></p> <p><span>In </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jbrBjFZabUE"><span>an interview with </span><i><span>GamerBraves</span></i></a><span>, </span><i><span>Rebirth </span></i><span>director Naoki Hamaguchi was asked about </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>’s inclusion of heaps of minigames, with interviewer Sean Lim noting that some players felt the onslaught interrupted the game’s pacing. Hamaguchi said that the team’s intention was to not only shake up what the player was doing throughout </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>’s lengthy runtime, but also pay homage to the original </span><i><span>Final Fantasy VII</span></i><span>, which had its fair share of minigames as well.</span></p>

  <blockquote><p><span>So, that’s not a unique problem for </span><i><span>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</span></i><span> only. A lot of games, aside from the main theme and main story progression, also have the side games and the minigames built into them. So, we don’t think we’re unique in that aspect. So when you’re playing the game and you’re going through the main story progression, as well as the intended game design, you tend to fall into this trap of having the same tempo. So, you tend to get bored playing it. To sort of combat this and keep that fresh feeling of going through the game, that’s why we introduced these minigames, to sort of add a diversity of experience as you’re playing the game, to keep up the good rhythm, so to say. So we understand when you introduce these different facets, some people would play it and really enjoy it, but some people would rather just get on with the main story. So it’s sort of a calculated move on our part to include all these different facets of the game. Whether it’s the amount of minigames or the pacing [with which] we introduce them, so on the creator side, it’s sort of something we have taken into account when we do the game design.</span></p> <p><span>So the original </span><i><span>Final Fantasy VII</span></i><span> also had lots of minigames, and it was very famous for that. So, when [we] were entrusted with doing the remake, [we] sort of wanted to keep that spirit of the diversity of play within the title, so that people can have lots of different experiences the same way they did with </span><i><span>Final Fantasy VII</span></i><span>.</span></p></blockquote> <p><span>I can appreciate wanting to be true to the original RPG’s minigames, but </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>’s obvious use of it as filler goes far beyond reimagining. It would be helpful if each diversion was good, but they varied from the good as hell </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ff7-rebirth-queens-blood-naoki-hamaguchi-interview-1851312733"><span>Queen’s Blood card game</span></a><span> to the infamous </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-cait-sith-box-throw-mod-remove-1851744876"><span>Cait Sith box throwing segment</span></a><span>. Walking through </span><i><span>Rebirth</span></i><span>’s open world was like trying to cross a minefield where the most obnoxious, unskippable landmines were waiting for you if you stepped in the wrong direction. </span></p>

 <p><span>Hamaguchi doesn’t say if this will persist into the next </span><i><span>Final Fantasy VII Remake</span></i><span> game, but he has said elsewhere that the third game will </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-part-3-remake-length-how-long-2000637274"><span>be more concise</span></a><span>, so hopefully that means&nbsp; the minigames get dialed down a bit in the final chapter. Or let Sephiroth strike me down.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-minigames-remake-trilogy-3-game-2000658234]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Source Blames Switch 2 Holiday Sales Slowdown on the Economic Landscape and the 'Absence of a Major Western Game' — Despite the Release of Me]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-source-blames-switch-2-holiday-sales-slowdown-on-the-economic-landscape-and-the-absence-of-a-major-western-game-despite-the-release-of-metroid-prime-4-beyond</link>
            <guid>1400950</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> sales over the holidays reportedly fell short of those recorded by the console's predecessor back in 2017, during its first end-of-year season.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As revealed by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A_NUBDTG8_4" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Game Business</a>, Switch 2 sales in the US and within key markets in Europe fell behind the equivalent pace of Switch 1 — something an unnamed senior Nintendo source blamed on a "complicated" economic climate today, and the "absence of a major Western game" during the year-end period.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That particular analysis will likely raise eyebrows among Nintendo fans, as the company launched the long-awaited <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metroid-prime-4-beyond">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> during the period — albeit to a more muted critical response than the franchise's beloved original trilogy. Nintendo has so far made no announcement on how that game has fared.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Game Business reports that US Switch 2 sales over the holiday period were down around 35% versus the Switch 1's sales performance back in 2017. In the UK, a similar comparison saw Switch 2 lagging Switch 1 by 16%. Even in Nintendo's homeland of Japan, Switch 2 holiday sales couldn't match Switch 1, and were down by 5.5% over the year's final nine weeks.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In France, 2025's final tally of Switch 2 sales was down by "over 30%" versus the amount Switch 1 notched up back in 2017, meanwhile.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While these numbers may take some of the shine off of a successful first year for Switch 2 overall, it's not all doom and gloom. Switch 2's lifetime sales in Japan are still above what Switch 1 managed in its first year, with less time on sale. And in the UK, Switch 1 continued to sell well enough that it made up Switch 2's holiday sales deficit. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking ahead, Nintendo has a smattering of first-party games already planned for 2026, including Mario Tennis Fever, Yoshi and the Mysterious Book and Fire Emblem: Fortune's Weave, as well as Switch 2 upgrades for Super Mario Wonder and Animal Crossing: New Horizons. There's also the FromSoftware exclusive The Duskbloods to look forward to, and the promising-looking Pokémon Pokopia life sim.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Animal Crossing: New Horizons – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">But as the Switch 2 prepares to celebrate its first anniversary in June, all eyes will be on Nintendo to roll out a truly new blockbuster entry in one of its biggest franchises. Back in 2017, Switch 1's first year was marked by the launch of both Super Mario Odyssey and The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild. Nintendo has not released a major new 3D Mario platformer since, while it will soon be three years since the arrival of 2023's The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Switch 1's other top-selling titles include Super Smash Bros. Ultimate and Animal Crossing: New Horizons — and for now, there's no suggestion a big new entry in either franchise is forthcoming. Smash Bros. series boss Masahiro Sakurai has only just finished work on Kirby Air Riders, while Nintendo is opting to update New Horizons for Switch 2 this year, as previously mentioned. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Could we see a new 3D Mario in 2026? Nine years on from Super Mario Odyssey, now feels like the right time. And then there's Pokémon, which celebrates its 30th anniversary next month. Could we get a glimpse soon of the series' long-awaited 10th generation? The arrival of these titles would certainly help Switch 2 keep its momentum, following last year's explosive launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-source-blames-switch-2-holiday-sales-slowdown-on-the-economic-landscape-and-the-absence-of-a-major-western-game-despite-the-release-of-metroid-prime-4-beyond]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New GTA 6 Delay Rumor Shot Down By Reporter, Says Statement Was Misconstrued]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-gta-6-delay-rumor-shot-down-by-reporter-says-statement-was-misconstrued/1100-6537283/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1400947</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537283">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi/" data-ref-id="5000-569323">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> is still a little over 10 months away, assuming its November 2026 release window holds. Earlier this week, GTA 6 watchers were unsettled when Bloomberg's Jason Schreier noted that the game might not be as "content complete" as Rockstar has said in the past, and he didn't rule out another delay. Some fans took that as if GTA 6 was already pushed back again, which is why Schreier has stepped forward to clarify his comments.</p><p>During a recent appearance on the <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/1EANk4uOn68ddip6pKliqY" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Button Mash</a> podcast, Schreier said, "The last I heard, [GTA 6] was still not content complete. That is to say people were still finishing things up, still finalizing levels, and missions, and seeing what is going to make it into the game." He added that he doesn't "think anyone at Rockstar can tell you, with 100% certainty, that they will make it out in November."</p><p>Schreier responded to reports based on his comments by reiterating that he "wouldn't be shocked if GTA 6 'does' come out this fall, following the same delay pattern as [Red Dead Redemption 2]." He also characterized some of the reports as, "a complete misunderstanding of what I said."</p><div data-embed-type="html"><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:2mkgbhbhqvappkkorf2bzyrp/app.bsky.feed.post/3mbw6vt7l3s25" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreifmmw55edle55ebrtjxurpv4qjqd4af2eggqctnleafiyz5jz2saq" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system"><div><p>This is a complete misunderstanding of what I said, which is that I wouldn't be shocked if GTA6 *does* come out this fall, following the same delay pattern as RDR2. Of course another delay is possible. It's a video game. But this blog post is very misleading (just reach out to me - it's not hard!)</p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2mkgbhbhqvappkkorf2bzyrp/post/3mbw6vt7l3s25?ref_src=embed" rel="nofollow ">[image or embed]</a></p></div>  — Jason Schreier (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2mkgbhbhqvappkkorf2bzyrp?ref_src=embed" rel="nofollow ">@jasonschreier.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:2mkgbhbhqvappkkorf2bzyrp/post/3mbw6vt7l3s25?ref_src=embed" rel="nofollow ">January 8, 2026 at 6:28 AM</a></blockquote>


  






  </div><p>As Schreier and others have previously noted, Rockstar does have <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/why-did-rockstar-delay-gta-6/1100-6536423/" data-ref-id="1100-6536423">a history of delaying its AAA games</a>, and GTA 6 in particular has already been pushed back twice. It's been reported that the current delay <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-delay-could-cost-rockstar-60-million-as-insiders-report-game-is-content-complete/1100-6536115/" data-ref-id="1100-6536115">may cost Rockstar upwards of $60 million</a>.</p><p>Some analysts continue to make the case that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-warrants-a-100-price-tag-gta-5-actor-says/1100-6535876/" data-ref-id="1100-6535876">GTA 6 could be $100 for its standard edition</a>, which would potentially encourage other publishers to raise their prices as well. For now, Rockstar has yet to commit to a price for GTA 6.</p><p>Grand Theft Auto 6 is scheduled to be released on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S on November 19.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-gta-6-delay-rumor-shot-down-by-reporter-says-statement-was-misconstrued/1100-6537283/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Yotei and Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 headline 2026 DICE Awards nominations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-embargo-1-30-et-today-ghost-of-yotei-and-clair-obscur-expedition-33-headline-2026-dice-awards-nominations</link>
            <guid>1400944</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">January 8, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>1 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via PlayStation / Sucker Punch Productions</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Academy of Interactive Arts and Sciences (AIAS) has announced its nominees for the upcoming 28th annual DICE Awards.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Via press release, 64 games from 2025 have been nominated. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arc Raiders</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Blue Prince</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dispatch</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ghost of Yōtei</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> are the candidates for game of the year. The latter two have accrued the most nominations with eight each, followed by </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arc Raiders</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dispatch</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> with six each.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"(...) on behalf of all of us at the Academy, I extend my congratulations to all of our finalists," AIAS president Meggan Scavio said in the announcement. "Each of these games has impressed us through its creativity, artistry, and technical achievement, and we look forward to celebrating your accomplishments at the 29th Annual DICE Awards."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">You can find the full nominee list </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.interactive.org/awards/29th_dice_awards_finalists_93k3p1.asp">here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, with select examples listed below. The DICE Awards are set to air in Las Vegas on Thursday, February 12.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game of the Year</span></span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arc Raiders</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Embark Studios)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Blue Prince</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Dogubomb/Raw Fury)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Sandfall Interactive/Kepler Interactive)</span></p></div></li><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ghost of Yōtei </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">(Sucker Punch Productions/PlayStation)</span></p></div></li></ul></div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Outstanding Achievement in Game Direction</span></span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Blue Prince</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Dogubomb/Raw Fury)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Sandfall Interactive/Kepler Interactive)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ghost of Yōtei </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">(Sucker Punch Productions/PlayStation)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hades II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Supergiant Games)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Warhorse Studios/Deep Silver)</span></p></div></li></ul></div><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gamestop-owned-eb-games-proposes-closing-all-its-new-zealand-stores" target="_self" data-discover="true">Report: GameStop-owned EB Games proposes closing all its New Zealand stores</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Outstanding Achievement in Game Design</span></span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Arc Raiders</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Embark Studios)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Blue Prince</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Dogubomb/Raw Fury)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hades II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Supergiant Games)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Warhorse Studios/Deep Silver)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Öoo</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (NamaTakanashi/tiny cactus studio/Tsuyomi)</span></p></div></li></ul></div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Outstanding Achievement in Art Direction</span></span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Sandfall Interactive/Kepler Interactive)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Kojima Productions/PlayStation)</span></p></div></li><li></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ghost of Yōtei </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">(Sucker Punch Productions/PlayStation)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Midnight Walk</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (MoonHood/Fast Travel Games)</span></p></div></li></ul></div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Outstanding Achievement for an Independent Game</span></span></p><div data-component="basic-list"><ul data-testid="basic-list-unordered"><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Baby Steps</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Gabe Cuzzillo/Maxi Boch/Bennett Foddy/Devolver Digital)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Blue Prince</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Dogubomb/Raw Fury)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Consume Me</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Jenny Jiao Hsia/AP Thomson/Jie En Lee/Violet W-P/Ken "coda" Snyder/Hexecutable)</span></p></div></li><li><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Despelote</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (Julián Cordero/Sebastian Valbuena/Panic)</span></p></div></li><li></li></ul></div></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-embargo-1-30-et-today-ghost-of-yotei-and-clair-obscur-expedition-33-headline-2026-dice-awards-nominations]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: Which Call Of Duty Do You Want To See On Switch 2?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-which-call-of-duty-do-you-want-to-see-on-switch-2</link>
            <guid>1400923</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"What the hell kind of name is 'Soap'?"</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="491ff96f5f5a9"><a title="Call of Duty Switch 2 Poll" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/491ff96f5f5a9/call-of-duty-switch-2-poll.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Activision</em></figcaption></figure><p>With rumours of the never-ending <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/call_of_duty_finest_hour">Call of Duty</a> franchise's imminent appearance on Switch 2 <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/rumour-call-of-dutys-nintendo-release-is-apparently-on-target-for-2026">once again doing the rounds</a> — following <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/12/microsoft-enters-10-year-commitment-to-bring-call-of-duty-to-nintendo">a 10-year agreement</a> to bring the series to Nintendo platforms as part of Microsoft's acquisition of Activision Blizzard, no less — we've been busy pondering just which of these storied shooters we'd like to see ported onto our new(ish) favourite platform first.</p>
<p>Yes, we know it's not going to work like that, most likely. We can't see them dropping a greatest hits first off, or even going with anything that'd make a bad first technical impression, so perhaps the newer stuff is out of the conversation. Also, this writer is of the opinion we're 100% going to see <a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-one/call_of_duty_warzone">Warzone</a> as an opening gambit.</p>
<p>However! There's still plenty of fun to be had in discussing which one exactly we'd prefer to see arrive first, especially given there's so many diverse and exciting entries in a 22-year-old series that's all about shooting stuff at its core.</p>
<p>For me, it's <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/reviews/ps4/call_of_duty_infinite_warfare">Infinite Warfare</a> all day long, easily my favourite of the lot. I'd also choose <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps4/call_of_duty_wwii">WWII</a> before any of the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/call_of_duty_black_ops_ii">Black Ops</a> entries (yep, I said it), and even <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps4/call_of_duty_advanced_warfare">Advanced Warfare</a> would have been a grand old time had it not been for the Spacey sourness.</p>
<p>Enough about us, though (or me, even), we want to hear which of the following mainline Call of Duty games <em>you</em> would like to see on Switch 2. So take a gander at them long, long list of options below, and give your fave a click. Do it for Roach.</p>

<hr>
<p><em>Thanks for voting. Make sure to check out the results to see how your selection is doing, and please jump into the comments to sound off! Ooh-rah and all that stuff.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:195663,147218,147217 @ 1767906032 --></section></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-which-call-of-duty-do-you-want-to-see-on-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 29th DICE Awards Nominees Have Been Revealed, Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 And Ghost Of Yōtei Lead The Pack]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/08/the-29th-dice-awards-nominees-have-been-revealed-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-ghost-of</link>
            <guid>1400908</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>The Academy of Interactive Arts &amp; Sciences has revealed the nominees for its 29th annual <a href="https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/06/former-naughty-dog-president-evan-wells-to-be-inducted-into-aias-hall-of-fame">D.I.C.E. Awards</a>, and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost Of Yōtei</a> lead the pack with eight nominations each. The award show will be livestreamed from the Aria Resort in Las Vegas at 8 p.m. PT/11 p.m. &nbsp;ET on Thursday, February 12.&nbsp;</p><p>Amongst the thousands of games released in 2025, 64 make up the nominations for this year's awards show. At the top of the list with eight nominations each are Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 and Ghost Of Yōtei, followed by <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a> and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/dispatch">Dispatch</a> with six nominations, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/blue-prince">Blue Prince</a> with five nominations, and <a href="https://gameinformer.com/product/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach">Death Stranding 2: On The Beach</a> with four.</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MWUO8e_jtiY"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MWUO8e_jtiY" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p><em>Kinda Funny</em> co-founder Greg Miller and media personality Stella Chung (who previously worked at IGN), return as co-hosts of the show this year – the two revealed the nominations during today's episode of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/sak9VNbAilI?si=V3s3pOqWL9CsShiP">Kinda Funny Games Daily</a> before AIAS released a press release with the nominations.&nbsp;</p><p>"First, thank you to our peer panelists," AIAS president Meggan Scavio writes in a press release. "Your dedication and expertise in our judging process, and your work in selecting the best games of 2025, is truly appreciated. And on behalf of all of us at the Academy, I extend my congratulations to all of our finalists. Each of these games has impressed us through its creativity, artistry, and technical achievement, and we look forward to celebrating your accomplishments at the 29th Annual D.I.C.E. Awards."&nbsp;</p><p>Notably, the D.I.C.E. Awards are voted on by a panel of judges who are all game developers, which differs from other shows, like Geoff Keighley's <a href="https://gameinformer.com/the-game-awards-2025/2025/12/11/every-winner-at-the-game-awards-2025-the-complete-list">The Game Awards</a>, in which the panel of judges is made up of media outlets (like <em>Game Informer</em>). Unlike The Game Awards, there are never any video game announcements, reveals, or world premieres at the D.I.C.E. Awards.&nbsp;</p><p height="360" width="640" url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PWSPKRXpwUI"><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PWSPKRXpwUI" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay" allowfullscreen="true">&nbsp;</iframe></p><p>You can find the full list of nominations for every award below:&nbsp;</p><h3><strong>Outstanding Achievement in Animation</strong></h3><ul><li>Death Stranding 2: On The Beach</li><li>Ghost Of Yōtei</li><li>Monster Hunter Wilds</li><li>South of Midnight</li><li>The Midnight Walk</li></ul><h3>Outstanding Achievement in Art Direction</h3><ul><li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li><li>Death Stranding 2: On The Beach</li><li>Dispatch</li><li>Ghost Of Yōtei</li><li>The Midnight Walk</li></ul><h3>Outstanding Achievement in Character</h3><ul><li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 – Esquie</li><li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 – Maelle</li><li>Dispatch – Courtney/Invisigal</li><li>Dispatch – Robert Robertson III/Mecha Man</li><li>Ghost Of Yōtei – Atsu</li></ul><h3>Outstanding Achievement in Original Music Composition</h3><ul><li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li><li>Ghost Of Yōtei</li><li>Herdling</li><li>Mario Kart World</li><li>Sword of the Sea</li></ul><h3>Outstanding Achievement in Audio Design</h3><ul><li>Arc Raiders</li><li>Death Stranding 2: On The Beach</li><li>Ghost Of Yōtei</li><li>Lumines Arise</li><li>Split Fiction</li></ul><h3>Outstanding Achievement in Story</h3><ul><li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li><li>Consume Me</li><li>despelote</li><li>South of Midnight</li><li>The Drifter</li></ul><h3>Outstanding Technical Achievement</h3><ul><li>Arc Raiders</li><li>Assassin's Creed Shadows</li><li>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</li><li>Donkey Kong Bananza</li><li>DOOM: The Dark Ages</li></ul><h3>Action Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>Absolum</li><li>Arc Raiders</li><li>DOOM: The Dark Ages</li><li>Hades II</li><li>Ninja Gaiden 4</li></ul><h3>Adventure Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>Blue Prince</li><li>Dispatch</li><li>Donkey Kong Bananza</li><li>Ghost Of Yōtei</li><li>Hollow Knight: Silksong</li></ul><h3>Family Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>LEGO Party!</li><li>LEGO Voyagers</li><li>Lumines Arise</li><li>Marvel Cosmic Invasion</li><li>POPUCOM</li></ul><h3>Fighting Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>2XKO</li><li>Capcom Fighting Collection 2</li><li>Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</li><li>Mortal Kombat: Legacy Kollection</li><li>WWE 2K25</li></ul><h3>Racing Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>EA Sports F1 25</li><li>Kirby Air Riders</li><li>Mario Kart World</li><li>Wheel World</li></ul><h3>Role-Playing Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li><li>Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector</li><li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li><li>Monster Hunter Wilds</li><li>The Outer Worlds 2</li></ul><h3>Sports Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>EA Sports FC 26</li><li>PGA Tour 2K25</li><li>MLB The Show 25</li><li>NBA 2K26</li><li>Rematch</li></ul><h3>Strategy/Simulation Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>The Alters</li><li>Drop Duchy</li><li>Europa Universalis V</li><li>The King is Watching</li><li>StarVaders</li></ul><h3>Immersive Reality Technical Achievement</h3><ul><li>Ghost Town</li><li>Hotel Infinity</li><li>Marvel's Deadpool VR</li><li>Star Wars: Beyond Victory – A Mixed Reality Playset</li><li>Unloop</li></ul><h3>Immersive Reality Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked</li><li>Ghost Town</li><li>Marvel's Deadpool VR</li><li>The Midnight Walk</li><li>Thief VR: Legacy of Shadow</li></ul><h3>Outstanding Achievement for an Independent Game</h3><ul><li>Baby Steps</li><li>Blue Prince</li><li>Consume Me</li><li>despelote</li><li>Dispatch</li></ul><h3>Mobile Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>Persona 5: The Phantom X</li><li>Umamusume: Pretty Derby</li><li>What The Clash?</li><li>Where Winds Meet</li></ul><h3>Online Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>Arc Raiders</li><li>Battlefield 6</li><li>Mario Kart World</li><li>Marvel Rivals</li><li>Split Fiction</li></ul><h3>Outstanding Achievement in Game Design</h3><ul><li>Arc Raiders</li><li>Blue Prince</li><li>Hades II</li><li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li><li>Öoo</li></ul><h3>Outstanding Achievement in Game Direction</h3><ul><li>Blue Prince</li><li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li><li>Ghost of Yōtei</li><li>Hades II</li><li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</li></ul><h3>Game of the Year</h3><ul><li>Arc Raiders</li><li>Blue Prince</li><li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li><li>Dispatch</li><li>Ghost of Yōtei</li></ul><p>And those are all the nominations for the 29th annual D.I.C.E. Awards.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>What game do you think will win Game of the Year? Let us know in the comments below!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2026/01/08/the-29th-dice-awards-nominees-have-been-revealed-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-ghost-of]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Download: 8th January (North America)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/nintendo-download-8th-january-north-america</link>
            <guid>1400890</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="ecdcf9ffd32f9"><a title="Temirana: The Lucky Princess and the Tragic Knights" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/ecdcf9ffd32f9/temirana-the-lucky-princess-and-the-tragic-knights.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Idea Factory</em></figcaption></figure><p><em>The latest Nintendo Download update for North America has arrived, and it's bringing new games galore to the eShop in your region. As always, be sure to drop a vote in our poll and comment down below with your potential picks for the week. Enjoy!</em></p>
<h2>Switch 2 eShop - New Releases</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/arcade-archives-2-space-invaders-part-ii">Arcade Archives 2 SPACE INVADERS PART II</a></strong> <strong>[Switch 2]</strong><em>(HAMSTER, 1st Jan, $9.99)</em> - "SPACE INVADERS PART II" is a shooting game released by TAITO in 1979. The enemy Invaders have returned more powerful than ever, having acquired new tactics like splitting and receiving reinforcements from UFOs! With added features like the Rainbow Bonus to aim for high scores, this title is long beloved by skilled experts looking to hone their abilities! “Arcade Archives 2” adds a new “TIME ATTACK MODE” to the lineup of “ORIGINAL MODE,” “HI SCORE MODE,” and “CARAVAN MODE” included in the Arcade Archives series.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytC1rrCdi_XjA" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067whjvit&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>841k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/suika-game-planet">Suika Game Planet</a></strong> <strong>[Switch 2]</strong> <em>(Aladdin X, 5th Jan, $3.75)</em> - Drop the fruits freely from any direction as ""Poppy"" flies 360° around the planet. Make fruits of the same type collide to make them ""evolve"" and aim to create watermelons for a high score!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/tomba_special_edition">Tomba! Special Edition</a></strong> <em>(Limited Run Games, 1st Aug, $19.99)</em> - Tomba! returns in Tomba! Special Edition, the ultimate version of the legendary platforming masterpiece. As the titular Tomba, you leap, bite, and throw your way across stunning 2.5D landscapes on a quest to overcome a deplorable cadre of nefarious pigs. Along the way, you’ll explore ancient relics, discover fascinating characters, unlock thrilling quests, and unearth hidden treasures. It’s a platforming adventure that perfectly fuses linear and nonlinear gameplay styles.</p>
<h2>Switch eShop - New Releases</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/a_planet_of_mine_mastermine_edition">A Planet of Mine MasterMine Edition</a></strong> <em>(Tuesday Quest, 13th Jan, $12.49)</em> - A Planet of Mine Mastermine Edition is a cozy 4X game with mass strategy ! Choose your winning gang, mastermine resources, and build your base and tools to boost your technology and conquer space ! Unless your neighbors don’t see it that way. . . Trade, peace or clash : your planet, your choice !</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/aaa_games_ultimate_collection">AAA Games Ultimate Collection</a></strong> <em>(Baltoro Games, 3rd Jan, $79.99)</em> - The AAA Ultimate Games Collection Step into the world of top-quality entertainment with The AAA Ultimate Games Collection! This exclusive bundle brings together the most acclaimed titles from our studio — from high-speed motorcycle mayhem and thrilling city traffic and railway management challenges to epic alien shoot-’em-ups, relaxing solitaire favorites, and heartwarming visual novels about cooking and running your own café.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/adventure_reborn">Adventure Reborn</a></strong> <em>(REDDEER.GAMES, 30th Dec, $5.99)</em> - A little girl with a big heart goes on a mysterious journey through dangerous lands ruled by a ruthless cult. Make choices that will help her save her parents. You decide what happens in the story! In Adventure Reborn the story depends on your choices. It’s a magical tale about the power of love overcoming the evil.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/arcade-archives-2-space-invaders-part-ii">Arcade Archives SPACE INVADERS PART II</a></strong> <strong>[Switch 1]</strong> <em>(HAMSTER, 1st Jan, $7.99)</em> - "SPACE INVADERS PART II" is a shooting game released by TAITO in 1979. The enemy Invaders have returned more powerful than ever, having acquired new tactics like splitting and receiving reinforcements from UFOs! With added features like the Rainbow Bonus to aim for high scores, this title is long beloved by skilled experts looking to hone their abilities!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/battletanks_-_animal_wars">BattleTanks – Animal Wars</a></strong> <em>(Kasur, 14th Jan, $4.99)</em> - Moles have declared war. The animal world is in chaos. Naturally, the solution is tanks. In BattleTanks - Animal Wars, you’ll roll into battle as a Racoon, Bear, Wolf or even Panda (yes, really) and blast your way through five bizarre worlds filled with explosions, bad driving, and questionable military decisions.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/best_of_upscale_studio_bundle_5_in_1">Best of Upscale Studio Bundle: 5 in 1</a></strong> <em>(Upscale Studio, 26th Dec, $49.99)</em> - Discover a collection of fan-favorite titles that showcase the very best of Upscale Studio, from hilarious adventures to intense survival challenges and clever puzzles.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/big_hops">Big Hops</a></strong> <em>(Luckshot Games, 12th Jan, $19.99)</em> - BIG HOPS is a 3D platformer, action-adventure with deep movement, fresh frog-tongue gameplay, where you can grow veggies to build paths forward! You'll play as Hop, a young frog who's been kidnapped from home by a trickster spirit called Diss. He has a mysterious, important mission and needs your help, but you just want to get back to your family. . . After a bit of searching, a wiry old Raccoon offers to build you a way home if you can find a few Airship Parts.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/biplanes">Biplanes</a></strong> <em>(HAPPY HOME GAMES, 12th Jan, $14.99)</em> - Take to the skies and become a WWI flying ace in Biplanes, an exciting arcade-style aerial combat game that captures the thrill of classic dogfighting action! Intense Aerial Combat Pilot your biplane through intense dogfights against enemy aces. Master the art of aerial combat as you loop, barrel roll, and outmaneuver your opponents in fast-paced battles. Whether you're a seasoned pilot or new to the skies, intuitive controls make it easy to jump in and start flying.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/blablublas_battle_royale_shooter">Blablublas Battle Royale Shooter</a></strong> <em>(CGI LAB GAMES, 5th Jan, $7.99)</em> - Step into a chaotic battlefield where survival is everything — and the fiercest foes are armed… cats! In this wild shooter, you face off against cunning, weapon-wielding felines across a dynamic map. Every encounter is unpredictable, every corner could hide a new adversary, and only the sharpest aim and quickest reflexes will keep you alive</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/clothing_store_simulator">Clothing Store Simulator</a></strong> <em>(UMURO, 5th Jan, $9.99)</em> - Ready to Write Your Own Fashion Story? Experience the thrill of managing the city's most popular clothing store from scratch on Nintendo Switch™ with Clothing Store Simulator! Transforming a small shop into a huge fashion hub is entirely in your hands. Impress Customers with Your Style Stock your shelves with the trendiest dresses, stylish shirts, and eye-catching accessories.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/construction_sim_city_and_road_builder">Construction Sim: City and Road Builder</a></strong> <em>(Head A Games, 6th Jan, $12.99)</em> - Take the reins of your own construction company and transform a small contracting gig into an industry-leading empire. In Construction Sim: City and Road Builder, every job is a stepping stone — from hauling materials and clearing sites to assembling massive bridges, paving roads, and even installing wind turbines.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/crayon_animal">Crayon Animal</a></strong> <em>(GaniTani, 1st Jan, $6.10)</em> - Crayon Animal is the newest entry in the Crayon series following Crayon Food, Crayon Dino, and Crayon Halloween. This time, a world full of lovable animals comes to life through coloring! Color cats, dogs, lions, penguins, and more in any colors you like. Relax and paint alone or enjoy a fun coloring time with your family. Collect your finished artwork and build your very own crayon zoo!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/direction_quad">Direction Quad</a></strong> <em>(eastasiasoft, 14th Jan, $4.99)</em> - Direction Quad is a 2D action-adventure presented in top-down pixel art style. Take the role of young Quad as he hops through the swamp in any diagonal direction, collecting coins and bugs along the way. The objective is to get Quad from his starting lily pad to the finish line of each stage without colliding with the terrain or any treacherous traps.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/dunkirk_-_the_forgotten_soldier">Dunkirk – The Forgotten Soldier</a></strong> <em>(GAME NACIONAL, 3rd Jan, $5.99)</em> - Dunkirk - The Forgotten Soldier is an action rogue-lite set in a war zone. Each run puts the player against increasingly dangerous waves of enemies. With every new attempt, you must grow stronger and more skilled, using everything at your disposal to endure and push forward against the enemy’s rising force.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/geo_iq_world_master">Geo IQ World Master</a></strong> <em>(Dinomore Games, 6th Jan, $4.99)</em> - Geo IQ World Master is an educational and competitive geography exploration game built around predicting locations on the world map. You’ll be shown a country, city, landmark, historical area, or tourist spot, and your goal is to pinpoint its location as accurately as possible. The closer your guess, the higher your score.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/go_kart_island">Go Kart Island</a></strong> <em>(Ant Workshop, 9th Jan, $7.99)</em> - Lachlan the highland cow has a dream to become Go Kart Champion, but the Mayor has an election campaign to fund and demands you raise 1,000 coins for an "entry fee" to the BIG RACE. Fortunately the inhabitants of Go Kart Island have no shortage of activities they would like you to partake in and they offer cold, hard cash as a reward.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/gray_war_conflict">Gray War Conflict</a></strong> <em>(Oddi Tycoon, 5th Jan, $9.99)</em> - Gray War Conflict is a gritty first-person shooter set deep within a hostile conflict zone — a remote war-torn forest where every step could be your last. As an elite special forces operative, your mission is clear: infiltrate enemy territory, eliminate threats, and survive.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hero_seekers">Hero Seekers</a></strong> <em>(KEMCO, 8th Jan, $19.99)</em> - The world has been rewritten, and the very name of "Hero" erased from memory. Once, three brave warriors defeated the Demon King and brought peace to the land—but now their deeds are lost to time. Lunette, the only one who remembers the true history, sets out on a journey to restore it by summoning the forgotten souls of heroes and reclaiming the light once stolen from the world.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hidden_cats_in_istanbul">Hidden Cats in Istanbul</a></strong> <em>(Silesia Games, 8th Jan, $3.99)</em> - Let the ever-wandering Hidden Cats crew be your guide through colourful Istanbul! Explore the city’s iconic landmarks like the Blue Mosque, the Grand Bazaar, and Gülhane Park while relaxing to soothing Turkish-inspired music.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/i_am_future_cozy_apocalypse_survival">I Am Future: Cozy Apocalypse Survival</a></strong> <em>(tinyBuild Games, 8th Jan, $19.99)</em> - BUILD THE COZY ROOFTOP BASE OF YOUR DREAMS Starting from scratch on an abandoned rooftop, build, decorate and expand the coziest camp ever! Unlock new buildings and furniture, set up electrical grids, and neatly organize your new life. Relax, build, wander around – the world is literally yours!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/jelly_and_toast">Jelly &amp; Toast</a></strong> <em>(Ratalaika Games, 9th Jan, $4.99)</em> - Jelly &amp; Toast are a team of food-based heroes who are hungry to recover the stolen magical ingredients used to cook their favorite entrees. Choose between local co-op multiplayer or solo mode, join forces, and embark on a challenging platform adventure full of puzzles and food. Run, jump, and throw projectiles (or even each other) to complete each level.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/lovely_spot_the_difference_fantasy_edition">Lovely Spot the Difference Fantasy Edition</a></strong> <em>(AGE, 3rd Dec, $5.40)</em> - Enjoy an easy and fun game that anyone can play while admiring adorable characters! Now introducing the Fantasy Version Vol.2 with increased difficulty! Includes 15 exciting stages!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/mist">Mist</a></strong> <em>(EpiXR Games, 8th Jan, $9.99)</em> - Mist fuses idle progression, visceral real-time combat, and an evolving horror narrative into a genre-defying experience. As you explore the ruins of civilization, you’ll form a pact with a mysterious alien being that grants you strength—at a cost. Level up, mutate, and unlock terrifying new abilities as you battle grotesque creatures and uncover long-buried truths. But the world isn’t empty. Survivors remain—scarred, strange, and not always trustworthy.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/mom_life_simulator">Mom Life Simulator</a></strong> <em>(RioverseGames, 2nd Jan, $9.99)</em> - Welcome to the daily life of the most caring — yet incredibly busy — mom! In this game, you take on the role of a mother who tries to manage it all: caring for her family, keeping the house cozy, and still finding a little time for herself.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/need_for_race_street_king_and_formula_auto_sport_racing_pack">Need for Race Street King &amp; Formula Auto Sport Racing Pack</a></strong> <em>(Yellow Games In, 26th Dec, $11.99)</em> - From the streets to the circuit - master them both. Two Worlds. One Obsession - Pure Speed. From the neon-lit chaos of underground street racing to the high-precision circuits of elite Formula competitions, this bundle unites two adrenaline-charged racing experiences for true speed enthusiasts</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/owlen_and_the_spirits_of_the_past">Owlen and the Spirits of the Past</a></strong> <em>(EpiXR Games, 8th Jan, $11.99)</em> - Embark on a heartfelt journey as Owlen, a small owl soaring through mystical worlds filled with wonder and secrets. Guided by the voices of ancient spirits, you must restore balance by flying through magical circles, bringing plants, trees, and wildlife back to life. While exploring, you’ll uncover hidden memory shards scattered across the lands. These shards hold the forgotten past and reveal Owlen’s true mission.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pin_strike_2">Pin Strike 2</a></strong> <em>(NOSTRA GAMES, 8th Jan, $4.99)</em> - You already know, that bowling doesn't have to be played in a bowling alley on a straight track. You also discovered that you can use bombs or springs here. Knock down more than just bottles! See what else you can do to have more fun. Find out how this game differs from classic bowling.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pool_and_snooker_fever_2_in_1_bundle">Pool &amp; Snooker Fever: 2 in 1 Bundle</a></strong> <em>(Baltoro Minis, 9th Jan, $8.99)</em> - Get ready to master the table in Pool &amp; Snooker Fever: 2 in 1 Bundle — the ultimate cue-sports experience on your Nintendo Switch™! Enjoy both the fast-paced excitement of pool and the strategic precision of snooker, all in one complete and immersive game..</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pursuit">Pursuit</a></strong> <em>(Play Lab, 5th Jan, $9.99)</em> - Pursuit puts you behind the wheel in a fast-paced, driving adventure where escape is the goal. Every delivery is a race against time, the police, and the city itself — a city that never forgives mistakes. With no room for error, you must rely on skill, quick reflexes, and sharp instincts to stay ahead of those chasing you.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/sheriff_park_ranger">Sheriff Park Ranger</a></strong> <em>(Head A Games, 13th Jan, $9.99)</em> - Patrol vast forests, winding trails, and scenic highways as you protect visitors, wildlife, and the wilderness itself. Respond to emergencies, stop offenders, rescue animals, and face unpredictable situations that test your skills and instincts. Drive your patrol truck, flash your lights, and keep order in the wild. From traffic stops and poaching investigations to lost hikers and wildfires — every call matters.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/speedsters_collection">Speedster’s Collection</a></strong> <em>(Pixelmob, 5th Jan, $23.99)</em> - Pick one of the impressive, highly detailed vehicles and show your driving skills in this demanding environment. The city is your greatest friend and the greatest enemy. It will amaze and astonish you with its views, while demanding your full attention with its narrow streets and crowded intersections.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/spotcat_vs_the_cheddar_mafia_in_the_americas">SpotCat vs The Cheddar Mafia In The Americas</a></strong> <em>(LUCKY RACCOON GAMES, 8th Jan, $4.49)</em> - The notorious Cheddar Mafia is spreading chaos across the Americas, and only SpotCat can stop them. Explore vibrant, hand-drawn scenes from different countries, spot the subtle differences, and stay sharp — mafia rats can appear when you least expect it.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/sugoroku_new_years_party">Sugoroku New Year’s Party</a></strong> <em>(SAT-BOX, 5th Jan, $12.99)</em> - Try your luck and test your wits in this adventure of fortune! Good luck abounds in Sugoroku New Year's Party! Collect lucky coins through festive New Year's games. Bring in the most good fortune, and you'll be crowned Master of the New Year! With a Joy-Con™ controller for each player, up to six players can join in the fun!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/suika_game_planet">Suika Game Planet</a></strong> <strong>[Switch 1]</strong> <em>(Aladdin X, 5th Jan, $2.99)</em> <em>-</em> The "Suika Game Planet" has evolved in many ways, including with a customization function that allows you to freely decorate the game screen (skin), and a collection function that allows you to collect stickers for completing missions and use them to create your original name tag. Try playing it now!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/temirana_the_lucky_princess_and_the_tragic_knights">Temirana: The Lucky Princess and the Tragic Knights</a></strong> <em>(Idea Factory, 13th Jan, $39.99)</em> - Key Features The knights behind the shining armor – From the minds of director Ayumi Takagi (Hana Yaka Nari, Waga Ichizoku), main scenario writer Uta Amemiya (Charade Maniacs), and character designer Nitaka (Touken Ranbu) comes a tale of luck, tragedy, and love developed by the otome game mainstay, ichicolumn! The kingdom of Temirana awaits – Enjoy a deep storyline with five possible routes that blends political intrigue with romance and drama.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/tile_jong">Tile Jong</a></strong> <em>(Webnetic, 8th Jan, $7.99)</em> - Dive into Tile Jong, a beautifully designed tile-matching game that blends relaxation with strategy! Solve engaging puzzles by selecting and matching sets of three identical tiles. Each level brings new challenges with increasingly intricate layouts that will test your concentration and problem-solving skills.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/ultimate_battle_simulator">ULTIMATE BATTLE SIMULATOR</a></strong> <em>(Play Games, 30th Dec, $9.99)</em> - ULTIMATE BATTLE SIMULATOR challenges you to master strategy, foresight, and precision placement. Command your army of NPC fighters, manage resources wisely, and outthink your enemies across varied battlefields. Whether you unleash endless ranks or rely on a few elite warriors, victory depends on your ability to plan, deploy, and adapt.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/van_life_home_simulator">Van Life: Home Simulator</a></strong> <em>(BurleaGamesStudio, 5th Jan, $7.99)</em> - Freedom comes with four wheels and a full tank of gas. Start with a dusty old van and turn it into your dream home—or flip it for profit and chase your next build. Whether you're in it for the thrill of renovation or the call of the open road, this game lets you live the nomadic dream, no GPS required. Explore a vibrant open world packed with hidden campsites, cozy lake views, and the occasional “did I take a wrong turn? ” mountain trail.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/wander_scoop">Wander Scoop</a></strong> <em>(REDDEER.GAMES, 1st Jan, $12.99)</em> - The Secret Ingredient: Empathy The true delight of Wander Scoop lies in the heartwarming cutscenes and dialogues. Every quirky character who slides onto a stool carries a personal puzzle and different ice cream flavors, and the process of making them serves as a metaphor for life’s challenges and joys. Level Up Your Cozy Kingdom Fortunately, guiding souls and making people happy can also be profitable!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/whiskers_warehouse_-_logic_puzzle_game">Whiskers Warehouse – Logic Puzzle Game</a></strong> <em>(EP Games, 5th Jan, $7.99)</em> - Master the art of strategic thinking in this modern take on classic Sokoban puzzles! With 1,000 meticulously crafted levels across 10 vibrant worlds, plus another 1,000 levels in New Game+ mode, you'll never run out of challenges. Start your journey through increasingly complex puzzles that will test your logic and spatial reasoning.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/zumba_-_marble_candy_rush">Zumba – Marble Candy Rush</a></strong> <em>(EpiXR, 8th Jan, $4.99)</em> - Zumba – Marble Candy Rush invites you into a delectable marble-shooter kingdom ruled by the Candy King! Select a level, aim your candy-cannon mouth, and fire to match three or more identical candy marbles before they spill past the sugar gate. Create explosive combos, clear waves swiftly, and earn up to three stars per level.</p>

<p><em>So that's your lot for this week's North American Nintendo Download. Go on, be a sport and drop a vote in the poll above, and comment below with your hot picks!</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/nintendo-download-8th-january-north-america]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why A 2025 Prediction For More Witcher 3 DLC Keeps Gaining Momentum]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/witcher-3-dlc-zerrikania-expansion-rumor-2000658222</link>
            <guid>1400881</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt-the-kotaku-review-1703766283"><i><span>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</span></i></a><span> turns 11 years old in May. Its last big update was a next-gen version released in 2022. But that hasn’t stopped speculation from mounting about a surprise expansion dropping sometime soon for the beloved open-world RPG.</span></p> <p><span>Rumors first began to swirl last summer, when prominent Polish leaker Borys Nieśpielak said he</span> <a href="https://kotaku.com/witcher-3-dlc-ciri-geralt-sequel-cdpr-2000655922"><span>suspected</span></a><span> developer CD Projekt Red might reveal new content for </span><i><span>The Witcher 3</span></i><span> at the Game Awards. And while this</span><a href="https://kotaku.com/everything-we-saw-at-the-2025-game-awards-2000652719"> <span>obviously didn’t come to pass</span></a><span>, rumors of the expansion’s possible existence have only continued to pile up in the months since:</span></p>

 <ul> <li aria-level="1"><span>During a November 2025 investor call, CD Projekt CFO Piotr Nielubowicz</span> <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/wp-content/uploads-en/2025/11/transcript-q3-2025-earnings-3.pdf"><span>implied</span></a><span> the existence of an unannounced product (via</span><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/is-there-really-going-to-be-a-2026-witcher-3-expansion"> <i><span>Eurogamer</span></i></a><span>), saying, “Given our current progress, there is a chance that new content hinted upon in recent calls and reports may see release in the coming year.”</span></li> <li aria-level="1"><span>CEO Michał Nowakowski also chimed in about a mystery project in a Q&amp;A session following the presentation, telling investors that a majority of the workforce at support studio Fool’s Theory is working on it (via</span><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-3-secret-expansion-rumors-swirl-after-cd-projekt-hints-at-new-content"> <i><span>IGN</span></i></a><span>), later noting this amounted to over 100 developers.</span></li> <li aria-level="1"><span>Polish Noble Securities analyst Mateusz Chrzanowski last month</span> <a href="https://strefainwestorow.pl/analizy/noblesecurities-cdprojekt-wiedzmin-dlc-orion-cyberpunk"><span>forecasted</span></a><span> a “paid add-on” with a budget of 52 million PLN (or around $14 million USD), scheduled for release in May 2026 (via</span><a href="https://www.dexerto.com/gaming/new-witcher-3-dlc-expected-in-early-2026-to-set-up-the-witcher-4-3297731"> <i><span>Dexerto</span></i></a><span>). “The release should kick off the actual marketing campaign for </span><i><span>The Witcher 4</span></i><span>,” Chrzanowski added, according to a rough machine translation.</span></li> <li aria-level="1"><span>The heart of Chzanowski’s prediction has to do with CD Projekt Red’s corporate incentive program for the studio, </span><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/witcher-3-expansion-rumours-analyst-100-percent-certain-cd-projekt-red-will-release-significant-new-content-this-year"><i><span>Eurogamer </span></i><span>reports</span></a><span>. “Currently, PLN 700 million [£144m] is needed to meet the first threshold, with only five quarters remaining,” Chrzanowski explained. “This implies the need for something significantly larger than just another update or a version for a niche platform.”</span></li> </ul> <h2>Why <em>Witcher</em> fans are talking about Zerrikania</h2> <p><span>Fast-forward to January 8. </span><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-3-expansion-reports-continue-now-with-discussion-of-a-possible-dune-style-location"><i><span>IGN Poland</span></i></a><span> reports local sources had previously known about a potential expansion to </span><i><span>The Witcher 3</span></i><span> for years. Furthermore, early rumors indicated the developers were at some point possibly interested in using an isolated, desert region known as Zerrikania as the add-on’s setting. Zerrikania is located to the east of the Northern Kingdoms (i.e. where most of </span><i><span>The Witcher</span></i><span> video game series takes place) and, according to</span> <a href="https://witcher.fandom.com/wiki/The_Wonders_of_Zerrikania"><span>an in-game book</span></a><span>, is home to dragon worship, tattooed “warriors maids,” and man-killing flies. Scary.</span></p>

 <p><span>With </span><i><span>The Witcher 4</span></i><span> planned to release</span> <a href="https://kotaku.com/witcher-4-2027-release-window-investor-call-ps6-cdpr-1851772310"><span>no sooner than January 2027</span></a><span>, it wouldn’t be shocking if CD Projekt wanted to fill the gap with something to tide fans over, especially if the long-awaited sequel slips into the next console generation. Of course, this is all still speculation, but the evidence is certainly building up to </span><i><span>something</span></i><span>.</span></p>

 <p><span>One thing we do know for sure is that sometime this year, </span><i><span>The Witcher 3</span></i><span> is getting </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/witcher-3-mod-support-ps5-xbox-final-patch-1851783100"><span>mod support on consoles</span></a><span>. The update was supposed to arrive last year but slipped to 2026. Hopefully that’s not all CDPR has planned. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/witcher-3-dlc-zerrikania-expansion-rumor-2000658222]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Seasonal Switch 2 sales show significant slowing as annual cycle sunsets]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2026/01/seasonal-switch-2-sales-show-significant-slowing-as-annual-cycle-sunsets/</link>
            <guid>1400878</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<p>Lingering sales of the original Switch might also be contributing to the relatively weak holiday performance for the Switch 2. In the UK, at least, the older console is still selling well enough to buoy Nintendo’s <em>overall</em> holiday hardware sales in the country to 7 percent higher than what the company achieved in 2017.</p>
<figure>
    <div id="caption-1417219"><p>
              Nintendo might need another <em>Super Mario Odyssey</em>-sized hit to keep up sales momentum for the Switch 2.
                              </p><p>
                  Credit:
                                      Nintendo
                                  </p>
                          </div>
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Nintendo might need another <em>Super Mario Odyssey</em>-sized hit to keep up sales momentum for the Switch 2.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Nintendo

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>That said, the transition from record-setting launch sales to relatively underwhelming holiday sales is a worrying sign for the Switch 2’s market momentum. A lack of system-selling Switch 2 exclusive games could explain that movement. In 2017, the October launch of <em>Super Mario Odyssey</em> built holiday excitement for the Switch on top of earlier hits like <em>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</em> and <em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</em>. For the Switch 2, holiday releases like <em>Pokémon Legends Z-A</em> and <em>Metroid Prime 4</em> don’t seem to have had as much impact as early system sellers like <em>Mario Kart World</em> and <em>Donkey Kong Bananza</em>.</p>
<p>Thus far, Nintendo’s planned 2026 schedule doesn’t seem primed to offer many big-name exclusive software to turn things around. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch/comments/1ok4hm6/nintendo_2026_graphic_update/">The year’s first-party lineup</a> is currently anchored by standard sequels for second-tier franchises like Yoshi, Mario Tennis, and Fire Emblem, alongside slightly upgraded “Switch 2 Edition” re-releases of popular Switch games. Aside from Nintendo’s own titles, the planned 2026 release of FromSoft’s <em>Bloodborne</em>-esque <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/04/switch-2-games-so-far-the-big-the-indie-the-unexpected-bloodborne-successor/"><em>Duskbloods</em></a> as a Switch 2 exclusive could make some fans of the company’s Souls-like games take a second look at the hardware.</p>
<p>Nintendo is likely to announce more Switch 2 exclusives and ports in the coming months, of course. Having a few system-selling blockbusters in that slate could be crucial to propping up the Switch 2’s sales now that pent-up launch-window demand seems largely satiated.</p>


          
                  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2026/01/seasonal-switch-2-sales-show-significant-slowing-as-annual-cycle-sunsets/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Some Believe A Witcher 3 Expansion Is Coming Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/why-some-believe-a-witcher-3-expansion-is-coming-soon/1100-6537282/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1400875</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537282">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Near the end of 2024, CD Projekt Red put <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-witcher-4/" data-ref-id="5000-561041">The Witcher 4</a> into full development with a release date potentially years away. Now, some outlets are putting forth theories that there may be a new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt/" data-ref-id="5000-167462">Witcher 3</a> expansion to fill the gap between the present and the fourth game's release.</p><p><a href="https://pl.ign.com/wiedzmin-3/69405/news/wiedzmin-3-nowe-dlc-zabierze-nas-na-pustynie-ujawniamy-nasze-informacje-sprzed-lat-i-rzucamy-nowe-sw?_gl=1*15mojc3*_up*MQ..*_ga*MTI2MzU0NjY5LjE3Njc4OTI3MzQ.*_ga_736S6FVMCL*czE3Njc4OTI3MzQkbzEkZzAkdDE3Njc4OTI3MzQkajYwJGwwJGgw" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IGN Poland</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/witcher-3-expansion-rumours-analyst-100-percent-certain-cd-projekt-red-will-release-significant-new-content-this-year" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a> separately released stories suggesting that The Witcher 3 will get its first expansion since Blood and Wine was released in 2016. Eurogamer's report suggests that the drive to release something new this year is because CD Projekt Red is behind sales goals that would trigger financial incentives for its employees.</p><p>That program has been <a href="https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/wp-content/uploads-en/2025/11/transcript-q3-2025-earnings-3.pdf" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">mentioned by the company itself</a>, which stated in a 2025 investor's call that, "There is a chance that new content hinted upon in recent calls and reports may see release in the coming year, having an impact on our results and increasing the likelihood of achieving the earnings condition for the first stage of the incentive program."</p><p>The report from IGN Poland offers some speculative details about what The Witcher 3 expansion may contain, including Zerrikania, "an exotic desert region to the far east of The Witcher 3's current map." Blood and Wine did refer to the Zerrikanian Manticore School, which could be followed-up on if the report is accurate.</p><p>For now, neither report is confirmed. CD Projekt Red has only announced that The Witcher 3 will get <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/witcher-3-adding-a-big-new-feature-10-years-after-launch/1100-6531938/" data-ref-id="1100-6531938">one final update</a> that will allow console players to enjoy many of the mods that PC players have used for years. However, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-witcher-3s-last-patch-is-delayed/1100-6535045/" data-ref-id="1100-6535045">that update was pushed back to this year</a> late in 2025. Outside of the games, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/witcher-season-5-coming-this-year-will-end-the-series/1100-6537256/" data-ref-id="1100-6537256">The Witcher Season 5</a> will wrap up its run on Netflix in 2026.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/why-some-believe-a-witcher-3-expansion-is-coming-soon/1100-6537282/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>