<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:28:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Legendary Developer And Insect Blocker Hideki Kamiya Is Getting His Own Book]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/legendary-developer-and-insect-blocker-hideki-kamiya-is-getting-his-own-book</link>
            <guid>1423771</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Welcome to my world</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="83238df4a3f5f"><a title="Kamiya Book 1" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/83238df4a3f5f/kamiya-book-1.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Hideki Kamiya, the legendary game developer behind titles like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/resident_evil_2">Resident Evil 2</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/bayonetta">Bayonetta</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/viewtiful_joe">Viewtiful Joe</a>, is getting his own book.</p>
<p>Titled <strong>'The World of Hideki Kamiya'</strong>, the book is currently only confirmed for release in Japan on <strong>2nd April 2026</strong>, but we'll be keeping a close eye on a potential western release. Naturally, it will cover Kamiya's career, with the creator providing his own thoughts on some of the games he's made over the years.</p>
<p>Not only that, but you can also expect to find over 100 examples of concept art from his games. Heck, even the front cover is an absolute banger, showcasing the likes of Dante from <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/devil_may_cry">Devil May Cry,</a> Leon and Claire from Resident Evil 2, and Amaterasu from <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/okami">Okami</a>.</p><div><figure data-videoid="53peCvnRDq8" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/53peCvnRDq8?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt53peCvnRDq8" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/53peCvnRDq8?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/53peCvnRDq8?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3938a0tquvni&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Speaking of which, Kamiya is currently hard at work on the official sequel to Okami at his new studio Clovers in collaboration with Capcom. There's no word on when the game might release, but we're very excited to see more.</p>
<p>For now, here's a look at the front cover for The World of Hideki Kamiya:</p>
<figure data-uuid="122017a2ee5fe"><a title="Kamiya Book 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/122017a2ee5fe/kamiya-book-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Kadokawa</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Fellow game developer Yoko Taro <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/hideki-kamiyas-block-happy-take-no-crappery-is-super-reassuring-says-yoko-taro">recently commented</a> on Kamiya's penchant for blocking users (or "insects", as Kamiya calls them) on social media. He noted that "it’s a net positive to instil that fear that there are some game creators who do have that edge", praising Kamiya for seemingly taking a stand.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:196866,195734 @ 1770123496 -->
<p><em>Are you keen to see a book focused on Hideki Kamiya's career hit western shores? Let us know your thoughts with a comment.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.famitsu.com/article/202602/64920" rel="noopener" href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202602/64920">famitsu.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/5470cb77d1b2afb2c200d592f05f3231 @ 1770124895 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/legendary-developer-and-insect-blocker-hideki-kamiya-is-getting-his-own-book]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yes, Star Wars: Galactic Racer Has Podracing]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/yes-star-wars-galactic-racer-has-podracing/</link>
            <guid>1423768</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-galactic-racer-the-game-awards-2025-fuse-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announcement of <strong>Star Wars: Galactic Racer</strong> at <strong>The Game Awards 2025</strong></a> was among the most unexpected. It had been many years since there was a Star Wars-themed racing game, so many gamers were overjoyed at the news. At the same time, it was not clear based on the released footage, screenshots, and info whether the game would include <strong>Podracing</strong>, the high-speed fictional sport featured prominently in the movie <strong>Star Wars: The Phantom Menace</strong>, in which a very young <strong>Anakin Skywalker</strong> enters and wins a podrace. The most popular older racing games, Star Wars Episode I: Racer, Star Wars: Racer Arcade, and Star Wars Racer Revenge, all prominently featured Podracing.</p>



<p>Now, though, <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/racing/the-outer-rim-is-your-highway-in-star-wars-galactic-racer-but-its-more-than-burnout-in-space-you-cant-make-a-star-wars-racing-experience-and-not-have-podracing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in an interview with Gamesradar</a>, <strong>Fuse Games</strong> CEO and co-founder <strong>Matt Webster</strong> confirmed that <strong>Podracing is indeed available in their upcoming title</strong>, albeit alongside other vehicle types:</p>



<p><em>You can’t really make a Star Wars racing experience and not have Podracing, can you? The core fantasy of the game is becoming an elite racing pilot in the Galactic League, and Podracing is a pinnacle of speed and racing in the Star Wars galaxy. However, when we set out to create Galactic Racer, we wanted to do more – to lean into multiple vehicle types and multiple expressions of speed to give players a breadth of experiences. Star Wars: Galactic Racer offers players the ability to pilot vehicles they know and love, alongside ones they won’t have experienced before, across a range of solo and multiplayer modes</em>.</p>



<p>Star Wars: Galactic Racer doesn't have a release date yet, but publisher <strong>Secret Mode</strong> is planning to launch it at some point in 2026 on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S and X. There's still a lot we don't know, except for the fact that tracks based on the <strong>Jakku</strong>, <strong>Ando Prime</strong> and <strong>Sentinel One</strong> planets have been confirmed. We also know that there will be a story-driven campaign, as well as competitive online PvP racing with a ranking system.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/yes-star-wars-galactic-racer-has-podracing/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft reportedly fire Assassin's Creed designer who spoke out publicly against return-to-office, as union reps call for CEO to resign]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-reportedly-fire-assassins-creed-designer-who-spoke-out-publicly-against-return-to-office-as-union-reps-call-for-ceo-to-resign</link>
            <guid>1423765</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>David Michaud-Cromp posted last week that the company had suspended him for "alleged breach of the duty of loyalty"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/naoe-in-master-assassin-armor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/naoe-in-master-assassin-armor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/naoe-in-master-assassin-armor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/naoe-in-master-assassin-armor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/naoe-in-master-assassin-armor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/naoe-in-master-assassin-armor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/naoe-in-master-assassin-armor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/naoe-in-master-assassin-armor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/naoe-in-master-assassin-armor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/Ubisoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>An Assassin's Creed designer who publicly spoke out against Ubisoft's return-to-office mandate claims the company have now fired him. Developer David Michaud-Cromp <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-designer-claims-ubisoft-have-suspended-him-for-alleged-breach-of-the-duty-of-loyalty-over-new-rto-policy">posted on LinkedIn last week</a> that he'd been put on unpaid disciplinary leave after recently criticising the policy change on the social media platform.</p>
<p>If you're out of the loop, Ubisoft have recently revealed plans to push remote staff back into offices amid a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake-and-more-cancelled-by-ubisoft-with-layoffs-potentially-on-the-horizon">bloodbath of game cancellations, restructuring and voluntary redundancies</a>. The company intend to have employees return to working in-office five days a week, with an annual allowance of work-from-home days. All of these moves have understandably not gone down well with French unions, who've <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/unionised-french-ubisoft-workers-put-out-call-for-an-international-strike-held-by-all-current-employees">subsequently called strike action</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>This brings us to Michaud-Cromp's latest <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7424133083051978757/">LinkedIn post</a>, in which the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/assassins-creed-codename-red">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a> team lead wrote he'd been "terminated by Ubisoft, effective immediately". "This was not my decision. I won’t be discussing internal details or circumstances. I’m taking time to regroup and will share next steps when appropriate," he added.</p>
<p>Asked about the firing, Ubisoft provided the following statement to <a href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-montreal-lead-fired-david-michaud-cromp-work-from-home-linkedin-2000665081">Kotaku</a> via a spokesperson: "Sharing feedback or opinions respectfully does not lead to a dismissal. We have a clear Code of Conduct that outlines our shared expectations for working together safely and respectfully, which employees review and sign each year. When that is breached, our established procedures apply, including an escalation of measures depending on the nature, severity, and repetition of the breach."</p><p>Speaking to Kotaku, Michaud-Cromp offered more of his view on remote work, outlining that in his estimation nailing "fundamentals like clarity of goals, trust, documentation, tooling, and communication practices" often has more of an impact on the effectiveness of teams than how physically close their members are from 9 to 5.</p>
<p>Ubisoft's decision to force staff back into the office, potentially costing those who can't do so due to various personal circumstances their jobs, has been one of the main areas the unions organising strikes on behalf of Ubisoft staff they represent object to. A number of staff have <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-union-representatives-call-for-resignation-of-ceo-yves-guillemot">reportedly</a> been left feeling as though they've suffered a "betrayal" at the hands of top management they can't trust. In that same article from Game Developer, two Ubisoft devs who serve as representatives for the Solidaires Informatique union - Marc Rutschlé and Chakib Mataoui - have publicly called for CEO Yves Guillemot to resign.</p>
<p>"I think Guillemot should move away at this point," Rutschlé said. "I think the level of hate people have for him [means] he should move on. Then, we could build some sort of trust again."</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-reportedly-fire-assassins-creed-designer-who-spoke-out-publicly-against-return-to-office-as-union-reps-call-for-ceo-to-resign]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest VII Reimagined: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-review-remake-steam-switch-ps5-rpg-2000665143</link>
            <guid>1423759</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Western RPG fans are finally becoming </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span>-curious thanks to Square Enix’s recent spate of re-releases and remakes. The past couple of years alone have given us </span><i><span>Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake </span></i><span>on top of </span><i><span>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</span></i><span>, updated versions of the three games that form the bedrock of the </span><i><span>Dragon Quest </span></i><span>series. These releases have also been a touch confusing, as the remake of </span><i><span>Dragon Quest III</span></i><span> was released before </span><i><span>Dragon Quest I &amp; 2</span></i><span>.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Square has decided to muddy things up further by giving us </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> before the expected </span><i><span>Dragon Quest IV</span></i> <i><span>HD-2D Remake. </span></i><span>What’s more, </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> utilizes bright, cartoony 3D character models instead of the HD-2D pixel art style of the earlier remakes. Thankfully, the models animate well, and they look particularly cool in battle. </span></p>

 <p><span>But </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span>‘s makeover also comes with quality-of-life tweaks that make for a much more streamlined gameplay experience than the Nintendo 3DS version of </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII, </span></i><span>which itself had already streamlined the original PSX version of the game. Some of the tweaks even make the game a good starting point for </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> newcomers who are worried the games might be too difficult for them. But </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span> is always going to be </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span> at the end of the day. It’s always going to be an imperfect RPG that has problems with pacing and a strange cast that I’ll never warm up to. (Barring Ruff, obviously.)&nbsp;</span></p> <p><span>Nonetheless, playing </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> is still fun as heck and it’s great to see </span><i><span>Dragon Quest </span></i><span>gain some momentum over here. As a long-suffering </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> fan who’s watched the series’ popularity gradually tick upwards in recent years, it gives me great pleasure to say this: Square Enix’s </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> is a great entry in a series that finally—</span><i><span>finally</span></i><span>!—has us western </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> fans spoiled for choice.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Ooooh, let me say that again: </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> fans are “spoiled for choice these days.” Shiver</span><i><span>.</span></i></p> <p><span>But</span><i><span> Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> might give pause to series’ newcomers and veterans alike, since </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span> is generally not named amongst beloved entries like</span><i><span> Dragon Quest III, V</span></i><span>, and </span><i><span>XI</span></i><span>. 2000’s </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span> for the PSX has a notoriously slow start that noodles away hours before you’re allowed your first taste of combat. It’s also not much of a looker, which is a shallow thing to say, but we were deep in PS2-mania by the time it came west. In any case, </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span> was ignored when it came to North America.</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000665145" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000665145"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000665145">©Square Enix</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Square Enix has never given up on trying to get westerners to like </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span>—not for more than a handful of years at one time, anyway—and we received </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII’</span></i><span>s full Nintendo 3DS make-over (subtitled “Fragments of the Forgotten Past”) in 2016. This iteration of </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span> fared better here: For one thing, westerners had stopped trying to hurt themselves by denying </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> as their lord and saviour by this point, and for another,</span><i><span> Fragments of the Forgotten Past </span></i><span>did a lot of trimming and slimming on the PSX game. The long introduction was nerfed, random encounters were done away with in favor of on-screen enemies, and other changes made it much easier to recommend the </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> series’ blackest of black sheep to newcomers.&nbsp;</span></p> <h2><b>Reimagine Dragons</b></h2> <p><span>Well, move on over Nintendo 3DS, because the award for “Most Digestible Version of </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span>” now goes to </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> for consoles and PC. Additional streamlining makes for a much snappier experience compared to previous releases, and the storybook-style environments and animations look wonderful. All that’s left is to evaluate </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> alongside other games in the series. </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span> is a rather linear game by design, with a story that tasks you and your pals with saving the world. It doesn’t feel as open and free as </span><i><span>Dragon Quest XI</span></i><span>, or even older titles like </span><i><span>VIII</span></i><span> or </span><i><span>III</span></i><span>. It’s still not a short game: You’re looking at around 60 hours. But if you like focused quests served to you with as few distractions as possible, expect some good eating here.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>While </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> is the best version of </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span> still isn’t my favorite </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> game. (At least I still like it more than </span><i><span>VI</span></i><span>.) That doesn’t mean much in the context of the series. Like pizza, a </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> game is never actually </span><i><span>bad</span></i><span>. It just doesn’t have your preferred toppings. Exploration is one of the things I love most about </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span>, but </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined </span></i><span>has you hopping from one small island to the next, and most of them don’t offer a lot of opportunities to get sidetracked on your journey. You’re usually there just long enough to beat up whatever dark force is plaguing the area. Then you zip back to the future and admire your holy handiwork as a new “rediscovered” island resurfaces on your map.&nbsp;</span></p> <div>       <div>                                         <figure>                            </figure>                           <div>                      <p>             Dragon Quest VII Reimagined           </p>                                       </div>       </div>               <div>           <ul>                           <li>                 <p>Back-of-the-box quote:</p>                 <p>"Dragon Quest VII, only it's better than the last time they made it better."</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>developer:</p>                 <p>Square Enix</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>type of game:</p>                 <p>RPG</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>Liked:</p>                 <p>Wonderful environment and creature designs, double-fisting jobs is fun, even more bloat has been cut from the 3DS version of DQ7.</p>               </li>                               </ul><ul>                                         <li>                 <p>disliked:</p>                 <p>Linear progression, so-so character roster.</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>platforms:</p>                 <p>Nintendo Switch, Nintendo Switch 2 (played on), PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, PC</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>release date:</p>                 <p>February 5, 2026</p>               </li>                                         <li>                 <p>played:</p>                 <p>Rolled credits at about 60 hours, but haven't done post-game stuff.</p>               </li>                                     </ul>         </div>           </div>  <p><span>Yes, </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> is technically about time travel. You, as the Chosen One, quickly learn there’s more to life than the single island your family lives on, and you must dip back in time to solve the problems that keep each individual island shrouded in the dark. The further you progress, the more you learn about the apocalyptic war that cut the humans off from each other and allowed monsters to roam the world. But what can be done can also be undone. You know what you must do™.</span></p> <h2><b>Get a Job (Heck, get two!)</b></h2> <p><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> also saddles me with the </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span> cast again, and they’re just not my favorite group. The hero is the typical wordless Toriyama-designed </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> homunculus the player drives through the game. Maribel is abrasive, though she does soften up as the quest goes on. And there’s something wrong with Kiefer’s face. Every time I look at it, my brain screams what I can only describe as an ancestral warning not to turn my back on him lest he might shank me.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>It might be that </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined’</span></i><span>s art style is just better suited for environments and monsters than humanoid characters. Unlike Kiefer, Ruff the wolf boy looks like he’s in his element. Something about his goofy perpetual grin meshes perfectly with the world and creatures around him. Speaking of creatures, the late, great Akira Toriyama whipped up a whole bunch of new critters for </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span>, and they all translate brilliantly into </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span>‘s 3D space. Not only are the monster designs peak (as per usual with </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span>), they animate fluidly too. Fur, scales, and metal are all textured and look fantastic.&nbsp;</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000665147" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000665147"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000665147">©Square Enix</figcaption></figure> <p><span>I do miss having costumes for each job like with </span><i><span>Fragments of the Forgotten Past </span></i><span>(Ruff and his wolf pal just belong in sheep costumes), but it’s the trade-off for one of </span><i><span>Reimagined</span></i><span>‘s better examples of streamlining: The dual job system, which lets you learn more than one job at a time. Yes, </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span> has a job system, but you’re going to be disappointed if you expect the kind of character fine-tuning that </span><i><span>Final Fantasy V</span></i><span> allows. </span></p>

 <p><span>You only have access to a job’s skills for as long as you’re wielding that job. The idea is to open up as many jobs as possible by mastering other jobs, until you finally unlock the high-tier jobs you’re going to want to keep for the rest of the game. “Learning” jobs feels more like speedrunning them in </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span>, but the job mixing and matching means you can make some pretty sick combinations of skills and spells that compliment each other. By the end of the game each fight starts to resemble a miniature episode of </span><i><span>Dragon Ball Z</span></i><span> as you and your foes trade blows of fire, ice, lighting, and steel.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p> <h2><b>Do a Little Island-Hopping</b></h2> <p><span>The dual job system helps make </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> one of the friendlier </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> games for beginners. It’s not exactly easy, and bosses will still whup your under-prepared ass on a bad day. But it also lets you pull from a common pool of items in a fight (not something </span><i><span>Dragon Quest </span></i><span>games typically let you do), and HP/MP restoration points are plentiful. The random battles are still gone here, same as they’re gone on the 3DS, but </span><i><span>Reimagined</span></i><span> does you one better by letting you attack and kill weaker enemies on the overfield. You’re not awarded as much experience for these fights, but the rewards still add up and you build levels very quickly compared to other </span><i><span>Dragon Quest </span></i><span>games.</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000665148" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000665148"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000665148">©Square Enix</figcaption></figure> <p><span>This is the point where I infuriate people who ask me, “But is </span><i><span>this</span></i><span> the </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> game I should start with if I’m new to the series?” </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> is not a bad place to start thanks to its lower difficulty and simple-to-grok job system. But I personally wouldn’t recommend it, especially if you prefer games that let you wander far and wide. </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> is a wonderful remake of </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII</span></i><span> 2000, but as I said earlier, all </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII </span></i><span>can be is itself with its small islands, portals, and a lot of walking back and forth to fix specific problems like appeasing an active volcano or helping a kingdom fight against rampaging robots. I’d more easily recommend </span><i><span>Dragon Quest XI, </span></i><span>which is a great entry point for anyone curious about 3D </span><i><span>Dragon Quest.</span></i><span> And of course, there’s the trio of HD-2D games that lay out the origin of everything </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> is about. There’s nothing wrong with choosing </span><i><span>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</span></i><span> as your first </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span>, but remember what I said before? We </span><i><span>Dragon Quest</span></i><span> fans are spoiled for choice now. And with that last thought, celebrate and revel in our good fortune.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dragon-quest-vii-reimagined-review-remake-steam-switch-ps5-rpg-2000665143]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Wants To Use Gen-AI To Feed You Fake Podcasts Voiced by PlayStation Characters]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sony-gen-ai-fake-podcast-playstation-characters/</link>
            <guid>1423756</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Have you ever sat there and wondered how cool it would be to listen to a fake podcast presented by God of War’s Kratos or Ellie from The Last of Us? No? Well, you’re probably not alone. But for some reason, Sony thinks that’s <strong>exactly </strong>what people want, as a recently discovered patent reveals that the tech titan plans to use generative AI to facilitate such a concept.</p>



<p>In an uncovered filing, the ‘LLM-Based Generative Podcasts for Gamers’ proposal was unearthed, and it would use generative AI to create <strong>personalized podcasts </strong>voiced by some of PlayStation’s most iconic characters.</p>







<h2 id="h-who-wants-to-listen-to-ai-delivered-podcasts">Who Wants To Listen to AI-Delivered Podcasts?</h2>



<p>Sony’s latest patent publication aims to use a gamer’s personal profile to piece together an AI-driven podcast feed hosted by their favorite first-party characters. That means you could have Ghost of Tsushima’s Jin Sakai’s dulcet tones in your ear, moulded by AI, giving you the lowdown on gaming news that might interest you.</p>



<p>The background <a href="https://patentscope.wipo.int/search/en/detail.jsf?docId=US471594142&amp;_cid=P22-MKTGE2-37885-1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">of the patent</a>, submitted in 2024 but only just published on the WIPO platform, explains:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>As recognized herein, video game platforms currently lack the ability to provide unique and targeted content to gamers to update the gamers about things that are happening on the platform. There are currently no adequate solutions to the foregoing computer-related, technological problem.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><em>(Thanks to <a href="https://tech4gamers.com/sony-patents-podcasts-games-gen-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Tech4Gamers</a> for the spot)</em></p>



<p>The lengthy summary of the proposed patent goes on to detail using an LLM (Large Language Model) to identify data associated with your PlayStation profile and then <strong>generate a podcast of news related to that data</strong>.</p>



<p>It would then be reeled off by a video game character of a game <strong>played by the video game player</strong>.</p>



<p>This could then be paired with video footage, trailers, screenshots, and other media.</p>



<p>But it would get pretty personal. The filing revealed how ‘the audio may include a joke at the video game player’s expense.’ Which means you could be roasted by a generative-AI podcast voiced by your favorite characters. Because that’s what we, as gamers, want.</p>



<p>The patent filing came with images that showed how this would fit on your PlayStation dashboard:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Another image showed how a video podcast using this same format would work, using ‘desk hosts’ to give players something visual to focus on:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>At no point in the filing does it indicate how the voice actors for these characters would potentially be compensated or represented via this technology. It could be a nightmare for the actors who brought these characters to life, as while it’s their voices that are being used ad infinitum, the <strong>characters </strong>and their personas are owned by PlayStation and the vast number of studios under that banner.</p>







<p>Do you think there are any major concerns regarding this patent, and would you want to listen to gen-AI podcasts featuring your favorite characters? Let us know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/paul-heyman-wwe-2k26-play-instead-fortnite-call-of-duty/">Paul Heyman wants you to ditch Call of Duty for WWE 2K26</a></p>


        <div>
              <!-- Row 1: Avatar + Name/Title + Socials -->
              <div>
                  <p><span>Written by</span>
                    
                                      </p>

                  <p>
                      Senior Editor and Esports Lead                    </p>
                                  </div>

              <!-- Row 2: Bio + CTA -->
                              <div>
                  <p>
                    Grant's adoration for gaming started on the Amstrad CPC in 1996. Now, he's a multi-platform expert gamer with a deep love for the industry, a passion for esports, and more…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/grant-taylor-hill/">
                    More from Grant Taylor-Hill                  </a>
                </p></div>
                          </div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/sony-gen-ai-fake-podcast-playstation-characters/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake press kits seemingly included a collectible dagger, further cementing just how darn close the game was to r]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake-press-kits-seemingly-included-a-collectible-dagger-further-cementing-just-how-darn-close-the-game-was-to-release</link>
            <guid>1423753</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alleged-Prince-of-Persia-The-Sands-of-Time-Remake-press-kit-dagger-collectible-on-a-display-stand.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alleged-Prince-of-Persia-The-Sands-of-Time-Remake-press-kit-dagger-collectible-on-a-display-stand.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alleged-Prince-of-Persia-The-Sands-of-Time-Remake-press-kit-dagger-collectible-on-a-display-stand.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alleged-Prince-of-Persia-The-Sands-of-Time-Remake-press-kit-dagger-collectible-on-a-display-stand.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alleged-Prince-of-Persia-The-Sands-of-Time-Remake-press-kit-dagger-collectible-on-a-display-stand.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alleged-Prince-of-Persia-The-Sands-of-Time-Remake-press-kit-dagger-collectible-on-a-display-stand.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alleged-Prince-of-Persia-The-Sands-of-Time-Remake-press-kit-dagger-collectible-on-a-display-stand.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alleged-Prince-of-Persia-The-Sands-of-Time-Remake-press-kit-dagger-collectible-on-a-display-stand.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alleged-Prince-of-Persia-The-Sands-of-Time-Remake-press-kit-dagger-collectible-on-a-display-stand.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>via Quiver/YouTube</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>It appears that the press kit for Ubisoft's cancelled <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake</a> would have included a collectible dagger.</p>
<p>A video which allegedly shows off this collectible was recently shared online, with the dagger being unpacked from a wooden box with Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake markings.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>The purported Sands of Time dagger itself, meanwhile, featured a golden painted hilt and iridescent resin-looking blade (thanks, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-collectible-dagger-looks-to-have-popped-up-in-an-unboxing-video-days-after-games-cancelation">IGN</a>). As well as the dagger, this unboxing video (which you can see below) included a display stand within the box, which again had the game's name written across it in gold writing.</p>
<p>While this dagger is, for now, only an alleged collectible for Ubisoft's Sands of Time remake, which would have been part of the press Kit sent out to media, many have said its reported existence shows just how close the Prince of Persia team was to releasing its game.</p><p>As a reminder, Ubisoft's Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-details-whats-new-in-its-prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake">unveiled in 2020</a>, but suffered numerous delays and setbacks since. This included the game seemingly being <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/three-years-on-ubisofts-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-is-still-in-the-conception-phase">rebooted from scratch</a> in 2023. However, it seemed the great wait was coming to an end, as towards the end of last year, Ubisoft itself had its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/five-years-later-ubisofts-much-delayed-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-gets-the-closest-thing-to-a-release-date-yet">Sands of Time Remake slated for release during"Q4" of the current financial year</a>, which comes to an end on 31st March. So, in just a couple of months.</p>
<p>Alas, it wasn't to be, though, and last month <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisofts-troubled-prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-is-dead-as-publisher-kills-multiple-projects-closes-studios-and-orders-staff-back-to-the-office">Ubisoft announced a "major organisational, operational and portfolio reset"</a>, which saw the company delay seven unspecified projects, close two studios and cancel multiple games including its Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake.</p>
<p>Eurogamer has Ubisoft for comment on the alleged <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time</a> press kit.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake [UNRELEASED PRESS KIT] Unboxing" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bUDpym7hwx0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake [UNRELEASED PRESS KIT] Unboxing</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bUDpym7hwx0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bUDpym7hwx0?autoplay=1" title="Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake [UNRELEASED PRESS KIT] Unboxing">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake [UNRELEASED PRESS KIT] Unboxing. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bUDpym7hwx0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Soon after Ubisoft announced its company reset, the team behind Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time's embattled remake shared a few words of its own, acknowledging the cancellation was "deeply disappointing" for fans. However, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sands-of-times-shock-cancellation-does-not-mean-we-are-stepping-away-from-the-franchise-says-remake-team">it was keen to stress this "does not mean [its] stepping away from the franchise" for good</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake-press-kits-seemingly-included-a-collectible-dagger-further-cementing-just-how-darn-close-the-game-was-to-release]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roku Goes Big for the Super Bowl With Nearly 50% Off Its 2025 Streaming Stick HD]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/roku-goes-big-for-the-super-bowl-with-nearly-50-off-its-2025-streaming-stick-hd-2000665111</link>
            <guid>1423741</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>How old is the television sitting in your living room? Does it lack smart features and built-in streaming apps altogether? Or maybe it is a smart TV, but you’re simply not a fan of the manufacturer’s interface (yes, LG, this means your wannabe Wiimote-style motion controls). The good news is that you don’t have to stay stuck with whatever functionality your TV shipped with on day one. Grab a Roku streaming stick for next to nothing, and suddenly you’ve got a clean, dependable way to stream your favorite content and move through apps with ease. Under normal circumstances, the 2025 Roku Streaming Stick HD sells for around $30. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4493/">Right now, though, Amazon is offering a limited-time discount that drops the price by almost half, bringing it down to just $16.</a></p>
<p>This is the bare bones Roku streaming stick. This one doesn’t support 4K or HDR, but that’s not such a bad thing. The TV you’re putting it on might not support those either, so why pay extra for support you can’t actually take advantage of? Plus, so much content is only available in up to 1080p anyway so you’re really not missing out much.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4493/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>The Roku streaming stick is super low profile. It’s compact design allows it to just plug into an HDMI port on the back of your TV. It’s small enough that it won’t rudely block the other HDMI slots so you can still use them all for consoles or cable boxes or whatnot. The TV is also it’s source of power, so it won’t be taking up a valuable outlet along your power strip either.</p>
<h2>One Remote for Everything</h2>
<p>With the Roku streaming stick setup, you can use it’s remote to replace your TV remote for most daily use. It has volume controls and power controls, so unless you’re trying to adjust some specific setting on your TV (like turning off motion smoothing which you should be doing), the Roku remote will be the only remote you need to have out on your coffee table.</p>



<p>The remote even has a built-in voice function. This can be super useful when trying to pull up a specific movie or show. It’s far, far easier to just speak the words, “Jay &amp; Silent Bob Strike Back,” then it is to type all that out on a digital keyboard with arrow keys.</p>
<h2>Watch It All</h2>
<p>Not only does a Roku streaming device allow for you to access all the great streaming apps like HBO Max, Netflix, Hulu, and Apple TV, but Roku even comes with a number of free TV channels&nbsp; with live news, weather, sports coverage, and more. That number is over 500, actually.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4493/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/roku-goes-big-for-the-super-bowl-with-nearly-50-off-its-2025-streaming-stick-hd-2000665111]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reanimal Release Date Countdown, Exact Start Times & All Platforms]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/reanimal-release-date-platforms/</link>
            <guid>1423738</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A terrifying new experience lies around the corner with the highly-anticipated release of Reanimal, which is set to make a splash upon its release date.</p>



<p>Coming from the developers of Little Nightmares 2, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/reanimal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reanimal</a> offers a co-op <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/genres/horror/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">horror</a> adventure through a disturbing world, and expectations are high for the Tarsier Studios title.</p>



<p>For all the release date details, the exact start time you can jump in and play, and all the platforms Reanimal is available on, Insider Gaming has you covered.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-the-reanimal-release-date">What is The Reanimal Release Date?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Frightening. Image by Tarsier Studios.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Reanimal’s official release date is Friday, February 13, though the date may change depending on where you are located in the world.</strong></p>



<p>THQ Nordic has adopted a global release structure for Reanimal, meaning the game becomes available to all players around the world simultaneously. In some regions, this means Reanimal will actually be released on February 14.</p>



<h2 id="h-reanimal-start-times">Reanimal Start Times</h2>



<p><strong>Reanimal releases at 6 AM PT on February 13, and the global release means simultaneous access for all players across the world.</strong></p>



<p>While this approach is familiar to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/pc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PC</a> players, it may be a different experience for those on console, where many releases adopt a staggered release. When a staggered release is available, it opens the door for some ways to access games early. However, this isn’t the case for Reanimal.</p>



<p>All the start times for Reanimal in major regions across the world are shown in the table below. Confirmation of the start times comes via the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/EP4389-PPSA23372_00-ANIMALGAMEGLOBAL?gclsrc=aw.ds&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gad_campaignid=14799736276&amp;gbraid=0AAAAADtLsqzzhyq21kgs5P_mNxvWxca6g&amp;gclid=CjwKCAiA1obMBhAbEiwAsUBbIsN0ZM7rsmkFMEJKbNtVK7mroKhXYUIcolb-aifIAV3nvNu6IwRTpRoCG3wQAvD_BwE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation Store</a> and <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2129530/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Reanimal Start Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">6 AM – Feb. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">8 AM – Feb. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">9 AM – Feb. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)</td><td data-align="center">2 PM – Feb. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Time (AET)</td><td data-align="center">1 AM – Feb. 14</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-all-reanimal-platforms">All Reanimal Platforms</h2>



<p><strong>Reanimal is available across multiple platforms on its launch date, with Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, PC, and Nintendo Switch 2, allowing all players to jump in.</strong></p>



<p>There is no release on last-gen consoles, however, so those on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/xbox-one/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox One</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/ps4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation 4</a>, and the original <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/platforms/nintendo-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch</a> will have to miss out.</p>



<p>Physical editions are also available immediately at launch, including a Collector’s Edition, and future DLC content is planned.</p>







<hr>



<p>What are your expectations for Reanimal? Share your thoughts on the game with other players in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/complete-reanimal-trophy-list-how-to-get-all-achievements-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full Reanimal achievements and trophy list</a>, and check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/high-on-life-2-release-date-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">release date details for High on Life 2</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/reanimal-release-date-platforms/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[High on Life 2 Release Date Countdown, Exact Start Times & All Platforms]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/high-on-life-2-release-date-platforms/</link>
            <guid>1423732</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Major releases continuen to come thick and fast in 2026, including the release of High on Life 2 this month, providing another foul-mouthed adventure to enjoy.</p>



<p>Squanch Games’ sequel to the initial title of the same name is set to make a mark when it lands, and Insider Gaming has all the important details on the release date, start times, and available platforms.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-is-the-high-on-life-2-release-date">What is The High on Life 2 Release Date?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Foul-mouthed. Image via Squand Games</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>High on Life 2 releases on Friday, February 13, though this may vary based on where you are located in the world.</strong></p>



<p>The release structure for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/high-on-life-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">High on Life 2</a> is global, becoming available to all players around the world simultaneously, which means that, for some regions, High on Life 2 will actually be released on February 14.</p>



<h2 id="h-high-on-life-2-start-times">High on Life 2 Start Times</h2>



<p><strong>High on Life 2 will be playable at 7 AM PT on February 13, with a global release resulting in simultaneous access for all players worldwide.</strong></p>



<p>The global release structure will be familiar to PC players, though many console releases instead adopt a staggered release. However, there’s no such approach on console for High on Life 2; no matter where you are located or the platform you are playing on, High on Life 2 is accessible at the same moment.</p>



<p>All the start times for High on Life 2 in major regions worldwide are shown in the table below. Confirmation of the start times comes via the <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP3024-PPSA30094_00-0334583576730525" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PlayStation Store</a> and <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2069250/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">High on Life 2 Start Time</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Time (PT)</td><td data-align="center">7 AM – Feb. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Time (CT)</td><td data-align="center">9 AM – Feb. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Time (ET)</td><td data-align="center">10 AM – Feb. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)</td><td data-align="center">3 PM – Feb. 13</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Time (AET)</td><td data-align="center">2 AM – Feb. 14</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-all-high-on-life-2-platforms">All High on Life 2 Platforms</h2>



<p><strong>High on Life 2 releases on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S and PC on February 13, but only digitally.</strong></p>



<p>Physical editions of High on Life 2 are not available until April 20, 2026, with a Nintendo Switch 2 version of the game set to launch on the same date.</p>



<p>Unlike the first game in the series, High on Life 2 does not release on last gen consoles, so it’s bad news for players on Xbox One, PlayStation 4, or the original Nintendo Switch console.</p>







<hr>



<p>What are your expectations for High on Life 2? Share your thoughts with other players in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For your next read, check out all the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-escape-from-tarkov-codes-rewards/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">active codes for Escape From Tarkov</a>, and take a look at the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/complete-reanimal-trophy-list-how-to-get-all-achievements-trophies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">full list of achievements and trophies in Reanimal</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/high-on-life-2-release-date-platforms/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Silent on Metroid Prime 4: Beyond Sales, Prompting Fan Concern Over the Series' Future]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-silent-on-metroid-prime-4-beyond-sales-prompting-fan-concern-over-the-series-future</link>
            <guid>1423726</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo's latest financial results are notably silent on the sales performance of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/metroid-prime-4-beyond">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a>, which has not appeared on the company's list of million copy-selling games for either Switch 1 or Switch 2. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest earnings from the company, released this morning, show that Switch 2 exclusive Kirby Air Riders sold 1.76 million units since its arrival on November 20. But there's no mention of how well Metroid Prime 4, which launched just a couple of weeks later on December 4 — and for both Switch and Switch 2 — has performed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Similarly, there's no word on sales for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a>, which launched on November 6. This, however, was a Switch 2 exclusive, a spin-off (from The Legend of Zelda), and an entry without the franchise's lead character (Link).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As part of its financial results, Nintendo includes lists of its first-party games that have sold over 1 million copies, divided by platform. Metroid Prime 4 is not on either the Switch or Switch 2 list — though could still have passed the 1 million sales figure via combined sales from both platforms. If it did, however, there's no mentioned of it doing so from Nintendo in any of its accompanying notes — and barely any mention of it having released at all.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment also did not make Nintendo's Switch 2 million-seller list, though its sales performance is likely to cause less concern among fans than the slow start for Metroid Prime 4. (Curiously, Age of Imprisonment's Japanese publisher <a href="https://www.koeitecmo.co.jp/e/ir/docs/ir6_20260126e.pdf" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Koei Tecmo has indicated the game has now hit 1 million sales</a>, though Nintendo has not acknowledged this.) </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For Metroid Prime, after years in the wilderness, a long and troubled development, and no other games for the franchise yet announced, it remains to be seen how or when we'll next see another entry — or whether players will ever get to see more of Prime 4's baddie Sylux, whose story remains unfinished. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-prime-producer-reportedly-leaving-nintendo-after-40-years-unsure-if-there-will-be-another-game-to-wrap-up-syluxs-story">Metroid Prime series producer Kensuke Tanabe abruptly announced that Metroid Prime 4 would be his last game for Nintendo</a> after four decades of service. When contacted for more detail by IGN, Nintendo did not comment.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Metroid Prime 4 Beyond Switch 2 Edition Screenshots</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Not surprising," wrote one fan, DarkLegend64, in a lengthy thread on the main Metroid <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Metroid/comments/1qult0l/facts_about_the_sales_data_is_from_apr_1stdec_31st/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reddit</a> that laments the latest game's sales. "The marketing for the game was horrendous, giving the feeling Nintendo just sent the game out to die. On top of that, the massive criticism the game has received from the fanbase has ensured it won’t bring in new fans from the word-of-mouth aspect. This game’s release has been a total disaster and I once again fear for the future of the Prime series."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Metroid Prime 4 wasn’t the best Metroid Prime, but it wasn’t a bad game," said TarnishedOctorok. "It was fun. It looked and sounded fantastic. It had some great bits, epic showcase elements, and standout special moments. At least I thought so. The massive collective s*** that was taken on it by WAY too many loud-mouth influencers and other people that didn’t get EXACTLY why they wanted, seriously hurt the brand, and will likely doom any chance for another Prime game. Perhaps another Metroid game of any kind."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other fans, however, pointed to comments from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-dread-end-future-storylines-nintendo">Metroid co-creator Yoshio Sakamoto who previously suggested to IGN in 2021 that another 2D Metroid game was planned</a>, to follow the better-received Metroid Dread.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Elsewhere, Switch 2 launch title Mario Kart World is now on an astonishing 14.03 million copies (including those sold in console bundles). This means that only 3 million of the Switch 2's 17.37 million-strong userbase do not have a copy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Pokémon Legends Z-A has shifted a combined 12.3 million copies across  Switch and Switch 2 (including 3.89 million physical Switch 2 copies sold). Switch 2 exclusive Donkey Kong Bananza has now passed 4.25 million copies sold since July. Nintendo's Switch ports of Super Mario Galaxy (2.28 million) and Galaxy 2  (2.42 million) have also performed well since their launch on October 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While Metroid Prime 4 only arrived at the start of December, the game had been highly-anticipated by core Nintendo fans following a near-decade in development. Unfortunately, reviews were less stellar than those of the franchise's beloved original trilogy, and there was notable criticism prior to launch for its chatty AI companions — a departure from the series' trademark of lone exploration. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Reading between the lines, it feels like Nintendo anticipated the game's reception somewhat. It has admitted that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/backtracking-development-again-was-out-of-the-question-nintendo-says-metroid-prime-4s-open-world-hub-was-a-victim-of-the-games-lengthy-development">it knew the game's open world concept might feel outdated by the time the game finally launched</a>, while an unnamed source within the company <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-source-blames-switch-2-holiday-sales-slowdown-on-the-economic-landscape-and-the-absence-of-a-major-western-game-despite-the-release-of-metroid-prime-4-beyond">reportedly blamed weaker Switch 2 console sales in some regions this past holiday on the lack of a major Western game</a> — a role Metroid Prime 4 should have performed.</p><span data-cy="poll-view-trigger"></span><p data-cy="paragraph">Upcoming first-party Switch 2 games include Mario Tennis Fever (February 12), Pokémon Pokopia (March 5), Super Mario Bros. Wonder Nintendo Switch 2 Edition + Meetup in Bellabel Park (March 26), Tomodachi Life: Living the Dream (April 16), and Yoshi and the Mysterious Book, which has a vague "spring" launch window. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Simply listed for 2026 are Fire Emblem: Fortune's Weave, Rhythm Heaven Groove and Pokémon Champions, while Splatoon Raiders has a "TBA" launch date.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Third-party games include Yakuza Kiwami 3 &amp; Dark Ties (February 12), Reanimal (February 13), Resident Evil Requiem (February 27), Fatal Frame 2: Crimson Butterfly Remake (March 12), Monster Hunter Stories 3: Twisted Reflection (March 13), Pragmata (April 24) and 007 First Light (May 27).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for Nintendo hardware, the company today confirmed that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/switch-becomes-nintendos-best-selling-hardware-ever-while-switch-2-has-already-outsold-wii-us-lifetime-total">Switch was now its best-selling console family ever</a> — and just shy of the PlayStation 2's record-breaking total.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-silent-on-metroid-prime-4-beyond-sales-prompting-fan-concern-over-the-series-future]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Quietly Withdraws Under Fire MMO Ashes of Creation From Sale As Fans Wonder Who's Left to Maintain the Servers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/steam-quietly-withdraws-under-fire-mmo-ashes-of-creation-from-sale-as-fans-wonder-whos-left-to-maintain-the-servers</link>
            <guid>1423723</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Steam has quietly withdrawn under fire MMO <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/ashes-of-creation"><u>Ashes of Creation</u></a> from sale after its director and leadership team quit just weeks after launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ashes of Creation was funded by a hugely successful <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1791529601/ashes-of-creation-new-mmorpg-by-intrepid-studios" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>$3.2 million Kickstarter campaign back in 2017</u></a>. It finally released in December as a $50 <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4124950/Ashes_of_Creation/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Early Access game on Steam</u></a>, but by the end of January, the game's director, Steven Sharif, and "much of" the senior dev team quit "in protest," claiming that its management board had asked him to do things he "could not ethically support." According to Sharif, the Board then issued WARN Act notices — layoff warnings, in other words — to the remaining staff. It's unclear how many employees remain employed or who sits on this mysterious board.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Although Sharif posted a brief statement explaining why he quit in the game's Discord community, he has not posted anything since. Given the comments, memes, and inappropriate comments flooding every channel, the Discord itself seems wholly unmoderated now. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Head over to the Ashes of Creation page on Steam now, however, and you'll see that the button to buy has been quietly removed. Conversely, the game's website is still live and accepting payment for cosmetics, but a notice at the top reads: "delivery of cosmetic purchases may be delayed on certain realms. Items will appear in your in-game mail once processing completes." While the site is typically updated several times a month, only one update was posted in the whole of January, and that was alluding to a developer diary livestream coming up on February 13, although it's unclear who will host that, given most of the familiar faces fans have seen in prior streams seem to have left.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Perhaps unsurprisingly, the Reddit and Discord communities are full of people asking if anyone's successfully convinced Steam to give them a refund. While anyone with less than two hours on the clock should get one automatically, those with more time are having mixed results, with <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MMORPG/comments/1qu659x/comment/o38513r/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>some reporting success</u></a>, others being <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MMORPG/comments/1qu659x/comment/o38yz7s/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>denied</u></a>, and the rest asked to wait while Steam "investigates" the issue. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The most successful requests seem to be via human checks, so<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AshesofCreation/comments/1qtwfd3/comment/o35udls/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u> players are suggesting</u></a> that those looking for a refund should not check the box to "request a refund," but instead contact Steam via the "I have a question about this product" option. That way, your request will be routed to a member of customer support, and not an automated service. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's unlikely Kickstarter donors will secure any refunds, given the nature of crowdfunded programs.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/02/03/screenshot-2026-02-03-at-09-26-31-1770114874090.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Interestingly, without any context or introduction, a standard member, Karen L. Boreyko, addressed the community earlier today (February 3) across several Discord channels, writing: "Hello everyone — my name is Karen L. Boreyko, and I want to take a moment to speak directly to this community as we begin a new chapter for Ashes of Creation. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Intrepid Studios is moving forward with a renewed long-term vision for the game, including continued development in China and a transition to a subscription-based model supported by optional daily battle passes, a new in-game gold shop, and expanded skill point progression systems. Our goal is to ensure the project’s sustainability while accelerating development and delivering a live service experience that can grow for years to come. We know change brings questions, and we’re committed to open communication as we move ahead together."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">At this time, because her account isn't tagged as an official team member, it's impossible to determine who Boreyko is or how she is involved in the game's development, if at all. A Leanne Boreyko is attached to a multi-level marketing wellness company called Vemma, and, coincidentially enough, a different wellness company called 310 Nutrition and <a href="https://310nutrition.com/pages/about-us" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">run by a man called Tim Sharif</a> who has just <a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?me=AXG4R53RTUQJ3&amp;marketplaceID=ATVPDKIKX0DER" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dropped a load of Ashes of Creation merch onto Amazon.com</a>. Make of that what you will.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I've a feeling February 13's livestream is going to be very well attended indeed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/steam-quietly-withdraws-under-fire-mmo-ashes-of-creation-from-sale-as-fans-wonder-whos-left-to-maintain-the-servers]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization 7's big Test of Time update that'll bring back playing as one civ for the whole game is set to drop this spring]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/civilization-7s-big-test-of-time-update-thatll-bring-back-playing-as-one-civ-for-the-whole-game-is-set-to-drop-this-spring</link>
            <guid>1423714</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Before that, another smaller bringing nested tooltips and more civ balancing is due</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civilization-7-anniversary-update-test-of-time-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civilization-7-anniversary-update-test-of-time-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civilization-7-anniversary-update-test-of-time-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civilization-7-anniversary-update-test-of-time-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civilization-7-anniversary-update-test-of-time-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civilization-7-anniversary-update-test-of-time-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civilization-7-anniversary-update-test-of-time-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civilization-7-anniversary-update-test-of-time-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/civilization-7-anniversary-update-test-of-time-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Firaxis</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>As any Civ player knows, time has a habit of passing. Next week, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii">Civ 7</a> will turn a year old. It's been a year of regular <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/civilization-7s-nautically-themed-130-update-arrives-today-delivers-significant-buffs-to-popular-civs">additions</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/civilization-7-update-131-drops-today-rolling-out-a-new-island-filled-map-and-knocking-egypt-off-the-top-of-the-pyramid">tweaks</a> following the mixed initial reception to Firaxis' attempt to do something different with their grant strategy behemoth. Fitting, then, that the devs have rung in that first birthday by revealing when they're hoping to drop some big changes that'll have "major implications" for Civ 7.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Civilization VII Anniversary Update - February 2026" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OYry-kvC8u4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Civilization VII Anniversary Update - February 2026</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OYry-kvC8u4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OYry-kvC8u4?autoplay=1" title="Civilization VII Anniversary Update - February 2026">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OYry-kvC8u4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>As outlined in a video and <a href="https://civilization.2k.com/civ-vii/news/anniversary/">blog post</a> fronted by Civ creative director Ed Beach, these larger changes and additions will be arriving as part of a free update dubbed Test of Time, which Firaxis are "tentatively aiming" to drop this spring. Headlining its contents thus far is the return of the ability to play as one civilization throug the whole game if you wish, something the studio <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/civilization-7-will-bring-back-the-ability-to-play-as-one-civ-for-the-whole-game-bypassing-the-divisive-age-system">announced they were working on</a> last year.</p>
<p>Beach outlined how exactly it'll be implemented here, making clear it's not a separate game mode or a replacement for the base game's system of shifting civs with each age change. Instead, when you hit the end of an age, you'll simply be offered the option to keep on plugging with the same civ, with AI civs mirroring whether you choose to stick or twist in their own end of age decisions. To help ensure long-running civs don't get stale, Firaxis have opted to introduce a couple of new features - Apex Ages and Syncretism.</p><p>The first of those is a "sole Age where this civ gets its full, unique kit", designed to mirror the period when it was in its prime or fits best with the world. Beach provided Rome in the antiquity age as an example. "Civs played outside of their Apex Age retain a core, defining part of their kit and gain a new Age-appropriate Civic Tree," he added. "In our example, this tree includes a unique node, Roman Renaissance, that lets you optionally unlock more Age-appropriate Roman perks, as well as two nodes based on your civ's attributes – in Rome's case that's Cultural and Militaristic. These attribute-based nodes are common for all civs outside of their Apex Age, providing perks that are relevant for the current Age's mechanics."</p>
<p>Syncretism, meanwhile, gives you the option "to study a Mastery on your new unique Civic node, and adopt the Unique Units or Infrastructure from another civilization currently in its Apex Age". So, if you're playing an ancient civ and want to incorporate another civ's unique exploration age ships into your fleet to bolster your effectiveness at that point in time, you can do so.</p>
<p>Alongside the ability to play as one civ throughout, Firaxis are using the update to switch up how victories are earned with the hopes of offering more variety in winning strategies via Military, Economy, Culture, or Science, rather than pushing you into a single legacy path. Finally, legacy paths themselves have been replaced with new "Triumphs", which offer a wide range of optional, challenging objectives to complete as you go, allowing you to score points in the various winning metrics civs are measured by.</p>
<p>So, that's Tests of Time. Prior to the big update, Firaxis also have a smaller update dubbed 1.3.2 set to arrive soon. That one'll bring nested tooltips, more civ balancing tweaks, the ability to immediately see how useful a tile is, plus reworks of AI diplomacy and coastal raids. A free leader - Gilgamesh - will also be arriving for every player with 1.3.2 as a nice little anniversary present.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/civilization-7s-big-test-of-time-update-thatll-bring-back-playing-as-one-civ-for-the-whole-game-is-set-to-drop-this-spring]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Logitech Clears Out G29 Driving Force Racing Wheel and Floor Pedals at Its Cheapest Price, Perfect for PlayStation and PC Gaming]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/logitech-clears-out-g29-driving-force-racing-wheel-and-floor-pedals-at-its-cheapest-price-perfect-for-playstation-and-pc-gaming-2000665156</link>
            <guid>1423708</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Growing up playing Need for Speed, I always wondered what using real racing gear for the game would feel like. The Logitech G29 driving force racing wheel and floor pedals bring that idea to life, and right now, you can get your hands on it without paying the full price.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5725/">This wheel kit is now going for $270 at Amazon, which is a solid 18% discount on its usual $330 price tag.</a> While it’s not an all-time low, it’s still the best price we have seen in the last 30 days. The retailer is also offering free delivery with your purchase, which brings the total cost down even further. But as you’d expect, this offer is a limited-time one. It likely expires soon, so it’s best to get your orders in without wasting much time.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5725/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Immersive, Responsive Gaming</h2>
<p>The wheel kit comes with a racing wheel and floor pedals. It’s optimized for PlayStation 5, PS4, and PC gaming titles, letting you enjoy the feeling of driving a real car with precision steering and pressure-sensitive pedals in the game.</p>
<p>There’s plenty to appreciate here. First, the wheel flaunts hand-stitched leather for a realistic feel. Then there’s dual-motor force feedback, which simulates the feel of tires on a turn, drifting, and oversteering, plus helical gearing to deliver smoother and quieter power transmission. The local-to-lock 900-degree rotation makes it incredibly easy to turn the wheel around two and a half times, hand over hand on wide turns – just like they do it in the movies.</p>



<p>You’ll also enjoy durable stainless steel paddle shifters right at your fingertips for quicker access. These help maintain consistency lap after lap, and especially come in handy during situations where every millisecond counts. Add in the high-strength mounting clamps, and you’re looking at supreme stability that keeps your car in place, even during intense sessions.</p>
<p>The floor pedals are just as impressive. This adjustable, pressure-sensitive nonlinear unit features an automotive-grade rolled steel throttle, pressure-sensitive brake, and clutch; all of which help with responsive braking and better control. You customize the pedal faces for finer control, too. Basically, this kit offers an immersive, hyper-realistic racing experience from the comfort of your home. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5725/">It normally sits at $330, but you can currently grab it for $270, after a solid 18% discount.</a></p>
<p>For an even better experience, you can consider pairing the G29 Racing Wheel with Logitech’s Driving Force Shifter and A10 Gaming Headset. The former offers a solid steel gear shaft and built-in clamps, while the latter delivers immersive, deep sound that brings your favorite titles to life. Just note that the current discount won’t be around forever. If you’ve been looking to upgrade the way you game, now is the time to make the move.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5725/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/logitech-clears-out-g29-driving-force-racing-wheel-and-floor-pedals-at-its-cheapest-price-perfect-for-playstation-and-pc-gaming-2000665156]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Civilization 7 solidifies its course-correction plans with massive expansion-sized spring update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/civilization-7-developer-firaxis-details-2026-reworks-free-updates</link>
            <guid>1423705</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gilgamesh_Civ7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gilgamesh_Civ7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gilgamesh_Civ7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gilgamesh_Civ7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gilgamesh_Civ7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gilgamesh_Civ7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gilgamesh_Civ7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gilgamesh_Civ7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gilgamesh_Civ7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>2K</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vii">Civilization 7</a> was a bit of an odd release last year. With a <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/sid-meiers-civilization-vii/">Metacritic score</a> of 79 and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-ceo-strauss-zelnick-insists-projections-for-the-lifetime-value-of-civilization-7-are-very-consistent-with-our-initial-expectations-for-the-title-despite-slow-start">positive comments from Take-Two's leadership</a>, it was considered a success. Longtime Firaxis fans weren't as kind to it though, as many felt it was too disruptive or shallow. As expected, 2026 might be the year the studio makes the game's future brighter.</p>
<p>I'm saying it was to be expected because we've been here before. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sid-meiers-civilization-5-spain-inca">Civilization 5</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sid-meiers-civilization-vi">6</a> also faced heavy criticism upon release, before going on to become stone-cold 4X classics of the modern era. Long story short: Firaxis likes to experiment, whereas Civilization diehards are allergic to big shakeups... at least at first. Now, following a number of quick reworks and hot patches (as well as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/im-loving-a-pirates-life-in-civilization-7-which-keeps-getting-better-as-firaxis-diligent-updates-continue">fun DLCs</a>), Civilization 7's future is coming into focus, and it's looking a lot brighter than we expected.</p>
<p>On 2nd February, 2K and Firaxis <a href="https://civilization.2k.com/civ-vii/news/anniversary/">shared their vision</a> for the seventh game in the series as it enters 2026. It all starts with Update 1.3.2, which is "going live soon" even if we've got zero words on a specific date yet. The tentative list of changes and additions is long, but players can expect nested tooltips, balance passes across more civs like the French Empire and the Mughal, and reworks of AI diplomacy, coastal raids, and the Appeal system. Moreover, the "legendary demigod of Uruk, Gilgamesh" is coming as a thank-you gift for free.</p>
<p>Further into 2026 (spring is the current target), a batch of deep-cut changes are coming with a huge expansion-sized update called 'Test of Time' which aims to heavily redesign the flow of the entire game and all end goals. The community will be invited to playtest these bigger changes through the <a href="https://civilization.2k.com/civ-vii/firaxis-feature-workshop/">Firaxis Feature Workshop</a>, but we've got a quick rundown of what you can expect if you're waiting for the final release. And you can watch the video version below:</p><figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Civilization VII Anniversary Update - February 2026" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OYry-kvC8u4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Civilization VII Anniversary Update - February 2026</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OYry-kvC8u4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OYry-kvC8u4?autoplay=1" title="Civilization VII Anniversary Update - February 2026">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OYry-kvC8u4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>First, players will be able to play as a single civilization throughout the entire game, offering a traditional alternative to the "dynamic empire-building experience" of vanilla Civilization 7. Of course, reworks will be happening to accommodate such a radical extra, with a system called Syncretism that allows to "create all-new builds" that borrow from other civilizations once per age without burying the original one.</p>
<p>Victories are getting a top-to-bottom rework as well; Legacy Paths are less important now, and victories can be achieved earlier and by completing "a wide range of different activities" that should make both short and long-term competition more flexible and engaging. In fact, Legacy Paths as we knew them will be binned, with Triumphs taking over. They're themed achievements of sorts that reward civilizations with bonuses and "cards" that can be used when an age starts.</p>
<p>Needless to say, that's a lot to digest, and we're not expecting all these changes to land from the get-go when they're out, but it's exciting to see Firaxis turn Civilization 7 into a game that bridges the gap between newcomers and veterans without erasing its original vision.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/civilization-7-developer-firaxis-details-2026-reworks-free-updates]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Division: Definitive Edition Shadow Dropped For $50 With Zero Improvements]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-definitive-edition-shadow-dropped-for-50-with-zero-improvements/</link>
            <guid>1423693</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Rumblings of The Division: Definitive Edition started a few weeks ago. While the wait for The Division 3 goes on, this could have served as the perfect means to tide fans over until then. Unfortunately, the very low-key release seems to be quite low-effort, with The Division: Definitive Edition shadow drop being a rehash of a previous version, with no PS5 or Xbox Series X|S upgrade.</p>



<p>Definitive Editions are usually released with the same content, but alongside a plethora of graphical updates to give a game a completely overhauled look. This is the bare minimum effort needed, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/the-division/" id="113" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Division</a>: Definitive Edition hasn’t even done this.</p>







<h2 id="h-the-division-definitive-edition-has-no-ps5-upgrades">The Division: Definitive Edition Has No PS5 Upgrades</h2>



<figure><figcaption>A letdown. Credit to Ubisoft</figcaption></figure>



<p>A <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-definitive-edition-could-be-coming-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Division: Definitive Edition</a> banner surfaced online, and clearly hinted that Ubisoft was working on an upgraded version of the original looter shooter.</p>



<p>With <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-3-shaping-up-to-be-monster-dev/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Division 3 ‘Shaping up to be a monster,’</a> this is the perfect gateway for new fans into the series, and the chance to warm up the skills of existing players. But alarm bells started ringing when The Division: Definitive Edition was unceremoniously shadow-dropped onto the PlayStation and Xbox Stores on February 3.</p>



<p>Therein lies the reason as to why it hasn’t been promoted: There’s not much to promote.</p>



<p>‘Tom Clancy’s The Division – Definitive Edition’ doesn’t have an upgraded PS5 or XSX version. You can play it on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S, but the game clearly states that it includes “The base game, all three Season Pass expansions, and multiple cosmetic packs.” No graphical improvements or even gameplay tweaks are mentioned because there are none.</p>



<p>There will be some natural upscaling because of the power of the modern-day consoles, but make no mistake, this is the already-existing The Division Gold Edition, with a few extra outfits and no upgrades, for $50.</p>



<p>Following the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prince-of-persia-sands-of-time-remake-canceled/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time Remake being canceled</a>, and the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-employee-who-was-suspended-for-criticising-the-company-has-now-been-fired/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft employee who was suspended for criticizing the company being fired</a>, it has not been a good few weeks for Ubisoft.</p>



<p>What do you think about this release? Is it a lazy rerelease? Could Ubisoft face even more flak after recent events? Let IG know through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-crosses-17-million-units-sold-to-remain-fastest-selling-platform/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2 remaining the company’s fastest-selling platform</a>, for more news.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-division-definitive-edition-shadow-dropped-for-50-with-zero-improvements/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Nintendo Switch 2 has topped 17 million sales worldwide]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-nintendo-switch-2-has-topped-17-million-sales-worldwide</link>
            <guid>1423684</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">February 3, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Hardware image via Nintendo</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Nintendo Switch 2 continues to outpace its predecessor after selling 17.37 million units worldwide.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2026/260203_3e.pdf">As noted in Nintendo's fiscal report for the past nine months</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the console launched on June 5, 2025, and reached that milestone on December 31, 2025.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For context, the original Switch sold 17.79 million units by March 2018—just over a year after it hit shelves on March 3, 2017.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sticking with the Switch 2 for a moment, Nintendo said hardware sales were driven by the "Nintendo Switch 2 + Mario Kart World Bundle" and "Nintendo Switch 2 + Pokémon Legends: Z-A – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Bundle."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As you might expect, the success of those bundles had a positive impact on software sales. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Kart World</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has now sold 14.03 million units worldwide since launching alongside the Switch 2, while </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Pokémon Legends: Z-A </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">has recorded sales of 8.41 million units.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Other notable sellers include </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Donkey Kong Bananza</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (4.25 million units sold) and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kirby Air Riders</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (1.76 million units sold). Overall, the Switch 2 has delivered cumulative software sales of 37.93 million units worldwide.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-union-representatives-call-for-resignation-of-ceo-yves-guillemot" target="_self" data-discover="true">Ubisoft union representatives call for resignation of CEO Yves Guillemot</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The original Switch cements its place in history&nbsp;">The original Switch cements its place in history&nbsp;</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo recorded consolidated net sales of 1.9 trillion yen ($12.2 billion) over the past nine months—an increase of 99.3 percent year-on-year.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sales declined by 10.1 percent year-on-year within the company's IP related business, mainly due to an increase in revenue related to The Super Mario Bros. Movie (although a sequel will touch down in April).&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Digital sales increased by 14.7 percent to 282 billion yen ($1.8 billion) over the same nine-month period and accounted for 50.4 percent of total software sales.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Nintendo Switch boasted around 129 million annual playing users during the 2025 calendar year, which is perhaps unsurprising given the console has now sold 155.37 million units worldwide to become the best-selling console in Nintendo history.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The handheld-hybrid looked certain to steal the crown from the Nintendo DS for some time, but has now cemented its place in the record books.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo said the "connections" it built with consumers through the Nintendo Switch have supported the smooth launch of the Switch 2.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Looking ahead, Nintendo hopes the launch of new titles such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Pokémon Pokopia</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mario Tennis Fever</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Yoshi and the Mysterious Book </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">will continue to drive momentum.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-nintendo-switch-2-has-topped-17-million-sales-worldwide]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sorry Dispatch fans, there's "no possibility" of an uncensored physical version on Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sorry-dispatch-fans-theres-no-possibility-of-an-uncensored-physical-version-on-switch</link>
            <guid>1423681</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bda97a69-ddeb-438e-be8c-d2ece91a6423~1.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bda97a69-ddeb-438e-be8c-d2ece91a6423~1.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bda97a69-ddeb-438e-be8c-d2ece91a6423~1.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bda97a69-ddeb-438e-be8c-d2ece91a6423~1.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bda97a69-ddeb-438e-be8c-d2ece91a6423~1.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bda97a69-ddeb-438e-be8c-d2ece91a6423~1.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bda97a69-ddeb-438e-be8c-d2ece91a6423~1.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bda97a69-ddeb-438e-be8c-d2ece91a6423~1.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/bda97a69-ddeb-438e-be8c-d2ece91a6423~1.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>AdHoc</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>AdHoc has said there is "no possibility" of an uncensored physical version of its superhero workplace comedy Dispatch on Switch or <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platforms/switch-2">Switch 2</a>.</p>
<p>Last week, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dispatch-switch-switch-2-censored-adhoc-comment">fans were disappointed to discover Dispatch was heavily censored on Switch and Switch 2 as standard</a>, with characters' nipples and penises covered with a black box by default, while noises of sexual pleasure were dampened down.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>Soon after AdHoc announced Dispatch was censored on Switch consoles, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-comments-on-dispatchs-switch-censorship">Nintendo released its own statement on the issue</a>, saying the company "requires all games on its platforms to receive ratings from independent organisations and to meet our established content and platform guidelines".</p>
<p>Since then, AdHoc said it understood why its fans were "pissed", and it is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dispatch-studio-apologises-if-it-looks-like-it-was-trying-to-hide-censored-switch-content-disclaimer-lots-of-lessons-learned-here">now working with Nintendo "on a path forward"</a>. The Dispatch studio added that while it "can't make any specific promises just yet", it is "confident we'll be able to push an update to address at least some of the censored content", albeit in several weeks' time due to the console submission process.</p><p>However, even with that being said, an uncensored Switch and Switch 2 physical version is not possible, according to a statement shared with <a href="https://gonintendo.com/contents/57271-dispatch-devs-say-uncensored-physical-switch-release-not-possible-can-t-comment-on">GoNintendo</a>. AdHoc added the discussion isn't "currently relevant as there are no announcements regarding a physical release at this time", despite previously hinting it would like to see a physical release of Dispatch.</p>
<p>GoNintendo also asked about the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/nintendo/comments/1qpxtya/i_think_dispatch_being_censored_on_switch_is/">singular worldwide release discussion</a> which has started to make the rounds following Dispatch's Switch censorship discussion. The publication got the following response back from AdHoc's PR: "AdHoc is legally unable to provide further comment on why separate SKUs were not possible for different regions."</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>AdHoc</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Despite this recent blip in public favour, Dispatch has been a huge success for AdHoc, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/is-episodic-gaming-back-on-the-map-ex-wolf-among-us-devs-superhero-workplace-comedy-dispatch-sells-big-to-become-a-well-deserved-smash">sold over 1m copies in just 10 days</a> following its initial release last year.</p>
<p>Thanks to this success, the studio is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dispatch-dev-adhoc-set-on-season-2-but-has-difficult-second-album-problem">now considering a second season</a>, possibly with even more sex scenes <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dispatch-writer-regrets-cutting-sex-scenes">given the "ravenous" response to the first season</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/sorry-dispatch-fans-theres-no-possibility-of-an-uncensored-physical-version-on-switch]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valheim developers celebrate the game's fifth anniversary with flower garlands, sweetbread, and Steam Deck optimisations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-developers-celebrate-the-games-fifth-anniversary-with-flower-garlands-sweetbread-and-steam-deck-optimisations</link>
            <guid>1423666</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Come for the patch notes, stay for the gift ideas</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/valheim-fifth-anniversary.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Coffee Stain Publishing / Iron Gate</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>I'm going to a toddler's birthday party on Saturday and I have it on good authority from Alva's dad that there will be trays of sandwiches and a couple of cakes from M&amp;S. There is no booze provided. I'm not sure if that's because there should be no booze consumed at a two-year-old's birthday, or only that we should bring our own. I guess I'll find out for sure if they frisk on the door. However, if <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/valheim">Valheim</a>'s latest anniversary update is anything to go by, I am now looking forward to Alva's fifth birthday.</p>
<p>To mark five years in Early Access, developer Iron Gate have released an anniversary patch that is a damn sight better than the prospect of watching a sad looking Colin the Caterpillar cake getting pawed at by hungry toddlers. There are flower garlands, mysterious axe heads, and a steady 60 fps on Steam Deck performance mode. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/d6gBu2Zd7Bc">Who doesn't want mysterious blades at a birthday party?</a></p>
<!--more-->
<p>While it may not be a name you would put on a banner, <a href="https://www.valheim.com/news/five-years-of-valheim-/">patch 0.221.10</a> offers a little something to both the players who love the idea of a party and those who would rather stay home.</p>
<p>For the partiers, there are Fey Lights to string up around your settlement, sweetbreads to bake and serve, and flower garlands to wear as you use the new Vibe and LoveYou emotes. If you want to keep things lowkey, you may just want to wear the celebratory cap.</p><p>On the midpoint of the partier to non-partier, you will find a pair of new materials – the mysterious axe head and the curious axehead. You'll need both if you want to craft Early Axes, a new dual-wielded axe you can attain much earlier than the Berserkir Axes.</p>
<p>Then on the non-partier end of the scale you will find a stack of quality of life changes. Engine optimisations to improve performance, fixes to reduce armour stands' exorbitant CPU usage, a less memory intensive minimap.</p>
<p>All those performance improvements have had a knock on effect for the Steam Deck's performance mode, which now sees Valheim reaching the all-important 60 fps.</p>
<p>What I really appreciate about this patch is not the improvements it's making the Early Access Viking simulation, but the gift ideas that it's given me for Alva's fifth birthday party. A nice cap and a pair of axe heads are easy enough to come by. And it saves me trying to work out which Famous Five books she's already read.</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valheim-developers-celebrate-the-games-fifth-anniversary-with-flower-garlands-sweetbread-and-steam-deck-optimisations]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metroid Prime 4 & Hyrule Warriors: Age Of Imprisonment Sales Get Off To A Slow Start]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/metroid-prime-4-and-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-sales-get-off-to-a-slow-start</link>
            <guid>1423654</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>One in a million</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="becb2cfbc7aae"><a title="Hyrule Warriors / MP4" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/becb2cfbc7aae/hyrule-warriors-mp4.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Jim Norman / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Nintendo's latest <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2026/260203_3e.pdf">financial report</a> is in, giving us the official sales numbers for all of its best-selling games as of 31st December 2025. We already highlighted the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/heres-a-look-at-the-best-selling-switch-and-switch-2-games-so-far">best-sellers</a>, in fact, but we couldn't help but notice that both <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_prime_4_beyond">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> — in either its Switch 1 or Switch 2 editions — <em>and</em> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a> were missing from the list.</p>
<p>We don't have concrete sales numbers for either of the three releases there (counting Metroid Prime 4's two editions separately), but what we do know is that none of them exceeded one million sales by the time the year was up.</p><div><figure data-videoid="6TAq6m9hxyY" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt6TAq6m9hxyY" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed76f4cepqngzy&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Now, sure, such a cutoff point means that MP4 would have had to exceed the big 'one milly' in under four weeks, which is a <em>slightly</em> tight turnaround, and sales being split between the two console versions was never going to help things — there's every chance that combining the Switch 1 and 2 editions pushes the title past the milestone — but come on. We would have thought that after <em>that much waiting</em>, general hype would boost the numbers a little.</p>
<p>Koei Tecmo announced that Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment had <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-surpasses-1-million-copies-sold">surpassed one million sales</a> late last month, but it seems that this wasn't the case by the cutoff for Nintendo's figures in December. Again, Switch 2 exclusivity and it <em>not</em> being a new mainline Zelda might have tempered sales a little, but considering that its <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/hyrule_warriors_age_of_calamity">predecessor</a> shifted <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2020/11/hyrule_warriors_age_of_calamity_is_already_the_best-selling_warriors_game_of_all_time">three million copies in its first week on the market</a>, we imagined this would come out of the gate a little stronger.</p>
<p><em>Update</em><em>: since Koei Tecmo published AOI in Japan, <em>Nintendo will only report the sales outside the region. So, while overseas sales did not exceed one million by Dec 2025, the Japanese numbers pushed it over the mark.</em></em></p>
<p>As we mentioned, we don't have the precise sales numbers for either of these titles just yet, so MP4 may well be closing in on one million already, while Hyrule Warriors reaches for two. Perhaps they'll make an appearance in the next financial update... <em>surely</em>...</p>
<p>You'll find a rundown of all the Switch 2 titles that <em>did</em> surpass one million sales in Q3 in our coverage below.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/metroid/related-articles:196947,196946 @ 1770124306 -->
<p><em>What do you make of Metroid Prime 4 and Hyrule Warriors' absence from the sales numbers so far? Will we see them pop up next time? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2026/260203_3e.pdf" rel="noopener" href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2026/260203_3e.pdf">nintendo.co.jp</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/metroid/related-info/3dcbf454ed856a8d74c13916c781e3ef @ 1770124582 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/metroid-prime-4-and-hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-sales-get-off-to-a-slow-start]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Crosses 17 Million Units Sold To Remain Fastest-Selling Platform]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-crosses-17-million-units-sold-to-remain-fastest-selling-platform/</link>
            <guid>1423651</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 has been a rip-roaring success since its historic June 5, 2025, launch. The sequel to the smash-hit Switch is more powerful and has more system-selling AAA exclusives, and people are gobbling up Switch 2 consoles faster than Yoshi does fruit.</p>



<p>You could argue the generational leap from the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/nintendo-switch/" id="302" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch</a> to the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2/" id="908" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Switch 2</a> hasn’t been as significant or as huge as in previous years, but this hasn’t stopped it from raking in millions for Nintendo across 2025 and up to FY2026.</p>







<h2 id="h-nintendo-fy26-financial-results-show-huge-numbers-for-switch-2">Nintendo FY26 Financial Results Show Huge Numbers For Switch 2</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Money. Image via Nintendo</figcaption></figure>



<p>The February 3 <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2026/260203_2e.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Nintendo Financial Earnings Report</a> is out, and it’s hard to escape the Switch 2’s incredible first-year success.</p>







<p>Nintendo’s newest statistics reveal that the Switch 2 has sold 17.37 million units as of December 31, 2025. A cool graphic shows the correlation between the Switch and Switch 2’s respective sales journeys.</p>



<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 still remains ahead of the original Switch’s sales curve, and this ensures the Nintendo Switch 2 is the “Fastest-selling dedicated video game platform released by Nintendo to date.”</p>



<p>First-party titles have clearly had a huge influence, with Nintendo reporting that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/mario-kart-world/" id="2527" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mario Kart World</a> has crossed 14 million units, Donkey Kong Bananza has sold 4 million units, and the Switch 2 version of Pokémon Legends: Z-A is also swiftly approaching 4 million.</p>



<p>With more Nintendo exclusives in the pipeline, from Mario Tennis Fever to Pokémon Pokopia, there are even more reasons to buy a Nintendo Switch 2 in 2026. You can bet your bottom dollar that the company is keeping some games a secret, and there’s still plenty of ammunition to keep the Switch 2 sales flowing.</p>



<p>Are you a Nintendo Switch 2 owner? What incentivized you to buy one? Conversely, if you like the brand but haven’t invested in a Switch 2 yet, why is this? Reveal everything and more via the free-to-join <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more hot news, you should check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ubisoft-employee-who-was-suspended-for-criticising-the-company-has-now-been-fired/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ubisoft employee who was suspended for criticising the company being fired</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-crosses-17-million-units-sold-to-remain-fastest-selling-platform/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Mystery of the Nintendo OSM: Is a Switch 2 Lite coming? Or could it be a Switch Mini?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/03/the-mystery-of-the-nintendo-osm-is-a-switch-2-lite-coming-or-could-it-be-a-switch-mini/</link>
            <guid>1423645</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Last year’s newest hardware from Nintendo has proven to be a massive hit. The Switch 2 has already sold 17.37 million units, in an impressively short space of time, making it the fastest-selling console ever. That’s a huge victory for the Japanese company, particularly when there was a point – I’m sorry, my beloved Wii U – where it looked like Nintendo could be heading out of the hardware business altogether.</p>
<p>Still, Nintendo isn’t known for resting on its laurels. The Switch 2’s predecessor went through a number of revisions, and while some of them were purely under the hood, both the Nintendo Switch OLED and the Switch Lite made major changes to the hardware. It seems unsurprising then, that rumours are already swirling about a Switch 2 revision of its own, with the three letter code “OSM” sparking this mystery.</p>

<p>Could the first revision we see of the Switch 2 be the Switch 2 Lite? Those nosy kids on the internet have dug around in Nintendo’s back pocket – well, the User Account Portal – and found what appears to be mention of an all-new hardware tag, that doesn’t correspond to any of the current Switch consoles out there.</p>
<p>This OSM model uses the same type of product identifiers as both the original Switch and the Switch 2. The original Switch model numbers all began with “HAC”, the Lite used “HDH”, and the OLED used “HEG”, while the Switch 2 itself is thought to be “BEE”. Now, OSM doesn’t really fit into either generation, and it’s never been an acronym, but that hasn’t stopped people suggesting it might stand for Ounce Small Model or relate to an OLED revision. Maybe it’s an Oversized Switch Museum to make Welcome Tour a reality?</p>


<p>So, we’ve got a mystery, and we love a good mystery don’t we? Especially if it means we might be seeing a new version of the Switch 2, but you do really have to ask, do we need a new version of the Switch 2 already? The initial hardware is less than a year old, and new hardware’s primary function is to reinvigorate sales or find a new market for a product where sales are slowing. That’s definitely not the case for the Switch 2. The Switch Lite arrived 30 months after the first Switch came out, and the Switch OLED even later, so to see a Switch 2 Lite in 2026 would be very premature.</p>
<p>Assuming that a Lite version of the Switch 2 arrived, we can probably predict various things about it. The first is that it will be smaller and lighter than the Switch 2. The Switch Lite was some 30 percent lighter than the original Switch, weighing in at 275g compared to the Switch’s 398g. The Switch 2 weighs a hefty 534g, so if Nintendo were looking to make a similar reduction, a Switch 2 Lite could weigh in around 374g. Despite undercutting the original Switch, that’s still a long way away from the dinky Switch Lite, so perhaps they’d take things even further.</p>
<p>The most likely barrier to that will be cooling. The Switch 2’s innards are considerably more powerful than the original Switch, and so the cooling also got an upgrade for the new generation. The Switch Lite only arrived when Nintendo was able to shrink the console’s chipset and reduce its power consumption (which also led to a better battery life version of the regular model). We would likely need to see Nintendo make the same move for the Switch 2 to avoid struggling with cooling and thermal throttling.</p>
<p>One of the reasons the Switch Lite was such a hit, though, was because it was so much easier for children to hold. The smaller form factor has smaller sticks and buttons, perfect for younger hands, and without the detachable Joy Con, it was a simpler, more straightforward device, never mind easier to carry around. If Nintendo couldn’t make it that small because of hardware issues, is there really any point?</p>

<p>Of course, there could be another option for the mystery hardware tag: a revised version of the original Nintendo Switch. The Switch has been an incredible success – with over 155 million sold, it’s just scooted past the Nintendo DS into second place behind the PlayStation 2 – and Nintendo certainly still see value in supporting a console with a huge library and a monstrous install base, particularly when it can work as a gateway console before buying the newer Switch 2. At a time where consoles have been getting more expensive instead of less, and with the skyrocketing RAM prices a possible concern for the Switch 2, a cheaper version of the Switch would be the perfect way to keep Nintendo consoles arriving in more people’s homes.</p>
<p>We saw Nintendo do this with the Wii Mini, a stripped-back, cheap version of the Wii hardware that appeared six years into the console’s lifespan. We’re nearly at 9 years for the original Switch, but it still remains relevant, with new games continuing to release for the plucky hybrid. Consoles are sticking around for much longer than in previous hardware generations, and though the Switch 2 will be Nintendo’s poster child for years to come, there’s money to made with the older console, particularly when its older components shouldn’t be as affected by the AI server farm craze. And OSM? How about Original Switch Mini?</p>
<p>Whatever the case, something is intriguing about the OSM model tag, but we’ll just have to wait and see exactly what it is. In the meantime, we’ll continue to love the Switch and Switch 2 we already have.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/03/the-mystery-of-the-nintendo-osm-is-a-switch-2-lite-coming-or-could-it-be-a-switch-mini/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["This shouldn’t have happened": GOG reportedly claim sale banner made with "Al tools" ended up on store by mistake]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-shouldnt-have-happened-gog-reportedly-claim-sale-banner-made-with-al-tools-ended-up-on-store-by-mistake</link>
            <guid>1423642</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"Some experiments are successful, and some (like this banner) are not"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gog-payment-processor.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>GOG</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>After being <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gog-accused-of-using-ai-generated-art-to-promote-sale-as-job-listing-indicates-theyre-keen-to-adopt-ai-assisted-development-tools">accused last week</a> of using AI-generated artwork to promote their store's new year sale, retro game sellers GOG have reportedly addressed the issue in a private Discord server for paying supporters. According to this fresh response from a GOG staffer, the banner was made "with the help of Al tools" and was "mistakenly allowed" to be pushed live on the storefront.</p>
<!--more-->
<p><a href="https://kotaku.com/gog-ai-art-banner-ad-confirms-discord-message-small-team-slop-2000665056">Kotaku</a> report having been sent a screenshot of this response posted in a message to GOG's official Patron Discord server by an employee with the handle Arthur Slay. Beginning with Slay making clear that they're addressing the New Year Sale banner, their message as shared by Kotaku continues as follows:</p>
<blockquote>First of all, regarding the quality of the asset: This banner was a work-in-progress asset that we mistakenly allowed to be displayed on the storefront. This shouldn’t have happened. We failed on at least two levels: Quality-control of the asset that landed on the front page, and then reacting quickly enough when we noticed the error. Second, I want to confirm that this WIP asset was indeed made with the help of Al tools. We hear your disappointment with the use of this technology, and see that it’s a sensitive topic for many of you.</blockquote>
<p>Slay then reportedly went on to discuss GOG's general approach to the use of AI, emphasising that the game sellers "don’t have the infinite resources of the industry giants" and that they "experiment with tools that can allow us to do more with the limited hands we have" as part of their preservation efforts. "We’ve been testing different technologies since our beginnings," the staffer added. "Some experiments are successful, and some (like this banner) are not. Exploring various tech gives us the reach of a much larger team, so we never have to settle for doing less."</p><p>Approached for comment on the sale banner last week, GOG told RPS they were unable to "comment publicly on our internal processes or tools". I've reached out to the company for a second time in light of this Discord message.</p>
<p>The Polish storefront - noted for revamping and selling a bunch of classic games - changed ownership in late 2025, with Witcher developers CD Projekt opting to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gogs-new-owner-will-stick-to-its-revamped-classic-and-zero-drm-guns-but-does-think-lessons-lie-in-steams-overstuffed-embrace">sell to original GOG co-founder Michał Kiciński</a> in a deal worth about £18.6 million. So far, Kiciński's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gogs-new-owner-will-stick-to-its-revamped-classic-and-zero-drm-guns-but-does-think-lessons-lie-in-steams-overstuffed-embrace">suggested the plan for the store going forwards</a> is to remain focused on preservation and DRM-less games.</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/this-shouldnt-have-happened-gog-reportedly-claim-sale-banner-made-with-al-tools-ended-up-on-store-by-mistake]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft union representatives call for resignation of CEO Yves Guillemot]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-union-representatives-call-for-resignation-of-ceo-yves-guillemot</link>
            <guid>1423630</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">February 3, 2026</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>5 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Two Ubisoft union representatives have warned that it will be impossible for company management to rebuild trust with employees while long-serving CEO, Yves Guillemot, remains in power.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Speaking to Game Developer about the current climate at the French publisher, Marc Rutschlé and Chakib Mataoui—who both ply their trade at Ubisoft Paris and serve as union representatives for Solidaires Informatique—indicated staff at the company panicked and angry after experiencing what they described as a "betrayal" from top management.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rutschlé and Mataoui shared their views just weeks after the French publisher </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-is-dismantling-its-studio-ecosystem-to-become-a-more-gamer-centric-company">announced a sweeping "reset"</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that kicked off with studio closures, game cancellations, the promise of more cost-cutting, and the announcement of a return-to-office (RTO) mandate that will require staff to work on-site five days a week.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Screenshots of internal messages viewed by Game Developer suggest the initial response to that announcement was one of widespread shock, disbelief, and condemnation.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/qa-workers-at-blizzard-ratify-union-contract-with-microsoft" target="_self" data-discover="true">QA workers at Blizzard ratify union contract with Microsoft</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Guillemot himself was also called out in multiple messages posted on the company's internal communications platform, Agora, with some employees questioning why he remains in charge after presiding over what will eventually be five years of downsizing when Ubisoft concludes its €500 million cost-reduction plan in 2028.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the wake of that announcement, Rutschlé and Mataoui feel Guillemot must head for the exit if there is any hope of the company regaining the trust of its employees. Although Rutschlé doesn't believe Ubisoft's struggles are solely the fault of Guillemot, he explained that as CEO he is ultimately responsible.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It's his company, at the end of the day," says Rutschlé. "But everyone around him are just yes men. That was also the issue during the sexual [harassment] scandal in 2020."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When asked directly whether he would like to see a change in leadership at the very top, Rutschlé had a simple answer: "Sure. I expect nothing from this guy."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a sentiment shared by Mataoui, who questioned Guillemot's decision to name his son, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-announces-leadership-for-tencent-backed-subsidiary">Charlie Guillemot</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, as co-CEO of a new subsidiary that will house some of the company's biggest franchises. He said that, apart from being an instance of nepotism, Guillemot's habit of promoting those closest to him is negatively impacting Ubisoft's ability to craft hit video games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"If you just put your white male friends in [those jobs], then you don't promote any diversity or get any new opinions or ideas," continued Mataoui. "We are in a creative job. We need new ideas to come in to [help us] make great new games. But we don't have that. We don't have this mindset for creativity."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-ashes-of-creation-developer-intrepid-studios-shuts-down" target="_self" data-discover="true">Report: Ashes of Creation developer Intrepid Studios shuts down</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Mataoui said it feels as if the current cohort of Ubisoft executives "don't understand their social responsibility to employees" and suggested that workers themselves should be able to elect people to oversee the company. "I'd rather have a manger who I consent to give my workforce, than a manager who I cannot trust. The situation right now is that we don't trust these people," he added.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Notably, both Mataoui and Rutschlé said the management team at Ubisoft failed to actively rebuild bridges with employees after the company was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-ubisoft-paradox-how-the-publisher-enabled-a-culture-of-abuse-and-control">accused of enabling a culture of fear and control in 2020</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> by allegedly cultivating a workplace where abusers could thrive.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rutschlé explained those reports, coupled with the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nft-peddler-ubisoft-complains-that-players-simply-don-t-get-the-pitch">company's decision to enter the divisive NFT market</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> shortly after, only served to eradicate any remaining goodwill between workers and management.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Now, he said it feels as if there is no going back. "I think Guillemot should move away at this point," said Rutschlé. "I think the level of hate people have for him [means] he should move on. Then, we could build some sort of trust again."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Five-day return-to-office mandate has left some Ubisoft workers feeling &quot;doomed&quot;">Five-day return-to-office mandate has left some Ubisoft workers feeling "doomed"</h2><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/analyzing-the-2026-gdc-state-of-the-industry-report-game-developer-podcast-ep-63" target="_self" data-discover="true">Analyzing the 2026 GDC State Of The Industry Report - Game Developer Podcast Ep. 63</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The return-to-office policy announced by Ubisoft is viewed as particularly incendiary by Rutschlé and Mataoui, who said it shows a complete disregard for the personal wellbeing and livelihoods of employees.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Most [employees] were very, very panicked by the [RTO] announcement because they started their lives very far from Paris and from their studios—and now they're being asked to come back knowing that their paycheck doesn't help with living in the Paris area," said Mataoui.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rutschlé agreed with that assessment and suggested there is a feeling of impending "doom" internally, with the RTO policy again being called out as particularly egregious. "The whole return-to-office policy is very hard to take," said Rutschlé, who claimed Ubisoft must be aware it will cost some employees—such as those who might have recently purchased homes or who have families—their jobs at the company.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He added that Ubisoft previously struck agreements with some employees that facilitated a level of remote working. Those, he suggested, have now been torched without reason. "We asked them for documentation or analysis that showed a link between production or creativity with the return to the office. They had none," Rutschlé continued. "So it's like 'okay, let's do that then.' As a union representative, I'm like 'what the fuck, man?.'"&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rutschlé suggested the newly-announced restructure and ongoing cost-cutting is simply a way for Ubisoft to "make big announcements that make shareholders happy." Those announcements, however, have sometimes rubbed shareholders the wrong way (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://insider-gaming.com/investors-demand-ubisoft-to-renegotiate-tencent-deal/">thanks Insider Gaming</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) and tanked Ubisoft's valuation on the stock market (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.reuters.com/business/ubisoft-shares-tumble-after-assassins-creed-creator-unveils-restructuring-2026-01-22/">via Reuters</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Mataoui claimed the only way Ubisoft can now course-correct is to remove the entire board of directors and recruit "fresh minds" who are willing to lead with integrity and accountability. Rutschlé said it's also vital for Ubisoft workers across the world—especially in locations such as Montreal, which is viewed as an influential studio within the company—to organize in order to secure their own futures and hold management to account.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Join the unions," said Rutschlé, when asked whether he has a message for his colleagues across the globe. "At least organize yourself within your workplace, because our bosses are speaking to each other so we should do that too."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ubisoft workers will have the opportunity to stand shoulder-to-shoulder later this month as part of an </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-it-s-time-for-real-accountability-ubisoft-unions-call-international-strike">international strike</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that has been called by Solidaires Informatique and four other unions based in France.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ubisoft-union-representatives-call-for-resignation-of-ceo-yves-guillemot]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[As player numbers fall, Highguard makes the actually-quite-good 5v5 mode permanent]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/highguard-gets-permanent-5v5-mode</link>
            <guid>1423627</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline_PelLtAo.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline_PelLtAo.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline_PelLtAo.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline_PelLtAo.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline_PelLtAo.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline_PelLtAo.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline_PelLtAo.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline_PelLtAo.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/highguard-headline_PelLtAo.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Wildlight Entertainment</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Barely over a month in, 2026 has been busy, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/highguard">Highguard</a> is easily the strangest game release we've had so far. Following a baffling, nearly marketing-free rollout following its reveal at <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-everything-announced-at-the-game-awards-2025">The Game Awards 2025</a>, it crashed into a wall of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/highguard-hits-almost-100k-concurrent-pc-players-on-launch-but-struggles-with-early-negative-steam-reviews">negative reviews</a>, but developer Wildlight Entertainment was quick to react. Now, the sentiment is more positive following 5v5 matches being tested and locked - but can it survive the poisoned conversation that's sprung up around the game so far?</p>
<p>Ahead of the last weekend, a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/highguard-update-reduces-crashes-by-90-adds-crouch-toggle-option">first patch</a> addressed some of the most pressing criticisms, with the devs also deciding to experiment with a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/highguard-has-a-new-5v5-mode-but-its-only-live-this-weekend">limited-time 5v5 mode</a> that could maybe make Highguard's large maps feel less empty outside the attack and defence phases. It turns out that was a good call, as the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4128260/Highguard/">Steam</a> reviews have now climbed up to "Mixed" as players (the hopeful ones, at least) engage with a more frenetic and brutal version of the shooter. Thus, the 5v5 queue is staying.</p>
<p>Of course, the conversation on social media and YouTube is far more negative, with the usual suspects using the latest big attempt at breaking into the live-service space as a punching bag instead of downvoting and moving on. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/are-we-being-too-hard-on-live-service-games">There's a conversation worth having</a> about the industry reaching peak live-service critical mass years ago, sure, but don't expect grifters to approach <em>any game</em> making waves in good faith.</p>
<p>That said, the reality of the situation is that Highguard is struggling after a confusing launch and due to its objectively under-cooked state. There's a few too many different shooters in that esports-oriented mix, and not all of them work or play well together. The 5v5 mode is promising in that it actually feels good to play and makes you catch a glimpse of what the game <em>could become</em> in the long run. That is, if there's a long run for it. We know <a href="https://www.polygon.com/highguard-roadmap-apex-legends-live-service-plan/">Wildlight worked on a full-year roadmap for Highguard</a>, but can the game really sustain itself for so long?</p><p>The game's <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/4128260/charts/#1w">SteamDB profile</a> paints a grim picture, at least on PC, with the concurrent players chart steadily going down since Highguard opened its gates on 26th January. 3,157 players are inside the game at the time of writing, with 8,404 at its 24-hour peak. Positive reviews are up, yes, and even surpassing the negative ones now, but these numbers aren't what you want to see only a week after launch when you're thinking big with another online shooter.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>SteamDB</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>We don't have access to the data on consoles yet, but so far, the crossplay capabilities are ensuring that matchmaking is quick, so there might be a bigger interest there that we can't quantify. In my personal case, I'm now curious about where it could go following the 5v5 update, but <a href="https://www.vg247.com/concord-review">having been burned in the past</a> a few too many times by similar shooters, I'm also staying realistic.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/highguard-gets-permanent-5v5-mode]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch finally surpasses the Nintendo DS to become company's best-selling console, ever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-finally-surpasses-the-nintendo-ds-to-become-companys-best-selling-console-ever</link>
            <guid>1423624</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Nintendo-Switch-console-with-party-confetti-to-the-lower-left.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Nintendo-Switch-console-with-party-confetti-to-the-lower-left.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Nintendo-Switch-console-with-party-confetti-to-the-lower-left.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Nintendo-Switch-console-with-party-confetti-to-the-lower-left.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Nintendo-Switch-console-with-party-confetti-to-the-lower-left.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Nintendo-Switch-console-with-party-confetti-to-the-lower-left.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Nintendo-Switch-console-with-party-confetti-to-the-lower-left.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Nintendo-Switch-console-with-party-confetti-to-the-lower-left.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Nintendo-Switch-console-with-party-confetti-to-the-lower-left.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The Nintendo Switch has surpassed the DS to become the company's best selling console ever.</p>
<p>As shared in <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2026/260203e.pdf">Nintendo's latest financial report</a>, which covers the first nine months of FY2026 up until 31st December 2025, the Switch has now sold 155.37m units. To compare, the company's previous best selling console - the Nintendo DS - has clocked up 154.02m units sold as of 31st December 2025.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>3.25m Switch units were sold during the nine-month period covered in Nintendo's latest financial report, which began on 1st April 2025.</p>
<p>Nintendo's Switch console is now the second best selling console of all time, only behind that of the PlayStation 2. Back in 2024, Sony confirmed its PS2 console - which first released back in March 2000 - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ps2-officially-surpasses-160m-sales-retaining-its-best-selling-console-crown">had shifted 160m units since its millennium launch</a>.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Meanwhile, Nintendo's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/platforms/switch-2">Switch 2</a> has sold 17.37m units as of 31st December 2025, with the company adding its latest console had got off to a "good start" on its release in June. The Switch 2 is Nintendo's fastest-selling dedicated video game platform.</p><p>As for Switch 2 software sales, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> has sold 14.03m units, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> has sold 4.25m units, Pokemon Legends: Z-A - Nintendo Switch 2 Edition has sold 3.89m units and Kirby Air Riders has sold 1.76m units.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Looking at the coming weeks, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-93-most-exciting-games-of-2026">Nintendo is set to release Mario Tennis Fever in February, and then Pokémon Pokopia will be arriving in March</a>.</p>
<p>Mario Tennis Fever promises 38 characters - the most in the series' history apparently - plus a range of different activities, online options, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-everything-announced-in-nintendos-latest-direct">an adventure mode starring the Mario babies</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  




  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-finally-surpasses-the-nintendo-ds-to-become-companys-best-selling-console-ever]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>