<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 20:35:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dark Messiah of Might and Magic RTX Remix Mod Gets New Trailer; Online Co-Op Mod Now Available]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-rtx-remix-mod-gets-new-trailer-online-co-op-mod-now-available/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-rtx-remix-mod-gets-new-trailer-online-co-op-mod-now-available.1109013/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-rtx-remix-mod-gets-new-trailer-online-co-op-mod-now-available/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The cult classic Dark Messiah of Might and Magic is receiving a lot of attention in the modding community <a href="https://wccftech.com/dark-messiah-of-might-and-magic-modders-show-rtx-remix-upgrade-co-op-also-planned/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">thanks to wiltOS Technologies</a>, which is hard at work on three mods (plus a bonus one) to rejuvenate the 2006 game originally developed by Arkane and published by Ubisoft.</p>
<p>Firstly, there's the <a href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/dark-messiah-restoration-mod" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Restoration mod</a>, which brings back some cut content with the help of Ubisoft. The modders were provided with access to assets from Elements, the Xbox 360 version of the game. Thanks to this, the bonus missions and alternate levels that were featured in that version of the game can now be played on PC. Players can also experience The Caves, a cut level, and use cut weapons such as the Sword of Misery or the Necromancer's Staff.</p>
<p>WiltOS Technologies even introduced quality-of-life features such as the Bonus Maps system, which allows level loading without console commands, and a redesigned new game menu with chapter and class selection taken from the Elements. With the Bonus Maps menu, the madders also added a Challenge mode that uses the map add system.</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>Then there's the online co-op mod, which has just launched as a public test build downloadable <a href="https://github.com/KingDavidW/DarkMessiah-Coop-Mod-Files" target="_blank" rel="noopener">via GitHub</a>. This is still an early build, though, as evidenced by the fact that three major features are missing: the new player models, the refined revive mechanics, and the cutscenes.</p>
<p>Lastly, there's the Dark Messiah of Might and Magic graphics overhaul mod powered by NVIDIA RTX Remix. This mod just got a new trailer, which you can find embedded below.</p>
<p><iframe title="RTX Remix Project | Dark Messiah of Might and Magic | The City of Stonehelm" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kN347m66sgc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The team of asset makers for the RTX Remix mod has expanded from two to three, but these high-quality assets take a long time to complete. Because of that, wiltOS Technologies plans to first release a version with the original textures and the RTX Remix enhanced lighting and then slowly introduce the improved textures as they are ready.</p>
<p>The bonus mod mentioned earlier in the article is a proof-of-concept for random map generation based on certain rules. Called 'The Trials of Kha-Baleth', it's meant to be an unofficial continuation to the story that uses DungeonGen technology derived from Alien Swarm's TileGen technology. In addition, players have the option to simply start a randomized level or create their own campaign. You can follow the progress of this work <a href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/the-trials-of-kha-baleth" target="_blank" rel="noopener">on the dedicated page</a>.</p>
<p>Are you excited that Dark Messiah of Might and Magic is getting all this attention after nearly twenty years from its release?</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arcane Wonders Announces Onstage, A Trick-Taking Game About A Theater Troupe]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/arcane-wonders-announces-onstage-trick-taking-game-about-theater-troupe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arcane-wonders-announces-onstage-a-trick-taking-game-about-a-theater-troupe.1109010/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/arcane-wonders-announces-onstage-trick-taking-game-about-theater-troupe<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Arcane Wonders has announced a new board game is coming to GenCon. They have partnered with Rolling Wizards Games to produce <em>Onstage</em>, a trick-taking game that blends Vietnamese-inspired artwork with theater performances.</p>

<h2>The <em>Onstage</em> Board Game Announcement</h2>

<p>In an official press release, Arcane Wonders provides more details on the Onstage board game. Three to five players are part of a theater company competing for the best performers to join their troupe. It is a must-follow trick-taking game with a twist. The trump suit can (and often will) change mid-round, which will keep players on their toes. Each game takes 15-30 minutes to complete.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/onstage-board-game-set-up-artwork.jpg?itok=59QnLjls 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/onstage-board-game-set-up-artwork.jpg?itok=dr_PWMos 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>On top of this unique gameplay, Onstage features beautiful Vietnamese-inspired artwork. Everything from the cards to the meeples to the game's pop-up stage all showcases a distinct art style featuring rich pinks, greens, blues, and dark reds.</p>

<p><em>Onstage</em> is the latest board game to join the Dice Tower Essentials line. This is a list of prestigious board games curated and hand-picked by board game critic Tom Vasel. This list has included the English language release of the 90s nostalgia-fueled board game <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/video-game-champion-brings-retro-game-collecting-fun-to-gaming-tables" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Video Game Champion</em></a>, and Mitsuru Nakamura's cooperative number card game, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/ito-card-game-getting-western-localization" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Ito</em></a>.</p>

<p>Arcane Wonders has a similarly acclaimed body of work. Their past titles include the detective board game <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/sherlock-13-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Sherlock 13</em></a>, and the deep diving board game <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/aquatica-board-game-review" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Aquatica</em></a>. They also helped produce an officially licensed <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/call-of-duty-board-game-deploys-to-kickstarter-this-august" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Call of Duty</em> board game</a>. They partnered with Vasel in 2014 to expand its catalog with the curated Dice Tower Essentials line.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/onstage-stage-box-artwork.jpg?itok=EjXr1h7_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/onstage-stage-box-artwork.jpg?itok=SiY_l8z4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p><em>Onstage</em> is the second board game developed by Rolling Wizards Games. The Vietnam-based studio's first game, <em>Stem and Branch</em>, is a fast-paced card game based on animals and elements from the Eastern zodiac. Each game is represented as a 60-year calendar.</p>

<p>The game will be sold during GenCon 2025. At time of writing there is no word on a retail release or price.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Hope Every RPG Steals Avowed's Brilliant Inventory System]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/avowed-rpg-xbox-game-pass-inventory-review-skyrim-1851762830</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/i-hope-every-rpg-steals-avoweds-brilliant-inventory-system.1109004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/avowed-rpg-xbox-game-pass-inventory-review-skyrim-1851762830<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Obsidian’s latest RPG, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avowed-xbox-pc-rpg-game-pass-skyrim-review-kotaku-1851761525&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-xbox-pc-rpg-game-pass-skyrim-review-kotaku-1851761525"><em>Avowed</em></a></span>, is out now on Xbox and PC (f<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/paid-early-access-pre-order-madden-star-wars-outlaws-1851596675&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/paid-early-access-pre-order-madden-star-wars-outlaws-1851596675">or those who pre-ordered the expensive fancy version</a></span>) and it’s a really good game! But one key thing I wanted to highlight is the RPG’s inventory and item management system because it’s really good and I want more games to copy it.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196055" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="227" data-playlist="196055,196599,196029" data-current="196055"><div><p>6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21584.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Sure, I’ll freely admit that an RPG’s inventory system might not be the sexiest or coolest topic. But it is a very important part of any game that features loot, potions, food, weapons, and gear. </p><p>A bad inventory system can ruin a great game and make it a chore to play. Having to endlessly fiddle about with various bags or being forced to run back to a shop or town to offload crap isn’t my idea of fun. So I was happy to discover that <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/avowed-rpg-obsidian-hands-on-preview-xbox-pc-1851703825&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-rpg-obsidian-hands-on-preview-xbox-pc-1851703825"><em>Avowed</em></a></span><em> </em>avoids all that annoying busywork with its streamlined and smart inventory system. The result is a more enjoyable experience because you spend less time fussing about with 400 items and more time doing stuff you actually want to do in a big RPG. </p><figure id="" data-id="aa43aa999221dd18d33e6c22b884af59" data-recommend-id="image://aa43aa999221dd18d33e6c22b884af59" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="aa43aa999221dd18d33e6c22b884af59" data-recommend-id="image://aa43aa999221dd18d33e6c22b884af59" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Perhaps the biggest and smartest feature in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-avowed-rpg-tips-tricks-before-you-play-1851760887&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-avowed-rpg-tips-tricks-before-you-play-1851760887"><em>Avowed</em></a></span><em> </em>is the ability to instantly and easily transport items to your camp stash. Find a cool sword that doesn’t quite fit your current build, but you want to play around with it later? Send it back to camp with a single button press. Stumble upon some valuable armor that is really heavy and will make you overencumbered, but you want to sell it later?  Well, just hit a button and send it back to your camp. You can do this anywhere with no restrictions and it’s awesome. Does it make sense? No, but the fact that I can even hold 10 swords in the first place doesn’t make sense either, so who cares?</p><p>The thing is, though, you might not even need to use this feature all that much because a lot of loot you find in <em>Avowed </em>doesn’t weigh anything. Consumable items—foods, potions, lockpicks—don’t weight anything. Likewise, crafting and upgrade materials—iron, wood, furs—also weigh nothing. I never, in my 40 hours or so with <em>Avowed</em>, left a dungeon  desperate to sell stuff in order to free up some inventory space. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/starfield-overencumbered-contraband-ship-parts-how-to-1850815667?_gl=1*29yk13*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczOTQ2NjIwNS40NDMuMS4xNzM5NDY2ODM4LjU3LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/starfield-overencumbered-contraband-ship-parts-how-to-1850815667?_gl=1*29yk13*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczOTQ2NjIwNS40NDMuMS4xNzM5NDY2ODM4LjU3LjAuMA..">That’s a common occurrence in many RPGs</a></span>, but not <em>Avowed</em>. And even if you do pick up way too many swords and armor items, which <em>do</em> weigh you down, you can just teleport that stuff to camp.</p><p>But funnily enough, you often won’t even have to do  that because you can always break down any weapon or piece of gear you find at any time and get its resources. Then you can use those resources, which weigh nothing, to upgrade your equipped gear and make it better. It’s wonderful.</p><figure id="" data-id="cad8190ca65bfb41f76a32380ce16da7" data-recommend-id="image://cad8190ca65bfb41f76a32380ce16da7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Obsidian / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="cad8190ca65bfb41f76a32380ce16da7" data-recommend-id="image://cad8190ca65bfb41f76a32380ce16da7" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Some might argue that this is too convenient and easy. I disagree. I think Obsidian correctly realized that managing stacks of crappy swords and pieces of iron isn’t much fun, nor is it what people want out of a roleplaying game. I want to fight monsters, meet new characters, explore strange lands and save the day. And <em>Avowed </em>focuses on all that stuff and doesn’t let inventory management get in the way.</p><p> I think more games should do that. Figure out what you want your game to be and the experience you want players to have while playing it. Then, once you understand that, cut anything that doesn’t help achieve that desired experience. Ultimately, sorting through forty pieces of iron isn’t why people play games like <em>Avowed</em>, so why make them do it?</p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA College Football 26 Could Offer Bigger Payouts To Players]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-college-football-26-could-offer-bigger-payouts-to-players/1100-6529500/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-college-football-26-could-offer-bigger-payouts-to-players.1108995/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-college-football-26-could-offer-bigger-payouts-to-players/1100-6529500/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529500">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Earlier this year, EA officially announced that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-26-announced-launches-this-summer/1100-6528861/" data-ref-id="1100-6528861">EA College Football 26 was in development</a> for release this summer. Last year, EA offered high-profile college football players $600 each for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-offering-college-athletes-600-to-appear-in-new-football-game/1100-6521289/" data-ref-id="1100-6521289">the right to use their names, images, and likenesses</a> in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/ea-sports-college-football-25-review-university-of-madden/1900-6418261/" data-ref-id="1900-6418261">EA College Football 25</a>. But if a new sports representative company is successful, EA may have to pay a significantly higher amount to include those players in EA College Football 26.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://sports.yahoo.com/college-football-players-sign-agreement-to-be-paid-for-likeness-in-video-games-134529715.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Yahoo Sports</a>, Pathway Sports and Entertainment is making aggressive inroads by pursuing the elite players in college football. The company has offered players $1,500 upfront for their NIL (Name, Image, Likeness) rights in addition to royalty pay that has yet to be fleshed out. Over 450 students at Alabama, Illinois, Georgia, Texas Tech, Wisconsin, and Oregon have already taken the deal, and Pathway has even grander ambitions.</p><p>Pathway is currently sending representatives to colleges across the nation with the desire to sign every football player who is on a scholarship program. There are approximately 11,000 players who have scholarships, and it would take more than $17 million to sign them all at the currently offered rate. However, the report suggests that the total payout may exceed $20 million when factoring in "ambassador payments" for certain students.</p><p>"The overall vision is for athletes to make more money than we saw in the first year of the video game," said Pathway co-founder Casey Schwab in a statement. "We are creating mutual value here. This is a good thing for athletic directors, coaches, and schools because they are trying to create legit opportunities for their players. These are legitimate."</p><p>EA doesn't have any involvement with Pathway at this point. But if Pathway can sign up all or most of the athletes that EA wants to get for EA College Football 26, then the video game publisher will either have to agree to a new deal or go without the star players who helped make the franchise into one of EA Sports' top-sellers. </p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed - All Totem Of Revelations Pieces And Locations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-all-totem-of-revelations-pieces-and-locations/1100-6529498/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/avowed-all-totem-of-revelations-pieces-and-locations.1108992/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-all-totem-of-revelations-pieces-and-locations/1100-6529498/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529498">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Each region in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/avowed/" data-ref-id="5000-516154">Avowed</a> is home to a totem you can find the pieces to and assemble, offering special passive bonuses when activated at camp. In Shatterscarp you can find the Totem of Revelations, with its six pieces and Totem Base scattered throughout the area. You can purchase a note with one-sentence hints and the names of each piece from the barkeep in Thirdborn, but it won't add markers to the map.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>The totem pieces can be found in any order.</strong></p><h2 dir="ltr" id="Totem_Base">Totem Base</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443808-shatterscarp9.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443808" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443808-shatterscarp9.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443808"></a><figcaption>The Shrine to Wael is in the southwest part of Shatterscarp.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443808-shatterscarp9.jpeg"></figure><p>The Totem Base can be found in the Shrine to Wael in the southwest region of Scatterscarp. It's inside a cave, which you must follow a path into.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443809-shatterscarp11.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443809" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443809-shatterscarp11.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443809"></a><figcaption>Wrap around the southern part of the shrine to find the entrance to the cave.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443809-shatterscarp11.jpeg"></figure><p>Start here on the cliff overlooking the ocean and jump down the path of rocks.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443810-shatterscarp12.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443810" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443810-shatterscarp12.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443810"></a><figcaption>Follow this tunnel to find the cave.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443810-shatterscarp12.jpeg"></figure><p>Wrap around the back cliffside to find an entrance into a pink flowing cave. There aren't any branching paths here, so just keep moving forward until you reach the cave interior, where the Totem Base can be found on an altar.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443811-shatterscarp6.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443811" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443811-shatterscarp6.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443811"></a><figcaption>The Totem Base is inside the Shrine of Wael cave.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443811-shatterscarp6.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Ruby_Eye">Ruby Eye</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443812-shatterscarp22.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443812" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443812-shatterscarp22.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443812"></a><figcaption>The Ruby Eye is also in the Shrine to Wael.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443812-shatterscarp22.jpeg"></figure><p>From the Shrine to Wael cave, where you found the Totem Base, turn to the part of the cave to the right of the altar, where there are some pink glowing rocks leading to a small cave path. Head inside.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443813-shatterscarp20.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443813" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443813-shatterscarp20.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443813"></a><figcaption>Follow the pink stones to a small tunnel leading to the Ruby Eye.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443813-shatterscarp20.jpeg"></figure><p>Follow the path and you will find a person, Ward of the Eye, standing next to the Ruby Eye. You can grab the piece or speak with the ward who will give it to you if you are cooperative.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443814-shatterscarp21.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443814" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443814-shatterscarp21.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443814"></a><figcaption>The Ruby Eye can be grabbed off the ground or given to you by the ward.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443814-shatterscarp21.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Amethyst_Eye">Amethyst Eye</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443816-shatterscarp14.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443816" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443816-shatterscarp14.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443816"></a><figcaption>This piece can be found in the southeast part of the Ancient Lakebed.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443816-shatterscarp14.jpeg"></figure><p>The Amethyst Eye can be found in the eastern part of the Ancient Lakebed. Head into the lake bed and look for a cave formation on the eastern part. Under there will be a woman and a bunch of graves; the Amethyst Eye is on a rock near the graves.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443817-shatterscarp13.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443817" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443817-shatterscarp13.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443817"></a><figcaption>The Amethyst Eye is on this rock next to the graves.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443817-shatterscarp13.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Topaz_Eye">Topaz Eye</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443818-shatterscarp16.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443818" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443818-shatterscarp16.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443818"></a><figcaption>The Topaz Eye is located in Leviathan's Hollow.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443818-shatterscarp16.jpeg"></figure><p>The Topaz Eye can be found in the Leviathan's Hollow, between the Sulfur Mines Basecamp and the Naku Kubel Approach in the northern part of Scatterscarp. You'll start by heading into the giant skull cave and swimming under the water.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443819-shatterscarp17.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443819" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443819-shatterscarp17.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443819"></a><figcaption>Go inside the mouth and underwater to reach the interior area.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443819-shatterscarp17.jpeg"></figure><p>When you emerge, head up to the ruins straight ahead of you and jump to the top of the building using the scaffolding to the left of it.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443821-shatterscarp18.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443821" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443821-shatterscarp18.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443821"></a><figcaption>Head up to the top of the building shown above and down the stairs behind it.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443821-shatterscarp18.jpeg"></figure><p>On the top of the ruins, there are stairs heading into a small cave, with a person's body next to a table, the Topaz Eye is on the table.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443825-shatterscarp15.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443825" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443825-shatterscarp15.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443825"></a><figcaption>The Topaz Eye is on this table, next to a side quest item.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443825-shatterscarp15.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Emerald_Eye">Emerald Eye</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443831-shatterscarp25.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443831" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443831-shatterscarp25.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443831"></a><figcaption>The Emerald Eye is located in Shark's Teeth ruins, in northern part.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443831-shatterscarp25.jpeg"></figure><p>In Shark's Teeth in the northwest region, start at the Sharks Teeth Party Camp. Turn to the southeast and you'll spot a small statue with scaffolding around it.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443832-shatterscarp26.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443832" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443832-shatterscarp26.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443832"></a><figcaption>The totem piece is on top of the statue shown here.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443832-shatterscarp26.jpeg"></figure><p>The Emerald Eye is on the top; just climb up to it.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443833-shatterscarp23.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443833" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443833-shatterscarp23.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443833"></a><figcaption>The Emerald Eye is on top of this partially built statue.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443833-shatterscarp23.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Agate_Eye">Agate Eye</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443836-shatterscarp3.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443836" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443836-shatterscarp3.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443836"></a><figcaption>The Agate Eye is in the Sand Sea Ruins, but not in the dungeon of the same name.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443836-shatterscarp3.jpeg"></figure><p>The Agate Eye can be found in the Sand Sea Ruins, specifically the ruins above the dungeon of the same name. To get inside, start north of the ruins and use the ruins there to climb towards the top.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443838-shatterscarp29.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443838" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443838-shatterscarp29.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443838"></a><figcaption>North of the ruins, use the bits of ruins and scaffolding to get on top of the main circular building.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443838-shatterscarp29.jpeg"></figure><p>Once inside, jump down to the middle floor of the main circular building and follow the hallway to find the Agate Eye on a table.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443839-shatterscarp2.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443839" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443839-shatterscarp2.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443839"></a><figcaption>The Agate eye is on a table on the second floor of the main ruins.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443839-shatterscarp2.jpeg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Sapphire_Eye">Sapphire Eye</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443841-shatterscarp28.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443841" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443841-shatterscarp28.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443841"></a><figcaption>The Sapphire Eye is located in the small Oasis water in the southeast corner of Shatterscarp.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443841-shatterscarp28.jpeg"></figure><p>The Sapphire Eye can be found in the southeast section of the map in the Sand Sea Oasis. It's located next to a skeleton in the water, just swim down to it.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443843-shatterscarp27.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443843" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443843-shatterscarp27.jpeg" data-ref-id="1300-4443843"></a><figcaption>Swim down to find the eye near a skeleton in the small pond.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1599/15997278/4443843-shatterscarp27.jpeg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Obsidian is no stranger to crafting compelling RPGs. For more help on the team's latest effort, use our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/avowed-guides-hub/1100-6529402/">Avowed guides hub</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Doubles Down On Open-World And Live-Service Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-doubles-down-on-open-world-and-live-service-games/1100-6529497/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-doubles-down-on-open-world-and-live-service-games.1108989/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-doubles-down-on-open-world-and-live-service-games/1100-6529497/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529497">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>As part of Ubisoft's earnings report, the company discussed what kinds of games it wants to focus on going forward--and these include open-world action adventure titles and games-as-a-service projects.</p><p>Ubisoft executive Frederick Duguet <a href="https://edge.media-server.com/mmc/p/nb5rhxgg/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">said on an earnings call that</a> the company has been "investing significantly" in recent times on a "big pipeline" of its two main product categories. These are the aforementioned open-world action adventure and games-as-a-service genres. "That's what we want to deliver year after year," the executive said.</p><p>Ubisoft focusing on big open-world games and live-service titles is nothing new for the company. However, historically, Ubisoft had a more diverse lineup of games spanning multiple different genres and formats. And not every live-service project has worked out for Ubisoft, as the company launched and shut down games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xdefiant-shuts-down-in-june-2025-ubisoft-closes-two-offices/1100-6528210/" data-ref-id="1100-6528210">XDefiant</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/hyper-scape-servers-are-shutting-down-april-28-ubisoft-says/1100-6500039/" data-ref-id="1100-6500039">Hyper Scape relatively quickly</a>. The pirate game Skull &amp; Bones is still up and running but hasn't exactly broken through to become a hit.</p><p>Duguet went on to list off some of Ubisoft's upcoming projects that have been announced so far, including Assassin's Creed Shadows and more ongoing updates for Rainbow Six Siege, Anno 117: Pax Romana, and The Division Resurgence. The executive said the company will share more details about other upcoming games around May, which is when Ubisoft will release its next earnings report. That's also around when many game companies open the floodgates for gaming news throughout the summer season after various shows and events.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="334214244" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465626,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Assassin%27s%20Creed%20Shadows%3A%20Story%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:151,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/assassins-creed-shadows-story-trailer\/2300-6465626\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465626\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465626\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465626\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465626&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465626,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6529497&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;assassins-creed-shadows,tom-clancys-the-division-resurgence&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-5,macintosh,ios-iphoneipad,android,mobile&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;ubisoft&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;assassins-creed,tom-clancy,tom-clancys-the-division&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;assassins-creed,tom-clancy,tom-clancys-the-division&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465626},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465626\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4432550-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/RPe14AAm.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1737654840,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="RPe14AAm" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465626" data-src="/videos/assassins-creed-shadows-story-trailer/2300-6465626/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Assassin's Creed Shadows: Story Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p>Whatever Ubisoft has coming--and the company hasn't said much about its future title slate--Duguet said the company has a "strong pipeline for the future years." It is expected that Ubisoft would speak in this manner. Duguet was responding to a question about the company's future outlook, and presenting it in a rosy and robust manner is normal behavior for an executive speaking to analysts.</p><p>Regarding Assassin's Creed Shadows, the game is coming this March and preorder numbers are tracking in line with those of Assassin's Creed Odyssey, Ubisoft said. Odyssey was the second most successful entry in the entire Assassin's Creed franchise, according to Ubisoft, though it didn't say by what metric.</p><p>In other news, Ubisoft is in the midst of a cost-reduction program that has resulted in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-closes-studio-eliminating-185-jobs-in-latest-round-of-cuts/1100-6529036/" data-ref-id="1100-6529036">layoffs and studio closures</a>. CEO Yves Guillemot said these changes were "difficult but necessary." Additionally, Ubisoft is undergoing a "formal review process" for helping to turn its business around, with one potential scenario being <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-refuses-to-comment-on-tencent-rumors-but-says-its-exploring-options-to-maximize-value/1100-6528718/" data-ref-id="1100-6528718">a deal of some type with Tencent.</a> Guillemot said of negotiations about the company's future, "We are convinced there are different potential paths to achieve this ambition."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 brings loot boxes back from the grave]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/overwatch-2-brings-loot-boxes-back-from-the-grave</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-brings-loot-boxes-back-from-the-grave.1108986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/overwatch-2-brings-loot-boxes-back-from-the-grave<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Blizzard Entertainment.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On February 18, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Overwatch 2's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Season 15 will bring loot boxes back so players can "earn a variety of cosmetics" for weekly and event in-game rewards.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24177197/overwatch-2-spotlight-a-new-era-of-innovation-and-excitement/">Blizzard Entertainment</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> explains it, the loot boxes will be transparent and players their chances of obtaining cosmetics. The developer said each box will feature an in-game item with a value of Rare or higher, an Epic item within five consecutive boxes, and a Legendary within 20 consecutive boxes.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The original </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Overwatch </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">featured random-chance loot boxes as part of its monetization model, wherein players could spend real money on the digital items. While profitable for Activision Blizzard, some like the Belgian government considered this a potential form of gambling. Blizzard later removed paid loot boxes from versions of the hero shooter sold in both </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blizzard-removes-paid-loot-boxes-and-loot-chests-for-players-in-belgium">Belgium</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blizzard-to-sell-i-overwatch-i-credits-instead-of-loot-boxes-to-chinese-players">China</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In 2022, the developer </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blizzard-will-stop-selling-i-overwatch-i-s-in-game-loot-boxes">eliminated paid loot boxes</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> from all versions of the game, and made it so players could solely earn them through leveling up via gameplay rather than spending money. Since launch, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Overwatch 2 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">has featured an </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blizzard-explains-i-overwatch-2-i-s-battle-pass-and-in-game-shop">in-game shop</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that explicitly shows players what they're buying, and has a rotating selection of items to purchase.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Blizzard's blog does not mention how much players can spend on loot boxes, or how this will affect the game's seasonal rewards going forward.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="New year, new ">New year, new <span>Overwatch 2</span></h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">What else is changing in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Overwatch 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">? In a 30-minute video, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cf5dPQ7YeE8">Blizzard</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> outlined a series of changes and updates to come, with the most significant being Perks.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These Hero-specific bonuses come after a Hero has leveled up mid-match. The first level up will feature "lighter upgrades" like cooldowns or passives, and the second will include major "gameplay-shifting perks." As an example, Torbjorn players will have the option to choose between setting turrets on walls and ceilings or calling in a single, Level 3 turret.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Pre-release, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Overwatch 2's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">much-touted </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-i-overwatch-2-i-director-explains-pve-pivot">PvE mode</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">would have let players level up their Heroes and upgrade them with in-game perks, which this new system appears to be a rework of. Blizzard has since begun incorporating elements from that scrapped mode, such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/blizzard-reboots-i-overwatch-2-i-s-pve-mode-into-seasonal-story-missions">seasonal story missions</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, into the hero shooter.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This will also sound familiar to those who play </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Apex Legends, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">which featured a similar mid-match leveling system with its </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/apex-legends-next-season-brings-mid-match-character-leveling">20th Season</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in early 2024.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">More information on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Overwatch 2's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">upcoming changes, including the next two Heroes, can be read </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24177197/overwatch-2-spotlight-a-new-era-of-innovation-and-excitement/">here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lost in Random: The Eternal Die Launching in Summer 2025, Demo Available on Steam]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/lost-in-random-the-eternal-die-launching-in-summer-2025-demo-available-on-steam/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lost-in-random-the-eternal-die-launching-in-summer-2025-demo-available-on-steam.1108941/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/lost-in-random-the-eternal-die-launching-in-summer-2025-demo-available-on-steam/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, Thunderful announced that Lost in Random: The Eternal Die will be launching in the Summer of 2025 on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch, and PC. This game is set within the same universe as Lost in Random, a Gothic fairy-tale-inspired action-adventure that was released in 2021 as an<a href="https://wccftech.com/ea-announces-originals-it-takes-two-lost-in-random-rocket-arena/"> EA Original</a>. If you want to see what you can expect from Lost in Random: The Eternal Die, there is an official gameplay trailer below to introduce you to the world and combat.</p>
<p>This game is the leading project for Stormteller Games, the recently rebranded studio that was previously known as Thunderful Gothenburg.</p>
<p><iframe title="Lost in Random: The Eternal Die | Official Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BsxC6L4k-kE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>For those on PC, the first public demo is available now on Steam, with the demo also being available on Xbox as of tomorrow, February 14. There is no word as to whether there will be a demo for this game on PlayStation 5 or Nintendo Switch as of yet.</p>
<p>In Lost in Random: The Eternal Die, Aleksandra, who was once known as The Queen, has been captured alongside her companion Fortune and jailed inside the Black Die by Mare the Knight, who is plotting their final chapter. As a result of this, you have to fight your way through a randomly generated gauntlet, where there will be pawns to take on and giant board games. As you explore, you will be given the opportunity to claim treasure, which will improve your improve your chances of dealing with Aleksandra's tormentor, much like typical roguelikes.</p>
<p>The roguelike element comes in with the randomly generated gauntlet, as well as the ability to combine over 100 relics that have powerful card-based abilities that can then unleash devastating synergies. You get to pick between four unique weapons as you explore four randomly generated worlds, with each of them being home to unique secrets and challenges to undertake. There are over 30 different enemy types that you will encounter on your journeys, with some really challenging bosses that will pull you out of your comfort zone.</p>
<p>Lost in Random: The Eternal Die is set to stand out from the crowd with a fully voiced story that takes place in a Tim Burton-inspired world, which is brought to life with gorgeous Gothic landscapes and a fitting soundtrack that encompasses the energy of Tim Burton's work.</p>
<p>Lost in Random: The Eternal Die will be available on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch, and PC via Steam in Summer 2025. As a reminder, there is also <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2564520/Lost_in_Random_The_Eternal_Die/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a demo</a> available on PC right now, with the demo set to release on Xbox tomorrow.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Horror At Highrook demo is a dangerously enticing marriage of Darkest Dungeon and Cluedo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-horror-at-highrook-demo-is-a-dangerously-enticing-marriage-of-darkest-dungeon-and-cluedo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-horror-at-highrook-demo-is-a-dangerously-enticing-marriage-of-darkest-dungeon-and-cluedo.1108938/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-horror-at-highrook-demo-is-a-dangerously-enticing-marriage-of-darkest-dungeon-and-cluedo<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>J'accuse the Plague Doctor in the Chapel with the bottle of reagent</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_ihNEWem.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nullpointer Games / Outersloth</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
It’s easy to lose moments watching the ambience of the gameboard change in the demo for haunted house RPG <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-horror-at-highrook">The Horror At Highrook</a>. The colours alter from daytime greyness through winey shades of sunset into pale lavender moonlight. There are little details to notice and zoom on: a fleeting embroidery of rain, the seep of flames in the kitchen and guest rooms, a fidgeting of moths in the archives. Ah, nice. The last time I felt so beguiled by a view of a house was while looking out from the hamlet of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/darkest-dungeon">Darkest Dungeon</a>. 
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
You can’t just sit and stare, however. Left idle, your characters will grow hungry, fatigued and unhinged, while useful items such as potent breeds of fungus will disintegrate. So move your cards around. Put somebody in the kitchen to make a meal out of that sack of grain you found, while somebody else combs the archives for the door code to the locked laboratory, and somebody else fumbles around in the courtyard with a trowel.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Welcome to the Manor | The Horror at Highrook Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/loZ_JDedKHY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Welcome to the Manor | The Horror at Highrook Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/loZ_JDedKHY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/loZ_JDedKHY?autoplay=1" title="Welcome to the Manor | The Horror at Highrook Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=loZ_JDedKHY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Once your party’s basic needs are met, you can spare a thought for the mysteries of the game’s house, beginning with the disappearance of the Ackeron family who once lived here. Notes hint at secrets in the sealed chapel and deep underground. Tunnels and “tears” and worrying designs upon the walls. Yes, this is like Darkest Dungeon in many more ways than one.
</p>
<p>
It’s also quite a lot like Cluedo, if Cluedo has been written by Poe or Lovecraft. In The Horror At High Rook, you plonk your characters down in rooms and give them items so they can complete tasks, ranging from deciphering books to running a spyglass over the crags beneath the mansion. These tasks have resource requirements corresponding to character stats, which can be amplified by means of other, supporting cards - some representing artefacts, some "visions", tendencies, qualities.</p>
<p>The “Gift of the Bee”, for example, might help your plague doctor Caligula with her lab work. “My blood buzzes, as if my body is a hive,” the card description explains, adding “I am in awe of the simple alchemies of the everyday”. There’s another “vision” card with simian properties that makes life easier in the machine shop, ensuring that your Mecanist always finds the correct spanner at her elbow.</p>
<p>These representations of the paranormal, together with the visual design of the cards themselves, put me heavily in mind of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/cultist-simulator">Cultist Simulator</a> - a game I loved but haven't played since its primary creator, Alexis Kennedy, was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/alexis-kennedy-denies-allegations-of-abusive-or-coercive-behaviour">accused of harassment by several women</a> (allegations he has denied). I'm still thinking about how that association shapes my feelings about The Horror Of Highrook. It's very much a case of one game being haunted by another.
</p>
<p>
The writing so far is wordier than you'd find in Cultist Simulator - a bit too opulent when you’re trying to process a bunch of card timers or attend to several characters who need resting or feeding, but there’s always the pause button. There are some more obvious rough edges. Atticus Hawk, the streetwise muscle in my group of occult investigators, has an accent I can’t quite hear in my head. Is he from Blighty or the States? It feels like the developer, former Big Robot lead programmer Tom Betts, hasn’t quite decided. But perhaps I just need to get used to Atticus. I’ve barely played this game for half-an-hour and there are many more layers to peel away.
</p>
<p>
Read more and find the demo on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2836860/The_Horror_at_Highrook">Steam</a>. For something similar and yet totally different, try <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1569580/Blue_Prince/">the demo for Blue Prince</a>.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals to Host $400,000 Global Invitational Tournament]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-to-host-400000-global-invitational-tournament/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-to-host-400-000-global-invitational-tournament.1108926/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-to-host-400000-global-invitational-tournament/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>NetEase has <a href="https://x.com/MarvelRivals/status/1890096608580366518" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> the biggest and most lucrative Marvel Rivals tournament series to date. The Marvel Rivals Invitational will see teams across the world compete in one of four regional tournaments, with $400,000 on the line across the whole series.</p>



<p>Could this be the first major step toward a serious Marvel Rivals esports scene?</p>



<h2 id="h-marvel-rivals-invitational-announced">Marvel Rivals Invitational Announced</h2>



<p>The Marvel Rivals Invitational will consist of four separate tournaments, one for each major region. Each region’s tournament will feature its own $100,000 prize pool, meaning a total of $400,000 will be given out across the five week span. The Marvel Rivals Invitational will begin with the Oceanic tournament, then Asia, then EMEA, and finally North America.</p>



<p>The matches will be broadcast on both the official Marvel Rivals <a href="http://twitch.tv/marvelrivals" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Twitch channel</a> and <a href="https://youtube.com/@MarvelRivals" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">YouTube channel</a>. Here are the dates for each region:</p>



<ul>
<li>Oceania – February 15-16</li>



<li>Asia – February 22-23</li>



<li>EMEA – February 28-March 2, March 7-9</li>



<li>North America – March 14-16, March 21-23</li>
</ul>



<figure><figcaption>Full schedule for Marvel Rivals Invitational</figcaption></figure>



<p>NetEase and Marvel Rivals have been hesitant to jump head first into a dedicated esports scene. Many point to the rushed creation of the Overwatch League as something that did more harm than good, as OWL was announced the same year that Overwatch released. Back in January 2025, Marvel Rivals game director Guangyun Chen <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-director-reveals-plans-for-esports/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said that he wanted to cater to both casual and competitive players</a>. As of now, Marvel Rivals is not rushing to put together a massive esports league.</p>



<p>Still, there’s been no shortage of interest in a potential esports scene. Streaming star Shroud mentioned <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shroud-marvel-rivals-esports-organisation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">potentially starting an organization</a> just to play Marvel Rivals back in January. He then <a href="https://x.com/JakeSucky/status/1888686812044103965" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed</a> that he’s building an organization after reaching a $150,000 donation goal during a charity stream a month later. He also <a href="https://x.com/RivalsAssembled/status/1887877669955514717" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">met</a> with Sentinels CEO Rob Moore, who said he would be open to Shroud running a Marvel Rivals team under the Sentinels brand.</p>



<p>Is a tournament of this size going to ignite the Marvel Rivals esports scene ?Let us know in the comments or on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read&nbsp;about Marvel Rivals <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-cancels-mid-season-rank-reset/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">canceling the mid-season rank resets</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Preorders In Line With Odyssey]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-preorders-in-line-with-odyssey/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-preorders-in-line-with-odyssey.1108923/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-preorders-in-line-with-odyssey/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Ubisoft is happy with the pre-launch build for Assassin’s Creed Shadows. Despite multiple delays that pushed the game out of 2024 to March 20, 2025, Ubisoft’s CEO Yves Guillemot says that the interest in the game has seen strong preorders overall.</p>



<p>During Ubisoft’s Q3 2025 <a href="https://staticctf.ubisoft.com/8aefmxkxpxwl/2GbdOQTUuRZV3mqGXgTfeK/520f2262c4f60b4bc13f0f3a59ec37e7/Ubisoft_FY25_Q3_PR_English_vFinal.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">earnings call on Thursday</a>, Guillemot said that preorders for Assassin’s Creed Shadows are “tracking solidly, in line with those of Assassin’s Creed Odyssey, the second most successful entry of the franchise”.</p>



<p>Aside from the pre-orders, Ubisoft says that the previews of the game have been strong from multiple angles.</p>



<p>“Early previews have been positive, praising its narrative and immersive experience, with both characters playing critical roles in the game’s storyline, as well as the quality and complementarity of the gameplay provided by the dual protagonist approach,” Guillemot said.</p>



<p>He continued: “I want to commend the incredible talent and dedication of the entire Assassin’s Creed’s team, who is working tirelessly to ensure that Shadows delivers on the promise of what is the franchise’s most ambitious entry yet.”</p>



<p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows was originally scheduled for release on November 15, 2024. The game <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-to-february-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was then delayed</a> to February 14,  2025 for more polish and updates. In January, it was <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-march/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">delayed again</a> to March 20.</p>



<p>What do you think of Assassin’s Creed Shadows preorders being as strong as they are? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read exclusive details on the recent&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/details-funko-fusion-developer-1010-games-recent-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">layoffs at Funko Fusion developer 10:10 Games</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sunless Sea studio's Fallen London tabletop RPG smashes crowdfunding goal, with £500K raised in two days]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sunless-sea-studios-falling-london-tabletop-rpg-smashes-crowdfunding-goal-with-500k-raised-in-two-days</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sunless-sea-studios-fallen-london-tabletop-rpg-smashes-crowdfunding-goal-with-%C2%A3500k-raised-in-two-days.1108920/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/sunless-sea-studios-falling-london-tabletop-rpg-smashes-crowdfunding-goal-with-500k-raised-in-two-days<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>And there's still 28 days left.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallen-london-ttrpg.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Failbetter Games/Eurogamer</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Just days into its Kickstarter campaign, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/sunless-sea">Sunless Sea</a> developer Failbetter's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallen-london">Fallen London</a> tabletop RPG adaptation has smashed its crowdfunding goal, raising over half a million pounds.
</p>
<p>
Fallen London, if you're unfamiliar, is a <a href="https://www.fallenlondon.com/login">free-to-play browser-based narrative adventure</a> that's been steadily expanding since its launch in 2009. At its heart is an alternate-universe version of Victorian London that was stolen by bats and carried to a vast underground cavern system deep beneath the Earth's surface - the centre of a darkly whimsical universe Failbetter has revisited in three standalone games: Sunless Sea, Sunless Sky, and Mask of Rose.
</p>
<p>
All three of those titles started life as Kickstarter campaigns, but for its latest crowdfunding endeavour, Failbetter is doing something a little bit different. Working in conjunction with Magpie Games, it's stepping away from the digital realm to crowdfund an officially licensed tabletop roleplaying game based on the Fallen London universe.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fallen London: The Roleplaying Game" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kwamNFDfWGs?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fallen London: The Roleplaying Game</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kwamNFDfWGs?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kwamNFDfWGs?autoplay=1" title="Fallen London: The Roleplaying Game">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>A brief overview of the Fallen London roleplaying game.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kwamNFDfWGs" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Being a Kickstarter, there are a variety of stretch goals and reward tiers, but the meat of the campaign consists of the Fallen London roleplaying game Core Book and the Guide to London supplement. Between them both, players can find all the rules, setting details, plot hooks, character types, conflicts, concerns, and dynamic systems - plus a sample 'venture' - they'll need as they start and chart their journey through the cavernous Neath.
</p>
<p>
There's obviously a lot more nuance to the Fallen London tabletop RPG than a single paragraph can do justice to, and there's plenty more detail (alongside a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DiDpWURGrG8">video play-through</a>) on its <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/magpiegames/fallen-london-the-roleplaying-game?ref=thanks-tweet">crowdfunding page</a>. And what's there is clearly resonating with potential backers; the campaign has already smashed its $50K funding target - raising more than $626K, or a little over half a million pounds - at the time of writing. And that's with 28 days still to go.
</p>
<p>
As to what Failbetter might be planning next in the world of video games following <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mask-of-the-rose-review-kissing-optional-but-recommended-and-tricky">2023's darkly romantic visual novel Mask of the Rose</a>, the developer hasn't yet said. But the studio, which recently celebrated its 15th birthday, continues to expand Fallen London and it's <a href="https://failbettergames.com/news/fallen-london-firmament-recap-update-and-the-state-of-the-game-2025">also confirmed an unannounced game is in the works</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Know What Ruled? Lies of P]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/lies-of-p-is-good-overture-annoucement</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-know-what-ruled-lies-of-p.1108902/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/lies-of-p-is-good-overture-annoucement<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure><figcaption><span><p>Welcome to the twisted world of Pinocchio. Credit: NEOWIZ Games</p>
</span></figcaption></figure></div><div><p>Several fantastic games came out in the time between me getting shot out of a cannon at Kotaku and the foundation of Aftermath that I have tremendously strong feelings about. One of those is <em>Lies of P</em>, a game I think is one of the few <a href="https://aftermath.site/death-howl-soulslike-dark-souls-deckbuilder" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Souls-adjacent</a> games to actually equal FromSoft. Now that I have a blog where I can write whatever the hell I want, I would like to introduce a segment called “You Know What Ruled?” starting with <em>Lies of P, </em>which<em> </em>ruled and I’m excited to play the DLC.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Lies of P: Overture - Announcement Trailer | PS5 &amp; PS4 Games" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b-pBtuYX6zc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><figcaption>The trailer for the newly announced Lies of P: Overture</figcaption></figure></div><p>During Wednesday’s Sony State of Play, Round8 and Neowiz unveiled the trailer for <em>Lies of P: Overture, </em>the new DLC for the game. <em>Overture </em>serves not only as a prequel, but also a director’s cut of the game, <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/02/12/lies-of-p-overture-launches-summer-2025-on-ps5-ps4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to director Jiwon Choi</a>. This DLC, as well as the planned sequel, have been in the works for a while now, and while both could potentially whiff it, I have confidence because <em>Lies of P </em>was so thoroughly my shit that it made me shout.&nbsp;</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Lies of P - Director's Letter" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RbCnjeUilhU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><figcaption>The Director's Letter talked about the plan for Lies of P after its release.</figcaption></figure></div><p><em>Lies of P </em>had much going against it: It can seem both hubristic and tiresome for a relatively green studio to say its making a Soulslike. The surface level absurdity of the pitch, <em>Pinocchio Bloodborne</em> with minor <em>Sekiro </em>characteristics, coupled with the fact that the game takes a while to settle into a rhythm, made it a hard sell. I was underwhelmed when I first played the demo. But <em>Lies of P</em>, like <a href="https://aftermath.site/kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess-feels-like-it-shouldnt-exist" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Kunitsu-Gami</em></a>, massively benefited from the slack afforded to it by being on Game Pass. Once you give the game a few hours, the systems start to lock in place and the game starts firing on all cylinders.&nbsp;</p><p>If <em>Lies of P </em>had simply aped <em>Bloodborne </em>competently that would have been satisfying. <em>Bloodborne </em>is still peerless in FromSoft’s catalogue, its excellence made bittersweet by being trapped in the strange limbo of Sony’s involvement. But <em>Lies of P </em>blossoms into more than a simple imitator around the tail end of its second chapter. The game features a Weapon Assembly system, where handles and blades can be swapped interchangeably and weapons can be customized. Using different combinations impacts not only the moveset and efficacy, but the Fable Arts, special moves similar to Ashes of War in <em>Elden Ring</em>. <em>Lies of P</em> also features different elemental damage types that change in efficacy depending on the type of enemy being faced (puppets, carcasses, or alchemists). On top of this, P’s mechanical Legion Arm opens up a lot of possibilities in a way that’s not dissimilar to <em>Sekiro’s </em>Shinobi Prosthetic.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Krat develops into its own place over time. Credit: NEOWIZ Games</span></figcaption></figure><p>It should go without saying that <em>Lies of P </em>is difficult, and the game quickly developed a reputation for being harder than many of FromSoft’s recent offerings. You could debate this until you are blue in the face, and since its release the game has undergone multiple difficulty tweaks. What actually matters is that the game feels fantastic when it’s grinding you into dust – it’s a blissful, relentless pressure that keeps you coming back for more. It says much about the planning and success of <em>Lies of P </em>that people put it up to the level of scrutiny <em>Souls </em>games normally face. When nerds start getting into annoyingly granular arguments about boss nerfs and weapon balance, there’s a nonzero chance you have succeeded.&nbsp;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Krat develops into its own place over time. Credit: NEOWIZ Games</span></figcaption></figure><p>But what floored me is that <em>Lies of P</em> actually makes such a goofy premise work. Over the course of the game, Krat becomes a totally realized world. P’s relationship to Geppetto actually gains heft as the lore of the universe develops. Appropriately, the game ceases being simply an imitation and becomes real. This culminates in a “true” ending that is well realized, one with actual meat on it in ways that many of FromSoft’s endings lack (FromSoftware is not allowed to do another ending where a bunch of guys bow or someone sits on a throne.).</p><p><em>Lies of P</em> also features an absurd and fantastic post-credit surprise. Normally I hate teasers like that because the Marvel cinematic universe has so thoroughly abused the form in the last 17 years. What’s more, if you had spoiled the surprise for me at the beginning I would have told you that it was corny. But <em>Lies of P </em>ended on such a strong note for me that when I saw what it was hinting at, I started hooting and hollering. Oh you guys are doing <em>that</em>? <em>That’s </em>where you’re going with this? Hell yes, I’m sold, I’m locked in, let’s fucking gooooooo.&nbsp;<br>God damn, <em>Lies of P</em> rules, and writing this made me want to play it all over again.</p><figure><figcaption>I wish to return. Credit: NEOWIZ Games</figcaption></figure></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/kennedy-center-nea-trans"><h3>They Can’t Stop Trans Art</h3></a><p>The Trump administration's attacks on arts institutions are bad, but they aren't the end</p></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Test Continues Today with Extended Hours]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-test-continues-today-with-extended-hours/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-test-continues-today-with-extended-hours.1108881/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-open-beta-test-continues-today-with-extended-hours/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Due to the PlayStation Network outage, Capcom has made the decision to extend the Open Beta Test by a full 24 hours across all platforms. The PlayStation Network outage occurred during the first weekend of the Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Test. Specifically, it happened on February 8, and as a result, millions of gamers were left without a way to play their games. This caused players to be locked out of all online services, even their single-player games, if they happened to own them digitally. While players who had them on the disc would be able to play, it would only be the case if the data of the game was already on the PlayStation and did not need to be installed.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, Sony didn't really give much of a <a href="https://x.com/AskPlayStation/status/1888454556125708758" target="_blank" rel="noopener">full reason</a> as to why the network was down for so long, but blamed the outage on an "operational issue." Luckily, it sounds as if it was just an internal error rather than the network being hacked from the outside and causing major data breaches across the board.</p>
<p>As a result of the network outage, the Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Test 2 will resume today at 7 PM PST / 10 PM ET / 3 AM GMT and will continue until February 17 at 6:59 PM PST / 9:59 PM ET / 2:59 AM GMT.</p>
<p>As the Open Beta Test takes place, players will be able to unlock the participation bonus that will become available in the full version of the game, which is set to release on February 28 on PlayStation 5, PC, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
<p>If you're not sure whether this game will run on your PC, Capcom has released a Benchmark for you to utilize, as well as the <a href="https://wccftech.com/monster-hunter-wilds-gets-free-benchmark-and-updated-pc-requirements/">full specification requirements</a>.</p>
<p>Like the original beta, Open Beta Test 2 will include a character creator, where the data can then be transferred into the full game. It will also include a story mission and free-roaming hunts with cross-platform multiplayer. Compared to the first Beta Test, this one comes with additional content, such as fighting the Gypceros and the flagship monster of the game, Arkveld.</p>
<p>Alongside those new features, the Training Area and online features such as Private Lobbies and Online Single Player mode are also included in this upcoming Beta Test.</p>
<p>Although it's been <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/tWqiYSA-t8E" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced by the Monster Hunter developers</a>, the performance and balance adjustments will not be available in this beta build; instead, the developers are instead focused on implementing these changes in the full release of the game.</p>
<p>Will you be participating in the Monster Hunter Wilds Open Beta Test 2? Let us know in the comments.</p>
<p>Monster Hunter Wilds will be released on February 28 on PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maximum Football Updates Add Invite Multiplayer And Multiple New Features]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/maximum-football-updates-add-invite-multiplayer-and-multiple-new-features/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/maximum-football-updates-add-invite-multiplayer-and-multiple-new-features.1108872/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/maximum-football-updates-add-invite-multiplayer-and-multiple-new-features/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Maximum Football is continuing forward with its promise to add new updates and features regularly while in early access. The game has recently seen new additions including invite multiplayer, native 4K support, screen passes, and more.</p>



<p>Released in early access in November on Steam, Maximum Football also launched in on Xbox in December as part of the Xbox Game Preview program. The game will be releasing on PlayStation 5 at a later date.</p>



<p>You can check out all of the latest Maximum Football updates for yourself below. The developers at Maximum Entertainment are also <a href="https://x.com/MaxFootballGame/status/1874520235727888740" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">working on the game’s</a> Franchise Mode, cross-play, weather system, and more for 2025.</p>







<h3>Overall Gameplay Improvements</h3>



<ul>
<li>Added Invite Multiplayer</li>



<li>Fixed certain achievements not tracking progress</li>



<li>Various crash fixes</li>



<li>New animations and polish: tackling, blocking, post-play movements, locomotion, and jump catches</li>



<li>Audio fixes and improvements for animations and commentary</li>



<li>Adjustments for replay mode</li>



<li>General stability improvements</li>



<li>Updated referee AI</li>



<li>Updated bull rush animation loop</li>



<li>Disabled over-the-shoulder and overhead catch animations</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where receivers did not play an animation after scoring a touchdown</li>
</ul>



<h3>Defensive Gameplay</h3>



<ul>
<li>Adjusted defensive plays to give defenders wider zones to cover more of the field sideline to sideline</li>



<li>Fixed an issue preventing defensive linemen from disengaging from blocks</li>



<li>Increased defenders’ odds of pushing blockers backward during engagements</li>



<li>Fixed safety pre-snap alignment in man coverage</li>



<li>Multiple fixes for defensive pre-snap alignment</li>



<li>Restructured pre-snap AI defensive alignment</li>



<li>Adjusted defenders in man coverage to play running backs out of the backfield more aggressively</li>



<li>Reduced the range and spread of the dive tackle AI</li>



<li>Made adjustments to red zone defenses</li>



<li>Fixed zone coverage defenders sometimes facing the wrong way briefly</li>



<li>Fixed a rare issue where defenders spawned inside one another pre-snap</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where field goal block defenders would stand still</li>



<li>Improved AI logic for assessing scrambling quarterback threat levels</li>
</ul>



<h3>Offensive Gameplay</h3>



<ul>
<li>Added new screen plays to expand play-calling options</li>



<li>Reduced drop-steps on play-action passes</li>



<li>Fixed an exploit that caused drop-back animations to cancel when attempting to pass to an unassigned receiver</li>



<li>Fixed snapping while strafing for offensive linemen</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where offensive linemen moved in the wrong direction</li>



<li>Improved logic for non-linemen blocking threats on run plays</li>



<li>Fixed a visual glitch when playing get-up and injury animations after downing a player</li>
</ul>



<h3>Special Teams Play</h3>



<ul>
<li>New kick meter for improved accuracy and control</li>



<li>Created a shield punt play to reduce blocked punts</li>



<li>Fixed an exploit where users could line up behind another rusher to easily block punts</li>



<li>Reduced the frequency of blocked punts</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where punting team blockers faced the wrong direction on returns</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that caused some punts to be ruled a touchback after going out of bounds</li>



<li>Made adjustments to onside kick formations</li>



<li>Added additional kick return formations to limit scum kicks online</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where kick returners would not go for the ball on the ground on onside kicks</li>



<li>Adjusted kick returners to aim for a catch at chest level rather than the landing area on kicks</li>



<li>Players can now audible on kick-off returns</li>



<li>Fixed punt return gunner coverage</li>
</ul>



<h3>Dynasty Mode Improvements</h3>



<ul>
<li>Spectate any game in Dynasty Mode</li>



<li>Simulate individual games in Dynasty Mode</li>



<li>Added a settings tab in the main menu to update the game clock and accelerated play clock preferences</li>



<li>Fixed overtime scores in simulated games</li>



<li>Adjusted Dynasty save deletion process</li>



<li>Adjusted stadium upgrade text</li>



<li>Fixed injury retrieval from gameplay to Dynasty</li>



<li>Match history and rating now used in team ranking calculations</li>



<li>Fixed conference name overflow issues</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where games were not showing up on match selection</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-mpl-multiplayer-fixes-amp-updates">MPL (Multiplayer) Fixes &amp; Updates</h3>



<ul>
<li>Updated backend system to fix user card creation issues</li>



<li>Fixed an issue impacting users’ ability to fair catch in multiplayer matches</li>



<li>Fixed overtime scores in match history</li>



<li>Made additional adjustments to the MPL system</li>



<li>Fixed match history visualization issues</li>
</ul>



<h3>UI &amp; Visual Fixes</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed some Season Pass items not having the correct names</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that prevented team uniform changes from reflecting until the game was restarted</li>



<li>Flip Play option added to all play selection screens</li>



<li>Added safeguards to prevent users from using the same jersey number for every player</li>



<li>Changing name and number font types now updates immediately on players</li>



<li>Added new red-dot notifications for Store/Card Packs, Challenges, and Season Pass</li>
</ul>



<p>Are you going to check out Maximum Football with these new changes and updates? Let us know down below, and join more discussions in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mecha-break-announces-open-beta-and-new-game-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mecha Break’s new game mode</a> along with the start date of its next open beta. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Insists Assassin's Creed Shadows Preorders are 'Tracking Solidly,' In Line With Odyssey]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-insists-assassins-creed-shadows-preorders-are-tracking-solidly-in-line-with-odyssey</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-insists-assassins-creed-shadows-preorders-are-tracking-solidly-in-line-with-odyssey.1108869/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-insists-assassins-creed-shadows-preorders-are-tracking-solidly-in-line-with-odyssey<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Ubisoft has insisted that its upcoming open world adventure Assassin's Creed Shadows has a strong number of preorders despite its troubled development and promotional period.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The struggling publisher said in its latest financial report that "preorders for the game are tracking solidly, in line with those of Assassin's Creed Odyssey, the second most successful entry of the franchise."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot maintained this confidence, saying the company is currently "fully focused on the upcoming launch of Assassin’s Creed Shadows on March 20.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Early previews have been positive, praising its narrative and immersive experience, with both characters playing critical roles in the game’s storyline, as well as the quality and complementarity of the gameplay provided by <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-players-wont-be-missing-out-if-they-largely-ignore-one-protagonist">the dual protagonist approach</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I want to commend the incredible talent and dedication of the entire Assassin’s Creed’s team, who is working tirelessly to ensure that Shadows delivers on the promise of what is the franchise’s most ambitious entry yet."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Assassin's Creed Shadows was originally planned for November before Ubisoft bumped it back to February 14. But while that means fans should have been playing the game tomorrow, another delay saw it pushed again to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-again-this-time-by-another-month">the current release date of March 20</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A lot rests on the shoulders of Assassin's Creed Shadows as not only the long-awaited Japan-set entry and the first full Assassin's Creed since 2020, but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-shares-take-a-hit-as-analysts-predict-lower-than-expected-star-wars-outlaws-sales">a struggling Ubisoft needs it to perform well</a> following recent flops and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-investors-grill-ceo-cfo-on-potential-tencent-sale-delays-and-financial-woes">investor frustration</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It's not enjoyed a particularly positive promotional period so far, however, with the development team having to apologize on separate occasions for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-team-issues-apology-to-japanese-fans-for-marketing-that-has-caused-concern">inaccuracies in Assassin's Creed Shadows' depictions of Japan</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-apologizes-to-japanese-historical-re-enactment-group-for-using-its-flag-in-assassins-creed-shadows-art-without-permission">using a historical recreation group's flag without permission</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Yet another controversy came as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-figure-removed-from-sale-over-insensitive-design">collectible figure maker PureArts removed an Assassin's Creed Shadows statue from sale</a> over its "insensitive" design, and combined with the two delays, fans are growing increasingly impatient as a result.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TMNT Collab Confirmed For Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 And Warzone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tmnt-collab-confirmed-for-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-warzone/1100-6529494/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tmnt-collab-confirmed-for-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-warzone.1108863/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tmnt-collab-confirmed-for-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-and-warzone/1100-6529494/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529494">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Following <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-tmnt-crossover-could-be-coming/1100-6529089/">recent leaks</a>, Activision has officially confirmed Call of Duty's next big IP collaboration is with the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles. Season 2 of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6/" data-ref-id="5000-630093">Black Ops 6</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone/" data-ref-id="5000-572198">Warzone</a> is themed around ninjas, so there's no better time to bring in the heroes in a half-shell.</p><p dir="ltr">Activision made the TMNT crossover announcement with a <a href="https://x.com/CallofDuty/status/1890098739915768252" rel="nofollow ">brief teaser clip</a> for Call of Duty, which shows Leonardo, Donatello, Raphael, and Michelangelo peeking out from a sewer manhole. This likely means there will be operator skins for all four turtles. Call of Duty previously had a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-tmnts-shredder-with-a-gun-in-call-of-duty-modern-warfare-2-and-warzone-2/1100-6512543/">TMNT collab for 2022's Modern Warfare 2</a>, but the only character featured was Shredder.</p><p dir="ltr">The video doesn't give a specific date for the TMNT collaboration, teasing only that the turtles will be "coming soon." However, the Season 2 Reloaded update is set to include a set of melee weapons, which is rumored to be a pair of sais, nunchucks, a bo staff, and a skateboard. Leonardo's katanas were previously teased in the promotional art for the launch of Season 2. This means the turtles will likely appear with the midseason "Reloaded" update or sometime shortly after.</p><p dir="ltr">Leakers suggested the crossover will include a limited-time event and a special TMNT-themed game mode, but those details haven't been confirmed by Activision. The turtles themselves will likely be included as operator shop bundles.</p><p dir="ltr">A Terminator crossover event is also currently live in Black Ops 6 and Warzone until February 20. For more on the upcoming midseason update, make sure to check out everything announced for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-2-reloaded-start-date-and-details/1100-6529404/">Black Ops 6 and Warzone in Season 2 Reloaded</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>