<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 19:18:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Years Later, Alien: Isolation Still Benefits From One Vital Design Decision]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/10-years-later-alien-isolation-still-benefits-from-one-vital-design-decision/1100-6528385/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/10-years-later-alien-isolation-still-benefits-from-one-vital-design-decision.1058298/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/10-years-later-alien-isolation-still-benefits-from-one-vital-design-decision/1100-6528385/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528385">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Even a decade after its release, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/alien-isolation/" data-ref-id="5000-232868">Alien: Isolation</a> remains a standout experience.</p><p dir="ltr">It's a monumental example of adaptation in video games, thanks to the fact that developer Creative Assembly was packed with fans of Ridley Scott's 1979 film, Alien, and an incredibly tight, detailed focus on the fidelity of the movie's setting. It also set a bar in horror game design, with the alien operating on a set of reactive artificial intelligence rules that made it terrifyingly unpredictable and unstoppably lethal.</p><p dir="ltr">It also stands apart from other games based on the Alien franchise, which tend to ignore Scott's original film in favor of iterations on Aliens, James Cameron's sequel, which moves away from straight horror to feature more action--and a bunch of well-outfitted, smack-talking Marines. Creative Assembly instead pitched an <em>Alien</em> game, not an <em>Aliens</em> game, one that would focus on making the creature feel like an unstoppable, unknowable predator instead of a horde of animals players would mow down with pulse rifles.</p><p dir="ltr">"The goal was to transport you back to that time and place, that 1970s view of the future, the kind of lo-fi sci-fi aesthetic of that first movie, allowing you to encounter and try and survive against that original alien--where just one alien could be terrifying, which is really different in terms of video games," director Al Hope told me in a recent interview. "The fact that you can play it today and get that experience, get that feeling--as part of the team that made it, that's so rewarding."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2699099-alienisolationdlc_001.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2699099" data-ratio="0.54895833333333" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2699099-alienisolationdlc_001.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2699099"></a><figcaption>Alien: Isolation focused on capturing the horror intrinsic in the original 1979 film, specifically to make the alien terrifying again.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2699099-alienisolationdlc_001.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Alien: Isolation recently celebrated its 10-year anniversary, and rather than fade into obscurity as time marched on and new game releases took attention away, it instead seems to have grown in popularity over the years since its release. Streamers and content creators seem to keep finding the game, and new ports have been released on Nintendo Switch, iOS, and Android. The Switch version also got a fairly expansive physical collector's edition release from Limited Run Games last year--fully nine years after Alien: Isolation first came out.</p><p dir="ltr">It seems that there's not just a fanbase for Alien: Isolation, but a growing demand for it. On the anniversary, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/alien-isolation-2-is-in-early-development-with-original-director-returning/1100-6526951/">Creative Assembly announced it has started work on an Alien: Isolation sequel</a>, with Hope returning as its director.</p><p dir="ltr">"What's really incredible is that it seems to have grown and snowballed over time, over the last decade, as more people have found it and people talk about it," Hope said. "It's still in the conversation around the scariest games and best Alien game, or whatever. One of the really rewarding things is people are still finding it for the first time today, and having a really fantastic experience. And, you know, considering it's a relatively old game now, or could be considered a relatively old game. And, yeah, I think that's just a testament to the fantastic work that the team did, because it was a labor of love. But, yeah, it's just immensely rewarding that people are still playing and talking about it today."</p><p dir="ltr">What makes Alien: Isolation so frightening is how much the game reacts to the player's actions, beginning with the impressive AI running its alien. The creature is designed to seek players out using its senses, and when it can't find you, to search the station in a fairly systematic way. Another AI, an underlying director, will sometimes direct the alien in your direction if you've gone too long without an encounter, or away from you if the tension has been high for a long time.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563858-01_1402071153.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2563858" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563858-01_1402071153.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2563858"></a><figcaption>Artificial intelligence systems at work in Alien: Isolation provide a sense that the creature is always hunting you, and being careful and aware are the only things that can save your life.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563858-01_1402071153.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Other systems also work dynamically to increase the tension and fear when things get intense. Sound design is a huge part of what makes Alien: Isolation so effective, and it's full of reactive elements to ratchet up the fear--including ramping up the music as the situation with the alien gets more and more harrowing.</p><p dir="ltr">"It was interesting for us because we had this idea that the creature wasn't going to be choreographed and scripted, which is what typically occurs in this kind of game," Hope explained. "And I seem to remember this kind of penny drop moment where we realized, well, we can't just ask the composers to create a wav file that we'll just hit play on and it will play out, because it will completely disconnect with what's happening. Because the creature and the drama and the action is completely dynamic and unpredictable, we're gonna have to do something completely different, and that felt like, wow, okay, this has a really big impact on everything, and especially the music, because the music needs to be able to support tension, anticipation, action, and we don't know what's going to happen."</p><blockquote data-size="medium" data-align="right"><p dir="ltr">We kept getting, 'We need more deaths. Everyone's dying all the time. We need more deaths.' Like 90 different death cues."</p></blockquote><p dir="ltr">"So much is going on under the hood with the music, to get on with the mixing of all the ambient sounds and local sounds," he continued. "We're doing some really fun and pretty clever things, where, when the alien is getting close, we might push the music so we have this emotional content that's kind of being more present than what the player's receiving. But, say there's an alarm going on in the room, we'll actually duck that down, so it's almost like we're replicating the player's focus on the alien so everything else doesn't matter. It's doing really quite brilliant, interesting things to really enhance the experience. And so what you're receiving is this constant, ever-fluctuating soundscape that's being remixed in real time."</p><p dir="ltr">In keeping with the heightened demand for Alien: Isolation, the 10th anniversary also saw another long-awaited release: the game's soundtrack. It's now available on streaming services, and a vinyl and cassette edition are available for preorder from <a href="https://www.iam8bit.com/products/alien-isolation-vinyl-soundtrack" rel="nofollow ">iam8bit</a>.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4413977-alienisolationsoundtrack.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4413977" data-ratio="1" data-width="1000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4413977-alienisolationsoundtrack.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4413977"></a><figcaption>True to the game's analog tech nature, the iam8bit release of Alien: Isolation's soundtrack is available on vinyl or on cassette tape.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4413977-alienisolationsoundtrack.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Creating music that could work dynamically with those systems was a challenge unto itself, as composers Joe Henson and Alexis Smith, who together make up English duo The Flight, told me. Alien: Isolation wasn't the duo's first game--they'd previously worked on Assassin's Creed IV: Black Flag and LittleBigPlanet. But on previous games, the pair was learning how music in games worked. Isolation was the first big game where they were able to do exactly what they wanted, Henson said, and they were drawn to its low-fi, '70s-inspired aesthetic.</p><p dir="ltr">While Alien: Isolation's approach to music <em>seemed</em> like a complex problem to solve at the time, the pair said, it didn't actually end up being that difficult to write music that could be used dynamically. It mostly required creating different layers of tracks for each level: an exploration layer for when the player wasn't under threat, a more intense layer for when the alien was present but not hunting you, and a "you're about to die" layer, Henson said.</p><p dir="ltr">"What I remember mostly is making this third layer, which was the 'you're about to die' layer, and it's all very well, making a five-minute ambient exploration piece," he explained. "In order for it to be able to go into this 'you're about to die' at any point, we had to make a five-minute 'you're about to die' layer. We were young and green and really wanting to put our mark on the first game we were going to be proud of, so we did these completely bespoke five minutes. We didn't copy bits. We did ups and downs and going with what was happening in the music. And it works really well. But they were exhausting [to write]."</p><p dir="ltr">"And loads of deaths," Smith chimed in, laughing. "We kept getting, 'We need more deaths. Everyone's dying all the time. We need more deaths.' Like 90 different death cues."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563863-06_1402071176.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2563863" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563863-06_1402071176.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2563863"></a><figcaption>Creative Assembly made sure the alien was a formidable opponent--you can never kill it, only drive it away, but your defenses become less effective the more you use them.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/536/5360430/2563863-06_1402071176.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">The music in Alien: Isolation is a big way in which the game links to the movie and works to convey its tone. Isolation's music uses portions of composer Jerry Goldsmith's score from the movie, but as The Flight have noted in the past, there's not actually that much music in Alien, period.</p><p dir="ltr">Isolation separates itself by using some elements of Goldsmith's original score, "threading that DNA" of Alien throughout the game, as Hope put it, while also adding its own sound with the use of other period-appropriate instruments, like synthesizers and electronic elements.</p><p dir="ltr">"That was an interesting discovery actually, while we're working on it, where, when we felt we were losing the Alien sound, we could just drop pepper in those--there are such strong sounds, not just motifs, just <em>sounds </em>from Alien from the score, that we could very easily kind of bring in and bring us back," Smith said.</p><blockquote data-size="medium" data-align="right"><p dir="ltr">We never thought about trying to compromise."</p></blockquote><p dir="ltr">"It's not like a theme song; it doesn't, like, repeat," Henson said, to which Smith added that the memorable musical elements of Alien are more like "little bits" and small musical phrases. Other elements of the score, like clicking sounds and different noises, as well as analog elements from the equipment and instruments used to create those sounds, ended up being very useful in keeping Isolation's soundscape feeling like Alien.</p><p dir="ltr">"We kind of saw them as almost like samples that we could throw in with other stuff," Henson continued. "And because we love that film so much, and we love that score and everything, that's the way we kind of treated it. Not with too much reverence that we wouldn't do anything to it or change anything, but we knew how to--you know, as long as the electronics we were adding, as long as the stuff we were adding was as crusty as the computers on the space station, then we thought it would work."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2589188-alienisolation2_1404833866.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2589188" data-ratio="0.56475" data-width="4000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2589188-alienisolation2_1404833866.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2589188"></a><figcaption>20th Century Fox gave Creative Assembly access to a huge amount of archival information from Alien, which the studio used to faithfully recreate the look and sound of the film.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2589188-alienisolation2_1404833866.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Getting that soundtrack released "has been an epic struggle," Hope said. A version has been ready to go for the last 10 years--Henson and Smith created a listening version akin to a film score back when Alien: Isolation was in production--but the complex web of stakeholders, copyright holders, and contracts held it back.</p><p dir="ltr">The situation around game soundtracks has changed during that period as well, Smith said. The business of selling game soundtracks has grown significantly, which increased the incentives to finally make Isolation's available.</p><p dir="ltr">For The Flight, the release is a big one. Of all the games they've worked on, Smith said, Alien: Isolation is the one the duo gets asked about most often.</p><p dir="ltr">"We've got a 1 million sales thing here [for Alien: Isolation]," Henson said. "I don't know what the sales have got to, but it doesn't touch some of the games we've done. But for fan adoration and respect, from our peers, as well, it's the one."</p><p dir="ltr">"The big thing about this game is, this kind of launched us," Smith said. "So it's a really special soundtrack for us. I still go back and play the game with people I know. I've just actually given it to a friend of mine whose kids have just got into Alien. They're like 18, 19, and one of my friend's kids is absolutely obsessed with it. And now the calls I've been getting are brilliant. The whole family are terrified."</p><p dir="ltr">"I finally played the game with my eldest son last year, but he couldn't. He wouldn't," Henson added. "He plays games all the time. He wouldn't play it on his own. He refused to play on his own when it was dark, because I turn out all the lights. He was shit scared. I feel like there are a lot of people like that."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2423662-0004.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2423662" data-ratio="0.56475" data-width="4000" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2423662-0004.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2423662"></a><figcaption>The intense attention to detail in visuals and sound makes Alien: Isolation one of the best film adaptations ever in video games.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1197/11970954/2423662-0004.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Replaying Alien: Isolation today, it absolutely holds up--the game is still as unpredictable and frightening as it was in 2014. But while it seems to continue to find its audience, there was a point at release that it seemed to struggle. Review aggregator Metacritic puts Alien: Isolation at an average score of 79, but there are scores that run the gamut, from several 10 out of 10s and 9 out of 10s, to a few that fall significantly lower. At the time, GameSpot gave Alien: Isolation a 6.5 out of 10. IGN reviewed it at a 6 out of 10. Reviewers lauded the game's fidelity in bringing players into its world, but some struggled with the difficulty and dealing with the alien itself.</p><p dir="ltr">I asked Hope if, looking back, there was anything he wished he and the team had done differently. His answer was short: "Ultimately, on balance, no."</p><blockquote data-size="medium" data-align="right"><p dir="ltr">I finally played the game with my eldest son last year, but he couldn't. He wouldn't. He was shit scared. I feel like there are a lot of people like that."</p></blockquote><p dir="ltr">"I think we knew, by its nature, we weren't trying to please everybody, you know?" he said. "Some players might think it's too hard. So do we then make it much easier? But then the people who want something more of a challenge will be disappointed. So that's not even really a discussion we had, because we wanted to create this Alien experience which presented a certain level of intrinsic challenge if we were going to take it the approach that we did. ...We never thought about trying to compromise."</p><p dir="ltr">The uncompromising vision was, ultimately, the correct call. It didn't happen all at once, but Alien: Isolation has left its mark both on the extended Alien universe and on the horror game landscape at large. Fede Alvarez, the director of the newest Alien movie, Alien: Romulus, has cited Isolation as an inspiration for the kind of horror he wanted to conjure up with the movie, and he even included the <a href="https://www.bing.com/ck/a?!&amp;&amp;p=27c6b2fb3ffa3b0bac2c0e649fbf149cb95e9e320d2907667ef3c3ad2b6448a6JmltdHM9MTczMzcwMjQwMA&amp;ptn=3&amp;ver=2&amp;hsh=4&amp;fclid=05d40eb0-41a0-65da-0c4b-1d16404e64d2&amp;psq=alien+romulus+alien+isolation+influence+gamespot.com&amp;u=a1aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ2FtZXNwb3QuY29tL2FydGljbGVzL2FsaWVuLXJvbXVsdXMtaW5jbHVkZXMtYW4tZWFzdGVyLWVnZy1mb3ItdGhpcy1wb3B1bGFyLXZpZGVvLWdhbWUvMTEwMC02NTI1NzUwLw&amp;ntb=1">iconic emergency phone save points from Isolation</a> as Easter eggs in the film. Amanda Ripley, Isolation's protagonist, has also become a recurring character in ongoing Alien comics and other media.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2677748-alienisolation_ai_launch_screen004_1411636900_result.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2677748" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2677748-alienisolation_ai_launch_screen004_1411636900_result.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-2677748"></a><figcaption>The story of Alien: Isolation has continued to influence other Alien media, with Amanda Ripley showing up in more stories in the wider canon.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1365/13658182/2677748-alienisolation_ai_launch_screen004_1411636900_result.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Other horror developers have started to take pages from Creative Assembly's approach to its creature, too, leading to some terrifying new experiences. Games such as <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/amnesia-the-bunker/" data-ref-id="5000-577134">Amnesia: The Bunker</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-outlast-trials/" data-ref-id="5000-505577">The Outlast Trials</a> feel like different riffs on the idea, putting players in the same kinds of tense situations with unpredictable, unkillable antagonists.</p><p dir="ltr">The Switch and mobile ports, the collector's edition, and the soundtrack release all suggest a demand for Alien: Isolation that's been building, not receding. That goes for the sequel, too--Hope wouldn't talk about it, but said a continual call of a sequel is something Creative Assembly has received every day since the game's release.</p><p dir="ltr">Hope said he and the Alien: Isolation team are "immensely proud" of what they achieved with the game.</p><p>"The team did what we set out to achieve, which was to create that authentic experience that felt like it had never been available before--and we were just <em>desperate </em>to experience that and play it ourselves," he said. "Ten years later, people are still picking up, for the first time, having an amazing experience and talking about wanting more. So, you know, we're really fortunate for the people out there. They've really connected with what we did."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Operations Manager Is Actually A Very Cool Video Game Job, But So Is Being A Hades Voice Actor]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/operations-manager-hades-supergiant</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/operations-manager-is-actually-a-very-cool-video-game-job-but-so-is-being-a-hades-voice-actor.1058280/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/operations-manager-hades-supergiant<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It's been a while since we ran a<a href="https://aftermath.site/category/what-i-do" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> 'What I Do' feature</a>, so let's rectify that!</p><p>This week's instalment is a <em>very </em>fun one. The main reason I started the column was to help shed a light on <em>every </em>corner of games development, from the most obvious job descriptions to the most obscure. And I don't think there are many more obscure than 'Operations Manager'.</p><p>Do you know what an Operations Manager does? Aside from...managing operations? Probably not! But it's an incredibly important job, often serving as the glue that can help hold an entire project--and studio--together. To help me (and you!) better understand the role and what it involves, I spoke with <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-ailshie-b85b785a/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Michael Ailshie</a> about operational health, keeping the lights on and...being a voice actor for <em>Hades</em>.</p><p><strong>Luke Plunkett</strong>: <em><strong>Hello, Michael! Tell us a little about yourself! </strong></em></p><p><strong>Michael Ailshie</strong>: Hello! I’m a California native who grew up about 15 minutes from Disneyland - where I also landed my first job as a canoe guide! After high school, I escaped the tropical Mediterranean climate of Orange County for the colder Mediterranean climate of the San Francisco Bay Area, where I studied English Literature at U.C. Berkeley. I graduated from college in the fortuitous year of 2008 (with an English degree, no less), and ended up managing front-of-house operations at Whole Foods in Oakland before responding to a Craigslist post from an anonymous San Francisco video game developer in 2011. That anonymous developer turned out to be Supergiant Games, with whom I would end up working for nearly a decade. I currently live in Hollywood with my wife, a voice actor and improviser who’s been involved with UCB, Second City, and the Groundlings (our pup, Chili Cheese, and our elderly cat, Craig). </p><figure><figcaption>Chili Cheese (L) &amp; Craig (R)</figcaption></figure><p><strong>LP</strong>: <em><strong>Can you tell us a little about your career in the video game industry? What's your current role, and what are some of your other recent positions?</strong></em></p><p><strong>MA</strong>: I’m currently the General Manager at Null Games, a new indie games publisher founded on the notion that developers don’t need to sign away their life’s work and their ability to earn a living to acquire funding and support for their games. We offer generous, equitable terms that enable our developers to focus on making great games. As with most of my jobs in the industry, I wear a lot of hats in this role: finance manager, HR administrator, legalese analyst, strategist, business developer, and guy who worries a lot. Prior to this role, I was the Senior Operations Manager at Night School Studio, Lead External Development Manager at Epic Games, and Operations Manager at Supergiant Games. Prior to the pandemic, I also moonlit as the head of merchandise operations for The Last Podcast on the Left.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>LP</strong>: <em><strong>That's...a lot of hats. So to stick to your most-worn hat, what does a job managing people and systems actually look like? Like, what does an average day or week entail? </strong></em></p><p><strong>MA</strong>: Operations is sort of an invisible discipline in games. If you’re doing the job of an Operations Manager well, your day-to-day is relatively incognito. Sometimes, though, things will go wrong and you’ll become acutely aware of what Operations teams are responsible for. If you’ve ever had an issue with onboarding, payroll, benefits, contracts, government agencies, payments, software licenses, hardware, or just having a functional, organized place to work and the means to do that work effectively, it’s likely something was rotten in the state of Operations. As my old colleague Greg Kasavin used to say, “Michael keeps the lights on around here.” While that might sound a bit reductive, I always wore that as a badge of honor because, frankly, it takes a lot of work to keep the lights on for a successful video game studio.&nbsp;</p><p>As the Operations Manager for Supergiant Games, there often wasn’t an “average” day-to-day since there was always some new and exciting challenge on the horizon, but on a given day, you could expect to find me vetting and negotiating contracts, maintaining the company’s financial records, filing taxes, literally paying the bills, building workstations, administering the studio’s benefits offerings, running the studio’s official merchandise store, planning the studio’s live event activations, and managing partnerships with any number of external mercenaries adjacent to those projects. During my time there, I built dozens of highly-themed event booths, packaged and shipped thousands of vinyl records, pestered people for countless receipts, scouted voice acting talent, and even navigated the treacherous waters of San Francisco commercial real estate.&nbsp;</p><p>While at Night School (which was acquired by Netflix), a fair amount of the Operations work mentioned above fell to dedicated teams like Finance, Facilities, HR, and so on. Some of the benefits of working with a large company! With much of that tactical work handled by better, faster, stronger colleagues, my day-to-day was more focused on the long-term operational health of the studio. When not moonlighting as a game producer, I wrote the studio’s employee handbook, built budget and team growth projections, managed new team member onboarding, organized and moderated the studio’s regular all-hands meetings, organized team-building events, constructed a centralized database that allowed our production and development teams to track all of our projects, negotiated contracts with external parties, and ran budgeting and forecasting exercises that tried to peer into the distant future.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>LP: </strong><em><strong>What is it about the job that you love? What keeps you coming into work every day, and doing what you do?&nbsp;</strong></em></p><p><strong>MA</strong>: It might sound strange, but I love it when my work removes worry and occupational stress from the equation for creative game developers. I hear so many horror stories from small development teams about losing creative development time to competing (and critically important) priorities like recruiting, negotiating, taxes, accounting, payroll, benefits, contracts, and generally “keeping the lights on,” and I love getting the chance to tank those problems. I firmly believe that when creative, passionate game developers are shielded from the anxieties that come with running and maintaining a business by someone with the aptitude to manage that work, they tend to make really good video games. Beyond that, I love figuring out how to solve problems that have no template to follow. For example, I had no playbook when it came to organizing an orchestra concert, but it was a blast to figure out and pull off.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>LP</strong>: <strong><em>Putting everything you love and work hard on aside, is there anything you </em>don't<em> enjoy about the job? And is there anything the wider games industry could do to make it better or easier for anyone doing a role like yours?</em></strong></p><p><strong>MA</strong>: I’ll never forget an interaction I had with a PAX attendee a few years into my tenure at Supergiant. When this person asked what I did at the studio, I let them know I was the Operations Manager and told them a bit about that role. Their response? “Ok. Can I talk to somebody relevant to the game?” Ouch! While I take it in stride and feel confident in my contributions today, I do think that many people both in and out of the industry consider folks who aren’t actively making video game assets as tangential at best and superfluous at worst, when that couldn’t be further from the truth. I’ll always appreciate Supergiant co-founder Amir Rao for insisting that everyone on the team, regardless of their title, was a “developer.” Just like any narrative designer, artist, or engineer, I got into this business to make incredible video games and am happy I get to do that in an unconventional way.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>LP</strong>: <strong><em>Before we go, I saw a </em>Hades<em> voice actor credit on your bio and it would be remiss if I didn't also ask how the hell that came to be and what it was like.</em></strong></p><p><strong>MA</strong>: I worked with Greg and Darren to track down some vocal talent for both <em>Pyre</em> and <em>Hades</em> via the SF Bay Area and LA improv communities (including my wife, Courtney Vineys, who voiced Ti’Zo in <em>Pyre</em>, and both Aphrodite and Dusa in <em>Hades</em>). I really enjoyed the casting process and loved finding uniquely talented actors that could bring their characters to life. Like a number of Supergiant’s core creative team members (including composer Darren Korb and voice actor Logan Cunningham), I was a high school theater kid and have never lost my passion for the DRAMATIC ARTS (aka playing make-em-ups and doing funny voices). At the tail end of casting for <em>Hades</em>, Greg and Darren actually asked me if I wanted to audition for the role of Orpheus. Of course, I said yes. Luckily, it wasn’t a stretch for me to pull off the disaffected, malaise-stricken vocal stylings of <em>Hades</em>’ resident bard, and I got the part. However, I left the singing work to Darren (trust me, you don’t want to hear my version of “Lament of Orpheus”).&nbsp;&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><a target="" rel="" tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/moxie-robot-ai-dying-llm-embodied"><h3>AI Company That Made Robots For Children Went Bust And Now The Robots Are Dying</h3></a><p>Embodied, maker of the AI robot called Moxie, is shuttering. With their closing, parents have to explain to their kids that Moxie is dead.</p></div><a target="" rel="" tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TankHead is out today!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/tankhead-is-out-today/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tankhead-is-out-today.1058265/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/tankhead-is-out-today/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>TankHead has a release date and that release date is… today! That’s right, the thoroughly unusual tank combat, survival and scavenging game TankHead is out now, exclusively on the Epic Games Store.</p>
<p><iframe title="TankHead - Launch Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fyZo9AC0bsM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>TankHead takes place in an apocalyptic setting where the war-torn world of ECA has become almost entirely uninhabitable. It’s because of this that Whitaker needs to tele-project his consciousness into a Needle drone that can survive the harsh environment. Also pilot a tank. That’s also quite important.</p>
<p>Heading into the wasteland, you’ll need a tank, but you’ll have to scavenge and cobble it together from parts. collecting new weapons, wheels, armour, spare parts, engines and more to improve your vehicle.</p>
<p>Because of the scrappily put together tanks you have, you’ll need a tactical approach to combatting the enemy tanks you face, always trying to present your strongest side – you have separate control of the tank’s direction and the turret – evade incoming fire as much as possible and chip away at their armour to reveal weak points to target.</p>

<p>The better and cleaner the vicoty, the more valuable the loot you can recover from the burning carcass of your fallen foes, grabbing replacement parts and upgrades for your tank.</p>
<p>It all culminates in battles against truly bizarre boss tanks, which in the trailer seems to include a very angry walking hotel or river boat?</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neon Abyss 2 brings more run ‘n gun roguelike action to Early Access in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/neon-abyss-2-brings-more-run-n-gun-roguelike-action-to-early-access-in-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/neon-abyss-2-brings-more-run-%E2%80%98n-gun-roguelike-action-to-early-access-in-2025.1058262/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/neon-abyss-2-brings-more-run-n-gun-roguelike-action-to-early-access-in-2025/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Veewo Games has revealed Neon Abyss 2, a sequel to their hit run ‘n’ gun roguelike from 2020. Neon Abyss 2 is heading to Steam Early Access in 2025.</p>
<p><iframe title="Neon Abyss 2 | Reveal Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A86PCFApasQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Neon Abyss 2 aims to take everything that was great about the original and amp it up to 11. There’s a wild range of weapons, from deadly plants to dragon-like creatures, all of which will shift your combat style in tandem with synergistic power-ups that you will combine and evolve through each run. You can also still hatch and train new companions, evolving them into allies that will fight alongside you.</p>
<p>And there’s now a Faith system that can be used to power up, recruit allies, or gamble away.</p>
<p>Oh, and of course there’s still minigames, with the trailer wrapping up with a little bit of basketball.</p>



<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Things I Love And 4 Things I Loathe About Indiana Jones And The Great Circle]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-bethesda-locks-doors-breath-1851718447</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/5-things-i-love-and-4-things-i-loathe-about-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle.1058250/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-bethesda-locks-doors-breath-1851718447<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="d4ec66d11f80dd94e286766189728cff" data-recommend-id="image://d4ec66d11f80dd94e286766189728cff" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indiana Jones in his trademark hat looks absolutely horrified, his mouth open, his eyes wide." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indiana Jones in his trademark hat looks absolutely horrified, his mouth open, his eyes wide." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d4ec66d11f80dd94e286766189728cff" data-recommend-id="image://d4ec66d11f80dd94e286766189728cff" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indiana Jones in his trademark hat looks absolutely horrified, his mouth open, his eyes wide." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>I’m having such a good time with <em>Indy</em> and his splendid circle. My hopes for the game were incredibly raised when I saw <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-bethesda-footage-1851628386&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-bethesda-footage-1851628386">the first in-game footage at Gamescom this year</a></span>, but even that didn’t properly convey that this was going to be a full-fledged immersive sim adventure. It’s tremendous fun, and a big part of that is the many title details that really shine. Oh, and then there’s the shit bits too.</p><p>Overall, I’m deeply impressed with <em>The Great Circle</em>, so this article isn’t some bizarre attempt to weigh bad against good. Given how much it’s occupying my time, how it’s making me happy in a way a video game hasn’t since <em>Prey</em>, in my experience the good enormously outweighs the bad. I have so many things to celebrate about it! However, as a committed curmudgeon, that doesn’t stop me from being <em>infuriated</em> every time I read the words “Opens from other side” or not being able to swim underwater for more than five seconds. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-review-is-it-good-pc-xbox-1851717174&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-review-is-it-good-pc-xbox-1851717174">Zack already did a brilliant job reviewing the game</a></span>, so again, this isn’t that. This is me picking out some teeny details and all-encompassing aspects that make me feel joy, then moaning like a bastard about equally small or ethereal annoyances. Let’s start with the loving (and the hating).</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="740017ab2e79031e645bb43536ca208a" data-recommend-id="image://740017ab2e79031e645bb43536ca208a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy rolling a safe's code wheels with his thumb." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indy rolling a safe's code wheels with his thumb." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="740017ab2e79031e645bb43536ca208a" data-recommend-id="image://740017ab2e79031e645bb43536ca208a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy rolling a safe's code wheels with his thumb." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>I know this seems like the most ridiculous way to start, something so incredibly minor in the scheme of the game, but I cannot get over how much I love this about <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em>. Every time I see a suitcase with a four-digit code lock, or a safe with five, I’m totally thrilled, not for the puzzle solving that’s to come (although that makes me happy), but for the sheer visceral pleasure of rolling the dials with Indy’s sausage fingers.</p><p>Those sorts of code locks are fun to fiddle with in real life, too, of course. There’s a reason those <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/fidget-cube/s?k=fidget+cube&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/fidget-cube/s?k=fidget+cube" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fidget cubes</a></span> have an approximation of them on one of the surfaces. But there’s something just so astonishingly perfect about how they’re rendered here, how perfectly they roll and click, and the incredibly tactile nature of scrolling them around with Indy’s thumb.</p><p>It’s a perfect piece of gaming interaction, and it deserves to be celebrated. I expect a special new category to be announced at The Game Awards.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="967ac797b05c2ccdda28b71bb2ceda8c" data-recommend-id="image://967ac797b05c2ccdda28b71bb2ceda8c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A locked door with the words &quot;Opens from Other Side.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A locked door with the words &quot;Opens from Other Side.&quot;" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="967ac797b05c2ccdda28b71bb2ceda8c" data-recommend-id="image://967ac797b05c2ccdda28b71bb2ceda8c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A locked door with the words &quot;Opens from Other Side.&quot;" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Locked doors have been a tedious issue in video games for as long as games have had doors. We all learned the unspoken video game language of nonfunctional doors that look painted into the scenery versus those with which we can interact, and as infuriating as it is that there’s never any narrative rationale for this bizarre design, we roll with it. But <em>The Great Circle</em> takes it a stage further, with clearly interactive doors that are locked on the other side, <em>everywhere</em>.</p><p>It’s obviously just gating the levels, all such doors marking routes you’ll use on your return, rather than having to trace back along the ledges and windows and drops and climbs and so on you are intended to traverse on your way there. But when where you want to be is <em>there</em>, on the other side of this flimsy door with glass panels, and you’re holding a sledgehammer that’s capable of knocking through walls, it’s pretty annoying stuff. The phrase “Opens from Other Side” appears so, so often in the game’s enormous first third, and I began to greet it with an exasperated growl.</p><p>It’s also weird that it capitalizes “Other Side,” rather suggesting these doors are opened from the afterlife.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="5c2ed28d0b1bd2adeb2d2e05f1eb800b" data-recommend-id="image://5c2ed28d0b1bd2adeb2d2e05f1eb800b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1041" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Admittedly this isn't a screenshot of an experiment working, but is instead a picture of Indy holding aloft a toilet brush as he approaches a Nazi guard. That counts, right?" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Admittedly this isn't a screenshot of an experiment working, but is instead a picture of Indy holding aloft a toilet brush as he approaches a Nazi guard. That counts, right?" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="5c2ed28d0b1bd2adeb2d2e05f1eb800b" data-recommend-id="image://5c2ed28d0b1bd2adeb2d2e05f1eb800b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1041" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Admittedly this isn't a screenshot of an experiment working, but is instead a picture of Indy holding aloft a toilet brush as he approaches a Nazi guard. That counts, right?" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Big-budget video games don’t often encourage experimentation. Every aspect of every moment is so expensive that it’s often unfeasible to offer anything that isn’t heavily telegraphed. <em>The Great Circle</em> eschews all that with alacrity, happily letting players miss entire sections and sequences without desperately fussing about it. So much so that a friend shared a clip of a funny cutscene from the Vatican that I’d never encountered in all my time there. Because, this is a game where there are huge rewards for just seeing if something might work.</p><p>My first experience of this was noticing a pedestal in a dingy stone corridor, the first of them I’d seen in the game, and remembering that quite a while back I’d seen a stone bust on the floor in a distant room. “I wonder,” I thought, assuming I’d be about to waste my time. But I ran all the way back, then lugged the heavy object back down the stairs and through the tunnels, and saw the “X” appear on the pedestal. “Surely not?” I said, and then delighted as it let out a resounding click, followed by the grinding sound of a nearby door opening. I’d found a secret area!</p><p>The game keeps on doing this. Find a note in some room far off the path of any of the main missions, and it’ll unlock a little storyline or offer a mystery to solve, or even cause conversation later in the area to change. Notice a pattern in a bunch of the ancient art on the walls, and then realize the number of unmentioned statues in this one room matches the number of images, and what if you just... I love that it respects the player enough to leave these things hanging loosely.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="247e508aa4d1f9f56d860f4f2b7c3761" data-recommend-id="image://247e508aa4d1f9f56d860f4f2b7c3761" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy has a hand on a door handle, another putting a key into the lock." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indy has a hand on a door handle, another putting a key into the lock." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="247e508aa4d1f9f56d860f4f2b7c3761" data-recommend-id="image://247e508aa4d1f9f56d860f4f2b7c3761" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy has a hand on a door handle, another putting a key into the lock." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>And that’s just the start of the issue. I don’t mean that I have an issue with either action in games, obviously—that would be weird. But rather I really hate how <em>The Great Circle</em> requires such things be done.</p><p>One of my favorite gaming moments was playing the <em>Amnesia</em> developers’ earlier game, <em>Penumbra</em>,<em>&nbsp;</em>for the first time, and interacting with the moveable objects. Doors and drawers moved in a whole new way: you’d reach out to them, and then push or pull with the mouse in the most tactile way, and it felt so much more involving as a result. It feels like <em>Indy </em>has tried for something similar, but entirely misunderstood how to get it right.</p><p>Here, you reach out to a locked door, and rather than just pressing the button to unlock and open it as would be normal, instead you interact with it, but then have to move the left analogue stick in an often arbitrary direction to complete the move. That’s <em>always</em> to the right when unlocking a door, even when the lock is on right side of the door, and it’s so unintuitive! If the game were aiming for the full-on interactivity of <em>Penumbra </em>(and more games should!), it’d be one thing, but this half-way point just makes for irritating interactions, when just pressing X and being done with it would be a much more rewarding experience.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="56281b6387daefd463407be1c1ab5df8" data-recommend-id="image://56281b6387daefd463407be1c1ab5df8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy holds a lit torch in front of a pile of unconscious bodies." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indy holds a lit torch in front of a pile of unconscious bodies." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="56281b6387daefd463407be1c1ab5df8" data-recommend-id="image://56281b6387daefd463407be1c1ab5df8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indy holds a lit torch in front of a pile of unconscious bodies." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>What <em>Indiana Jones And The Great Circle</em> gets right better than anything I could have expected is that thrilling sensation of exploration. Combining its musical score, its lighting, and the way Indy moves, makes for this absolutely sensational experience whenever I enter a new cavern or catacomb or mysterious tunnel for the first time.</p><p>Indy stoops through doorways, and you can hold your torch aloft to light the way, as beasties scurry away and you semi-automatically reach the torch out to light a nearby lamp. There’s an incredible sense of being the first person to enter this location in a thousand years, of having everything laid out in front of you as <em>yours</em>, your discovery, and most of the time, without that being spoilt by impossibly located enemies.</p><p>This might be a me-thing, but one of my pet peeves in movies and games is when the adventurers find the lost, hidden temple, and then somehow the baddies are already inside! <em>Tomb Raider</em> has always been the worst for this, as Lara completes near-impossible obstacle courses through the jungle to find the Mayan ruin, and then guns down the seven people hanging out outside. No!</p><p>But not here. Here, unless there’s a narrative justification (like enemies crashing a tractor through the rocky ceiling due to their wild incompetence), Indy (and sometimes a chum) have the place to themselves. The threat comes in the form of ancient traps, tricksy obstacles, and those ghastly scorpions and the like. It’s <em>so</em> much better for it.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="200bf5008988d118a418af892b875afd" data-recommend-id="image://200bf5008988d118a418af892b875afd" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1038" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A shot Indy looking surprised, in front of golden decor." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A shot Indy looking surprised, in front of golden decor." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshots of not breathing are tough, so here’s a shot of breathing instead.</figcaption><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="200bf5008988d118a418af892b875afd" data-recommend-id="image://200bf5008988d118a418af892b875afd" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1038" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A shot Indy looking surprised, in front of golden decor." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>I am not a very fit man. I’m trying to improve that, making some progress, but even at my most wheezingly incapable, I could hold my breath underwater for more than three seconds.</p><p>I don’t know if Indy is secretly smoking 120 a day, or if he was born with a serious lung disorder, but my goodness me, he needs to see a doctor, sharpish. Sure, I’m used to games having super-buff protagonists who can only sprint for five seconds before collapsing into breathless piles (and there I can identify), but I’ve never known anyone run out of air and start drowning as quickly as Dr Jones.</p><p>It’s literally three seconds of underwater swimming before he’s panicking, making desperate gasping noises, and the blackness of death starts creeping in around his vision. If someone did a nasty fart near him, he’d die.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="25a1637819046de1307d5a98505a9343" data-recommend-id="image://25a1637819046de1307d5a98505a9343" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A wall with alcoves that cause it to look like an aghast face." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A wall with alcoves that cause it to look like an aghast face." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>I’m afraid I don’t have a shot of the dynamite exploding, so share your disgust with this wall.</figcaption><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="25a1637819046de1307d5a98505a9343" data-recommend-id="image://25a1637819046de1307d5a98505a9343" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A wall with alcoves that cause it to look like an aghast face." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>While <em>The Great Circle</em> isn’t aiming to be some sort of real-world simulator with “spreading fire” or whatever thing no game has ever actually properly delivered, it does adhere to a few basic laws of physics. And, given how few games do, these moments can really take you by surprise.</p><p>A few of us at<em> Kotaku</em> have experienced that moment when you’re sneaking up on a Nazi, holding a glass bottle, and then spot something better to use for bonking them on the head. “Ooh, a hammer!” you think, and then press to grab that, forgetting that dropping a thing made of glass tends to have consequences. Then comes the smash on the ground, and the guard, hearing it, spins around and spots you—a doofus holding a hammer—right away.<br></p><p>I took this to another level when the thought was “Ooh, some dynamite,” and I was holding not a bottle but a fiery torch. As you might have guessed, when I dropped the open flame onto the sticks of explosives, the fuses immediately started fizzing, and I realized the situation I’d created for myself in one big rush. It was “Oh, this game is realistic like that!” combined with “Shit! I need to get away!” And this led to my incompetently fumbling the controls, tripping over a fallen pillar that was immediately behind me, and eventually gathering my wits enough to scramble into an opposite corner as the whole lot spectacularly blew up.</p><p>Sure, this is a tale about what a twit I am, but at the same time, it’s a wonderful demonstration of the emergent moments that this lovely game can offer.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="0be33f70dc5c6e3dcf5a5cf153b4e65c" data-recommend-id="image://0be33f70dc5c6e3dcf5a5cf153b4e65c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1052" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0be33f70dc5c6e3dcf5a5cf153b4e65c" data-recommend-id="image://0be33f70dc5c6e3dcf5a5cf153b4e65c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1052" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Yes, I am absolutely scraping the barrel for complaints at this point, but it’s still something that really grates with me. While this is certainly exacerbated by my desire to be able to screenshot the game for articles, I do think it remains a thing that could be improved upon, in any number of games.</p><p>For some reason, so many of the cutscenes in <em>The Great Circle</em> are lit so that the characters are in shadow in the foreground, then the mid-ground with no features is floodlit, and the slightly more interesting backgrounds muted and out of focus. It’s so weird! It keeps doing it!</p><figure id="" data-id="eb86f43c36df67854c9f0e7a3c1680b6" data-recommend-id="image://eb86f43c36df67854c9f0e7a3c1680b6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1081" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Voss and his driver drive in shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Voss and his driver drive in shadows." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="eb86f43c36df67854c9f0e7a3c1680b6" data-recommend-id="image://eb86f43c36df67854c9f0e7a3c1680b6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1081" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Voss and his driver drive in shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Over and over.</p><figure id="" data-id="11f860370d94ae4b9dcedd358a43ad0d" data-recommend-id="image://11f860370d94ae4b9dcedd358a43ad0d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1054" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows again." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows again." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="11f860370d94ae4b9dcedd358a43ad0d" data-recommend-id="image://11f860370d94ae4b9dcedd358a43ad0d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1054" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows again." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Even outdoors.</p><figure id="" data-id="4a1660b546f48c82772017c3b708222f" data-recommend-id="image://4a1660b546f48c82772017c3b708222f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1041" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows outdoors." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows outdoors." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="4a1660b546f48c82772017c3b708222f" data-recommend-id="image://4a1660b546f48c82772017c3b708222f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1041" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Indie and Gina sit in shadows outdoors." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Stop that.</p></div></div><div><figure id="" data-id="8e27f08fac5bcf19918183ad36d275f2" data-recommend-id="image://8e27f08fac5bcf19918183ad36d275f2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The game's main menu, in front of a lively scene in Egypt, in front of a pyramid." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The game's main menu, in front of a lively scene in Egypt, in front of a pyramid." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="8e27f08fac5bcf19918183ad36d275f2" data-recommend-id="image://8e27f08fac5bcf19918183ad36d275f2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The game's main menu, in front of a lively scene in Egypt, in front of a pyramid." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Again, tiny detail, but it’s such a lovely one! <em>The Great Circle</em> makes the very reasonable assumption when you load it that you’re most likely going to want to continue playing where you last left off. So, it loads that already.</p><p>Doing this means the game’s main menu is the last checkpoint you reached, such that when you hit continue, but for a couple of moments, you quickly zoom from third-person to a first-person view from Indy’s eyes, and you’re just off! It’s so much more involving, removing all those “YOU’RE PLAYING A GAME!!!” messages that so like to break any elements of immersion.</p><p>Even better, that menu screen is alive! It’s packed with NPCs going through their animations, such that you might see Gina wander into shot, scratch her chin, then pootle off elsewhere, all while a group of workers hammer rocks amid patrolling Nazis. Yes, I’m describing what’s happening on the window behind the one I’m writing in—it’s the perfect example. And next time I play, it’ll be something completely different!</p><hr><p>There are a wealth of other things to sing about in <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em>, and likely a good few others to gripe on, but we’re all already tired.</p><p>The most important thing to know is this just isn’t what anyone was expecting, which I think it’s fair to say was a first-person action game in an Indiana Jones skin. Instead, this truly feels like a vivid part of the <em>Indiana Jones</em> universe, and is a far more involving, intricate and interesting game than I’d ever hoped for. I’m delighted!</p><p>.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Day Of The Devs 2024 Game Awards Edition: Every Game Shown]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/day-of-the-devs-2024-game-awards-edition-every-game-shown/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/day-of-the-devs-2024-game-awards-edition-every-game-shown.1058247/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/day-of-the-devs-2024-game-awards-edition-every-game-shown/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-73512">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Day of the Devs: Game Awards Edition 2024 from Double Fine Productions was held on Wednesday, showcasing 19 upcoming indie games from studios like Heart Machine, Annapurna, and more.</p>



<p>The event featured a mix of premieres, trailers, and even release dates for games. To help you keep up on everything that was shown, Insider Gaming has put together the full list of every game shown during the event. If you want to watch the full show with walkthroughs and breakdowns of certain games, you <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WvxGulZT9Ig" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">can do so here</a>.</p>



<h6>RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-2024-all-nominees-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Game Awards 2024 – All Nominees Announced</a></h6>



<p>Check out the games from Day of the Devs below. And be sure to let us know what upcoming indie games you’re looking forward to the most down below and in the official Insider Gaming Forums.</p>



<h2 id="h-day-of-the-devs-game-awards-edition-2024-games">Day of the Devs: Game Awards Edition 2024 Games</h2>



<h3>Faraway – Coming to PC in 2025</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="FARAWAY | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5LxbmaXQa-E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-ultimate-sheep-racoon">Ultimate Sheep Racoon</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ultimate Sheep Raccoon Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J4hC8GudgBU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-sleight-of-hand">Sleight of Hand</h3>



<p>TRAILER COMING SOON</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-demon-tides">Demon Tides</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Demon Tides - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4g9hmjD_WTM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-kingmakers-coming-2025">Kingmakers – Coming 2025</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Kingmakers | Winter Games Expo Trailer - Early Access Release in Q1 2025 AD" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZXujvsd9C58?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-recur">Recur</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="RECUR - Announcement Trailer | Time-Bending Puzzle Platformer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P2TVqmdZYUc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-blue-prince-spring-2025">Blue Prince – Spring 2025</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Blue Prince Release Window Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SxT2jjn2yZ8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-incolatus">Incolatus</h3>



<p>TRAILER COMING SOON</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-lok-digital">LOK Digital</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="LOK Digital Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ofCYQGRWcS4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-neon-abyss-2">Neon Abyss 2</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Neon Abyss 2 | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A86PCFApasQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-crescent-county">Crescent County</h3>



<p>TRAILER COMING SOON</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-pbj-the-musical">PBJ – The Musical</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="PBJ – The Musical (Gameplay)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/enk-553M3v4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-curiosmos">Curiosmos</h3>



<p>TRAILER COMING SOON</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-bionic-bay-march-13-2025">Bionic Bay – March 13, 2025</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Bionic Bay - Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XTqkn2vkcUY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3>Inkonbini</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="POV: You've met inKONBINI developer in konbini in Tokyo" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/E37Ajl5C2vY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-feltopia">Feltopia</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Feltopia Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N5GOLZG20v4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-blippo">Blippo+</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Blippo+ Reveal Teaser" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KVIZjoZ8WWQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-hyper-light-breaker-early-access-on-january-14-2025">Hyper Light Breaker – Early Access on January 14, 2025</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Hyper Light Breaker | Release Date Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VijrcUbspqU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<h3 id="h-tankhead">Tankhead</h3>



<figure><p>
<iframe loading="lazy" title="TankHead - Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KzYw01FIwUc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/delta-force-has-no-plans-for-battle-royale-mode/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/delta-force-has-no-plans-for-battle-royale-mode/">Delta Force Has “No Plans” For Battle Royale Mode</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>In a recent Q&amp;A, Delta Force game director Shadow Guo shut down the idea of a battle royale mode coming to the game soon.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-escape-from-tarkov-competitor-pioner/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/next-escape-from-tarkov-competitor-pioner/">Tarkov’s Next Competitor Can Now Be Wishlisted On Steam</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Escape from Tarkov’s next competitor (and STALKER’s, and Metro’s) has surfaced on Steam, and it’s ready to be wishlisted.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-15-new-games-in-december/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-15-new-games-in-december/">PlayStation Plus Game Catalog Gets 15 New Games In December</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Sony has announced that 15 new games are coming to the PlayStation Plus Game Catalog for Extra and Premium subscribers in December 2024.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kick-streamer-performance-report-2024/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kick-streamer-performance-report-2024/">Kick’s Streaming Performance Soared in 2024, Report Reveals</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Kick.com underwent massive growth through 2024, recent data has revealed. Check out Kick’s 2024 numbers here.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roguelite exploration and vehicle game TankHead announced for PC, now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/roguelite-exploration-and-vehicle-game-tankhead-announced-for-pc-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roguelite-exploration-and-vehicle-game-tankhead-announced-for-pc-now-available.1058244/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/roguelite-exploration-and-vehicle-game-tankhead-announced-for-pc-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>A surprise release from Toronto-based studio Alpha Channel.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Toronto-based developer <a title="Companies > Alpha Channel" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/alpha-channel">Alpha Channel</a> has announced <em><a title="Games > TankHead" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tankhead">TankHead</a></em>, a <a title="Genres > Roguelite [206 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite game</a> built around exploration and vehicle gameplay. It is available now for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,926 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/tankhead-2f3b51" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> at a 17 percent-off discount price of $24.89 until December 18, after which it will cost $29.99. <span id="more-933403"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/tankhead-2f3b51" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Embark on a thrilling journey as Whitaker, piloting a drone-controlled tank through the desolate ECA. Battle fierce enemies, scavenge valuable parts, and fight to survive in this fast-paced science-fiction world, as you strive to reach the mysterious Highpoint.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Fight to Reach Highpoint</strong> – As Whitaker your goal is to fight to reach Highpoint, to do that you must traverse the ECA—an area where humans cannot survive. Whitaker must project his mind into a Needle, a robust drone capable of surviving in the harsh conditions of the ECA—and of piloting your Tank. Use your Needle and Tank to combat the vehicles and creatures of the ECA to reach Highpoint.</li><li><strong>Rich, Detailed <a title="Genres > Science-Fiction [71 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/science-fiction">Science-Fiction</a> World</strong> – Explore the ECA a world torn apart by war and a mysterious cataclysmic event that left it uninhabitable by humans. Where humans must “tele-project” their minds into drones in order to survive and pillage the remains of a once great society.</li><li><strong>Fast-Paced Tank Combat</strong> – Your vehicle of choice is a Light Tank; capable of moving quickly and delivering devastating damage to your enemies and the reactive world around you. Your tank can be equipped with various weapons, armor, wheels, motors and abilities to customize your gameplay.</li><li><strong>Dismantle and Destroy</strong> – Use a variety of weaponry to dismantle your enemies, blow off parts, to get a clear shot at their vulnerable weak points to deliver decisive blows. Defeated enemies leave behind their remaining parts for you to salvage or steal. Take what you need, scrap the rest. Use everything to survive.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch the launch trailer and a gameplay overview video below.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="TankHead - Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KzYw01FIwUc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Game Overview and Tips</span></h2><p><iframe title="TankHead - Game Overview and Tips" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uVJrBT1SB1M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bionic Bay launches March 13, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/bionic-bay-launches-march-13-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bionic-bay-launches-march-13-2025.1058238/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/bionic-bay-launches-march-13-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Physics-based action platformer dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Side-scrolling <a title="Genres > Action [2,357 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Platformer [583 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em>Bonic Bay</em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,511 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,926 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1928690/Bionic_Bay/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/bionic-bay-93dd7c" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> on March 13, 2025, publisher <a title="Companies > Kepler Interactive [37 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kepler-interactive">Kepler Interactive</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Mureena [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mureena">Mureena</a> and <a title="Companies > Psychoflow [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/psychoflow">Psychoflow</a> announced. <span id="more-933397"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em><a title="Games > Bionic Bay [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bionic-bay">Bionic Bay</a></em> is a unique physics-based platformer with action, creative game mechanics and a mysterious world crafted with exceptional detail.<br>It introduces a unique Swap mechanic, allowing players to interact with the physics-based world in new ways. The immersive gameplay is<br>completed by spectacular environments and creative level design.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Innovative swap mechanism offers players a new way of interacting with the environment. It can be used to move, defend or attack.</li><li>Stunning environments with an incredible attention to detail.</li><li>An extraordinary world with massive levels.</li><li>Extremely physics based gameplay. Tons of dynamic objects, particles and liquids with large variety of physical properties makes the gameplay exceptionally fun and unique.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Bionic Bay - Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XTqkn2vkcUY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Path Of Exile 2's Huge Early Access Launch Is Overwhelming Its Support Staff]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-huge-early-access-launch-is-overwhelming-its-support-staff/1100-6528388/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/path-of-exile-2s-huge-early-access-launch-is-overwhelming-its-support-staff.1058235/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-huge-early-access-launch-is-overwhelming-its-support-staff/1100-6528388/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528388">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/path-of-exile-2/" data-ref-id="5000-504817">Path of Exile 2's</a> massive early-access launch came with some unforeseen consequences, as developer Grinding Gear Games is now struggling to keep up with player-support requests.</p><p dir="ltr">The dark fantasy ARPG's launch proved to be huge. Grinding Gear Games confirmed it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-passes-over-1-million-early-access-players-dev-warns-of-server-struggles/1100-6528281/" data-ref-id="1100-6528281">sold more than 1 million early-access keys</a> across PC and consoles, and Path of Exile 2 peaked at over 570,000 concurrent players on Steam shortly after its release on December 6. It has remained one of the top-played and top-selling games on the platform since release.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1553012789" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465506,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Path%20of%20Exile%202%20-%20Official%20Early%20Access%20Gameplay%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:159,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/path-of-exile-2-official-early-access-gameplay-trailer\/2300-6465506\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465506\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465506\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465506\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465506&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465506,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6528388&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;path-of-exile-2&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,macintosh,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;grinding-gear-games&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;path-of-exile&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;path-of-exile&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465506},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465506\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4403771-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/TxqifKiM.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1732227240,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="TxqifKiM" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465506" data-src="/videos/path-of-exile-2-official-early-access-gameplay-trailer/2300-6465506/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Path of Exile 2 - Official Early Access Gameplay Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">Unfortunately for Grinding Gear Games, the huge influx of players is wreaking havoc on the studio's support team. As detailed in a forum <a href="https://www.pathofexile.com/forum/view-thread/3616595" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">post</a>, Grinding Gear Games said it is now dealing with an "enormous" amount of support tickets from players that are taking much longer to process than usual. Whereas the developer's support team would usually respond within the same day, or sometimes even within the same hour, it currently can't keep up.</p><p dir="ltr">Technical limitations have compounded the situation, Grinding Gear Games said. Its support system was overloaded with requests, causing emails to not be processed correctly.</p><p dir="ltr">The good news is Grinding Gear Games is looking to hire more people for its support team to "decrease the backlog as soon as possible." It also improved its support systems so that it can process more emails. The developer is urging players who are currently waiting to have their tickets answered to not send follow up requests, as doing so can just create more problems and delays.</p><p dir="ltr">"Please be assured if you're waiting for a response from our Support team, they'll get back to you as soon as humanly possible," Grinding Gear Games said.</p><p dir="ltr">Grinding Gear Games is already making <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-devs-promise-to-make-game-more-rewarding-with-new-update/1100-6528338/" data-ref-id="1100-6528338">changes to Path of Exile 2 to make it a little less punishing and more rewarding</a>. Players should be body-blocked by monsters less thanks to changes to the game's dodge-roll, and the added ability to teleport between saved checkpoints on a map means players will have to do less backtracking after dying. Rewards from Path of Exile 2's magic, rare, and boss enemies will also be more lucrative, with higher item drop rates.</p><p dir="ltr">For those diving into the punishing world of Wraeclast, be sure to check out our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/path-of-exile-2-guides-hub/1100-6528305/" data-ref-id="1100-6528305">Path of Exile 2 guides hub</a> on how to survive and progress your character in the challenging ARPG.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo owns Monolith Soft after completing stake buyout]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-owns-monolith-soft-after-completing-stake-buyout</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-owns-monolith-soft-after-completing-stake-buyout.1058232/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-owns-monolith-soft-after-completing-stake-buyout<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Monolith Soft/Nintendo.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo appears to have quietly bought the remaining stake in Xenoblade Chronicles developer Monolith Soft, and now completely owns the studio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As spotted by </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/nintendo-now-owns-100-of-monolith-soft/">Automaton</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the developer's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://eu-app.contentstack.com/#!/stack/blt740a130ae3c5d529/content-type/article/en-us/entry/create?branch=main">company brochure</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> shows Nintendo now owns all 2,400 shares. The console maker first bought an 80 percent stake (or 1,920 shares) in Monolith back in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/nintendo-acquires-stake-in-monolith-soft">2007</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, then increased that stake to 96 percent (2,304 shares) in 2011. Archived web pages (thanks, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/nintendo-now-owns-100-of-xenoblade-studio-monolith-soft/">VGC</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) show Nintendo owned </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20241125191136/https://www.monolithsoft.co.jp/media/2024/02/monolithsoft_brochure2024-01.pdf">2,230 shares</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as recently as October 1 before buying the remainder.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">While Monolith Soft has been making games for Nintendo systems since 2008, it used to be a somewhat multiplatform studio. Its debut game, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Xenosaga Episode I, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">was released on PlayStation 2, and it developed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Xenosaga: Pied Piper </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">for mobile phones in 2004. But the majority of its work (and series) is on Nintendo hardware, such as the Gamecube (Baiten Kaitos), 3DS (Project X Zone), and Switch (Xenoblade Chronicles).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It has also been a co-developer on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/-i-xenoblade-i-dev-monolith-soft-co-developing-i-the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-i-">Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tears of the Kingdom, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">the first two Splatoon games, and several Animal Crossing installments.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Monolith Soft's next game is a remaster for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Xenoblade Chronicles X, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">which releases in 2025 and brings the full series to the Switch.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's everything featured in Day of the Devs' 2024 indie showcase]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-everything-featured-in-day-of-the-devs-2024-indie-games-showcase</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-everything-featured-in-day-of-the-devs-2024-indie-showcase.1058229/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-everything-featured-in-day-of-the-devs-2024-indie-games-showcase<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
The showcases continue! Following yesterday's batch of cosily tantalising indie games via this year's Wholesome Snack jamboree and just ahead of the triple-A glitz and glamour of The Geoffs, Day of the Devs has returned to spotlight a fresh bunch of promising indies.
</p>
<p>
And as always, it's delivered. This year's showcase brought us intriguing glimpses of everything from star-slinging puzzling to a musical about sandwiches featuring Shakespeare-reciting by children. We've got ever-shifting mansions, witchy broom-racing, convenience store management, fascinating felt creations, and even some sort of haunted 1-bit TV station tumbled straight out of the 80s. And if that's sufficiently whetted your appetite, you can see everything featured in <a href="https://youtu.be/WvxGulZT9Ig?si=46B_tqZuvA5AWobz">Day of the Devs' latest showcase</a> below.
</p>
<h3>Faraway</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="FARAWAY | Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5LxbmaXQa-E?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>FARAWAY | Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5LxbmaXQa-E?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/5LxbmaXQa-E?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Faraway reveal trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5LxbmaXQa-E" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Faraway, from developer Steph Thirion, is a 'musical and infinitely replayable' minimalist one-button puzzle game that challenges players to create constellations by connecting stars together - all while extracting handy life energy and maximising scores. There's a little bit more to it than that, of course, with talk of score-multiplying loop-building and other mechanical nuances to add depth - and it even features a couple of different puzzle modes to really get those brain cells humming. Faraway <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2831000/Faraway/">comes to PC</a> next year.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Ultimate Sheep Racoon</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Ultimate Sheep Raccoon Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J4hC8GudgBU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Ultimate Sheep Raccoon Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J4hC8GudgBU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/J4hC8GudgBU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Ultimate Sheep Racoon announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J4hC8GudgBU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Ultimate Sheep Racoon is the work of Clever Endeavour Games, and is described as a spiritual success to the studio's Ultimate Chicken Horse. It's a party game of tumbling, side-scrolling, bike-riding action, where up to eight players can work together - either locally or online - to create perilous obstacle courses featuring the likes of whirling axes, rotating platforms, and conveyor belts. Then with the track built, it's time to see who can race to the finish line first. Ultimate Sheep Racoon is coming to PC and consoles next year.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Sleight of Hand</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Sleight of Hand Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YBHg3xKnYTk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Sleight of Hand Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YBHg3xKnYTk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/YBHg3xKnYTk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Sleight of Hand announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YBHg3xKnYTk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Sleight of Hand is a third-person "stealth-action deck builder" that sees players, in the role of Lady Luck, taking on their old witch coven using a cursed deck of cards. It all unfolds across the "hardboiled, rain-slicked" streets of Steeple City, with developer Riffraff Games promising the "experimentation and expression" of deck builders, mixed with the "possibility space and environmental strategy" of stealth-sims. It doesn't have a release date yet, but it's coming to Xbox, PC, and Game Pass.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Demon Tides</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Demon Tides - Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4g9hmjD_WTM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Demon Tides - Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4g9hmjD_WTM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4g9hmjD_WTM?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Demon Tides announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4g9hmjD_WTM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Demon Tide, from developer Fabraz, is a vibrant 3D platforming adventure with a big seamless open world - and it looks a little bit like Sonic the Hedgehog with a touch of The Legend of Zelda: Wind Waker's island-hopping seafaring thrown in. At the heart of all this is Beebz and her crew, on a voyage of self-discovery across the oceans of Ragnar's Rock. It's a journey blending platform challenges and secret-hunting built around an "expressive" range of chainable, upgradable, and modifiable abilities forming a flexible traversal toolkit. It's got a "cinematic" story, multiplayer, ghost challenges, extensive character customisation, and you can even slap stickers all over the world for other players to see. Demon Times is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2585890/Demon_Tides/">out next year on PC</a>.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Kingmakers</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Kingmakers | Winter Games Expo Trailer - Early Access Release in Q1 2025 AD" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZXujvsd9C58?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Kingmakers | Winter Games Expo Trailer - Early Access Release in Q1 2025 AD</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZXujvsd9C58?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ZXujvsd9C58?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Kingmakers early access trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZXujvsd9C58" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
There's a very good chance you're already more than a little familiar with developer Redemption Road's Kingmakers; its mesmerising blend of third-person shooter and strategic medieval city builder - featuring literally tens of thousands of soldiers careening around at any given time - has already turned enough heads that it's being made into a movie. And it's still not out yet. This is a game of time-travelling medieval warfare in which players and their friends very much get to bring a gun (or tank, or rocket launcher, or motorbike) to a sword fight in the name of saving future-Earth. Its Day of the Devs showing featured a bit more footage, and it's coming to PC early access via Steam and Epic next year.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Recur</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="RECUR - Announcement Trailer | Time-Bending Puzzle Platformer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P2TVqmdZYUc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>RECUR - Announcement Trailer | Time-Bending Puzzle Platformer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P2TVqmdZYUc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/P2TVqmdZYUc?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Recur announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P2TVqmdZYUc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Angry dogs, bad weather, unhelpfully numberless doors; all things I'd imagine are quite high on the list of annoyances for posties. And to that, you can probably also now add the apocalypse, thanks to developer Kaleidoscube's Recur. What you've got here is a side-scrolling narrative puzzle adventure in which an "average postman" is suddenly faced with the end of the world. It's a calamity brought to life through a striking art style and some appropriately apocalyptic scenarios that see massive objects hurtling around the screen. Bridges collapse, vehicles rain from above, bombs explode - but our postie friend can escape (or cannily utilise) the carnage by controlling the flow of time. There are puzzles to solve, platforms to traverse, and secrets to discover - and all that'll be possible when Recur <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2595260/RECUR/">launches for Steam</a> in 2026.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Blue Prince</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Blue Prince Release Window Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SxT2jjn2yZ8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Blue Prince Release Window Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SxT2jjn2yZ8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/SxT2jjn2yZ8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Blue Prince release window trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SxT2jjn2yZ8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
This first-person "atmospheric architectural adventure" from developer Dogubomb already has puzzle fans a-chatter. It presents players with an ever-changing house they'll need to explore as they search for the elusive Room 46. Each of the manor's shifting chambers - arranged on a 9x5 grid - promises mystery, strategy, puzzles, and secrets, but players can only venture so many steps before the house reconfigures itself again. "The deeper you go the more you will discover," teases Dogubomb. "The more you discover even deeper you'll go." I am super excited for this one, and it's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1569580/Blue_Prince/">coming to Steam</a> in spring 2025.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Incolatus: Don't Stop, Girlypop!</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="DON'T STOP, GIRLYPOP! | Incolatus Gameplay Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KKTolOomD3I?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>DON'T STOP, GIRLYPOP! | Incolatus Gameplay Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KKTolOomD3I?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KKTolOomD3I?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Incolatus: Don't Stop, Girlypop! gameplay trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KKTolOomD3I" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
And then, in a dramatic tonal shift, we've got Don't Stop, Girlypop - a "Y2K girly-pop arena-style movement shooter where standing still is not an option". The trees are dying and the fairies are fleeing, all thanks to a nefarious mining corporation. That's where you come in, pinging around the place while keeping the golden rule in mind: "the faster you go, the more damage you deal and the more you heal". There's also a dress-up meta game - inspired by 90s CD-ROMs and 2000s Flash games - and it's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2610650/Incolatus_Dont_Stop_Girlypop/">out on PC</a> "soon".
</p>
<hr>
<h3>LOK Digital</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="LOK Digital - Explainer Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5d-hsX707ew?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>LOK Digital - Explainer Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5d-hsX707ew?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/5d-hsX707ew?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>LOK Digital explainer trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5d-hsX707ew" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Based on Blaž Urban Gracar's book of whimsical puzzles, LOK Digital is word-search game built around an entirely invented language. The more you play, the more words you'll learn, with new rules being introduced as you go - meaning by the end of it all, you'll be fluent in the LOK language. On top of its core puzzles, there are secrets to discover, plus daily puzzles where you can compete against friends or strangers on global leaderboards. LOK Digital <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2207440/LOK_Digital/">launches today on PC</a> and is coming to mobile next year.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Neon Abyss 2</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Neon Abyss 2 | Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A86PCFApasQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Neon Abyss 2 | Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A86PCFApasQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/A86PCFApasQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Neon Abyss 2 announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A86PCFApasQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Veewo Games's frantic 2020 roguelike run-and-gunner Neon Abyss is back and as garishly hued as ever. Neon Abyss 2 promises the same relentless action as its well-received predecessor but brings a few new twists to the table, including an all-new combat system enabling players to mix and match fight styles as they rip through enemies using their arsenal of melee weapons and firearms. There's also talk of powerful stackable items capable to creating "crazy combinations" each run, and if that's left you curious, Neon Abyss 2 is set to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2235200/Neon_Abyss_2/">debut on Steam</a> next year.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Crescent County</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Crescent County - Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0iFFaArOwlY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Crescent County - Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0iFFaArOwlY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0iFFaArOwlY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Crescent County announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0iFFaArOwlY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Crescent County, a "game about underground street racing and kissing your friends", is an open-world witch-tech adventure that's part life-sim, part hurtling around on the back of a motor broom. When you're not making friends or smooching them, there's money to be made by doing delivery jobs, herding sheep, or fixing leylines. But will you use your earning to spruce-up your home or use it to trick our your broom? After all, once the sun sets, it's time to head out into the night for some "crunchy, flow-state" racing. Crescent County doesn't have a release date yet, but it's coming to Xbox Series X/S and PC. And if you fancy giving it a go before then, developer Electric Saint is having a play test right now on itch.io and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2202650/Crescent_County/">Steam</a>.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>PBJ: The Musical</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PBJ – The Musical" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qdLCva5CV0o?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PBJ – The Musical</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qdLCva5CV0o?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qdLCva5CV0o?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>PBJ: The Musical reveal trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qdLCva5CV0o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
For all the unquestionably good stuff seen elsewhere during Day of the Devs latest showcase, PBJ: The Musical absolutely stole the show for me. Inspired by Romeo and Juliet, developer Kamibox tells the "badly researched story" of the beloved sandwich's tragic origins - all as players guide a strawberry and disillusioned peanut across ten wildly surreal stages, each accompanied by a different song. Stages are fashioned from the animated cuttings of vintage cook books, it's all voiced by children struggling their way through Shakespeare quotes, and it features music (and remixed music!) written by Britain's Got Talent contestant Lorraine Bowen. PBJ: The Musical is coming to iPhone and iPad next year, and I can't bloody wait.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Curiosmos</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="✶ curiosmos ✶ Teaser" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IRvD7hucX8Y?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>✶ curiosmos ✶ Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IRvD7hucX8Y?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IRvD7hucX8Y?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Curiosmos teaser trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IRvD7hucX8Y" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Developed by Céline &amp; the Silly Stars, Curiosmos is a delightful-looking "whimsical space sim" that gives players the tools to create solar systems from the ground up. That involves gathering stardust to fashion new planets and moons before diving down to shape the land. You can conjure clouds, rain, thunder, mountains, and volcanoes into existence - even animal and plant life that can be tweaked through evolution. It's not all chill cosmic expansion, however; an insatiable black hole is closing in and player must stop them from swallowing up their solar system. Curiosmos <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2585710/Curiosmos/">comes to PC</a> in 2025.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Bionic Bay</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Bionic Bay - Gameplay First Look Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GTafYBNP_g8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Bionic Bay - Gameplay First Look Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GTafYBNP_g8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/GTafYBNP_g8?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Bionic Bay first look trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GTafYBNP_g8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Who'd want to be a scientist in a video game, eh? You're either being typecast as the baddy or on the run from extraterrestrial forces after some laboratory mishap. I'm pretty sure the protagonist of Bionic Bay (from developers Mureena Oy and Psychoflow Studio) falls into the latter camp, given he's trying to escape an ancient biomechanical world filled with "imaginative technology, deadly traps, and hidden secrets". Thankfully, he's got some sort of teleportation device to help him navigate Bionic Bay's striking sci-fi vistas and physics-based puzzle platforming - and that's alongside time control powers, gravity flipping abilities, and a kind of comically dramatic force punch. Oh and there's some sort of online racing component against other players too. All this arrives for <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10011377/">PS5</a> and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1928690/Bionic_Bay/">PC</a> on 13th March next year.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>InKONBINI: One Store, Many Stories</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="inKONBINI: One Store. Many Stories | Official Announcement Teaser" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Te1nyC29EdE?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>inKONBINI: One Store. Many Stories | Official Announcement Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Te1nyC29EdE?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Te1nyC29EdE?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>InKONBINI announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Te1nyC29EdE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
I do love a title that gets straight to the point. Nagai Industies' InKONBINI: One Store, Many Stories is a slow-paced, meditative game about working in your aunt's small-town convenience store in the early 90s and hanging out with its customers. Officially dubbed a "slice-of-life narrative-driven simulation", part of your time will be spend stocking shelves and keeping things in order, but as regular customers come and go, you'll gradually piece together details about their lives - and, depending on the choices you make, maybe even influence their stories. InKONBINI is coming to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2723430/inKONBINI_One_Store_Many_Stories/">PC</a>, Mac, Xbox Series X/S, PS5, and PC in 2025.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Feltopia</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Feltopia Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N5GOLZG20v4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Feltopia Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N5GOLZG20v4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/N5GOLZG20v4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Feltopia trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N5GOLZG20v4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
What happens when you take a bunch of fuzzy hand-crafted visuals and turn them into a cosy take on the arcade side-scrolling shooter genre? Why, you get "cute 'em up" Feltopia, of course. Described as a "felt-crafted stop-motion video game" - and by me as "ooooOOOooooooOh" when I saw the trailer - Feltopia casts players as a sheepherder with magical powers on a quest to save their flock. On a fundamental level, it plays out much like any arcade shoot-'em-up of yore - but instead of obliterating enemies into atoms, you'll transform them back to their true forms using your elemental powers. Sadly, Feltopia is still some way out - it's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3159860/Feltopia/">coming to Steam</a> in 2026.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Blippo+</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Blippo+ Reveal Teaser" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KVIZjoZ8WWQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Blippo+ Reveal Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KVIZjoZ8WWQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KVIZjoZ8WWQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Blippo+ reveal trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KVIZjoZ8WWQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"Hooray!", is what I thought after receiving a factsheet for Blippo+. "Finally I've got something that'll help me parse its inscrutable Day of the Devs trailer!" But no - here's what it listed under features: "non-demand", "linear broadcast", "⣿⣿⣿⣿⣿ enabled", "commercial-free", "over-the-top", "read-only", "end-user information system, with robust electronic guide". What Blippo+ <em>appears</em> to be though, is an FMV game featuring fictional 80s public broadcast TV footage squeezed through a 1-bit filter. Why, I don't know, but I'm definitely eager to find out. It's developed by Blippo+, comes from Thank Goodness You're Here publisher Panic, and is due to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3323850/Blippo/">arrive on Steam</a> "soon". 
</p>
<hr>
<h3>Hyper Light Breaker</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Hyper Light Breaker | Summer Game Fest Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pKOTGyWXi_o?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Hyper Light Breaker | Summer Game Fest Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pKOTGyWXi_o?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/pKOTGyWXi_o?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Hyper Light Breaker trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pKOTGyWXi_o" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Hyper Light Breaker - developer Heart Machine's fully 3D rogue-lite spin on its acclaimed Hyper Light Drifter - has been a long time coming. It was initially announced in March 2022, with a release of spring 2023, but has seen a number of delays since then. But now, finally, Heart Machine has announced a new release date, revealing it'll be <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1534840/Hyper_Light_Breaker/">launching into Steam early</a> access on 14th January next year. It looks to be a very different beast to its predecessor, each run challenging players to venture out from their upgradable settlement across a "vast, ever-changing" world of massive, open biomes and deep labyrinths - where they'll defeat "hordes of enemies and gigantic bosses in frenetic third-person combat". It all sounds closer to <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/risk-of-rain-2">Risk of Rain 2</a> than Hyper Light Drifter, but given Heart Machine's strong track record, it's still one to watch.
</p>
<hr>
<h3>TankHead</h3>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="TankHead - Launch Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KzYw01FIwUc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>TankHead - Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KzYw01FIwUc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KzYw01FIwUc?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>TankHead launch trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KzYw01FIwUc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
And finally, there's developer Alpha Channel's TankHead, set in a war-torn sci-fi world that's become uninhabitable for humans. Unhelpfully, what's left is still rich in resources, and the only way to scavenge them - and to survive - is to "tele-project" into drones that can roam the world unhindered through the medium of GREAT BIG TANK. What you have there, then, is a bit of a roguelike based around vehicular exploration, where the goal is to venture out, take on huge bosses, then use any salvage to upgrade your tank and improve your chances in tougher fights to come. TankHead's got some pretty nifty creature design - the robot with an entire motel on its head is a real winner - and it's <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/p/tankhead-2f3b51">out today</a> on the Epic Games Store.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ultimate Sheep Raccoon is a bike racing sequel to Ultimate Chicken Horse]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/ultimate-sheep-raccoon-is-a-bike-racing-sequel-to-ultimate-chicken-horse/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ultimate-sheep-raccoon-is-a-bike-racing-sequel-to-ultimate-chicken-horse.1058208/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/11/ultimate-sheep-raccoon-is-a-bike-racing-sequel-to-ultimate-chicken-horse/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Clear Endeavour Games has revealed Ultimate Sheep Raccoon, their bike racing party game successor to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ultimate-chicke-horse">Ultimate Chicken Horse</a> set to launch in 2025.</p>
<p><iframe title="Ultimate Sheep Raccoon Reveal Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J4hC8GudgBU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Similar to Ultimate Chicken Horse, you’re all in a race to survive and reach the finish line of a level, replaying it multiple times to decide a winner… except that between each round players are able to lay deadly traps and modify the level, making it harder and harder to survive.&nbsp;Ultimate Sheep Raccoon, however, puts you all on bikes instead of having you platform around – it’s a bit more Trials-like in that regard, and you can earn bonus points for pulling off tricks.</p>
<p>Helping you survive will be power-ups, including jetpacks, parachutes to glide, bouncy mines to off your rivals, and more. Helping to make things utterly awful and hilarious are all of the traps and level parts, whether it’s adding rails, ramps and bouncy pads, or pendulums, spikes and laser-emitting TVs.</p>
<p>There’s returning characters in the form of Chicken, Horse, Sheep and Racoon, as well as a bunch of new barnyard animals… because this game support up to 8 players! There’s local, online and cross-platform multiplayer, so anyone and everyone can hop into the game together.</p>

<p>For now, though, the only confirmed platform is PC, and you can wishlist on Steam.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Ballistic Out Now; Creators Can Publish Islands in First Person]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fortnite-ballistic-out-now-creators-can-publish-islands-in-first-person/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-ballistic-out-now-creators-can-publish-islands-in-first-person.1058205/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/fortnite-ballistic-out-now-creators-can-publish-islands-in-first-person/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Epic Games has <a href="https://x.com/FortniteGame/status/1866894827930976259" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> that <a href="https://wccftech.com/fortnite-ballistic-is-a-5v5-tactical-first-person-competitive-mode-launching-next-week/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fortnite Ballistic</a> is now available on early access as planned. This is a 5-versus-5 tactical competitive mode made exclusively for first-person view. Here, players are always split into attackers and defenders, and each team is tasked with an opposing goal: to either plant a Rift Point Device at one of two sites on the map or prevent this from happening, respectively.</p>
<p>All matches in Fortnite Ballistic begin with players on each team selecting one of five Flex Gadgets that they alone will be able to purchase and use. Each Flex Gadget is very powerful, according to Epic, enough to potentially turn the tide of a match if used correctly.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Proximity Mine can be placed on the floor, wall, or ceiling to surprise an unsuspecting enemy. They can be picked up and placed again and will explode if shot.</li>
<li>The Bubble Shield allows you to drop a temporary protective bubble that shields you and your team from bullets and grenades alike.</li>
<li>The Recon Grenade gadget will mark any enemies near where it's thrown, even through walls. Throw a Recon Gadget into a location before entering to get an idea of who might be waiting for you.</li>
<li>The regular but always trustworthy Frag Grenade couldn't be missing, of course. It will bounce and explode as you'd expect, dealing damage to nearby enemies. In Fortnite Ballistic, you'll take damage from your own grenades, but the same does not apply to allies.</li>
<li>Last but not least, the Impulse Grenade gadget is a disruptive tool that scatters enemies and allies. It has many creative uses, such as launching teammates into a location from a distance.</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe title="Fortnite Ballistic Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wYdar6yxg7E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Today, Epic Games also announced that Fortnite creators can publish Islands using the First Person Camera Mode device, allowing even more dedicated first-person experiences to be created and shared throughout the game. It certainly looks like Epic is pushing hard to improve first-person content in their title.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>In related news, LEGO Fortnite just <a href="https://wccftech.com/lego-fortnite-gets-launch-of-new-game-and-major-content-update/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">received</a> a big update.</p>

			
			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
	</div>

		
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox tests streaming your Xbox games to your Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318876/xbox-tests-streaming-games-console</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-tests-streaming-your-xbox-games-to-your-xbox.1058202/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318876/xbox-tests-streaming-games-console<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Microsoft is going to let Xbox Insiders who also subscribe to Game Pass Ultimate test the ability to stream some Xbox games they already own to their Xbox <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/12/11/xbox-insiders-with-game-pass-ultimate-stream-your-own-game-on-xbox-consoles/">starting today</a>. The feature could be useful if you want to jump into a game without having to install the whole thing; given how big game file sizes can be nowadays, streaming a game via the cloud might be a faster way to play or save you from hitting a data cap. </p><p>Microsoft has published a list of games that support the feature <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.xbox.com%2Fen-US%2Fplay%2Fgallery%2Fbuy-and-stream">on its website</a>. There are some great games on the list, including <em>Animal Well</em>, <em>Balatro</em>, <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>, <em>Cyberpunk 2077,</em> and <em>Price of Persia: The Lost Crown</em>.</p><p>You’ll be able to stream games on Xbox Series X / S and Xbox One consoles, Microsoft says, and the feature is set to come out of testing next year. The company started letting Xbox players stream select games they own on TVs and browsers <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/20/24300547/xbox-cloud-gaming-game-library-streaming">last month</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft wants to make the Xbox app the home of PC gaming]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318799/microsoft-xbox-app-new-games-homescreen</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-wants-to-make-the-xbox-app-the-home-of-pc-gaming.1058199/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318799/microsoft-xbox-app-new-games-homescreen<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Microsoft is updating the Xbox app on Windows today with hundreds of PC games that weren’t previously available and a new home experience. It’s part of a broader effort to make the Xbox app <em>the </em>place to find PC games, regardless of whether they’re part of PC Game Pass or not.</p><p>“Earlier this summer, we began working with partners to bring all PC games with Xbox features into the Xbox app,” <a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/games/articles/2024/12/updates-to-the-xbox-app/">explains Chris Charla</a>, general manager of content curation and programs at Xbox. “We’re super excited to see what Xbox games come to Windows PC from game creators in the future and to welcome nearly 400 titles that previously weren’t discoverable or purchasable in the Xbox app.”</p><div><figcaption><em>The new Xbox app homescreen.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Microsoft</cite></p></div><p>The 400 new games include titles from Japanese studios like Kemco and Kairosoft, alongside games like <em>The Invincible</em>&nbsp;by Double 11. More than 100 of these new titles are also Xbox Play Anywhere, so if you buy the Xbox console version then you can play the Xbox PC version too. “Universal Xbox ownership, as well as universal cloud saves on Xbox, and cross-play between Xbox versions on console and PC (and other platforms, at the developer’s discretion) are awesome features players love,” says Charla.</p><p>This update fixes a big problem with the Xbox app, where it wasn’t easy to find Xbox Play Anywhere games that might have otherwise been available in the Microsoft Store. The <a href="https://xboxera.com/2024/11/29/microsoft-is-slowly-fixing-the-xbox-pc-apps-biggest-problem/">XboxEra community</a> has been compiling lists of missing games from the Xbox app, and it looks like Microsoft has been taking note.</p><p>Microsoft has been gradually improving its Xbox app over the past year, including some <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/8/24152252/microsoft-xbox-handheld-compact-mode-controller-improvements">handheld-focused improvements</a>. The software giant has also been trying to tempt game developers over to its Windows-based store in recent years, even <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409285/microsoft-store-cut-windows-pc-games-12-percent">lowing its cut from 30 percent to just 12 percent</a> to try and shake up PC gaming. </p><p>Despite these efforts, there are plenty of PC games that have cross-play between the Xbox and PC version of the game but aren’t part of the Microsoft Store currently or the Xbox app. Microsoft now appears to be working to bring even more of these games into the Xbox app, and it will be interesting to see whether the company makes the bold move of listing Steam, Epic Games Store, or <a href="http://itch.io/">itch.io</a> games in the Xbox app soon, too. Microsoft says it will have more to share about its Xbox app plans at the game developers conference in March.</p><p>Microsoft is also rolling out a new home UI for the Xbox app on Windows today. The home UI now includes featured content from PC Game Pass and the Microsoft Store, alongside collections of deals and discounts. Microsoft has also added a “jump back in” section that lets you quickly get back into recent games just like you can on an Xbox console.</p><p><em><strong>Update, November 11th</strong>: Article updated with details on the Xbox app changes.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Game Catalog Additions for December 2024 Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-plus-game-catalog-additions-for-december-2024-revealed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-game-catalog-additions-for-december-2024-revealed.1058184/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-plus-game-catalog-additions-for-december-2024-revealed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Sonic Frontiers, Forspoken, and more.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Sony has revealed the full line-up of PlayStation Plus Games Catalog additions for December 2024, which includes Sonic Frontiers, Forspoken, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Announced on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/12/11/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-december-sonic-frontiers-forspoken-rabbids-party-of-legends-wrc-generations-and-more/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog</a>, a total of 12 games are joining the library, 11 on the PlayStation Plus Extra tier and one on the PlayStation Plus Premium Tier through a PSVR2 offering. They're available December 17.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Though the monthly offerings usually include a handful of classic games too, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-adds-classic-sly-cooper-and-jak-and-daxter-games-to-playstation-plus-games-catalog-today">Sony has already released Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy, Sly 2: Band of Thieves, and Sly 3: Honor Among Thieves</a> this month. It did so as part of its 30th anniversary celebrations, though didn't mention they'd replace the usual releases.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">PlayStation Plus Games Catalog Additions for December 2024</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/sonic-frontiers">Sonic Frontiers</a> | PS4 + PS5</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/forspoken">Forspoken</a> | PS5</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/rabbids-party-of-legends">Rabbids: Party of Legends</a> | PS4</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/wrc-generations">WRC Generations</a> | PS4 + PS5</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/fist-forged-in-shadow-torch">F.I.S.T. Forged in Shadow Torch</a> | PS4 + PS5</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/jurassic-world-evolution-2">Jurassic World Evolution 2</a> | PS4 + PS5</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/coffee-talk">Coffee Talk</a> | PS4 + PS5</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/coffee-talk-episode-2-hibiscus-butterfly">Coffee Talk Episode 2: Hibiscus and Butterfly</a> | PS4 + PS5</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/a-space-for-the-unbound">A Space for the Unbound</a> | PS4 + PS5</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/phogs">PHOGS</a> | PS4</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/biped">Biped</a> | PS4 + PS5</li><li><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/star-wars-tales-from-the-galaxys-edge">Star Wars: Tales from the Galaxy's Edge</a> | PSVR2</li></ul><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Sonic Frontiers Gameplay Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Sonic Frontiers is the lasted game from the Blue Blur and includes a franchise first "open-zone" gaming experience. "Sonic Frontiers is an ambitious open-world adventure that mostly succeeds at mixing up the Sonic formula, even when some of its ideas fall flat," <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-frontiers-review">IGN said in our 7/10 review</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Forspoken Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">A PlayStation 5 exclusive, Forspoken arrived with grand promises of an open world full of magic but fell flat on release due to a lacklustre story, gameplay, and performance. "Forspoken’s flashy combat and parkour can be fun, but they aren’t enough to make its cliche story and barebones open world very interesting to explore," <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/forspoken-review">IGN said in our 6/10 review</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Just in time for the holidays, party game Rabbids: Party of Legends brings mayhem to PlayStation through four player local multiplayer. "Embark on a legendary journey filled with colorful characters with the Rabbids in this uproarious party game," reads the synopsis.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">WRC Generations Screens</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Another entry in the WRC racing series, WRC Generations is promised to be "an authentic and comprehensive rally racing simulation, giving players the chance to drive powerful cars in the most famous rallies of all time." <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/wrc-generations-review">It earned an 8/10 in IGN's review</a>, in which we said: "With its absolute mountain of rally locations, WRC Generations is uncommonly generous package for gravel groupies, asphalt addicts, and mud-slinging maniacs alike."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">F.I.S.T. Forged in Shadow Torch is described as a "diesel-punk exploratory platformer" where players must fight through intense combat sequences, overcome challenging puzzles, and interact with an anthropomorphic cast of vibrant characters.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Screens  -  Jurassic World Evolution 2</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">When managing zoos becomes too tiresome, players can turn up the intensity by putting some dinosaurs on show. Jurassic World Evolution 2 allows just that: dinosaur park management simulation where players take charge of their own Jurassic World park. "While park management and customization aspects are a bit shallow, Jurassic World Evolution 2 has tons of excellent dinosaurs and exciting ways to interact with them," <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/jurassic-world-evolution-2-review">IGN said in our 7/10 review</a>.</p><a href="https://blog.playstation.com/tachyon/2024/12/5cf60c15d992071250b45318795c2447f9384e22.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">If that's too much, players also have the option for something cozier. "As the Barista in late-night coffee shop, Coffee Talk offers players friendly conversation and late-night warm drinks to the colourful and fantastical inhabitants of alternative-Seattle including elves, aliens, and orcs," its synopsis reads.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Fancy a double shot? "Dust off your coffee machine and prepare your warmest smile to meet your favorite customers again in the second episode of Coffee Talk: Hibiscus &amp; Butterfly, a coffee brewing and heart-to-heart talking simulator."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Another quieter game comes in the form of A Space for the Unbound, a 2023 game with pixel art and a heartwarming story. "A Space for the Unbound is a slice-of-life set in the late 90s rural Indonesia that tells a story about overcoming anxiety, depression, and the relationship between a boy and a girl with supernatural powers," its synopsis reads.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">What's better than one dog? A two headed dog? Maybe. "In Phogs! you play as a two headed dog called Red and Blue. Linked by a stretchy belly, you’ll need to bark, bite and bounce your way through obstacles set across the themed worlds of Food, Sleep and Play."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">More multiplayer fun comes in Biped, "a co-op action-adventure game that emphasizes real-time collaboration between two players" according to its official synopsis. "Guide Aku and Sila, two charming bipedal robots, through intricate paths leading to planetary beacons."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, virtual reality fans can this month enjoy Star Wars: Tales from the Galaxy's Edge - Enhanced Edition. IGN called it "an excellent way to showcase the best features of a fancy new PlayStation VR2," <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-tales-from-the-galaxys-edge-enhanced-edition-review">IGN said in our 7/10 review</a>. "The first few hours of the story are its Episodes 1 and 2 (bad) but then things turn around and immerse us in Star Wars greatness."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 – Meet the Medieval Cast | IGN First]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-meet-the-medieval-cast-ign-first</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-%E2%80%93-meet-the-medieval-cast-ign-first.1058181/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-meet-the-medieval-cast-ign-first<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">You don't need to have played the original Kingdom Come: Deliverance to get up to speed with the sequel, thanks to an extended intro that fills you in on the broader details. But it might help to know a bit about the main cast before you set off into the medieval Bohemian countryside. The story features a rich cast made up of both real historical figures and fictional ones, and the politics of it all can be tricky to untangle. Luckily, we've got you covered. Let's meet the characters of Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Be warned that these bios contain some spoilers from the first game!</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Wenceslaus IV and Sigismund of Hungary: A Clash of Kings</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">In 1378, 25 years before the events of Kingdom Come: Deliverance, the emperor Charles IV, who was widely regarded as a pretty cool guy, died. As is often the case when a really cool king or emperor dies, this led to an inconvenient series of events. His son Wenceslaus became his successor to the throne of Bohemia, and gained a reputation for spending his days doing sod all, not showing much interest in his kingly responsibilities.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In response to this, his younger half-brother, Sigismund of Hungary, decided to make a play for the Bohemian throne and took Wenceslaus prisoner. During the events of the first game, he is seen riding around demanding the loyalty of local nobles and burning down villages he believes are harboring rebels – including Skalitz, the hometown of our protagonist, Henry.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In real life, it was a complicated situation with no clear good guys and bad guys, necessarily. I mean, if you ask me, pretty much all medieval nobles were bad guys. But in the context of KCD, Wenceslaus is the good and true king and Sigismund is the plunderous pretender. That's how Henry sees it, anyway. And if the guy on one side of a civil war had burned down my village and killed my parents, I'd probably agree.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As an additional fun fact, the real-life Sigismund founded the chivalric Order of the Dragon. You may have heard of it, since a certain Romanian prince, Vlad Dracul, was nicknamed such for being a member of it. His son, Dracula ("son of the dragon"), would go on to be even more famous.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Henry of Skalitz: The Blacksmith's Son</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The protagonist of both Kingdom Come: Deliverance games is a common lad named Henry who saw his whole life go up in flames and his family murdered. The son of a blacksmith, he was forced to make his way in the world without many useful skills to speak of – the very picture of a level-one RPG character. But steadily, over the course of the first game, he became a capable swordsman, a daring adventurer, and even learned to read and write – which was a rare enough skill in the middle ages, even among the nobles, that it was practically a superpower.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Henry becomes involved with a faction of nobles who oppose Sigismund and want to see Wenceslaus restored to the Bohemian throne, rising from his lowly status to be a trusted and valued retainer. He also spends some time as a monk. It's kind of a long story. But he also has a more specific quest: retrieving the stolen sword he and his father made for their lord, Radzig Kobyla, before the village was attacked.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Istvan Toth: A Big Ol' Jerk</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">This is the jerk who stole said sword. A Hungarian noble and supporter of Sigismund, he was the main antagonist of the first game and managed to wriggle free from the good guys' grasp by exchanging some hostages. While Henry certainly feels a sense of duty to Wenceslaus, his more personal motivation is getting that dang sword back from Toth. And then probably giving it back, pointy end first, if we're being honest. His whereabouts are currently unknown.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Sir Radzig Kobyla: A Friendly Noble</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">The Lord of Skalitz before its destruction, Sir Radzig is part of the pro-Wenceslaus faction, which is why Sigismund saw his seat of power ransacked. Also – last warning for spoilers – he's Henry's real, biological father. Which sort of makes Henry nobility. Or at least, there is a nobleman with a very strong interest in his future and wellbeing. Martin the blacksmith is still definitely Henry's father figure. But Sir Radzig has become a very important man in his life.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Sir Hans Capon: Your Spoiled BFF</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Sir Hans Capon is a young nobleman about Henry's age and a member of Wenceslaus' faction who plays a much larger role in KCD2 than he did in the first game, being Henry's main compatriot. They're not always the best of friends, though. Hans is a bit of a playboy nepo baby who was raised with the proverbial silver spoon in his mouth and tends to act petulant and entitled, often to Henry's frustration. He's also quite easily distracted by women.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 - Gamescom 2024 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">At the start of KCD2, Henry and Hans have been dispatched on a mission to feel out which of the remaining Bohemian nobles might be willing to stand up against Sigismund and help restore Wenceslaus to the throne. And while he's not entirely apathetic to politics, he mostly looks at this as an opportunity for travel and adventure. To be blunt, he's a bit of a dick. But he seems to have a good heart, even if he doesn't normally let it guide him. Can we fix him? That remains to be seen.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Theresa: The Girl Who Saved Your Sorry Butt</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">A fellow refugee from Skalitz who now lives with her uncle, Theresa is a bold woman who has saved Henry's life more than once. She's also the potential main love interest in KCD1, if you choose to pursue her side quests. It's not clear what role, if any, she will play in KCD2. But especially considering she and Henry were likely to have become romantically involved, I would be somewhat surprised if we've already seen the last of her.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 - First Screenshots</h3></div></output><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Sir Divish: The Guy Who Saved Your Sorry Butt</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Sir Divish is the Lord of Talmberg, where Henry took refuge right after the destruction of Skalitz. The fortress was later seized in an intrigue orchestrated by Toth, and the climax of the first game involves a siege to reclaim it. He is, along with Radzig, one of the main conspirators of the Wenceslaus faction, and a very shrewd leader who has kept his people safe by holding his allegiances close to his chest.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Markvart von Aulitz: Probably The Real Final Bad Guy</strong></h3><p data-cy="paragraph">If I'm being honest, I don't give Istvan Toth long to live. The fact that we didn't get to stick it to him at the end of the first game was a huge tease, and he only made it out by the skin of his teeth. Markvart is a bit higher up the food chain, as one of Sigismund's main army commanders and the man who led the attack on Skalitz. He was a somewhat distant enemy in the first game, seeming almost untouchable. But if I had to place my bets on who we'll be crossing swords with at the end of KCD2? I think it's probably this guy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That should give you a pretty good idea of which important pieces are on the board at the start of this new adventure. For more, stay tuned all December long as our exclusive IGN First coverage of Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 continues.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Original Halo Trilogy Soundtrack on Vinyl Is Up for Preorder]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-halo-original-trilogy-soundtrack-vinyl</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-original-halo-trilogy-soundtrack-on-vinyl-is-up-for-preorder.1058178/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/where-to-buy-halo-original-trilogy-soundtrack-vinyl<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Cue the choir.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Halo was a groundbreaking video game on a number of fronts. Right out of the gate, it cemented Microsoft’s new Xbox console as a serious competitor for Sony and Nintendo. It established a first-person shooter control scheme for controllers that we basically still use today. And the music… well, it was instantly iconic and remains so today. The music rules. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, Halo Studios and Laced Records are putting out remastered original soundtracks for Halo: Combat Evolved, Halo 2, and Halo 3 on vinyl, available individually or in a collected set (<a href="https://zdcs.link/z6bGpk?object_uuid=97f939e9-531f-4209-b348-86bcec1f1893&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">see it on Amazon</a> or the <a href="https://store.ign.com/collections/halo-vinyl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN Store</a>).</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Halo Original Trilogy Original Soundtrack Preorders</h2><div catalogid="88f976cd-b15d-44ad-9bae-bd9ab2ccbe99" id="213317"><div id="213317" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Halo Original Trilogy Original Soundtrack (Vinyl)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><em><strong>Also available individually</strong></em></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Halo: Combat Evolved - <a href="https://zdcs.link/zjG0E2?object_uuid=97f939e9-531f-4209-b348-86bcec1f1893&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DMPKFLJX" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Amazon</a> | <a href="https://store.ign.com/products/halo-combat-evolved-original-soundtrack-2-lp-vinyl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN Store</a></li><li>Halo 2 - <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qx7vEb?object_uuid=97f939e9-531f-4209-b348-86bcec1f1893&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DMPKTYY2" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Amazon</a> | <a href="https://store.ign.com/products/halo-2-original-soundtrack-3-lp-vinyl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN Store</a></li><li>Halo 3 - <a href="https://zdcs.link/z7b7D8?object_uuid=97f939e9-531f-4209-b348-86bcec1f1893&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DMPK6NQL" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Amazon</a> | <a href="https://store.ign.com/products/halo-3-original-soundtrack-3-lp-vinyl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN Store</a></li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">The soundtracks are set to release on April 4 and are available for preorder on Amazon right now. If you buy the whole set, it costs $200.98. Purchased individually, the price totals $195, so that’s the better value, oddly enough. That said, the Amazon preorder price guarantee means you’ll be locked into the lowest price any of these items drop to prior to release. So preorder now, and you’ll pay the lowest price.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">All told, if you buy the complete set, you get 83 songs spread across eight heavyweight LPs. All of the tracks are specially remastered for vinyl and come in a wide-spined outer sleeve, with printed inner sleeves.</p><h3 data-cy="title3"><strong>Halo: Combat Evolved</strong> Original Soundtrack Track Listing</h3><ol data-cy="list"><li>Opening Suite</li><li>Truth and Reconciliation Suite</li><li>Brothers in Arms</li><li>Enough Dead Heroes</li><li>Perilous Journey</li><li>A Walk in the Woods</li><li>Ambient Wonder</li><li>The Gun Pointed at the Head of the Universe</li><li>Trace Amounts</li><li>Under Cover of Night</li><li>What Once Was Lost</li><li>Lament for PVT. Jenkins</li><li>Devils... Monsters</li><li>Covenant Dance</li><li>Alien Corridors</li><li>Rock Anthem for Saving the World</li><li>The Maw</li><li>Drumrun</li><li>On a Pale Horse</li><li>Perchance to Dream</li><li>Library Suite</li><li>The Long Run</li><li>Suite Autumn</li><li>Shadows</li><li>Dust and Echoes</li><li>Halo</li></ol><h3 data-cy="title3">Halo 2 Original Soundtrack Track Listing</h3><ol data-cy="list"><li>Halo Theme Mjolnir Mix</li><li>Peril</li><li>Ghosts of Reach</li><li>Heretic, Hero</li><li>Flawed Legacy</li><li>Impend</li><li>Ancient Machine</li><li>In Amber Clad</li><li>The Last Spartan</li><li>Orbit of Glass</li><li>Heavy Price Paid</li><li>Earth City</li><li>High Charity</li><li>Remembrance</li><li>Prologue</li><li>Cairo Suite</li><li>Mombasa Suite</li><li>Unyielding</li><li>Mausoleum Suite</li><li>Unforgotten</li><li>Delta Halo Suite</li><li>Sacred Icon Suite</li><li>Reclaimer</li><li>High Charity Suite</li><li>Finale</li><li>Epilogue</li></ol><h3 data-cy="title3">Halo 3 Original Soundtrack Track Listing</h3><ol data-cy="list"><li>Luck</li><li>Released</li><li>Infiltrate</li><li>Honorable Intentions</li><li>Last of the Brave</li><li>Brutes</li><li>Out of Shadow</li><li>To Kill a Demon</li><li>This Is Our Land</li><li>This Is the Hour</li><li>Dread Intrusion</li><li>Follow Our Brothers</li><li>Farthest Outpost</li><li>Behold a Pale Horse</li><li>Edge Closer</li><li>Three Gates</li><li>Black Tower</li><li>One Final Effort</li><li>Keep What You Steal</li><li>Gravemind</li><li>No More Dead Heroes</li><li>Halo Reborn</li><li>Greatest Journey</li><li>Tribute</li><li>Roll Call</li><li>Wake Me Up When You Need Me</li><li>Legend</li><li>Choose Wisely</li><li>Movement</li><li>Never Forget</li><li>Finish the Fight</li></ol><p data-cy="paragraph">That's a lot of great music right there. These soundtracks have the iconic main theme, complete with choral singing, plus lots of exciting tracks filled with strings and driving percussion. It's the good stuff, particularly for anyone who grew up playing the Halo games on Xbox and Xbox 360. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, check out the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-deals">best Xbox deals</a> available now, including a huge discount on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-3-month-woot-indiana-jones">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate</a>, which lets you play Indiana Jones and the Great Circle for no additional charge. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Check Out More Soundtracks on Vinyl at the IGN Store</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Chris Reed is a deals expert and commerce editor for IGN. You can follow him on Bluesky <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/chrislreed.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@chrislreed.bsky.social</a>.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Dec 11, 2024 4:50 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Neon Abyss 2 announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/neon-abyss-2-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/neon-abyss-2-announced-for-pc.1058172/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/neon-abyss-2-announced-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in Early Access in 2025.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Chinese developer <a title="Companies > Veewo Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/veewo-games">Veewo Games</a> has announced <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [857 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> <a title="Genres > Roguelike [282 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelike</a> <a title="Genres > Action [2,357 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> sequel <em><a title="Games > Neon Abyss 2" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/neon-abyss-2">Neon Abyss 2</a></em>. It will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,926 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2235200/Neon_Abyss_2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> in 2025. <span id="more-933340"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2235200/Neon_Abyss_2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Dive deeper into the chaotic, beautifully pixelated Abyss with <em>Neon Abyss 2</em>! The action is faster, the stakes are higher, and the possibilities are endless in this cybermyth roguelike. With explosive <a title="Genres > Run-and-Gun [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up/run-and-gun">run-and-gun game</a>play, diverse combat styles, and unlimited item synergies, <em>Neon Abyss 2</em> delivers a dramatic, thrill-packed experience every time you enter.</p><div id="carousel_933347"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Unimaginable Weaponry: Revolutionary Weapon System</strong> – What’s your combat style? Smash enemies up close with a bat or saber, unleash attacks with deadly plants, or command fierce dragon-like creatures to fight for you—the choice is yours! With limitless options and imaginative weapons, every run lets you experiment with unique, wild ways to conquer the Abyss.</li><li><strong>Unlimited Item Synergies: Even More Monstrous!</strong> – Random item drops in the Abyss grant you powers that combine in surprising and powerful ways. Stack as many as you can to create wild, unstoppable synergies that make every run feel unique. Show the Abyss who’s really in charge—there’s no limit to how many items you can wield!</li><li><strong>Hatch Them All! Hatchmon! I Choose Your!</strong> – Your favorite Abyss companions, now in even brighter colors! Hatch and collect these cute creatures, then evolve them into powerful and unique allies to spice up your runs. With a variety of Hatchmon to discover, each run brings new possibilities!</li><li><strong>The Power of Faith: Turn the Tides!</strong> – Introducing the all-new Faith System, designed to turn the tides when the Abyss gets unreasonable. How will you wield this power? Spend it in a shop stocked with powerful items, recruit more Hatchmon to fight by your side, or…risk it all in a game of chance? Either way, we have faith in you!</li><li><strong>…And More! Discover As You Explore</strong> – Uncover a host of new features and surprises in this dynamic second installment. From new enemies and powerful gods to updated loot and hidden secrets, there’s always something fresh to find. The Abyss awaits—dive deeper and uncover secrets you may not face alone!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/neon-abyss-2/december-11-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Neon Abyss 2 | Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A86PCFApasQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></blockquote></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Word game LOK Digital for PC now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/word-game-lok-digital-for-pc-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/word-game-lok-digital-for-pc-now-available.1058169/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/12/word-game-lok-digital-for-pc-now-available<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Learn a cryptic language of world-changing words.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Draknek &amp; Friends" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/draknek-friends">Draknek &amp; Friends</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Letibus Design" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/letibus-design">Letibus Design</a> and <a title="Companies > Icedrop Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/icedrop-games">Icedrop Games</a> have released word game <em><a title="Games > LOK Digital" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/lok-digital">LOK Digital</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [21,926 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2207440/LOK_Digital/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://draknek.itch.io/lok-digital" rel="noopener" target="_blank">itch.io</a> for $14.99 with a 10 percent-off launch discount, the companies announced. iOS and Android versions are due out in early 2025. <span id="more-932778"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Draknek &amp; Friends:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Learn the rules as you go and uncover how each new word has its own special ability to change the world around you in deep and surprising ways. Expand your vocabulary through 15 distinct worlds, each one exploring a new mechanic and completely shaking up the way you solve puzzles.</p><p>With approachable mechanics and mind-bending gameplay, <em>LOK Digital</em> invites you to return every day for new procedurally generated puzzles showcasing the breadth and depth of mechanics.</p><p>Bring the LOK creatures to life by spelling words that shape their world. They can only live on blackened tiles, so by solving puzzles you’re expanding their horizons and helping their civilization thrive.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Intuitive mechanics and many magical words to find and learn.</li><li>Elegant, hand-drawn art style and meditative, entrancing soundtrack.</li><li>Learn the nuances of the LOK language across the 150-plus puzzle campaign.</li><li>Demonstrate your mastery of the mechanics in the expertly crafted daily puzzle mode and compete on the leaderboards.</li><li>Go up against friends, family and the world in the daily leaderboards.</li><li>Based on the critically acclaimed puzzle book, LOK.</li><li>Published by the award-winning puzzle experts, Draknek &amp; Friends, the team behind <em>A Monster’s Expedition</em>, <em>Cosmic Express</em>, <em>Bonfire Peaks</em>, and more.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the launch trailer below.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="LOK Digital Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ofCYQGRWcS4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reminder: Donate to win swag in our annual Charity Drive sweepstakes]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/reminder-donate-to-win-swag-in-our-annual-charity-drive-sweepstakes-14/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reminder-donate-to-win-swag-in-our-annual-charity-drive-sweepstakes.1058166/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/reminder-donate-to-win-swag-in-our-annual-charity-drive-sweepstakes-14/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                      
                      
          <p>If you've been too busy <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-captures-the-feel-of-a-great-indy-movie/">punching virtual Nazis</a>&nbsp;to take part in <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/win-hardware-collectibles-and-more-in-the-2024-ars-technica-charity-drive/">this year's Ars Technica Charity Drive sweepstakes</a>, don't worry. You still have time to donate to a good cause and get a chance to win your share of over $4,000 worth of swag (no purchase necessary to win).</p>
<p>In the first three days of the drive, over 100 readers have contributed almost $9,500 to either the <a href="https://supporters.eff.org/donate/">Electronic Frontier Foundation</a> or <a href="http://www.childsplaycharity.org/">Child's Play</a> as part of the charity drive (Child's Play is now leading in the donation totals by about $1,000). That's a long way off from <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2021/01/ars-readers-gave-a-record-58000-in-2020-charity-drive/">2020's record haul of over $58,000</a>, but there's still plenty of time until the Charity Drive wraps up on Thursday, January 2, 2025.</p>
<p>That doesn't mean you should put your donation off, though. Do yourself and the charities involved a favor and give now while you're thinking about it.</p>
<p>See below for instructions on how to enter, and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/win-hardware-collectibles-and-more-in-the-2024-ars-technica-charity-drive/">check out the Charity Drive kickoff post</a> for a complete list of available prizes.</p>
<h2>How it works</h2>
<p>Donating is easy. Simply <a href="https://childsplay.salsalabs.org/Donate/index.html">donate to Child's Play</a> using a credit card or PayPal or <a href="http://eff.org/AT2014">donate to the EFF</a> using PayPal, credit card, or cryptocurrency. You can also support Child's Play directly by using <a href="https://my.onecause.com/fundraiser/organizations/8534d777-53ce-4d94-a537-c8e0cbb7acb0/fundraisers/fundraiser:ae0c129c-94ac-4e63-a265-20b71ac4bd03">this Ars Technica campaign page</a> or picking an item from the Amazon wish list of a specific hospital on <a href="https://childsplaycharity.org/get-involved#hospital-map">its donation page</a>. Donate as much or as little as you feel comfortable with—every little bit helps.</p>

          
                      
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metaphor: ReFantazio Is GameSpot's Game Of The Year 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/metaphor-refantazio-is-gamespots-game-of-the-year-2024/1100-6528323/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metaphor-refantazio-is-gamespots-game-of-the-year-2024.1058163/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/metaphor-refantazio-is-gamespots-game-of-the-year-2024/1100-6528323/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="">

            
          
  

<section><p>Here's why Atlus's fantasy RPG is our choice for game of the year.</p></section>
        
  
  

        
              <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                                        <p>Though Metaphor: ReFantazio is the former Persona team's first foray into high fantasy, it might also be the most grounded and deeply human game they've ever created. By weaving magical elements with universal topics--such as prejudice, poverty, grief, cycles of violence, anxiety, and the role religion and politics can play in both oppressing and empowering the people--Metaphor is able to examine humanity with some distance and through a unique lens. It poses countless questions to its players, all while admitting the answers might not be simple or absolute. And yet, it places special emphasis on one question in particular: Does fiction have the power to shape our world?</p><p dir="ltr">By the time the game comes to a close, the answer is a resounding yes. Metaphor: ReFantazio is a beautiful exploration into how fantasy is a vessel for ideas and humanity even in the darkest of times. It understands the impact that art and the ideas transferred through it have on society, and asks us to both believe in and scrutinize the media we consume.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="27876394" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465561,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Why%20Metaphor%3A%20ReFantazio%20Is%20GameSpot%27s%20Game%20Of%20The%20Year%202024&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:358,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/why-metaphor-refantazio-is-gamespots-game-of-the-year-2024\/2300-6465561\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465561\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465561\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465561\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465561&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465561,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;high_end_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6528323&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;metaphor-refantazio&quot;,&quot;collection&quot;:&quot;best-of-2024&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,pc,playstation-5,playstation-4&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;sega,atlus,sega-europe&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465561},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465561\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4413326-boty2024_goty.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/VjzBQ5sQ.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1733940000,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="VjzBQ5sQ" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465561" data-src="/videos/why-metaphor-refantazio-is-gamespots-game-of-the-year-2024/2300-6465561/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Why Metaphor: ReFantazio Is GameSpot's Game Of The Year 2024</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr"><span>The game's cast of characters--from bubbly, blonde pop star Junah and the wisened ninja Heismay, to the disgraced-yet-beloved Louis--are all well-designed, well-voiced, and utterly engaging, making them instantly appealing (or detestable) to players. Each offers their own exploration into the various aforementioned themes, weaving stories that are equal parts heart-wrenching and heartwarming. This depth is also afforded to the game's numerous side characters, which comprise the greatest and most fully-realized roster of social links in an Atlus game thus far.</span></p><p dir="ltr">The studio handles all these narratives with nuance and precision, demonstrating a respect for its players' intelligence as well as immense conviction in its own beliefs. In a time when games are all too often criticized for being too political, Atlus takes a firm stand on the side of compassion and makes it clear that there is virtue in addressing social issues, taking collective action, standing up for your ideas, and believing in a better future for both yourself and those around you. Living in fear and giving into hatred is easy, Metaphor reminds us. It is remaining hopeful and caring that takes strength.</p><p dir="ltr">Despite being a lengthy game, Metaphor is phenomenally paced, with an appropriate amount of time dedicated to each area, character, and story arc. These arcs are all particularly memorable, too, as the game is filled with spectacle, off-the-wall situations that ward off monotony, and compelling plot twists. In that sense, the game often reminded me of the late '90s JRPGs I grew up playing--the ones filled with theatrics, humor, and a keen sense of adventure. It's an almost intangible and indescribable quality, but one that Metaphor undoubtedly possesses.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4412473-4378508-metaphor_refantazio%E2%80%94storytrailer_xboxseriesx_s%2Cwindowspc1-37screenshot-1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4412473" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="2560" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4412473-4378508-metaphor_refantazio%E2%80%94storytrailer_xboxseriesx_s%2Cwindowspc1-37screenshot-1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4412473"></a><figcaption>Antagonist Louis looks out into a smoke-filled sky.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1639/16394322/4412473-4378508-metaphor_refantazio%E2%80%94storytrailer_xboxseriesx_s%2Cwindowspc1-37screenshot-1.png"></figure><p dir="ltr">And yet, Metaphor markedly improves old-school, turn-based combat, addressing the most common complaints with the system--namely its slower pace--through smart button mapping, superb party flexibility, and the addition of light action-style combat. This all makes for battles that are strategic yet breezy, and dungeon traversal that doesn't overstay its welcome or begin to feel more like a chore than an adventure. The game's other systems, from its calendar and Royal Virtues to its Archetype tree, perfectly fit within the combat, creating dynamic gameplay that feels interconnected and immensely satisfying.</p><p dir="ltr">Remarkable art direction and music further elevate the experience, as rather than use a single color palette, as Persona typically does, Metaphor leverages several different colors to convey various themes, tones, and amplify its sense of journey. Its music is similarly complex and juxtaposing, as it bounds between angelic choirs to frenzied chanting. Though its stories might be universal, there is an otherworldly quality to its visuals and music, reminding players that this world is dark and fantastical.</p><p dir="ltr">Regardless of when Metaphor: ReFantazio was released, it would remain an exceptional title. But in the year 2024--a year marred by political unrest, growing inequality, fear, distrust, misinformation, and division--no game feels quite as apt and essential. While not every work of fiction can change the world, or instill within it a goodness that has seemingly been stripped away, Metaphor: ReFantazio is a reminder that art can change us.</p><p dir="ltr"><i>Curious if your favorite game of 2024 made it in our top 10? Check out our list of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/gamespots-10-best-games-of-2024/2900-6045/" data-ref-id="2900-6045">GameSpot's 10 best games of 2024</a>.</i></p>
                          
                                                              </div>
    
                <div>
  <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>
  
    </div>
            


  

    

    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>