<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 15:48:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons and Kingdoms mixes medieval fantasy with polygonal dungeon delving]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/24/dungeons-and-kingdoms-mixes-medieval-fantasy-with-polygonal-dungeon-delving/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-and-kingdoms-mixes-medieval-fantasy-with-polygonal-dungeon-delving.935640/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/24/dungeons-and-kingdoms-mixes-medieval-fantasy-with-polygonal-dungeon-delving/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>We do enjoy a good bit of medieval fantasy at TheSixthAxis, so we welcome with open arms the announcements of Dungeons and Kingdoms, a game that is seemingly about building up your domain, or kingdom, and then adventuring down into some dark, mine-like areas. Possibly dungeons. There’s nothing wrong with a Ronseal-like name for a game though, and if you like both of those things too, we’re off to a good start.</p>
<p><iframe title="Dungeons and Kingdoms | Reveal Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5hrNzDad5Fg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The trailer sees you astride your polygonal mount, surveying the landscape, before giving us a taste of what you’ll need to do to turn a tiny village into a full-blown kingdom, starting with chopping down trees (doesn’t it always?) and building wooden huts, before going off in search of great wealth and treasure by heading into a dungeon to fight off evil creatures like skeletons, giant snake beasts and the odd dragon.</p>
<p>It’s definitely got it’s own unique art style going on, and it’s looks as though you’re going to be able to really get into the nitty-gritty of building and adventuring, with hopefully an array of different tools and building types to work on. You can either work on things yourself, or become a lord by ordering all the lowly serfs to do it for you instead.</p>
<p>Alongside building things up, you can manipulate the landscape, creating hills, mountains, rivers and moats to bring your kingdom to life, and make it truly your own. Besides that, you can farm for crops, hunt wild animals, and create the infrastructure needed for an expanding kingdom</p>


<p>While there’s no set date for release, the development team at Uncle Grouch Gaming are eying up an Early Access launch in either Q4 2024 or Q1 2025, with a demo showcase due in an upcoming Steam Next Fest.</p>
<p>You can wishlist <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3092110/Dungeons__Kingdoms/">Dungeons and Kingdoms right now on Steam</a>, and stay tuned to TheSixthAxis for more!</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony tests a new PS5 3D audio profile setup to personalize in-game effects]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/24/24205192/playstation-5-beta-3d-audio-profiles-remote-play</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-tests-a-new-ps5-3d-audio-profile-setup-to-personalize-in-game-effects.935637/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/24/24205192/playstation-5-beta-3d-audio-profiles-remote-play<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/07/24/new-ps5-beta-rolls-out-tomorrow-with-personalized-3d-audio-profiles-and-new-remote-play-settings/">latest PlayStation beta</a> lets you create personalized 3D audio profiles on your PS5 that could help you “better sense the positions of characters and objects in a game world.” If you’re wearing headphones or earbuds with your PS5, you can perform sound tests to optimize the audio to best suit your needs.</p><p>As shown in the <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DQhZzPyc-Zas%26embeds_referring_euri%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fvoxmedia.stories.usechorus.com%252F%26source_ve_path%3DMjM4NTE">video provided by Sony</a>, the tests will ask you various questions, like where you hear a particular sound coming from and the angle you hear a sound moving in. Based on your answers, your PS5 will create an audio profile that will be saved to your account and ideally improve the simulated effect to help you track sounds around you in games. </p><p>You can create an audio profile by going to the settings menu and selecting <strong>Sound</strong> &gt;<strong> 3D Audio (Headphones)</strong>.</p><p>Additionally, if you have friends or family members who are signed in to their accounts on your PS5, you can now choose whether they can access your console for Remote Play or whether they’ll need their own system to stream <em>College Football 25</em> on a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24012547/sony-playstation-portal-handheld-remote-player-ps5-chiaki-review">PlayStation Portal</a>. </p><p>You can modify these permissions by going to the Settings menu and selecting <strong>Systems &gt; Remote Play &gt; Enable Remote Play</strong>. From there, you’ll see a list of users signed in on your PS5, along with toggles that allow or restrict access.</p><div><figcaption><em>You can allow or restrict access to your console via Remote Play.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Sony</cite></p></div><p>There’s a new adaptive charging feature for DualSense wireless controllers, DualSense Edge wireless controllers, PlayStation VR2 Sense controllers, and Access controllers — but it’s only available on the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/10/23955005/sony-playstation-5-ps5-slim-size-comparison-photo-gallery-hands-on-impressions">latest PS5 model released last year</a>. If enabled, your PS5 will limit the amount of power supplied to your controllers while in rest mode, depending on your controller’s battery level. It will also stop supplying power to the USB port if you don’t have a controller connected.</p><p>The beta is available to “selected participants” in the US, UK, Canada, Japan, Germany, and France. Sony notes that it plans to roll out the update globally in the “coming months.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delta Force: Hawk Ops Announces Open Alpha Test]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/delta-force-hawk-ops-announces-open-alpha-test/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/delta-force-hawk-ops-announces-open-alpha-test.935631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/delta-force-hawk-ops-announces-open-alpha-test/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Delta Force: Hawk Ops is a free-to-play platformer with tactical shooter elements. The developers behind it have officially announced that the official Alpha Test for the game will be open for players to participate in as of August 6. They are expecting a big turnout for the Alpha test, as over 600,000 people have wishlisted the game on Steam and the Epic Games Store thus far.</p>
<p>For those who want to see what <a href="https://wccftech.com/delta-force-hawk-ops-qa-early-access-in-october-release-window-in-q1-2025/">Delta Force: Hawk Ops</a> is all about, you will need to sign up to participate in the <a href="https://www.playdeltaforce.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Alpha test</a>, where you can experience two game modes: Hazard Operations and Havoc Warfare. Signing up for the Alpha test is easy, as you have to go to the official website for Delta Force: Hawk Ops and register your interest in participating. Alternatively, you can go to the Steam webpage for the game and register interest there. Finally, you can follow the developers on X, where they will be announcing a Twitch Drop of codes for people interested in taking part in the Alpha test for Delta Force: Hawk Ops.</p>
<p>The developers behind the newest iteration in the Delta Force franchise have released a small statement expressing their joy with seeing how hugely anticipated this upcoming game is. "We are immensely grateful for the incredible support and enthusiasm shown by our community. Hitting 600,000 wishlists is a remarkable achievement, and we couldn't have done it without our dedicated players," said Shadow Guo, the Game Director at Team Jade.</p>
<p>The two modes available in the alpha test are wildly different. Havoc Warfare is a large-scale battle with multiple teams battling it on gigantic maps. You can utilize an arsenal of weaponry and military vehicles, such as tanks and Aircraft, to get the advantage over your opponent.</p>
<p>Hazard Operations has players split off into rival teams. They have to take on AI-controlled mercenaries and Royal Guards, and random events happen across the map to allow the teams to gain an advantage. There are two maps for players to explore and various PvE challenges to overcome to reign victorious.</p>
<p>The latest iteration of the Delta Force franchise is still in relatively early stages of development. For those interested, the game will be available on PC, Console, and Mobile. Not only will there be a variety of multiplayer activities to participate in, but there will also be a high-intensity single-player and co-op campaign that you can play through if you're looking to get more of a story fix to your game. The campaign is inspired by the 2001 Ridley Scott movie Black Hawk Down.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus Datamine Teases Wild Bunch Of Crossover Stages]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mutliversus-datamine-powerpuff-barbie-harry-potter-1851603498</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-datamine-teases-wild-bunch-of-crossover-stages.935622/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/mutliversus-datamine-powerpuff-barbie-harry-potter-1851603498<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="793ad223cc1f58b19a420cfd242ff4f5" data-recommend-id="image://793ad223cc1f58b19a420cfd242ff4f5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Barbie sits at her vanity inside her dreamhouse" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Barbie sits at her vanity inside her dreamhouse" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Warner Bros.</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="793ad223cc1f58b19a420cfd242ff4f5" data-recommend-id="image://793ad223cc1f58b19a420cfd242ff4f5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Barbie sits at her vanity inside her dreamhouse" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.google.com//search?udm=14&amp;q=kotaku+mutliversus&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.google.com//search?udm=14&amp;q=kotaku+mutliversus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>MultiVersus</em></a></span>, the platform fighter that brings characters from Warner Bros. properties together in the field of combat, just got a big update, and dataminers have used it to learn even more about what’s to come. The latest datamine has unearthed stages based on <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/best-barbie-games-pc-retro-video-games-greta-gerwig-1850714926&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/best-barbie-games-pc-retro-video-games-greta-gerwig-1850714926"><em>Barbie</em></a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hogwarts-legacy-review-harry-potter-rowling-transphobia-1850127849&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hogwarts-legacy-review-harry-potter-rowling-transphobia-1850127849"><em>Harry Potter</em></a></span>, and even some unannounced fighters. That’s on top of the newly released Samurai Jack and the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/evo-2024-guilty-gear-lucy-cyberpunk-tekken-8-heihachi-1851601248&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/evo-2024-guilty-gear-lucy-cyberpunk-tekken-8-heihachi-1851601248">official reveal</a></span> that Beetlejuice will be coming later this season.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196923" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="355" data-playlist="196923,196922,196918" data-current="196923"><div><p>Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22494.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The datamine, posted on X (formerly Twitter) by user <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@AusilMV</a></span>, has a wealth of information on what to expect in <em>MultiVersus</em>’s future. First up is the lineup of new fighters set to come at some point. That includes the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815780822080794744&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815780822080794744" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Powerpuff Girls</a></span>, who were previously spotted in a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/powerpuff-girls-multiversus-revealed-leak-joker-trailer-1851472871&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/powerpuff-girls-multiversus-revealed-leak-joker-trailer-1851472871">May trailer</a></span> for <em>MultiVersus</em>. The trio will likely be one fighter slot that you can swap between during combat, each with their own unique attacks. The datamine also teased <em>Adventure Time</em>’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815781343889899559&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815781343889899559" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Marceline</a></span>, who appears to have a big vampire transformation form, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815780738706329909&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815780738706329909" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nubia</a></span> from DC Comics. </p><p>A bunch of new stages were also revealed, though some are much further along than others. More than one <em>Adventure Time</em> stage in the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815783189597614284&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815783189597614284" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Candy Kingdom</a></span> was discovered, as well as a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815831816986845530&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815831816986845530" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Powerpuff Girls</em> stage</a></span> I would imagine will release alongside the new fighter. A stage modeled after <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815821132651548714&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815821132651548714" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Barbie’s dreamhouse</a></span> from the 2023 film, as well as a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815827879361487036&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815827879361487036" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">quidditch-themed</a></span> stage, and a very early version of what appears to be a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815829143084261766&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815829143084261766" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Mad Max</em></a></span> stage also appear in the datamine. </p><p><em>MultiVersus’ </em>second season is currently live and has already brought Samurai Jack to the roster. The recent datamine teases even more Jack-related content coming to the game in the future, including a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815817885358694675&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815817885358694675" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">stage</a></span> that will transition between two different versions of itself during fights. There will also be a bunch of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815780626336718916&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815780626336718916" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">skins for Jack</a></span>, with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815780628522029212&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815780628522029212" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one</a></span> making the samurai look like Beetlejuice with his signature green hair and striped attire. In fact, an entire Beetlejuice-themed event looks like it’ll soon come to <em>MutliVersus</em> to tie into the new movie, with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815782308122685553&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/AusilMV/status/1815782308122685553" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">art</a></span> for the event showing more characters getting a Beetlejuice makeover.</p><p>Just this week it was <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/warner-bros-games-multiversus-player-first-games-acquisition&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warner-bros-games-multiversus-player-first-games-acquisition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">announced</a></span> that Player First Games, the developer of <em>MultiVersus</em>, has been acquired by Warner Bros. Games. For now it seems the studio will continue to operate the game as usual.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gran Turismo 7 Update Brings New Cars And Updated Physics]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-7-update-brings-new-cars-and-updated-physics/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gran-turismo-7-update-brings-new-cars-and-updated-physics.935619/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-7-update-brings-new-cars-and-updated-physics/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Sony <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/07/24/gran-turismo-7-update-1-49-brings-six-new-cars-updated-physics-simulation-model-and-more-on-july-24/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">has announced the next</a> Gran Turismo 7 update for all players, and it includes a number of new cars along with changes to the game’s physics model. </p>



<p>Starting with the new cars, six new vehicles are coming to the game. In a mix of old and new, Gran Turismo 7 will see the following cars added:</p>



<ul>
<li>BMW M3 ’97</li>



<li>Ferrari 430 Scuderia ’07</li>



<li>Genesis X Gran Racer Vision Gran Turismo Concept</li>



<li>Lamborghini Gallardo LP 560-4 ‘08</li>



<li>RUF RGT 4.2 ‘16</li>



<li>Subaru Impreza Rally Car ‘98</li>
</ul>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Gran Turismo 7 - July 1.49 Update | PS5 and PS VR2 Games" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sN3Qq25ODFc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Moving on to the physics model, Sony says it’s a “major update” to the system for the game.</p>



<p>“This update mainly affects the suspension physics model and tire physical calculation model resulting in much more natural weight shifting during cornering,” Sony said. “Tire response has also been improved, along with more realistic tire heating and wear. Look forward to more dynamic car movement and a further polished driving feel.”</p>



<p>Other updates to Gran Turismo 7 include new menus in the GT Cafe, new World Circuits, Pokal wheel brand to GT Auto, and new AI agent named Gran Turismo Sophy.</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the new cars and the physics model update coming to Gran Turismo 7? For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-is-coming-to-xbox-game-pass-on-august-8-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the next Activision game set to come to Xbox Game Pass</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rise of the Ronin demo now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/rise-of-the-ronin-demo-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rise-of-the-ronin-demo-now-available.935616/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/rise-of-the-ronin-demo-now-available<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Plus various player data shared.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>A free demo for <em><a title="Games > Rise of the Ronin [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/rise-of-the-ronin">Rise of the Ronin</a></em> is now available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,509 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP9000-PPSA04539_00-RONINDEMO0000000" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Store</a>, publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,859 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Team NINJA [632 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games/team-ninja">Team NINJA</a> <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/07/24/explore-the-top-choices-in-rise-of-the-ronin/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-901100"></span></p><p>The demo features the first chapter of the game’s story, and save data can be carried over to the full game if you decide to purchase it.</p><p>Team NINJA also shared various player data collected since the game’s March 22 launch:</p><ul><li><strong>Story Choices</strong><ul><li><strong>Gonzo</strong><ul><li>35 percent of players killed Gonzo</li><li>65 percent of players spared Gonzo</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </li><li><strong>Faction Siding</strong><ul><li>62 percent of players sided with the Shogunate</li><li>38 percent of players sided with the Anti-Shogunate</li></ul></li></ul></li><li><strong>Forging Your <a title="Series > Fate [62 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">Fate</a></strong><ul><li>42 percent of players achieved Level 4 personal bonds</li><li>30 percent of players started romances</li></ul></li><li><strong>Combat</strong><ul><li>1,9235,232,468 countersparks were performed</li></ul></li><li><strong>Difficulty</strong><ul><li>36 percent of players selected “Dawn” difficulty</li><li>51 percent of players selected “Dusk” difficulty</li><li>13 percent of players selected “Twilight” difficulty</li><li>18 percent of players selected “Midnight” difficulty</li></ul></li><li><strong>World Exploration</strong><ul><li>16 percent of players collected all 100 cats</li><li>35 percent of players defeated all 50 fugitives</li></ul></li></ul><p><em>Rise of the Ronin</em> is available now for PlayStation 5.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Player Achievements</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Rise of the Ronin - Player Achievements | PS5 Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ycT1cQlmowA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『Rise of the Ronin』プレイヤーデータハイライト" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G_18Hj0KKnE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom's Latest Shareholder Q&A Is a Terrifying Indictment of Capitalism]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/capcom-shareholder-qa</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcoms-latest-shareholder-q-a-is-a-terrifying-indictment-of-capitalism.935580/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/capcom-shareholder-qa<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Capcom has released its latest shareholder Q&amp;A summary, and while some of the questions asked by shareholders are perfectly sane and sensible, there are some that truly beggar belief.</p>
<p>The summary&nbsp;gives Capcom shareholders a chance to ask the company pertinent questions about its operations, and if you ask me, some of those questions truly demonstrate that some Capcom shareholders don't appear to know the first thing about video games or how they're made.</p>
<p>One shareholder, for instance, asks Capcom whether it wouldn't be more prudent, from a profit perspective, to bump the release date of&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>up from 2025 to "the December 2024 holiday season". Why didn't every other studio ever think of that?</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-capcom-shareholder-qa-slope.jpg?itok=CundxPcY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/monster-hunter-wilds-capcom-shareholder-qa-slope.jpg?itok=1zsQ8zqk 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>A Capcom shareholder wants to know why Capcom doesn't just release&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>earlier. Genius!</figcaption></figure><p>The studio's response is characteristically patient. Capcom simply says that it will announce&nbsp;<em>Wilds</em>' release date "<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/monster-hunter-wilds-summer-capcom">once preparations are complete</a>" and reiterates the studio's commitment to a goal of 10% or better profit growth each year.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, another shareholder asks whether the gaming giant has thought about engaging in a share buyback scheme in order to ensure "the current share price is appropriate" and that share prices aren't "simply left to the market".</p>
<p>Capcom's response to this question is fairly stock; it says that it typically engages in share buyback schemes and the like "after comprehensively considering several factors". Given the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-layoffs-share-buyback">state of the industry right now</a>, I can't say I'm particularly sad Capcom doesn't seem to have any plans in this direction.</p>
<p>One shareholder asks Capcom about whether&nbsp;<em>Monster Hunter Wilds&nbsp;</em>will be limited to "non-portable consoles", which is, on the surface, a reference to the Switch, but which could also be read as an attempt to perhaps tease some information out regarding the Switch's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-announcement-confirmation">much-talked-about successor</a>. No such luck, sadly.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/mega-man-11-capcom-shareholder-qa.jpg?itok=yv4g3OeI 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/mega-man-11-capcom-shareholder-qa.jpg?itok=T98Tl-vn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Capcom says it's "considering" how to make more&nbsp;<em>Mega Man&nbsp;</em>games.</figcaption></figure><p>Some shareholders have some pretty pertinent questions for Capcom. One asks about what's in the pipeline for&nbsp;<em>Mega Man</em>, for instance, to which the studio responds that it is "considering how to create games" for the franchise.</p>
<p>Another wonders why Capcom hasn't made a cozy game yet, and while I can't say I'm personally sad about this, I can't deny there would be a significant market for it. Who doesn't want to chill with a cute Palico in Raccoon City?</p>
<p>It's worth reading the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.capcom.co.jp/ir/english/assets/pdf/stock/2024capcom_d.pdf" rel="noopener" target="_blank">full shareholder Q&amp;A</a> if you want to see what kind of issues the shareholders hold close to their hearts, and also if you want to know why shareholders probably shouldn't be allowed any kind of creative control over games.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team FOLON tease Fallout: London’s Release]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/team-folon-tease-fallout-londons-release/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/team-folon-tease-fallout-london%E2%80%99s-release.935574/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/team-folon-tease-fallout-londons-release/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Just over a year ago, Team FOLON uploaded a video of the song "I Just Can't Wait (For Tomorrow)" to their YouTube channel, which will be heard on the Fallout: London radio in-game. As of today, the developers behind the expansive mod posted this song on their Discord server, which is home to over 50,000 members with only a handful of moderators to take care of the entire server.</p>
<p>Since they posted this, fans are excitedly waiting for the release of Fallout: London, which is expected to be released tomorrow, as the song suggests. However, they have not officially confirmed a date, so this is speculation.</p>
<p>The Fallout: London mod is a complete overhaul of Fallout 4, allowing players to explore a brand-new universe in a familiar game. The mod is hosted by GOG.com, and players can access it from the GOG mod launcher. This mod takes players through many different boroughs of London, each with unique traits and aesthetics.</p>
<p>The mod introduces some very well-known voices to breathe life into the characters of the mod, such as Neil Newbon from Baldur's Gate 3, Colin Baker from Doctor Who, and John Bercow, who was Speaker of the House of Commons from 2009 to 2019, and is now reprising his role as a Speaker in Fallout: London.</p>
<p>With the release of the next-gen update for Fallout 4, players who have purchased the game through the Epic Games Store <a href="https://wccftech.com/gog-confirms-fallout-london-wont-be-playable-through-epic-games-store-versions-of-fallout-4/">can no longer access</a> the mod unless it is purchased directly through Steam or the GOG.com store. This is because players must be able to roll back the Next Gen update, which resulted in Team FOLON having to redo the coding for the mod entirely, as it isn't compatible with the Next Gen update. However, the current version of the mod is compatible with the game pre-update. As it stands, Team FOLON is working on a version of the mod that will be compatible with the Next Gen update, but it may take a while for that to be realized, as they found out at the very last second about the update being released.</p>
<p>Per <a href="https://fallout4london.com/faq/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the FAQ</a> listed on the official Fallout: London website, players must make a new save entirely to explore the mod in full, as pre-existing quests that players will have completed in their previous save can cause issues with the mod.</p>
<p>If the Fallout: London Discord post is true, it means that the full release of Fallout: London is just around the corner for excited players to get stuck into.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Testing Three New Neat Features On PS5 After Latest Update]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/sony-testing-three-new-neat-features-on-ps5-after-lates-1851603451</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-testing-three-new-neat-features-on-ps5-after-latest-update.935568/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/sony-testing-three-new-neat-features-on-ps5-after-lates-1851603451<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="f498d5e10bbd4d2b98454a7b3bcb25af" data-recommend-id="image://f498d5e10bbd4d2b98454a7b3bcb25af" data-format="jpg" data-width="1315" data-height="740" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A PlayStation controller floats in space. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A PlayStation controller floats in space. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sony</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f498d5e10bbd4d2b98454a7b3bcb25af" data-recommend-id="image://f498d5e10bbd4d2b98454a7b3bcb25af" data-format="jpg" data-width="1315" data-height="740" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A PlayStation controller floats in space. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>As the PlayStation 5 nears its four-year anniversary, the platform team at Sony is continuing to cook up small new improvements to help players get the most out of the console. The latest batch of changes we’ll soon get to test are hyper-niche, but still pretty cool. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196181" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="196181,196230,193348" data-current="196181"><div><p>The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21718.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The first new feature, going into early beta access starting July 25, is D audio profiles for headphones and earbuds. Instead of needing to tweak the settings each time, the console will let players save custom settings based on what sounds best to them and for certain games. Maybe you want a different set of tweaks when you’re playing a multiplayer shooter versus a moody horror game. </p><p>“For example, your personalized 3D audio profile may enable you to better sense the positions of characters and objects in a game world more clearly than before, making the experience more immersive,” Sony’s VP of product management, Hiromi Wakai, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://blog.playstation.com/2024/07/24/new-ps5-beta-rolls-out-tomorrow-with-personalized-3d-audio-profiles-and-new-remote-play-settings/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/07/24/new-ps5-beta-rolls-out-tomorrow-with-personalized-3d-audio-profiles-and-new-remote-play-settings/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote</a></span> on the PlayStation Blog today.</p><p>Custom Remote Play settings are also going into testing. This will let players authorize which friend-and-family member accounts have authorization to access their console for streaming to their phones, laptops, or PlayStation Portals. I’m now tempted to see how well I can play games on my buddy’s console five miles away. Both of these new settings options are available on all PS5 models. </p><p>What Sony is calling adaptive charging for DualSense controllers and other peripherals, however, is only available on the new slim PS5 models released last year. This feature will save power by only charging your connected controller when its battery is low, rather than keeping the USB ports powered on even when the devices are fully juiced. </p><p>While most users will have to wait until these features go live in an official update to try them, everyone will get to play around with the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.playstation.com/en-us/support/hardware/ps5/system-software-info/?smcid=pdc:us-en:plays923:default&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/support/hardware/ps5/system-software-info/?smcid=pdc:us-en:plays923:default" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PS5's latest firmware version out today</a></span>. Players can now ask their consoles to show them game help for a game rather than needing to find it on the home screen. They can also share links to their game sessions with QR codes. I can’t wait to invite everyone I know to play <em>Foamstars</em> with me. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 Beta Rolls Out tomorrow with Personalized 3D Audio, New Remote Play Settings, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ps5-beta-rolls-out-tomorrow-with-personalized-3d-audio-new-remote-play-settings-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-beta-rolls-out-tomorrow-with-personalized-3d-audio-new-remote-play-settings-and-more.935565/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/ps5-beta-rolls-out-tomorrow-with-personalized-3d-audio-new-remote-play-settings-and-more/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Sony Interactive Entertainment has announced a beta test for the PlayStation 5, enabling players to access new features such as personalized 3D audio profiles, remote play settings, and adaptive charging for their controllers. Learn more about these features and how to sign up for the PS5 beta below.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Enrolling in the PS5 beta is an exclusive opportunity. It will only be available for invited participants in select countries and will be released globally shortly. The players who are selected for the beta will receive an email invitation on July 25. However, some features showcased during the beta test may not make the Final Cut.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-personalized-3d-audio-profiles">Personalized 3D Audio Profiles</h2>



<p>This new feature allows players to create a personalized 3D audio profile for headphones and earbuds. Players invited to the PS5 beta can run sound quality tests to analyze many factors to create an audio profile that best suits their hearing characteristics. For example, players will have a “better sense of the positions of characters and objects in a game world more clearly than before,” which helps enhance immersion.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>To access this feature, players must go to Settings, Sound, and 3D Audio headphones on the PS5 console. Then, follow the steps on the screen to create and save their audio profile. Players can create one audio profile per user and also select from the 3D Audio presets if they wish to.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-remote-play-settings">Remote Play Settings</h2>



<p>The PS5 Beta also adds new Remote Play settings per user, allowing them to choose individuals to connect to their console through this feature. To access the features, head to Settings, System, Remote Play, and Enable Remote Play. Here, you can choose which users you want to enable access to.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-adaptive-charging-for-ps5-controllers">Adaptive Charging for PS5 Controllers</h2>



<p>Players should know that this feature is only available for the beta testers using the latest PS5 console, which comes with a detachable disc drive. Adaptive charging for DualSense wireless controller, DualSense Edge wireless controller, PlayStation VR2 Sense controllers, and Access controller players can save power “by adjusting the time that power is supplied to your controller based on its battery level”.</p>



<p>This saves power and contributes to a more eco-friendly gaming experience. Players must enable this feature through the Features Available in Rest Mode menu and change the Supply Power to USB ports as Adaptive.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>In other news, the latest PS5 firmware update added a ‘<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-5-adds-a-share-link-feature-with-the-latest-firmware-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Share Link</a>’ feature. Also, players recently saw some of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/no-mans-sky-ps5-pro-upgrade-details-revealed-through-datamine/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">No Man’s Sky</a>’s PS5 Pro upgrade features through a datamine. What are your views on the PS5 Beta features? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shift-up-job-listings-hint-at-possible-pc-port-future-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">job listings at Shift Up</a>,&nbsp;possibly reinforcing that a Stellar Blade PC port is coming, and sign up to receive the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: Bleach Rebirth of Souls Producer on Why It Will Be More Than Another Run-of-the-Mill Anime Fighter]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-producer-says-game-wont-be-another-run-of-the-mill-anime-fighter</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-bleach-rebirth-of-souls-producer-on-why-it-will-be-more-than-another-run-of-the-mill-anime-fighter.935559/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-producer-says-game-wont-be-another-run-of-the-mill-anime-fighter<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>During Anime Expo 2024, Bandai Namco shocked fans by announcing a brand new 3D fighting game, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-new-bandai-namco-fighting-game-trailer-anime-expo"><u>Bleach Rebirth of Souls</u></a>. Much like Bandai Namco’s other hotly-anticipated anime fighter, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-hands-off-preview-and-new-details-revealed-at-gamescom-latam"><u>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero</u></a>, it's been well over a decade since we’ve last seen a Bleach game, and expectations for it are understandably at an all-time high.  </p><p>Piggybacking off Bleach Rebirth of Soul’s newly released gameplay trailer, which saw a recreation of Ichigo Kurosaki’s battle against Byakuya Kuchiki, IGN spoke with producer Katsuaki Tsuzuki about how the game will differentiate itself from other titles in the series and what players can expect out of its swordplay-centric combat once it releases on PS4, PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and Steam.</p><p>Anime arena fighters have a track record of having a short shelf life in players' minds, in part because their gameplay <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/anime-deserves-more-than-run-of-the-mill-arena-fighters"><u>tends to lack depth</u></a> beyond the bread-and-butter strategies that are sussed out within the honeymoon period of their release. Tsuzuki says Rebirth of Souls will distinguish itself from the pack by incorporating the anime’s intricate power systems into the DNA of its gameplay, resulting in an enthralling ebb and flow of mechanically-rich battles. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>“While developing the game as a fighting action game, we delved into details from Bleach like reishi, konpaku, spiritual power, and spiritual pressure. After looking into that, we were surprised by how the worldview had been created in detail and how well those features aligned with our game concept and the fighting action genre," Tsuzuki said.</p><p>"For example, konpaku, which represents the concept of the soul in Bleach, is constructed with reishi. Drawing inspiration from that concept, we set reishi as a health gauge in the game, and players can break the konpaku to decrease reishi," he added." We introduced systems that allow players to experience reversals such as breaking konpaku with a single strike or enhancing power through transformations to facilitate breaks.” </p><p>In action game layman's terms, Rebirth of Soul’s combat is like a pastiche Sekiro’s stagger swordplay, Tekken 7 reversals, and Smash Bros. Ultimate’s stock health bar system, wherein players win battles by destroying an opponent’s 9 stocks or konpaku. Although Tsuzuki referred to established action games like the Naruto Ultimate Ninja Storm games, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/jojos-bizarre-adventure-all-star-battle-r-review">JoJo’s Bizarre Adventure: All-Star Battle R</a>, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/06/02/tekken-7-review">Tekken 7</a>, and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/01/22/dragon-ball-fighterz-review">Dragon Ball FighterZ</a> when making Rebirth of Souls, Rebirth of Souls feel authentically Bleach to fans new and old.</p><p>"I know that Bleach is loved by fans worldwide, so I have been eager for the opportunity to work with this IP," Tsuzuki says. "We know that there is strong enthusiasm from Bleach fans, and I wanted to develop a new Bleach game for modern high-spec platforms, especially since it is also around the timing of the 20th anniversary of Bleach."</p><h2>A balanced shonen fighting game</h2><p>Arguably the most difficult challenge in making Rebirth of Souls was integrating major tenets of the anime’s unique power systems. While Rebirth of Souls’ naming conventions may prove intimidating to prospective players on first blush, Tsuzuki stressed that players won’t be required to have an overfamiliarity with Bleach’s encyclopedic power structure to enjoy the game and eke out a victory. Rebirth of Souls will also come with a comprehensive in-game play guide, tutorials, and a user-friendly battle UI to make it easy to understand, akin to standard action games to ensure first-time players aren’t lost in the sauce of Bleach’s unique flavor of shonen anime power schemes.  </p><p>In contrast to Sparking! Zero, whose producer hinted that the game would reflect the <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/fighting/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-is-delightfully-unbalanced-and-definitely-not-an-esports-game-so-the-devs-had-to-find-a-unique-approach-to-ranked-online/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>anime ensemble’s power scaling with unbalanced battles</u></a>, Rebirth of Souls characters were designed to have an equal win rate with another. </p><p>“Our game concept revolves around the reversal experience and each character is really unique, especially their zanpakuto [the weapons wielded by Bleach's Shinigami], which offers multifaceted abilities,” Tsuzuki said. “Each character retains distinct features: some characters excel in speed, while others focus on heavy power, and some are good at attacking from distance. </p><p>“Additionally, each character can enhance their abilities through Awakening. In that regard, some characters are easy to handle, even for casual gamers, while others cater more [to] core action gamers,” Tsuzuki added. “However, every character has the chance to reverse the situation, ensuring that all have an equal chance to win.”</p><p>Historically, Bleach has been noticeably out of the gaming zeitgeist in comparison to its fellow “big three” shonen contemporaries, Naruto and One Piece. As mentioned earlier, it's been 13 years since Bleach characters have graced a video game—that is if you don’t count their appearance in 2019’s anime Oscars-esque arena fighter, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/02/14/jump-force-review"><u>Jump Force</u></a>. The last fully-fledged Bleach game was <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2011/07/28/bleach-soul-resurreccion-review"><u>Bleach: Soul Resurrección</u></a> for the PlayStation 3. Bleach: Soul Resurreccion received <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2011/07/28/bleach-soul-resurreccion-review"><u>middling reviews from critics including our own</u></a>, where we said the game had a simple yet enjoyable Dynasty Warriors-esque combat system that players wouldn’t be missing out on if they passed it up.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Bleach: Rebirth of Souls - Announcement Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>As far as the “big three” are concerned time hasn’t slowed down their output of games with recently released titles like <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/naruto-x-boruto-ultimate-ninja-storm-connections-review"><u>Naruto x Boruto Ultimate Ninja Storm Connections</u></a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/one-piece-odyssey-review"><u>One Piece: Odyssey </u></a>— a classic turn-based action RPG that Tsuzuki produced. When approaching Bleach Rebirth of Souls, Tsuzuki said the upcoming anime action game will be an exception to the trend of anime action games by having a combat system that is as complex as its beautifully rendered 3D models.</p><p>“Each of the previous Bleach games published by the other companies have different features and all of them capture the charm of Bleach. The development team played these games before starting the development of Bleach Rebirth of Souls and really enjoyed them. We learned the core features of Bleach like bankai, and integrated them into the necessary components of an action game,” Tsuzuki said. “Thanks to the capabilities of new-generation platforms, we tried to create a Bleach game that delivers cutting-edge visual expression in battle.”</p><p>Although Bleach has one of the largest casts of characters in shonen anime with more personalities and power sets being introduced in <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bleach-thousand-year-blood-war-part-3-will-air-in-october-2024">Bleach: Thousand Year Blood War, </a>— the anime's sequel series which adapts the manga's final arc — Rebirth of Souls will only feature characters from the anime’s first two story arcs, Soul Reaper and Arrancar arc. </p><p>“This is the first Bleach game that Bandai as a company is introducing and it's been a while since the last game was introduced so we thought that it would be great to introduce these characters from the original [arc] to the Arrancar time period and introduce the history of these characters, how they met, and how battles have taken place,” Tsuzuki said. </p><p>Fans can look forward to more updates like Rebirth of Souls playable character roster in the future as the game inches closer to its yet-to-be-announced release date.</p><p><em>Isaiah Colbert is a freelance writer for IGN. You can follow them on Twitter @ShinEyeZehUhh</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree’s Only Accessibility Option Is Its Fantastic Open World]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtrees-only-accessibility-option-is-its-fantastic-open-world</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree%E2%80%99s-only-accessibility-option-is-its-fantastic-open-world.935556/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtrees-only-accessibility-option-is-its-fantastic-open-world<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>It’s been two years since I traversed The Lands Between. Two years since I became Elden Lord. Two years since I beat a game that I now consider one of my top 10 favorite games of all time. And now, with Shadow of the Erdtree, I’m once again reminded why Elden Ring is a masterpiece, despite some accessibility flaws.</p><p>For this Access Designed, I’m going to talk about how Shadow of the Erdtree is nothing short of incredible – it’s more of the same game that left me in awe of its combat, open world, and inclusive design. Yet, despite following the same formula of vast landscapes dotted with optional, difficult content, nothing substantial is brought forth to increase FromSoftware’s latest title’s accessibility.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/02/21/eldenringthumb-1708528702214.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>The open world structure of Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree, while not explicity an accessibility feature, is nontheless a good example of inclusive design.</figcaption></figure></output><h2>Exploration and Discovery</h2><p>Shadow of the Erdtree’s introduction immediately transports players to the Land of Shadow, an area that rivals Limgrave in its size. It’s an understatement to say that it’s massive and occasionally overwhelming with direction and choice. As is common with the Eden Ring base game, players are given no guidance on where to go. A glowing white castle that leads to a giant divine lion puppet, a castle that mirrors the Raya Lucaria Academy, and empty fields filled with huge dead birds and a giant flaming golem are immediately present, and it’s up to you to decide what you want to tackle first. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>For physically disabled players that struggle with fatigue, it’s entirely possible to save a troublesome boss for later or even skip it altogether. </p></div><p>Naturally, I ignored all of these and traveled into a pleasant forest where a naked man named Logur, the Beast Claw killed me 10 times over. Rather than give up and move to a different section, I stubbornly fought Logur until I defeated him, claiming his Beast Claw weapon as my prize. This was my first foray into Shadow of the Erdtree.</p><p>Do I recommend this path? Absolutely not, unless you want to try the new Beast Claw weapon type. However, my questionable decision demonstrates one of the best inclusive design practices of Elden Ring – optional content. Much like the base game, players are not required to fight many of the bosses. For physically disabled players that struggle with fatigue, it’s entirely possible to save a troublesome boss for later or even skip it altogether. While classic Elden Ring accessibility mechanics like summoning spirits and other players are available, many of the enemy encounters are brutal, especially when players refuse to explore and rush to progress the game.</p><h2>The Difficulty Question</h2><p>Shadow of the Erdtree is immensely tough at first, so much so that the award-winning game received mixed reviews on Steam because of the drastic spike in difficulty above that experienced in the base game. And, in true FromSoftware fashion, the game doesn’t explicitly tell you how to mitigate this jump in challenge – you need to explore to learn how. I praise Elden Ring’s exploration as a crucial accessible tool, and the DLC is no different. Yet while the design practice can ultimately be viewed as optional in the base game, it’s a mandatory requirement for the expansion. You <em>need </em>to explore. You <em>need </em>to discover items that boost you over the game’s difficulty spike.</p><p>Dotted around the massive map are Scadutree Fragments and Revered Spirit Ashes, two key items that act as Shadow of the Erdtree's new leveling system, called the Shadow Realm Blessing. While you are within the Land of Shadow, your traditional rune level does little, if anything, to provide buffs for combat. Instead, you must use Scadutree Fragments to boost your stats, and Revered Spirit Ashes to bolster the offenses and defenses of your spirit summons. While it’s entirely possible to beat the expansion without ever using these, nobody should ever follow this method unless they're a masochist. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/24/divine-beast-dancing-lion-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-1721834616491.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>The Divine Beast Dancing Lion is a strong and fast boss that poses a big challenge.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Prior to discovering any Fragments or Ashes, I attempted to fight the Divine Beast Dancing Lion using my magic build that could obliterate most base game bosses in under 10 seconds. After around 15 tries, the closest I came to defeating this optional boss was by bringing its health bar down to one third. My spells did pitiful damage, and my summons did nothing more than boost the Lion’s already-inflated health bar. So I left. I explored until I discovered a significant number of Fragments and Ashes, and only returned after significantly increasing by Shadow Realm Blessing levels. And while the Blessing's enhancements didn't allow my magic build to melt the Lion like it had done bosses prior, the boost to my damage, defenses, and my summon’s stats was incredibly noticeable. It allowed me to survive long enough to finally defeat the beast. The overall boss mechanics may have still mirrored the base game – I sat at the back and fired off spells while my summons distracted the boss – but I needed to explore and find specific items before succeeding.</p><h2>No New Accessibility</h2><p>Despite being a new expansion to a two-year-old game, Shadow of the Erdtree does little to increase Elden Ring’s overall accessibility. While there are new weapons, armors, spells, and talismans that you can discover that lead to new accessible playstyles, no new accessibility-focused options were added. Blind and low vision players still have nothing to assist with combat or exploration, Deaf and hard of hearing players have no new environmental subtitles or visual cues, and cognitively disabled players still need to heavily rely on extensive memorization and pattern recognition. For me, a physically disabled player, Elden Ring and its expansion are near flawless for my needs. Yet, as I continuously say, the disabled experience is incredibly vast and individualistic, meaning the inclusive designs and options like customizable controls that I regularly praise may not be enough for others.</p><p>It’s difficult to review Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree from an accessibility perspective. My thoughts remain the same from two years ago: it was my game of the year in 2022, and this expansion reignites those same feelings. However, it’s admittedly disappointing to see FromSoftware continue to fail to implement accessible tools beyond inclusive designs. Is this DLC accessible? If it wasn’t accessible for you two years ago, I can confidently say this expansion will leave you feeling disappointed. If you found the game to perfectly suit your accessible needs before, then I encourage you to once again lead your Tarnished into unexplored territories. Just be sure to search for Scadutree Fragments and Revered Spirit Ashes.</p><p><em>Grant Stoner is a disabled journalist covering accessibility and the disabled perspective in video games. When not writing, he is usually screaming about Pokémon or his cat, Goomba on </em><a href="https://x.com/Super_Crip1994" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Twitter</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[X-Men's 35-Year History of Games That Are Wildly Hit and Miss]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/x-mens-35-year-history-of-games-that-are-wildly-hit-and-miss</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/x-mens-35-year-history-of-games-that-are-wildly-hit-and-miss.935550/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/x-mens-35-year-history-of-games-that-are-wildly-hit-and-miss<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The X-Men may be one of the biggest superhero franchises in the world, but these mutant freedom fighters haven’t always had the best track record when it comes to video games. X-fans the world over are still feeling the sting of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2011/10/01/x-men-destiny-review">the massive disappointment that was 2011’s X-Men: Destiny</a>. But that’s not to say there haven’t been some truly excellent Marvel games over the years that have prominently featured Marvel’s merry mutants. And with Hugh Jackman’s Logan finally making his MCU debut in Deadpool &amp; Wolverine, there’s no better time to celebrate that gaming legacy. </p><p>From early winners like X-Men: The Arcade Game and X-Men: Children of the Atom to the fan-favorite X-Men Legends series, here’s a look back at the X-Men games that have captured what we love about these colorful yet tragic heroes.</p><h2>The Early X-Men Games</h2><p>By the beginning of the 1980s, the X-Men had risen from forgotten C-List Marvel team to arguably the biggest franchise in comics. Heroes like Wolverine, Storm and Cyclops became as recognizable to comics fans as Batman and Spider-Man. But despite this explosive growth, Marvel was surprisingly slow to capitalize on the X-Men’s newfound popularity outside the comics themselves. Only at the end of the decade did the X-Men begin dipping their toes into the gaming waters.</p><p>1989’s Uncanny X-Men for the NES has the distinction of being the very first X-Men game… and not much else. The game allowed players to take control of a wide variety of mutant heroes in a top-down action-adventure setting. However, it proved to be punishingly difficult, to say nothing of the fact that the final level is only accessible by a secret code. Uncanny X-Men is often lumped in among the worst NES games of all time. Not an auspicious start for the X-Men’s gaming career.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/24/nes-wolverine-1684956720483-1721789916073.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image Credit: TheCoverProject.net</figcaption></figure></output><p>1991’s Wolverine wasn’t much better. That game proved to be a somewhat more traditional side-scroller, pitting Logan against his nemeses Sabretooth and Magneto. But any game that revolves around Logan scarfing down hamburgers to unsheathe his claws like some sort of bloodthirsty J. Wellington Wimpy has missed the mark. </p><p>Both Wolverine and Uncanny X-Men struggled with a problem that’s hounded superhero games over the years. How do you properly represent the X-Men’s powers in an interactive setting? How do you allow Wolverine to unleash his berserker fury and incredible healing without tying those powers to limited energy meters and punishing players for using them too often? It would be a long time before developers truly overcame that hurdle.    </p><h2>Welcome to Die: The X-Men Hit the Arcade</h2><p>It fell on Konami to give Marvel fans their first great X-Men gaming experience. 1992’s X-Men followed the same side-scrolling beat-em-up formula that made Konami’s Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles and Simpsons arcade games such a blast. But X-Men had an extra trick up its sleeve, cramming in a double-wide monitor and no fewer than six sets of joysticks so that gamers could team up and control the full team - Wolverine, Colossus, Storm, Nightcrawler, Cyclops and Dazzler - simultaneously.</p><p>X-Men didn’t necessarily reinvent the arcade brawler wheel. Like its many brethren, the goal was simply to move from left to right, pummeling wave after wave of Sentinels, Reavers and other foes until making it to the boss battle. And like many X-Men games, it penalized players for using the X-Men’s mutant powers by tying them to the characters’ health meters. But with its large, colorful sprites and its deep roster of X-Men villains (including Magneto, Pyro, Mystique and The Blob), the game scratched that comic book itch. And who could forget Magneto’s most iconic catchphrase - “Welcome to Die!!!”?</p><p>Sadly, unlike TMNT, X-Men never got a sequel of any kind. It probably didn’t help that the game was based on the short-lived Pryde of the X-Men cartoon, hitting the same year X-Men: The Animated Series catapulted the franchise in a much different and more successful direction. But the silver lining is that X-Men ‘97 recently paid homage to the arcade game with the episode “Motendo.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2>The X-Men Get Their Genesis On   </h2><p>The X-Men may have found success in the arcade, but their track record on home consoles remained pretty spotty in the early ‘90s. No matter which version of 1992’s Spider-Man/X-Men: Arcade’s Revenge you played, the experience was pretty underwhelming.</p><p>1993’s X-Men on the Sega Genesis proved to be the first ray of light on the horizon. While not a huge departure from past X-Men games, the vibrant graphics and stylized music were a definite step up, taking full advantage of the newfound power the Genesis brought to the table. Some of the old flaws remained, however. This was another extremely difficult action platformer, and the various mutant powers, be they Wolverine’s claws or Nightcrawler’s teleportation, were tied to rapidly depleting special meters.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/24/xmen1993-1648585311013-1684956630662-1721790003410.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Fortunately, the 1995 sequel, X-Men 2: Clone Wars, improved on that formula and established itself as arguably the best of the Genesis/SNES era. Clone Wars shook things up by allowing free, unlimited use of the X-Men’s powers and offering gamers a wide cast of playable heroes whose respective powers significantly affected the gameplay. Even Magneto was playable this time around. The game also benefited from a much more robust story that drew heavily from the contemporary X-Men comics.</p><p>Not to be outdone, the SNES got one gem of an X-Men game to compete with the Genesis titles. 1994’s X-Men: Mutant Apocalypse offered its own spin on the side-scrolling action formula, benefitting from colorful graphics and a large ensemble cast of mutant heroes. Mutant Apocalypse wasn’t as brutally difficult as its peers, making for an all-around enjoyable experience and the pinnacle of X-Men gaming on home consoles up to that point. But a new hope was brewing in the arcade… </p><h2>How Capcom Cracked the Code</h2><p>If Capcom only published X-Men: Mutant Apocalypse, they’d still deserve a special place in the hearts of Marvel fans. But the publisher’s real success story came in bringing these colorful heroes back to the arcade and forging an entirely new fighting game franchise.</p><p>1994’s X-Men: Children of the Atom built on the foundation of other Capcom fighting game series like Street Fighter and Darkstalkers, but with an extra layer of over-the-top action that befits the X-Men. The game featured a wide cast of heroes and villains, each with their own playstyle and special moves. Who can forget Wolverine’s Berserker Barrage or Iceman’s Ice Boulder?</p><p>Speaking of special moves, Children of the Atom tapped into the X-Men’s mutant abilities like no game before it. As in Clone Wars, no longer did players have to worry about depleting a special meter just to slash claws or fire off an optic blast. Instead, the game hinged on a combo system where players could build up energy to unleash devastating special attacks. Finally, the X-Men played like real superheroes.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Finally, the X-Men played like real superheroes.</p></div><p>Children of the Atom was also undoubtedly the most attractive X-Men game released to date, with large, colorful sprites that instantly appealed to fans of the comics and animated series. And with many of the animated series’ iconic voice actors reprising their roles, Children of the Atom had all the nerd cred it needed to be an arcade hit.</p><p>And it was definitely a hit. Children of the Atom spawned numerous follow-ups, such as 1995’s Marvel Super Heroes and 1996’s X-Men vs. Street Fighter. That latter crossover paved the way for the even more popular Marvel vs. Capcom franchise. By the time 2000’s Marvel vs. Capcom 2 rolled around, gamers were building teams of three fighters pulled from a roster of dozens of fan-favorite characters. Who could ever have imagined we’d see Wolverine fighting alongside Jill Valentine and Mega Man? </p><p>Sadly, the Marvel vs. Capcom franchise has run out of steam in recent years, with 2017’s Marvel vs. Capcom Infinite disappointing most fans. To add insult to injury, that sequel didn’t even feature any X-Men characters. Talk about forgetting where you came from.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2>The X-Men Become Legendary</h2><p>By the time the 2000s rolled around, the X-Men had more or less found their footing in the gaming world. Fans had several decent action platformers from which to choose, as well as Capcom’s bombastic fighting games. But with home consoles rapidly growing in power and complexity, the time had come to up the ante and show players what it really felt like to don some spandex and battle the Brotherhood of Mutants.</p><p>Developer Raven Software and publisher Activision answered the call with 2004’s X-Men Legends. Legends was no mere platformer, but an isometric action RPG in the vein of Diablo. Players were allowed to build teams of four X-Men from a cast of 15 playable characters, each with their own moves and combo potential. Each character could be individually leveled and upgraded.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Not only was the gameplay deeper and the storyline more complex than any X-Men game before it, X-Men Legends also raised the bar in terms of presentation.</p></div><p>Not only was the gameplay deeper and the storyline more complex than any X-Men game before it, X-Men Legends also raised the bar in terms of presentation. The game featured a unique cel-shaded graphical style inspired by Marvel’s Ultimate X-Men comics. The voice cast included such X-Men luminaries as Patrick Stewart’s Professor X and Steve Blum’s Wolverine.  </p><p>X-Men Legends quickly spawned a sequel in 2005’s X-Men Legends II: Rise of Apocalypse. Rise of Apocalypse proved to be a textbook case of a sequel dialing everything up to 11, with more playable characters, deeper gameplay, a bigger scope, and an engrossing story that involved the X-Men teaming up with the Brotherhood of Mutants to take down the mighty Apocalypse.</p><p>Even two decades later, the X-Men Legends games are widely regarded as some of the best games ever to feature the merry mutants. And while there haven’t been any direct sequels to these two classics, they did pave the way for the Marvel: Ultimate Alliance series, which continued that trademark blend of action RPG combat and deep Marvel superhero rosters. That hasn’t stopped many X-fans from crying out for an X-Men Legends III, however. </p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><h3>X-Men: The Complete Playlist</h3><p>Here is every Marvel-licensed X-Men video game ever made.</p></div><h2>Wolverine and Deadpool’s Solo Adventures</h2><p>It’s been surprisingly quiet on the X-Men gaming front since the release of X-Men Legends II. Again, we’d bring up 2011’s X-Men: Destiny, but the less said about that game, the better. But if there’s been a real lack of ensemble X-Men games in recent years, things have been slightly rosier where Wolverine and Deadpool are concerned.</p><p>2003’s X-Men: Wolverine’s Revenge served as one reminder of how much potential Wolverine has as a video game protagonist. While ostensibly a tie-in to the movie X2: X-Men United, Wolverine’s Revenge actually took its cues from Grant Morrison’s New X-Men comics, right down to the costume design for Logan himself.   </p><p>In terms of its third-person action gameplay, Wolverine’s Revenge was a giant mixed bag. But the game still deserves credit for its comic book-inspired trappings and the fact that it features none other than Luke Skywalker himself, Mark Hamill, as the voice of Logan. Ultimately, both Wolverine’s Revenge and 2006's movie-based X-Men: The Official Game served as a loose prototype for what was to come.</p><p>Cue X-Men Origins: Wolverine, perhaps the only game that can rival X-Men Legends as the best X-game of all time. That’s a strange thing to say considering that the movie it’s based on is universally panned by superhero fans. But in this case, Origins took the best parts of the source material and ran with them. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/24/wolverine-x360-boxshot-esrb-1721790221703.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Lousy movie, great game.</figcaption></figure></output><p>In this heavily embellished take on the movie’s plot, players take control of Hugh Jackman’s Wolverine in two different time periods, as Logan both carves his way through a deadly jungle in search of adamantium in the past and singlehandedly takes on the Weapon X program in the present. The game did an admirable job of adapting God of War’s visceral character action gameplay. Lunging across gaps to impale enemies on your claws never gets old. </p><p>Origins deserves a lot of credit for solving many of the problems that had always plagued X-Men games. Wolverine’s powers aren’t locked behind special meters and limited in use. Even his healing factor plays an integral role in the gameplay, with players able to actually see his ruined body stitching itself together in real-time. No game has done a better job of making players actually feel this iconic hero’s berserker rage.</p><p>As for the Merc With a Mouth, he got his due in 2013’s Deadpool. Another violent third-person action game, Deadpool immediately stood out by embracing the fourth-wall-breaking antics of its titular anti-hero. It didn’t hurt that the game was actually scripted by prolific Deadpool comic book writer Daniel Way. And with a large ensemble cast that includes many mutant favorites and Mister Sinister as its main villain, Deadpool features enough X-Men pedigree to satisfy fans starved for new content. Temporarily, at least.    </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2>The X-Men’s Murky Gaming Future</h2><p>Outside of the occasional game like Marvel: Ultimate Alliance 3 and Marvel’s Midnight Suns, it’s been pretty quiet on the X-Men gaming front over the past several years. It didn’t help that Marvel has been accused of purposely downplaying the X-Men in other media while feuding with 20th Century Fox over the movie rights, an alleged battle that only came to an end <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/03/19/disney-completes-acquisition-of-21st-century-fox">when Disney purchased Fox in 2019</a>.</p><p>Fortunately, the future is beginning to look brighter for our mutant heroes. X-fans the world over have their eyes on Insomniac’s upcoming Wolverine game, which will put players back in the shoes of the Ol’ Canucklehead as he claws his way through the seedy town of Madripoor. If the game is even half as good as Insomniac’s Spider-Man series, X-Men Origins: Wolverine will be facing some serious competition.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Thanks to a massive data leak, we also know that Insomniac’s plans for the X-Men franchise don’t stop with Wolverine. The studio reportedly intends for Wolverine to kick off a trilogy that will <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-signs-deal-with-marvel-to-make-exclusive-x-men-games-until-2035-insomniac-cyber-security-attack-reveals">culminate in a full-fledged X-Men game</a>. That’s great news for fans… so long as they have a Playstation 5.</p><p>As for what else the future holds for the X-Men in video games, only time will tell. Will the X-Men return to the Marvel vs. Capcom franchise? Will the calls for X-Men Legends III finally be answered? For now, all we can do is replay these classics and hope for a brighter future for mutantkind.</p><p>What’s your favorite X-Men game of all time? Cast your vote in our poll and let us know in the comments. </p><p>For more on the X-Men franchise, brush up on <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/upcoming-new-next-marvel-movies-2024-tv-shows-release-dates">every Marvel movie and show in development</a> and check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/deadpool-wolverine-mcu-explained-multiverse-saga-x-men">IGN's review of Deadpool &amp; Wolverine</a>.</p><p><em>Jesse is a mild-mannered staff writer for IGN. Allow him to lend a machete to your intellectual thicket by </em><a href="https://twitter.com/jschedeen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u><em>following @jschedeen on Twitter</em></u></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New PS5 Beta Includes Personalized 3D Audio Profiles and New Remote Play Settings]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/new-ps5-beta-includes-personalized-3d-audio-profiles-and-new-remote-play-settings</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-ps5-beta-includes-personalized-3d-audio-profiles-and-new-remote-play-settings.935547/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/new-ps5-beta-includes-personalized-3d-audio-profiles-and-new-remote-play-settings<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Adaptive controller charging coming to PS5 Slim.</h2></div><section><p>Sony has released a new firmware update for <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/playstation-5">PlayStation 5</a> and announced new features coming to the console in a future release.</p><p>First off, the PS5 system software update 24.05-09.60.00 is available to download now. This adds PS5 Session Share to the console. Check out the patch notes below:</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The Best PS5 Games</h3></div></output><h2>PS5 firmware update 24.05-09.60.00 patch notes in full:</h2><h3>Version: 24.05-09.60.00</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>You can invite other players to game sessions by sharing a URL to the session. <ul data-cy="list"><li>To invite other players, open the game session action card and select <strong>Share Link</strong>. Then, scan the QR code with your mobile device to share the link.</li><li>This feature is available only for open sessions that anyone can join. </li><li>This feature will gradually be rolled out to all players by July 24.</li></ul></li><li>Voice Command now supports the ability to open Game Help action cards by saying "Show Game Help". <ul data-cy="list"><li>Currently, Voice Command (Preview) is available only in English for players with accounts for PlayStation Network in the US and UK. </li></ul></li><li>We've improved system software performance and stability. </li><li>We've updated the device software of some DualSense wireless controllers to improve stability. </li><li>We've improved the messages and usability on some screens.</li></ul><p>Meanwhile, Sony announced a new PS5 beta rolls out tomorrow, July 25, that adds personalized 3D audio profiles and new Remote Play settings. Beta participants using the latest, slimmer PS5 model can also test adaptive charging for controllers.</p><p>In a post on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/07/24/new-ps5-beta-rolls-out-tomorrow-with-personalized-3d-audio-profiles-and-new-remote-play-settings/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog</a>, Hiromi Wakai, VP of Product Management, Sony Interactive Entertainment, said Sony plans to release this update globally in the coming months.</p><h2>Here are the PS5 beta update highlights, per the PlayStation Blog:</h2><p><strong>Personalized 3D audio profiles for headphones and earbuds (available for all PS5 models)</strong></p><p>In this generation, 3D audio is one of the key ways that creators have enhanced the immersive quality of games. As individuals, we all hear sounds differently based on the size and shape of our head, ears, and ear canals.</p><p>We’re pleased to introduce a feature that lets your PS5 console create a personalized 3D audio profile just for you. With a set of headphones or earbuds like the Pulse Elite wireless headset or Pulse Explore wireless earbuds,  you can run through a set of sound quality tests to analyze a vast number of factors to create an audio profile that best fits your hearing characteristics. For example, your personalized 3D audio profile may enable you to better sense the positions of characters and objects in a game world more clearly than before, making the experience more immersive.</p><p>To create a personalized 3D audio profile for your headphones or earbuds, go to [Settings] &gt; [Sound] &gt; [3D Audio (Headphones)] on your PS5 console, and follow the steps displayed on the screen. Your audio profile will be saved on your PS5 per user, and you can also still select from 3D audio presets like before.</p><p>This feature builds on the 3D audio enhancements we’ve introduced to PS5 since launch, including 3D audio support for built-in TV speakers and support for compatible Dolby Atmos-enabled audio devices. These features give you additional options to immerse yourself more deeply in the rich variety of soundscapes in PS5 games, powered by Tempest 3D AudioTech.</p><p><strong>Enable Remote Play for individual users (available for all PS5 models)</strong></p><p>You can now adjust Remote Play settings per user and choose who is allowed to connect to your PS5 console using Remote Play. So, if your friends or family members come over and sign in to your PS5 console with their account for PlayStation Network, you can easily modify who can continue to access your PS5 console using Remote Play when they leave.</p><p>To adjust these settings, go to [Settings] &gt; [System] &gt; [Remote Play] &gt; [Enable Remote Play], and choose which user you want to enable access to your PS5 console through Remote Play.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/24/ps5-1721824457140.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: Sony Interactive Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p><strong>Adaptive charging for your controller (available for the latest PS5 model)</strong></p><p>Adaptive charging for the DualSense wireless controller, DualSense Edge wireless controller, PlayStation VR2 Sense controllers, and Access controller is now available for PS5 beta participants using the latest PS5 model, when the console is in rest mode. Adaptive charging helps save power by adjusting the length of time that power is supplied to your controller based on its battery level.</p><p>To use adaptive charging, go to [Settings] &gt; [System] &gt; [Power Saving] &gt; [Features Available in Rest Mode], and then select [Supply Power to USB Ports] &gt; [Adaptive]. After your PS5 enters rest mode, if a controller isn’t connected, the power supply to the USB port will stop after a certain period of time.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/24/ps5-again-1721824497692.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: Sony Interactive Entertainment.</figcaption></figure></output><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jujutsu Kaisen: Cursed Clash adds Kamo Noritoshi via free update on July 25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/jujutsu-kaisen-cursed-clash-adds-kamo-noritoshi-via-free-update-on-july-25</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jujutsu-kaisen-cursed-clash-adds-kamo-noritoshi-via-free-update-on-july-25.935544/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/jujutsu-kaisen-cursed-clash-adds-kamo-noritoshi-via-free-update-on-july-25<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Pierce through enemies with archery and Blood Manipulation.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Two-versus-two <a title="Genres > Action [2,029 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Jujutsu Kaisen: Cursed Clash [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/jujutsu-kaisen-cursed-clash">Jujutsu Kaisen: Cursed Clash</a></em> will add new playable character Kamo Noritoshi on July 25 via a free update, publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,532 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Byking [103 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/byking">Byking</a> announced. <span id="more-901096"></span></p><p>Noritoshi Kamo uses archery and Blood Manipulation to pierce through enemies. The update also includes four color variations for Noritoshi Kamo, as well as Noritoshi Kamo as an online <a title="Genres > Co-Op [186 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> mode enemy, and additional customization items (title, emblem, nickname, and plate).</p><p><em>Jujutsu Kaisen: Cursed Clash</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,509 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,717 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,969 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,343 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,693 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,720 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1877020/Jujutsu_Kaisen_Cursed_Clash/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>DLC “Hidden Inventory / Premature Death” Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="JUJUTSU KAISEN CURSED CLASH - Kamo Noritoshi FREE Update 2" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1zBgGh8OgL8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="「呪術廻戦 戦華双乱」無料アップデート第2弾 紹介トレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-x4L8T_K-GM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twitch Updates Sexual Harassment Policy And Adds New Moderation Category]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/twitch-updates-sexual-harassment-policy-and-adds-new-moderation-category/1100-6525256/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/twitch-updates-sexual-harassment-policy-and-adds-new-moderation-category.935541/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/twitch-updates-sexual-harassment-policy-and-adds-new-moderation-category/1100-6525256/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525256">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Looking to create "the best and safest place to stream," Twitch has clarified it sexual harassment policy as well as added AutoMod functionality to block problematic messages before they even appear in chats. It's all part of an enhanced effort to fight back against abuse on the platform.</p><p dir="ltr">On <a href="https://safety.twitch.tv/s/article/How-We-re-Combatting-Sexual-Harassment-on-Twitch?language=en_US" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a blog post</a>, Twitch shared a new definition for sexual harassment on the platform to provide "clear boundaries around what behaviors are and aren't allowed." The full explanation is below:</p><p dir="ltr">"We define sexual harassment to encompass non-physical behaviors of a sexual nature that cause users to feel uncomfortable, degraded, unsafe, or discouraged from participation. We prohibit unwanted comments--including comments made using emojis/emotes--regarding someone's appearance or body, sexual requests or advances, sexual objectification, and negative statements or attacks related to a person's perceived sexual behaviors or activities, regardless of their gender. We also do not tolerate the recording or sharing of non-consensual intimate images or videos under any circumstances, and may report such content to law enforcement."</p><p dir="ltr">It is possible the company's team may get it wrong on consensual messages, Twitch admitted. That's why there is an Appeals Portal, though any expression of sexual violence will not be allowed on the streaming service--no matter the context.</p><p dir="ltr">In addition, Twitch announced that AutoMod has been updated to catch sexual harassment messages before appearing in a streamer's chat. It's also customizable, allowing users to make it more or less strict. The updated AutoMod functionality only works for the English language so far.</p><p dir="ltr">Earlier this month, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/twitch-will-reinstate-former-president-donald-trumps-account-report/1100-6525160/" data-ref-id="1100-6525160">Twitch reinstated former President Donald Trump's channel</a> after he became the official Republican nominee for the US presidency in 2024. At the beginning of the year, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/twitch-is-laying-off-500-employees-in-latest-round-of-job-cuts/1100-6520222/" data-ref-id="1100-6520222">Twitch fired 500 people</a> as part of massive downsizing.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch Introduces Its First-Ever Mythic Weapon Skin]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/overwatch-introduces-its-first-ever-mythic-weapon-skin/1100-6525258/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-introduces-its-first-ever-mythic-weapon-skin.935535/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/overwatch-introduces-its-first-ever-mythic-weapon-skin/1100-6525258/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525258">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/overwatch-2/">Overwatch 2</a>'s first-ever Mythic Weapon skin is finally here. The Bound Demon Reinhardt Mythic Weapon skin was added to Overwatch 2's in-game Mythic Shop this week, and is the first of its kind.</p><p dir="ltr">Designed to evolve visually as players compete in matches, the Bound Demon skin features dynamic reactions to the player's in-game behavior. The skin's visuals change with each swing and charge, similar to the way <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/apex-legends/">Apex Legends</a>' reactive weapon skins function (though Reinhardt's Mythic Weapon itself is much closer to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/apex-legends-heirloom-set-guide-all-heirloom-weapons-mythic-items-and-rare-animations/2900-4954/#62">Apex's Heirloom Weapons</a>).</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1834211911" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464416,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Overwatch%202%20-%20Super%20Mega%20Ultrawatch%20%7C%20Official%20Season%2011%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:185,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/overwatch-2-super-mega-ultrawatch-official-season-11-trailer\/2300-6464416\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464416\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464416\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464416\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464416&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464416,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6525258&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;overwatch-2&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-one,playstation-4,nintendo-switch,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;blizzard-entertainment,activision&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;overwatch&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;overwatch&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464416},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464416\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4320108-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/a7nbP948.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1718642220,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="a7nbP948" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Overwatch 2 - Super Mega Ultrawatch | Official Season 11 Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">The Bound Demon skin has three levels of visual effects that can be unlocked via Mythic Shards. These visuals include unique weapon flourishes, special animations/VFX that play when eliminating an enemy, and other reactive visual effects that reflect players' in-game actions.</p><p dir="ltr">The basic version of Reinhardt's Mythic Weapon can be unlocked for 50 Mythic Shards ($40 USD), but the three levels of the Bound Demon Mythic Weapon skin cost 10 Mythic Shards ($10 USD) each. Players looking for a more wallet-friendly way to obtain the skin may want to opt for the Reinhardt Mythic Weapon Skin Bundle, which is currently available via the in-game shop for $40 USD.</p><p dir="ltr">The bundle includes the basic version of the weapon, along with 2,000 Overwatch Coins and an instant, 20-level boost for the current season's battle pass. Since 80 Mythic Shards are included in the premium version of the game's battle pass, that 20-level boost could easily provide more than enough Mythic Shards to unlock the three tiers of Reinhardt's new Bound Demon Mythic Weapon skin.</p><p dir="ltr">It's unclear how long the Reinhardt Mythic Weapon skin bundle will be available for purchase, but Blizzard did say the bundle will only be available for a "brief period," so players looking to get their hands on the new skin--along with a battle-pass boost and some Overwatch Coins--will likely want to act fast, as the bundle option could be gone in a matter of days, when the in-game store's weekly restocking takes place.</p><p>More information on the fiery new weapon skin--and the story behind its creation--can be found on the official <a href="https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24104604/unleash-your-inner-demon-with-reinhardt-s-mythic-weapon/" rel="nofollow ">Overwatch blog</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crash Bandicoot N. Sane Trilogy is coming to Xbox Game Pass next month, leak suggests]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-is-coming-to-xbox-game-pass-next-month-leak-suggests</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-is-coming-to-xbox-game-pass-next-month-leak-suggests.935520/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-is-coming-to-xbox-game-pass-next-month-leak-suggests<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>
It looks like Crash Bandicoot N. Sane Trilogy is on its way to Xbox Game Pass next month.
</p>
<p>
That's according to leaker <a href="https://x.com/eXtas1stv/status/1815874694349770896">eXtas1stv</a>, who previously correctly leaked that Call of Duty Modern Warfare 3 would arrive on Game Pass on 24th July, which was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-3-is-heading-to-xbox-game-pass-this-week">officially confirmed yesterday</a>.
</p>
<p>
The leaker suggests the Crash trilogy will be available from 8th August, claiming it's "100 percent confirmed".
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Crash Bandicoot N Sane Trilogy Gameplay - New PS4 Gameplay" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nTGu8B5AySQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Crash Bandicoot N Sane Trilogy Gameplay - New PS4 Gameplay</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nTGu8B5AySQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nTGu8B5AySQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Crash Bandicoot N Sane Trilogy Gameplay - New PS4 Gameplay<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nTGu8B5AySQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>

Previously, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/crash-bandicoot-n-sane-trilogy-reportedly-heading-to-game-pass-in-august">leaker claimed the game would arrive in August</a> - now the date has been specified.
</p>
<p>
If proven true, it will be the next of Activision's back catalogue to make it to Xbox's subscription service following the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-has-finally-bought-activision-blizzard">completed purchase of Activision Blizzard for $68.7bn</a>.

</p>
<p>
Blizzard's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/diablo-4-will-make-a-hellish-addition-to-xbox-game-pass-this-march">Diablo 4 was already added to Game Pass</a> back in March.

</p>
<p>The Crash Bandicoot N. Sane Trilogy is a remastered compilation of the first three games in the platformer series, developed by Vicarious Visions and published by Activision.</p>
<p>
Meanwhile, Crash Bandicoot 4: It's About Time developer <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/spyro-and-crash-bandicoot-studio-toys-for-bob-confirms-xbox-will-publish-new-game">Toys for Bob has split from Activision to go independent</a>, but its next game will be published by Xbox.

</p>
<p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-confirms-big-changes-for-xbox-game-pass-ditching-day-one-releases-for-basic-tier">Microsoft recently altered its Xbox Game Pass tiers</a>, removing day one releases for its basic tier and increasing the price, all in the run-up to October's Call of Duty: Black Ops 6.

</p>
<p>
The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ftc-slams-microsofts-xbox-game-pass-tier-changes-calls-it-a-degraded-product">FTC slammed the change as a "degraded product"</a>, which Microsoft has since defended as "wrong".


</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 New Beta System Software Rolls Out Tomorrow, Introducing New Remote Play Settings, Adaptive Charging]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-new-beta-adaptive-charging/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-new-beta-system-software-rolls-out-tomorrow-introducing-new-remote-play-settings-adaptive-charging.935517/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-new-beta-adaptive-charging/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A new PlayStation 5 beta system software will start rolling out tomorrow, introducing new features to the system, which will eventually make their way to a future public system software update.</p>
<p>The new beta, whose access is limited to invited participants in select countries, introduces some new features, starting with personalized 3D audio profiles for headphones and earbuds. This new feature allows users to undergo a set of sound quality tests to analyze a large number of factors to create an audio profile that best suits their hearing.</p>
<p>The new PlayStation 5 beta system software also introduces some new Remote Play settings, allowing users to adjust settings per user and choose who is allowed to connect to a console via Remote Play. The third and final major addition is the introduction of Adaptive Charging, which can only be used on the new PlayStation 5 model to adjust the length of time that power is supplied to controllers based on their battery level. Adaptive charging applies to DualSense controllers, DualSense Edge controllers, PlayStation VR 2 controllers, and Access controllers. More information on these new features can be found on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/07/24/new-ps5-beta-rolls-out-tomorrow-with-personalized-3d-audio-profiles-and-new-remote-play-settings/">official PlayStation Blog</a>.</p>
<p>Sony seems to be working hard on the software side of things lately. Just <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-system-software-update-24-05-09-60-00-performance-improvements/">yesterday</a>, a new PlayStation 5 system software update went live, introducing a new feature that allows players to invite others using a URL of the multiplayer session and more.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Trolls Crowdstrike Over Worldwide Outage]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-joke-arrowhead-crowdstrike-1851603412</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-trolls-crowdstrike-over-worldwide-outage.935514/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/helldivers-2-joke-arrowhead-crowdstrike-1851603412<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="42ee7ab725142f1aa051635c197c2a79" data-recommend-id="image://42ee7ab725142f1aa051635c197c2a79" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Helldiver watches as a ship crashes and burns." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Helldiver watches as a ship crashes and burns." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Arrowhead Game Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="42ee7ab725142f1aa051635c197c2a79" data-recommend-id="image://42ee7ab725142f1aa051635c197c2a79" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Helldiver watches as a ship crashes and burns." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Live-service games face an extraordinarily tough time battling to maintain their player-base, competing against a dozen similar games, and trying to constantly satisfy impossibly disparate audience—but one benefit that’s all too rarely utilized is the ability to be incredibly topical and reactive. <em>Helldivers 2</em> is flexing that muscle in the best way, with an in-game gag based on last week’s colossal computing failure that saw <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/crowdstrike-microsoft-worldwide-outage-crash-1851599499&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/crowdstrike-microsoft-worldwide-outage-crash-1851599499">a Crowdstrike update bring the planet to a standstill</a></span>.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196395" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="80" data-playlist="196395,192712,196086" data-current="196395"><div><p>The Week In Games: Co-Op Bug Blasting And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196395/196395_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21945.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Boot the game, and those brave enough to defend Super Earth’s managed democracy will see a message informing them of a crucial system update.</p><figure id="" data-id="ec82f457e4eb015aab0cd540fdb78e4a" data-recommend-id="image://ec82f457e4eb015aab0cd540fdb78e4a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1000" data-height="751" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The spoof systems update message in Helldivers 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The spoof systems update message in Helldivers 2." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Kotaku / Arrowhead Game Studios</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ec82f457e4eb015aab0cd540fdb78e4a" data-recommend-id="image://ec82f457e4eb015aab0cd540fdb78e4a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1000" data-height="751" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The spoof systems update message in Helldivers 2." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>“A cybersecurity software update has caused an unexpected outage for all Destroyer surveillance systems,” the note begins, before issuing the order: “All personnel are ordered to manually record their own behavior until services are restored.”</p><p>Clearly, any Helldiver worthy of their uniform would immediately begin their own personal surveillance, and report back any infractions they may commit. However, there are more specific instructions directed at members of the Ministry of Science’s IT department:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>Instructions to Service Technicians: to bring systems back online, please manually reboot each affected computer 15 times.</p></blockquote><p>This is all, of course, a reference to the Crowdstrike security software update that caused Microsoft computers around the world to BSOD (blue screen of death), with no simple recovery option. Every affected computer had to be manually restarted, with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.pcmag.com/news/microsofts-outage-tip-for-customers-try-rebooting-your-system-15-times&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.pcmag.com/news/microsofts-outage-tip-for-customers-try-rebooting-your-system-15-times" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reports from Microsoft</a></span> that it could take up to 15 reboots before the issue would be resolved. This was seemingly because of the random nature of the boot order of high-priority functions, and needing to beat the odds of Crowdstrike’s error kicking in before Windows could access the internet to apply the fix.</p><p>While <em>Helldivers 2</em>'s gag doesn’t have any direct impact on playing the game (it would have been amazing if it could have been rolled into a Major Order, but obviously such things are planned and written and programmed long in advance of rollout), it shows a fantastic advantage of a game that’s constantly alive and able to react to events. Although presumably any real-world IT managers, looking to play the game for a bit of escapism after the last week, might not have found it <em>quite</em> as funny.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bleach Rebirth of Souls First Look Gameplay Overview Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-first-look-gameplay-overview-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-first-look-gameplay-overview-revealed.935511/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-first-look-gameplay-overview-revealed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Sdss7AXask" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new trailer</a> released today, Bandai Namco revealed a first look at Bleach Rebirth of Souls with a detailed gameplay overview.</p>



<p>It breaks down the goal of each fight, where players must wear out their opponent’s Reishi gauge and destroy all 9 of their Konpaku to win. </p>



<p>There are also Spiritual Pressure Moves and reverse actions to keep battles balanced. Fighters can use reverse actions while attacking or defending, inviting fans to make tactical decisions. Players can also accumulate power to reach an “Awakened State” and wield an ultimate ability. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="BLEACH Rebirth of Souls – Gameplay Overview Trailer" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Sdss7AXask?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Some fans were concerned Bleach Rebirth of Souls might resemble Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero too closely. However, many praised the distinct combat style and flow in today’s trailer.</p>



<p>Bandai Namco first announced Bleach Rebirth of Souls during a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-bleach-game-possibly-coming-to-bandai-namco-showcase/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2024 showcase event</a> earlier this month. The event mostly revealed cinematic footage and story beats. There is currently no concrete release window or date.</p>



<p>There are a variety of previous games based on the popular Bleach anime. However, many of these titles only released on mobile devices.</p>



<p>Last week, Bandai Namco also announced its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/bandai-namco-announces-gamescom-2024-lineup/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lineup for Gamescom 2024</a>. That will include Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero, which will be playable for the first time.</p>



<p>Bleach Rebirth of Souls will be available on PC via Steam, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about new <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shift-up-job-listings-hint-at-possible-pc-port-future-content/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">job listings at Shift Up</a> possibly reinforcing that a Stellar Blade PC port is coming, and sign up to receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bleach: Rebirth of Souls ‘Gameplay Overview’ trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-gameplay-overview-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-%E2%80%98gameplay-overview%E2%80%99-trailer.935508/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/bleach-rebirth-of-souls-gameplay-overview-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Soul Reapers jump into battle.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,532 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Tamsoft [282 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tamsoft">Tamsoft</a> have released the gameplay overview trailer for <em><a title="Games > Bleach: Rebirth of Souls [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bleach-rebirth-of-souls">Bleach: Rebirth of Souls</a></em>. <span id="more-900836"></span></p><p>“Wielding swords that personify their soul, Soul Reapers now jump into battle,” the trailer narrator explains. “Utilize each character’s unique Zankensoki action to cut down your opponent’s Reishi. Cutting down one gauge of Reishi decreases your opponent’s Konpaku. After damaging your opponent, unleash your Kikon Move and destroy several your opponent’s Konpaku. Destroy all nine of your opponent’s Konpaku and win the game. Using the spiritual power accumulated while attacking, unleash a special Spiritual Pressure Move. You can also activate Reverse <a title="Genres > Action [2,029 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> while attacking and defending. Turn the tide of battle with well-timed combos. In the midst of battle, accumulated power brings you to an Awakened state. Unleashing your true power will overwhelm your opponent!”</p><p><em>Bleach: Rebirth of Souls</em> will be available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,509 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,717 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,969 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,720 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1689620/BLEACH_Rebirth_of_Souls/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date has yet to be announced.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Overview Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="BLEACH Rebirth of Souls – Gameplay Overview Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Sdss7AXask?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="「BLEACH Rebirth of Souls」バトルコンセプトトレーラー" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r-ICbkP20RQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gran Turismo 7 Update Brings Six New Cars, Major Physics Refresh, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gran-turismo-7-update-physics-new-cars</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gran-turismo-7-update-brings-six-new-cars-major-physics-refresh-and-more.935484/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gran-turismo-7-update-physics-new-cars<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A new&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7&nbsp;</em>update has been released, and this one is adding six iconic cars to the racing sim's roster, as well as a "major update" for the game's car physics simulation model and more.</p>
<p>Most&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7&nbsp;</em>updates <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gran-turismo-7-update-144">bring</a> new <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gran-turismo-7-january-update-coming-tomorrow-with-3-new-cars-and-more">cars</a> with them, and this one is no exception, but it's a bumper crop: you're getting six cars spanning decades of racing history, with high-profile brands like Subaru, Lamborghini, and more represented.</p>
<p>First up, the BMW M3 '97 brings a touch of 90s racing class to&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7</em>. It's followed by the 2007 Ferrari 430 Scuderia, a sleek racer that "greatly improved upon the performance of the F430", as Sony and Polyphony have it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gran-turismo-7-update-july-six-new-cars.jpg?itok=aSL6cGFf 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gran-turismo-7-update-july-six-new-cars.jpg?itok=0aySxSkP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This month's&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7&nbsp;</em>update has six new cars for you to stare lovingly at.</figcaption></figure><p>The Genesis X Gran Racer Vision Gran Turismo Concept is next, and it's a "racing version of the Gran Berlinetta" with a very sleek and idiosyncratic shape.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Your next car in this&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7&nbsp;</em>update is the Lamborghini Gallardo LP 560-4 from 2008, which is an updated version of the 2003 Gallardo model that sports a frame 20kg lighter than previous models.</p>
<p>Finally, you can drive the 2016 RUF RGT 4.2 and the iconic Subaru Impreza Rally Car from 1998. Let it never be said that you don't have enough cars to choose from in&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7</em>, eh?</p>
<p>All of these cars come with an update to the game's physics simulation model, which Sony says should give cornering a more natural weight-shifting feel and improve tire response as well. It's a pretty significant change that should alter the way cars feel to drive.</p>

<p>As well as all of the above, you're also getting a new GT Circuit in the form of Eiger Nordwand, a classic circuit situated in the Swiss Alps. As you'd expect, it's breathtakingly beautiful, so try not to get distracted by the sights while you're zooming along its track.</p>
<p>If you want to see everything that's new in this&nbsp;<em>Gran Turismo 7&nbsp;</em>update, you can <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/07/24/gran-turismo-7-update-1-49-brings-six-new-cars-updated-physics-simulation-model-and-more-on-july-24/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">do so right here</a>. The update lands at 11pm PT, which means you'll have to wait until early tomorrow morning if you're on Eastern time.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former Epic Games exec Alain Tascan is the new president of Netflix Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/former-epic-games-exec-alain-tascan-is-the-new-president-of-netflix-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/former-epic-games-exec-alain-tascan-is-the-new-president-of-netflix-games.935481/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/former-epic-games-exec-alain-tascan-is-the-new-president-of-netflix-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Epic Games former EVP of game development, Alain Tascan, has been named president of Netflix Games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Prior to joining Epic, Tascan served as CEO of Umi Mobile, vice chairman at Funcom, VP and general manager at EA Montreal, and VP of production at Ubisoft.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://variety.com/2024/digital/news/netflix-games-president-alain-tascan-epic-1236081464/">Variety broke the news</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and explained Tascan will report directly to Netflix co-CEO Greg Peters.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Alain brings over 30 years of experience in global video game development, production, licensing and building studios," said Peters, discussing the appointment. "He has a passion for making great games and a proven track record of taking bold creative bets. We’re thrilled to have him leading Netflix Games."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Tascan said he intends to build on the "remarkable foundation" the Netflix Games team has laid, and claimed the streaming company is "uniquely positioned to redefine the future of gaming."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">His appointment comes weeks after Netflix confirmed its VP of Games, Mike Verdu, would be </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/netflix-games-boss-mike-verdu-is-taking-on-a-new-role-at-the-streamer">taking on a new, unspecified role within the company</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> focused on "innovation in game development."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Netflix Games on the rise">Netflix Games on the rise</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Netflix is getting serious about making games. The company has acquired a number of studios in recent years, including Spry Fox, Next Games, and Night School Studio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It launched Netflix Games in 2021 with a lightweight roster that comprised just five titles. It has since brought over 100 games to the platform and has more than 80 projects currently in development.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">During a recent earnings call (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.polygon.com/2024/7/22/24203719/netflix-game-development-earnings-call">thanks Polygon</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">), Netflix co-CEO Greg Peters explained the company now has a better idea of how to approach and refine its video game business. "We've launched over 100 games so far. We've seen what works, what doesn't work. We're refining our program to do more of what is working with the 80-plus games that we currently have in development," he said.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>