<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 04:08:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ys X: Nordics launches October 25 in the west]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/ys-x-nordics-launches-october-25-in-the-west</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ys-x-nordics-launches-october-25-in-the-west.919320/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/ys-x-nordics-launches-october-25-in-the-west<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em><a title="Games > Ys X: Nordics [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ys-x-nordics">Ys X: Nordics</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,405 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,897 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,602 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,598 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2731870/Ys_X_Nordics/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/ys-x-nordics-0ed760" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/ys_x_nordics" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GOG</a> on October 25 in the west, publisher <a title="Companies > NIS America [145 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nippon-ichi-software/nis-america">NIS America</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Nihon Falcom [693 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nihon-falcom">Falcom</a> announced. <span id="more-896751"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via NIS America:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Following their tenuous encounter at sea, the young red-haired adventurer Adol Christin and the proud pirate Karja Balta find themselves bound by fate—and the mysterious power of Mana! As they search for a way to undo the mystical ties that bind them, they soon find themselves caught up in a conflict between two factions: the seafaring warriors known as the Normans and the enigmatic and seemingly immortal Griegr. In order to save the people of Obelia Gulf, Adol and Karja must navigate the depths of their unexpected bond and the power that it grants them.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_896762"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Two Heroes, One Story</strong> – Bound by unexpected circumstances, the young <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,601 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>r Adol and the Norman pirate Karja must work together to determine the fate of Obelia Gulf and its people.</li><li><strong>Cross <a title="Genres > Action [1,989 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> System</strong> – Swap between controlling Adol and Karja independently or together. Combine their unique strengths to overcome enemies, and build up the Revenge Gauge to unleash devastating attacks.</li><li><strong>The Power of <a title="Series > Mana [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a></strong> – Harness the unique abilities of Mana to overcome challenges. Grapple and slide through dungeons, demolish obstacles, create new platforms, and uncover hidden treasures and critical points.</li><li><strong>Sailor’s Delight</strong> – The sailing ship known as the Sandras takes your exploration to new levels. Ocean travel, naval battles, and discovering uncharted islands are all made possible with this seaworthy vessel.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/ys-x-nordics/july-4-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Ys X: Nordics - Western Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7cBXFPfsh_g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What’s New in the Escape From Tarkov Patch Notes Today? – Answered]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-patch-notes-today-answered/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what%E2%80%99s-new-in-the-escape-from-tarkov-patch-notes-today-%E2%80%93-answered.919311/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/escape-from-tarkov-patch-notes-today-answered/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>It’s always exciting when Escape From Tarkov drops an update, especially when it’s right before the weekend. I don’t know about you, but I usually take a full Saturday off after a patch to check out what’s new, what’s broken, and whether or not I’m still terrible at the game (Spoiler: I am!). For now, let’s check out the Escape From Tarkov patch notes today!</p>



<h2 id="h-today-s-escape-from-tarkov-patch-notes">Today’s Escape From Tarkov Patch Notes</h2>



<p>The most recent Escape From Tarkov update proves rather comprehensive. It’s a big one, with countless new tasks, additional customization, the ability to wipe your PvE profile, AI adjustments in the PvE game mode, balance adjustments, and plenty more.</p>



<p>If you consider yourself a hardcore fan of EFT, then you’ll want to parse through the following patch notes for the game line by line!</p>



<blockquote>
<h4>PVE ZONE offline single player</h4>



<p>For all players with access to PVE ZONE, raids for solo players will be run on the local PC. The game experience, as well as the operation of in-game mechanics, is completely identical to online play.<br><strong>For group raids, raids as a Scav, and raids on Streets of Tarkov, the game will utilize the servers.</strong></p>



<h4>Wishlist mechanics</h4>



<ul>
<li>Players can add an item to one of several pre-created Wishlist categories. Items added to Wishlist are displayed in a separate section of the Handbook;</li>



<li>Wishlist items have unique visual differences. When obtaining such items through various methods, the player will receive a corresponding notification. Players can customize the frequency of notifications in the game settings;</li>



<li>Added the ability to automatically add items needed for Hideout to Wishlist. The available options for this feature can be configured in the game settings;</li>



<li>The Wishlist persists after wipes. You can clear the list manually in the game settings.</li>
</ul>



<h4>In-game feedback surveys</h4>



<ul>
<li>Added a community feedback survey system within the game, available at the “Surveys” tab in the bottom menu;</li>



<li>Completing surveys helps improve the quality of the game based on community feedback;</li>



<li>Players can earn in-game rewards for completing surveys.</li>
</ul>



<h4>AI adjustments in PvE mode</h4>



<ul>
<li>AI PMCs now pick up items, loot crates and bodies, trying to choose more valuable loot;</li>



<li>They can also pick up weapons and equipment, and if they find better equipment, they replace theirs with it;</li>



<li>AI PMCs can travel all over the location. They build routes to points of possible loot concentration. Bots move in tactical formation. When they reach the destination point, they collect loot, and then can wait for enemies for some time, setting up ambushes;</li>



<li>AI PMCs now extract from the location if they have collected enough loot or enough time has passed since the start of the raid;</li>



<li>AI PMCs now sprint more often when moving in open terrain;</li>



<li>AI PMC level on beginner Ground Zero will be limited to level 20;</li>



<li>All AI will now react to the enemy if information about them came from any nearby bot. For example, if you are spotted by a bot and they yell, all bots regardless of faction will hear it and decide to move in your direction, take cover or perform other actions;</li>



<li>AI Scavs will now travel all over the location and search for valuable loot. Scavs are less picky about loot quality than AI PMCs. Scavs move between potential loot destinations in tactical formation if they are traveling in a group;</li>



<li>This is the first iteration of AI improvements within PvE mode. In future updates, we also plan to refine the tactical behavior of AI, as well as the interaction system between AI of different factions.</li>
</ul>



<p>In future updates, the necessary mechanics will be moved to PvP mode.</p>



<h4>New tasks</h4>



<ul>
<li>Added the Nostalgia quest line for the game’s life path, available only to owners of the Edge of Darkness edition bonuses;</li>



<li>Added a new quest line for obtaining Mark of The Unheard, allowing owners of any edition to obtain this item in PvE mode;</li>



<li>Added a new quest line for obtaining extended PMC pockets, allowing owners of any edition to obtain this item.</li>
</ul>



<h4>Customization</h4>



<p>Added new outfits for USEC and BEAR, available for purchase for “Lega” Medal. Purchasing these outfits requires high standing with Ref.</p>



<h4>PvE profile wipe</h4>



<p>Expanded the profile reset options in the profile page on the website. Now you can reset your PvE and PvP progress separately or together.</p>



<h4>Compensation for reporting players who violated game rules</h4>



<ul>
<li>Players will receive in-game currency compensation after the report that led to the blocking of the violator;</li>



<li>Compensation comes with an in-game message informing of a successful report. Compensation for several successful reports will be combined.</li>
</ul>



<h4>Balancing adjustments</h4>



<ul>
<li>Increased the spawn chance of the following optics:
<ul>
<li>VOMZ Pilad 4×32 25.4mm riflescope;</li>



<li>Burris FullField TAC30 1-4×24 30mm riflescope;</li>



<li>EOTech Vudu 1-6×24 30mm riflescope;</li>



<li>Leupold Mark 4 LR 6.5-20×50 30mm riflescope;</li>



<li>March Tactical 3-24×42 FFP 30mm riflescope;</li>



<li>Vortex Razor HD Gen.2 1-6×24 30mm riflescope;</li>



<li>Schmidt &amp; Bender PM II 1-8×24 30mm riflescope;</li>



<li>SIG TANGO6T 1-6×24 30mm riflescope;</li>



<li>Hensoldt FF 4-16×56 34mm riflescope;</li>



<li>Nightforce ATACR 7-35×56 34mm riflescope;</li>



<li>Schmidt &amp; Bender PM II 3-12×50 34mm riflescope;</li>



<li>Schmidt &amp; Bender PM II 5-25×56 34mm riflescope;</li>



<li>NcSTAR ADO P4 Sniper 3-9×42 riflescope;</li>



<li>BelOMO PSO-1 4×24 scope;</li>



<li>BelOMO PSO-1M2-1 4×24 scope;</li>



<li>BelOMO PSO-1M2 4×24 scope;</li>



<li>NPZ USP-1 “Tyulpan” 4x scope.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Reduced the recoil for the following bolt-action rifles:
<ul>
<li>Accuracy International AXMC .338 LM bolt-action sniper rifle;</li>



<li>Mosin 7.62x54R bolt-action rifle (Infantry);</li>



<li>Mosin 7.62x54R bolt-action rifle (Sniper);</li>



<li>SV-98 7.62x54R bolt-action sniper rifle;</li>



<li>Lobaev Arms DVL-10 7.62×51 bolt-action sniper rifle;</li>



<li>Molot Arms VPO-215 “Gornostay” .366 TKM bolt-action rifle;</li>



<li>ORSIS T-5000M 7.62×51 bolt-action sniper rifle;</li>



<li>Remington Model 700 7.62×51 bolt-action sniper rifle.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Increased the leveling speed of Hideout Management and Crafting skills;</li>



<li>Removed the hearing distance bonus from the Perception skill.</li>
</ul>



<h3>List of changes:</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed the incorrect physics of character bodies and loot objects in offline raids;</li>



<li>Fixed the EFT and EFT: Arena interaction UI when interacting with Ref;</li>



<li>Fixed the cause of incorrect behavior of character bodies after death;</li>



<li>Fixed several localization errors in interface and tasks.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>







<h2 id="h-how-big-is-the-escape-from-tarkov-update">How Big is the Escape From Tarkov Update?</h2>



<p>Despite the massive number of changes to the game, I’m continually impressed by Battlestate Game’s ability to shrink-wrap an update into such a small package for us. When I booted up the EFT Launcher, my game downloaded an 83 MB patch to bring it up to 0.14.9.5. It took mere seconds to finish the download. A little longer to unpack and check the file’s integrity before I could play. </p>



<p>All in all, I was back in-game in minutes.</p>



<hr>



<p>This is just one small update, though. Don’t miss <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/everything-new-coming-escape-from-tarkov-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">everything new coming to Tarkov in 2024</a>! While we await new content, now’s a good time to sign up for the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>!</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kowloon Walled City: An Illustrated Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/kowloon-walled-city-cross-section-illustrated</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kowloon-walled-city-an-illustrated-guide.919308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/kowloon-walled-city-cross-section-illustrated<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I don't have the time or space to fully introduce Kowloon Walled City if you've never heard of it before--countless others have <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kowloon_Walled_City" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">already done so</a>, and <a href="https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/kowloon-walled-city" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">done a great job</a>--but suffice to say it was an architectural marvel and a cyberpunk icon that inspired, well, almost everything you've ever seen (<em>Ghost in the Shell</em>!) or played (<em>Stray</em>!) that featured dystopian, crowded and man-made spaces.</p><p>With its population exploding in 1945 and its demolition coming in 1994, it's existence in a specific time and place in the world has long made it a fascination of historians and nerds alike. But because it's gone, and was so difficult to fully document, it can be tough to get a real idea of what the scale of the place was like beyond some old <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WLn_QTFVZgE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">footage, photos and first-hand accounts</a>. </p><figure></figure><p>It used to be the most densely-populated space on Earth! By a <em>lot</em>! But individual visual records, no matter how comprehensive, have just never been able to capture the reality of what life must have been like in Kowloon Walled City like this cross-section by Hitomi Terasawa.</p><p>Illustrated for the book<em> Kowloon City: An Illustrated Guide</em>, which is now long out of print, the panorama depicts the city in its entirety, showing just how chaotic life there must have been, and the architectural slapdash that led to its ever-changing interiors often being described as a "<a href="https://www.thisiscolossal.com/2024/07/kowlooon-walled-city-illustration/#:~:text=Rather%20than%20navigate%20the%20city,and%20was%20razed%20in%201994." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">living organism</a>".</p><p>This hi-res scan from the book was recently<a href="https://cohost.org/belarius/post/6677850-architectural-cross" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> uploaded by Belarius</a>, who adds that while the original version with Japanese annotations is no longer available, one <em>without </em>them is present in<a href="https://www.greggirardpictures.com/product/city-of-darkness-revisited-with-slipcase" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> 2014's <em>City Of Darkness Revisited</em>, which <em>is</em> still available</a>.</p><figure></figure><p>As a noted cross-section enjoyer I'm in love with the detail here, from the tiniest piece of furniture to the ricketiest walkway, but what makes this truly special is the addition of some of the city's 35,000 inhabitants going about their daily lives, doing everything from playing in playgrounds to performing bathroom renovations. </p><p>You can see the full spread in all its glory <a href="https://staging.cohostcdn.org/attachment/11357255-b6b9-4a57-98eb-823776a4a828/KowloonWalledCityGrandPanorama.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>. </p><figure></figure></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix’s Horizon Zero Dawn show has been scrapped]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/04/netflixs-horizon-zero-dawn-show-has-been-scrapped/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflix%E2%80%99s-horizon-zero-dawn-show-has-been-scrapped.919287/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/04/netflixs-horizon-zero-dawn-show-has-been-scrapped/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Rolling Stone has published a troubling report about Steve Blackman, the showrunner for The Umbrella Academy, in which they say he has been accused of “toxic, bullying, manipulative, and retaliatory behaviour”. Sadly it’s yet another story of a alleged abuse, sexist, homophobic, and transphobic remarks, and a toxic workplace.</p>
<p>Blackman calls the claims “entirely untrue” and “completely absurd”.</p>


<p>As well as running The Umbrella Academy Blackman was also adapting Horizon Zero Dawn for Netflix along with an outer-space thriller series called Orbital. Rolling Stone reports that both of these projects are no longer moving forward.</p>
<p>The Horizon TV show was revealed by Sony in an <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/05/27/gran-turismo-god-of-war-and-horizon-tv-shows-announced-by-sony/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">investor briefing </a>in April 2022 but it was not until August that year we had more details, including the confirmation that Steve Blackman was going to be the showrunner. The synopsis was also revealed.</p>
<p><em>“Co-created by Steve Blackman and Michelle Lovretta,&nbsp;Horizon Zero Dawn is an epic sci-fi adventure series set a thousand years in the future, in a strange and beautiful world full of primitive tribes and high-tech machines, all built on the bones of the ‘Old Ones’ – the ruins of our present-day United States. The disaster that destroyed our world is long forgotten, but when these formerly peaceful machines mysteriously turn into dangerous hunters of all life, a young outcast named Aloy discovers that the only chance to save her world is to fight to uncover what happened to ours.”</em></p>

<p>A Horizon television show always seemed implausible as almost everything would have to be CGI, including the many robot creature, and that would be very expensive. In comparison something like The Last of Us can use real world locations, a log cabin in the woods is a log cabin in the woods, even if it’s a few years after a plague.</p>
<p>However all is not lost for Horizon fans as there is the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/07/lego-horizon-adventures-revealed-for-ps5-switch-and-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">upcoming LEGO game which will launch on PS5, Switch, and PC this Christmas.</a></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-features/umbrella-academy-steve-blackman-abuse-allegations-1235047142/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rolling Stone</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows – Everything We Know About Ubisoft's Open-World Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-release-date-story-gameplay-trailer-news</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-%E2%80%93-everything-we-know-about-ubisofts-open-world-japan.919281/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-release-date-story-gameplay-trailer-news<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Ubisoft is finally taking Assassin’s Creed to Japan with Assassin’s Creed Shadows. The highly requested setting for Ubisoft’s biggest franchise will be explored through two protagonists: the fictional shinobi assassin Naoe and the real-life Black samurai Yasuke.</p><p>In anticipation of Ubisoft’s highly anticipated journey into feudal Japan, we’ve put together this breakdown of everything you need to know about Assassin’s Creed Shadows, from its price and release date to its gameplay and story.</p><p><strong>Jump to</strong>:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><a href="#release-date">Release Date</a></li><li><a href="#story">Story and Setting</a></li><li><a href="#gameplay">Gameplay Details</a></li></ul><h2>Latest Assassin’s Creed Shadows Trailers</h2><p>Ubisoft has released several trailers for Assassin’s Creed Shadows, the most informative of which — the reveal trailer and the most recent gameplay trailer from <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-forward-2024-everything-announced"><u>Ubisoft Forward</u></a> — are embedded below.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 id="release-date">Assassin’s Creed Shadows Release Date</h2><p><strong>Assassin’s Creed Shadows will be released on November 15.</strong></p><p>It will be playable three days early, on November 12, for those who preorder either of Shadows’ three premium editions (more on these below) or subscribe to Ubisoft+ Premium on PC ($18/month).</p><h3>Assassin’s Creed Shadows Platforms and Price</h3><div id="200650" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Out November 15 Assassin's Creed Shadows</h3></p></div><p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows is coming to<strong> PS5, Xbox Series X|S, PC (via Ubisoft Store or Epic Games Store), Mac, iPad, and Amazon Luna</strong></p><p>The base version of Assassin’s Creed Shadows costs <strong>$70</strong> across all platforms. An <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-requires-an-internet-connection-to-install-but-not-to-play-after"><u>internet connection will be required</u></a> to install even the physical version of the game, though it can then be played offline. </p><h2 id="story">Assassin’s Creed Shadows Story</h2><h3>Plot and Characters</h3><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows stars two protagonists: the shinobi assassin Naoe and the samurai Yasuke. Naoe is the fictional daughter of the real Fujibayashi Nagato; <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/who-is-yasuke-assassins-creed-shadows-black-samurai-explained"><u>Yasuke</u></a> is based on the real, 16th-century Black samurai of the same name.</p><p>Set during the late Sengoku period (or Azuchi-Momoyama era) of feudal Japan, Shadows begins in 1579 during a time of civil war within the country, complete with the era’s samurai, shinobi, Portuguese merchants, and Jesuit missionaries. The two protagonists converge as they find themselves on opposite sides of conflict: Yasuke served as a retainer to Nobunaga, the daimyo who led the Oda clan in its invasion of Iga; Naoe, under the leadership of her father, is part of the Igan resistance.</p><p>Here’s the official synopsis from Ubisoft:</p><p><em>Live the intertwined stories of Naoe, an adept shinobi Assassin from Iga Province, and Yasuke, the powerful African samurai of historical legend. Against the backdrop of the turbulent late Sengoku period, this remarkable duo will discover their common destiny as they usher in a new era for Japan.</em></p><p>Like Assassin’s Creed Mirage and the original AC before it, Shadows’ main targets can be assassinated in any order. “One thing that we really wanted is [to make] sure the world feels alive, and those targets are always in the world,” said game director Charles Benoit. “So it's possible that you’ll encounter some of them without really knowing about them before.</p><p>Quests, therefore, won’t point you toward your next target but will “guide” you with hints. “It's less of ‘follow a quest up to a point’, but it's much more, ‘I want to do this’ and then you'll find the way how to do it,” said creative director Jonathan Dumont. </p><h3>Feudal Japan Setting</h3><p>Assassin’s Creed is well known for its exploration of different places and eras with each new entry. This year’s game takes players to feudal Japan, specifically 1579 through the early 1580s. Shadows is set during the end of the tumultuous Sengoku period at the height of Oda Nobunaga’s power when the warlord overthrew the Ashikaga shogunate and began his campaign to unify the warring factions of Japan.</p><p>Central Japan, where Nobunaga held power, will serve as the center of Shadows. Locations we’ve seen in the hitherto released trailers include the Iga province and Takeda Castle.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3>Game Length and Map Size</h3><p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows is closest in size to 2017’s Egypt-set Assassin’s Creed Origins, according to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/japan-set-assassins-creed-shadows-is-around-the-same-size-as-assassins-creed-origins"><u>Dumont</u></a>. "It's in-line with the latest Assassin's Creeds that we've done," he said, referring to the series’ post-Syndicate RPGs. "On a scale level, maybe we can compare it a little bit more to the size of Assassin's Creed Origins.</p><p>"We did want to have a much closer to real life scale ratio,” Dumont added. “So because castles took a lot of space, and we really wanted the mountains to feel like mountains, [we've made] the environments feel wider in the game. But I would say around the same size as Origins."</p><p>Dumont didn’t comment on game length, though we’ll note Origins main story takes roughly 30 hours to complete, according to IGN sister site <a href="https://howlongtobeat.com/game/46402" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>How Long to Beat</u></a>.</p><h3>Does Assassin’s Creed Shadows Have a Modern-day Story?</h3><p>Ubisoft has yet to reveal details about Shadow’s potential modern-day segments, though it sounds like there will be one. Assassin’s Creed executive producer Marc-Alexis Côté told <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/assassins-creed-shadows-interview" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Game File</u></a>, “You are in the Animus,” when asked about the modern day in Shadows. He also revealed Assassin’s Creed Infinity will be known as the Animus hub and serve as a portal to the series’ modern-day sections moving forward.</p><p>This section will be updated as more information is announced.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 id="gameplay">Assassin’s Creed Shadows Gameplay</h2><h3>Yasuke and Naoe Differences</h3><p>Assassin’s Creed Shadows allows you to switch between Yasuke or Naoe at will, with the exception of introduction quests and character-specific missions.</p><p>Naoe plays as a more typical assassin; she’s equipped with a Hidden Blade and the ability to kill stealthily by scaling walls and hiding in foliage. As Naoe, you’ll also have access to throwable kunai and her chained blade, which is swung around to slice through enemies and environments. The assassin is also given a grappling hook to improve traversal; it can be attached to the edges of roofs and other miscellaneous anchor points. “It's all physics-based, so there's a little bit of improbability sometimes when using it,” said Dumont. “There's a danger to using it, but you could also perform assassinations from it.”</p><p>Yasuke, on the other hand, has a more head-on approach to combat; the samurai’s heavy armor keeps him on the ground, where he excels as a master swordsman.</p><p>Each character has individualized skill trees and gear, though XP, collected weapons, and resources are shared.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h3>General Combat</h3><p>Dumont says the team’s goal was to make Shadows’ combat feel “spectacular,” and to this end they’ve increased the amount of environmental items that can be carved up or destroyed and reintroduced instant kills with the Hidden Blade. “The thing that shines the most, I feel, in Assassin's Creed, it's really the Hidden Blade, the assassination, being able to stay hidden,” said Benoit. “So that's the core that we want to keep. What we needed to push forward [was to make it] feel a bit more modern in the approach.”</p><p>Shadows also adds duels reminiscent of those seen in Akira Kurosawa's samurai films. “When we have a mini-boss type of fighter, we really want it to feel like a duel,” said Benoit. “So this exchange of blocking, parrying, dodging. So it's always like a dance.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Assassin's Creed Shadows - Art and Concept Art</h3></div></output><p>Weapons you’ll acquire throughout Shadows include katanas, the kanabō war club, yari spears, shuriken, kunai, and the kusarigama (sickle on chain). Weapons have their own skill trees, and proficiency is increased by playing with each weapon. These can be found or crafted by gathering components throughout the game world. And yes, the ability to transmog is still here, allowing flexibility in the appearance of your gear.</p><p>Yasuke and Naoe will also be faced with a new enemy type: servants. These characters exist between civilians and enemies, and are able to raise alarms and call for reinforcements.</p><h3>Exploration and Traversal</h3><p>The big addition to Shadows world is a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-50-details-you-need-to-know"><u>light-dark system</u></a>, which has a major influence on the game’s stealth mechanics. Powered by an upgraded version of Ubisoft’s Anvil engine, Shadows global illumination system creates dynamic light and shadows that affect enemy vision. You can influence this by snuffing out lamps and taking out torch carriers. The degree to which you are hidden is displayed through a new light meter on the UI.</p><p>The light-dark system intersects with Shadows new seasons mechanic, which changes the terrain (and therefore how you interact with it) as spring turns to summer, fall, then winter. Seasonal differences include changes to weather/wind, bodies of water (swimmable or frozen), the height of grass, foliage, enemy positioning, and visibility. “Players will have to adapt constantly to what the environment is giving them,” said Dumont. The seasons will change as you progress through the main quest.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Eagle vision, which allows you to see characters through walls, returns in Shadows, though gone are the drone-like birds used to scout locations in Origins, Odyssey, and Valhalla. In an effort to reduce the amount of map icons, climbing to the top of synchronization points no longer unlocks a portion of the map, rather they provide a vantage point from which you can survey the surrounding area for highlighted points of interest. However, these locations still serve as fast-travel points.</p><p>Shadows will take you through Japan’s diverse landscape of towns, trading posts, farmland, mountains, forests, and historic castles rendered nearly to scale. Each castle serves as a type of bespoke dungeon, according to<strong> </strong>Benoit, who added, “It’s so big, it's like an adventure each time you go in the castle.”</p><h2>Assassin’s Creed Shadows Development</h2><p>Ubisoft Quebec is leading development of Assassin’s Creed Shadows. The studio previously headed up development on Assassin’s Creed Odyssey, Syndicate, and Black Flag, as well as 2020’s Immortals: Fenyx Rising. Over a dozen other Ubisoft studios are providing development support.</p><p>Jonathan Dumont, creative director of Assassin’s Creed Odyssey, is again overseeing the creative direction of Shadows. Charles Benoit, who served as a game designer on Odyssey, is the game director for Shadows.</p><p>Shadows was first announced in 2022 as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-infinity-announced-with-two-new-games"><u>Assassin’s Creed Codename Red</u></a>. It was officially named and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-trailer-release-date-dual-protagonists-and-more-revealed-by-ubisoft"><u>subsequently unveiled</u></a> in May 2024.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Every IGN Assassin's Creed Review</h3></div></output><h2>Assassin’s Creed Shadows Editions, Preorder Bonus</h2><p>Ubisoft is selling three <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-release-date-collectors-edition"><u>editions of Assassin’s Creed Shadows</u></a> — Standard, Gold, and Ultimate — as well as a GameStop-exclusive Collector’s Edition. Preordering any version will net you a bonus quest called “Thrown to the Dogs.”</p><p>Here’s everything you need to know about each edition:</p><p><strong>Standard Edition</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>$70 USD</li><li>Includes base game</li></ul><p><strong>Gold Edition</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>$110 USD</li><li>Includes base game</li><li>Three days of early access</li><li>Season Pass</li></ul><p><strong>Ultimate Edition</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>$130 USD</li><li>Includes base game</li><li>Three days of early access</li><li>Season Pass</li><li>The Ultimate Pack<ul data-cy="list"><li>Sekiryu character pack</li><li>Sekiryu hideout pack</li><li>5 skill points</li><li>Red dragon filter in photo mode</li></ul></li></ul><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p><strong>Collector’s Edition</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>$280 USD</li><li>Includes Ultimate Edition of game</li><li>Diorama figurine with dual protagonists</li><li>Steelbook</li><li>Hardcover artbook</li><li>Shinobi's metal tsuba replica with stand</li><li>Silk creed kakemono roll</li><li>Set of 3 sumi-e lithographs</li></ul><p>Separately, the IGN Store is offering a life-sized, officially licensed replica of <a href="https://store.ign.com/products/assassins-creed-yasuke-helmet-1-1-scale-replica" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Yasuke’s helmet</u></a>. This ultimate collector’s item is now available to preorder, with an estimated ship time of Q4 2024.</p><div id="202097" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p><h3>Assassin's Creed - Yasuke Helmet 1/1 Scale - Replica</h3></p></div><p><em>Jordan covers games, shows, and movies as a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard Will Feature A ‘Robust’ Transmog System At Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gameinformer.com/exclusive/2024/07/04/bespoke-armor-transmog-and-other-aspects-of-gear-in-dragon-age-the-veilguard</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-will-feature-a-%E2%80%98robust%E2%80%99-transmog-system-at-launch.919254/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gameinformer.com/exclusive/2024/07/04/bespoke-armor-transmog-and-other-aspects-of-gear-in-dragon-age-the-veilguard<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Dragon Age features a ton of different customization options. Just within the <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/exclusive/2024/06/13/a-deep-dive-into-dragon-age-the-veilguards-expansive-character-creator">character creator</a>, there are hundreds of options to customize things like hair, body type, what your playable character Rook's face looks like, and so much more. There are also a ton of armor options, too.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Companions have an armor slot, a ring slot, an accessory slot, and a weapon slot, while Rook has access to even more – a helmet, two weapon slots, a belt, an amulet slot, and two ring slots. A belt having its own slot might sound odd as it's not an armor piece people typically think of when kitting out an RPG warrior. However, the belt is an important facet of Rook's kit. The better Rook's belt, the better the potency of their healing potions, which are replenished by destroying green pots scattered about the world. That's not all, though, as higher-quality belts can proc [<em>editor's note</em>: proc is a term used as a shorter way of saying "programmed random occurrence"] additional effects like momentary invulnerability.&nbsp;</p>












<article data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.body_default_rendered" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="7e3bac2b-af4f-4b6b-89da-339d5d099bf6" data-langcode="en" data-entity-embed-display-settings="[]">





</article><p>When creating your character, you can immediately view aspirational armors, which won't play into Rook's class until the "mid-to-late game," according to game director Corinne Busche. You can also toggle Rook's starting gear and casual wear in the creator, giving you a pretty good look at how Rook will look in more laidback cutscenes, in combat, and how they might appear later in your Veilguard journey. Busche tells me a lot of the gear in Veilguard is bespoke to your Rook or their followers, which is to say, an armor piece for a Warrior-class Rook probably won't be in a chest for a Mage-class Rook. On a similar note, armor designed for companion Bellara Lutara can't be used for another companion like Lace Harding.</p>

<p>In just my few hours viewing Busche play the game as part of my visit to BioWare's Edmonton office for our current <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/cover-reveal/2024/06/09/cover-reveal-dragon-age-the-veilguard"><em>Game Informer </em>cover story</a>, I see a lot of armor to collect from things like chests scattered about Arlathan Forest, for example, and elsewhere. Some of it looks awesome, and some of it doesn't quite line up with my personal taste. That's how it goes in the genre of RPGs.</p>

<p>However, Busche tells me there is transmogrification, or transmog for short, in the game, and calls it "robust." This means you can take an armor's stats and apply it to a different piece of armor. In other words, if you have a really cool piece of armor you like and find a new piece with better stats but don't want to give up the look of your current armor, you don't have to. Transmog allows you to take that new armor's stats and apply them to your current armor, giving you all the benefits while keeping the visual style you prefer.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Transmog isnt just for Rook, though; you can transmog armor and other things for your companions as well. I don't get to see how Veilguard's transmog system works in-game, but just knowing it exists allows me to rest easy knowing my Rook will look as fashionable as possible while saving Thedas.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p>For more about the game, including exclusive details, interviews, video features, and more, click the Dragon Age: The Veilguard hub button below.&nbsp;</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guilty Gear Strive Anime Teaser Trailer Debuts At Anime Expo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/guilty-gear-strive-anime-teaser-trailer-debuts-at-anime-expo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/guilty-gear-strive-anime-teaser-trailer-debuts-at-anime-expo.919251/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/guilty-gear-strive-anime-teaser-trailer-debuts-at-anime-expo<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>During Anime Expo, Arc System Works unveiled a world premiere teaser trailer for its upcoming Guilty Gear anime, Guilty Gear Strive: Dual Rulers, which is set to be released sometime next year. </p><p>Guilty Gear Strive: Dual Riders is a 3D CG anime adaptation of the eponymous fighting game that is being animated by <a href="https://myanimelist.net/anime/producer/537/SANZIGEN" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>SANZIGEN</u></a>. While the teaser gave little away story-wise, the trailer did showcase the long-running fighting game's central characters, Sol Badguy and Sin Kiske. The trailer, which is stylized in a similar fashion to the game's cutscenes, pits the pair against a mysterious new foe named Unika, who has a grudge against Gears. </p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Arc System Works America (@ArcSystemWorksU) <a href="https://twitter.com/ArcSystemWorksU/status/1808932912542462425?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 4, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Guilty Gear stands head and shoulders above other fighting games series thanks in part to it being one of the flashiest anime fighters of all time. Consequently, Guilty Gear also has a reputation for being one of the <a href="https://youtu.be/QIjtNL7Pfqw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>hardest story timelines to follow</u></a>. A case in point is the fact that the story mode for Strive's predecessor, Guilty Gear Xrd Rev 2, is essentially an uninterrupted hour-long anime unto itself. For folks wondering where Guilty Gear Strive: Dual Riders will sit in the series storied lore, here's a plot synopsis for the show:</p><p>"After the decline of the once robust fields of science and technology, a new energy source known as magic fuels the modern era," the official description reads. "Humanity creates forbidden biological weapons: Gears. Those Gears eventually stand against humanity in a rebellion. Although they manage to overcome in the struggle for survival known as the Crusades, humanity’s losses are so great that even after several decades pass, their emotional wounds remain unable to fully heal. </p><p>"Sin Kiske, the child of a human and a Gear, heads to his father Ky and mother Dizzy’s wedding ceremony. Their wedding breaks the ultimate taboo: a union between a human and a Gear. Even with the world at peace, it took many years for such a ceremony to come to fruition. Despite the complex array of emotions surrounding it, the wedding ceremony is met with blessings. When suddenly, a mysterious girl appears… The fated child inheriting Gear blood–and the mysterious girl who despises Gears. Their meeting would shake the world."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>In <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/guilty-gear-strive-review"><u>our review</u></a> of Guilty Gear Strive, we gave the game a 9/10, saying, "Guilty Gear Strive sets a new standard for anime-like fighting games with its visuals, stellar netcode, and flexible fighting system that encourages and rewards creativity."</p><p>Isaiah Colbert is a freelance writer for IGN. You can follow them on Twitter @ShinEyeZehUhh.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horizon Zero Dawn TV Series No Longer Moving Forward at Netflix - Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/horizon-zero-dawn-tv-series-no-longer-moving-forward-at-netflix-report</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/horizon-zero-dawn-tv-series-no-longer-moving-forward-at-netflix-report.919248/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/horizon-zero-dawn-tv-series-no-longer-moving-forward-at-netflix-report<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The news was part of a report on The Umbrella Academy showrunner Steve Blackman.</h2></div><section><p>According to a report on the alleged "toxic, bullying, manipulative, and retaliatory behavior" of The Umbrella Academy showrunner Steve Blackman, The Horizon Zero Dawn TV series is seemingly not moving forward at Netflix.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-features/umbrella-academy-steve-blackman-abuse-allegations-1235047142/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rolling Stone,</a> twelve staffers and a HR complaint have detailed the hostle workplace that was said to have been fostered by Blackman, although the showrunner has said these claims are "entirely untrue" and "completely absurd." </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/04/horizonzerodawn-1280-1487544580639-1720123902519.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>At the end of the report, it is stated that Blackman was offered an overall development deal reportedly worth $50 million at Netflix in 2020, and the Horizon Zero Dawn series was part of that package alongside an original outer-space thriller series called Orbital.</p><p>Now, however, Rolling Stone has "learned that the two projects are no longer moving forward." Per a representative for Blackman, the showrunner "has a long, ongoing, and close working relationship with Netflix" and "continues to work on new projects." Furthermore, Blackman signed a "new multi-year deal earlier this year."</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/umbrella-academy-director-to-adapt-playstations-horizon-netflix-series">The Horizon Netflix series was revealed back in 2022</a> with Blackman as the showrunner, and it was going to star Aloy.</p><p>“Horizon Zero Dawn is an exceptionally well-crafted game with wonderful characters not often seen in the rank-and-file of the gaming world,” Blackman said at the time. “Guerrilla Games has created an incredibly lush and vivid world of man and machine who find themselves on a collision course to oblivion.</p><p>“Their salvation comes in the form of a young female warrior named Aloy, who has no idea she's the key to saving the world,” added Blackman. “Suffice it to say, yes, Aloy will be a main character in our story. My writing partner on this, Michelle Lovretta, and I are thrilled to be able to expand this remarkable IP into a series for all types of viewers.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Sony said back in January 2024 <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-shows-gravity-rush-movie-updates-on-god-of-war-and-horizon-shows">that writing had begun on the series,</a> but we haven't really learned anything else since.</p><p>For more, check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-horizon-adventures-preview-lets-do-a-silly-one">our preview of LEGO Horizon Adventures</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-reveals-the-shapes-collection-figures-with-god-of-war-horizon-and-ghost-of-tsushima">who will join Aloy as a figure in PlayStation's upcoming The Shapes Collection.</a></p><p><em>Have a tip for us? Want to discuss a possible story? Please send an email to </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/"><em>newstips@ign.com</em></a><em>.</em></p><p><em>Adam Bankhurst is a writer for IGN. You can follow him on X/Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/AdamBankhurst" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@AdamBankhurst</em></a><em> and on </em><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@adambankhurst" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>TikTok.</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Zenless Zone Zero Mobile Only? – Answered]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/zenless-zone-zero-mobile-only-answered/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/is-zenless-zone-zero-mobile-only-%E2%80%93-answered.919203/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/zenless-zone-zero-mobile-only-answered/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>The rise in popularity of gacha-style games, following the immense success of Genshin Impact and Honkai: Star Rail, led to additional titles from the same studio and many similar developers. But the former continues taking the world by storm, now with Zenless Zone Zero. But there’s a bit of confusion surrounding the release. Is Zenless Zone Zero mobile only?</p>



<h2 id="h-what-can-i-play-zenless-zone-zero-on">What Can I Play Zenless Zone Zero On?</h2>



<p>Thankfully, the answer to whether Zenless Zone Zero is mobile-only is a resounding “No.” You can play ZZZ on multiple systems, including PC, PlayStation 5, Android, and iOS. It’s free to play, though there are numerous microtransactions and in-game currencies to purchase with real-world money.</p>



<h2 id="h-is-zenless-zone-zero-on-console">Is Zenless Zone Zero on Console?</h2>



<p>Currently, the only console that supports Zenless Zone Zero is PlayStation 5. It’s unlikely miHoYo will backport the free-to-play gacha game to last-gen systems. Furthermore, none of their previous titles launched on Xbox Series X|S. We don’t expect this one to, either!</p>







<h2 id="h-is-zenless-zone-zero-free-on-ps5">Is Zenless Zone Zero Free on PS5?</h2>



<p>Yes! If you visit the PlayStation Store and search for “Zenless Zone Zero,” you’ll find the recent release completely free to download and play. There are no strings attached; add the game to your account, then wait for the rather large download size of around 60GB to finish before hopping in-game!</p>



<h2 id="h-will-zenless-zone-zero-be-on-nintendo-switch">Will Zenless Zone Zero Be On Nintendo Switch?</h2>



<p>Unfortunately, it’s improbable that Zenless Zone Zero will launch on Nintendo Switch. While the studio unveiled Genshin Impact for Nintendo Switch, it never came about. They went quiet following its announcement, and many still wait impatiently for the handheld’s chance to play.</p>



<p>It’s likely Zenless Zone Zero won’t even receive an empty announcement for a Nintendo Switch port.</p>



<hr>



<p>Once you hop into Zenless Zone Zero, learn <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-get-polychrome-in-zenless-zone-zero/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to earn Polychrome</a> to help improve your gameplay and strengthen your heroes. While you wait for the download to finish, why not sign up for the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>?</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guilty Gear Strive: Dual Rulers airs in 2025, teaser trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/guilty-gear-strive-dual-rulers-airs-in-2025-teaser-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/guilty-gear-strive-dual-rulers-airs-in-2025-teaser-trailer.919191/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/guilty-gear-strive-dual-rulers-airs-in-2025-teaser-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/anime">Anime</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>First look at the new Guilty Gear anime.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em>Guilty Gear Strive: Dual Rulers</em>, the <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/guilty-gear-strive-dual-rulers-anime-series-announced">newly announced</a> anime produced by SANZIGEN based on <a title="Companies > Arc System Works [1,249 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/arc-system-works">Arc System Works</a>‘ <em>Guilty Gear</em> franchise, will air in 2025, the company announced. <span id="more-896917"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the anime, via Arc System Works:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>After the decline of the once robust fields of science and technology, a new energy source known as magic fuels the modern era. Humanity creates forbidden biological weapons: Gears. Those Gears eventually stand against humanity in a rebellion. Although they manage to overcome in the struggle for <a title="Genres > Survival [294 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> known as the Crusades, humanity’s losses are so great that even after several decades pass, their emotional wounds remain unable to fully heal. Sin Kiske, the child of a human and a Gear, heads to his father Ky and mother Dizzy’s wedding ceremony. Their wedding breaks the ultimate taboo: a union between a human and a Gear. Even with the world at peace, it took many years for such a ceremony to come to fruition. Despite the complex array of emotions surrounding it, the wedding ceremony is met with blessings. When suddenly, a mysterious girl appears… The fated child inheriting Gear blood–and the mysterious girl who despises Gears. Their meeting would shake the world.</p><p><strong>Staff</strong></p><ul><li>Based on <em>Guilty Gear</em> by Arc System Works</li><li>Original Character Designs by Daisuke Ishiwatari (Arc System Works)</li><li>Directed by Shigeru Morikawa</li><li>Series Composition: Norimitsu Kaiho</li><li>Associate Producer: Seiji Mizushima</li><li>Animation Production: SANZIGEN Inc.</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Cast</strong></p><ul><li>Sin Kiske: Issei Miyazaki</li><li>Sol Badguy: Jouji Nakata</li><li>Unika: Yui Ishikawa</li><li>Narration: Tomokazu Sugita</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the teaser trailer below. Visit the official website <a href="https://www.guiltygear.com/ggstdr/en/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="『GUILTY GEAR STRIVE: DUAL RULERS』Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ODo4fjcPkbI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="TVアニメ『GUILTY GEAR STRIVE: DUAL RULERS』ティザーPV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BOZ6F9G5YX8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Suicide Squad Kill the Justice League Season 2 Is Out Next Week, Will Add Mrs. Freeze and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-season-2-is-out-next-week-will-add-mrs-freeze-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-season-2-is-out-next-week-will-add-mrs-freeze-and-more.919185/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-season-2-is-out-next-week-will-add-mrs-freeze-and-more/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>A few hours ago, Rocksteady sent out an email newsletter to announce the release date and details for Suicide Squad Kill the Justice League Season 2.</p>
<p>The big addition is the playable new character Mrs. Freeze, also known as Nora Fries. She's an alternate version of Mr. Freeze, who is more commonly found in DC adaptations (including Batman Arkham City, where the Caped Crusader fights him in one of the boss battles). The newsletter did not go into further details on Mrs. Freeze's moveset, but the developers will likely do so shortly, given that Season 2 is coming to Suicide Squad Kill the Justice League next Thursday.</p>
<p>Episode 3, called Frozen Hearts, will add an Elseworlds Mayhem map, a Superman versus Flash Brainiac fight, an 'ever-changing' Metropolis,&nbsp;new Infamy sets and Notorious gear such as the Killer Frost Infamy set, Firefly Notorious, and Parasite Notorious Melee, and of course, a new Battle Pass.</p>
<p>Episode 4, called Winter, brings a Green Lantern versus Superman Brainiac fight, new incursions, new Infamy sets and Notorious gear such as the Captain Cold Infamy set, Icicle Notorious, and Trickster Notorious Melee, and new Shop items.</p>
<p>It does look like Rocksteady will keep its promise to deliver four seasons of post-launch content for the game despite its massive failure. As revealed by parent company Warner Bros., Suicide Squad Kill the Justice League <a href="https://wccftech.com/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league-contributed-to-200-million-lower-ebitda-for-wb/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">contributed</a> to a $200 million lower EBITDA compared to last year's outstanding performance bolstered by Hogwarts Legacy. The game was also panned by critics, including Wccftech's Nathan Birch, who <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/suicide-squad-kill-the-justice-league/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">gave it just 5 out of 10</a>:</p>
<p><em>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League has a sprinkling of that classic Rocksteady charm, delivering polished visuals, fluid traversal and combat, and some snappy repartee, but the whole experience is bogged down by dreary, repetitive mission design, empty live service elements, and a feel-bad story that’s mean-spirited to the point of feeling oddly resentful.</em></p>
<p>The studio isn't at any risk of being shut down, though. According to Bloomberg's Jason Schreier, it will be given the chance to return to what it does best: a single-player game. Meanwhile, some Rocksteady employees <a href="https://wccftech.com/hogwarts-legacy-directors-cut/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">are helping on a Hogwarts Legacy Director's Cut</a>.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Disables Vehicles, Nitro Fists and More for Ranked Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-disables-vehicles-nitro-fists-and-more-for-ranked-mode/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-disables-vehicles-nitro-fists-and-more-for-ranked-mode.919182/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-disables-vehicles-nitro-fists-and-more-for-ranked-mode/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Fortnite has just announced the commencement of the <a href="https://x.com/FortniteGame/status/1808863497897304138" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">All Sweat Summer</a>, during which players can embark on exclusive quests to earn unique summer-themed rewards. In addition, Fortnite has decided to implement significant changes to the Ranked Mode as part of the All Sweat test. </p>



<p>These changes are designed to immerse players in a tournament-like experience. Discover all the alterations to Fortnite’s Ranked mode below.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-time-to-sweat">Time to Sweat</h2>



<p>The Fortnite Status account has announced a series of changes that will be implemented in Ranked Battle Royale and Zero Build between July 4 and July 18. Among these changes, all vehicles and vehicle items, including the upgraded boss cars, will be disabled. The unique and new weapon of Chapter 5, Season 3, the Nitro Fists, will also be disabled. </p>



<p>Lastly, players will no longer be able to hire characters, but enemy NPCs and Bosses with medallions will still be present. It’s time to bring out your competitive spirit, as Fortnite’s All Sweat Test for Ranked mode has begun. The development team will be closely monitoring player feedback during this time.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>During All Sweat Summer, Ranked Battle Royale and Zero Build will be switching things up a bit! From July 4 to July 18:</p><p>– Vehicles and vehicle items are disabled, including Boss Cars.<br>– Nitro Fists are also disabled.<br>– Characters are no longer Hireable, but hostile Characters… <a href="https://t.co/nLBFutgq7u">pic.twitter.com/nLBFutgq7u</a></p></div>— Fortnite Status (@FortniteStatus) <a href="https://twitter.com/FortniteStatus/status/1808864035380601000?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>For those wondering, you don’t need to worry about the entire season being vaulted; these changes only arrive for Fortnite’s Ranked Modes. The standard Battle Royale and Zero Build Mode will still include all the elements introduced for Fortnite’s Chapter 5 Season 3, Wrecked. </p>



<p>This consists of the newly announced <a href="https://x.com/FortniteGame/status/1808139084440736232" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Magneto mythic, </a>which allows players to defend themselves with a metal shield and shoot projectiles at other players, builds and vehicles to cause damage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nascar-integration-with-rocket-racing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nascar recently revealed a landmark integration </a>with Fortnite’s Rocket Racing Mode. Also, the official status account confirmed that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-pirates-of-the-caribbean/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pirates of the Caribbean collaboration will arrive on July 19</a>. What do you think about Fortnite’s Ranked Mode changes to make the game more sweaty? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-tokyo-game-show/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation announcing it will exhibit at the Tokyo Game Show this year </a>and sign up to receive the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Generative AI, Which Is The Future Of Art, Cannot Draw A Map Of The United States]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/generative-ai-map-of-the-united-states</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/generative-ai-which-is-the-future-of-art-cannot-draw-a-map-of-the-united-states.919167/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/generative-ai-map-of-the-united-states<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Maybe you’ve been on Twitter and seen the video of “<a href="https://x.com/bindureddy/status/1807928777357644027" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stunning AI spaghetti art</a>” that one gormless loser has claimed is proof that generative AI will one day win Oscars and Grammys. This is what I do every time I hear that claim: I ask ChatGPT to draw a map of the United States.</p><p>Before I show you the image that ChatpGPT produced for me today after being given the prompt “use ascii art to draw a map of the United States,” I want you to imagine the contours of the United States in your mind. It’s July 4th, after all, a day when we celebrate America’s freedoms, such as … and … and who could forget …. You might not be able to remember all of the states names, but I can picture the Florida panhandle and the weird triangle part of Texas and the curvature of California. Hold that image in your head, and now scroll down.</p><hr><figure></figure><p>Is this a fluke? A one off? No. Here’s another response to this prompt that looks like a little dog.</p><figure></figure><p>Generative AI is stupid. It is not a thinking machine. Art is made by people who can see and interpret symbols, and then re-interpret them into new images. At the very least it is made by people who can picture the United States in their mind and draw a vague outline of it when prompted. All the rest is stunning AI spaghetti art.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[16 Extraordinary Games You Need To Wishlist This Indie-Penance Day!]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/best-indie-games-steam-wishlist-indiepenance-day-1851577525</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/16-extraordinary-games-you-need-to-wishlist-this-indie-penance-day.919149/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/best-indie-games-steam-wishlist-indiepenance-day-1851577525<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="ca92b325cb4fe4ed18010002ad6a5f5a" data-recommend-id="image://ca92b325cb4fe4ed18010002ad6a5f5a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A battle scene in My Familiar, set in a diner." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A battle scene in My Familiar, set in a diner." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Chintzy Ink</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ca92b325cb4fe4ed18010002ad6a5f5a" data-recommend-id="image://ca92b325cb4fe4ed18010002ad6a5f5a" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A battle scene in My Familiar, set in a diner." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Astonishingly, this is the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/happy-indie-penance-day-1847230744&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/happy-indie-penance-day-1847230744">fourth</a></span> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/indie-games-pc-wishlist-steam-demo-free-coming-soon-1849140280&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/indie-games-pc-wishlist-steam-demo-free-coming-soon-1849140280">year</a></span> in a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/indie-games-pc-steam-indie-penance-smushi-come-home-1850604670&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/indie-games-pc-steam-indie-penance-smushi-come-home-1850604670">row</a></span> <em>Kotaku</em> has celebrated <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/search?blogId=9&amp;q=indie-penance&amp;timestamp=1720100447947&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/search?blogId=9&amp;q=indie-penance&amp;timestamp=1720100447947">Indie-Penance Day</a></span>, since the holiday was invented to mark the liberation of gaming from the cruel rule of the British monarchy. To mark the occasion, we’ve picked a selection of some of the most interesting, enticing, unknown upcoming indie games that deserve to be on your radar.<br></p><p>Oh my goodness, I cannot believe the range of fantastic-looking games we’ve got here. And I feel overwhelmingly guilty over the literally <em>hundreds</em> of games we haven’t included, that responded to our call-out.</p><p>I <em>implore</em> you, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/botherer/status/1808814782994117083&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/botherer/status/1808814782994117083" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">please go look through the 363</a></span> (at the time of writing) replies to this tweet, to see the most astounding variety of intriguing games. I’ve picked 16 of them at random here, but I could have kept going forever.</p><p>Yes, this is a slideshow. You will cope. It means we can write about unknown games <em>and</em> pay the staff. If you’re reading on mobile, it scrolls anyway, and if you’re not, narrow your browser until it tricks the site into thinking it’s in portrait. </p></div></div><div><p>It’s a roguelite! It’s a claw machine game! It’s a deckbuilder! No, agreed, that sounds like it makes no sense, but look at the video above! See! It’s a 2D <em>Slay the Spire</em>-style battling roguelite, but you get your weapons and attacks from a claw machine above you. I mean, that’s scientifically genius. It looks amazing, and will be in Early Access toward the end of 2024, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2356780/Dungeon_Clawler/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2356780/Dungeon_Clawler/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">there’s a demo</a></span> already. Also, it has the best name.</p><p>Developer: Stray Fawn Studio</p><p>Release Date: Q4 2024</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2356780/Dungeon_Clawler/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2356780/Dungeon_Clawler/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>Forget whether you can pet the dog. What about whether you can <em>be</em> the dog? <em>Tailgate</em> has you playing as a Labrador trying to find his way back to his owner, while solving a mystery. It’s a sniff-based third-person game, from a doggy’s perspective.</p><p>Developer: Dmytro Yarynych</p><p>Release Date: 2025</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/3046820/Tailgate/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3046820/Tailgate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p> Kimmo Lahtinen is the developer behind two brilliant and woefully under-noticed games, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/813450/Barbearian/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/813450/Barbearian/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Barbearian</em></a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1532520/Day_Repeat_Day/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1532520/Day_Repeat_Day/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Day Repeat Day</em></a></span>. The two games couldn’t be more different, and the same is true for Lahtinen’s next game, <em>Sektori</em>, a bullet-hell twin-stick techno shooter, with the stated intention to “transport you into another state of consciousness.”</p><p>Developer: Kimmo Lahtinen</p><p>Release Date: 2024</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2105620/Sektori/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2105620/Sektori/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>Very strong <em>Zelda</em> vibes in this “bite-sized” top-down retro RPG, except you’re not rescuing a princess. Nope, you’re rescuing your pup. This is from Canari, who gave us last year’s too-ignored <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lunark-rotoscoped-graphics-visuals-video-game-switch-pc-1850413622&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lunark-rotoscoped-graphics-visuals-video-game-switch-pc-1850413622"><em>Lunark</em></a></span>, and promises a story-mode that’s then followed up by a “50-floor ‘Death Tower’.”</p><p>Developer: Canari Games</p><p>Release Date: TBA</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2564860/Castaway/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2564860/Castaway/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>A Bollywood-inspired game, <em>Aikyam</em> looks <em>beautiful</em>. It describes itself as an RPG, while the footage seems to show some sort of QTE-based turn-based combat, all set within a paint-based explosion of color that seems very inspired by Holi.</p><p><em>Aikyam</em> is coming to consoles as well as PC, with the support of various Canadian funding groups. It looks very special.</p><p>Developer: Thousand Stars Studio</p><p>Release Date: TBA</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2363840/Aikyam/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2363840/Aikyam/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>We first saw a glimpse of <em>Exophobia</em>&nbsp;<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/if-you-want-indie-gaming-news-you-just-have-to-ask-1847004718&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/if-you-want-indie-gaming-news-you-just-have-to-ask-1847004718">back in 2021</a></span>, and now the 2.5D shooter is due to finally release toward the end of the month. Combining boomer shooter with Metroidvania, it’s about exploring a crashed spaceship, upgrading your weapons and powerups, and shooting hordes of enemies. And it looks fab.</p><p>Developer: Zarc Attack</p><p>Release Date: 23 July</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1189220/Exophobia/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1189220/Exophobia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>A black-and-white time-loop murder mystery, set in Brazil! It’s hard to argue you’ve played too many of those. However, rather than just looping against your will, here the game is about manipulating the situation to uncover all the secrets and solve the crime.</p><p><em>The Posthumous Investigation</em> is inspired by the works of 19th century Brazilian author, Machado De Assis, who I could pretend to have heard of, or just link you to the same <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machado_de_Assis&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machado_de_Assis" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wikipedia article I just read</a></span>.</p><p>This is coming from the co-developer of mobile game <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://slashquest.com/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://slashquest.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Slash Quest</em></a></span>, which by odd coincidence is the game I’ve been playing on my tablet all week.</p><p>Developer: Mother Gaia Studio</p><p>Release Date: Q4 2024</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2718010/Slash_Quest/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2718010/Slash_Quest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>Crafting games pretty much took over for a while there. But oddly, not a single one of them actually involved any <em>crafting</em>. <em>CraftCraft </em>looks to address this anomaly, letting you scavenge parts to build your own objet d’art, which you can then sell in your shop.</p><p>Add to that the ability to befriend and romance your customers, and this looks like a winner. This is from the same team that gave us delightful oddity <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1166290/Death_and_Taxes/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1166290/Death_and_Taxes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Death and Taxes</em></a></span><em> </em>back in 2020, so it’s great to see them return.</p><p>Developer: Placeholder Gameworks</p><p>Release Date: November 20</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2226430/CraftCraft_Fantasy_Merchant_Simulator/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2226430/CraftCraft_Fantasy_Merchant_Simulator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>Nope, not a typo, it’s really <em>Mushroom Musume</em>. A spelling that isn’t even close to as strange as the game. This is about raising your very out mushroom child, from spore to... young woman? Calling itself a “life simulation game,” it sure looks a lot more like a super-fucked-up RPG to me, and I am very much wishlisting it as I type this. (Literally, I stopped mid-sentence and did it.) Ooh, and there’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2484580/Mushroom_Musume/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2484580/Mushroom_Musume/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a demo</a></span>.</p><p>Did the trailer... did it say “commit murder”?</p><p>Developer: Mortally Moonstruck Games</p><p>Release Date: Q4 2024</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2484580/Mushroom_Musume/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2484580/Mushroom_Musume/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>OMG, you <em>have</em> to check out the trailer above. Not only does <em>My Familiar</em> look utterly incredible, but the song! It’s by <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@megaran&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/@megaran" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mega Ran</a></span>, and what a track.</p><p>Meanwhile, back at the game, this is a turn-based “Isekai” RPG, where you must “fight, flee, and aggressively rap your way through a vibrant inner city gauntlet.” It looks stunning, and despite the far-off release date, there’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1502750/My_Familiar/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1502750/My_Familiar/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a demo</a></span> already. Which I am now downloading. This looks like it deserves to go <em>huge</em>.</p><p>Developer: Chintzy Ink</p><p>Release Date: Q4 2025</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1502750/My_Familiar/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1502750/My_Familiar/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p><p>Meanwhile, check out Mega Ran’s ode to fruit.</p></div><div><p>Are they voxels? They <em>are</em> voxels! <em>Dawn Apart </em>is a fully destructible base-building sim, that’s combining building a space colony with the high fashion of factory building. It’s about, um, colonizing a planet and exploiting its resources, so you’ll also want to defend your buildings from the locals. Except—phew—apparently you can just jack all that in and instead try to destroy the corporation by starting a rebellion!</p><p>Developer: Industrial Technology and Witchcraft</p><p>Release Date: TBA</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1866300/Dawn_Apart/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1866300/Dawn_Apart/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>My job here is to write a useful summary of what the game’s about, but having watched the trailer above I just want to make explodey-bang noises with my mouth, then pa-chew pa-chew sounds as I pretend to fire magic spells. I think that would be the perfect description of <em>Blood For The Old Gods</em>. </p><p>It describes itself as “a flintlock fantasy roguelite where you shoot, summon, and survive your way across the war-torn countryside,” but I still think “pa-chew!” captures it better. This looks stunning!</p><p>Developer: Foggy Box Games</p><p>Release Date: “Early Access Soon”</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2668030/Blood_for_the_Old_Gods/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2668030/Blood_for_the_Old_Gods/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>In case you’ve ever wondered what the criteria for guaranteed inclusion in a list like this might be, I will reveal it to you for reading all the way through this slideshow. It’s making your game entirely out of scanned-in pieces of fabric. Shhhh, don’t tell anyone else.</p><p>That’s why <em>Hyperdrive Inn</em> is here, an adventure game set in an infinite hotel “on the edge of collapse.” It looks spectacularly bonkers, and there’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2561260/Hyperdrive_Inn/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2561260/Hyperdrive_Inn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a demo</a></span> to make sure.</p><p>Developer: Horsefly Games</p><p>Release Date: October</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2561260/Hyperdrive_Inn/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2561260/Hyperdrive_Inn/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>Third-person story-led game <em>Spiral</em> has a wonderful-looking aesthetic, and a very tough-sounding subject matter. It’s a game about cognitive degeneration, as an older man called Bernard says goodbye to his childhood memories. Handled well, this could be very touching. There’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1579390/Spiral/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1579390/Spiral/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a demo</a></span> ahead of a September release.</p><p>Developer: Folklore Games</p><p>Release Date: September</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1579390/Spiral/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1579390/Spiral/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>This looks a bit like if <em>Hades</em> hated you. A really ace-looking roguelite brawler, set in the world of an ‘80s graphic novel, in what promises to be a “punishing” game.</p><p>What stands out to me in the trailer is how your own character’s attacks are telegraphed in the same way as the enemies’, with marks on the ground in front of you—I think that could be a really neat design. Oh, and all the blood. There’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1266060/Lethal_Honor__Order_of_the_Apocalypse/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1266060/Lethal_Honor__Order_of_the_Apocalypse/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a demo</a></span>, too.</p><p>Developer: Viral Studios</p><p>Release Date: 2024</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1266060/Lethal_Honor__Order_of_the_Apocalypse/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1266060/Lethal_Honor__Order_of_the_Apocalypse/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p></div><div><p>The stranger the premise, the more intrigued I become. <em>Underboard</em> wins here, with an aut0-battler set on a chess board that’s all about team-building. Yes please.</p><p>You apparently will assign rules, spells and tactics to your team of characters before a battle, and then watch it play out accordingly. It looks absolutely ludicrous, and I can’t wait.</p><p>Developer: Headless</p><p>Release Date: 2025</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2376610/Underboard/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2376610/Underboard/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wishlist</a></span></p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Online Adds 7 Classic Titles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-online-adds-7-classic-titles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-online-adds-7-classic-titles.919131/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-online-adds-7-classic-titles<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Urban Champion, Golf, and more.</h2></div><section><p>Nintendo has added seven classic titles to the Nintendo Switch Online library including Urban Champion, Golf, and more.</p><p>Revealed on X/Twitter, the other games joining the collection — which will be available at no extra cost to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-online-expansion-pack-release-date-pricing-n64-sega-games">users who have a Nintendo Switch Online membership and have purchased the Expansion Pass</a> — include Donkey Kong Jr. Math, Mach Rider, The Mystery of Atlantis, Solar Jetman, and Cobra Triangle.</p><p>All titles come as part of the Nintendo Entertainment System library. Urban Champion is a fighting game released in 1984, Golf is, well, a golf game released in the same year, and Donkey Kong Jr. Math is an educational game from 1986.</p><p>The first racing game among the new additions comes in Mach Rider, a vehicular combat racing game also from 1986. In a similar vein comes Cobra Triangle, a 1989 game from Rare, where players control a speedboat equipped with weapons.</p><p>The Mystery of Atlantis, meanwhile, is a side scrolling platformer, and Solar Jetman: Hunt for the Golden Warship is a shooter.</p><p>Nintendo periodically adds a handful of classic titles to its myriad Switch Online libraries, which also includes games from the Super Nintendo Entertainment System, Nintendo 64, Game Boy, and more.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Heaven Burns Red – English version announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/heaven-burns-red-english-version-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heaven-burns-red-%E2%80%93-english-version-announced.919128/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/heaven-burns-red-english-version-announced<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Free-to-play story-driven RPG published by Yostar.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Yostar will release an English vesrion of Key and <a title="Companies > WFS [38 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gree/wfs">WFS</a>-developed <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [287 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> story-driven RPG <em><a title="Games > Heaven Burns Red [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/heaven-burns-red">Heaven Burns Red</a></em>, the publisher <a href="https://yo-star.com/en-us/news/18" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-896889"></span></p><p><em>Heaven Burns Red</em> first launched for iOS and Android on February 10, 2022 in Japan, followed by <a title="Platforms > PC [20,598 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam on August 10, 2022.</p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>About the Game</strong></p><p>Co-developed by Wright Flyer Studios and <a title="Companies > Visual Arts [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/visual-arts">Visual Arts</a> / Key , this story-driven RPG was first released in 2022 in Japan. It has garnered major accolades at the Google Play Best of 2022 Awards, claiming titles such as “Best Game 2022,” “User Voting Category Game Category Grand Prize,” and “Story Category Award.”  </p><p><strong>Discover the Intricate World of <em>Heaven Burns Red</em></strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><a title="Games > Besiege" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/besiege">Besiege</a>d by mysterious life-forms known as “the Phage,” Earth teeters on the brink of ruin. All human weaponry proved futile against the Phage’s onslaught, and without any means to fight back, humanity has been forced to retreat. Land was forsaken, and nations were erased in the ensuing chaos. Now, over half of the Earth’s surface has been lost to the Phage.</p><p>With little time left and the danger of extinction looming, humans developed a brand-new, ultimate weapon called “Seraph,” and those endowed with Seraphim can finally fight against the Phage with vigor. Those who can master their Seraphim are gathered to create a special squadron, becoming humanity’s last beacon of hope. They have one thing in common: they are all girls with special talents. Among them stands Ruka Kayamori, poised to throw herself into the war against the Phage. </p><p><strong>Highlights from <em>Heaven Burns Red</em></strong></p><p><em>Heaven Burns Red</em> is a story-driven <a title="Genres > RPG [16,399 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">role-playing game</a> co-developed by Wright Flyer Studios and Visual Arts / Key. This title is Jun Maeda’s first completely new game in 15 years. As a narrative-centric RPG, <em>Heaven Burns Red</em> uses a timeline narrative design to advance the story, breaking new ground in the RPG genre by offering an engaging and evolving storyline driven by player choices. Players will experience fierce battles through the eyes of Ruka Kayamori as well as the value of each day in the deeply immersive world of <em>Heaven Burns Red</em>. </p><p><strong>English Version First Reveal at <a title="Platforms > Anime [316 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/anime">Anime</a> Expo 2024</strong></p><p>Leveraging the influential platform of Anime Expo 2024, Yostar will introduce <em>Heaven Burns Red</em> to the international gaming community. Attendees who come to the Yostar booth at Anime Expo 2024 will witness the sophisticated graphics, elaborate character artistry, and well-crafted music of <em>Heaven Burns Red</em>.</p><p><strong>Special Message from Jun Maeda</strong></p><p>“Hello, everyone, this is Jun Maeda. You may have heard of the global craze for taiyaki inspired by the work <em><a title="Games > Kanon [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/kanon">Kanon</a></em>, but are you familiar with its original creator and head writer, Naoki Hisaya? I had the honor of being a sub-writer for that project. Naoki Hisaya started the trend of ‘<a title="Genres > Visual Novel [417 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel">visual novel</a>s that make players cry,’ a pursuit that I have passionately followed for over 20 years. The pinnacle of this journey is <em>Heaven Burns Red</em>. Whereas Hisaya used sophisticated storytelling techniques to evoke tears, I took a rather direct approach, and that’s the essence of <em>Heaven Burns Red</em>. To think that this work would be released in places where he sparked the taiyaki craze—such a delightful coincidence feels like fate. We eagerly look forward to sharing <em>Heaven Burns Red</em> with you. Thank you.”</p><p>Jun Maeda, a Japanese writer and composer. He is considered a pioneer of visual novel and his notable works includes <em>AIR</em>, <em>CLANNAD</em>, <em>Little Busters!</em>, and <em>Angel Beats!</em>. </p></blockquote><p>Watch the western announcement trailer and a video message from Jun Maeda below. Visit the official English website <a href="https://heavenburnsred.yo-star.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Reveal Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Heaven Burns Red - Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rd-xsR3GRsE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>A Special Message from Jun Maeda</span></h2><p><iframe title="A Special Message from Jun Maeda [Heaven Burns Red]" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yRGlIT8xjt4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>