<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:08:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake Review - All That Glitters Are Pixels]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-review-all-that-glitters-are-pixels</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-review-all-that-glitters-are-pixels.1034928/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-review-all-that-glitters-are-pixels<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>To the average gamer, 1988’s <em>Dragon Quest III: The Seeds of Salvation</em> may seem like just another <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/features/history-dragon-quest" rel="nofollow"><em>Dragon Quest</em></a> game that was released for the NES. In fact, the original "<em>Dragon Warrior III,</em>" as it was known in the West, didn’t really take off outside of Japan, but the game’s impact on the future of gaming is significant. It was the first mainstream game to have such a versatile job system, feature a day and night cycle, and let you swap your party members in and out.</p>

<p>As a newcomer that’s been a fan of the franchise since <em>Dragon Quest XI</em>, the NES trilogy has been one that I’ve never been able to get into. While grinding for hours to level up and clear a dungeon was the norm back in those days, it’s an absolute slog to do so today. And so, I moved onto trying out the more recent titles and remasters.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/20241025214621_1.jpg?itok=gaBryHuW 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/20241025214621_1.jpg?itok=Geq7gWKk 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>I was elated beyond measure when <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> was announced. The <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/octopath-traveler-ii-review" rel="nofollow"><em>Octopath Traveler</em></a> series is one I hold close to my heart, so <em>Dragon Quest III</em> getting the HD-2D treatment felt perfect. Not to mention, <em>Dragon Quest</em> fans have been getting crumbs in the form of low-budget <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/dragon-quest-treasures-review" rel="nofollow">spinoffs</a>. A remake was definitely in order. Needless to say, I went into <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> with a lot of excitement and expectations, but what was to follow was pretty…underwhelming.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There’s no doubt about the fact that graphically, this game is gorgeous. The HD-2D look is a wonderful visual facelift from <em>Dragon Quest III</em>’s 16-bit pixel art. From the very moment you’re plopped into the game as the main character, you’re surrounded by lush greenery and flowing waterfalls.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A mysterious voice asks you some very thorough questions to determine your character, and by thorough, I mean questions like, “Do you believe the world to be filled with more sadness than with joy?” I was not expecting to be asked that on a Tuesday morning, that’s for sure. Depending on your characters, you get assigned a personality type, something that’s significant to the way your character’s abilities grow, but more on that later.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/20241025223449_1.jpg?itok=MHTUuzhK 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/20241025223449_1.jpg?itok=KemdvhRv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>You later awake on your 16th birthday, and have an audience with the King of Aliahan. Your father is the legendary warrior, Ortega, but after he perishes in his quest to destroy the evil Baramos, it’s time that you assume his mantle. And so, you go and find some party members to recruit, or in my case, create.</p>

<p>The original <em>Dragon Quest III</em> was praised for letting you choose which class of characters you could hire. Later, once they reach level 20, you can change their class again and go back to level 1 while still retaining your spells and abilities. <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> takes this a step further and gives you 5 additional seeds with which you can increase their default stats. Additionally, the remake gives you the option of the new monster wrangler class. I had a monster wrangler in my party throughout the game, and they definitely became my most useful character.</p>

<p>Back to the personality type system, it felt like more of a hindrance than anything, as it added nothing to the game apart from changing how your character’s stats evolved. You’ll be able to randomly find books in chests and bookshelves throughout the game, and having a character read them will alter their personality, but you don’t get to know how that affects their stats. I ended up just giving my characters books to read according to what personalities I had imagined them to have. Yes, you can even change the protagonist’s personality, so the quiz in the beginning feels a bit redundant.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/20241025233728_1.jpg?itok=v02lvbas 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/20241025233728_1.jpg?itok=pheuSFSz 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>I don't want to sugarcoat it, this game is an absolute snoozefest when it comes to combat. I mentioned earlier that the NES games were simply too boring for me to get into. Well, <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> follows the same framework of the original’s combat. Turn-based combat and random encounters are really no problem for me when it’s well-executed, but <em>Dragon Quest III</em>’s combat feels ancient. I was really hoping that the remake would bring some intuitiveness into the game, such as <em>Dragon Quest XI</em>’s pep powers, but it’s barebones traditional JRPG combat.</p>

<p>While that wouldn’t be so bad, there’s a bunch of quality-of-life improvements that are definitely missing. For starters, the lack of a turn indicator is a huge inconvenience, especially when a single enemy can end up attacking three turns in a row and kill your healer. Any strategies that you might want to execute just end up being thrown to the winds.</p>

<p>Also, the fact that you need to assign items to your party members is a completely unnecessary chore. The item bag exists for a reason! It makes complete sense to be able to use it in combat, but I guess I’ll die just because I didn’t have any medicine on me at the time. Sure, there are other quality-of-life features, such as being able to adjust the battle speed and three different difficulty settings, but the game definitely needs a lot more to make the combat palatable for the modern day.&nbsp;</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/20241111182315_1-large.jpg?itok=hAJ0Dnqe 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/20241111182315_1-large.jpg?itok=UaiVaEid 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>There are also monster arenas where you can make the monsters you’ve rescued take place in tournaments against other monsters, but even that ended up being a bit of a disappointment. You can only advise your monsters as to how they should fight, so one might have to ‘Fight wisely’ while the other needs to ‘Focus on healing.’ These weren’t particularly fun as I would much rather be able to give them commands à la Pokemon, so I only went to the arenas a couple of times when I needed the money to buy some new equipment.</p>

<p>There’s not really a whole lot of changes going on in the story department either. <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> follows the same story as the original with a few additional scenes featuring the Hero and their father. For how long this game is, I was really hoping it wasn’t just tidbits of story every 10 hours or so. I can see how narratively all the twists and turns in the game would have made this game a real masterpiece in 1988. Even for today’s standards, it’s a decent story, but nothing to write home about.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The atmosphere of the game sort of makes up for that though, as it’s a beautiful world to be in. I had a blast exploring each town and taking in the details. The little birds that fly away as you walk near them, the glowing plants at night in the Faerie Village, and even the damp caves that lurk below. The addition of voice acting is welcome, and whether big character or NPC, the performances are superb. While all of the music is reused from the original, the symphonic arrangements are soothing, although the battle theme did get on my nerves around the 20-hour mark.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/20241110193454_1.jpg?itok=TmXVl6tn 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/20241110193454_1.jpg?itok=Ets3bWnc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2><em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>There's a lot to love in <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em>. The spritework is fantastic, the music is soothing, and it's a world that you want to live in and explore. That being said, there's just as much to loathe. Given the number of random encounters you'll have to face, the combat holds back the game a lot. It also feels like a missed opportunity to expand upon the original's story. By today's standards, the game feels dated, much unlike the game from 1988 that lit a fire under gamers and developers alike.</p>

<p>Everyone’s expectations for remakes are, of course, different, but I was hoping for more than just a fresh coat of paint from the <em>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</em>. For fans of the original, I’m sure the game will meet their wishes, but it’s not a game I’d recommend to newer fans or to today’s JRPG aficionados looking to get into the franchise.&nbsp;</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Dragon Quest III HD-2D</strong> Remake was reviewed on PC with a copy provided by the publisher over the course of 40 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Workers at Bethesda parent company strike over remote work policies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295556/video-game-developer-strike-zenimax-microsoft</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/workers-at-bethesda-parent-company-strike-over-remote-work-policies.1034925/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295556/video-game-developer-strike-zenimax-microsoft<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The members of ZeniMax Workers United-CWA, one of the largest video game unions in the United States, have gone on strike. The action involves workers in ZeniMax offices in Texas and Maryland, who do quality assurance work for games including<em> Fallout</em> and <em>Elder Scrolls</em>. Workers are striking over claims that ZeniMax leadership has failed to address employee issues regarding remote work and outsourcing. </p><p>“Today, we are on strike,” <a href="https://x.com/ZeniMaxWorkers/status/1856714377992278336">ZeniMax Workers United posted on X</a>. “We are not afraid to do what’s necessary to make sure that Microsoft meets us at the bargaining table over key issues like remote work options and outsourcing.”</p><div><p>ZeniMax Workers United is made up of approximately 300 quality assurance testers. When the union <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/1/3/23537455/microsoft-has-formally-recognized-the-zenimax-union">was formally recognized in January 2023</a>, it became parent company <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/12/5/23495139/microsoft-union-zenimax-bethesda-cwa">Microsoft’s first union</a> and, at the time, was the largest video game union in the United States. Just a few months later in March, that title was eclipsed by the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/8/24094602/activision-blizzard-qa-workers-unionizing-microsoft">600 members of Activision Quality Assurance United</a>, another union under Microsoft’s corporate umbrella.</p></div><p>Remote work policies seem to be a major sticking point for Microsoft’s video game unions. In the immediate outbreak of the covid-19 pandemic, many video game companies instituted flexible work-from-home policies that they’ve <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24290345/return-to-office-mandates-amazon-productivity-remote-work-hybrid-decoder-podcast">recently begun rolling back</a>. In October of this year, Activision Quality Assurance United held a rally outside their offices in Texas, California, and Minnesota <a href="https://cwa-union.org/news/cwa-members-activision-qa-rally-remote-work-options">to protest Microsoft’s restrictive return-to-office polic</a>y that, according to workers, failed to accommodate workers with medical issues or doctor recommendations. The Communications Workers of America (CWA), the organizing committee that supports ZeniMax Workers United along with multiple video game unions in the US, has also filed an unfair labor complaint with the National Labor Relations Board over contracting out work without notifying the union.</p><p>There have been several video game-related strikes in the US in recent year. In 2021, workers at Raven Software — a subsidiary of Activision Blizzard before its eventual acquisition by Microsoft — participated in <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/6/22820549/activision-blizzard-raven-software-layoffs-walkout-call-of-duty">a walkout</a> that turned into a five-week strike after several employee contracts were not renewed. After that strike, workers at Raven Software <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/21/22894964/activision-blizzard-raven-software-employees-create-game-workers-alliance-union">organized and won one of the first video game unions at a AAA game publisher</a> in the country.</p><p>In July of this year, voice actors and motion performers covered under SAG-AFTRA’s interactive media agreement <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/25/24206357/video-game-performer-strike-sag-aftra">went on strike</a> to protest <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/5/24213808/video-game-voice-actor-strike-sag-aftra">worker protections regarding AI</a>. While SAG-AFTRA and the video game companies that make up the interactive media agreement bargaining committee <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/15/24270821/sag-aftra-video-game-voice-actor-strike-resume-negotiations">have returned to the negotiation table</a>, the strike continues. </p><p>ZeniMax Workers United strike will not last as long as SAG-AFTRA’s or Raven Software’s, with workers striking today until 6PM ET. In a statement to <em>The Verge</em>, Microsoft spokesperson Becca Dougherty wrote, “We respect our employees’ rights to express their point of view as they have done today. We will continue to listen and&nbsp;address their concerns at the bargaining table.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Boss Says No 'Red Line' With Exclusives, Including Even Halo]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-boss-spencer-halo-ps5-switch-exclusive-no-red-line-1851697549</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-boss-says-no-red-line-with-exclusives-including-even-halo.1034922/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/xbox-boss-spencer-halo-ps5-switch-exclusive-no-red-line-1851697549<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Earlier this year, Xbox brought some of its games to PlayStation 5 and Switch. Apparently that worked pretty well, as<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-phil-spencer-layoffs-hi-fi-rush-studios-closed-1851461546&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-phil-spencer-layoffs-hi-fi-rush-studios-closed-1851461546"> Microsoft’s CEO of gaming Phil Spencer</a></span> says more of its games are coming to other platforms, and that might even include the Xbox’s crown jewels, like the next <em>Halo </em>game. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196181" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="196181,196230,197298" data-current="196181"><div><p>The Best Reveals From The Game Awards 2023</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196181/196181_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21718.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>In February 2024, the first <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-starfield-ps5-hi-fi-rush-sea-of-thieves-1851225324&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-starfield-ps5-hi-fi-rush-sea-of-thieves-1851225324">reports surfaced</a></span> claiming <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-games-rumored-for-playstation-and-switch-1851239628&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-games-rumored-for-playstation-and-switch-1851239628">Xbox was planning</a></span> to bring some of its previously Xbox-exclusive games to other consoles. The news led to an <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-fans-content-creators-ps5-ports-starfield-rumors-1851230962?_gl=1*6ndmfk*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUxNjI0MS4yOS4wLjE3MzE1MTYyNDEuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-fans-content-creators-ps5-ports-starfield-rumors-1851230962?_gl=1*6ndmfk*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUxNjI0MS4yOS4wLjE3MzE1MTYyNDEuNjAuMC4w" target="_blank">Xbox fan community meltdown.</a></span> Eventually, four games—<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/hifi-rush-pentiment-xbox-multiplatform-1851262144&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/hifi-rush-pentiment-xbox-multiplatform-1851262144" target="_blank"><em>Sea of Thieves, Grounded, Penteniment, </em>and <em>Hi-Fi Rush</em></a></span>—made the leap to PlayStation and Nintendo Switch. Then in August, Xbox revealed that the Bethesda-published <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-game-pass-ps5-exclusive-1851626140&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-game-pass-ps5-exclusive-1851626140"><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em></a></span> would land on PS5 in Spring 2025, after being announced as an Xbox console exclusive. And if you thought that was the end of the Xbox games going multiplatform, you were very wrong.</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-13/microsoft-s-gaming-chief-is-still-looking-for-acquisitions-sees-future-growth?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTczMTQ5OTU0MSwiZXhwIjoxNzMyMTA0MzQxLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTTVcxQ01UMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.UjaVdB-1hJKO1VKY0-vUQaOjf2cpmUgGaLSXNqqYnHU&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-13/microsoft-s-gaming-chief-is-still-looking-for-acquisitions-sees-future-growth?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTczMTQ5OTU0MSwiZXhwIjoxNzMyMTA0MzQxLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJTTVcxQ01UMEcxS1cwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJCMUVBQkI5NjQ2QUM0REZFQTJBRkI4MjI1MzgyQTJFQSJ9.UjaVdB-1hJKO1VKY0-vUQaOjf2cpmUgGaLSXNqqYnHU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">In a November 13 Bloomberg interview</a></span>, Phil Spencer talked about the future of Xbox and the company’s plans for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/microsoft-xbox-pc-gaming-handheld-steam-deck-game-pass-1851697278&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-xbox-pc-gaming-handheld-steam-deck-game-pass-1851697278">a handheld Steam Deck-like device</a></span>. In the the conversation, Spencer also said he was “pleased” with the results of bringing Xbox games to other consoles and confirmed <em>any</em> game could make the leap. </p><p>“I do not see sort of red lines in our portfolio that say ‘thou must not,’” Spencer told <em>Bloomberg</em>. He also suggested that even <em>Halo </em>could make the leap, adding:  ‘It’s too early to make any sort of decision on the next version of <em>Halo</em>.” </p><p>That’s not a yes, but the fact that he’s openly talking about <em>Halo </em>on PlayStation is pretty remarkable considering how important the franchise has been to Microsoft for over 20 years. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/xbox-microsoft-ceo-halo-ps5-more-multiplatform-games-1851482805&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-microsoft-ceo-halo-ps5-more-multiplatform-games-1851482805">A report in May</a></span> claimed that Microsoft’s CEO, Satya Nadella, was pushing for more Xbox games to make the transition to PlayStation and Switch. Reportedly, after buying <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/microsoft-activision-blizzard-acquisition-game-pass-1850923561&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-activision-blizzard-acquisition-game-pass-1850923561">Activision for $69 billion</a></span>, the leadership at Microsoft was now watching Xbox very closely and wanted more growth. According to Spencer, “The Xbox business has never been more healthy.” But there’s always room for more growth and bigger numbers when you are part of a massive corporation. And if that means putting Master Chief on PS5, then that will happen sooner rather than later. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Brings Back Grand Theft Auto V And A Bunch Of Other Big Games]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-new-games-november-2024-gta-5-dying-light-2-1851697560</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-brings-back-grand-theft-auto-v-and-a-bunch-of-other-big-games.1034919/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-new-games-november-2024-gta-5-dying-light-2-1851697560<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="d7e4a6c3abc0dcc14d087443cf19c8e5" data-recommend-id="image://d7e4a6c3abc0dcc14d087443cf19c8e5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1393" data-height="783" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Rockstar Games</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d7e4a6c3abc0dcc14d087443cf19c8e5" data-recommend-id="image://d7e4a6c3abc0dcc14d087443cf19c8e5" data-format="jpg" data-width="1393" data-height="783" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The last few months of PlayStation Plus’ subscription catalog have been a  rollercoaster ride of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-premium-extra-games-september-plucky-squire-ps5-1851645955&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-premium-extra-games-september-plucky-squire-ps5-1851645955">great new additions</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-ps5-october-2024-red-dead-2-kingdom-hearts-gta-1851672709&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ps-plus-ps5-october-2024-red-dead-2-kingdom-hearts-gta-1851672709">some big departures</a></span>. November continues the whiplash with a bunch of big names joining the paid service including <em>Grand Theft Auto V</em> and <em>Dying Light 2</em>. If you’ve somehow managed to go 11 years without ever dipping your toes into Rockstar Games’ open-world hit, opportunity has once again come knocking. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196230" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Cool New Retro Console Is A Great Gift For Atari Fans" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="217" data-playlist="196230,196447,195410" data-current="196230"><div><p>This Cool New Retro Console Is A Great Gift For Atari Fans</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196230/196230_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21779.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Sony announced the full list of new PS Plus games for November 2024 in both the Extra and Premier tiers—the more expensive all-you-can-eat buffets rather than the monthly a-la-carte deals. In addition to<em> GTA V</em> and the parkour zombie RPG, <em>Like a Dragon: Ishin</em> and <em>Digimon Survive</em> are also joining the Netflix-like library, while <em>Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain </em>and <em>Resistance: Fall of Man</em> join the ranks of the PlayStation classics section. </p><p>Here’s the full list:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p><strong>PS Plus Extra</strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>Grand Theft Auto V</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Dying Light 2: Stay Human</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Like a Dragon: Ishin</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>MotoGP 24 </em>| PS4, PS5</li><li><em>The Sims 4 Island Living</em> (Add-on only) | PS4</li><li><em>Digimon Survive </em>| PS4</li><li><em>Overcooked! All You Can Eat</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Stick Fight: The Game</em> | PS4</li><li><em>Clash: Artifacts of Chaos</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Killer Frequency</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Hungry Shark World </em>| PS4</li><li><em>Chivalry 2 </em>| PS4, PS5</li></ul><p><strong>PS Plus Premier</strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><em>﻿Synapse </em>| PS VR2</li><li><em>Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain</em> | PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Blood Omen 2 </em>| PS4, PS5</li><li><em>Resistance: Fall of Man</em> | Streaming from PS3</li><li><em>Resistance 2 </em>| Streaming from PS3</li></ul></blockquote><p>Personally, I’m most excited for <em>Digimon Survive</em>. The 2022 hybrid between a visual novel and tactical RPG got mixed reviews, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/digimon-survive-rpg-visual-novel-review-1849377900&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/digimon-survive-rpg-visual-novel-review-1849377900">including from <em>Kotaku</em></a></span>, but I’m looking forward to giving it a low-stakes, no-strings-attached second chance. <em>Blood Omen 1</em> and <em>2 </em>are also arriving just in time for the <em>Soul Reaver 1 &amp; 2 Remastered </em>collection next month, providing much-needed backstory to the PS2 follow-ups.</p><p>It’s also nice to see the first two<em> Resistance</em> shooters—memorable games from Insomniac about a mid-WWII alien invasion—joining the classics collection, though having them relegated to cloud streaming because of the lack of PS3 backwards compatibility or emulation remains a drag. We probably won’t see it anytime soon, but the whole <em>Resistance</em> trilogy deserves a remaster collection on modern platforms.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GOG’s Preservation Program is the DRM-free store refocusing on the classics]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/gogs-preservation-program-is-the-drm-free-store-refocusing-on-the-classics/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gog%E2%80%99s-preservation-program-is-the-drm-free-store-refocusing-on-the-classics.1034901/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/gogs-preservation-program-is-the-drm-free-store-refocusing-on-the-classics/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                      
                      
          <p>The classic PC games market is "in a sorry state," according to DRM-free and classic-minded storefront GOG. Small games that aren't currently selling get abandoned, and compatibility issues arise as technology moves forward or as one-off development ideas age like milk.</p>
<p>Classic games are only 20 percent of GOG's catalog, and the firm hasn't actually called itself "Good Old Games" in 12 years. And yet, today, GOG announces that it is making "a significant commitment of resources" toward a new GOG Preservation Program. It starts with 100 games for which GOG's own developers are working to create current and future compatibility, keeping them DRM-free and giving them ongoing tech support, along with granting them a "Good Old Game: Preserved by GOG" stamp.</p>
<figure><a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-13-at-10.47.07%E2%80%AFAM.png">
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p><span>
          Credit:

          
          GOG

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </a></figure>
<p>GOG is not shifting its mission of providing a DRM-free alternative to Steam, Epic, and other PC storefronts, at least not entirely. But it is demonstrably excited about a new focus that ties back to its original name, inspired in some part by <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/5-years-after-it-was-yanked-off-stores-gogs-bringing-underrated-spy-rpg-alpha-protocol-in-from-the-cold-with-fewer-crashes-and-new-achievements/">its work on </a><em><a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/5-years-after-it-was-yanked-off-stores-gogs-bringing-underrated-spy-rpg-alpha-protocol-in-from-the-cold-with-fewer-crashes-and-new-achievements/">Alpha Protocol</a>.</em></p>
<p>"We think we can significantly impact the classics industry by focusing our resources on it and creating superior products," writes Arthur Dejardin, head of sales marketing at GOG. "If we wanted to spread the DRM-free gospel by focusing on getting new AAA games on GOG instead, we would make little progress with the same amount of effort and money (we’ve been trying various versions of that for the last 5 years)."</p>
<figure><p><iframe allow="fullscreen" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IetvbdoeIhg?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent"></iframe></p><div>
    
    <p>
      GOG Preservation Program's launch video.

          </p>
  </div>
</figure>
<h2>Getting knights, demons, and zombies up to snuff</h2>
<p>What kind of games? Scanning the list of <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/gog-preservation-program">Good Old Games</a>, most of them are, by all accounts, both good and old. Personally, I'm glad to see the <em>Jagged Alliance</em> games,&nbsp;<em>System Shock 2</em>,&nbsp;<em>Warcraft I &amp; II</em>,&nbsp;<em>Dungeon Keeper</em> <em>Gold </em>and&nbsp;<em>Theme Park</em>,&nbsp;<em>SimCity 3000 Unlimited,&nbsp;</em>and the&nbsp;<em>Wing Commander</em> series (particularly, personally,&nbsp;<em>Privateer)</em>. Most of them are, understandably, Windows-only, though Mac support extends to 34 titles so far, and Linux may pick up many more through Proton compatibility, beyond the 19 native titles to date.</p>

          
                      
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Dragon Age: The Veilguard's Hair Looks So Darn Good]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/why-dragon-age-the-veilguards-hair-looks-so-darn-good/1100-6527742/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-dragon-age-the-veilguards-hair-looks-so-darn-good.1034898/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/why-dragon-age-the-veilguards-hair-looks-so-darn-good/1100-6527742/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527742">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/dragon-age-the-veilguard/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> has introduced some striking visual changes to the world of Thedas, and while the new art style has been <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dragonage/comments/1eszz0t/opinions_on_the_art_style/" rel="nofollow ">met with mixed reception</a>, there's one aspect of the game's aesthetic that most players seem to agree on: The hair looks really, <em>really</em> good.</p><p dir="ltr">EA and BioWare appear to share the sentiment, and have revealed the recipe for high-quality hair animations via <a href="https://www.ea.com/technology/news/strand-hair-dragon-age-the-veilguard" rel="nofollow ">a new blog post</a> that examines every individual strand of The Veilguard's glorious collective locks. According to the post, each of the game's hairstyles--of which there are over 100--contain 50,000 individually rendered strands of hair. EA and BioWare credit the Frostbite engine for the high-quality results.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="929909020" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465422,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;The%20Good%20and%20The%20Bad%20of%20Dragon%20Age%3A%20The%20Veilguard&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:1479,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/the-good-and-the-bad-of-dragon-age-the-veilguard\/2300-6465422\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465422\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465422\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465422\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465422&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465422,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6527742&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;dragon-age-the-veilguard&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;dragon-age&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;dragon-age&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465422},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465422\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4391345-reviewinprogress_daveilguard_v1_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/mqLC3cXY.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1730127600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="mqLC3cXY" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465422" data-src="/videos/the-good-and-the-bad-of-dragon-age-the-veilguard/2300-6465422/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>The Good and The Bad of Dragon Age: The Veilguard</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">Frostbite has been <a href="https://www.ea.com/frostbite/news/the-future-of-hair-rendering-technology-in-frostbite" rel="nofollow ">working on realistic hair tech</a> for a while now, but the engine's progress truly shines in Veilguard, and it's not simply due to the number of hairstyle options or the amount of hairs on each character's head--length plays a major role, too. The Veilguard features a number of waist-length hair options (curly or straight) that move in combat, realistically responding to momentum, wind, blasts of magic, changes in direction, and other variables. But getting there wasn't easy.</p><p dir="ltr">"With hair attachments that move seamlessly and the decoupling of simulation and render tessellation, this is the first EA game to offer such detailed, physics-driven long hairstyles," the blog post explains. "The Frostbite team increased maximum hair length from 63 points to 255, and implemented a new system for complex hair structures like braids."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1752/17528202/4399041-hairguard.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399041" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1752/17528202/4399041-hairguard.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399041"></a><figcaption>One of Veilguard's longest hairstyle options sees Rook's hair hovering just above their hips.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1752/17528202/4399041-hairguard.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Changes to the Frostbite engine's lighting also played a major role in mastering Veilguard's hair physics, but it wasn't all fun and games--BioWare faced various challenges while working to perfect the way hair moved in-game. The main culprit? Horns.</p><p dir="ltr">"While Strand Hair is present in other EA games, the BioWare team had to push the limits even further for Dragon Age: The Veilguard," the post continues. "For example, implementing Strand Hair technology for characters who have waist-length hair with horns on their head presented some unique challenges."</p><p>Veilguard's beautifully rendered hair options haven't been overlooked by players, many of whom are very <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DragonAgeVeilguard/comments/1gndrbl/the_best_hair_to_date_in_dragon_age_the_veilguard/" rel="nofollow ">pleased with the game's well-animated cosmetic offerings</a> and spent <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-streamer-spent-almost-a-whole-day-making-sure-her-rook-was-a-smokeshow/1100-6527593/">hours perfecting their Rook</a> in the game's character creator. In a medium where "long hair" often translates to "shoulder-length at best," Dragon Age: The Veilguard seems to represent the industry's first major step in finally perfecting the art of realistic, complex hair structures in games. That's good news for everyone, especially <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/mass-effect/">Mass Effect</a> fans, who will likely have access to similarly realistic hair options when the next entry in the franchise finally arrives.</p><p>For more info on BioWare's latest fantasy RPG, check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/dragon-age-the-veilguard-review/1900-6418294/" data-ref-id="1900-6418294">Dragon Age: The Veilguard review-in-progress</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord Is Still In Amazon’s Secret Level Show]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/concord-amazon-secret-level</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-is-still-in-amazon%E2%80%99s-secret-level-show.1034895/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/concord-amazon-secret-level<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The latest round of hype for <em>Secret Level</em>, Amazon’s show based on various video games, is here, ahead of the show’s official premiere on December 10. Both an interview with the creator and a new trailer have answered the lingering question of whether <em>Concord</em> will still be featured: awkwardly, but maybe thankfully, yes.</p><p>To quickly recap:<em> Concord</em>’s servers were <a href="https://aftermath.site/sony-concord-shutdown-offline-refund-ps5-pc-live-service" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">taken offline</a> less than two weeks after the game launched in August, and Sony ultimately <a href="https://aftermath.site/sony-concord-firewalk-studios-shutdown" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">closed developer Firewalk Studios</a> in late October after seemingly completely <a href="https://aftermath.site/firewalk-concord-sony-playstation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">losing faith</a> in a studio it poured gallons of money and hype into. Some of that hype was in the form of its inclusion in <a href="https://deadline.com/2024/08/secret-level-reveals-featured-games-premiere-trailer-1236045052/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Secret Level</em></a>, which you could see as an odd choice given that, at the time the show was announced, <em>Concord</em> was newly out, and the most we’d seen of the world Sony and the show’s creators were banking on was an awkwardly-received <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mBnStS9d2xg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cinematic trailer</a>.</p><p>Despite all that, in the newest <em>Secret Level </em>trailer, you can catch a glimpse of <em>Concord</em>, most clearly through the word "Concord" showing up on screen. This is, interestingly, separate from another episode apparently focusing on PlayStation more broadly.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Secret Level - Official Trailer | Prime Video" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SvY9Uq7I30Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/tim-miller-secret-level-prime-video-1235161263/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rolling Stone</a>, <em>Secret Level</em> creator Tim Miller addressed the issue. Rolling Stone writes that “it was never an option to kill the [<em>Concord</em>] episode… there was no way for Miller to know what that eventual fate [of the game and studio] would be during the three years it took to produce <em>Secret Level</em>, nor had it ever been a consideration to remove the episode from the anthology.”</p><p>Miller says:</p><blockquote><p>There was no nicer, more invested group of developers than the team on <em>Concord</em>… I honestly don’t understand why it didn’t work. I know that they were trying to do the best they could, and they were a talented group of artists, so I feel terrible for that…</p><p>I don’t feel bad that it’s a part of the show, because I think it’s an episode that turned out really well, and you can kind of see the potential of this world and the characters… If it’s the remaining vestige of that product, I hope the developers feel that it’s in some way worthy, just a little bit, of the blood, sweat, and tears they put into it.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>I find the vibes very weird here, but I don’t necessarily think this is a bad thing. If something of the game can live on, if Miller and ::shudder:: Amazon can believe in <em>Concord</em> in a way Sony wouldn’t, I hope that brings some positive feelings and closure to the folks from Firewalk. But it also feels like one more reminder of how weird the situation around <em>Concord</em> was, proof of how much Sony was putting behind the game until it so abruptly wasn’t, and another crack in the foundation of Sony’s focus on live service despite the cost and risks.</p><p>And it’s hard not to grimace at Miller’s mention of <em>Concord</em>’s “potential” given everything that happened. At a <a href="https://collider.com/secret-level-episode-descriptions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Comic-Con panel in October</a>, before it was clear to the public the game wasn’t coming back, <em>Secret Level</em> co-creator Dave Wilson reportedly described the <em>Concord</em> episode as “the last ride of Captain Cassidy and the freegunners,” which, well, yes. But even this quote speaks to the tragedy of <em>Concord</em>’s life–what emotions are we expected to have about the “last ride” of characters few people even got to know?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Like I said, I hope <em>Concord</em>’s creators feel good about this version of their work seeing the light of day. I look forward to feeling very weird about the episode when the show comes out.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket pack picking mechanics all an illusion, fan suggests]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-pack-picking-mechanics-all-an-illusion-fan-suggests</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket-pack-picking-mechanics-all-an-illusion-fan-suggests.1034892/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-pack-picking-mechanics-all-an-illusion-fan-suggests<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Screenshot-2024-11-13-164803.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>The Pokémon Company</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Fans believe that whatever you pick in <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/pokemon-trading-card-game-pocket">Pokémon TCG Pocket</a>'s pack opening carousel, you'll get the same cards regardless.
</p>
<p>
That's right: carefully choosing the booster pack you want to open from the game's carousel doesn't matter. 
</p>
<p>
Whether you're looking for a bent corner, crossing your fingers or dropping lots of real-world money on the game versus playing for free, the cards are all the same - and actually pre-determined. Choice is an illusion! 
</p>
<p>
Where's the evidence? Well, YouTuber <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oJhGaOrd1qU">Rustywolf</a> has come up with this convincing video where he shows a script he's authored that sniffs data packets sent by Pokémon TCG Pocket to the game's servers. 
</p>
<p>
Behind the scenes, you can see that pack opening data is determined as soon as a pack is purchased, before the user picks the on-screen booster they want to open or sees any of its cards. 
</p>
<p>
The video below shows this all in action, with card IDs received from the game's server and able to be cross-referenced with the game's card database - revealing the cards you'll get whatever pack you pick before you've even picked it.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Pokemon TCG Pocket pack wheel selection does not change what cards you receive." data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oJhGaOrd1qU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Pokemon TCG Pocket pack wheel selection does not change what cards you receive.</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oJhGaOrd1qU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/oJhGaOrd1qU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Pokémon TCG Pocket booster pack opening mechanics explained.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oJhGaOrd1qU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Eurogamer previously reported on the various <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-conspiracy-theories-to-cheat-the-series-mechanics-have-always-existed-and-now-theyre-here-for-pokemon-tcg-pocket">Pokémon TCG Pocket conspiracy theories being passed around the game's playerbase</a> for how to "hack" or "glitch" the game to get better cards.
</p>
<p>
Pokémon TCG Pocket looks to be off to a great start, with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-passes-30m-downloads-in-a-week">$12m earned over the game's first four days</a> and more than <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-off-to-strong-start-reportedly-earns-12m-in-four-days">30m downloads after a week</a>. Looking to get ahead of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-first-expansion-due-late-january-leak-suggests">the game's first expansion, expected in January</a>? Here's our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-tcg-pocket-tier-list-best-cards-trainer-rental-decks">Pokémon TCG Pocket tier list for the best Pokémon cards, Trainer cards, rental decks and decks</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake (PS5) Review – Sowing the Seeds of the Future]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake-ps5-review-%E2%80%93-sowing-the-seeds-of-the-future.1034883/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-remake/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
				<main>

					

					<!--<div class="ads-container banner-ad floated p-0">
						<div data-pg-ad-spot='div-gpt-ad-wccftechcom38564' style="min-height: 280px;"></div>
					</div>-->
					
										<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</h5><p><span>November 14th, 2024</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PlayStation 5, Nintendo Switch, Microsoft Windows, Xbox Series X|S</span>
						</p></div><div>
							<h5>Developer</h5><p><span>Armor Project, Bird Studio, Spike Chunsoft</span>
						</p></div></div></div>
					<p><span>Few Japanese role-playing games have been as influential to the genre as a whole as the first four Dragon Quest titles originally released for the Famicom/NES. While it may seem strange to start a new trilogy with the third entry, Square-Enix has a very good reason for beginning the Erdrick Trilogy with what used to bear the Seeds of Salvation moniker. Whether this is your first time playing Dragon Quest III or your thirtieth, there’s enough here to make it feel like a fresh experience.</span></p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Dragon-Quest-III-HD-2D-Remake-King-1456x819.png"></a></figure>

<p><span>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake opens with a familiar premise to the NES original. As the son or daughter of the famous warrior Ortega, you’re tasked by the King himself to pick up in your father’s shoes after he disappears on a journey to slay the great evil of the world, Baramos. This simple narrative tale harkens back to a time when the big bads were front and center and venturing out to slay them was a task often reserved for a coming-of-age tale.&nbsp; Players won’t have to venture out alone as they did in the very first Dragon Warrior title. Instead, adventurers just need to stop at the local tavern conveniently located in the Hero’s hometown and make a call to action to pick up three more folks to tag along for the trip.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>While the player’s role is set in stone as the eponymous Hero, the three that come along are free to pick up any one of eight initial classes to fit the ideal party role. While only seven base classes were available in the original release of Dragon Quest III, Square-Enix has introduced a new Monster Wrangler class first featured in later Dragon Quest titles to the roster of available professions. This new class takes advantage of meeting and befriending more than a hundred different monsters scattered throughout the landscape and rather than using them in individual combat, they merely increase the effectiveness of just a small handful of the class’ signature attacks. The other purpose for recruiting these monsters is to do battle in the Monster Arenas that are found in various cities and provide a great source of income assuming the monsters are strong enough to win. These monsters don’t gain levels in the traditional sense and only get more powerful as players recruit more monsters of the same subspecies. It’s ideal to keep one of these Monster Wranglers in the party at all times, given their combat potential, but also to sneak up on pacifist monsters and recruit them to your cause without them running away from smelling the player’s powerful stench.</span></p>

<p><span>One of the things that made Dragon Quest III such a memorable title in its original release was the open-ended design of the adventure once players secure themselves a boat. As players get more comfortable in their adventure, suddenly the guardrails are taken off and players are given the chance to explore the world as they see fit in order to acquire six mythical orbs needed to secure a path to the game’s main antagonist. There are a plethora of side quests, main story missions, and collectible diversions along the way for players who aim to seek everything out and unlock the platinum trophy. Think along the lines of 110 Mini Medals and even more monsters to recruit for the battle arena. Pro Tip: try to collect and hold onto five Hardwood Headgear along your journey. You’ll thank me later.</span></p>
<p><span>Dragon Quest is one of the purest and most perfect versions of turn-based JRPG combat, and the HD-2D Remake of Dragon Quest III is no exception. There are no fancy gauges to clutter the screen or combination attacks that need advanced preparation. Instead, players give out commands to each of their four party members individually and watch as turns play out simultaneously based on which attacker has the highest agility stat. Unlike the original game, there’s a significant amount of bloat to the outgoing damage that players give and health pools to the tune of sometimes ten times what the original enemy list had in both the NES and SNES versions of Dragon Quest III.</span></p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/DRAGON-QUEST-III-HD-2D-Remake-Baramos-Fight.png"></a></figure>

<p><span>By the time I nearly cleared the postgame of Dragon Quest III (neither Pachisi nor the Monster Medals made their return, but Xenlon and his list of wishes did), my Hero was just shy of level 60 with all three party members in their mid-30s on their third or fourth class change. The added stats and having access to nearly every skill/spell across the whole party was definitely beneficial, especially given how prone enemies in the late game are to unleashing critical attacks, inflicting status effects, or even outright killing a character.</span></p>
<p><span>Depending on your tolerance for punishment, all three difficulty settings are available from the adventure’s onset, whether you’re craving a much more challenging Draconian Quest or want to take it easy and just enjoy the story with Dracky Quest. I will admit that Dracky Quest is one of the series’ easiest difficulty modes to date, with enemies literally unable to kill a party member no matter how hard they try and simply reduce their HP to 1. If you’re in a lengthy dungeon and out of restoration items, you could consider taking the easy way out and flipping the difficulty mode just long enough to make it back to the overworld and save an expensive trip to the church to revive your party.</span></p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p><span>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake has been given a complete graphical overhaul, instead giving the iconic RPG a makeover in the same vein as Square-Enix’s Octopath Traveler and other similar titles. The entire world is brightly colored and blooming with light. Even if you’re intimately familiar with every step retracing Ortega’s journey, the complete reimagining of the adventure makes this feel like a brand new adventure rather than just another release of Seeds of Salvation. All I can say now is that I can’t wait to go through Dragon Quest I+II HD-2D Remake next year.</span></p>
<p><em>[Editor's Note: A PlayStation 5 copy was provided by the publisher for editorial purposes.]</em></p>

					
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>


					<div>
	<div>
			
			<p>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</p>
		</div>
	<header>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake</header>
</div>

<p>Dragon Quest III HD-2D Remake, while not the definitive edition that includes all of the previous side content, embodies the perfect version of Erdrick's adventure that both old and new fans can appreciate as if a brand new adventure from Yuji Horii</p>

<div>
		<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Pros</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>Dracky and Draconian Quest difficulties depending on your tolerance for punishment
</li><li>Erdrick's adventure has never looked better
</li><li>Quality-of-Life improvements keep players from getting lost
</li><li>Players can cheat with Dracky Quest and clear out the Monster Arena with low ranked monsters
</li><li>Monster Wrangler a natural fit (even if it's a bit overpowered) for the limited roster of classes</li>		</ul>
	</div>
			<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Cons</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>Gadabout still next to useless but still the easiest route to getting a Sage in your party
</li><li>Late and postgame challenges require grinding just to survive a hit or two
</li><li>Many treasures and mini medals remixed and moved around, so old guides won't find every mini medal.
</li><li>No easy way to track what side dungeons and locales have already been cleared of loot without revisiting them with a Thief or Monster Wrangler</li>		</ul>
	</div>
	</div>


<p>The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>
					
				</main>
			</article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inside Asmodee: US GM Julien Sharp Talks Running The Business]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/interviews/inside-asmodee-us-gm-julien-sharp-talks-running-business</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/inside-asmodee-us-gm-julien-sharp-talks-running-the-business.1034880/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/interviews/inside-asmodee-us-gm-julien-sharp-talks-running-business<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Every day, millions of gamers around the world sit down at the table and crack into a board game with friends and loved ones. And while we maybe, <i>maybe</i>, think about the game’s designer or artist from time to time, it’s rare that we think about all the other people involved in bringing our favorite games to life! That’s why I’m starting <b>Inside Asmodee</b>, an ongoing series of interviews with employees across one of the world’s largest gaming distributors. For our first in the series, I got the chance to chat with Julien Sharp, General Manager, U.S. of <a href="https://store.asmodee.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Asmodee Group</a>!</p>

<p>Meeting over Zoom before she headed off for a vacation, we spent some time catching up (we’d previously met for coffee while Sharp was in NYC on business several months prior), before diving in.</p>

<p>“I’m really excited to do this with you, Giaco,” she said, because, “it’s kind of an intro to a business that a lot of people don't really even think about.”</p>

<p>For me, the entire point of this article series is to, A. get to know the people who work at a company as big as Asmodee, and B. Find out what exactly it is that they do there, and find out how what they do helps get games to the table.</p>

<p>It’s time we give profiles, and shine a spotlight, on the gaming industry in much the same way other industries are covered in the media.</p>

<p>“There's a person that is making and designing these games,” explained Sharp, “but then there's also a person that wants to play those games, and they can't get to each other and connect without what we do at Asmodee.”</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-with-the-catan-studios-team.jpeg?itok=UgjTo3hZ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-with-the-catan-studios-team.jpeg?itok=3q9OZNkU 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Julien and the Catan Studios Team playing a giant game of <em>Catan</em>. Image: Julien Sharp.</figcaption></figure>

<p>But what does it mean when we say Julien Sharp is the General Manager, U.S. of Asmodee Group? “In our company,” she said, “we call this role a Country Manager, but here in the U.S., people might know it more as a GM. It's also kind of akin to a CEO role as it relates to our territory, too.”</p>

<p>Julien explained that the crux of her job relies on maintaining a 360-degree view on the four main pillars of the distribution business: Sales, Commercial, Purchasing, and Logistics.</p>

<h2>The Four Pillars of the Business</h2>

<p>Sales covers everything from, “mass market to Amazon, and our hobby sales,” Julien explained, “which is the network of over 3,500 local game stores, where people who play games for a hobby go and sit at tables, play and purchase games, and meet their community.</p>

<p>“Our Commercial side includes marketing,” she said, but she explains that Commercial also includes their relationships with the myriad game design studios that create the games that Asmodee distributes. “We have our first-party studios, and then we also have our partner or third-party studios, which are outside companies we don't own, but we distribute their games in the U.S. So our commercial side manages all those relationships <i>and</i> all of our marketing.”</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-in-the-warehouse.jpeg?itok=kQRSXNTX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-in-the-warehouse.jpeg?itok=tSafx0Oc 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Julien Sharp in the Minnesota warehouse with members of the Logistics and Distribution team. Image: Julien Sharp.</figcaption></figure><p>Purchasing includes all of the company’s purchasing and, importantly, reorders. “We have to look at all the forecasts and following trends of how the sales are going,” Sharp said, “to know when we need to reorder. There’s a balance, we have to make sure we don't over order, but also that we don't <i>under</i> order and not order enough for demand and run out early, right? Because that's not fun. When we don't have games to sell, we miss inventory turns, and that's <i>not</i> good.”</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"We have to look at all the forecasts ... to know when we need to reorder. There’s a balance, we have to make sure we don't over order, but also that we don't <i>under</i> order...”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Finally, the fourth pillar of the role revolves around Logistics. This includes both the front office, but also an entire distribution facility. “Our facility is hooked onto a very big warehouse,” Sharp said.</p>

<p>"Our facility, when you walk around the warehouse and office one time, is a half mile. So it's quite big, and because of the hobby businesses, year round, we have semi trucks coming in and going all day long. And we have many, many bays that are bringing games into us that we have ordered and picking up games that we have sold out. So it's a full-out logistics operation, and I need to keep my eye on all of those pieces and be able to dive down if there's a problem in them.”</p>

<h2>Managing at the GM Level</h2>

<p>At this point I joke sarcastically about how <i>simple</i> this all sounds, but Sharp isn’t phased by the workload or the need to oversee four very disparate areas of the business.</p>

<p>“I believe in a strong team,” she emphasized, “and I have VP level people that run all four of those areas, the sales, the commercial, the logistics, and the purchasing. They are experts in their field, and they know their their business. They run their teams, I come in if they need help, or if there’s a big, overarching decision that could impact multiple areas of the business."</p>

<p>But even with leads reporting up to her across these four areas of the business, Sharp prides herself on knowing a little bit about every single part of each area. She said that she needs to understand all aspects of the business so that she can properly staff, “but I also have to know enough to be able to speak to it if I'm needed. So this role is kind of a generalist.”</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-giving-a-presentation-with-her-dog-simey-looking-on.jpeg?itok=3BlIS5zC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-giving-a-presentation-with-her-dog-simey-looking-on.jpeg?itok=wap1jyxU 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Dogs are welcome at the Asmodee offices, and Julien Sharp's dog Simey watches on as Julien leads a Town Hall meeting. Image: Julien Sharp</figcaption></figure><p>Sharp said her beginnings, which included owning her own game company (Funnybone Toys, acquired in 2017 by <a href="https://foxmind.com/" rel="nofollow">Foxmind</a>), have helped her understand all the different nuances of a gaming company. From stickering her games in a Wisconsin warehouse before Barnes &amp; Noble would put them on shelves, to sending out advanced shipping notices to big box retailers, Sharp's seen it all.</p>

<p>And now, as she takes a more top-down view of the business, one of the things she’s most keen to relate to me is her open-door policy. In what sounds like a truly meeting-heavy workload, Julien excitedly recounts that she has one-on-one meetings with her direct reports weekly, and up to two to three levels down from that every few weeks. She also takes pride in the aforementioned open-door policy, where anyone from the company can come in and pick her brain if the door’s open.</p>

<h2>A Day in the Life Inside Asmodee</h2>

<p>Next, I really wanted to get into the nitty gritty and find out what an average day is like for Sharp, so she pulled up her work calendar for a random Wednesday a week prior, and walked me through it.</p>

<p>“I had a touch base with marketing,” she began, “the regional manager of all Europe who's running some global programs. I met with our legal team. I did some financial projection scenarios coming up for the next three years with my senior team — we're working on doing our budget for next year. So we’re also figuring out how many games we are going to buy from each studio.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Suddenly, she lit up, “Oh! And I walked three laps around the building, we're having a walking contest right now. And so I walked three laps, which is a mile and a half. That was pretty fun!” From there, she recounts business reviews with the head of finance, a look at their trade show presence, more one-on-ones, and so on.</p>

<p>“I guess that's the biggest part of what a day is for me,” she explained, “finding any fires that I need to put out - though there's been less and less of that, which is really great, but also keeping an eye on what's going to impact us next year. It's a lot of review, and then I get that pulse from the one on ones that I have.”</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/inside-asmodee-lino-lakes-office.jpg?itok=jf1EsNF6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/inside-asmodee-lino-lakes-office.jpg?itok=2q2xzemJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>An image of the Lino Lakes Asmodee offices. Image: Asmodee USA.</figcaption></figure><h2>What Makes An Asmodee Game Feel Like An Asmodee Game?</h2>

<p>Next up, I wanted to dig into the overall approach to game acquisition, design, and marketing to find out if there was a throughline through the games in the Asmodee family.</p>

<p>“Remember, we are a distributor,” Sharp said, “so we distribute our own made games, <i>and</i> we distribute third-party games. And the mentality of the third party is: what is missing from our offerings.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>She explained that for their own games, “what we did internally is divide our games into three verticals, and those verticals are Social, which is kind of party games. Then in the middle we have catch-all tabletop games, games in a box, that aren't necessarily party games. And then we have what's called our lifestyle games."</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"And the lifestyle vertical... that's where the secret sauce is in this business."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>"And the lifestyle vertical is really interesting, and that's where the secret sauce is in this business. That’s our trading card games, which are like our <em><a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/star-wars-unlimited-review-trading-card-gamings-new-hope" rel="nofollow">Star Wars: Unlimited</a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/altered-tcg-review-world-of-potential" rel="nofollow">Altered</a></em>, games that you can continue to buy new packs of and build your decks and play, and of course our miniatures. Miniatures like <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/star-wars-shatterpoint-first-impressions" rel="nofollow"><i>Star Wars: Shatterpoint</i></a>, where you take the the plastic molds out of the box, you have to build your miniature, and then you have to paint your miniature.”</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-shatterpoint-sprues.jpg?itok=nYLiYVcc 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-shatterpoint-sprues.jpg?itok=km3Lb-EN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>An image from our&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: Shatterpoint</em>&nbsp;first look article, showing the hobby or "lifestyle" nature of the game. Image: Giaco Furino.</figcaption></figure><p>As you can imagine, each of those verticals needs to be marketed totally differently. But as to what makes an Asmodee game feel like an Asmodee game, even when they’re coming from multiple publishers and fit into different verticals, is the quality.</p>

<p>“I will say that I've never seen a company, and I've worked for many, including my own,” Sharp said, “that can create a marriage of what’s outside the box and what’s inside.” She explained that it’s that perfect blend of tight mechanics, high-quality design, and evocative artwork that sets an Asmodee game apart.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“We're in the business of selling games, but it makes it really fun to sell when you know that from the moment you look at it to the moment you open it and play it, that it's got that same quality. And that's what I think sets Asmodee games apart.”</p>

<h2>Staying Nimble in a Shifting Business Landscape</h2>

<p>Next, I wanted to hear about how she helps steer the sales and other business orgs through an ever-shifting landscape. When gaming trends and fads rise and fall like the tides, how does Asmodee stay afloat?</p>

<p>“This is a constant theme of every single day, every single week, month, and year of this job. What is a fad? What is a trend that has some staying power?” She explained that because of the nature of game production, you can’t really take a chance on a fad.</p>

<p>“You sell a year in advance for what's coming out for the next, so our fall pitches for 2025 are done. You always have to look at what's coming, what's trending, what relationships and partnerships are you doing? It's meeting with the studios. It's meeting with our marketing team, looking at our our data, marketing data, Point Of Sale data, what's selling, what's hot, what's not.”</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-and-team-playtesting-duck-and-cover.jpeg?itok=XJdp4ocY 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-and-team-playtesting-duck-and-cover.jpeg?itok=zRmhcv6R 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Playtesting incoming games helps the team get familiar with the product. Image: Julien Sharp</figcaption></figure><p>Sharp stressed, however, that they’re not the <i>designers</i> of the games themselves, but “that doesn't mean we can't impact and ask for things we see. So we are very involved in saying ‘we have a hole here that could be filled,’ and I get very involved in executive-level meetings looking at staffing from a global perspective, all toward making sure that we have the right game at the right time.</p>

<p>“We see the market here in the U.S. and we're stewarding that knowledge and putting it up the chain, that way our game design studios, and our heads of these different verticals can get the right product into the U.S.”</p>

<h2>Women in Toys and Giving Back</h2>

<p>I also wanted to get a chance to speak to Sharp about her role in <a href="https://www.womenintoys.com/" rel="nofollow">Women in Toys</a>, a non-profit organization and global community that champions and advocates for the advancement of women in Toys, Licensing, and Entertainment through leadership, networking, and educational opportunities.</p>

<p>“I’m at a point in my career where I can give back a little more,” Sharp explained, “you know, for the next generation of people coming in. So I was thrilled to be asked last year to sit on the board. I'm on a three-year appointment to the board of Women in Toys. There wasn't as much board-game representation there, so I work with a team of gamer gals that are in different areas trying to build the board game awareness a little more at Women in Toys, which is really exciting.”&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote>
<p>"I work with a team of gamer gals that are in different areas trying to build the board game awareness ... at&nbsp;Women in Toys..."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>“What I love about WiT, though,” Sharp said, “and that I think is just incredible, is that they have a scholarship program, and I'm on one of the committees that reviews scholarship applicants and helps pick the recipients. The idea of giving a chance for women to get into board games via this scholarship is really exciting. So I love doing that.” Along with Women in Toys, she also helps as part of the judging panel for young inventors with the resource/networking hub <a href="https://peopleofplay.com/about" rel="nofollow">People of Play</a>.</p>

<h2>Finding Work in the Gaming Industry</h2>

<p>To cap off our conversation, I wanted to get Sharp's advice for people looking to get into the gaming industry. “I love this question,” she exclaimed, “and this is really the purpose of what we're doing together in this series.”</p>

<p>She said that while there are more programs than ever to study game design, and even art and illustration for games, that’s not the only way to <i>be in the industry</i>. “If you get your general business degree, look who's working in games right now?” I get her point, people with business degrees are still needed in the industry.</p>

<p>“On my team, there are people in the warehouse that are working in games, there are people in PR that are working in games. There are people working in marketing, people working in sales,” she pauses here for emphasis, and I have to admit I’m whipped up right along with her. “They could be selling pet supplies, they could be selling picture frames, they could be selling furniture, but sales are sales, and they're selling board games.”</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-with-it-team.jpeg?itok=VvyYJprA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-with-it-team.jpeg?itok=mvMn4tsJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Julien Sharp with a visiting IT team, just one of the many ways to get into the Tabletop industry. Image: Julien Sharp.</figcaption></figure><p>“There's a lot of ways to get into games. Our head business analyst, he plays! He built incredible <i>Star Wars: Unlimited </i>decks! He plays every game. There isn’t a game that comes through that he doesn't play. And he's our business analyst, right? So there's a lot of ways to get into the game industry.”</p>

<p>And Sharp emphasized that Asmodee <i>wants</i> their employees to play. “We give a huge discount to employees,” she explained, “I mean, that's the coolest perk you get. I can't believe some of the games I've been able to buy at an incredible discount. So you can come in and be a business person, or work in PR, or marketing, and come in and get into the board game industry and work at getting our games en route to market. We have all the elements of any other business entity, so you don't have to be an expert in board game design to get in to working games.”</p>

<h2>What’s Julien Playing?</h2>

<p>Before we wrapped up, I had to know what Sharp, with all this access to Asmodee’s gaming library, was playing right now. First, she said she’s totally in love with one of their third-party games which hasn’t hit the U.S. yet, <a href="https://captain.games/en/games/duck-and-cover" rel="nofollow"><i>Duck and Cover</i></a>.</p>

<p>“I love it. It's really, really fun. It's a quick game, just three rounds, and you're trying to get the lowest score. So that's a little counter intuitive.” But Julien has also been really getting into <i>Star Wars: Unlimited</i> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/altered-tcg-review-world-of-potential" rel="nofollow"><i>Altered</i>, the newest Asmodee Trading Card Game</a>.</p>

<p>“They couldn't be more different from each other,” Julien says of <i>Unlimited </i>and <i>Altered</i>, “but they're two fabulous games. I went to England for a work trip this summer and went to <i>Star Wars: Unlimited</i> pre-release event at a local game store,” and since then she’s been bit by the <i>Unlimited </i>bug (I’m also afflicted).</p>

<p>“I also really love <i>Altered</i>,” she said. “It's a different philosophy. The art is incredible, and the gameplay is really, really neat. So I hope that people will fall in love with that as it starts to ship out. Those are my picks this year.”</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-with-the-duck-and-cover-team.jpeg?itok=F1n2n-xC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/inside-asmodee-julien-with-the-duck-and-cover-team.jpeg?itok=YYpE2NdX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Julien Sharp and the creators of one of her new favorite third party Asmodee titles,&nbsp;<em>Duck and Cover</em>. Image: Julien Sharp.</figcaption></figure><p>With that, our time had come to an end, and this first chapter of Inside Asmodee comes to a close. Thanks so much to Julien Sharp for taking the time out to talk with us, and give us an insider’s view into what it’s like running so many facets of a gaming company. We’ll continue our series throughout the year with designers, marketing professionals, shipping logistics managers, and more to ensure we’re getting a full 360 view Inside Asmodee!</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GOG are doubling down on game preservation, and making it easier to see which games run well on modern PCs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gog-are-doubling-down-on-game-preservation-and-making-it-easier-to-see-which-games-run-well-on-modern-pcs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gog-are-doubling-down-on-game-preservation-and-making-it-easier-to-see-which-games-run-well-on-modern-pcs.1034877/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gog-are-doubling-down-on-game-preservation-and-making-it-easier-to-see-which-games-run-well-on-modern-pcs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>DRM-free game merchants want to refocus on restoring old classics</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/GOG-Preservation-Program-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>GOG</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Over the years, game retailers <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/gog">GOG</a> have drifted from almost purely offering classic oldies to welcoming more and more modern blockbusters onto their storefront. In one sense, they've turned from a game preservation champion into a slightly dustier, DRM-less Steam. Now, though, GOG have declared a renewed focus on not just selling aged games, but on tweaking more of them to work on non-aged hardware. And you'll be able to tell which games have got this restoration treatment from a fancy badge plastered on top of them.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The GOG Preservation Program, as the endeavour is being called, is an extension of the store’s previous efforts in restoring older games (see their recent fix-ups of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/obsidians-espionage-rpg-alpha-protocol-returns-to-store-shelves-after-four-years-in-license-hell">Alpha Protocol</a> and the first <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-original-resident-evil-3-is-now-available-via-gog-following-the-arrivals-of-its-predecessors">Resident Evil trilogy</a>). It's also combined with elements of Valve’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-compatibility-interview">Steam Deck Verified</a> system, which conveys whether a game performs well on the handheld. </p>
<p>First, GOG’s in-house software boffins set about squishing all the bugs and adding all the missing features (modern video codecs, Windows 10/11 compatibility, etc) that might prevent them from playing nice with an up-to-date PC. Then, the games that graduate this process get a certified "Good Old Game" badge on their store listing, showing at-a-glance that they’re ready to play without needing a bunch of unofficial patches or mods.</p>
<p>Badged games will also be "the most complete version available," in terms of DLCs, expansions, and even the availability of manuals and alternative languages. They’ll also come with offline installers and, of course, no DRM.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/resident-evil-3-original.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Capcom</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>To kick things off, over 100 games are being relaunched with Good Old Game status. These include Resident Evils 1, 2, and 3, the original <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/diablo">Diablo</a> (and its Hellfire expansion), <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/system-shock-2">System Shock 2</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines">Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines</a>, both OG <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout">Fallout</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-new-vegas">Fallout: New Vegas</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-curse-of-monkey-island">The Curse of Monkey Island</a>, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/x-com-ufo-defense">X-COM: UFO Defense</a> and dozens more classics. Is it bad if I say I’d be particularly keen on playing an updated New Vegas over this (considerable) batch of <em>old</em>-old stuff? If anything, its relative newness makes me extra mad that I need to mod it so hard just to avoid my post-2008 graphics card breaking the framerate-based physics and sending my Courier whizzing about like they’re on rocket-strapped Heelys. Anyway, you can <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1yA9kOZBT5pvBRABFBIjITmS8ZdV3QMgPl2emR5dqbv8/edit?gid=0#gid=0">read the full list here</a>.</p><p>"Our goal is for all games, whether recent or classic, to eventually become part of the Preservation Program," sayeth GOG themselves. "There is a long backlog of classic games available on GOG that may already qualify for the program, but our Team has not been able to confirm that yet. We aim to support as many games as possible, but it's not always entirely up to us."</p>
<p>Indeed, restoration projects like this require the original developers/publishers giving permission to poke around their games’ code, and you can probably imagine how that isn’t always forthcoming. And those on the game-making side won't be the only ones thinking about the bottom line: GOG ultimately exist to sell games, not immortalise them in museums, nor hand them out to people who owned an original CD-ROM copy back in yesteryear.</p>
<p>Still, on balance it’s probably better that someone profits off a healthy game preservation pipeline than to not have one at all, so it's hard to complain that much about this unusually niche-facing turn back towards GOG’s roots. It's a timely move too, considering disgruntled players have <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-is-being-sued-over-the-crew-in-a-lawsuit-that-compares-the-server-shutdown-to-a-bumperless-pinball-machine">resorted to suing publishers</a> for yanking games into unplayability through server shutdowns. Hopefully GOG persevere through any naysaying and can keep producing these offline-compatible, preservation-friendly semi-remasters for a good long while.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's Our Favorite Cosplay From Dragon Con 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/cosplay-gallery-dragon-con-2024-elden-ring-dune-1851697399</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-our-favorite-cosplay-from-dragon-con-2024.1034865/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/cosplay-gallery-dragon-con-2024-elden-ring-dune-1851697399<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="fbe6eb3ad1d3aa237e3ab13e696b83ba" data-recommend-id="image://fbe6eb3ad1d3aa237e3ab13e696b83ba" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Three images of cosplayers from Dragon Con 2024." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Three images of cosplayers from Dragon Con 2024." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Photo<!-- -->: <!-- -->Mineralblu / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="fbe6eb3ad1d3aa237e3ab13e696b83ba" data-recommend-id="image://fbe6eb3ad1d3aa237e3ab13e696b83ba" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Three images of cosplayers from Dragon Con 2024." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Atlanta’s Dragon Con draws vast crowds to Georgia every year, for the big ol’ mix of all geek culture and celebrity spotting. It also draws in crowds of fantastic cosplayers, and with them, <em>Kotaku</em>’s favorite photographer, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3IngBBUGFUduHp-7haK1lw&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3IngBBUGFUduHp-7haK1lw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mineralblu</a></span>.</p><p>This year’s Dragon Con saw Walter Koenig, Ming-Na Wen, Danny Trejo, Nathan Fillion and Cobie Smulders among the many famous faces in attendance, and even offered guests the opportunity to do their best to avoid meeting John Cleese.</p><p>But even more importantly to us, it also saw some absolutely wonderful cosplay, and we’ve compiled together some of the most impressive fits from the show. Huge showings for <em>Dune</em> and <em>Elden Ring</em> this year, with some nice surprise twists and crossovers.</p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Prime Members Can Save 10% on PlayStation and Xbox Gift Cards Before Black Friday]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-xbox-gift-cards-amazon-black-friday-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amazon-prime-members-can-save-10-on-playstation-and-xbox-gift-cards-before-black-friday.1034862/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-xbox-gift-cards-amazon-black-friday-2024<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">That's some huge saving potential.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-black-friday-2024-when-will-the-sale-start-this-year">Amazon</a> Prime members can now take advantage of a <a href="https://zdcs.link/z3bWmq?object_uuid=77df69be-79ed-4d43-9678-fc8a21595768&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">10% discount on gaming gift cards</a>, including those for <a href="https://zdcs.link/zjGqEe?object_uuid=77df69be-79ed-4d43-9678-fc8a21595768&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">PlayStation</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QGVkOY?object_uuid=77df69be-79ed-4d43-9678-fc8a21595768&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox</a>. The offer comes as retailers gear up for the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2024">Black Friday sales season</a>, providing an opportunity for digital gamers to prepare for upcoming deals.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The promotion includes significant savings, such as <a href="https://zdcs.link/zjGqEe?object_uuid=77df69be-79ed-4d43-9678-fc8a21595768&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$25 off a $250 PlayStation gift card</a> and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QODJWD?object_uuid=77df69be-79ed-4d43-9678-fc8a21595768&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">$10 off a $100 card</a>. These discounts are particularly valuable for those planning to purchase digital games, downloadable content, or subscriptions during the holiday sales period.</p><div id="210705" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="3432ae1d-309c-45dd-8db4-0708c5b8eb3a"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>PlayStation $100 Gift Card</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>10% off deal is available on from $250 to $10 gift cards.</p></div></div><div catalogid="3432ae1d-309c-45dd-8db4-0708c5b8eb3a" id="210706"><div id="210706" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Xbox $100 Gift Card</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>10% off deal is available on from $100 to $10 gift cards.</p></div></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Think about it this way: There's a 100% certainty of digital games sales over the Black Friday period, and these gift card discounts mean you can save even more. Or you could actually <em>gift </em>them, if you want? There are also discounts on <a href="https://zdcs.link/QPbkej?object_uuid=77df69be-79ed-4d43-9678-fc8a21595768&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Fortnite V-Bucks</a>, <a href="https://zdcs.link/91b0Dq?object_uuid=77df69be-79ed-4d43-9678-fc8a21595768&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Xbox Game Pass Core</a>, and <a href="https://zdcs.link/QLnkeb?object_uuid=77df69be-79ed-4d43-9678-fc8a21595768&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Roblox Digital Gift Cards</a> if you're so inclined. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">With <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-black-friday-sale-2024">Nintendo already revealing its Black Friday plans</a>, similar announcements from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-5-slim-console-black-friday-2024">PlayStation</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-deals-black-friday-what-to-expect-2024">Xbox</a> are expected in the coming days. For now, these gift card offers provide a timely chance to save ahead of the main sales event. Not a Prime member? Consider taking out a <a href="https://zdcs.link/QODJeE?object_uuid=77df69be-79ed-4d43-9678-fc8a21595768&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">30-day free trial</a> and cover yourself for the whole Black Friday sales season.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">What About PS Plus and Xbox Game Pass?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Friday often delivers discounts on gaming memberships like Game Pass and PlayStation Plus, so the first tip is to be patient. Additionally, these digital gift cards can be used to purchase subscriptions, making them a handy option if digital deals on memberships are announced soon. Otherwise, there's a pretty great deal on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-deals">Xbox Game Pass UItimate at Woot</a> right now if you're keen to grab a deal today.</p></div><div catalogid="d0a019c2-b31e-4e7b-afdb-2a73c34152bd" id="148732"><div id="148732" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>3 Months of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate Membership</h3></p><div data-cy="solo-product-description"><p>Multiple digital codes can be stacked</p></div></div><h2 data-cy="title2">When Is Black Friday 2024?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The actual date of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/black-friday-2024"><strong>Black Friday</strong></a><strong> in 2024 falls on November 29</strong> this year, but the deals have already kicked off. Leading up to the big event, retailers have begun to open deals online. Each day leading up to the event will slowly roll out more deals, which ultimately leads to massive discounts on Black Friday. Retailers will not reveal their biggest Black Friday deals until the big day, but most general deals will be available well in advance, such as this excellent discount on gift cards.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Robert Anderson is a deals expert and Commerce Editor for IGN. You can follow him <a href="https://twitter.com/robertliam21" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@robertliam21</a> on Twitter.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Nov 13, 2024 4:12 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halo Had Emotional Punch Because It Underlined Quiet Tragedy]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/halo-had-emotional-punch-because-it-underlined-quiet-tragedy/1100-6527741/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halo-had-emotional-punch-because-it-underlined-quiet-tragedy.1034859/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/halo-had-emotional-punch-because-it-underlined-quiet-tragedy/1100-6527741/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527741">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><em>Halo: The Master Chief Collection celebrated its 10-year anniversary on November 11, 2024. Below, take a look back at the quiet sense of loss that permeated throughout the main trilogy.</em></p><p dir="ltr">Halo: Combat Evolved opens with waking up. Halo 3 concludes with falling asleep. Between is death. It's fun, of course. It's in space and exaggerated: a holy war between Americanized space marines and zealot aliens who find a common enemy in the zombie "Flood." I don't want to pretend that Halo is anything other than a blockbuster FPS. Yet, there is something sad about it, isn't there? The Halo rings themselves are all machines of death: tools of mass eradication. But all have sunrises and sunsets, wildlife, plants, ecosystems, snowy mountains, and rocky deserts. They have the texture of life, albeit carved in with ancient tech that outlived its creators and resounding with the sound of gunfire. Master Chief wanders through it all. One man, no matter how great, enveloped in majesty and terror. The original trilogy, despite its massive scale and gigantic stakes, comes down to intimate tragedy: just a man and the ghost in his head.</p><p dir="ltr">It's hard to remember that Halo: Combat Evolved was stark and bare. Since its release, there have been multiple miniseries, a television show, an abandoned movie project, dozens of novels, and real-time-strategy spin-offs. It is a downright multimedia phenomenon (though not all of its projects have been successful, in terms of popularity or quality). It is a universe that has been thoroughly elaborated on, with many of its gaps plastered over.</p><p dir="ltr">Nevertheless, Halo: Combat Evolved itself, despite a tie-in novel releasing just weeks before its launch, is uninterested in explaining things to you. You can gather from context clues what the alien "Covenant" is and what makes Master Chief "a Spartan," but it's hard if you aren't paying attention. Every character you meet, except Master Chief and Cortana, presumably perish in the game's explosive finale (though Sgt. Johnson and 343 Guilty Spark return in sequels). The game itself is snappy and quick, but the story is ponderous and exposition-heavy, without much opportunity for emotional investment.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4399038-ss_3a4d84cdabf7e015e4409b4218bcd00ba6aa730f.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399038" data-ratio="0.42553191489362" data-width="799" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4399038-ss_3a4d84cdabf7e015e4409b4218bcd00ba6aa730f.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4399038"></a><figcaption>Halo: The Master Chief Collection</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1585/15855271/4399038-ss_3a4d84cdabf7e015e4409b4218bcd00ba6aa730f.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Master Chief himself is not much of a character. He is stoic: a halfway point between silent protagonist and fleshed-out hero. He spits out one-liners and kills bad guys, but not much else. Cortana is flirty and witty, and expressive in a way Master Chief is not, but there still isn't a lot to her. She acts as a way to give the player context for what is happening. She has character in that expression, but doesn't really have a psychology beyond that (at least not yet).</p><p dir="ltr">So, most of Halo's emotional space is taken up by its still-impressive combat and sometimes-transcendent level design. It has a lot of empty space, giving you walking time, and flying or driving back through places you've already been. That's not all good. The Library is still, for my money, one of the most miserable levels in FPS history. Still, all that non-combat time offers beauty and melancholy. The game's best moments, such as "The Silent Cartographer's" sprawling set pieces (which stretch from a beach assault to underground abysses) and "Halo's" rambunctious road trip, offer interludes in Halo's "natural" world. Drives between mission locations and firefights grant contemplation. Its level design lets you look up at the sky as much as run down your enemies.</p><p dir="ltr">Halo is no nature walk, however. Its final set piece--an awkward but exhilarating drive across the spine of a capital ship--gets interrupted when Cortana calls in a transport for evac. It is immediately shot down. The set piece pauses in a strange, grieving breath. You hear the pilot's dying words, then an explosion. Cortana says, "She's gone," a beat passes, then she adds, "Calculating alternate escape route." This moment is a complication in the escape: a reason to stretch the set piece just a little further. But that death hangs in the air. Master Chief will, once again, escape this alone.</p><p dir="ltr">Halo 3 offers a parallel set piece: another driving escape across an exploding spaceship. This time, most of the Chief's allies escape, but he stays behind. He and Cortana float in one half of a spaceship and he goes into cryosleep yet again. His last words are, "Wake me when you need me." What else would you need him for but killing? It was inevitable that he would wake up again. But, absent any follow-ups, that fact is more dreadful than inspiring. The fight finished with nothing to hope for but another one beginning.</p><p dir="ltr">Narratively speaking, single-player Halo since Reach has been stuck. Halo 4, 5: Guardians, and Infinite are all soft franchise reboots. Ultimately, they have nothing close to the still-satisfying arc of the original games. Halo 4 picks up a few years after where Halo 3 left off, with Master Chief awakening once again from cryosleep. Guardians holds on to some of 4's plot threads, but turns Cortana into a malevolent AI, setting her up to be the big bad of a sequel that never came. Infinite is a Force-Awakens-esque run at the original Halo, ending with the promise that the franchise will continue more or less how it began. In these games, the tragedies are grand and explicit. Across Infinite's Halo ring, you'll find audio logs with the words of the dead. Cortana cries when she dies in Halo 4 and (disturbingly) quotes Virginia Woolf's actual suicide note when she dies again in Infinite. It's <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/halo-infinite-is-a-fun-sandbox-stuck-inside-a-very-old-video-game/" rel="nofollow ">cheap tragedy</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">In the Bungie games, with the exception of Reach, most of the main characters live. Cortana and the Arbeiter both make it to the end, though side characters like Miranda Keyes and Sergeant Johnson are less fortunate. Most deaths are of generalized populations, like the Brutes' massacre of the Elites in Halo 2, or offscreen, like the death of Spartans. Master Chief carries a grief that is almost absent--historical even. Reach's surface was already destroyed, "glassed" as the games put it. Chief does win the war, but the battle was lost before he could start.</p><p dir="ltr">In contrast, Infinite wakes up Chief after hope is lost and then lets him blaze across the battlefield, triumphing over the enemies that every other Spartan could not defeat. In Infinite, he wins the battle with the promise that he'll win the war too. It starts in tragedy, sure. But its ending is hopeful, for perhaps the first time in Halo, rife as it is with tragic endings and cliffhangers. This is necessarily not bad, but it does illustrate the limits of franchise storytelling. There must always be another fight and it must still be empowering and fun, even if Chief is ever more world-weary. It means that future Halo games will likely never match Halo 3's ending note: sleeping and waking up, with nothing but death to frame your days.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/103097971921006863809?rel=author">Grace Benfell</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reflections on my score for Tactical Breach Wizards]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/reflections-on-my-score-for-tactical-breach-wizards</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/reflections-on-my-score-for-tactical-breach-wizards.1034856/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/reflections-on-my-score-for-tactical-breach-wizards<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Within this article, I will be going over various aspects of my score for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards,</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> including my creative process, inspirations, experiences, challenges, and reflections post-release. I hope that this gives hopeful composers some behind-the-scenes insight into the production of a full game score.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Creative process and vision">Creative process and vision</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I feel like the biggest obstacle for any score, whether it’s a film, game, or other type of media, is to land the vision correctly and stay true to it.&nbsp; When I sent my work to Tom over at Suspicious Developments when he announced the composer opening, the two tracks that helped me stand out were two trailer tracks I had written that heavily used percussion. With that in mind, I wanted to ensure that percussion was at the forefront when the game called for more serious or dramatic music mixed with orchestral and sometimes electronic elements.&nbsp; It helped that I was a trailer composer, so I had access to a fair bit of trailer samples to bring some punch and intensity.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards,</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> there are four main acts and a prologue to start the game, showing the last mission between Liv and Zan.&nbsp; Along with the references Tom had sent to me, I also wanted to try to give each act a different direction while staying true to the vision of the overall score, sometimes with different instrumentation focuses, such as Act 1 (DSR) having a lot of synths and a lead electric guitar, a choir for when dealing with Chapel in Act 3 (Kalan), and using bells to put the players in a historical setting in Act 4 (Medil).&nbsp; The prologue is more of an opening sequence made of two more orchestral tracks with some of my favorite trailers, SFX.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The two outliers with the vision of the overall soundtrack were “At Ma’s” and “The Necromedic,” which were Reggae and Jazz, respectively.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Technical challenges">Technical challenges</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When it came to the challenges of writing the soundtrack, at times, I was my own worst enemy, which I will talk more about later in this article.&nbsp; At times, my own tools led to limits I had to overcome.&nbsp; Sometimes, it was my production level at the time.&nbsp; The challenges all led me to find creative ways to overcome them, and eventually, they all went away fairly quickly.&nbsp; Don’t be afraid to face them head-on, as you may be surprised by what you can do.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Influences">Influences</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Overall, the score was meant to have different militaristic elements mixed with elements that worked well with the setting.&nbsp; I thought back to older game scores and developed ideas of what I liked from those scores.&nbsp; Some of it was the use of percussion, some of it was the use of synths, and some was the use of strings and brass, which I loved.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I remember once trying to take the whimsical approach when the players were selecting their perks; however, it didn’t work. There were other moments I attempted it, but it never stuck.&nbsp; I do know that when you think of wizards and magic, you think whimsical and fantasy, but that had no place here!&nbsp; We had a more gritty theme that went with this, though there was a lot of humor around them.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Evolving as a composer">Evolving as a composer</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When working on the score, I went through an evolution over the three and a half years I was involved with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp; In ways, my process was all about experimentation with sounds, textures, and themes, but as time went on, my process evolved into a more methodical approach, mainly thanks to my studies with Penka Kouneva, who helped me clean up my methods, have more of a detailed plan with each cue, and most importantly, executing it.&nbsp; I know that has been a common issue, so it was very important for me to get it right.&nbsp; This also showed an evolution of the score with sometimes more complex writing in the latter half of the soundtrack.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Also, I had really worked on my production skills so I could achieve great results with whatever orchestral libraries and synths I owned at any time.&nbsp; I should also thank developers such as Rocky Mountain Sounds (Complexity, Majestica 2, etc.) for making great libraries and expansions that really contributed to the soundtrack in various ways.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">With all that said, all of these changes led to an issue I hadn’t accounted for, such as having to go back to a few older tracks and use what I learned to improve their quality.&nbsp; Keep in mind that if you’re working on a score over the course of several years and are still really developing, you may be in a similar position!</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Feedback from players and reflections">Feedback from players and reflections</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Over the course of the beta rounds, the feedback was great, but there was one surprise.&nbsp; The Necromedic stood out to many players in a good way, and it showed when looking at the feedback for the score. It was the favorite, which honestly made me chuckle because I didn’t consider my jazz chops to be much to write about.&nbsp; This process has shown me to be open to such nice surprises.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The overall reception to the soundtrack upon release had been something I was nervous about as this is one of the first times many people would hear my work, AND they know my name behind it as many other projects I worked on (trailers and films) didn’t thrust me into the open like this one did, especially with that hype around it.&nbsp; I appreciate the great response to the game and the soundtrack, and I hope more people play </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Tactical Breach Wizards,</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as the game is awesome with great writing, level design, art, and more.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When I look back at the soundtrack as a whole, I plan to keep using the knowledge gained during the experience and continue writing great scores, as this has so far been my best work. You never truly know how you will handle the challenges thrown at you at work like this until you’re in the thick of it, and I urge everyone to pursue these challenges.&nbsp; I really hope you enjoy the score as much as I enjoyed writing it.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[November's PlayStation Plus Premium and Extra games include GTA5, Dying Light 2, Like a Dragon: Ishin!]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/novembers-playstation-plus-premium-and-extra-games-include-gta5-dying-light-2-like-a-dragon-ishin</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/novembers-playstation-plus-premium-and-extra-games-include-gta5-dying-light-2-like-a-dragon-ishin.1034853/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/novembers-playstation-plus-premium-and-extra-games-include-gta5-dying-light-2-like-a-dragon-ishin<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Plus Resistance 1 &amp; 2 and more!</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>
Sony has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/11/13/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-november-grand-theft-auto-v-dying-light-2-stay-human-like-a-dragon-ishin-and-more/">revealed</a> the games coming to PlayStation Plus Premium and Extra subscribers this month, with November's offerings including Dying Light 2, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/like-a-dragon-ishin">Like a Dragon: Ishin</a>!, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/grand-theft-auto-v">GTA5</a> (presumably for the benefit of the two remaining people who haven't yet played it).
</p>
<p>
In total, November brings 12 new PlayStation Plus catalogue additions for Premium and Extra members, alongside five Premium-exclusive titles - including Insomniac's fondly remembered PS3 shooters <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/resistance-fall-man">Resistance: Fall of Man</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/resistance-2">Resistance 2</a> - which combine to look like this:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Grand Theft Auto 5 (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Dying Light 2: Stay Human (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Like a Dragon: Ishin! (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>MotoGP 24 (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>The Sims 4 Island Living - add-on only (PS4)</li>
<li>Digimon Survive (PS4)</li>
<li>Overcooked! All You Can Eat (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Stick Fight: The Game (PS4)</li>
<li>Clash: Artifacts of Chaos (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Killer Frequency (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Hungry Shark World (PS4)</li>
<li>Chivalry 2 (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Synapse (PSVR2)</li>
<li>Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Blood Omen 2 (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Resistance: Fall of Man </li>
<li>Resistance 2</li>
</ul>
<p>
So while November's Premium and Extra catalogue additions aren't, perhaps, quite as strong as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/octobers-playstation-plus-extra-and-premium-games-include-dead-island-2-dino-crisis">last month's stellar line-up</a>, there's still plenty of amusement to be found. GTA5 needs no introduction, of course, but there's also solid parkour-focused zombie slaying in Dying Light 2, enjoyable historical action as Like a Dragon spins off into the Edo period with Ishin!, and even some chaotic multiplayer medieval hack-and-slashery in the acclaimed <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/chivalry-2">Chivalry 2</a>.
</p><p>
And that's on top of those Premium tier exclusives, pretty much all good stuff this month. Alongside the first two Resistance games, there's Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain and its sequel - which should stand you in good stead if you been <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-2-remastered-enhancements-include-map-compass-and-more">eyeing the upcoming Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver 1&amp;2 remasters</a> - plus some solid sci-fi shooting with Synapse for PSVR2.
</p>
<p>
All the above joins the PlayStation Plus game catalogue next Tuesday, 19th November, and you'll find more details on what else is on offer in our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-plus-games-list-premium-extra-this-month-6300">full PlayStation Plus guide</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aloft Early Access Release Date Revealed for January]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/aloft-early-access-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/aloft-early-access-release-date-revealed-for-january.1034838/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/aloft-early-access-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher Funcom and developer Astrolabe Interactive have announced the Early Access release date for co-op survival game&nbsp;<em>Aloft</em>, which takes place in a world in which you can transform floating islands into "your personal skyship".</p>

<p>Per a press release,&nbsp;<em>Aloft&nbsp;</em>launches into Early Access on January 15th, which is roughly two months off at time of writing. It's due to land on Steam, and there's no word about whether a console version is on the way anytime soon.</p>

<p>Unlike other Funcom survival games like&nbsp;<em>Conan: Exiles&nbsp;</em>or <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dune-awakening-reveals-spectacular-gameplay-and-details" rel="nofollow">the upcoming&nbsp;<em>Dune: Awakening</em></a>,&nbsp;<em>Aloft&nbsp;</em>takes place in a bright, cartoony world in which you can freely soar through the skies, searching for resources and looking for an island to call your own.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/aloft-early-access-release-date-archery.jpg?itok=-CEo7HWX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/aloft-early-access-release-date-archery.jpg?itok=_iyOw2sq 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Aloft&nbsp;</em>takes place in a whimsical world overtaken by fungal corruption.</figcaption></figure><p>Although&nbsp;<em>Aloft</em>'s world is more breezy (no pun intended) than other survival games offer, that doesn't mean there's no darkness lurking beneath the surface. A fungus-based corruption is taking hold of the islands, and it's up to you to put a stop to it.</p>

<p>With that said, though,&nbsp;<em>Aloft</em>'s Steam page says the game is "more about rewarding positive action than punishing mistakes", so if you've been looking for a survival game that doesn't break you in half when you mess up, this seems like it'll be up your street.</p>

<p>Once you discover the island you want to call your own, you'll be able to build it into a skyship and use it to traverse&nbsp;<em>Aloft</em>'s world of floating archipelagos in a manner not dissimilar to Bossa Studios' <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/bossa-studios-worlds-adrift-is-shutting-down-this-summer" rel="nofollow">ill-fated&nbsp;<em>Worlds Adrift</em></a>. Let's hope this one fares a bit better!</p>




<p>Over the course of its Early Access run, which the developers estimate will last "at least a year",&nbsp;<em>Aloft&nbsp;</em>will be regularly updated with new mechanics, biomes, and challenges, plus lots more.</p>

<p>You can wishlist&nbsp;<em>Aloft&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1660080/Aloft/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC via Steam</a> ahead of its Early Access release on January 15th.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The rarely discounted PlayStation Pulse Elite headset hits a record low price]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295476/sony-playstation-pulse-elite-ps5-gaming-headset-deal-sale</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-rarely-discounted-playstation-pulse-elite-headset-hits-a-record-low-price.1034835/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295476/sony-playstation-pulse-elite-ps5-gaming-headset-deal-sale<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It’s inordinately rare to find the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/10/30/23938722/sony-playstation-pulse-explore-elite-earbuds-headset-release-date"><strong>PlayStation Pulse Elite</strong></a> on sale, but <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24288220/black-friday-best-deals-guide-cyber-monday-tech-gadgets-2024">Black Friday</a> season is always a good opportunity for retailers to break the rules. Sony’s flagship wireless headset is discounted to $129.99 ($20 off) at <a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPlayStation-PULSE-Elite-Wireless-Headset%2F5113175920">Walmart</a> right now as part of its early Black Friday sale. Although the discount doesn’t appear massive, that still represents the lowest price we’ve seen so far.</p><p>The Pulse Elite launched in late 2023 alongside a slate of other mid-cycle PlayStation 5 accessories, including the $199.99 <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23957860/sony-pulse-explore-playstation-earbuds-impressions">Pulse Explore earbuds</a> and the once-elusive <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24012547/sony-playstation-portal-handheld-remote-player-ps5-chiaki-review">PlayStation Portal</a> handheld companion.</p><div><p>Sony’s PlayStation Pulse Elite is an over-ear headset with a retractable boom mic. It’s designed to filter out background noise, deliver low latency and lossless audio, and work with the PlayStation Portal or the PlayStation 5, PC, and Mac via the PlayStation Link USB adapter. </p></div><p>While many third-party wireless headsets support 3D Audio (PlayStation’s take on simulated spatial audio), Pulse Elite supports what Sony considers the ideal acoustics and tuning to get the most from your games. Sony also uses planar magnetic drivers, which are usually reserved for studio-grade monitors. They’re said to offer a more accurate soundstage with less distortion compared to the dynamic neodymium drivers used in most consumer-oriented headphones and headsets.</p><p>Besides its decidedly PlayStation, almost alien design, the headset notably supports Sony’s low latency lossless wireless audio codec. That feature requires the included PlayStation Link dongle, which works with the PS5, PlayStation Portal, Windows PCs, and Macs. It also has Bluetooth, so you can use it with your mobile devices and simultaneously hear from both sources. The retractable voice-isolating boom microphone enables game chat and voice calling in either scenario. </p><p>Whether you’re already a PS5 owner or looking to take your first jump into the deep end of the PlayStation pool with the newly released <a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/24289319/ps5-pro-review">PS5 Pro</a>, it may be worth a shot if you don’t already have a viable headset.</p><div><form><div><h2>Verge Deals</h2><p> / <span>Sign up for Verge Deals to get deals on products we've tested sent to your inbox weekly.</span></p></div></form></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Game Catalog Gets 16 Games In November]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-16-games-in-november/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-16-games-in-november.1034829/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-plus-game-catalog-gets-16-games-in-november/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-68442">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Sony <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/11/13/playstation-plus-game-catalog-for-november-grand-theft-auto-v-dying-light-2-stay-human-like-a-dragon-ishin-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">has revealed</a> that the PlayStation Plus Game Catalog will get 16new games in November 2024. All of the games will be available for subscribers starting November 19.</p>



<p>With the list of new games, 11 of them will be available for both PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium subscribers. The remaining 5 games are exclusively for the higher-tiered Premium members. There’s also one game for PS VR 2.</p>



<p>Some of the bigger games in this list include Grand Theft Auto 5, which returns <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-among-12-games-leaving-ps-plus-game-catalog-in-june/">after leaving in June</a>, as well as Dying Light 2: Stay Human, MotoGP 24, and Like a Dragon: Ishin.</p>



<p>In addition to the games, The Sims 4 Island Living expansion pack is part of this month’s offerings from the catalog.</p>



<h6>RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/free-playstation-plus-games-for-november-2024-announced/">Free PlayStation Plus Games For November 2024 Announced</a></h6>



<p>You can check out the full list of games coming to the catalog below.</p>



<h2 id="h-playstation-plus-game-catalog-games-november-2024">PlayStation Plus Game Catalog Games November 2024</h2>



<h3 id="h-playstation-plus-extra-and-premium">PlayStation Plus Extra and Premium</h3>



<ul>
<li>Grand Theft Auto V | PS4, PS5</li>



<li>Dying Light 2: Stay Human | PS4, PS5</li>



<li>Like a Dragon: Ishin | PS4, PS5</li>



<li>MotoGP 24 | PS4, PS5</li>



<li>The Sims 4 Island Living (Add-on only) | PS4</li>



<li>Digimon Survive | PS4</li>



<li>Overcooked! All You Can Eat | PS4, PS5</li>



<li>Stick Fight: The Game | PS4</li>



<li>Clash: Artifacts of Chaos | PS4, PS5</li>



<li>Killer Frequency | PS4, PS5</li>



<li>Hungry Shark World | PS4</li>



<li>Chivalry 2 | PS4, PS5</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-playstation-plus-premium-ps-vr2-amp-classic-games">PlayStation Plus Premium | PS VR2 &amp; Classic Games</h3>



<ul>
<li>Synapse | PS VR2</li>



<li>Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain | PS4, PS5</li>



<li>Blood Omen 2 | PS4, PS5</li>



<li>Resistance: Fall of Man | PS3</li>



<li>Resistance 2 | PS3</li>
</ul>



<p>What do you think of the new games coming to the PlayStation Plus Game Catalog in November? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official Insider Gaming Forums. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about who could be a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-ceo-andrew-wilson-ceo-of-disney/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">candidate for the next Disney CEO</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-brand-patent-trademark/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-brand-patent-trademark/">The Game Awards Calls on Fans to Help Protect Its Brand</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Geoff Keighley’s The Game Awards is seeking a US patent registration – and it’s the fans of the showcase that’ll determine whether it’s successful.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/union-workers-at-bethesda-have-gone-on-strike/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/union-workers-at-bethesda-have-gone-on-strike/">Union Workers At Bethesda Have Gone On Strike</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Hundreds of Bethesda union workers have gone on strike over a number of issues that it claims the company isn’t addressing.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-no-longer-supports-windows-7-or-8/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/steam-no-longer-supports-windows-7-or-8/">Steam No Longer Supports Windows 7 or 8</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>With Valve’s latest update to the client, Steam no longer supports users on Windows 7 or 8 meaning an update is necessary.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leak-reveals-all-nike-and-jordan-kicks-cosmetics/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-leak-reveals-all-nike-and-jordan-kicks-cosmetics/">Fortnite Leak Reveals All Nike and Jordan Kicks Cosmetics&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A reliable Fortnite leaker has revealed all upcoming Nike and Jordan Kicks cosmetics. Check out the complete list here. </p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[HEAVEN SEEKER: The Savior of This Cruel World coming to PS5, PS4, and Switch on December 5]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/heaven-seeker-the-savior-of-this-cruel-world-coming-to-ps5-ps4-and-switch-on-december-5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heaven-seeker-the-savior-of-this-cruel-world-coming-to-ps5-ps4-and-switch-on-december-5.1034823/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/heaven-seeker-the-savior-of-this-cruel-world-coming-to-ps5-ps4-and-switch-on-december-5<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>PlayStation versions newly announced.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > SUCCESS Corporation [92 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/success-corporation">SUCCESS Corporation</a> will release twin-stick <a title="Genres > Roguelite [202 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite</a> <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,928 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> <em><a title="Games > HEAVEN SEEKER: The Savior of This Cruel World [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/heaven-seeker-the-savior-of-this-cruel-world">HEAVEN SEEKER: The Savior of This Cruel World</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,426 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> and <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,298 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> on December 5, the company <a href="https://twitter.com/HEAVEN_SEEKER_S" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. The <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,417 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> versions are newly announced. Wishlisting is available via <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-nz/concept/10011618" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Store</a> in regions where it is already November 14, and via <a href="https://store-jp.nintendo.com/item/software/D70010000086087" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Nintendo eShop</a> in Japan. <span id="more-927398"></span> </p><p><em>HEAVEN SEEKER: The Savior of This Cruel World</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2865230/HEAVEN_SEEKER_The_Savior_of_This_Cruel_World/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on June 21.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2865230/HEAVEN_SEEKER_The_Savior_of_This_Cruel_World/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>HEAVEN SEEKER: The Savior of This Cruel World</em> is a twin-stick roguelite shooter where you take your own shot at the castle in the sky! A dungeon with a different structure each time you enter, a variety of magic bullets—and a formidable barrage of bullets—await you.</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>In this world, Pentagaia, there were five countries that had been transferred from five different worlds.</p><p>Magi Province, the land of wizards, where magical technology flourished. A land of priestesses and samurai, a land of warriors and the four seasons. A land of elves, with the blessings of the World Tree. A land of mechanical ingenuity, where super-science rules the world. A land of wilderness and dust, ruled by demons.</p><p>The rulers of each nation sent explorers to the Castle of Heaven, where the secrets of Pentagaia were said to lie. They did so with the longing to return to the original world. These explorers were called “Heaven Seekers.”</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Explore a Dungeon That Changes Each Time You Enter</strong> – In this title, you move with the left stick and aim with the right stick. This is a bullet hell shooting game where you freely control your character and explore random dungeons. When your HP reaches 0, you will lose all the items you have gained during this exploration. The player gains experience by exploring many times and learning the patterns of the rooms and the nature of the enemies.</li><li><strong>Create Your Own “Magic Shot!”</strong> – The shot fired by the player character can be modified by freely combining over 20 customizable items to change its properties. Since items are randomly acquired during each quest, players will fight with a different “personalized shot” each time they dive into a dungeon.</li><li><strong>Dot Art Style Game Visuals</strong> – All in-game elements in this title, including player characters, enemies, and dungeons, are rendered in high-quality dot art.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Animal Well's home-brewed engine was key to its success]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/why-animal-well-s-home-brewed-engine-was-key-to-its-success</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-animal-wells-home-brewed-engine-was-key-to-its-success.1034820/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/why-animal-well-s-home-brewed-engine-was-key-to-its-success<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For most of his development career, Billy Basso has attended gaming conventions on a work and promotional capacity. He'd stand near an incomplete game demo kiosk, watching people play it, taking notes, figuring out if he's on the right track. Analyze, focus, guess, and hope.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In September, he finally got a taste of the other side of the booth.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"PAX West was the first show that happened after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well's</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> launch," Basso says weeks later from his home studio in Chicago. "I was looking forward to taking, in a way, a victory lap." He describes a crowd of people lining up at the Seattle expo–not to play a new game, but to greet Blasso and share "all of these stories" about their positive experiences with his months-old title.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As Animal Well's sole coder, artist, and designer, Basso deserves the lap. Since its April 2024 launch on consoles and PCs, the indie "Metroidvania" game has amassed nearly universal acclaim. Sales estimator Gamalytic points to sales figures exceeding 300,000 copies on Steam alone. During its launch month,</span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/813230/ANIMAL_WELL/">Animal Well</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> at one point outsold every first-party Nintendo game on Switch's eShop.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In a chat with Game Developer, Basso and his business partner, Dan Adelman, reflect on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s development, launch, and success. What worked? How did surprising fare, like a Wisconsin tourist attraction and the 3D adventure </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Shadows of the Colossus</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, inspire and guide the game's unique spin on Metroidvanias? And what might come next?</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a data-discover="true" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/art/creature-feature-the-surreal-pixel-art-and-animation-of-animal-well" target="_self">Creature feature: The surreal pixel art and animation of Animal Well</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Opting out of battles with pre-made engines">Opting out of battles with pre-made engines</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> journey began in two phases, Basso says: a quick stab at a Metroidvania-styled prototype in 2012, and a bespoke engine project that he took more seriously, which he began coding alone in 2014 during his day job's off hours. That day job, to clarify, was programming work at the video game studio Phosphor Games.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I was typically working on mobile games with live service elements that were heavily dependent on network infrastructure," he says. "We were using off-the-shelf game engines that had a lot of bloat and were laggy." Having his own bespoke, offline engine was a priority for whatever kind of game he would eventually make on his own, to avoid the "sour taste" of inefficient tools and workflows.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But Basso's work on a "general purpose, 3D game engine" dragged on during nights and weekends for three years before he came to a tough conclusion: the engine-focused project had been too focused on "preemptively solving problems," instead of "having enough direction to actually turn into a game."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It was 2017, and some of the design ideas from his 2012 Metroidvania lark had continued pulling on him, so Basso "wrote off" his 3D engine as "a learning experience" and started anew with 2D search action as a priority. Like before, off-the-shelf solutions weren't going to cut it, but at least this time, he had a genre and some design directives in mind.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For his new game, he wanted pixels to scale perfectly to a variety of common screen resolutions, along with visual effects that meshed well with his integer-scaled pixel art. He disliked "built-in lighting effects" that developers had to "fight against quite a bit" in engines like Unity: "they have point lights and stuff, they have a smooth gradient, and that clashes with pixel art."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Build your own technology, then let it set the tone">Build your own technology, then let it set the tone</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">With that baseline in mind, Basso's early project took shape, but roughly one year in, he found it "looked like an NES game, where the art wasn't that striking." Thanks to his full control of the engine and rendering efficiency at the fore, Basso had more wiggle room at this point in development to add what he describes as a crucial technical upgrade: a rim light shader.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">&nbsp;"Everything was now kind of in shadow, but the edges were highlighted, and your character sprite in the bushes got blended in with the foreground tiles in a way that tied it all together," Basso says. "Immediately, when I got that shader working, I'm like, 'This is a unique look."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The inspiration dominos began falling. Basso noticed that his effects' shadow-and-light interplay "informed the stylistic direction" of the game's environments and animals. Newly inspired, he built a "full screen Navier-Stokes fluid simulation" to power the game's smoke and water effects for more haziness and dreaminess, along with more lighting and particle-effect systems, painting more highlights and posterization effects over backgrounds and sprites.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Image via Billy Basso/BigMode.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This is interesting," Basso recalls thinking, "where I have this high-fidelity physics simulation working, but it's being paired with this, in some ways, primitive pixel art." As Basso's work bounced between design, art, and engine development, "the richness of the game got layered on, and I found the game's tone and identity gradually over that process." Despite his earlier hiccups with a 3D engine, he still recommends an engine-first mentality for new game development: "That opens up a lot of unique creative avenues. Once I get a cool system working, then I can play around with it and see what it allows for."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Digging the well with Adelman's aid">Digging the well with Adelman's aid</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">With his 2D game in full swing, Basso inadvertently learned about Adelman, a business- and marketing-focused industry veteran, through a pair of interviews in late 2017 and early 2018. Basso appreciated hearing how Adelman had transitioned from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/making-world-of-goo-an-all-time-indie-darling">revolutionizing Nintendo's digital distribution channels</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to dedicated support for indie devs, particularly for the breakout Metroidvania hit </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Axiom Verge</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "I'm naturally a pretty introverted person, so having someone like him to work with sounded very appealing to me," Basso says. He sent a cold-call email.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In hindsight, Adelman admits that his near-instant email reply turned out to be a bit disingenuous. "What was special enough about [Animal Well] that made me think, 'oh I want to work on this,' versus what it eventually became, were actually very different games," he says on the PAX West 2024 show floor. "I really like both games." The game he originally envisioned landed somewhere between </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>VVVVVV </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>You Have To Win The Game</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">–since both eschewed combat in favor of exploration, puzzles, and hardcore platforming. For Adelman, the cherry on top was the early game's emphasis on nooks and crannies, which might otherwise be hidden in shadow or other Basso-developed effects: "I really loved finding secret passageways that I walked past, like, four or five times before I noticed them," Adelman says. "Like, oh, this opens up into a whole new area!"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">With Adelman on board, Basso's more richly developed prototypes started getting in front of industry players, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s first major reveal came in a small booth at the inaugural Summer Game Fest in June 2022, an in-person event in the wake of the defunct Electronics Entertainment Expo (E3). That event's biggest </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> payoff came one week later, as a six-second blip in</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YBD3ExFI9_E"> a wrap-up video</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> made by popular YouTube creator Jason "Dunkey" Gastrow.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="A big leap with BigMode">A big leap with BigMode</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Jason, in his normal style, basically shit on the whole event, but he did give us a positive shout-out," Adelman says. "Just from that one mention, our wishlist numbers had a big spike." Shortly after this, Gastrow and his wife Leah traded follows with the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> team on Twitter, which led to a series of DMs between Adelman and Leah during that September's Tokyo Game Show. Leah requested a playable build of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">; Adelman asked that it not be used as YouTube or Twitch content. Leah replied that she had something else in mind: "We're starting a publishing label, called BigMode," Adelman recalls her saying. "Would you have any interest in talking about that?"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Adelman had not planned to add a formal publisher to the Animal Well development period; after all, he didn't need one for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Axiom Verge</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. And the Dunkey YouTube channel's reputation–full of curse words and overt trolling in online games–gave Adelman some pause: "is [Gastrow's] real-life persona the same as his online persona?" (The past few years have seen other YouTube and Twitch creators take </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/marketing/dr-disrespect-s-ousting-should-be-a-wake-up-call-for-devs">huge</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> missteps in their own game-publishing efforts.)</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Image via Billy Basso/BigMode.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But Adelman and Gastrow's initial conversations were polite and promising. Game promotion and marketing were changing in the years since </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Axiom Verge</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Jason's online reach and the couple's genuine enthusiasm filled an information gap for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> at this point in development. Jason had made a career out of tapping into a modern gaming audience's attention span–how people engage with new games and pick favorites out of a deluge of indies. If Gastrow saw something special in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, he could convince a lot of people to do the same. In short, what a good publisher does.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This could be a disaster, or it could be a really good fit," Adelman recalls thinking.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">(When asked for comment on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s development and success at PAX West 2024, Jason Gastrow replies by repeating the same sentence twice: "I feel like one hundred penguins." It is unclear whether this statement was in line with Gastrow's humorous YouTube persona, or whether he was offering a hint about an undiscovered </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> secret, since the game prominently features penguins.)</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="&quot;Layers&quot; work–but they need to be distinct and appealing">"Layers" work–but they need to be distinct and appealing</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">wastes no time hinting at its range of secrets. With no plot or narration, players begin running-and-jumping around a dark, eerie cave. In one direction, players can pick up an "egg" from a treasure chest with no indication of what it means or does. In the other direction, a squirrel runs away, and a rabbit is seen hiding in a seemingly unreachable corner of the screen. Neither of these hints is borne out with prompt clarification, and the mysteries and layers keep coming.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But that opening beat is nothing compared to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s "layers" of deeper puzzles. Some required dozens of players' collaboration to figure out, and others required connecting specific hardware to a PC while playing the game. Layers found their way into </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in a few ways:</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">With a publishing deal in place and budget settled, Bigmode, Adelman, and Basso agreed not to rush the game's launch–and to let Basso ultimately lead on the development, implementation, and difficulty of the game's crisscrossing puzzles. Basso would often hand a new build to Adelman and the BigMode team without spoiling its four "layers" of puzzles, though the deepest layer was so obtuse that its puzzles simply couldn't be tested by Bigmode's tiny team without cheat codes.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This part of the game's development never exceeded Adelman's "scope creep" bandwidth, as he found the deeper puzzle additions never added "bloat" to the development process. Basso would review feedback after each build was turned in and accept "maybe half" of the suggestions. "It wasn't so much like I was asking permission ever to do something," Basso says. "I kind of just did it."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For Basso, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s deeper layers would have no value unless players connected with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s surface-level content. He drew inspiration from an unlikely 3D-adventure game: 2005's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Shadow of the Colossus</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, whose online community eventually began hunting for a "hidden" 17th "colossus" boss (which never existed).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"It was almost like a religious conviction that they wanted to find this missing part of the game," Basso says. "But then you realize that that's only true because </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Shadow of the Colossus</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is one of the most finely crafted games ever made, and people care that much because the base game is so compelling."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Early on, Basso committed to one principle in particular: none of its items could be considered "staples" in other Metroidvania games. Midway through development, Basso inadvertently realized he'd leaned on children's toys as the game's foundation, including a Slinky, a yo-yo, a bubble wand, and a frisbee—which gave him immediate reference points for their designs, plus the freedom to add clever surprises to each (particularly the bubble wand's unique "climbing" system). Basso likes the "safe bet" nature of the popular toys he picked out: "That's already a proven interaction."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Inspiration from The House on the Rock">Inspiration from The House on the Rock</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The last step was to coalesce Basso's artistic and design leanings in a way that would make his mysterious world inviting and exciting to explore, not confusing. Basso had his vision catalyzed after visiting</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.thehouseontherock.com/"> The House on the Rock in Wisconsin</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "It's this ramshackle collection of weird objects that the original owner of the house collected, and he built all these expansions to store them all," Basso says. "You can go in any direction and find cool stuff to look at. It's always surprising, and you can't really predict what the through line is between all of them, but it still feels consistent."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Basso says he wanted to make "the video game version" of the tourist attraction, though his version would include an unspoken mythology defined by "all the weird, Midwestern lawn ornaments I was seeing in my neighborhood." This explains some of the game's atypical animals standing amongst overgrown, lawn-like weeds (hello, pink flamingos), but Basso also describes an effort to keep his game's animals as unique as its items.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Basso admits leaning towards a cast of animals in the game because he finds them "more enjoyable" to draw than humans, and that he can have more creative license since people on average are "more forgiving about the [visual] details, about what they look like." His initial impulse was to draw "more zoo animals," Basso says. "There's a zebra in the [early versions]. And there's just some, like, bears."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Image via Billy Basso/BigMode.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As the game's more mysterious tone took shape, Basso began watching nature documentaries on YouTube, then found himself compelled by the weirder, less popular animals he saw. "I remember learning that the beluga whale can imitate the sound of children underwater," Basso says. "They trick a lot of divers into thinking there's a child drowning." He might have otherwise picked a better-known creature to fit whatever biome he needed (water, forest, cavern, etc.), but documentaries shaped his excitement: "Oh, I like this detail. That's scary and creepy and interesting." He thus filled out the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Community matters—with a pre-release twist">Community matters—with a pre-release twist</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Adelman admits that before working on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, he'd never focused pre-release efforts on the concept of community, and he was particularly ambivalent about one popular service, which he'd seen other game developers adopt for their own games with mixed success. "I guess we've got to start up a Discord server and hope people show up," Adelman recalls initially thinking. But in the game's run-up, Basso hid a number of puzzles across the game's promotional channels, including videos and website posts–all hinting to the caliber of puzzles that would eventually debut in the game's deeper layers. The resulting Discord engagement was immediately massive.&nbsp; "These ARGs brought a lot of people together, and friendships started to form," Adelman says. "So I was like, 'Oh, I get what [people] mean now, when they talk about building community.'"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Before that full community could coalesce, Adelman elected to test one unique version of "community": a pre-release, critics-only Discord channel. In addition to giving critics a few weeks to play the final game, Adelman wanted to provide a meeting place for critics to "share information and collaborate on certain puzzles," admitting that Basso's design vision always included an expectation of community-driven puzzle solving. (In other words: it's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>not</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> cheating to ask for Animal Well help!)</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This had two outcomes for the very small </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> development team: First, the developers could see in real time a miniature version of how </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> would be digested by a community at large–something that couldn't necessarily be replicated by a dedicated QA team. Second, it arguably bumped the game's review scores. "I think if everyone had been playing in isolation, they might have missed out on some things," Adelman says. "Sometimes a reviewer would say, 'I just found this,' and everyone would be, like, 'What?! I gotta look for that." We might have gotten a lot of 7 out of 10s, 8 out of 10s, if people didn't seek out some of the more interesting content or didn't know where to find it."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Not &quot;niche,&quot; but &quot;intense&quot;">Not "niche," but "intense"</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The community's response to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s pre-release ARG puzzles gave Basso confidence to build complex puzzles for the final game, and that community responded even more fiercely to the final retail game. "People really appreciated the secrets in the game," he says. "I'd assumed there'd be a hardcore group of people that that appealed to. And most people would just enjoy the game. Maybe that is the case, but I think everybody that did experience those deeper, later parts of the game, they all seemed to really resonate with it.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Still, when the game's deepest riddles were uncovered by the community–particularly a cypher whose only hint is the pixel-long direction a bunny's ears are turned–Adelman and Basso admit they were shocked by how quickly it happened.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Adelman suggests the internal estimate for full puzzle discovery was somewhere around ten years. "There were so many people who were so passionate about </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, that there were probably, you know, ten man-years dedicated in that condensed amount of time," Adelman says. "It was just way more people working way harder on [the game's puzzles] than we ever expected." (Basso insists that "there are some things the community hasn't found" in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> but has not elaborated further.)</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As Basso speaks to trusting his development instincts, he confirms that he's "thinking about another game" and is thus in the "very early stages of setting a new project and engine up." He intends to deliver something similar to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Well</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">'s scope, if not something "bigger."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I'm looking forward to releasing a game within the context of having already released Animal Well," Basso says. "I think I'll have more flexibility with how it is marketed, and it will be fun to play off, and subvert, existing fans' expectations." And he clarifies that the afterglow of Animal Well's launch, including a "victory lap" where feedback has moved from comment sections to critical accolades and real-life lines, made years of solo-development isolation worth it. He had ultimate control over its tools, engines, art, and mechanics. Now, and forever, he says that's out of his hands.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Animal Well was this sort of pure side project where I could implement things in what I felt was the ideal way," Basso says. "Robust, not dependent on things. [The result was] a timeless quality that older cartridge games have–that still have, like, really intense speed running communities. I wanted to make a game that, you know, could still have a fandom around it 30 years from now."</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Pro Game Boost Falls Short of Promised 45% Performance Increase, Likely Due to Memory Bandwidth Constraints]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-game-boost-falls-short-memory-bandwidth/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-5-pro-game-boost-falls-short-of-promised-45-performance-increase-likely-due-to-memory-bandwidth-constraints.1034802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-game-boost-falls-short-memory-bandwidth/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The PlayStation 5 Pro Game Boost feature isn't delivering the 45% improvements promised before launch likely due to memory bandwidth constraints.</p>
<p>Speaking during the latest episode of their weekly podcast, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DigitalFoundry">Digital Foundry</a> commented on the system's features delivering, so far, only a 30%, 35% improvement in titles that did not receive a PS5 Pro Enhanced patch. While it is still not clear if Game Boost, which is essentially a compatibility mode, offers all the features and all the performance of the system, which seems unlikely, considering the Xbox Series X, powered by AMD hardware like Sony's consoles, offers the full GPU power when running Xbox One X using a similar compatibility mode, there's a very good chance that memory bandwidth constraints are limiting the improvements. This is similar to what happened on the PlayStation 4 Pro, as the 45% GPU upgrade over the base model was accompanied by only a 28% improvement in memory bandwidth, although the unbalance was way worse in the previous generation refresh system, which couldn't target 4K resolution in games even if the system had the shading power for it.</p>
<p>The PlayStation 5 Pro Game Boost feature being limited by memory bandwidth hypothesis is somewhat backed up by how AMD handles its GPU, as the increase in CU is parallel to an increase in memory bandwidth and memory controller improvement that allows larger cache GPUs to better handle high resolutions such as 4K. As such, there may be situations in the future where the PS5 Pro will be able to handle 1080p at 120 FPS with ease but struggle more at higher resolutions, as the higher the resolution, the more memory bandwidth is needed.</p>
<p><iframe title="DF Direct Weekly #188: Death Stranding Xbox, God of War Ragnarök PS5 Pro, Switch 2 Back Compat!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7rzR03knFfk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Despite unpatched games not seeing the improvements that some were expecting, the PlayStation 5 Pro seems to be delivering in PS5 Pro patched games, as in cases like<a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-god-of-war-ragnarok-pssr-framerate-down/"> God of War Ragnarok</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-patch/">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a>, the visual and performance improvements are substantial. You can learn more about what else the recently released system is capable of doing in our <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/playstation-5-pro-hardware-the-next-gen-graphics-upgrade/">review.</a></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Secret Level Trailer Teases Warhammer 40K, Armored Core, And Concord's Final Send-Off]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-prime-secret-level-trailer-concord-space-marines-1851697385</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-secret-level-trailer-teases-warhammer-40k-armored-core-and-concords-final-send-off.1034787/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/amazon-prime-secret-level-trailer-concord-space-marines-1851697385<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Secret Level</em> continues to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/secret-level-amazon-armored-core-playstation-keanu-1851627812?_gl=1*eacxyu*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUxMDI2MC4xMTAuMS4xNzMxNTExNTUzLjUxLjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/secret-level-amazon-armored-core-playstation-keanu-1851627812?_gl=1*eacxyu*_ga*MzQzNjkwNDM2LjE2NDY2NjQ1NzQ.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTczMTUxMDI2MC4xMTAuMS4xNzMxNTExNTUzLjUxLjAuMA..">look like a sizzle reel for a new console launch lineup</a></span>, but in a good way. The Prime Video series featuring over a dozen stories set in the fantasy and sci-fi worlds of actual video (and tabletop) games has one last trailer before its premiere, and it’s packing in a lot, including the briefest glimpse of a story based on Sony’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/firewalk-studios-concord-ps5-sony-live-service-shutdown-1851684290&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/firewalk-studios-concord-ps5-sony-live-service-shutdown-1851684290">recently scuttled hero shooter <em>Concord</em></a></span>. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195624" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: August 2023 Edition" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="279" data-playlist="195624,196395,196049" data-current="195624"><div><p>The Top 10 Most-Played Games On Steam Deck: August 2023 Edition</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195624/195624_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21125.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Revealed last summer, <em>Secret Level</em> is from the studio that made <em>LOVE, DEATH + ROBOTS</em> and each of its 15 episodes is a one-off animated take on a popular gaming franchise or property, from classics like <em>Pac-Man </em>and <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> to more recent indie hits like<em> Spelunky</em> and <em>Sifu. </em>Complete with a star-studded cast featuring the talents of Arnold Schwarzenegger, Keanu Reeves, and others, the show’s latest trailer whips between each one-off episode to demonstrate the full breadth and visual variety of animation powering the series. </p><p>I don’t know if any of the stories will actually be good, but I’m excited to watch:</p><p>Buried between the<em> Warhammer 40,000</em> space marines and Keanu Reeves piloting an <em>Armored Core </em>mech, there’s a lightning-quick flash of a beautiful blue and magenta nebula with a ship flying through it and the title card <em>Concord</em> overtop. That episode will be the last gasp of an ambitious sci-fi universe the developers at Firewalk Studios helped to jumpstart this year. Unfortunately, the game itself ended up being an unprecedented flop, and Sony shut down the studio just last month. </p><p> “I don’t feel bad that it’s a part of the show, because I think it’s an episode that turned out really well, and you can kind of see the potential of this world and the characters,” Tim Miller, the lead creative behind<em> Secret Level</em>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/tim-miller-secret-level-prime-video-1235161263/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/tim-miller-secret-level-prime-video-1235161263/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told <em>Rolling Stone</em></a></span> this week. “If it’s the remaining vestige of that product, I hope the developers feel that it’s in some way worthy, just a little bit, of the blood, sweat, and tears they put into it.” </p><p>He added that he personally has no idea why <em>Concord</em> failed the way it did. “There was no nicer, more invested group of developers than the team on <em>Concord</em>,” Miller said. “I honestly don’t understand why it didn’t work. I know that they were trying to do the best they could, and they were a talented group of artists, so I feel terrible for that.”</p><p><em>Secret Level</em> premieres on Amazon’s streaming service on December 10 with new episodes dropping throughout that week. That might be when players finally catch a better glimpse of what <em>Concord</em>’s developers hoped would make it so special. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Game Awards Calls on Fans to Help Protect Its Brand]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-brand-patent-trademark/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-game-awards-calls-on-fans-to-help-protect-its-brand.1034784/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/the-game-awards-brand-patent-trademark/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Next month, The Game Awards celebrates its tenth anniversary as the leading award show in the gaming space. It’s the premier presentation for gamers worldwide, with awards being dished out, new games being teased, and updates being revealed. This year’s event, which will take place on December 12, is set to be a monumental showcase.</p>



<p>In the run-up to the event, The Game Awards has posted an email revealing to fans that it’s trying to secure registration with the US Patent &amp; Trademark Office, legitimising the brand. It has called on those same fans to bolster the application and help secure the trademark.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-distinctive-association">Distinctive Association</h2>



<p>In an email circulated amongst fans, The Game Awards’ team explained:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We are just 1 month away from The Game Awards and our 10th anniversary. </p>



<p>As a fan who joined us for one of our Zoom sessions during the pandemic, we are reaching out with a quick request. </p>



<p>We are currently in the midst of registering “The Game Awards” as a mark with the US Patent &amp; Trademark office. We are looking for letters of support to establish that consumers (that’s you!) distinctively associate the term “The Game Awards” with our annual awards show.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The email then requested any ‘personal reflections’ that fans might have, all of which will be added to the application when it’s submitted in the coming weeks. If successful, the patent will recognise The Game Awards with a trademark, representing the legitimacy of the event and the high standard to which it’s now held by gamers everywhere.</p>



<p>Upon opening the link in the email, users are presented with a pre-written letter regarding them as a ‘video game enthusiast and an avid viewer of The Game Awards’. By signing the letter, you confirm to the best of your ability that The Game Awards is a ‘well-known trademark’ associated with the showcase hosted by Geoff Keighley – and Ola Balola LLC.</p>



<p>What do you think? Do you associate the term ‘The Game Awards’ with <strong>nothing but </strong>the annual showcase hosted by Geoff?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/union-workers-at-bethesda-have-gone-on-strike/">the union strike at Bethesda</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout, Elder Scrolls, and Doom Workers Go on Strike in Protest at Parent Company Microsoft]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-elder-scrolls-and-doom-workers-go-on-strike-in-protest-at-parent-company-microsoft</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-elder-scrolls-and-doom-workers-go-on-strike-in-protest-at-parent-company-microsoft.1034778/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/fallout-elder-scrolls-and-doom-workers-go-on-strike-in-protest-at-parent-company-microsoft<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Hundreds of unionized ZeniMax workers go on strike today over an alleged lack of bargaining by parent company Microsoft.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Staff who are members of ZeniMax Workers United-CWA are on a one-day strike to call out Microsoft for an alleged lack of progress at the bargaining table over remote work and for allegedly unilaterally outsourcing quality assurance work without bargaining with the union.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In January 2023, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsofts-zenimax-media-sees-300-qa-workers-unionize">ZeniMax Workers United-CWA formed the first video game studio union at Microsoft</a>, representing over 300 quality assurance workers in Maryland and Texas. Today's strike takes place at four ZeniMax locations across Maryland and Texas, with workers set to return to their desks tomorrow, November 14. Microsoft did not immediately respond to a request for comment from IGN.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">ZeniMax is the umbrella organization that includes The Elder Scrolls and Fallout maker Bethesda and Doom developer id Software, among other studios. It also owns <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> developer MachineGames and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/blade-arkane">Marvel's Blade</a> developer Arkane Lyon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last month, Communications Workers of America Union (CWA) filed an unfair labor practice charge against ZeniMax for contracting out work without notification. ZeniMax Workers United-CWA members have raised concerns that ZeniMax’s recent unilateral decision to outsource quality assurance work threatens job security amid record layoffs across the video game industry.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The strike comes hot on the heels of Microsoft gaming boss Phil Spencer's insistence that “the Xbox business has never been more healthy.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every Video Game Franchise Xbox Owns After Acquiring Activision Blizzard</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">After splashing out $69 billion on Call of Duty maker Activision Blizzard last year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-lays-off-another-650-staff-from-its-video-game-workforce-xbox-boss-phil-spencer-sends-memo-to-staff">Microsoft has cut more than 2,500 jobs from its gaming business</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-closes-redfall-developer-arkane-austin-hifi-rush-developer-tango-gameworks-and-more-in-devastating-cuts-at-bethesda">closed three ZeniMax studios</a>. Sales of Xbox Series X and S continue to plummet, and Game Pass subscriber numbers are flat, although <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-biggest-call-of-duty-launch-ever-sets-new-single-day-game-pass-sub-record">Microsoft said it enjoyed a record bump from the recent day one launch of Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Speaking to <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-13/microsoft-s-gaming-chief-is-still-looking-for-acquisitions-sees-future-growth" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bloomberg</a>, Spencer said 2025 is looking brighter for Microsoft’s gaming effort. “The Xbox business has never been more healthy,” he said, citing growth in cloud and PC gaming as well as console usage. “The business is performing right now, and I think that means a more healthy future for hardware and the games we build.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Spencer is even optimistic about the growth of mobile games, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-layoffs-hit-call-of-duty-warzone-mobile-which-didnt-hit-as-big-as-hoped">despite cutting staff from the teams behind the underperforming Call of Duty Warzone Mobile and Warcraft Rumble</a>. “I feel pretty good about where this industry is going,’’ he said. “To reach new players, we need to be creative and adaptive of new business models, new devices, new ways of access. We’re not going to grow the market with $1,000 consoles.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Spencer is of course under pressure to deliver following the Activision Blizzard acquisition, and is in the middle of a big multiplatform push <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-gaming-boss-phil-spencer-wont-rule-out-any-xbox-exclusive-making-the-jump-to-playstation-including-halo">that may end up seeing Halo launch on PlayStation</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We run a business,” <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-boss-phil-spencer-explains-decision-to-launch-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-on-ps5">Spencer said in August</a>. “It’s definitely true inside of Microsoft the bar is high for us in terms of the delivery we have to give back to the company. Because we get a level of support from the company that’s just amazing and what we’re able to go do.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“So I look at this, how can we make our games as strong as possible? Our platform continues to grow, on console, on PC, and on cloud. It’s just going to be a strategy that works for us.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>