<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 11:44:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 x Street Fighter 6 Kicks Off Today, Bringing New Skins, Signature Special Moves as Emotes and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/overwatch-2-x-street-fighter-6-kicks-off-today-bringing-new-skins-signature-special-moves-as-emotes-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-x-street-fighter-6-kicks-off-today-bringing-new-skins-signature-special-moves-as-emotes-and-more.1193823/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/overwatch-2-x-street-fighter-6-kicks-off-today-bringing-new-skins-signature-special-moves-as-emotes-and-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Overwatch 2 x Street Fighter 6 collaboration is going live today, introducing new content inspired by the latest entry in the CAPCOM fighting series, such as new skins and signature special moves as emotes.</p>
<p>The collaboration event, which will run from today May 20th until June 2nd, brings eight new skins, the highest number of any Overwatch 2 collaboration, for Hanzo, Juno, Sigma, Soldier 76, Kiriko, Winston, Widowmaker, and Zenyatta. These skins change the character's appearance and introduce new animations and visual effects inspired by the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/street-fighter-6-review-best-fight-our-lives/">Street Fighter 6</a> central game mechanics. All eight skins can be purchased with the Street Fighter 6 Ultra Bundle, but those who wish to get only some of the eight skins can either purchase the Mega Bundle 1, which includes Legendary Juno as Chun-Li, Hanzo as Ryu, Zenyatta as Dhalsim and Epic Sigma as M.Bison, or Mega Bundle 2, which includes Legendary Kiriko as Juri and Widowmaker as Cammy in their fiercest forms, with Winston as Blanka and Soldier: 76 as Guile. All fighters are also available individually.</p>
<p>For the duration of the Overwatch 2 x Street Fighter 6 collaboration event, players will also be able to take part in special time-limited challenges that will reward them with up to 40,000 XP, exclusive themed sprays, voice lines, and the Street Fighter player title. More information on the collaboration event can be found on the game's <a href="https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/news/24178101/overwatch-2-x-street-fighter-6/">official website</a>. A trailer showcasing the new content can also be watched below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Overwatch 2 x Street Fighter 6 | Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aKR-7k-AZQ4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Overwatch 2 is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, Xbox One, and Nintendo Switch.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Asks Court To Force Apple To Return Fortnite To US App Store]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/epic-asks-court-to-force-apple-to-return-fortnite-to-us-app-store/1100-6531659/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-asks-court-to-force-apple-to-return-fortnite-to-us-app-store.1193820/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/epic-asks-court-to-force-apple-to-return-fortnite-to-us-app-store/1100-6531659/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531659">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/epics-fortnite-ban-and-apple-google-legal-battle-explained/1100-6480913/" data-ref-id="1100-6480913">ongoing legal battle between Epic Games and Apple</a> has fired up again recently after a district-court injunction led Epic to attempt to get Fortnite back on the US App Store for the first time in five years. Apple has since blocked the submission, and Epic is appealing to the court to uphold its injunction against Apple.</p><p>After Apple left the Fortnite submission unaddressed for over a week, it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-wont-be-coming-to-ios-soon-as-apple-blocks-epics-app-store-submission/1100-6531588/" data-ref-id="1100-6531588">finally responded to Epic</a> to block Fortnite's return in the US. Apple has said that it won't take action on the Fortnite submission "until after the Ninth Circuit rules on our pending request for a partial stay of the new injunction," a move Epic believes is in violation of the injunction itself. In response, Epic has filed a second Motion to Enforce Injunction with the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-returning-to-us-ios-soon-after-judge-slams-apple-for-insubordination/1100-6531258/" data-ref-id="1100-6531258">California district court in question</a>.</p><p>Epic Games managed to get Fortnite back on iPhones <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-is-back-on-iphone-after-4-years-depending-on-where-you-live/1100-6525849/" data-ref-id="1100-6525849">in Europe last year</a>, thanks to the European Union's Digital Markets Act, but the game is currently offline again in the EU due to the ongoing drama with the US App Store.</p><p>In a letter sent by Apple, the company suggests Epic resubmit Fortnite only for EU territories "to prevent our discussions surrounding the US storefront of the App Store from impacting Fortnite in other geographies." The letter further recommends submitting Fortnite to the US App Store "separately through an entity other than Epic Sweden," but Epic's <a href="https://x.com/EpicNewsroom/status/1923558197802971459" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">response</a> suggests this recommendation is in violation of Apple's own guidelines.</p><p>"That's not the standard Apple holds other developers to and it's blocking us from releasing our update in the EU and US," Epic says. "Apple is again retaliating against Epic for challenging the legality of their anticompetitive behavior and we will fight on."</p><p>The next step in this legal battle is now with the courts, with Apple having filed a request for partial stay with the Ninth Circuit Court, and Epic filing a Motion to Enforce Injunction with the US District Court for the Northern District of California. The district court judge who filed the latest injunction against Apple has also referred the case to a US criminal attorney for possible contempt charges.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite's AI Darth Vader Voice Draws Union Complaint]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnites-ai-darth-vader-voice-draws-union-complaint/1100-6531662/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnites-ai-darth-vader-voice-draws-union-complaint.1193817/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnites-ai-darth-vader-voice-draws-union-complaint/1100-6531662/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531662">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Earlier this month, Fortnite's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-chapter-6-season-3-start-date-star-wars-battle-pass-and-everything-else-to-know/1100-6530938/" data-ref-id="1100-6530938">Star Wars-themed Galactic Battle event</a> reintroduced <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/where-to-find-ai-darth-vader-in-fortnite/1100-6531612/" data-ref-id="1100-6531612">Darth Vader</a> to the game with a twist. Thanks to an AI-generated voice based on the late <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/star-wars-and-lion-king-actor-james-earl-jones-dies-at-93/1100-6526373/" data-ref-id="1100-6526373">James Earl Jones</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-now-lets-you-speak-to-darth-vader-with-the-ai-generated-voice-of-james-earl-jones/1100-6531599/" data-ref-id="1100-6531599">players can speak to Darth Vader</a> in real time and get the Dark Lord of the Sith to respond <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/darth-vader-could-say-the-f-word-in-fortnite-for-a-brief-time/1100-6531608/" data-ref-id="1100-6531608">within certain limitations</a>. Now SAG-AFTRA--the actors union which is currently engaged <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/video-game-voice-actors-and-publishers-clash-over-best-and-last-offer-to-end-the-strike/1100-6531336/" data-ref-id="1100-6531336">in a protracted voiceover performers strike</a> against video game publishers, largely over <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/spider-man-resident-evil-actors-discuss-ongoing-strike-and-the-issue-of-ai/1100-6529949/" data-ref-id="1100-6529949">the use of AI voices</a>--has filed an unfair-labor-practice complaint against Epic Games for Fortnite's use of Darth Vader's AI voice.</p><p>Two years before Jones passed away in 2024, he retired as the voice of Darth Vader and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/james-earl-jones-steps-back-as-darth-vaders-voice-as-ai-takes-over-the-role/1100-6507813/" data-ref-id="1100-6507813">signed a deal that allows an AI program to recreate his iconic voice</a> in perpetuity. SAG-AFTRA's filing contends that the deal with Jones' estate doesn't extend to other voice actors who have portrayed Darth Vader in its filing with the National Labor Relations Board.</p><p>"We celebrate the right of our members and their estates to control the use of their digital replicas and welcome the use of new technologies to allow new generations to share in the enjoyment of those legacies and renowned roles," noted a SAG-AFTRA spokesperson via <a href="https://deadline.com/2025/05/sag-aftra-fortnites-ai-darth-vader-unfair-labor-complaint-1236405218/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Deadline</a>. "However, we must protect our right to bargain terms and conditions around uses of voice that replace the work of our members, including those who previously did the work of matching Darth Vader’s iconic rhythm and tone in video games."</p><p>SAG-AFTRA contends that Fortnite's parent companies, Llama Productions and Epic Games, committed the unfair labor act by failing to disclose its intent to replace a human performer with AI and for not coming to an agreement with the union ahead of time.</p><p>It remains to be seen if the filing will have any effect on Vader's presence in the game. In the meantime, fans have posted numerous videos on social media that encourage the AI Vader to say off-the-wall and sometimes-offensive things. </p><p>Fortnite's Star Wars Galactic Battle event will continue until June 7.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Heart of Democracy Update Finally Brings the Illuminate Invasion to the Streets of Super Earth]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-finally-brings-the-illuminate-invasion-to-the-streets-of-super-earth</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-finally-brings-the-illuminate-invasion-to-the-streets-of-super-earth.1193802/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-finally-brings-the-illuminate-invasion-to-the-streets-of-super-earth<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii">Helldivers 2</a> finally has Super Earth maps to fight on as part of the Heart of Democracy major update.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-playstation-leak-suggests-players-will-fight-against-the-illuminate-on-super-earth-itself-next-week-and-now-gameplay-of-super-earth-mega-cities-has-leaked-too">As had leaked last week</a>, the Heart of Democracy update — out now across PC and PlayStation 5 — sees the Illuminate invasion reach Super Earth. You can now select missions on our home planet in Mega Cities and fight back alongside SEAF soldiers.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The city biomes include operations that work towards liberating the cities, which, developer Arrowhead said, have “a significant impact on planetary campaigns.” This is a part of Helldivers 2’s ongoing Galactic War, a community-driven meta narrative that Arrowhead orchestrates behind the scenes.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div data-cy="paragraph" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>The Illuminate have reached the Heart of Democracy. </p><p>Our Mega Cities are under siege. Liberty now hangs in the balance. The Ministry of Defence has authorised arsenal upgrades and placed SEAF soldiers on active duty. Today, we fight for the future of Super Earth! <a href="https://t.co/GxkrAQCmKD" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/GxkrAQCmKD</a></p></div>— HELLDIVERS™ 2 (@helldivers2) <a href="https://twitter.com/helldivers2/status/1924753084095307848?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">May 20, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">Here’s the official blurb, per the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/05/20/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-live-brings-the-fight-to-the-streets-of-super-earth/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PlayStation Blog</a>:</p><blockquote>The Helldivers are tasked with a new objective: to repel the Illuminate invasion by gaining ground over the squids as they fight to control areas where the fleet is landing. It won’t be a walk in the park, divers. Like a game of intergalactic tug-of-war, you will struggle against the incoming forces, gaining and losing control quickly.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">You can activate Planetary Defense Cannons and take down the Illuminate fleet, as shown in the trailer. And, as mentioned, SEAF troops will help join the fight to defend the cities. These small squads will fight enemies on their own, or they can be ordered to follow Helldivers and provide temporary backup as you navigate toward objectives. You do, however, need to be mindful of civilians who are still roaming the streets; Helldivers 2 is as much about friendly fire management as it is blowing aliens up.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Heart of Democracy update is part of Arrowhead's long-term committment to keeping Helldivers 2 going for years to come following its record-breaking launch last year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Last week, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-is-our-main-focus-and-will-be-for-a-loooong-time-arrowhead-boss-insists-as-long-as-you-keep-playing-and-buying-super-credits-we-can-keep-it-going">Arrowhead CEO Shams Jorjani addressed player concern that the studio might leave the game behind to focus on its next project</a>, dubbed "Game 6."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Nah. It's ALL Helldivers 2 for now," he insisted. "A very, very small team will spin up something later this year and go at it sloowly. Helldivers is our main focus and will be for a loooong time."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, how long does Jorjani expect content updates for Helldivers 2 to last?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"As long as you folks keep playing and buying Super Credits we can keep it going," Jorjani said, pointing to Helldivers 2's virtual currency that's used to buy Premium Warbonds. "Last summer we were kinda screwing the pooch so it looked like we wouldn't be able to keep the train going for a long time - but we turned the ship around, you support us a lot so it's looking bright."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons of Hinterberg publisher Curve Games acquired by Nazara Technologies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/dungeons-of-hinterberg-publisher-curve-games-acquired-by-nazara-technologies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-of-hinterberg-publisher-curve-games-acquired-by-nazara-technologies.1193799/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/dungeons-of-hinterberg-publisher-curve-games-acquired-by-nazara-technologies<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dungeons of Hinterberg</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Human Fall Flat</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> publisher Curve Games has been acquired by Indian esports and mobile game company Nazara Technologies.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Curve Games former parent company Catalis Group confirmed the deal in a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7330517529372614656/">post on Linkedin</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The value of the transaction wasn't disclosed.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">UK-based Curve will continue to operate independently and will retain its office in London. All current employees and the Curve leadership team will remain with the company.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Curve's in-house development studios in Brighton, UK, and Vancouver, Canada, have been included in the acquisition.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Curve executive chairman Stuart Disney described the move as a "perfect fit" for the company. "We're joining a group that lives and breathes games and tech—including mobile, where we've barely scratched the surface," he added.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"With Nazara, we will build on our strengths across console and PC, staying true to our indie spirit. It's still about great games, great studios, and great players. Our next chapter starts here."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nazara CEO Nitish Mittersain said Curve was targeted because of its "proven publishing expertise" and strong track record of working with indie studios.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This acquisition not only brings valuable IP, global market access, and a highly experienced team into our fold—it also reflects our broader strategy of doubling down on core gaming," he continued.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/voice-actor-union-hits-back-after-fortnite-debuts-controversial-ai-powered-darth-vader" target="_self" data-discover="true">Voice actor union strikes back after Fortnite debuts controversial AI-powered Darth Vader</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We're committed to scaling high-quality game IPs, investing in new development, and supporting passionate indie creators as we build a global gaming powerhouse from India."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Last year, Nazara unveiled a $100 million fund it said would be used to expand its footprint in development and publishing through mergers and acquisitions. It subsequently acquired UK studio Fusebox Games, which specializes in creating titles based on television properties. It has now added Curve to its growing portfolio.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 14 on mobile will release in June, but only in China]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-14-on-mobile-will-release-in-june-but-only-in-china</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-14-on-mobile-will-release-in-june-but-only-in-china.1193796/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-14-on-mobile-will-release-in-june-but-only-in-china<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Lightspeed Studio</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The mobile version of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/final-fantasy-xiv-a-realm-reborn">Final Fantasy 14</a> will be released in June, but only in China.</p>
<p>Yesterday, a trailer for the game was released on Chinese video platform <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1BeEtzBEip/?spm_id_from=333.1387.homepage.video_card.click">Bilibili</a> including the date, while a Live Letter stream provided new details on the game.</p>
<p>The mobile game is being developed by the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/tencent">Tencent</a>-owned Lightspeed Studio, which previously developed <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/playerunknowns-battlegrounds">PUBG</a> Mobile, hence being released in China first.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="FINAL FANTASY XIV MOBILE – Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n1vk2A--ZbY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>FINAL FANTASY XIV MOBILE – Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n1vk2A--ZbY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/n1vk2A--ZbY?autoplay=1" title="FINAL FANTASY XIV MOBILE – Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Final Fantasy 14 Mobile – Reveal Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n1vk2A--ZbY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>However, a global release is still expected, though its date is unknown. In the meantime, players worldwide are able to sign up for updates and news on future tests on the <a href="https://ffxivmobile.com/web202409/index.html#/">game's website</a>.</p>
<p>A livestream for the game provided fresh details, including its 16 gear dye layers that will allow players to customise the look of their Warrior of Light in great detail.</p>
<p>For comparison, the main Final Fantasy 14 added only its second dye layer with the latest expansion, Dawntrail.</p>
<p>Also shown, as per a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ffxiv/comments/1kqa1wx/xiv_mobile_live_letter_notes_16_dye_layers_dodge/">reddit thread</a>, were a new dodge button for all classes, as well as auto-pathing to quests and fates for ease of control - note there won't be auto-combat.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-14-mobile-officially-revealed">Final Fantasy 14 Mobile was officially revealed</a> by director and producer <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/naoki-yoshida">Naoki Yoshida</a> back in November last year. He confirmed the game will be free-to-play but won't include gacha mechanics.</p>
<p>A trailer at the time gave us our first proper look at gameplay, including a fully-realised version of Eorzea in the palm of your hand.</p>
<p>The game's release will follow the cancellation and shutdown of a number of mobile games from <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> in recent years.</p>
<p>Just last week, the company <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/kingdom-hearts-missing-link-cancelled-but-kingdom-hearts-4-still-on-the-way">cancelled development of mobile game Kingdom Hearts Missing-Link</a>, though confirmed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/first-look-at-kingdom-hearts-4-in-three-years-suggests-mickey-mouse-is-playable">Kingdom Hearts 4 is still on the way</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-sees-game-sales-drop-but-multiplatform-strategy-continues-in-earnest">Square Enix's latest financial reports showed a drop in sales of its games</a>, particularly with mobile games owing to multiple cancellations. However, sales and profits of its MMOs have increased thanks to Final Fantasy 14 expansion Dawntrail.</p>
<p>It makes business sense, then, to release a version of the MMORPG on mobile as part of its multiplatform strategy.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 major update promises victory for squidkind as the Illuminate finally invade hated Super Earth]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-major-update-promises-victory-for-squidkind-as-the-illuminate-finally-invade-hated-super-earth</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-major-update-promises-victory-for-squidkind-as-the-illuminate-finally-invade-hated-super-earth.1193787/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-major-update-promises-victory-for-squidkind-as-the-illuminate-finally-invade-hated-super-earth<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>PlayStation</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
After many months of dogged campaigning in the face of zealotry, atrocity and propaganda about fake WMDs, the heroic avatars of the Illuminate have finally invaded Super-Earth. In just a few short days, the humans and their fanatical and clownish "Helldiver" enforcers may be wiped from the face of the galaxy, ushering in a brave new era in which the surviving bots, bugs and squids link clamps, mandibles and tentacles and dance around singing. You ever hear an Illuminate sing? Literally mind-blowing.
</p>
<p>
All of which is to say that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a>'s Heart Of Democracy update is upon us, following <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2s-enemy-squids-are-headed-to-super-earth-so-now-you-can-tinker-with-your-guns-more">teasers earlier this month</a>. It lets the game's sordid playerbase of perfidious human stormtroopers blow the shit out of some ace nano-tech molluscs on the streets of planet Earth. The new Earth maps are also full of NPC human soldiers who can be left to fight for themselves or enlisted as cannon fodder. There are crowds of panicking civilians, too. The <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/05/20/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-live-brings-the-fight-to-the-streets-of-super-earth/">PlayStation blog post</a> announcing the update's release suggests that you'll be "punished" for accidentally shooting them, but that's not the impression given by the below orgiastic trailer.
</p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Helldivers 2 - Heart of Democracy | PS5 &amp; PC Games" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uwDx7-HTk0s?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Helldivers 2 - Heart of Democracy | PS5 &amp; PC Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uwDx7-HTk0s?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/uwDx7-HTk0s?autoplay=1" title="Helldivers 2 - Heart of Democracy | PS5 &amp; PC Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uwDx7-HTk0s" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
"Last week, we released a powerful primary weapon customization system and expanded surplus options to fight against the Illuminate as they emerged from the singularity," adds the PlayStation blog. "Now that you have learned the tactics of these new squid troops - like the Crescent Overseer and the hulking Fleshmob - you must master these tools to continue the fight on Super Earth. Use every available resource, divers, and decimate their forces!"
</p>
<p>
Those newly customisable primary weapons aren't the beefiest bullet-throwers you'll find on Super Earth's streets. There are planetary defence cannons that must be woken from their slumber and turned against the majestic Illuminate fleets, lest they succeed in bringing about a future in which the brutality and idiocy of the human race is just a bedtime story for wide-eyed space plankton.</p>
<p>Let the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers">Helldivers</a> enjoy turning their own cities into battlezones, I say. Let the strutting caped vermin relish the spectacle of their own ruination. As for us squid sympathisers in the shadows, let's all cross our tentacles and pray that the flag-fellating bipeds are unambiguously vanquished. Framing jokes aside, it would free Arrowhead up to work on their <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/playstation-are-great-says-arrowheads-ceo-but-whatever-the-helldivers-2-devs-are-making-next-its-fully-self-funded">unannounced new game</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SAG-AFTRA files unfair labour practice charge against Fortnite maker Epic, following AI-generated Darth Vader voice lines]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sag-aftra-files-unfair-labour-practice-charge-against-fortnite-maker-epic-following-ai-generated-darth-vader-voice-lines</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sag-aftra-files-unfair-labour-practice-charge-against-fortnite-maker-epic-following-ai-generated-darth-vader-voice-lines.1193772/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/sag-aftra-files-unfair-labour-practice-charge-against-fortnite-maker-epic-following-ai-generated-darth-vader-voice-lines<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>SAG-AFTRA has filed an unfair labour practice charge against <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> maker Epic, following its use of AI to recreate James Earl Jones' voice for Darth Vader.</p>
<p>Prior to his death, actor Jones - who along with Darth Vader also lent his vocal stylings to Disney's The Lion King as Mufasa - gave <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/hollywood/2022/09/darth-vaders-voice-emanated-from-war-torn-ukraine">permission for his voice to be replicated using AI</a>, and technology was used to generate Vader's voice in the Disney+ show Obi-Wan Kenobi. Jones' AI-powered voice as the Star Wars Sith Lord then cropped up again last week, this time in Fortnite, where players could chat with Darth Vader via Epic's online game.</p>
<p>The AI-generated voice used in Fortnite arrived with permission from Jones' family, who said they hoped the collaboration with Epic would "allow both longtime fans of Darth Vader and newer generations to share in the enjoyment of this iconic character". However, soon <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-now-lets-you-chat-with-darth-vader-using-generative-ai-speech">players began using the technology to get Darth to cuss</a>, resulting in Epic swiftly issuing a hotfix to stop this from happening.</p>
<p>Now, American actors' union SAG-AFTRA - which represents 160,000 American media professionals, including voiceover artists - has filed an unfair labour practice charge with the NLRB against Llama Productions, which is wholly owned by Epic Games. The union stated the company "chose to replace the work of human performers with AI technology… without providing any notice of their intent to do this and without bargaining with us over appropriate terms".</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sag-aftra-statement-fortnites-use-ai-darth-vader-voice-and-ulp-filing">statement shared last night</a>, SAG-AFTRA said it "[celebrates] the right of our members and their estates to control the use of their digital replicas", and that it welcomes " the use of new technologies to allow new generations to share in the enjoyment of those legacies and renowned roles".</p>
<p>However, the organisation believes it must still protect its "right to bargain terms and conditions around uses of voice that replace the work of our members". It noted this includes actors who have also worked to replicate "Darth Vader's iconic rhythm and tone in video games".</p>
<p>In its filing - <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sites/default/files/2025-05/Llama%20Productions%20ULP%20Charge.pdf">which you can read here</a> - SAG-AFTRA said Llama Productions via Epic "failed and refused to bargain in good faith with the union", and it did this by "making unilateral changes to terms and conditions of employment, without providing notice to the union or the opportunity to bargain, by utilising AI-generated voices to replace bargaining unit work" for Fortnite.</p>
<p>Eurogamer has reached out to Epic for comment on SAG-AFTRA's filing.</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Epic Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Actors from <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/us-video-game-performers-are-striking-over-ongoing-ai-concerns">SAG-AFTRA have been on strike since July</a>, as the union negotiates with various video game companies on the Interactive Media Agreement. AI has been one of the biggest sticking points of the strikes.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mass-effect">Mass Effect</a> voice actor <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/negotiations-over-ai-are-still-holding-up-video-game-development-mass-effects-jennifer-hale-explains-why">Jennifer Hale spoke to Eurogamer about why the strike remains ongoing</a>.</p>
<p>"It's a huge issue for all of us and the repercussions are vast," she said. "So to me, it makes sense that everyone needs to take their time. As performers - and we saw this in the writers strike and the theatrical contract strike - we're just the canary in the coal mine."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2: Heart of Democracy update sees Super Earth itself invaded]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-sees-super-earth-itself-invaded</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-sees-super-earth-itself-invaded.1193769/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-sees-super-earth-itself-invaded<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Arrowhead Game Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> has received a big new update, Heart of Democracy, that sees the fight move to the streets of Super Earth.</p>
<p>Until now, the game's battles against bugs and robots alike have taken place on alien planets. But now Super Earth itself has been invaded by the squid-like Illuminate, towering over skyscrapers and crowded city streets.</p>
<p>Players will need to activate the Planetary Defense Cannons on Super Earth alongside SEAF troops, but must simultaneously protect civilians on the streets - friendly fire will be punished.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Helldivers 2 - Heart of Democracy | PS5 &amp; PC Games" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uwDx7-HTk0s?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Helldivers 2 - Heart of Democracy | PS5 &amp; PC Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uwDx7-HTk0s?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/uwDx7-HTk0s?autoplay=1" title="Helldivers 2 - Heart of Democracy | PS5 &amp; PC Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Helldivers 2 - Heart of Democracy | PS5 &amp; PC Games<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uwDx7-HTk0s" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"The worst nightmare of all those who fight for Managed Democracy has been made a grim reality," reads a notice on the Helldivers 2 Discord.</p>
<p>"Despite the valiant efforts of our <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/helldivers">Helldivers</a> to push back the fleet, the Illuminate have reached Super Earth. Now they are swarming our cities, terrorizing citizens, and destroying our infrastructure. It's time to rise up and take arms and fight for the precious foundations and soil of Democracy manifest. Helldivers, return to our planet and defend what is rightfully ours."</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2s-illuminate-faction-unleashes-deadly-new-enemy-terrors-as-latest-update-lands">invasion was pre-empted last week with an update</a> that saw the Illuminate setting a course for Super Earth, with new enemies to fight.</p>
<p>The update also added weapon customisation, which allows new attachments to be unlocked as weapons level up.</p>
<p>"Last week, we released a powerful primary weapon customisation system and expanded surplus options to fight against the Illuminate as they emerged from the singularity," reads a <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/05/20/helldivers-2-heart-of-democracy-update-live-brings-the-fight-to-the-streets-of-super-earth/">PlayStation Blog post</a> about the update. "Now that you have learned the tactics of these new squid troops - like the Crescent Overseer and the hulking Fleshmob - you must master these tools to continue the fight on Super Earth. Use every available resource, divers, and decimate their forces!"</p>
<p>On <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/553850/charts/#6m">Steam</a> at least, these latest updates have seen player numbers rise to their highest since December 2024, when the Omens of Tyranny update was released.</p>
<p>Back in January, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-creative-director-takes-sabbatical-promises-to-start-arrowheads-next-game-on-return">Helldivers 2 creative director Johan Pilestedt said he would be taking a sabbatical</a> and will begin development of Arrowhead's next game on his return.</p>
<p>Then, at the Game Developer Conference, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-boss-says-industry-doomed-to-unnecessarily-brutal-layoffs-while-chasing-after-the-battle-royales">he discussed the state of the industry</a>, calling industry layoffs "unnecessarily brutal" while "chasing after the battle royales".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anno 117: Pax Romana Gets First Gameplay Showcase]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/anno-117-pax-romana-gets-first-gameplay-showcase/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anno-117-pax-romana-gets-first-gameplay-showcase.1193763/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/anno-117-pax-romana-gets-first-gameplay-showcase/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Nearly a year after <a href="https://wccftech.com/anno-117-pax-romana-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the game's announcement</a>, Ubisoft Mainz has released the first gameplay showcase for Anno 117: Pax Romana. The video is accompanied by a narrating voice that describes the player's journey throughout the upcoming real-time strategy/city-building game:</p>
<p><em>Latium is where your journey begins, young governor. First, lay down roads to keep your people connected. Organic layouts add charm, while efficient grids boost productivity. Start with dirt roads. They may be humble, but they're the first step on the path to greatness.</em></p>
<p><em>Resources are your lifeblood. Wood from the untouched forests will be essential, but manage your lumber camps wisely to maintain a sustainable supply. And remember, efficient logistics are key.</em><br>
<em>Warehouses will keep goods flowing and production smooth.</em></p>
<p><em>Your residents need more than just work. They need homes. Build neighborhoods that suit your city's vision. Markets drive income and population growth, while taverns keep spirits high.</em><br>
<em>And mind the fire hazards, especially the bakeries. Fires are practically a Roman tradition.</em><br>
<em>Just be mindful of your city's layout. </em></p>
<p><em>Residents will love lavender's sweet scent, but they won't be so fond of the pig farm's stench. Balance charm and profit wisely. An Anno 117: Pax Romana governor must also live among the people. Establish your own villa as a sign of stability and leadership. Meet your people's needs</em><br>
<em>and they'll advance, unlocking new industries and opportunities.</em></p>
<p><em>A resilient economy is vital. Stockpile resources and prepare for challenges, as not every island will yield the goods you desire. Trade is key to securing essential items, but keep an eye on rival governors. Not all share your vision of cooperation. Diplomacy may seem wise, but some rivals favor force. Protect your trade routes with armed escorts and fortified ports. And beware of pirates. A well-defended harbor keeps your goods safe from thieving hands.</em></p>
<p><em>As your city in Anno 117: Pax Romana prospers, your people's desires grow. Fine goods, entertainment, and culture become their demands. Libraries and grammaticus schools pave the way for technological advancements. Public service buildings like bathhouses boost health, while theaters keep happiness high. Grand monuments, like the Colosseum, bring prestige and secure the emperor's favor. Never underestimate the power of reputation. After all, it's the key to lasting legacy.</em></p>
<p><em>Faith unites your people and strengthens your leadership. Each island may dedicate itself</em><br>
<em>to a single deity, but shrines for other gods are welcome. Believing in Neptune grants faster ships</em><br>
<em>and bountiful sea production, while believing in Mars empowers your soldiers and bolsters your army's morale. Choose your patron god wisely, as faith will shape your province's destiny.</em></p>
<p><em>Expand through diplomacy or force. The choice is yours. Trade and alliances can build</em><br>
<em>a sprawling network, but conquest secures your rule. Aqueducts fuel growth while fortresses guard your borders. Prepare your military to defend your ambitions. Whether close combat or long-range firepower, your strategy will determine your legacy.</em></p>
<p><em>Your rule may extend to lands beyond the empire, like Albion, where Celts resist Roman influence. It's a wild place. Will you protect Celtic traditions or remain loyal to Roman ambition? Your choices will determine your fate: a prosperous metropolis, or a city in bankruptcy?</em></p>
<p><iframe title="Anno 117: Pax Romana - Gameplay Showcase Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GBXNl88yeW4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It's been six years since the previous franchise installment, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/anno-1800-review/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Anno 1800</a>. This time, players are going to the earliest historical setting of any Anno game thus far, dating back to the Pax Romana, a time when peace reigned and the economy thrived in the Roman Empire. The developers have claimed that the new game will retain the series' trademark complexity while making things easier for newcomers.</p>
<p>Anno 117: Pax Romana will debut later this year on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Voice actor union strikes back after Fortnite debuts controversial AI-powered Darth Vader]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/voice-actor-union-hits-back-after-fortnite-debuts-controversial-ai-powered-darth-vader</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/voice-actor-union-strikes-back-after-fortnite-debuts-controversial-ai-powered-darth-vader.1193757/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/voice-actor-union-hits-back-after-fortnite-debuts-controversial-ai-powered-darth-vader<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Voice performer union SAG-AFTRA has filed an unfair labor practice charge against Epic Games subsidiary Llama Productions for deploying a controversial AI-powered Darth Vader chatbot in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fortnite</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The AI-powered version of the iconic villain arrived in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fortnite</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> last week. It imitated the performance of deceased Darth Vader voice actor James Earl Jones (with permission from his estate) by leaning on two conversational AI models in the form of Google Gemini 2.0 Flash and ElevenLabs Flash v2.5.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Epic described the feature as "experimental" in a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/this-will-be-a-day-long-remembered-speak-with-darth-vader-in-fortnite?lang=en-US">blog post</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> but still implored players to speak with the character. Naturally, they obliged, and soon had Darth Vader dishing out all manner of statements ranging from bizarre to downright offensive (including slurs). Epic recognized the issue and quickly deployed a hotfix (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/ethangach.bsky.social/post/3lpcdjp773c2y">thanks Kotaku</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">), but not before clips of the AI character's vocal misdemeanours had flooded social media.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Now, the company has also caught the attention of SAG-AFTRA, which is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/sag-aftra-authorizes-video-game-actor-strike-over-ai">currently striking against major game studios</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to secure better AI protections for its union members.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sag-aftra-statement-fortnites-use-ai-darth-vader-voice-and-ulp-filing">In a statement</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, SAG-AFTRA acknowledged the rights of its members and estates to control the use of their digital replicas, but said it must also "protect our right to bargain terms and conditions around uses of voice that replace the work of our members."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/trump-administration-cuts-funding-for-the-strong-museum-of-play" target="_self" data-discover="true">Trump administration cuts funding for the Strong Museum of Play</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That, it noted, includes those performers who previously helped bring Darth Vader to life in video games.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="SAG-AFTRA accuses Fortnite maker Epic of replacing human performers with AI technology">SAG-AFTRA accuses Fortnite maker Epic of replacing human performers with AI technology</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">SAG-AFTRA claimed that opportunity has now been taken away by Llama Productions, which it said chose to "replace the work of human performers with AI technology."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Unfortunately, [Llama] did so without providing any notice of their intent to do this and without bargaining with us over appropriate terms. As such, we have filed an unfair labor practice charge with the NLRB against Llama Productions," continued SAG-AFTRA.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The full unfair labor practice charge </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sites/default/files/2025-05/Llama%20Productions%20ULP%20Charge.pdf">can be read here</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and states that Llama "failed and refused to bargain in good faith with the union by making unilateral changes to terms and conditions of employment, without providing notice to the union or the opportunity to bargain, by utilizing AI-generated voices to replace bargaining unit work on the Interactive Program Fortnite."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In short: SAG-AFTRA feels Llama and parent company Epic refused to open a constructive dialogue before deploying an AI-generated character that might have instead been voiced by a human actor.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/former-playstation-boss-says-stupid-money-crippled-the-game-industry" target="_self" data-discover="true">Former PlayStation boss says 'stupid money' crippled the game industry</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">SAG-AFTRA </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sag-aftra-publicly-releases-its-proposed-ai-terms-to-end-strike">recently detailed</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> the AI protections it is seeking in order to ratify a new Interactive Media Agreement with a bargaining group containing studios like Take 2 Productions, EA, Activision, and WB Games. Prior the that, the union suggested there were "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/sag-aftra-strike-to-continue-due-to-alarming-loopholes-in-ai-proposals-from-major-game-studios">alarming loopholes</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" in the AI proposals being tabled by those studios.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Horror at Highrook Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/20/the-horror-at-highrook-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-horror-at-highrook-review.1193751/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/20/the-horror-at-highrook-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/20/the-horror-at-highrook-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="The Horror at Highrook Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Steve C">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2025-05-20">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2025-05-20">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>I love the idea of board games, but the reality of the time, space, and effort required to set them up and get enough people together, let alone learning the arcane rulesets means that anything outside of a card game or a nostalgic game of Scrabble or Cluedo (never Monopoly, though) is rarely an option for me. That being the case, I’m always happy to see digital versions that alleviate most of those concerns, where even the rules are more easily learned through in-game tutorials. y latest foray in this genre feels like a mix of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2018/06/01/cultist-simulator-review/">Cultist Simulator</a> and Cluedo, with a static mansion game board and cards being used to carry out your actions. The end result is a fantastic tactical experience that enthrals throughout.</p>
<p><iframe title="The Horror At Highrook - Release Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/drjG1Pj8HGE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You start out by meeting your group of investigators as they arrive at Highrook Mansion in order to solve the mystery of what happened to the family that lived there. All you know at first is that they have disappeared under suspicious circumstances and that there may be eldritch forces at work. To begin with only a few areas of the mansion are available with others being unlocked as you progress through the chapters. This works really well at preventing the overwhelming effect of multiple systems and lets you learn the different actions as they are unlocked. Rather than a linear completion, all the rooms continue to be useful until the end of the game so the systems build on one another.</p>


<p>Everything is clear and easy to understand with zooming in and out and panning around the board feeling intuitive. I mostly played on my desktop PC, but spent a little time on Steam Deck and the accessibility was good here too, albeit with more zooming needed when reading the cards and descriptions. The developer explains that they could not afford voice acting – which is a much better option than using the terrible AI voices that haunt low budget games – so there is a lot of reading required here. That may be a deal breaker for some, but it is definitely worth the effort as the writing is excellent.</p>


<p>Each of your team has different skills and abilities which make them more effective in different parts of the map. Atticus the Hunter has brawn on his side but can also be useful in scouting areas and serves as your main source of items. Astor the Mechanist is most often used in the machine room to investigate items and packages, whilst Vitali is as scholar and can be found in the library and archives. After a few turns you also meet Dr Caligar who comes into her own in the lab. Aside from their primary functions, all characters have secondary skills that mean that they can be used in combination when multiple leads need to be investigated.</p>
<p>The general gameplay mechanic involves using a character and an action card in a specific room to carry out a range of investigations. Upgrades and bonus cards can help in performing more complex tasks and so you need to find the raw materials to develop these as you progress. In practice, this means that there is usually the need to have most of your characters working simultaneously and as you get more experienced you’ll be multitasking like a pro.</p>

<p>As the mansion opens up you’ll begin to face the threat of horrific spectres and creatures, but all the way through you’ll need to manage hunger, fatigue, wounds, and madness stats. I’ll freely admit that I turned these options down to the lowest difficulty setting as that kind of survival mechanic isn’t my cup of tea and I definitely appreciate the fact that you can adjust these to suit your play style. Even on easy you’ll need to make sure that you’re making food and healing items whilst sleeping is vital to continue the plot as many hints are revealed to you through dreams and visions.</p>
<p>My only real gripe is that it can be easy to feel like you’ve reached a dead end if you stop playing for a couple of days as remembering how to develop the various booster cards is essential for end game investigations. I’d recommend taking notes as you go for that.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		The Horror at Highbrook is one of the best tabletop-style games I’ve played. The card-based mechanics are complex but introduced in a way that doesn’t leave you feeling overwhelmed, while the writing is top-notch and the atmosphere develops perfectly. Whether you’re a fan of board games, horror writing or just after an excellent written Lovecraftian mystery then this is an easy recommendation.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Complex systems</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Excellent onboarding</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Very well written and atmospheric</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Survival mechanics can be annoying</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Easy to get stuck if you’re not paying attention</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open your hands so I may plop in a nice frog game inspired by Doom and Resident Evil]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/open-your-hands-so-i-may-plop-in-a-nice-frog-game-inspired-by-doom-and-resident-evil</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/open-your-hands-so-i-may-plop-in-a-nice-frog-game-inspired-by-doom-and-resident-evil.1193748/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/open-your-hands-so-i-may-plop-in-a-nice-frog-game-inspired-by-doom-and-resident-evil<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>I'll stop writing about frog games when you stop putting frogs in them</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Elliott Dahle</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>"What if Resident Evil and Frogger had a boomer shooter baby?," teases the trailer blurb for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">FPS</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/frog-legs">Frog Legs</a>. Stop, stop. You had me at Frog. Then you had me again when I saw the frog using a super shotgun, and then once again when they used a BFG. Then, inconceivably, you had me twice more reading the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1734110/Frog_Legs/">Steam page</a>. Once when I learned the game was about 40 minutes long, and then again when I noticed it costs two quid. Trailer? Yes. I already said there was. Please, keep up.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Frog Legs Launch Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/63vAskgkO3Y?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Frog Legs Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/63vAskgkO3Y?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/63vAskgkO3Y?autoplay=1" title="Frog Legs Launch Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=63vAskgkO3Y" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"I think they could have done more with the ribbit and tear pun," said Edwin, preventing me from using any other puns - the game had already been won. Then he told me that it wasn't his pun, it was in the press release. Too late, Edwin. I'd already assumed you were trying to pass it off as your own, and I will now never not imagine your RPS Slack posts being typed atop a throne of lies, into a keyboard made of deception, with biomechanical fingers forged from the melted slag of robotronic autobastards. Features ahoy:</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li>Can be completed in a single sitting (30-40min)</li>
<li>Story-driven experience with a little horror, some action, and plenty of humor!</li>
<li>2D Arcade gameplay reminiscent of the classics</li>
<li>3D First-Person puzzles</li>
<li>Retro Boomer Shooter FPS action with a shotgun and BFG (Big Froggin' Gun)!</li>
<li>(Note: This is not a full boomer shooter / FPS game. That is only part of the game.)</li>
<li>An ensemble of characters you'll never frog-get!</li>
<li>Auto-save on each new level for convenience</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>Why are frogs so good? Like orcs, they emanate green idiocy. Unlike orcs, it's a benign green idiocy. You could have a cuppa with a frog. You could play squash. You could sing a fireside ballad. I'm not sure if Frog Legs contains these things. But, again: shotgun. It's by Elliot Dahle, whose other works you can find on <a href="https://elliottdahle.itch.io/">Itch here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Half-Life Writer Marc Laidlaw Never Expected His 40-Year-Old Cyberpunk Story Would Be Turned Into a Love, Death and Robots Episode for Netflix]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/half-life-writer-marc-laidlaw-never-expected-his-40-year-old-cyberpunk-story-would-be-turned-into-a-love-death-and-robots-episode-for-netflix</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/half-life-writer-marc-laidlaw-never-expected-his-40-year-old-cyberpunk-story-would-be-turned-into-a-love-death-and-robots-episode-for-netflix.1193739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/half-life-writer-marc-laidlaw-never-expected-his-40-year-old-cyberpunk-story-would-be-turned-into-a-love-death-and-robots-episode-for-netflix<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Marc Laidlaw wrote 400 Boys in 1981 aged 21, long before he ended up Valve’s lead writer and one of the chief creators of the Half-Life games. The short story was published in Omni magazine in 1983, before it was picked up for Mirrorshades: The Cyberpunk Anthology and enjoyed a wider audience. <a href="https://www.marclaidlaw.com/online-fiction/400-boys/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On Marc’s website</a>, at the bottom of the short story itself, he points out 400 Boys has probably been read by more people than anything else he’s written, except perhaps Dota 2 seasonal ad copy. Yes, the video game world knows Marc Laidlaw as the lead writer of the Half-Life series. But he’s done a lot more than video games. It’s funny how things work out.</p><blockquote>In a post-apocalyptic city where warring gangs follow a bushido-like code of honor, a new gang, the 400 Boys, forces them to unite. A blend of beauty and brutality from Canadian director Robert Valley, whose LDR episode “Ice” won the Emmy for Outstanding Short Form Animation.</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">“The inspiration for it just came out of walking around,” Marc remembers. “I lived in Eugene, Oregon and there was always the phone poles with the names of bands that were playing in town, and it was just name after name of super cool bands, and I just wanted a way to do that. I just wanted to make up lots of band names. So I came up with the idea of, if I have all these gangs in the story, I can come up with names for all these different gangs and that would be fun. And it was funny. That was kind of the thing that drove a big part of the story, just wanting to make band names.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/20/marc-laidlaw-1747728952628.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Marc Laidlaw is done with Half-Life, but not, it seems, the internet. Photo credit: Mimi Raver.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, over 40 years after 400 Boys was first published, it’s an episode of the fourth season of Netflix’s hugely popular animated anthology series <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tv/love-death-and-robots">Love, Death and Robots</a>. The episode was directed by Robert Valley, the director of Zima Blue in Season 1 and Ice in Season 2. Tim Miller wrote it. The voice cast includes John Boyega, who famously played Finn in Star Wars. All of a sudden, 400 Boys is having its big moment. Marc Laidlaw never expected this.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The story kind of faded out, but cyberpunk kept going and I didn't really think about it that much,” Laidlaw tells me over a video call just days before Season 4 of Love, Death and Robots kicks off on Netflix.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">40 years. That’s a long time for anything to be turned into something, isn’t it? But it might have happened earlier, around 15 years ago, when Tim Miller from Blur (the company that does all those fancy video game cutscenes and, these days, so much more), got in touch about maybe turning 400 Boys into something. It didn’t happen. Like so many projects, it fell apart following studio changes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Then Love, Death and Robots exploded onto the scene in March 2019. This edgy, adult-oriented animated anthology was unlike anything we’d seen on the streamer. Some episodes were challenging, some were weird, some were weirdly challenging. Whatever they were, you couldn’t help but watch. And, Marc noticed, Tim Miller from Blur was involved. “I always say, I can't imagine anybody else who would've turned The Drowned Giant, this J. G. Ballard story, into an episode of an animated feature,” Marc says. “So I had a lot of respect for Tim just from that.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/19/400-boys-1747656689255.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">400 Boys is now an episode of Love, Death and Robots on Netflix. Image credit: Netflix.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Marc moved to Los Angeles in 2020 and, as the pandemic eased, met Tim a few times at various events around town. He didn’t want to push 400 Boys, but maybe, <em>just maybe</em>, if this Love, Death and Robots thing kept on going, maybe it would come back around. Then, a year ago, Marc got the ‘would you be interested in us optioning 400 Boys?’ email. It was finally happening.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marc spoke with Tim, who took over the script, about the story itself. He says the episode is faithful to the source, but there’s some new stuff that helps sell the story visually. He had a couple conversations with Robert Valley, the director. He pointed him to the 400 Boys audiobook, which Marc narrated (“I did a reading of this back in the pandemic when everybody was trying to entertain people by posting audio books of their fiction and stuff on YouTube”).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But really, Marc wasn’t that involved. “It just was fun to sit back and not have to be involved in the trenches on something for once,” he says. “And I just kind of wanted to enjoy it when it was done and see what they made of it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And Marc has seen the episode, as you’d expect. “John Boyega and the characters and the accents and the setting is just so cool to me. I mean, they made the story just so much more fun visually, I think.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">400 Boys is, as Marc describes it, from “a different me from lifetimes ago.” Of course it is, he wrote it over 40 years ago when he was a young man. “I'm still pretty happy with it considering how young I was when I wrote it.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“And then there was a long time of not much happening,” he says. And then, as we all know, Marc got into the games industry in 1997, into Valve as it was making Half-Life. “And that whole thing happened…”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Laidlaw “retired” from Valve in 2016, but it came across as a hard retirement from everything. In truth, he’s in a comfortable enough position to be able to do what he wants, pick his own projects and share them when they're done. “I think I retired too hard,” he admits. He never wanted to stop being creative. He wanted to get back to writing, but the publishing industry sort of disappeared while he was working on video games. Forget new video games, too. “I can't do games without a bunch of people. I can't make a game myself.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So Marc makes music now. He got a boost in audience after Valve’s Half-Life 2 anniversary documentary came out last year and he released a lost development video from the early days on his YouTube channel. “I'm like, I'm in the wrong business!” Marc jokes. “I should just be leaking information about my old employer.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Did it feel weird looking back at Half-Life all these years later for the Valve documentary, I wonder? </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Yeah, it was good for me to just kind of process and put a bow on that stuff, see a bunch of old friends, think about that, the whole thing,” Marc says.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I hadn't talked to or seen a lot of those people for a long time. I still stay in touch with a few folks, but they're also not really there anymore. I don't know what's going on there right now, but it was fun to hang out with people and talk it over and it was therapeutic.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With Half-Life and Half-Life 2 anniversary documentaries done and dusted, the only Valve game Marc might be asked to reminisce over now is Dota 2, which, ominously, is 12 years old. Perhaps in eight years Valve will come calling. “I could speak to Dota. That's the only thing left.” Unless, of course, Valve fancies doing something on Alien Swarm (“I did a little bit on Alien Swarm”).</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It is impossible, I find, to talk to Marc Laidlaw without talking about Half-Life. With those Valve documentaries out in the wild, there isn’t much left to say about the past. But maybe (hopefully?!) Half-Life has a future, and it’s that thread I want to pull on.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There is no point asking Marc if he knows whether Half-Life 3 is in the works. As he says, he doesn’t really know the people still left at Valve, but even if he did, he’s not about to announce the game here in our interview. Can you imagine the email Gaben would send if he did?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It is a better use of our time, I think, to ask Marc if he’d ever write for a video game again. Marc says he is, generally, still open to writing for a video game, and suggests Hideo Kojima should perhaps have given him a call. “When Death Stranding came out, I just was grinding my teeth. Like, does he know I'm available? I'd be happy to help do the last polish of dialogue on your script and not wreck anything, but just make it lines that actors would sound better coming out of their mouth.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marc, as he alluded to earlier, “retired really hard,” and he thinks that because of that, the industry doesn’t think to ask him to do anything. “When I see the Miyazaki stuff, the From studio stuff, of course you go to George R. R. Martin first if you could. Nobody needs my name on their project to sell copies. But I mean, that kind of thing to me is exciting.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The lack of interesting offers post-Valve came as something of a surprise, Marc says. “I did kind of expect more interesting offers of stuff to do afterward and was kind of like, ‘this is weird: somebody wants me to write their synopsis for their mobile phone laser tag game.' It's like, they don't know what I do.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Wait, really? Someone actually asked Marc Laidlaw to write a mobile phone laser tag game after he left Valve? “Those are the kind of things I would get,” Marc admits. “I'm like, ‘I don't know that I have much to offer you guys, but I mean, I don't really like to say no to stuff.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Marc continues: “I haven't really heard any interesting game offers that seemed right for me. People think of me as, you can come in and write a bunch of stuff for a game. I'm like, 'do you notice how little writing there was in Half-Life?' Sort of the point of it was I hated reading in games.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And then the inevitable interview-closer: if Valve gave Marc Laidlaw a call and said, ‘we want to get the band back together for Half-Life 3,’ would he answer that call?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I would not do that,” he replies, matter of factly. “I can definitely say I would not do that. Even when I was there, I started to feel like, ‘Oh, now I'm the old guy shooting stuff down.’ I think at some point you need to let the people who are the fans and the creators who've come in because of what they learned from you maybe, and let them have that. We need new stuff. We didn't need me going, ‘Well, the G-Man wouldn't do that in my day.’ And I found I had to restrain myself. People would get enthusiastic about stuff, and I felt like it was becoming a negative force on some of the creative process.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I haven't played the VR Half-Life: Alyx, so I don't really feel like I can. I don't know what's going on with anything. And it is not really my place. God knows what it's doing in terms of creative process of how to get a great experience that will surprise people. And you have to be right at the edge of what you can do in a moment. And I'm not on that edge anymore. That's not what's interesting to me at this point. So I don't think I'd be good.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Plus, I'm one of the older guys, maybe not the oldest, but it's so much work. I mean, I don't think I could do that anymore. I get into my own things, but it's not on anyone else's schedule. And yeah, I'm pretty much done. I mean, maybe not done with games altogether, but definitely the Half-Life part of my life is way behind me.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, that’s that. Half-Life is done with Marc Laidlaw, and Marc Laidlaw is done with Half-Life. But there’s a lot more he’s done in the past that’s relevant now. Just look at Netflix making 400 Boys, 40 years later. Maybe, at some point in the future, Netflix will knock on Valve’s door and ask to turn Half-Life into something. Then Marc Laidlaw can go through all this all over again.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“The fact that I got into the cyberpunk thing before it was called cyberpunk, and then I came across this sort of beginning game company that ended up making Half-Life… I've been lucky to be a part of these things that just kind of become phenomena.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deliver At All Costs Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/deliver-at-all-costs-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/deliver-at-all-costs-review.1193736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/deliver-at-all-costs-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">As far as package-shipping simulators go, Deliver At All Costs more closely resembles drunk driving than it does <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/death-stranding">Death Stranding</a>. There's no need for complicated weight management or careful navigation through its 1950s small-town USA setting; instead, this kooky courier quest loads your pickup truck with increasingly quirky cargo and sends you careening through road signs, fences, shopfronts, and countless pedestrians, with almost every dispatched delivery quickly devolving into a full-on destruction derby. It’s a riotously good time for a while, but it soon starts to sputter out and eventually breaks down well before it reaches the end of its 10-hour journey when its nonsensical sci-fi story fails to pay off and this world turns out to be far more rewarding to reduce to rubble than it is to actually explore.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There is a plot connecting all of its street-shredding shipments, but honestly the less said about it, the better. You’re Winston Green, a likeable fresh hire at the We Deliver corporation who’s seemingly on the run after a mysterious incident in his past. Though it begins as a sort of goofy workplace comedy it soon makes jarring tonal shifts into corporate crime conspiracies and eventually a preposterous tale of time travel, before crashlanding into a fast-tracked climax that left me feeling about as hollow as someone who’s tried to make a meal out of packing peanuts. Deliver At All Costs’ story is a bit like a box of flatpacked furniture delivered from IKEA; it’s full of interesting parts to pore over, but once you’ve put it all together it seems noticeably wonkier than you expected and it’s clear that there’s more than a couple of screws loose.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Deliver At All Costs Review Screens</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The real star is the staggering destructibility of its world, which is viewed from your choice of two top-down angles. Pretty much everything above ground can be satisfyingly smashed asunder as you tear around in your delivery truck turning every apartment block into a potential Jenga tower. There’s admittedly an overly fragile and weightless feel to it all – it’s a bit like crashing through houses made of cards rather than bricks and mortar because you rarely feel the impact or lose momentum – but punching my own shortcuts through everything from hotel lobbies to tennis courts and tombstone-covered graveyards kept me consistently amused for at least the first half of the drive. I gleefully sped around chewing through scenery like I was Nicholas Cage in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/faceoff-1997">Face/Off</a>. Pretty much the only time I pumped the brakes was when I had to keep something from spilling out of my truckbed, or whenever I hit one of the abrupt loading screens that separates each district of the three cities that make up its decently sized open-world map. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Can’t Hardly Freight</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Deliver At All Costs’ 20-mission-long chain of violent cargo hauls aren’t so much door-to-door as they are wall-through-wall, but that’s not to say I didn’t face some resistance along the way. Different challenges are introduced in keeping with the object that’s dumped into the back of your truck or dragged behind you with a winch, and a few entertainingly wacky work orders had me laughing out loud. In one mission reminiscent of Pixar’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/up">Up</a>, I was hired to transport a bouquet of helium balloons, which meant that even the smallest bump in the road launched me into a clumsy aerial drift that left me struggling to stay on terra firma like a mailman on the moon’s surface. In another, I had to steer around a leaking tank of napalm that was igniting a growing wall of fire behind me, turning a simple pick-up and drop-off into a citywide game of Snake that blew me to smithereens if I attempted to double back on my delivery route.Then there was the time I had to drag a new statue of the local mayor towards the town square without it getting bombed by the swooping seagulls dropping their own special deliveries. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I gleefully sped around chewing through scenery like I was Nicholas Cage in Face/Off.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Unfortunately, though, there are almost as many duds in the mix as there are standouts. Being asked to drive recklessly to scare a limousine full of crooked executives doesn’t really come as a break from the norm when you’ve been otherwise hurtling around like a madman during each and every other job, for example. A mission to photograph a series of cows being abducted by a UFO can be passed simply by mindlessly spamming the camera button. Meanwhile, the on-foot retrieval of your stolen truck from under the nose of a patrolling security van becomes less of a daring infiltration into a scrapyard and more of a walk in the park because Deliver At All Costs’ stealth system is non-existent, to the point where you can just stroll in there unopposed with minimal thought or effort. That’s not to say the rest of the on-foot action is much better – pretty much whenever you’re forced to leave your car for more than a moment it becomes a dull stretch of basic platforming where your only actions are walk, jump, climb, and shove. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Haul or Nothing</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Elsewhere in Deliver At All Costs there’s rarely any substantial consequences for your actions, and that makes it start to get dull sooner than it seems like it should. If you accidentally flip your car over it will automatically right itself. If you bust a tyre you can hop out and instantly repair it with the tap of a button. If you bring down an entire building because you’re doing doughnuts through all four corners of its foundations you will almost certainly draw the attention of the police (who, the intro movie explains, are all but non-existent in this island town), but you can instantly lose that heat by leaving your truck and diving into a dumpster – even without necessarily breaking the line of sight. In fact, even if you’re caught, you just instantly respawn with no punishment served anyway. On the one hand, the general lack of rules or repercussions gave me the freedom to drive as recklessly as I wanted to, but it also meant that almost everything felt noticeably low in stakes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sometimes, in fact, Deliver At All Costs is so forgiving that it completely sucks any tension out of the task at hand. Steering your delivery truck from one side of the city to the other with an armed atom bomb couched in its cargo bed shouldn’t just have you flirting with danger, but buying danger a drink, beckoning danger onto the dance floor, and giving danger an open-mouthed kiss. But in practice, it’s surprisingly lacking in intensity: there’s no ticking clock to pressure you into keeping your foot clamped down on the accelerator, allowing you to take things as slow and steady as you like. That means the only challenge here is to <em>not</em> drive like a maniac. Even when I did accidentally bump into a car and blow myself to bits, generous checkpoints meant that I was back on the road with my unstable payload with minimum penalty to my progress. I don’t want a game to be overly punishing, but there’s a happy medium to be struck that this one never manages to nail.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Sometimes Deliver At All Costs is so forgiving that it completely sucks any tension out of the task at hand. </p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Elsewhere, and despite the consistently impressive amount of environmental detail to be found throughout its toy town world from Christmas tree-lined main streets to a giant drive-in theater projecting black and white films, there’s not a great deal of interesting activities to amuse yourself with when you’re off the clock. There are a further 10 side missions to be found dotted around the map, but few of them are particularly memorable. There’s a basic circuit race to place first in and a couple of missing persons to track down, but there’s little here to match the more creative courier tasks found in the main story path. Well, there’s one enjoyable exception that had me piloting a satanic sports car straight out of Stephen King’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/christine">Christine</a>. Deliver At All Costs could’ve used a lot more like her to make its map call me back for more.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There are other unique vehicles to track down too, but these are uniformly disappointing on a number of counts. For one, their locations are clearly marked on the map from the outset, so you’re not provided with the same thrill of discovery of, say, a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/forza-horizon-5">Forza Horizon</a> barn find. You also don’t have a garage to store them in, and nor can you use them for a delivery mission, so they’re mainly there for a brief joyride before being ditched in favour of a return to your trusty We Deliver truck. Worse still, they don’t provide any real point of difference to make them even remotely worth the minimal effort to uncover – they each handle more or less the same, and there are no unique emergency missions to undertake in the ambulance or dessert drops in the ice cream van to trigger like you might find in a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v">Grand Theft Auto</a> game. They’re just sort of… there.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another underwhelming factor is the upgrades you can weld onto your truck using spare parts found throughout the world (as ridiculous as it may be to open a giant chest to find someone has stashed a single roll of duct tape in it). They seem like they should open up new possibilities for mayhem and creativity in a world that’s as eager to be knocked down as this, but these, too, are disappointingly limited in their use. The crane is handy for the job that sees you load a giant marlin onto your truck and then literally fishtail your way to a drop-off point, but both it and the winch you get access to afterwards can’t actually be used outside of a mission to mess with objects at will. You can’t, say, attach the winch’s tow cable to a random car or pedestrian and drag them around town just for kicks like you can in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/saints-row">Saints Row</a> or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/just-cause">Just Cause</a>. You can supercharge your car horn to blast the windows out of shopfronts, but you can't use the cargo bed catapult at all outside of a handful of specific story moments. There’s a lot of potential for Deliver At All Costs to achieve the same sort of freeform fun that we see in games like <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/goat-simulator">Goat Simulator</a>, but it just doesn’t give you enough flexibility to really revel in it after you’ve grown tired of blasting into people’s living rooms like a Kool-Aid Man on wheels.
</p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="title3">Tristan's Favourite Destruction Games</h3><p>Break @#$% like you're Fred Durst!</p></div></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">In its best moments, Deliver At All Costs is as entertaining as it is uneven. For every truly creative cargo haul twist there’s another that’s uninspired or lacking in intensity and urgency, and although there’s certainly fun to be had crashing through its many structures like a bully through a sand castle, the novelty wears off long before it ends and all you’re left with is an impressively realised 1950s world with depressingly little else to do in it. Throw in a silly, slapdash story and some toys for your truck you’re largely forbidden from playing with, and Deliver At All Costs is one shipment that’s far from the complete package.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 GameChat Supports Live Subtitles and Text to Speech]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-gamechat-supports-live-subtitles-and-text-to-speech/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-gamechat-supports-live-subtitles-and-text-to-speech.1193727/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-gamechat-supports-live-subtitles-and-text-to-speech/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>One of the more surprising Nintendo Switch 2 features added to the new console is undoubtedly GameChat. Historically, Nintendo never put a lot of its focus on online communication between players, but this feature is looking to change that in a major way, allowing users to chat, share screens, and even share video (with the dedicated camera, purchased separately from the console).</p>
<p>Interestingly, the Nintendo Switch 2 GameChat was designed partly as a consequence of the COVID-19 pandemic, as confirmed by console producer Kouichi Kawamoto <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/whatsnew/ask-the-developer-vol-16-nintendo-switch-2-part-3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in an official developer interview</a>:</p>
<p><em>Back then, we were using a video conferencing system to check the software we were developing with our team, but the screen-sharing function built into the video conferencing system only allowed us to share one gameplay screen at a time. So, we had each person place their game screen in front of their camera instead of their faces. When we did that, it felt like we were all in the same place, each bringing our own console to play the game together, which was a lot of fun. Based on this experience, we proposed adding a feature to the Nintendo Switch 2 where people can share their gameplay screen with other players.</em></p>
<p>Now, we've learned that GameChat will also support live subtitles (it will transcribe what everyone is saying) and text-to-speech, which is great news as those are excellent accessibility options to have. You can check out those features in action below.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:tf7tjgkrqwai2kbxpx2dbr6k/app.bsky.feed.post/3lpevyywrvw2p" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreib7bn352szlugn7q2nbxwjjulaqbfgt7smjji4hew4jnohedcsace">
<p>[Switch 2]GameChat supports live subtitles. The system can transcribe what everyone is saying and display it in a "chat box" on screen.</p>
<p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:tf7tjgkrqwai2kbxpx2dbr6k?ref_src=embed">OatmealDome (@oatmealdome.bsky.social)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:tf7tjgkrqwai2kbxpx2dbr6k/post/3lpevyywrvw2p?ref_src=embed">2025-05-17T16:00:03.0380394Z</a></p></blockquote>

<blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:tf7tjgkrqwai2kbxpx2dbr6k/app.bsky.feed.post/3lpcewgnfao2p" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreignwyqhudwmbr3ewbq243tielmm5zchod4tphjbqvjmlpq6ynq4qq">
<p>[Switch 2]GameChat supports text-to-speech. If enabled, you can type in text and the system will read it for you.While not explicitly confirmed, USB keyboards should be supported too (the Switch 1 already supports them for text input).</p>
<p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:tf7tjgkrqwai2kbxpx2dbr6k?ref_src=embed">OatmealDome (@oatmealdome.bsky.social)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:tf7tjgkrqwai2kbxpx2dbr6k/post/3lpcewgnfao2p?ref_src=embed">2025-05-16T15:49:03.5157015Z</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Of course, there's a high chance those will only be available as long as you have access to GameChat. As a reminder, the voice communication (activated when you press the new C button on the Joy-Con 2 controller) will only be free to use until March 31, 2026; after that date, it will remain available to active Nintendo Switch Online membership subscribers.</p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 is just a couple of weeks away from its launch. Keep in mind, though, that Nintendo isn't planning to allow pre-release reviews due to a day-one patch issue. As such, you might have to wait until later in June to get our opinion on the new console.</p>
<p>In the meantime, check out <a href="https://wccftech.com/roundup/nintendo-switch-2-everything-we-know-about-nintendos-new-console/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">our roundup article</a>.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We Harvest Shadows is both a rustic PT and a first-person Stardew Valley]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/we-harvest-shadows-is-both-a-rustic-pt-and-a-first-person-stardew-valley</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/we-harvest-shadows-is-both-a-rustic-pt-and-a-first-person-stardew-valley.1193724/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/we-harvest-shadows-is-both-a-rustic-pt-and-a-first-person-stardew-valley<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>David Wehle</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>About 30 minutes into the demo for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/we-harvest-shadows">We Harvest Shadows</a> a picture appeared on my wall, just by the farmhouse main entrance. The picture is of a long hallway of nested door frames, with a sealed door at the end. Any mystery it offers is, in theory, cancelled by the tutorials, which briskly informed me that the picture is, essentially, an alarm system. It will change in subtle and less subtle ways when danger is nearby. Still, this blunt advertisement of mechanical purpose does nothing to dispel the artefact's menace. It's right opposite the stairs, so that I can't avoid seeing it every morning unless I walk down the stairs backwards, and if I do that, I'm leaving myself vulnerable to anything else that might be waiting in the front hall or the kitchen to the right. </p><!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="We Harvest Shadows - Official Reveal Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5svvtbIdKFU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>We Harvest Shadows - Official Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5svvtbIdKFU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/5svvtbIdKFU?autoplay=1" title="We Harvest Shadows - Official Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5svvtbIdKFU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>I observe several picture changes during my time with the demo. By day, the tunnel of doors appears inverted, perhaps symbolising the subterranean retreat or Tarot-style reversal of whatever supernatural element it registers. Sometimes the door at the end of the tunnel is slightly ajar. And sometimes, the tunnel of doors is replaced by a glaring Rorschach rictus that is all the worse for the silence of its scream. The first time I saw the face in the picture, I had two thoughts: 1) gosh, it's getting late and I have work tomorrow, better wrap this up, and 2) the tutorial doesn't quite specify whether the picture itself might be the source of danger.</p>
<p>We Harvest Shadows, then: quite good fun. In this first-person blend of survival <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror</a> and Stardewlike, you play Garrett - name very probably a reference to the psychic resonance of attics - a city worker who has randomly bought an abandoned farm in the boondocks and sealed himself off from society forever. Garrett has a lot of baggage, evidently, which is perhaps why he keeps seeing things in the woods. Still, he's a cheery soul, the kind of affable space cadet who says things like "mad skills, Garrett!" when he assembles a chicken coop.</p>
<p>The game follows a day-night cycle. By day, you complete tasks like picking tomatoes according to a to-do list on right controller bumper. You can sell miscellaneous junk and produce by dropping it on the trailer by the kitchen: the process by which said junk and produce is converted into dollars is left cheerfully unexplained, as is the sorcerous summoning of tools and construction recipes from the brochure on the table by the wall. The inexplicability of these things suggests both a shortage of development resources and a developer who is confident that their creation's atmosphere and themes can overpower a few bare fittings. Or possibly, make use of them. I reckon the confidence is justified, so far.</p>
<p>Everything on the to-do list needs to be completed before Garrett can go to bed, saving the game and ending the day. This promises to be a source of tension later on, because the sun rolls swiftly through the sky, and Garrett really doesn't want to be outside watering vegetables after dark. The game's paranormal entities run a gamut from scuttling mutants to giant, staring faces that remind me a little of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nix-umbra-review-occult-horror-at-its-most-focused-and-intense">Nix Umbra</a>. There are firearms, but this doesn't feel remotely like a shooter. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1559720/We_Harvest_Shadows/">The Steam page</a> cites A24 films, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/pt">P.T.</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/what-remains-of-edith-finch">What Remains Of Edith Finch</a> as influences.</p>
<p>We Harvest Shadows is the work of David Wehle, crafter of charming fox 'em up <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/555150/The_First_Tree/">The First Tree</a>. There's no release date yet. If you find the Steam demo tantalising, you might want to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1559720/view/503946642097963130?l=english">check out this blog about "the advanced dynamic horror system"</a>. If you're more enthused by the Appalachian farming elements, you may be reassured to hear that there's an "endless mode" in the works that sandboxes the story and dials back the spooks. I will conclude by saying that I found this sufficiently chilling that I'm glad I don't currently have any pictures hanging up in my flat.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Developer Naughty Dog Working on a Second, Unannounced Game Other Than Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet, Neil Druckmann Confirms]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-developer-naughty-dog-working-on-a-second-unannounced-game-other-than-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-neil-druckmann-confirms</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-developer-naughty-dog-working-on-a-second-unannounced-game-other-than-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-neil-druckmann-confirms.1193721/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-developer-naughty-dog-working-on-a-second-unannounced-game-other-than-intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-neil-druckmann-confirms<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Naughty Dog chief Neil Druckmann has revealed the studio has a secret, unannounced second game in the works other than <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview with the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p08x7kb5" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Press X to Continue podcast</a>, Druckmann discussed his ongoing roles at Sony-owned Naughty Dog. On Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet, Druckmann works with two game directors: Matthew Gallant and Kurt Margenau, and is co-writing the game with narrative director Claire Carré. Druckmann did not say which director is working on the second game, however.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“There’s another game that’s being worked on at Naughty Dog where I am more of a producer role and I get to mentor and watch this other team and give feedback and be like the executive in the room,” he said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I enjoy all those roles, and the fact I jump between one to the next, it makes my job very exciting and always feeling fresh. I’m never bored.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">It is unclear at which stage each game is in production. Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet is announced, so you’d imagine it’s further along. But what is the second game?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There are some obvious candidates. Could it be The Last of Us 3? Druckmann has expressed his uncertainty in the past about being able to make the game, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/if-there-is-no-the-last-of-us-3-would-naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-keep-the-tv-show-going-past-the-games">but has said he has an ending in mind for what the game would be</a>. Based on Druckmann’s comments about having more of a producer role on this mystery second game, it doesn’t sound like it’s The Last of Us 3, as you’d imagine he’d want to be heavily involved and take on a director role for that game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alternatively, it could be another Uncharted game. There hasn’t been a brand new Uncharted game since 2017’s The Lost Legacy. Could it finally be time for a return? And there’s always a chance this second game could be a brand new intellectual property, as Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet is.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s worth noting that there’s always a chance this second game never comes out, or is never properly revealed by Sony. Naughty Dog has endured a tumultuous time in recent years, with the cancelation of its The Last of Us multiplayer game to focus on single-player games coming amid an apparent pull-back of live service titles at Sony.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-multiplayer-game-cancelled-will-focus-on-single-player-games-going-forward"><u>Naughty Dog stopped development on The Last of Us Online</u></a> in December 2023, saying it would have needed to put all its resources into post-launch content for years to come — an approach that would have severely impacted its ability to develop future single-player games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Historically, Naughty Dog has struggled to work on two big games at the same time, with one tending to end up top of the tree internally. The studio hasn’t released a brand new game since 2020’s The Last of Us 2, with remakes and collections in the interim.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/05/20/gettyimages-2208060751-1747724906242.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Neil Druckmann says Naughty Dog is working on a second game. Photo by Rich Polk/Deadline via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">As for Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet, it features a star-studded cast that includes Tati Gabrielle from the Uncharted movie as protagonist Jordan A. Mun, and Kumail Nanjiani of Marvel's Eternals as a man called Colin Graves. It is not expected to release until 2027 at the earliest. It’s a pretty long wait, but speaking to IGN on the red carpet ahead of The Last of Us Season 2 premiere, Druckmann said that Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet is not only playable right now, but “really good.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I will say we are playing it at the office and it's incredible,” Druckmann teased. “It's really good. I'm so excited to finally put gameplay out into the world and show people about it, because we just showed you the very, very, very tip on the iceberg. The game goes pretty deep beyond that.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Rich Polk/Deadline via Getty Images.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo bolsters Switch 2 supplies with Samsung chip partnership]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-bolsters-switch-2-supplies-with-samsung-chip-partnership</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-bolsters-switch-2-supplies-with-samsung-chip-partnership.1193718/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-bolsters-switch-2-supplies-with-samsung-chip-partnership<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Pushing for OLED screens in future.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Nintendo has partnered with Samsung to increase production of its <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-nintendo-direct-everything-announced">Switch 2</a> chips.</p>
<p>The partnership could mean Nintendo has enough stock to sell 20m consoles by March 2026, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-05-20/nintendo-turns-to-samsung-to-make-chips-ramp-up-switch-2-output">Bloomberg</a> has reported.</p>
<p>That's higher than <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-predicts-switch-2-will-outsell-its-predecessor-at-launch-despite-demand-exceeding-expectations">Nintendo forecast in its latest financial report</a> - it expects to sell 15m consoles in the first year.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9CF8nQGolWY?autoplay=1" title="Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Nintendo Switch 2 Hands-On Preview: Mario Kart World Impressions &amp; More!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9CF8nQGolWY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Samsung is aiming to compete with Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co. in producing chips across the world, and this partnership with Nintendo will certainly boost business.</p>
<p>Still, with increased chip supply, production will depend on the capacity of hardware assemblers such as Foxconn Technology Group.</p>
<p>Further, Samsung is reportedly pushing for OLED panels in a potential Switch 2 hardware refresh. The Korean firm already supplies flash memory and OLED screens for the original Switch.</p>
<p>Despite following its original Switch with an OLED model, Nintendo has opted for LCD for its bigger Switch 2 screen. While some have criticised the decision, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-hands-on-with-switch-2-the-digital-foundry-experience">quality of the LCD screen is excellent</a> - and leaves the door open for new hardware in future.</p>
<p>In a Q&amp;A following its latest financial report, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/switch-2-sales-forecast-not-affected-by-production-or-tariffs-nintendo-reiterates">Nintendo was criticised by investors for its conservative forecast</a> of 15m units. The console is expected to be incredibly popular - in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-admits-switch-2-demand-far-exceeds-expectations-in-japan-as-company-president-offers-stark-warning-over-stock">Japan alone demand for the console "far exceeds expectations"</a>, the company said.</p>
<p>Nintendo president Shuntaro Furukawa stated the company's sales forecast was not influenced by production capacity or US tariffs. However, he admitted that should US tariffs change, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-considering-switch-2-post-launch-price-rise-if-tariff-situation-worsens">company will consider price adjustments accordingly</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us Creator Is Also Producing an Unannounced Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-last-of-us-creator-is-also-producing-an-unannounced-game/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-creator-is-also-producing-an-unannounced-game.1193715/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-last-of-us-creator-is-also-producing-an-unannounced-game/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Last of Us creator Neil Druckmann is undoubtedly a very busy person these days. In an interview <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mNtAhRQNfcA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">with the Press X to Continue podcast</a>, the acclaimed game designer and writer revealed he is producing an unannounced game.</p>
<p><em>Then, you know, there's another game that's being worked out in Naughty Dog where I'm more of a producer role and I get to mentor and watch this other team and give feedback and be, like, the executive in the room. I enjoy all those roles and the fact that I jump between one to the next, it makes my job very exciting and always feeling fresh. I'm never bored.</em></p>
<p>Of course, that is in addition to the <a href="https://wccftech.com/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-is-a-game-about-faith-and-religion-where-players-will-feel-lonely-says-druckmann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet, which he's personally directing. And he's also an executive producer and episode director on The Last of Us HBO show, which is likely to continue beyond season two, given that it didn't include all of the story from the second game.</p>
<p>Druckmann's statement confirms a recent rumor <a href="https://wccftech.com/naughty-dog-reportedly-canceled-a-single-player-game-this-year-but-another-unannounced-game-is-still-in-the-works/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> by movie insider Daniel Richtman, who mentioned that Naughty Dog recently canceled a game formerly directed by Vinit Agarwal but still has another active project that's been in the works for at least three years with Shaun Escayg as its director.</p>
<p>Now, when it comes to what that will be, we inevitably enter guessing territory. The mind immediately goes to The Last of Us Part III, which many fans would like to see at some point. However, Druckmann himself <a href="https://wccftech.com/this-could-be-it-for-the-last-of-us-says-series-creator-neil-druckmann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">suggested</a> just over two months ago that there may not even be a third installment in the beloved franchise. Was he just misdirecting until a proper announcement? Or is Escayg perhaps working on a new installment in the Uncharted IP, which is familiar ground for him, having already co-directed Uncharted: The Lost Legacy with Kurt Margenau? It may be a while until we learn the answers to these questions.</p>
<p>During that podcast conversation, Druckmann also marveled at the improvements made in the gaming medium when discussing things that The Last of Us fans preferred in the game over the TV show adaptation:</p>
<p><em>Lately, I've just been really fascinated with the adaptation and all the various reactions to it. And I just had this moment the other day where I was reading something, actually people were critical of some choices that we've made in the show and they were saying like, oh, I like this better in the game and this was more subtle in the game, and I just had this joyous moment of like, look how far games have come that we could have this conversation. You can compare the two and the game can sit side by side with an HBO show and you can have this conversation and even if people are critical of it, I just love it. And then there's people that love it and there's people that love the show better, and they're like, "Oh, these choices were better than the game." And I'm like, "Isn't that fascinating? Look at that."</em></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer Skulls returns amidst Dawn Of War 4 rumours]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-skulls-returns-amidst-dawn-of-war-4-rumours</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-skulls-returns-amidst-dawn-of-war-4-rumours.1193712/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/warhammer-skulls-returns-amidst-dawn-of-war-4-rumours<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Some more of that classic T-shirt based journalism I know you all love</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Sega</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Now we're cooking with asbestos: Warhammer Skulls, the yearly power armoured excite-o-thon hosted by <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/warhammer-40000-boltgun">Boltgun</a> actor Rahul Kohli, returns this Thursday. It's traditionally a time of reveals and revelry, with the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/warhammer-40000-mechanicus">Mechanicus</a> sequel a likely contender for the spotlight this year. You can watch it live on <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/warhammer">TwitchHam</a> at  17:00 BST/12:00 EST/9:00 PST. Here's a teasytrailyhypeyshouty in the meantime.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Warhammer Skulls returns! #WarhammerSkulls" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wEonJHkA9ZU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Warhammer Skulls returns! #WarhammerSkulls</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wEonJHkA9ZU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wEonJHkA9ZU?autoplay=1" title="Warhammer Skulls returns! #WarhammerSkulls">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wEonJHkA9ZU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>There'll also be discounts on a bunch of Warhammer licensed electronic entertainment products. There likely will not be any news on the next <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-warhammer-iii">Total War: Warhammer 3</a> DLC, because Creative Assembly like to keep to their own inscrutable schedule. And, if certain conspiratorial corners of the internet and also <a href="https://www.thegamer.com/dawn-of-war-4-linkedin-post/">The Gamer</a> are to be believed, we might also see something <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/warhammer-40000-dawn-war">Dawn Of War</a> shaped.</p>
<p>These rumours have bubbled up from LinkedIn; fetid swamplands where drowning souls beg the local alligators for a swift crunchdeath but are instead tortured with bullet pointed posts by self-styled analysts using 500 of their businessiest words to say "game sold well because fun, also no woke, share if agree" (I really need to get off LinkedIn). Specifically, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/dominik-dolenec-57153146_emonacapital-activity-7302358433092030464-x6t8">a post by</a> one Dominik Dolenec, whose UK based investment firm Emona Capital includes both Relic and Blackbird Interactive in its portfolio.</p>
<p>Dolenec shared a picture of himself at Nottingham's Warhammer World, thanking Owen Rees - Games Workshop's head of licensing and project lead on multiple Dawn Of War titles. "Looking forward to deepening our partnership in years to come,” wrote Dolenec. From The Gamer:</p>
<blockquote><p>Why is this post suggesting Dawn of War 4, rather than a Baneblade deconstructing game from Hardspace: Shipbreaker devs Blackbird Interactive? That all comes down to Dolenec’s t-shirt, which appears in the corner of one of his photos. It appears to bear the logo of Relic Entertainment, suggesting that he’s in Nottingham on its behalf. He also confirms that we’re not seeing things in the comments and he is, in fact, emblazoned with Relic’s crest.</p></blockquote>
<p>So, there's your grist, rumour millers. Do with it what you will. Me? I don't especially need another Warhammer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-strategy-games-on-pc">strategy game</a> in my life that doesn't have Skaven in it, and I'm not entirely sure I trust modern Relic to deliver a decent one even if I did. I would play it though of course, yeah. Who do you think I am, someone who hasn't bought every Killteam big box this season despite not having assembled the Vespids from the starter yet?</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frostpunk 2 wins Polish Game of the Year at Digital Dragons]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/20/frostpunk-2-wins-polish-game-of-the-year-at-digital-dragons/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/frostpunk-2-wins-polish-game-of-the-year-at-digital-dragons.1193703/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/20/frostpunk-2-wins-polish-game-of-the-year-at-digital-dragons/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Digital Dragons is Poland’s biggest games industry expo, with developers, publishers, press and support companies descending on Krakow for two days of lectures, interviews and showcases. As part of the conference, last night played host to the Digital Dragons Awards Gala, celebrating the best and the brightest of the Polish gaming scene. Across multiple awards, several big titles duked it out, including global hits like Nobody Wants To Die and The Thaumaturge, but it was survival city-builder <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1601580/Frostpunk_2/">Frostpunk 2</a> that took home the top honours, winning Polish Game of the Year.</p>
<p>The awards ceremony began with the Indie Dragons awards, spotlighting smaller studios and new teams. Third place went to Arms of God, while XYZ from Screen Tear Games came second. The ultimate winner, though, nabbing the award, additional funding, and a powerful new AMD workstation from the sponsors, was <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1868360/Deep_Sleep_Labyrinth_of_the_Forsaken/">Deep Sleep: Labyrinth of the Forsaken</a>, a point-and-click title from scriptwelder. My favourite quote of the night? The presenter for first place saying, “And now, let’s see who baked the best turkey.” I’m going to judge all game award winners as turkey bakers for the foreseeable.</p>



<p>Frostpunk 2 also scooped two additional awards, winning Best Polish Game Design and Best Polish Game Audio, with the post-apocalyptic city builder winning over judges across the board. Its main competitor at this year’s show was <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1939970/Nobody_Wants_to_Die/">Nobody Wants To Die</a>, the dystopian detective story winning both Best Polish Game Narrative and Best Polish Visual Art.</p>
<p>Further awards went to Tomorrow: Online Survival for best Polish Mobile Game, while Magdalena Cielecka received a Special Recognition Award for her work within the industry. Finally, Best Foreign Game went to Canada’s all-conquering Balatro, which was well received in the hall.</p>

<p>What was clear throughout the show, and the wider Digital Dragons conference, was the excellent health that the Polish game development scene is in. Hundreds of game studios call Poland home, and while global giants like CD Projekt, Techland and Bloober Team are at the forefront, there’s a wealth of talent here, with Poland hosting the second-largest development community in Europe.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dreaming in Cherry Blossoms, I Fall in Love with You launches in June]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/dreaming-in-cherry-blossoms-i-fall-in-love-with-you-launches-in-june</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dreaming-in-cherry-blossoms-i-fall-in-love-with-you-launches-in-june.1193676/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/dreaming-in-cherry-blossoms-i-fall-in-love-with-you-launches-in-june<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Voice cast announced.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Romance <a title="Genres > Visual Novel [569 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/visual-novel">visual novel</a> <em><a title="Games > Dreaming in Cherry Blossoms, I Fall in Love with You [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dreaming-in-cherry-blossoms-i-fall-in-love-with-you">Dreaming in Cherry Blossoms, I Fall in Love with You</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,102 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,158 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/3690420/" target="_blank">Steam</a> in June, developer Operahouse announced. It will support English, Japanese, Korean, Traditional Chinese, and Simplified Chinese language options. <span id="more-965800"></span></p><p>The game’s voice cast was also announced:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Cherry</strong> (voiced by Rin Kurusu)</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Dreaming-Cherry-Blossoms_05-20-25_Characters_001.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Wathy</strong> (voiced by Saku Mizuno)</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Dreaming-Cherry-Blossoms_05-20-25_Characters_002.jpg"></a></figure><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Yuri Takai</strong> (voicd by Yurina Uchiyama)</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Dreaming-Cherry-Blossoms_05-20-25_Characters_003.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Shoko Ina</strong> (voiced by Non Harusaki)</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Dreaming-Cherry-Blossoms_05-20-25_Characters_004.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Yua Orihara</strong> (voiced by <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>tsu Murakami)</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Dreaming-Cherry-Blossoms_05-20-25_Characters_005.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Hayato Kusanagi</strong> (voiced by Kakeru Hatano)</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Dreaming-Cherry-Blossoms_05-20-25_Characters_004.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>And more…!</strong></p></blockquote><p>Here is the story synopsis:</p><blockquote><p>A story where the “memories of cherry blossoms” gently unravel the heart.</p><p>It is a tale of a person encountering “everyday life” once again in a quiet season.​</p><p>A visual novel set in a small town where fantasy and reality intersect, quietly touching the heart.</p><p>In the changing scenery, as if searching for something that once certainly existed.​</p><p>Eventually, it becomes a journey to face forgotten emotions once more.​</p><p>Within the game, graphics enveloped in soft light and delicate sounds color the story.</p><p>Multiple “forms of the heart” are depicted based on the player’s choices.​</p><p>Feelings that everyone has experienced at least once but couldn’t express in words—.</p><p>Find the answer within the spring breeze.</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digimon Expo ’25 set for September 20 to 21]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/digimon-expo-25-set-for-september-20-to-21</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/digimon-expo-%E2%80%9925-set-for-september-20-to-21.1193673/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/digimon-expo-25-set-for-september-20-to-21<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Details to be announced on June 26.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,681 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> will host Digimon Expo ’25 from September 20 to 21 at Prism Hall in Tokyo Dome City, the company <a href="https://twitter.com/digimonweb_net/status/1924667061453914557" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-965803"></span></p><p>The in-person event will bring together all things <em>Digimon</em>, including the anime, video games, card game, and merchandise.</p><p>Detailed information about Digimon Expo ’25 will be announced on June 26. </p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oh No, Anyway]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/web3-nft-crypto-game-fail-close-scam-snake-oil</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/oh-no-anyway.1193652/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/web3-nft-crypto-game-fail-close-scam-snake-oil<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I opened Linkedin the other day--I am <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/lukeplunkett.com/post/3lpdtuo37g225" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">addicted</a> to <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/lukeplunkett.com/post/3lp6gpavvos2y" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">scrolling</a> through the <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/lukeplunkett.com/post/3lof746xyg226" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">depravity</a> of its most popular members, please send help immediately--and was greeted with an alarming moment of self-reflection.</p><p>This person, who works for a weird<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Web3</a> website, posted:</p><figure></figure><p><a href="https://playtoearn.com/news/web3-shooter-nyan-heroes-shuts-down-despite-1m-players-and-250k-wishlists" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">What went wrong</a>? Where was the long-term success?</p><p>I think some dipshits fleeced some even bigger dipshits out of $22 million, failed to make enjoyable video games because they were never interested in making video games in the first place and now someone–anyone who owned any of these games’ now-worthless tokens–is left holding the bag.</p><p>Hope that helps!</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/fortnite-ai-darth-vader-star-wars-epic-games-sag-aftra"><h3>Fortnite’s AI Darth Vader Has, Predictably, Been A Comedy Of Errors</h3></a><p>Swears, slurs, and an unfair labor practice – all in just a few days</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/wind-breaker-shonen-anime-toxic-masculinity"><h3>This Shonen Anime Fights Toxic Masculinity</h3></a><p>Wind Breaker is a shonen anime where teenage boys talk about their feelings while punching toxic masculinity in the face.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/the-last-of-us-season-2-hbo-tv-series-show-impressions"><h3>The Last Of Us Season 2 Is Bad Television</h3></a><p>It's not great, whether you've played the game or not</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>