<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 15:38:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Life By You devs spent “a month in purgatory” prior to closure, says laid-off designer, despite their sim-like exceeding Paradox's expectations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/life-by-you-devs-spent-a-month-in-purgatory-prior-to-closure-says-laid-off-designer-despite-their-sim-like-exceeding-paradoxs-expectations</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/life-by-you-devs-spent-%E2%80%9Ca-month-in-purgatory%E2%80%9D-prior-to-closure-says-laid-off-designer-despite-their-sim-like-exceeding-paradoxs-expectations.905865/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/life-by-you-devs-spent-a-month-in-purgatory-prior-to-closure-says-laid-off-designer-despite-their-sim-like-exceeding-paradoxs-expectations<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>“We were a strong team on a strong project ready to launch to a strong audience.”</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1.-Ronnie-heading-to-Work_LotusGym.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Paradox Interactive</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Yesterday, we <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/paradox-shutter-studio-tectonic-and-cancel-troubled-sims-competitor-life-by-you">learned that</a> Sims-like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/life-by-you">Life By You</a> had been canceled, and its developers Paradox Tectonic had been shut down by parent company Paradox Interactive. Later the same day, game designer Willem Delventhal shared more a detailed account of his experience working on the game through to its cancellation, via <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7208887303224606720/">LinkedIn</a>.</p>

<p>Paradox <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sims-contender-life-by-you-gets-delayed-once-again-this-time-indefinitely">delayed Life By You indefinitely on 21st May</a>, having previously announced that it would launch on 4th June. According to Delventhal, however, it wasn't till some weeks after that the developers were told that they were being laid off.</p>
<p>“Two weeks before launch we were told we wouldn't be launching, and just now that we've all lost our jobs” Delventhal writes in the LinkedIn post, which has attracted messages of support from other former Paradox Tectonic staff. "We were only informed of this via a public announcement.”</p>
<p>The “public announcement” in question was yesterday’s post from Paradox Interactive CEO Fredrik Wester. “This is difficult and drastic news for our colleagues at Tectonic, who’ve worked hard on Life by You’s Early Access release,” said Wester. “Sadly, with cancellation of their sole project, we have to take the tough decision to close down the studio.”</p>
<p>Paradox, says Delventhal, never really communicated the reasons for suspending Life By You's release. “Instead we spent a month in purgatory, and did everything we could to prove to them we were worth launching, including things like finding potential buyers or suggesting cutting ties and going indie. We heard virtually nothing back.”</p>
<p>Life By You has long had a reputation for being <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sims-contender-life-by-you-gets-delayed-once-again-this-time-indefinitely">a difficult project</a>, thanks to repeated delays, but Delventhal - who’s part of <a href="https://indiegameacademy.com/">educational workshop The Indie Game Academy</a> - says the team had been doing "extremely well" in recent months.</p>
<p>"I cannot share specific numbers, but I can say that we had an internal metric we were aiming for that had been approved, and that we exceeded that number by a significant portion," he writes in the post. "We also got a thumbs up a few weeks before launch."</p>
<p>Delventhal has his own speculations about why Life By You was cancelled, commenting that "as a business owner, some of them are understandable, but many of them are not", but he doesn't want to indulge in conjecture.</p>
<p>"We were a strong team on a strong project ready to launch to a strong audience," he concludes. "Really I'd like to be much more fire and brimstone about it. I'm pretty pissed, not gonna lie. But I'm trying to stay kind and respectful. So instead I'll say: this industry has become a place in which you can deliver more than expected, have AA money behind you, and still have the rug pulled two weeks before launch."</p>
<p>Paradox Interactive reported <a href="https://videogames.si.com/news/paradox-financials-2023">record revenue last year</a>, but a decrease in profits.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s A Dark Souls Typing Game]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/heres-a-dark-souls-typing-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here%E2%80%99s-a-dark-souls-typing-game.905862/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/heres-a-dark-souls-typing-game<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Shadow of the Erdtree </em>is the FromSoftware game on everyone’s minds, but if you, like me, aren’t an <em>Elden Ring</em> person, you can experience some of the game’s punishing difficulty in <a href="https://woe-industries.itch.io/fromsoftword" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>FromSoft Wor</em>d</a>, a recent browser-based typing game by Woe Industries that bills itself as “the <em>Dark Souls </em>of word processors.”</p><p>Unlike other typing games that give you prompts to copy, opening <em>FromSoft Word</em> presents you with the truest cosmic horror: a blank page. You can type whatever you want, accompanied by dramatic music and sword-slashing sound effects. The catch is that if you make a typo, the game ends and all your work is deleted. </p><p>I thought at first that this openness would be easy–I’m not going to purposefully choose words I can’t spell, right? But after playing for a while, I think it’s actually what makes the game so hard. I either got into an overly-confident writing groove and made a mistake, or all that freedom morphed into pressure not to mess up until I sabotaged myself.</p><p>As in its boss battle-heavy namesake, I learned the game's patterns as I played. Putting aside the deeply correct choice that “<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/rcmacleod.bsky.social/post/3kvagfx62k22f" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">videogame</a>” is run-ending, I was surprised to find words like “blog” and “screenshot” triggering a game over. <em>FromSoft Word</em> also draws from US English, so no “grey” or “centre.” (Sorry, Luke!) Not knowing what words count as typos could feel unfair, but the mystery adds another layer of tension and difficulty to the game. Should you stick to basic words, or risk the journey to the edges of your vocabulary? For such a simple premise, it’s terrifically compelling, with the temptation of a high score calling me to play it safe while my desire to push the game’s boundaries pulled me inexorably toward failure.</p><p>Developer <a href="https://woe-industries.itch.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Woe Industries</a> has made a host of other browser games about the horrors of modern life, including a <a href="https://woe-industries.itch.io/dr-mario-insurance" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">game</a> that’s “Dr. Mario, but the worse your insurance is, the harder this game gets” and a <a href="https://woe-industries.itch.io/job-hunt-new-post" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Duck Hunt</em> knockoff</a> where you shoot at open jobs on LinkedIn.</p><p>I spotted <em>FromSoft Word</em> thanks to a <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/graysonmorley.bsky.social/post/3kvag6p7zp32n" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BlueSky post</a> by writer Grayson Morley, who horrifyingly suggested writing a whole novel in it. I tried to write this blog in it, but ironically, “Erdtree” and “FromSoftware” both gave me a game over.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Life By You, Paradox's The Sims Competitor, Has Been Cancelled]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/life-by-you-paradoxs-sims-competitor-has-been-cancelled</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/life-by-you-paradoxs-the-sims-competitor-has-been-cancelled.905850/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/life-by-you-paradoxs-sims-competitor-has-been-cancelled<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>Update: Paradox Tectonic Closed</h2>
<p>June 18th: Today, Paradox Interactive announced that following its cancellation of <em>Life by You</em>, it's also <a href="https://www.paradoxinteractive.com/media/press-releases/press-release/paradox-interactive-to-close-down-paradox-tectonic" rel="noopener" target="_blank" title="Paradox Interactive to close down Paradox Tectonic">closing the game's developer</a> Paradox Tectonic, laying off 24 employees as a result.</p>
<p>Original Story Below</p>
<hr><p>Fans of cozy life simulators got some sad news today. Paradox Interactive has announced <em>Life By You</em>, their highly anticipated life simulator, has been shelved. This is disappointing for fans of the project since it was seen as competition for EA's <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/sims-4" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>The Sims</em></a> series.</p>
<h2>The <em>Life By You</em> Cancellation</h2>
<p>The cancellation of <em>Life By You</em> was announced in a <a href="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/life-by-you-is-cancelled.1688889/">Paradox forum post</a> by Deputy CEO Mattias Lilja. Lilja mentions that the decision was difficult and a failure on Paradox's part to meet expectations.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/life-by-you-conversation-system-screenshot.jpg?itok=yblRMSCR 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/life-by-you-conversation-system-screenshot.jpg?itok=XvgszgKL 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Guess we won't see this get any more polish.</figcaption></figure><p>Lilja continues stating the developers were given a fair shot to realize the game's potential, citing two different delays as well as choosing to hold off on an Early Access release.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A few weeks back, we decided to hold off on an Early Access release in order to re-evaluate <em>Life by You</em>, as we still felt that the game was lacking in some key areas. Though a time extension was an option, once we took that pause to get a wider view of the game, it became clear to us that the road leading to a release that we felt confident about was far too long and uncertain. This is not to say the game has not shown any promising qualities; <em>Life by You</em> had a number of strengths and the hard work of a dedicated team that went into realizing them. However, when we come to a point where we believe that more time will not get us close enough to a version we would be satisfied with, then we believe it is better to stop. This is obviously tough and disappointing for everyone who poured their time and enthusiasm into this project, especially when our decision comes so late in the process.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Overall, Lilja's explanation of <em>Life By You's</em> cancellation is measured and principled; putting accountability on management. It puts into perspective the promises and ambition the game touted on its Steam storepage. It also sours our preview of the game, which held promise.</p>
<p>The cancellation of <em>Life By You</em> is a shame for fans of the recent trend of cozy games. Life simulators are built around pleasant suburban environments and a relaxed atmosphere. These have included high profile releases like <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/disney-dreamlight-valley" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Disney Dreamlight Valley</em></a>, and smaller indie titles like <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/cozy-grove" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Cozy Grove</em></a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Delists Beyond Good and Evil on Steam With Remaster Waiting in the Wings]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-delists-beyond-good-and-evil-on-steam-with-remaster-waiting-in-the-wings</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-delists-beyond-good-and-evil-on-steam-with-remaster-waiting-in-the-wings.905841/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-delists-beyond-good-and-evil-on-steam-with-remaster-waiting-in-the-wings<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Ubisoft has delisted <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/beyond-good-and-evil">Beyond Good and Evil</a> on Steam ahead of an expected reveal of a remaster.</p><p>A note on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/15130/Beyond_Good_and_Evil/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the Steam page</a> for the cult classic adventure signals Ubisoft’s decision: “Notice: At the request of the publisher, Beyond Good and Evil is unlisted on the Steam store and will not appear in search.” At the time of this article’s publication, Beyond Good and Evil remains available to buy on GoG.</p><p>Ubisoft has said it will announce more news about Beyond Good &amp; Evil - 20th Anniversary Edition during the Limited Run Games Showcase on June 20 at 11am Pacific / 2pm Eastern 7pm UK. It seems likely a re-release is inbound.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Looks like Uncle Pey'j has a message to share with you all...<br>See you at the Limited Run Games Showcase on June 20th at 2pm EST for more news about Beyond Good &amp; Evil - 20th Anniversary Edition! 👉 : <a href="https://t.co/zaLKVRlN2A" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/zaLKVRlN2A</a> Big thanks to Hubert Chevillard for this little teaser😀 <a href="https://t.co/dY2PqL2JWn" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/dY2PqL2JWn</a></p>— Beyond Good and Evil 2 (@bgegame) <a href="https://twitter.com/bgegame/status/1803095350950949107?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>In August 2023, the Electronic Software Ratings Board (ESRB) rated Beyond Good &amp; Evil: 20th Anniversary Edition for PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X and S, Nintendo Switch, and PC. Then, in November, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/beyond-good-evil-20th-anniversary-edition-pops-up-on-xbox-store">Ubisoft accidentally released Beyond Good &amp; Evil 20th Anniversary Edition early</a>, blaming it on a "technical error” while confirming an early 2024 release window.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/19/0000004063-1920x1080-1718804915664.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: Ubisoft.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Beyond Good &amp; Evil first launched on November 11, 2003, so we’ve skipped past the actual 20th anniversary. In IGN’s <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2003/11/12/beyond-good-evil-3"><u>9/10 Beyond Good &amp; Evil review</u></a>, we said: “While it's over a bit before you'd want it to be, Beyond Good &amp; Evil tells its story with amazing pizzazz and polish. Even better, it's a story well worth telling.”</p><p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/beyond-good-and-evil-2">Beyond Good &amp; Evil 2</a> remains missing in action after yet another no-show during the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ubisoft-forward-2024-everything-announced">Ubisoft Forward event this month</a>.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Was Metroid Prime 4 Running on Switch 2?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/was-metroid-prime-4-running-on-switch-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/was-metroid-prime-4-running-on-switch-2.905838/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/was-metroid-prime-4-running-on-switch-2<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">IGN asked tech experts Digital Foundry to analyse the gameplay footage to get the definitive answer.</h2></div><section><p>While this week’s Nintendo Direct was full of surprises, perhaps the biggest was that we finally got a release date for Metroid Prime 4 and, more importantly, our first proper look at gameplay seven years after it was initially announced. It was enough to send <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C8X_tCXyYCw/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>some fans into meltdown</u></a> and it’s with equal parts relief and excitement to know the long-awaited sequel is finally coming in 2025.</p><p>But once the dust settled, some parts of the internet started asking the question: Was Metroid Prime 4 running on Switch 2? The release date certainly ties in with everything we know about the Switch successor, plus there are moments in the trailer when it looks like a step up from what we’ve seen on the original Switch hardware. Of course, Nintendo would never come out and say what the demo was running on so IGN sought the advice of the next best thing – the tech experts at <a href="https://www.digitalfoundry.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Digital Foundry</u></a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>For years, Digital Foundry has been analysing video game performance to an unparalleled level and recently did a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2023-inside-nvidias-latest-hardware-for-nintendo-what-is-the-t239-processor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>deep dive into what we can expect from Nintendo’s next-generation of hardware</u></a>, so it’s better placed than anyone to provide trustworthy insight into Metroid Prime 4’s gameplay reveal.</p><p>So, was Metroid Prime 4 running on Switch 2?</p><p>Digital Foundry’s technology editor Richard Leadbetter gave us the definitive answer: “It's looking great and there are a couple of nice effects in there we took a closer look at, but ultimately, all the evidence points to this game running on the original Switch. The internal rendering resolution counts out at 900p, which is the same as Metroid Prime Remastered. And as good as it is, there are some aliasing issues and even some very minor frame-rate drops. Everything about the visual make-up is consistent with a really well-made Switch game, where Retro has an excellent track record. I can imagine the development studio is really happy that people are making a connection with Switch 2, mind you.”</p><p>So although many were convinced we’d had our first look at a Switch 2 game in Metroid Prime 4: Beyond, the truth is it’s likely running on existing hardware. While that’s disappointing for some, it’s also hardly surprising; I expect Nintendo to pull out all the stops when the Switch successor is finally revealed rather than stealth-drop our first look at the end of an (admittedly surprising) Nintendo Direct.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>There's a few things at play but ultimately it's the skill of the developer working on a fixed platform they've had time to get to know over a great period of time</p></div><p>That said, developer Retro Studios should be congratulated because making a game look this good on technology that’s over seven years old is no mean feat, and Leadbetter explains how Retro might have managed to achieve it: “There's a few things at play here but ultimately it's the skill of the developer working on a fixed platform they've had time to get to know over a great period of time. That singular focus makes great things possible. Another good example would be Halo 4 on Xbox 360 – at the end of a console's lifecycle you get to see the hardware pushed in ways you would have never envisaged earlier on.”</p><p>Another reason the gameplay demo could look as good as it does is because it might be representative of what the final game will look like rather than exactly how it’ll turn out. It’s certainly not uncommon for this to be the case with early looks at games and it’s also not the first time Nintendo has done something similar, as Leadbetter reveals: “Nintendo has released some trailer assets that looked better than the final release games. There's the now legendary '<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BLlZBwN_-C4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Too Big For Switch</u></a>' trailer for The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom and a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8Nf51ixmR9o" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>trailer for Bayonetta 3</u></a> that ran consistently at 60fps where the final game certainly does not. However, in this case, with this developer and a game in gestation for this long, the instinct is to say that this is Switch 1 and representative of the actual console experience. If it were on Switch 2, we'd expect anti-aliasing via DLSS  – there is none at all in this trailer – and a higher output resolution, for starters.”</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>[For Switch 2] I'd expect any kinks in performance to be ironed out, while running at a higher resolution, potentially augmented by DLSS</p></div><p>While all evidence points to Metroid Prime 4’s gameplay reveal being on original Switch hardware then, there’s no doubt given its 2025 release that it will eventually make it onto the Switch 2. Indeed, cross-gen games have long been part of every new console cycle for years and it would make sense that Retro is developing an upgraded version of Metroid Prime 4 for when Switch 2 finally comes out. Which begs the question – what improvements can we expect to see over Metroid Prime 4 running on the original Switch? We can only theorise right now, but Leadbetter has his thoughts: “It’s a tricky one because it's as much about Nintendo's cross-gen strategy as it is about the capabilities of the hardware. One thing that always stands out from running Switch games on PC emulators is how scalable the artwork is. The quality of the art itself benefits immensely from higher resolutions, while gameplay benefits from higher frame-rates. At the very least, I'd expect any remaining kinks in performance to be ironed out, while running at a higher resolution, potentially augmented by DLSS. If there are noticeable loading times, you'd expect those to be reduced as Switch 2 has faster storage plus a hardware decompression block to ease the load on the CPU.”</p><div data-cy="carousel"><h3>Nintendo Direct June 2024 Games</h3><p>Every game featured in the Nintendo Direct on June 18, 2024.</p></div><p>Of course, faster loading times and improved visuals are commonplace for cross-gen games running on more powerful hardware, but personally it’s something I’m still excited for – not just for Metroid Prime 4 but also Nintendo’s other back catalogue. I would buy a Switch 2 in a heartbeat if it brought out improved versions of The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom and I’m sure I’m not alone.</p><p>But we don’t know what Nintendo’s approach will be with Switch 2 right now. Many are hoping for backwards-compatibility, myself included, but what about cross-gen games running on Switch 2? “The question is whether Nintendo goes for 'easy wins' like higher resolutions, higher precision effects and so on, as we've seen on Sony and Microsoft consoles before”, says Leadbetter. “Or will it dip into the Switch 2's feature set more extensively and push for more game-changing effects. It does support ray tracing, after all.”</p><p>If Nintendo’s past has taught us anything, it’s that it doesn’t like to follow in the footsteps of others so I’m hoping Nintendo goes all out with Switch 2.</p><p><em>Alex Simmons is IGN's Features Director.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Developer behind Steam smash hit Banana swears it isn’t a scam]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/developer-behind-steam-smash-hit-banana-swears-it-isnt-a-scam/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=developer-behind-steam-smash-hit-banana-swears-it-isnt-a-scam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/developer-behind-steam-smash-hit-banana-swears-it-isn%E2%80%99t-a-scam.905832/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/developer-behind-steam-smash-hit-banana-swears-it-isnt-a-scam/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=developer-behind-steam-smash-hit-banana-swears-it-isnt-a-scam<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="477" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Chances are you’re well aware of <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/i-played-weird-banana-game-blowing-up-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">that bizarre <em>Banana</em> game</a> that’s exploded in popularity recently. Even though all you do is click a static image of a banana to make a number go up, it’s currently the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/banana-is-currently-the-second-most-played-game-on-steam/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">second-most played game on Steam</a>, losing only to <em>Counter-Strike 2</em>. This success appears to have attracted scrutiny, however, as the game’s developer has had to issue a statement about how <em>Banana</em> isn’t a scam of some kind, as reported by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/banana-game-not-a-scam-says-developer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Eurogamer</a>.</p> <p data-characters="428" data-current-count="428" data-injectable="true">For anyone not in the know, you can earn bananas (either by clicking enough times or waiting long enough), which can then be sold on the Steam marketplace. While most only go for a few cents, there are reports of people spending hundreds, if not thousands of dollars on these bananas, even though they don’t do anything in-game. As such, members of the <em>Banana</em> Discord and <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/2923300/discussions/0/4340987076276621290/">Steam users</a> have found the whole thing suspicious.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot via Destructoid.</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="706" data-current-count="1006" data-injectable="true">Things appeared to escalate when one of <em>Banana</em>‘s team members, only known as Theselions, was accused of once being part of a Steam market bitcoin scam. <em>Banana</em>‘s co-founder, aestheticspartan, has since explained on Discord that this is true, but insisted no one else on the team was even aware of Theselions’ involvement. What’s more, when confronted on the matter, Theselions is said to be “showing remorse and is sorry about what happened in the past.” However, aestheticspartan added that Theselions has now “parted ways” with the team, and his inventory has been cleared of “any valuable bananas that could concern and/or worry the community.”</p>
 <p data-characters="448" data-current-count="448" data-injectable="true">It’s unlikely the removal of a single team member will put to bed any suspicions about the <em>Banana</em> game itself, but the developers have said their working on updates that will “turn this game into something bigger and better than just a clicker game.” This includes letting players “do much more with your bananas,” suggesting there’ll eventually be some in-game function for the bananas people have been earning.</p>
 <p data-characters="520" data-current-count="520" data-injectable="true">In a recent interview with <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-gb/entertainment/gaming/why-clicker-game-banana-the-legal-infinite-money-glitch-is-going-viral-on-steam/ar-BB1nPmuR" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Polygon</a>, developer Hery assured everything the team is doing is perfectly legal, but it remains unclear how much of its 786,000+ players (at the time of writing) are actual humans and not bots set up to farm for bananas. Hery admitted there is a bot problem, saying only a third of <em>Banana</em>‘s concurrent player count from last week were real people, but they believe more human players have since joined in. Plus, it’s contacted Valve to figure out how it can clamp down on the bots.</p>
 <p data-characters="355" data-current-count="355" data-injectable="false">I have to admit, I am a bit curious to see how much longer <em>Banana</em> can maintain its popularity, and what sort of additions it could make with these promised updates. The whole thing does sound worryingly similar to the NFT fad, though, and if the <em>Banana</em> bubble bursts, people could be left with a bunch of useless items that they can’t even sell off.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree Review – Worthy of the Greater Will’s Blessing]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-worthy-of-the-greater-wills-blessing/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-review-%E2%80%93-worthy-of-the-greater-will%E2%80%99s-blessing.905820/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-worthy-of-the-greater-wills-blessing/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
				<main>

					

					<!--<div class="ads-container banner-ad floated p-0">
						<div data-pg-ad-spot='div-gpt-ad-wccftechcom38564' style="min-height: 280px;"></div>
					</div>-->
					
										<div><header>Game Info</header><div><div>
						<h5>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree</h5><p><span>June 21st, 2024</span>
					</p></div><div>
							<h5>Platform</h5><p><span>PC (Steam), PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, Xbox One</span>
						</p></div></div></div>
					<p>The release of DLC expansions for games developed by FromSoftware is often met with plenty of anticipation, as the Japanese development studio is known for releasing additional content that is often even better than the base game. With <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/elden-ring-make-way-for-the-elden-lord/">Elden Ring</a>, however, this was not very easy to achieve. The studio's latest game is a masterclass of action role-playing games and open-world design, which is difficult to top, something that FromSoftware is surely aware of, as the Shadow of the Erdtree expansion does not present a markedly better experience than the base game. At the same time, it is undeniable it is an excellent continuation of the long and grueling journey of the Tarnished in the Lands Between.</p>
<p>The Shadow of the Erdtree expansion takes place in the Shadow Realm, which can be accessed after defeating Starscourge Radahn and Mogh, Lord of Blood. As soon as the Tarnished enters this hauntingly beautiful world, dominated by the looming figure of the Scadutree, they will meet the enigmatic Leda and several other companions who are trying to ascertain what happened to the missing god Miquella, a task that is far from being easy, as retracing the god's footsteps into this mysterious land will get the Tarnished to face countless challenges, including some of the most powerful beings seen in the Elden Ring universe.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/20240608010832_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>As is tradition for FromSoftware at this point, the Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree story is masterfully told with environmental storytelling, leaving players to piece together every little detail gleaned from the environment, item descriptions, and the small amount of information revealed by the many new NPCs they will meet in the Shadow Realm. Leda and her companions play an important part in the expansion events, and completing their sidequests provides additional information on a story that makes the experience even more engaging once everything has been more or less understood. The story and some of its reveals, which also involve characters from the base game, also feel very coherent with what has been seen in the base game, taking full advantage of the world and expansive lore crafted by FromSoftware in collaboration with A Song of Ice and Fire's author George R.R. Martin.</p>
<p>Gameplay wise, the Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree expansion doesn't push boundaries. For all intents and purposes, the expansion plays exactly like the base game does. With little to no guidance, save for items that, once gathered, reveal the Shadow Realm's map in great detail, the Tarnished has to explore a huge open-world map whose size is very roughly the same as the Limgrave region in the Lands Between, venture inside a variety of dungeons, ranging from smaller optional ones like caves and catacombs to main story Legacy dungeons, and defeat countless enemies. Once all the mandatory bosses have been defeated, the way will open for the final confrontation of the expansion and a big reveal that not too many expected.</p>
<p>Being a combat-focused action role-playing game experience, enemy design is one of the elements that could have made or broken the Shadow of the Erdtree expansion. Thankfully, FromSoftware did not disappoint in this regard. The new enemies roaming the Shadow Realm are some of the best-designed and most challenging designed by the Japanese studio. Those coming in unprepared will suffer greatly: even the weakest-looking mob can put up quite a fight, and their complex movesets can be a nightmare to deal with, even when using some of the most effective builds that can easily carry players in the base game. The only enemies that are unlikely to give too much trouble to veteran players are recycled enemies from the base game, whose number is balanced out by that of the new enemies.</p>
<p>Bosses, unsurprisingly, are the highlight of the Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree expansion. While the minor, optional bosses are not particularly inspired in terms of movesets nor especially challenging with an appropriately built Tarnished, the Remembrance bosses, those that reward the player with a Remembrance that can be used to unlock new weapons and spells in the Roundtable Hold, on the other hand, are extremely unique, and extremely challenging. The Divine Beast Dancing Lion and Rellana, Twin Moon Knight, the first two Remembrance bosses that most players will fight first, are only the tip of an iceberg that goes very, very deep, although one of the bosses, whose identity I won't mention to avoid spoilers, was definitely a little disappointing, in terms of design. No matter who you are facing, however, expect to die in just a few hits and defeat them by the skin of your teeth.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/20240615143305_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>Thankfully, Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree provides plenty of tools to deal with the difficult challenges it presents, starting with a new progression mechanic, the Shadow Realm Blessing. By using Scadutree Fragments and Revered Spirit Ashes, which can be found in specific locations in the Shadow Realm, it is possible to enjoy improved stats and Spirit Ashes, respectively. These improvements are applied only in the Shadow Realm, so the Tarnished stats will return to normal when traveling back to the Lands Between.</p>
<p>The remainder of the tools the Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree expansion offers are additions to the systems already in place in the base game. There are some rather unique new weapon types, including a new Light Greatsword with a unique moveset, Hand-to-hand gloves that finally make it possible to create a proper monk class Tarnished, Great Katana to expand samurai builds, and throwable weapons. Added to the mix are also new armor sets, a new Talisman that gives access to some very nice perks, such as automatic FP recovery, new Ashes of War that grant new weapon skills, new Spirit Ashes for new summoned companions, new Crystal Tears for use in the Flask of Wondrous Physics (including a new tear that provides access to Spontaneous Guards) and new spells. All of these additions are extremely worthwhile and will make everyone looking to come up with new builds quite happy. On the other hand, those who wish to continue using their base endgame builds will be able to do so effectively for the most part. For example, my Samurai dual katana-wielding, cold/bleed build worked fine for pretty much the entirety of my time in the Shadow Realm, and I only switched things up to try out some new strategies using the new weapons and talismans, and not because I felt I needed to. As the new additions can be brought over to the Lands Between, I expect future New Game Plus playthroughs of the base game to be more interesting than ever before.</p>
<p>Alongside the lack of innovation, which can be an issue for some, where Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree definitely disappoints is in the performance, at least on PC. Nothing has changed over the base game - it still fails to keep a smooth performance most of the time. In a benchmarking session held in the Scadu Altus open-world area, a pretty busy area with plenty of enemies and vegetation, the game ran at an average of 58 frames per second at 4K resolution, max settings, and no ray tracing on my machine (i7-13700F, RTX 4080, 32 GB RAM). Unfortunately, the experience wasn't smooth, as highlighted by the recorded 18 FPS 1% low, with some frame rate drops that did not impact the gameplay in a major way but were still quite noticeable.</p>
<p>Though rare, I also experienced some seconds-long stutters where the game completely froze for an unknown reason, which never happened to me in the base game and on a much weaker system (i7-10700, RTX 3070, 16 GB RAM). In this regard, FromSoftware still has much to do, especially if they will go the open-world route for their next major game.</p>

<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/20240616135050_1-scaled.jpg"></a></figure>

<p>If you have already checked the score I have awarded the Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree expansion, you may be wondering why it deserves such a high score, given how it is, essentially, just more of the same. There are two reasons for this. For starters, the quality of the content included in the expansion is excellent and possibly among the best offered in the entirety of Elden Ring. Everything, from the new, dense Shadow Realm map (which requires well over 40 hours to explore to the fullest) to the Legacy and optional dungeons, is extremely well-designed, with multiple paths and plenty of secrets, making exploration a joy. The real reason Shadow of the Erdtree deserves a perfect score, however, is because it manages to evoke the same sense of wonder the base game offered over a hundred hours later.</p>
<p>The moment I reached the Gravesite Plains, I felt the same way I did when I emerged from the Stranded Graveyard for the first time to see the huge plains of Limgrave ahead of me, the Erdtree shining on the horizon, and the Tree Sentinel roaming about, ready to take down unaware Tarnished, ill-prepared for the challenge it posed. The Erdtree was, of course, replaced by the ominous Scadutree and the Tree Sentinel by the first, fearsome Fire Golem, who, much like the mounted knight of the base game, can make very short work of an unprepared Tarnished.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree 4K PC Gameplay" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8wh9DfG1kjA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>After that, it did not take long to get back into the engaging adventuring loop of the Elden Ring experience, searching for map fragments to get a better look at the map, placing markers where points of interest are seemingly located, and getting amazed by beautiful vistas, immense castles, and sprawling haunting forests, unaware of the dangers that lurked inside of them. With open-world fatigue setting in earlier this year due to the many open-world games released in 2024—like Final Fantasy VII Rebirth, Rise of the Ronin, and the PC versions of Horizon Forbidden West and Ghost of Tsushima—Shadow of the Erdtree's open-world design stands out as a testament to how the Elden Ring experience still surpasses anything else on the market. As such, I believe a perfect score is justified, even with the evident lack of significant innovation and some technical hiccups.</p>
<p><em>PC version tested. Review code provided by the publisher.</em></p>

					
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>


					<div>
	<div>
			
			<p>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree</p>
		</div>
	<header>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree</header>
</div>

<p>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree expands the base game by offering more of what made it one of the best open-world games ever. It features a well-sized map dense with secrets to discover, new masterfully designed dungeons, and introduces new, fun tools to help the Tarnished tackle some of the most challenging enemies in the game's dark and brutal world. While the lack of new gameplay mechanics may disappoint some, don't let this deter you. Shadow of the Erdtree is every bit as good as the base game, and it is an essential purchase for all those who loved FromSoftware's amazing action role-playing game.</p>

<div>
		<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Pros</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>Nicely sized map dense with all sorts of secrets
</li><li>New weapons, talismans, Ashes of War and spells to create more powerful character builds
</li><li>Challenging new enemies and bosses
</li><li>Impressive visual design of the Shadow Realm</li>		</ul>
	</div>
			<div>
		<h6>
			<span>Cons</span>
		</h6>
		<ul>
			<li>Some recycled enemies, including bosses
</li><li>Lack of innovation
</li><li>Performance still isn't the best</li>		</ul>
	</div>
	</div>

					
				</main>
			</article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[McDonald's Drive-Thru AI Is McCanceled]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mcdonalds-drive-thru-ai-failure-tiktok-1851548668</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mcdonalds-drive-thru-ai-is-mccanceled.905817/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/mcdonalds-drive-thru-ai-failure-tiktok-1851548668<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>AI is such big business right now it’s propelled Nvidia, that company that you once knew for making your GeForce graphics cards, to becoming <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cyrr40x0z2mo&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cyrr40x0z2mo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the biggest business in the world</a></span>. And yet the technology is so far next to useless in all but the most specific circumstances. For example, McDonald’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.restaurantbusinessonline.com/technology/mcdonalds-ending-its-drive-thru-ai-test&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.restaurantbusinessonline.com/technology/mcdonalds-ending-its-drive-thru-ai-test" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">has just announced</a></span> it’s abandoning its disastrous experiment with AI, after it turned out people didn’t want bacon on their ice cream.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196923" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="355" data-playlist="196923,196922,196918" data-current="196923"><div><p>Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22494.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The technology, introduced to around 100 McDonald’s stores in 2022, was supposed to be the future of its drive-thrus, where a magical robot would listen to orders and process them, rather than some l0w-tech meat-sack human being. It has, of course, proven far worse, with orders going completely barmy. Now, according to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.restaurantbusinessonline.com/technology/mcdonalds-ending-its-drive-thru-ai-test&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.restaurantbusinessonline.com/technology/mcdonalds-ending-its-drive-thru-ai-test" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a report by <em>Restaurant Business</em></a></span>, the fast food giant is ending the experiment. For now.</p><p>The AI was developed for Ronald and his chums by IBM, but that partnership is now coming to an end, with the AI drive-thrus being removed over the next month. For an example of how successful they were, just look at TikTok:</p><p>And my favorite, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.tiktok.com/@that_usa_guy/video/7122628949061963054?q=mcdonald%27s%20ai&amp;t=1718805748677&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@that_usa_guy/video/7122628949061963054?q=mcdonald%27s%20ai&amp;t=1718805748677" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this guy trying to convince the McBot to not add bacon to his ice cream</a></span>.</p><p>OK, it’s over-simplistic to refer to “AI” as one specific thing, rather than multifarious technologies that all rely on some form of machine learning. There are the god-awful generative AIs that we hear the most about, the industrial-scale plagiarism machines like ChatGPT and Midjourney, but there are also the models being used to massively accelerate drug discovery and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.cancer.gov/news-events/press-releases/2024/ai-tool-matches-cancer-drugs-to-patients&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.cancer.gov/news-events/press-releases/2024/ai-tool-matches-cancer-drugs-to-patients" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cancer treatments</a></span>.</p><p>But it’s fair to say that in the immediate, the vast majority of times we hear about a company “embracing AI,” it loosely translates to “seeing how many people’s jobs we can fuck over for profit.” And of course this is the most likely intention McDonald’s could have had here, given they already had a mostly functioning drive-thru system where humans took the orders.</p><p>Sadly, this isn’t the end of McD’s experiments with AI, as the company insists it’s going to carry on exploring the tech. Plus, you know, all the other chains are trying it too. Anything to stop having to pay those people their minimum wages.</p><p>Although I’ll tell you what, as a Brit, I’m with the AI on this one:</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shadow of the Erdtree is Now the Highest-Rated DLC of All Time]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-highest-rated-dlc-of-all-time/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shadow-of-the-erdtree-is-now-the-highest-rated-dlc-of-all-time.905814/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/shadow-of-the-erdtree-highest-rated-dlc-of-all-time/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>With the reviews pouring in, it’s a moment of pride and excitement for the gaming community as FromSoftware’s highly anticipated Elden Ring expansion, Shadow of the Erdtree, has already soared to the top, becoming the highest-rated DLC of all time. According to Metacritic, Shadow of the Erdtree has secured an impressive <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Metascore of 95</a>, based on 56 critic reviews at the time of writing. </p>



<p>This remarkable achievement is a testament to this expansion’s quality and anticipation. The broader audience can experience this triumph on June 21, 2024, when the user scores start rolling in. The top spot was previously held by The Witcher 3’s DLC, Blood and Wine, with a <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt-blood-and-wine/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Metascore of 92</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>The anticipation and excitement surrounding the Shadow of the Erdtree expansion is palpable, to the extent that even the original author of the Elden Ring manga, Nikiichi Tobita, is taking a break to play the DLC. Tobita recently shared on X (formerly Twitter) that the manga’s latest episode, ‘ELDEN RING’, The Road to the Golden Tree Episode 45, has been updated. He also announced a ‘hiatus’ to fully immerse himself in the Elden Ring DLC. This level of excitement from the manga creators themselves is a testament to the thrill and anticipation that awaits the players.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>The Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree expansion promises an exciting new adventure. In the perilous Land of Shadow, players will delve into fresh mysteries, navigate treacherous dungeons, and confront ruthless enemies. They’ll also be able to wield new weapons and equipment, enhancing their gameplay experience. </p>



<p>The expansion will be available for Xbox Series X/S, PlayStation 5, and PC via Steam, offering a wide range of players the chance to explore this thrilling new world. Before the release, you can find the official system requirements and the additional benefits of the Shadow of the Entree patch here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Do you think Shadow of the Erdtree deserves to become the highest-rated DLC ever? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out what&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-announced-for-september-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">classic Nintendo franchise is getting a new game</a>&nbsp;this year, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creatures of Ava launches August 7]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/creatures-of-ava-launches-august-7</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/creatures-of-ava-launches-august-7.905811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/creatures-of-ava-launches-august-7<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Creature-taming action adventure game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Creature [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/creature">Creature</a>-taming <a title="Genres > Action [1,940 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,577 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Creatures of Ava [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/creatures-of-ava">Creatures of Ava</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,603 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,503 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2304440/Creatures_of_Ava/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/creatures-of-ava-cacd2c" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>, <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/creatures-of-ava/9NV5LTSPHQD2" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/creatures_of_ava" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GOG</a> on August 7, publisher <a title="Companies > 11 bit studios [47 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/11-bit-studios">11 bit studios</a> and developers <a title="Companies > Inverge Studios [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/inverge-studios">Inverge Studios</a> and <a title="Companies > Chibig [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/chibig">Chibig</a> announced. It will also be available via <a title="Platforms > Xbox [24,305 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Game Pass. <span id="more-893933"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via 11 bit studios:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Can you save a life?</p><p>Welcome to <em>Creatures of Ava</em>, a unique creature saver game inviting you to explore a world brimming with wild beings. Instilling joy and wonder, they provide a unique bond that enables you to utilize their skills for traversing the planet and solving environmental challenges. Once peaceful creatures, they now succumb to an unknown infection driving them to behave aggressively, which makes your mission to save them an urgent necessity.</p><p><strong>Exploration-Driven Gameplay</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The gameplay encourages curiosity-driven exploration of its distinct ecosystems—such as the colorful Nari jungle or mysterious Mâruba swamp—creating an interconnected world. With non-aggressive combat mechanics designed for healing rather than defeating and indigenous Flute melodies that you play to tame creatures, the game further highlights the creature-saver nature of the experience.</p><p><strong>Meaningful Narrative</strong></p><p>Step into the shoes of Vic, a 22-year-old nature adventurer as she navigates through the immersive expedition alongside Tabitha, a composed and astute researcher. Together, you confront the recurring infection—called “the withering” by the local race of Naam—threatening Ava’s inhabitants. The game’s narrative, co-created by Rhianna Pratchett, is a journey of wonder and mystery but also discovery, leading to the revelation of the planet’s captivating secrets.</p><p><strong>Saving Through Understanding</strong></p><p><em>Creatures of Ava</em> is a game featuring a dense, populated world of rich ecosystems filled with creatures that play a vital role in the planet’s natural balance. It goes beyond traditional creature-related genres, offering a deeper understanding and connection with the things you’ll encounter on Ava. Once you come to understand the true meaning of the infection, you will be challenged to step out of the human-centric point of view and learn about the real toll it takes to preserve the primal beauty at the very roots of Ava.</p><p>After all, can you save something you don’t understand?</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Creatures of Ava | Date Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BVHr7xL9960?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Singles, not albums': A guide to making smaller games | GI Sprint]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/singles-not-albums-a-guide-to-making-smaller-games-gi-sprint</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/singles-not-albums-a-guide-to-making-smaller-games-gi-sprint.905808/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/singles-not-albums-a-guide-to-making-smaller-games-gi-sprint<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>UK studio Ant Workshop has embarked upon a significant shift in how it makes games, and it's one that managing director Tony Gowland believes could benefit a lot of developers.</p>
<p>The change follows the studio investing two years and approximately £750,000 into Dungeon Golf, a quirky take on mini-golf that Gowland tells us underperformed. Despite a five-figure marketing spend, and positive feedback from players and critics, the game "never managed to quite reach an audience."</p>

<p>Unable to invest further in the game or in any project of a similar size, the studio decided to take inspiration from publishers and their portfolio-centric strategies.</p>
<p>"What we needed to do is get more things out there and do it a bit quicker, a bit smaller, and being a bit more agile," Gowland explains. "Not falling into the trap of developing something for 15 months or whatever it was on Dungeon Golf before we even went public with it."</p>
<p>He discussed the idea with industry veteran and original Grand Theft Auto developer Gary Penn, who summed up Ant Workshop's new approach nicely.</p>
<p>"It's really irritating that he came up with this but it is a great line," Gowland laughs. "He said 'Okay, so if Dungeon Golf is an album, what you're making is singles.' And as soon as he said it, it was like, 'Yes, that's just the absolute perfect encapsulation of what this idea is.'</p>
<p>"We can't afford to make another album, and to be honest, it feels too risky to make another album. So let's bang out a few different things in different genres and different styles. We can afford to be a bit riskier with each individual little one, because you're making stuff on just a much smaller budget and a much smaller timescale, and just trying to get it in front of the audience a lot sooner."</p>
<p>Ant Workshop is attempting to develop games that each have a full budget of £50,000 to £100,000 and can be released after four to six months of work. Other developers have also experimented with shorter titles, such as Bithell Games' narrative shorts Quarantine Circular and Subsurface Circular.</p>
<p>Convinced this approach may be something that benefits other studios, Gowland shared his advice and offered more insight into his studio's strategy for GI Sprint.</p>
<h2>Keep it small, keep it simple</h2>
<p>Firstly, Gowland clarified that the four-to-six-month development time won't necessarily include prototyping, but encouraged developers to nail down a basic concept and mechanics as soon as possible. A large part of this is not designing games that are likely to become too complex.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/tony-gowland.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Tony Gowland, Ant Workshop</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"The key thing with the singles is that they are <em>small</em> games," he explains. "We're not trying so we're not trying to make something that's totally feature-packed. I doubt that we would make an online multiplayer game as any of these, for example, because that's way out of scope.</p>
<p>"It's about not going wild. It's a blessing and a curse – you have to be very disciplined with it, but it does mean that you can really focus down."</p>
<p>He points to an example from Dungeon Golf. The game featured a couple of commentators that would remark on what was happening in-game, apeing televised sports. But on reflection, Gowland and the team questioned whether this offered enough benefit considering the time spent working on them, and says he would have cut this if he were making the game again. Developers should be more brutal about which features are worth devoting development resources and time to, he advises.</p>
<h2>Revisit past ideas (but, again, keep them simple)</h2>
<p>Ant Workshop's first 'single' is Into The Restless Ruins, a roguelike deck builder where you use cards to attach new rooms and expand your dungeon.</p>
<p>This idea actually stemmed from a completely different game: a top-down 2D title where players were in charge of flying a plane. If your mission was to deliver a parcel, you would snap on a parcel delivery element to the plane. If the plane was on fire, you would snap on a hose that would douse the flames. But the central mechanic never quite fit.</p>
<p>"We went over it for certainly two or three weeks of trying to iterate on the plane flying bit, what's working and what's not working, and never quite got that bit feeling nice," Gowland explains. "But the bit where you're snapping new things onto your plane and then running around felt so good that the coder just put in a debug button where you could just keep generating new bits and keep snapping them on. It felt so satisfying to do that."</p>
<p>Ant Workshop decided to ditch the flying concept and focus on expanding the plane with new elements. This became the dungeon-building core of Into The Restless Ruins, something Gowland says "came together quite quickly."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/restless-ruins.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Into The Restless Ruins was built upon a mechanic from an abandoned game</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>Build something with legs</h2>
<p>Smaller games do not have to be one-and-done affairs. Gowland encourages developers to think about replayability, but also 'expandability.' The idea of making singles is not to shun albums entirely, but to find the basis of what a future album might be.</p>
<p>"Every idea we're coming at has to be something that is extendable, something where we can rein the scope in for an initial launch and sell for a cheap price," he says. "And if that game finds an audience, that's great. We can keep making updates for this, we could do free content updates or DLC, or we could expand it for a sequel and that kind of thing."</p>
<h2>Make your studio more flexible</h2>
<p>Like many studios, Ant Workshop also works on co-development projects alongside its own games, but the scope of the latter can affect its ability to handle the former. During work on Dungeon Golf, taking on a co-dev project would have potentially thrown off the schedule as devoting a few coders to external work would have delayed development.</p>
<p>"But when you're working on much smaller things, if a couple of coders are needed for some other project for two months, that's fine, we have plenty of other things that we're working on," he says. "People can just adjust their time and shift around and deal with it that way. It's given us a lot more flexibility."</p>
<p>Gowland also says developers should not be afraid to pause work on one of their 'singles' if it's not quite coming together yet. For instance, one of the titles Ant Workshop is working on centres around "a street food van for monsters," where you serve customers as fast as you can.</p>
<p>"We've made an initial version of that," Gowland says. "The idea is good but it's not quite working. If you're working on this as a bigger thing, you would be like, 'Well, we've got artists that are making things, we've got coders, there's a machine that needs feeding here, and we need to just sit down and crunch through what's going wrong and try different things.' But because we have so many different 'singles' on the go at once, we'll just park that one for a little bit and then come back to it when we have an idea of what to do with it."</p>
<h2>Tell people what you're working on</h2>
<p>A crucial element of knowing which smaller games you should be devoting more time to is getting player feedback. This, Gowland says, was a key element in Dungeon Golf's failure as the studio kept it under its belt "way too long."</p>
<blockquote><p>"You have to be very disciplined with [singles], but it does mean that you can really focus"</p></blockquote>
<p>"With previous games like Dead End Job, we've taken it out to little local events and shows, or even EGX Rezzed,"  he explains. "[With Dungeon Golf], we'd just gotten a little bit too much in our own heads of 'OK, we'll keep working on it until <em>we </em>think it's ready to show people.' That point of feeling it's ready to show people just stretched on and on and on, and ultimately, unfortunately, it just never managed to find a market – and I'm not sure that the size of the market that it would have needed actually exists for the type of game that it is."</p>
<p>Showing your game earlier gives you a better sense of the potential audience it might reach, as well as building up anticipation and those all-important wishlists.</p>
<h2>Smaller games lend themselves to smaller price points</h2>
<p>Ant Workshop is currently planning to charge a maximum of £5 for each of its 'singles', something Gowland believes makes them more of an "impulse purchase," similar to gamers' propensity for snapping up cheaper titles in Steam sales. He likens it to his childhood of taking his pocket money to the market each week and seeing which Acorn Electron titles he could afford..</p>
<p>"Sometimes you get things that are absolutely incredible and that's great, and sometimes you get things that were absolutely rubbish – but it's a cheap thing. You are taking a punt on a sort of pocket money-based thing. We've seen plenty of games now coming out on Steam that are decent quality, well-made things, and people are launching them for £4 or £5."</p>
<p>He adds that lower price points also keep player expectations in check.</p>
<p>"With things being cheaper, there's less expectation of super high-quality art fidelity and that kind of thing – look at something like Vampire Survivors," he says. "As long as you're quite clear to people. You need to be able to go, 'Look, we're not developing a full, massive thing, but it is a little thing that you could enjoy and has a lot of replayability'."</p>
<h2>Re-evaluate your metrics for success</h2>
<p>Gowland asserts that the break-even point for games scales up and down at a similar rate to the budget. He estimates that Ant Workshop would ideally need to be able to sell 20,000 units of its 'singles' for them to break even.</p>
<p>Again, the price point comes into play here; while it's no easy thing to sell 20,000 units, it's less challenging to do so at an impulse price than "at a price where people are waiting for it to go on sale on Steam instead."</p>
<p>And Gowland emphasises his original point about this being similar to how publishers handle their portfolios.</p>
<p>"We're not expecting every one of these to break even and cover themselves. A quarter of them might, maybe less than that, but as they each make something. We'll also get a lot of information and feedback from actual real players.</p>
<p>"Because you're making a much smaller bet on each individual one, you can afford to spread that and figure things out. I expect that, even into the second year of doing this, we'll start to get a lot more refined. We can go, 'This was popular so we can how about we try taking those bits and making something out of them and then see what happens with that?'"</p>
<section><p><em>Gowland will also appear on tomorrow's GI Sprint panel about the art of failing fast, another vital element of making games cheaper, faster and better.</em></p></section>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cat Rescue Story Lets You Run Your Very Own Cat Shelter in September]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cat-rescue-story-release-date-september</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cat-rescue-story-lets-you-run-your-very-own-cat-shelter-in-september.905793/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cat-rescue-story-release-date-september<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nacon and Tivola have announced&nbsp;<em>Cat Rescue Story</em>, a cat shelter sim that lets you start and run your very own center for adorable stray kitties.</p>
<p>Launching on September 26th,&nbsp;<em>Cat Rescue Story&nbsp;</em>originated on mobile devices, but it's now making the leap to PC and consoles, so if you haven't had the chance to get to know the game's cuddly cats, you soon will.</p>
<p>Unlike other pet sims, you won't just be hanging out and playing with cats in&nbsp;<em>Cat Rescue Story</em>. Rather, as the name implies, you'll be taking strays in off the street, caring for them until they're ready to leave, and then finding an adoptive family for them.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/cat-rescue-story-release-date-washing.jpg?itok=QDngjgdT 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/cat-rescue-story-release-date-washing.jpg?itok=Tr8u96hC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Cat Rescue Story&nbsp;</em>looks perfect for all the cat lovers out there, myself included.</figcaption></figure><p>Nacon is promising a "child-friendly" and "endearing" story for&nbsp;<em>Cat Rescue Story</em>, in which you'll get the chance to meet over 50 breeds of cat, each of which will have their own needs and personality quirks.</p>
<p>You'll also get the chance to engage with various minigames that will give you the chance to unlock new rooms and customization options for your cat rescue center.</p>
<p>The debut trailer for&nbsp;<em>Cat Rescue Story&nbsp;</em>shows various ways in which you can interact with your cats as well, including grooming, helping to deal with and dress wounds, and play.&nbsp;</p>
<p>You can check out that trailer here if you want to get a sense of the kind of gentle management sim gameplay&nbsp;<em>Cat Rescue Story&nbsp;</em>looks like it's going for.</p>

<p>Your duties will also include buying supplies for your cats (and, of course, making sure to get the good treats, because they won't eat anything else), decorating your center, and even playing as your cats in certain minigames.</p>
<p>Between this, <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/little-kitty-big-city-players-sales">cozy exploration game&nbsp;<em>Little Kitty, Big City</em></a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/stray-review">weird cyberpunk adventure&nbsp;<em>Stray</em></a>, it's fair to say cat fans are eating well right now when it comes to video games.</p>
<p><em>Cat Rescue Story&nbsp;</em>launches for PC, PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo Switch on September 26th. Hopefully, this isn't the last cat rescue center management sim we get to play.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4 great games I played at Summer Game Fest 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/19/24180304/summer-game-fest-2024-best-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/4-great-games-i-played-at-summer-game-fest-2024.905790/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/19/24180304/summer-game-fest-2024-best-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><p>With <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24170561/summer-game-fest-2024-trailers-news-geoff-keighley">Summer Game Fest</a> over, it’s time to take a look back at some of the stand-out hits of the show. I don’t mean the most exciting reveals, but the best games I actually got to play. The SGF space was full of interesting games, some from high-profile studios and others from indie outfits. And there were some games that were surprisingly fun that I only discovered by just picking up a controller and playing.</p><p><h4><em>Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess</em></h4></p><p>Though I’ve seen trailers for Capcom’s sumptuous-looking game, I was never quite sure what it was about. I thought it was a generic hack-and-slash game dressed up in the richness of Japanese mythology, but&nbsp;I was surprised and frankly delighted to discover it’s a tower defense game. Your job is to protect a shrine maiden as she works to purge corruption from the land. Gameplay is divided into two sections: day and night. In the daytime, you go through a village rescuing inhabitants from the corrupting infection. At night, you protect the shrine maiden from demons as she slowly works her way through the village purging it of evil.&nbsp;</p><p>I really enjoyed <em>Kunitsu-Gami</em>’s novel twist on the genre. The villagers you rescue become part of your army, and you assign them jobs to assist in the maiden’s defense. The woodcutter is a powerful melee attacker that works as your first line of offense, while the monk uses their holy power to freeze demons in place, making them easy targets. Once the fight is over, there’s a base-building element that has you upgrading and unlocking jobs and acquiring new powers for your warrior.&nbsp;</p><p>I’m really glad I took a chance to play <em>Kunitsu-Gami</em>. I love strategy-type games, especially when they’re dressed in such a richly ornate art style. I found myself staring at everyone’s clothing, looking at the details, and wondering what significance each little piece had. It releases July 19th on Xbox, PlayStation, and PC.</p><p><h4><em>Star Wars Outlaws</em></h4></p><p>I’m not a <em>Star Wars</em> person — but <em>Star Wars Outlaws</em> was enough to intrigue my Force-agnostic ass. My hands-on was divided into three chunks: ship-to-ship combat, stealth combat, and platforming. Since the children (i.e., me) yearn for <em>Ace Combat</em> (<a href="https://x.com/BandaiNamcoUS/status/1803080642080473426">Thanks, Bandai Namco</a>!), I decided to try the ship first. Before setting off, I had to do a little stealth section to get to my ship that involved a couple of hacking mini-games. Usually, hacking mini-games are tedious and terrible (looking at you, <em>Mass Effect</em>), but I enjoyed both of them, especially the data spike mini-game that involves turning a tumbler in time with rhythmic clicks.&nbsp;</p><p>Once in space, I had a great time. The controls were very responsive, and I didn’t feel like I had to fight to keep my target in front of me like in other aerial combat games. I also enjoyed how the game doesn’t automatically reorient you if you turn the ship upside down, because it’s space, and there is no up or down. Toward the end of the demo, there was a moment where I flew down from space to the surface of a planet, and it all looked very seamless, a true “you can go anywhere” moment (even though I’m sure there’s some game developer trickery involved).</p><p>For the stealth mission, I wasn’t very stealthy, frequently blowing up an enemy instead of distracting them with Nix, my pet axolotl-looking thing. It turns out Nix is very useful as a distraction and a retriever. You can have it fetch the guns your enemies have dropped for when you need a bit of extra firepower. Your main weapon is a simple blaster equipped with special ammo; the default blaster setting takes out humanoid enemies, while the plasma setting is effective on droids. During one encounter involving a shallow water feature, I thought it’d be clever to shoot the water with plasma in hopes of electrocuting the enemies standing in it. Unfortunately, the game didn’t work that way.</p><p>The platforming section was the weakest bit because it didn’t really do much new. There’s a grappling hook to make use of, but other than that, my scoundrel Kay Vess simply runs, jumps, and climbs up bright yellow grates and ledges like anyone else. Overall, I was once again pleasantly surprised. <em>Star Wars Outlaws</em> launches on Xbox, PlayStation, and PC on August 30th.</p><p><h4><em>Arranger: A Role Puzzling Adventure</em></h4></p><p><em>Arranger</em> is a puzzle game well-suited for mobile, which might explain why it was prominently featured in the Netflix booth. You play as a messy girl named Jemma who has a quirky way of moving through the world. As you slide your finger up and down or side to side, the world moves with her, either horizontally or vertically, moving everything on that axis along with her. You use that unique movement to solve puzzles or get around impassable obstacles. To Jemma, a locked door means nothing: she can warp to the other side once she reaches the end of a row or column.</p><p>One thing I appreciate about games is how you are always in conversation with the developers; I enjoy when I’m able to hear their voice in the way they design their games. There was a moment early on when I couldn’t figure out how to solve a pressure plate puzzle. Confused, I left the room only to find two strategically-placed planters. I didn’t yet know you could bring objects from room to room, so upon seeing the planters, I had this very obvious (and audible) “Aha!” moment. The developers could have left a planter or other object in the room with me to make the puzzle easier, but I would have missed out on deepening my understanding of the game’s mechanics.</p><p><em>Arranger</em> comes out on Switch, PlayStation, PC, and mobile via Netflix on July 25th.</p><p><h4><em>Astro Bot</em></h4></p><p>Playing <em>Astro Bot </em>was joyful. I, of course, enjoyed all the games I’ve highlighted here, but <em>Astro Bot</em> was the one that had me giggling and kicking my feet like a 10-year-old given free rein of a candy store. A mascot platformer, in the year 2024… we might be back, y’all! Astro jumps, kicks off walls, and can hover in the air evoking the feeling of Mario. But even though the game is mechanically similar, <em>Astro Bot</em> feels uniquely charming. Astro squeaks, squeals, cheers, and waves — his enthusiasm and happiness are so infectious that it’s impossible not to hurt your face grinning as you play.</p><p>Strewn throughout bright and cheery levels are robots to rescue, some representing characters from PlayStation’s past. I thoroughly loved panning the camera looking for places off the beaten path and figuring out the best way to get there. I was rewarded every time with a collectible or a secret bot in need of rescue. The different levels also contain different movement abilities akin to the special powerups you might find in Mario. One ability that inflates Astro like a balloon, allowing him to float to out-of-reach areas. Another involves a dog that acts like a jet engine that rockets Astro through tough glass or bounces him off special platforms.</p><p><em>Astro Bot</em>, on sheer charm alone, is my game of the show. It launches September 6th on PS5.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All-Time Classic TimeSplitters Looking Likely For PS4, PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/timesplitters-playstation-ps4-ps5-classics-catalog-1851548513</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-time-classic-timesplitters-looking-likely-for-ps4-ps5.905787/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/timesplitters-playstation-ps4-ps5-classics-catalog-1851548513<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If you wanna know what games are coming up next on PlayStation, you just need to ask the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamerating.org.tw/Search/GameList&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamerating.org.tw/Search/GameList" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Taiwanese ratings board</a></span>. That’s <em>Gemastu</em>’s brilliant trick, that allowed the site to <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-xbox-game-pass-ps4-ps5-1851520559&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-xbox-game-pass-ps4-ps5-1851520559">correctly predict</a></span> the arrival of <em>Octopath Traveler</em> last week, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/gematsu/status/1803186507974377868&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/gematsu/status/1803186507974377868" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">now suggests</a></span> subscribers to PlayStation Plus are about to finally be reunited with <em>TimeSplitters</em>.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196917" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Halo’s Joseph Morgan On The Joys Of Halo Co-Op" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="96" data-playlist="196917,195840,196049" data-current="196917"><div><p>Halo’s Joseph Morgan On The Joys Of Halo Co-Op</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196917/196917_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196917/196917_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196917/196917_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196917/196917_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22473.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The PlayStation Plus Classics Catalog really seems to have sprung to life over the last month. In the middle of June <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/playstation-2-classics-ps4-ps5-tomb-raider-star-wars-1851503467&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/playstation-2-classics-ps4-ps5-tomb-raider-star-wars-1851503467">we saw the arrival of</a></span> <em>Tomb Raider Legend</em>, <em>Star Wars: The Clone Wars</em>, and <em>Sly Cooper and the Thievius Racoonus</em>. Now it appears the original <em>TimeSplitters </em>will soon be joining them, with ratings issued for both PS4 and PS5.</p><p>(<em>Gematsu</em> accidentally used a cover shot of threequel, <em>TimeSplitters: Future Perfect</em>.)</p><p>  <strong>Read More: </strong><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-xbox-game-pass-ps4-ps5-1851520559&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/octopath-traveler-xbox-game-pass-ps4-ps5-1851520559">Beloved Square Enix RPG Series <em>Octopath Traveler </em>Is Now On Game Pass, PlayStation</a></span></p><p>The classic PS2 launch game, <em>TimeSplitters</em>, was originally released in 2000, created by the brand new studio Free Radical Design, formed by key figures from studio Rare. These were the people who had worked on <em>GoldenEye</em> and <em>Perfect Dark</em>, aiming to recreate that magic once more—and in a twist, they succeeded. The century-spanning, multi-protagonist shooter was immediately loved, going on to spawn two more equally adored sequels, with a fourth in development, before everything started going wrong for Free Radical.</p><p>In 2008, the company went bankrupt, following the flop of <em>Haze</em>, and the sudden cancellation of <em>Star Wars: Battlefront III</em>, despite claims it was almost finished. It was bought by Crytek in 2009, but that was a complete disaster, and in 2014 the whole place broke apart. This all left the <em>TimeSplitters</em> franchise owned by Deep Silver, which in 2018 inevitably became part of Embracer Group.</p><p>So you’ll never guess what happened next: Embracer brought Free Radical back into existence in 2021, including original developers, with the goal of making a new <em>TimeSplitters </em>game, before fucking up the entire situation as only Embracer can. “Restructuring” saw the company closed down two years later, and <em>TimeSplitters 4</em> thrown, once again, into limbo.<br></p><p>So while a new game seems to be cursed for all eternity, at least there’s soon to be a much easier way of playing the beloved original on your PS4 or PS5.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty’s Fallout Crossover Dresses Price, Ghost, Soap, and Gaz in Vault Dweller Skins]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-dutys-fallout-crossover-dresses-price-ghost-soap-and-gaz-in-vault-dweller-skins</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty%E2%80%99s-fallout-crossover-dresses-price-ghost-soap-and-gaz-in-vault-dweller-skins.905784/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-dutys-fallout-crossover-dresses-price-ghost-soap-and-gaz-in-vault-dweller-skins<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Activision has detailed Call of Duty’s Fallout crossover and confirmed a release date of June 20, 2024.</p><p>The fusion of both Microsoft-owned franchises sees Price, Ghost, Soap, and Gaz of Task Force 141 dressed in Vault Dweller skins. There are Vault-Tec-themed weapon blueprints and other Fallout-themed items for use in <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-iii-2023">Modern Warfare 3</a>, <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone">Warzone</a>, and <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-warzone-mobile">Warzone Mobile</a>.</p><p>The in-game Fallout: Vault Dwellers event goes live at 10am PT on June 20 through to 8am PT June 26. The Tracer Pack: Fallout Vault Dweller Bundle includes two Fallout-themed weapon blueprints featuring Vault-Tec Tracers and a V.A.T.S. Death Effect.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/19/mwiii-fallout-002-1718802376433.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: Activision Publishing.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Here are the details, per the <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/06/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-iii-warzone-wzm-fallout-141-bundle" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Call of Duty blog</a>: </p><blockquote>Equip the “Vault-Tec Approved” M16 Weapon Blueprint with two Aftermarket Parts: the JAK Cutthroat Stock offering an unrivaled combination of speed and stability while aiming down sights, plus the JAK Patriot Conversion Kit which transforms the M16 into a fully automatic rifle with superior recoil control and firing aim stability. </blockquote><blockquote>Accompanied by a 45 Round Mag plus two attachments improving handling and recoil control, this is the ideal weapon for lasering down foes from a distance.</blockquote><blockquote>For closer fights, opt for the “Atomic Disintegrator” HRM-9 Weapon Blueprint geared for sustained combat in close quarters. With a 50 Round Drum Magazine plus thermal target identification, improved accuracy and recoil control, and extended range, this SMG configuration is ideal for aiming down sights with the ability to compete out to the mid-range.</blockquote><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/19/mwiii-fallout-001-1718802342360.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: Activision Publishing.</figcaption></figure></output><p>The Fallout Bundle also features a “Vault 141” Operator Skin for Price, Ghost, Soap, and Gaz plus six loading screens and more. The full list of included content is as follows:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Four “Vault 141” Operator Skins</li><li>“Atomic Disintegrator” HRM-9 Weapon Blueprin</li><li>“Vault-Tec Approved” M16 Weapon Blueprint</li><li>“Let’s Do This!” and “Fatman” Charms</li><li>“Wasteland Workshop” Calling Card</li><li>“You’re Special” Large Decal</li><li>“Vault-Tec Engineer” Emblem</li><li>“Nuka-Cola Spacer” Sticker</li><li>Six Loading Screens including “Nuka-Cola,” “Please Stand By,” “Survivors’ Journey,” “Sanctuary Hills,” “Vault 141,” and “Restoring Democracy”</li></ul><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/19/mwiii-fallout-003-1718802418511.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: Activision Publishing.</figcaption></figure></output><p>The Fallout: Vault Dwellers Event, meanwhile, features challenges across Multiplayer, Zombies, and Warzone. Here are the details:</p><blockquote>Use any of the Vault Dweller Skins during the Vault Dwellers Event for an additional XP boost. Earn additional Fallout-themed cosmetic items like the “New California Republic” Large Decal, “Nuka-Cola Caps” Emblem, “Slocum’s Joe” Sticker, “Nuka-Cola” Charm, and the “Nuka-Cola Quantum” Weapon Camo.</blockquote><p>Activision has gone big on crossover events in Call of Duty in recent years, with everything from Warhammer 40,000 to Gundam seeing in-game skins and weapons. The Fallout bundle comes hot on the heels of the breakout success of Amazon Prime’s Fallout TV show, which has boosted interest in everything related to the post-apocalyptic setting.</p><p>This Fallout crossover as well as the recent Gundam event were unearthed in a May datamine, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-dataminers-unearth-evidence-of-fallout-gundam-and-the-crow-crossovers-for-modern-warfare-3-season-4">which also found evidence to suggest The Crow content is on its way</a>. This is clearly designed to coincide with the upcoming <a href="https://www.ign.com/movies/the-crow-2024"><u>The Crow movie</u></a> starring Bill Skarsgard.</p><p>Modern Warfare 3 continues to receive updates as Activision prepares to launch <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Black Ops 6</a> in October. Activision is expected to move on from last year's shooter to focus on new seasons for Black Ops 6 and Warzone later this year.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tales of the Shire Is the Hobbit Game the Cozy Genre Was Always Meant to Have]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/tales-of-the-shire-is-the-hobbit-game-the-cozy-genre-was-always-meant-to-have</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tales-of-the-shire-is-the-hobbit-game-the-cozy-genre-was-always-meant-to-have.905781/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/tales-of-the-shire-is-the-hobbit-game-the-cozy-genre-was-always-meant-to-have<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>If your favorite part of The Hobbit and The Lord of the Rings books or movies is the time spent in the Shire – the lush, verdant, and hilly home of the habitually hungry halflings who live in holes (albeit well-decorated ones) known as Hobbits  – then I’ve got good news for you: Tales of the Shire might make you very happy, regardless of whether or not you already play and enjoy the cozy genre. I played an all-too-brief 20 minutes or so, split across two save files: one from the beginning of the game (post-character creator) and another from around halfway through. My takeaway after that time was exactly what I was hoping for heading into the hands-on: that Tales of the Shire is shaping up to be a relaxing, no-pressure, no-drama escape into the Hobbit hillside where your biggest worry is getting a new recipe just right so you can make a new friend in town.</p><p>First, I love the art style in Tales of the Shire. It’s bright, sunny, and overall just pleasant, as it should be. The village feels big without being overwhelming or annoying to navigate. On that note, I adore the designers’ twist on the compass or arrow pointing you in the direction of your current objective that so many games use (or, to compare it to another charming fantasy game, the golden breadcrumb trail in Fable): here, when you’ve marked a destination on your map, adorable birds will land on fence posts or tree branches ahead of you every 50 feet or so, literally pointing with their beaks in the direction you’re supposed to go. It’s a great unintrusive touch that keeps you looking at the beautiful game world rather than constantly pulling up the map. Music, too, is as mellow and delightful as you’d expect.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Tales of the Shire - June 2024 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>I saw the basics of the cozy gameplay mechanics during my demo: cooking, building relationships with your fellow Hobbits, as well as both interior design and landscape architecture. The latter two are the most simple, mechanically speaking, but also allow you to most customize your Hobbit home. Outside, I picked up a watering can from the garden, refilled it in the adjacent stream (which, by the way, you can also fish out of in other locations like off of a bridge), and then set about watering the plentiful amount of vegetables in my garden. (This, I should add, was the mid-game save that already had a rather impressive garden planted and thriving). From there you can, if you choose, rearrange the placement of your plant beds however you see fit. So if you want to have a nice unspoiled lawn on one side of your Hobbit hole and cram all of your plants into a dense garden on the other, go for it. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It's a zero-stakes, relaxing time spent in the Shire.</p></div><p>Inside the house, meanwhile, you can do the same micromanage-y levels of home decoration. You can move rugs, tables, chairs – anything that isn’t part of the foundation, really. Although even there, you’ve got options. You can choose the style of your walls, from wood patterns to wallpaper. But it goes deeper than that: you can even rearrange individual pieces of fruit on tables and individual books on your bookshelf. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>As for cooking, that’s where the most gameplay I saw factored in. Hobbits love to eat, of course, so the best way to make new friends and improve your relationships with Hobbits you already know is to cook a meal for them. That first involves getting new recipes – after you’ve received an invitation in the mail for the meal, that is; effectively it’s how you get quests – then gathering all of the correct ingredients, and finally bringing everything together in the kitchen. You can choose how chunky or smooth you cut some things by pressing ‘A’ a certain number of times. A more complicated cooking moment I experienced involved adding just the right amount of salt in order to spice the recipe just right, indicated by a plotted point on a small chart in the corner of the interface. </p><p>All in all, Tales of the Shire was exactly what I was hoping it would be: a zero-stakes, relaxing time spent in the Shire. This game is set after The Hobbit but before The Lord of the Rings, so the Scouring of the Shire is still far, far away. But hopefully, Tales’s release is much closer in 2024.</p><p><em>Ryan McCaffrey is IGN's executive editor of previews and host of both IGN's weekly Xbox show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/watch/unlocked">Podcast Unlocked</a><em>, as well as our monthly(-ish) interview show, </em><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/04/ign-unfiltered-every-episode-ever">IGN Unfiltered</a><em>. He's a North Jersey guy, so it's "Taylor ham," not "pork roll." Debate it with him on Twitter at </em><a href="https://twitter.com/DMC_Ryan" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@DMC_Ryan</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hollow Knight Fans Crushed as Summer Showcases Pass With No Silksong Announcement]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-fans-crushed-as-summer-showcases-pass-with-no-silksong-announcement</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hollow-knight-fans-crushed-as-summer-showcases-pass-with-no-silksong-announcement.905778/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-fans-crushed-as-summer-showcases-pass-with-no-silksong-announcement<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Hollow Knight fans were left with an all-too familiar feeling of dismay after 2024's E3-esque video game summer showcases came and went with no word on sequel Silksong.</p><p>Fans of the franchise took to social media to share their disappointment after <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-direct-june-2024-everything-announced">the June Nintendo Direct</a>, which premiered yesterday, June 18, had announcements for <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-direct-june-2024-opens-with-mario-luigi-brothership">Mario</a>, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-announced-for-nintendo-switch-with-zelda-as-protagonist">Zelda</a>, and even <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-prime-4-gameplay-revealed">long-missing game Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> — but no Hollow Knight: Silksong.</p><p>"All the major summer showcases have now aired, and we still haven't heard anything new from Silksong," wrote ResetEra user <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/so-silksong-was-a-no-show-again.905331/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cvbas</a> in a post with more than 10,000 clicks. "What gives?" Fans in the comments admitted to growing concerned for the game, which hasn't received any official updates in over a year when <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-team-cherry-release-date-update">developer Team Cherry delayed it out of early 2023</a>.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/06/19/screenshot-2024-06-19-130046-1718799162932.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: rookideperdido on Reddit.</figcaption></figure></output><p>"I obviously want them to cook as hard and as long as possible, but I think some communication is still necessary," said SirKai. "At this point I just feel bad for the guys at Team Cherry. It has to be tough to have this insane amount of expectations on your shoulders," added Greywaren.</p><p>"We got Prime 4 before Silksong," complained a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HollowKnight/comments/1disfj8/fk_silksong/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reddit</a> user, referencing the aforementioned Metroid game which was essentially missing for seven years. Another <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HollowKnight/comments/1dik7q6/2_years/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted</a> a quote from Team Cherry in May 2022, after Silksong won the "Most Anticipated Game Award from Unity. "It can't be too much longer, surely," the developer said.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Just dropped my Hornet statue it's a rough day for Silk Song copers <a href="https://t.co/c3sih6joLO" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/c3sih6joLO</a></p>— Andy Cortez (didn't pay) (@TheAndyCortez) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheAndyCortez/status/1803098704045568276?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/5-years-after-it-was-announced-hollow-knight-silksong-is-still-one-of-the-most-anticipated-games-around">Silksong was announced on February 14, 2019</a> as a Hollow Knight expansion turned full sequel focused on Hornet from the original game. "Almost from the very start, Hornet’s adventure was intended to take place in a new land, but as we dove in, it quickly became too large and too unique to stay a DLC, as initially planned," <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/02/14/hollow-knight-sequel-announced-for-pc-and-nintendo-switch">Team Cherry said at the time</a>. "We do know that makes the wait a little longer, but we think the final, fresh world you’ll get to explore is worth it."</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Hollow Knight Silksong isn’t a real game. We collectively hallucinated it.</p>— Tamoor Hussain (@tamoorh) <a href="https://twitter.com/tamoorh/status/1803075999871164725?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We got Metroid Prime 4 before Silksong 👏</p>— Daily Silksong News (@DailySilksong) <a href="https://twitter.com/DailySilksong/status/1803075838113407334?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>The developer then went quiet for two years, only emerging in 2021 to announce <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dont-expect-hollow-knight-silksong-news-at-e3-2021">it wouldn't have anything to say about Silksong at E3 that year</a>, perhaps inadvertently setting the expectation that fans should expect news unless Team Cherry says otherwise.</p><p>Another year passed and Silksong finally reared its head, as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-silksong-trailer">the Xbox &amp; Bethesda Games Showcase of 2022</a> revealed the game would be coming to Microsoft's console and Game Pass on day one. Further hope was inspired as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/hollow-knight-release-window-next-12-months">Xbox had said everything shown at the event would be released within a year</a>. That, obviously, did not happen.</p><p>The last time Team Cherry issued an update on Silksong was in February this year, when the studio's PR and marketing chief Matthew 'Leth' Griffin posted a brief comment to say it was still "hard at work on the game."</p><p>Thoughts now turn to upcoming showcases and the potential for an appearance in August at Gamescom, where Microsoft may host an Xbox event.</p><p><em>Image Credit: </em><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Silksong/comments/1diszdt/when_its_the_next_major_game_event/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>rookideperdido on Reddit</em></a></p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Evercade announce two new arcade collections to coincide with new console]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/19/evercade-announce-two-new-arcade-collections-to-coincide-with-new-console/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/evercade-announce-two-new-arcade-collections-to-coincide-with-new-console.905763/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/19/evercade-announce-two-new-arcade-collections-to-coincide-with-new-console/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Evercade have been doing great things with retro gaming for the past few years, and that march looks set to continue, with today’s announcement of the Toaplan Arcade 3 and the Data East Arcade 2 collections. They’re set to launch in September this year, alongside the all-new Evercade Alpha, a bartop arcade system that’s compatible with all the previous Evercade cartridges.</p>
<p>The Toaplan Arcade brings even more great arcade action to Evercade with a total of seven awesome titles from the more recent history of the legendary Japanese developer. The lineup includes fan-favourites Batsugun and Out Zone, as well as Batsugun Special Version, Truxton II, and more great cuts from the vaults of Toaplan.</p>
<p><iframe title="Evercade - Toaplan Arcade 3 - Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ealOG2Sq0KM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Data East Arcade 2 sees one of Evercade’s original license partners return to the system. The large selection of genres available from Data East makes it a perfect starter for new fans and a great dive into cult arcade classics for existing fans with early releases like Shoot Out and Express Raider alongside Super BurgerTime, B-Wings, Midnight Resistance and the fan favourite Joe &amp; Mac Returns. There are 12 games in total on this collection.</p>

<p>Evercade began life as a handheld system, and it was one that we were very taken with when we <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/04/19/evercade-premium-pack-review/">reviewed it back in 2021</a>. Its party trick was that you could plug it into the TV via mini-HDMI, and it has subsequently collected some of the most well-known retro titles from creators including the likes of Atari, Namco and Interplay. That was then followed by the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/04/23/the-evercade-vs-is-a-new-retro-loving-home-console-with-a-perfect-price/">Evercade VS</a>, a home console version with two cartridge slots, before a hugely revised handheld, the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/05/31/evercade-exp-is-a-brand-new-retro-infused-handheld-coming-this-winter/">Evercade EXP</a> arrived. Recently they’ve started to manufacture larger-capacity cartridges, with an original Tomb Raider collection the first to arrive.</p>
<p><iframe title="Evercade - Data East Arcade 2 - Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZaFZsnVUSTw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Both collections are due for release in November 2024 at the same time as the new Evercade Alpha bartop arcade system. <a href="https://evercade.co.uk/?utm_source=Evercade%20Press&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=ToaDat%20Arcade%20PR%20%2801J0QYXG3K2PKPHYP17T5BRZBE%29&amp;id=01F603VJMJC53NT7WTKW8FKCY1&amp;_kx=XJkKkkWhrQeHTjIxtzVFyBaKcLnlRfoLbEWUNpz0RBRCJxkDauI2EOtlSp55FlrL.RYVpED">They’re available to pre-order from September 26th, 2024 from all Evercade retailers</a>. These collections are in the new purple spine colour to show that they’re arcade collections and if you’re collecting the full set they’re numbered cartridges 11 and 12.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Life by You Creators Tried "Everything" to Avoid Cancellation]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/life-by-you-dev-cancellation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/life-by-you-creators-tried-everything-to-avoid-cancellation.905760/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/life-by-you-dev-cancellation<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A former&nbsp;<em>Life by You&nbsp;</em>developer has spoken out about his experiences working on the now-canceled life sim, which he says was "a strong project ready to launch to a strong audience".</p>
<p>Speaking <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7208887303224606720/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">on LinkedIn</a>, designer Willem Delventhal shared his thoughts about the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/life-by-you-paradoxs-sims-competitor-has-been-cancelled">seemingly sudden cancellation</a> of&nbsp;<em>Life by You</em>. He also says he was "warned against writing anything" about it on the grounds that doing so may hurt his career or even invite legal action.</p>
<p>According to Delventhal,&nbsp;<em>Life by You&nbsp;</em>was doing "extremely well", having exceeded an important "internal metric" significantly, as well as receiving a "thumbs up a few weeks before launch".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/life-by-you-dev-comments-kitchen.jpg?itok=ui1qzYGe 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/life-by-you-dev-comments-kitchen.jpg?itok=WHIME0yO 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Life by You&nbsp;</em>sounds like it was doing pretty well before it was canned.</figcaption></figure><p>Delventhal goes on to say that despite these encouraging signs, Paradox Tectonic was then told "two weeks before launch" that the game wouldn't be launching after all.</p>
<p>The team then found out the studio would be closing and that they would all lose their jobs "via a public announcement", so it sounds like there was no internal heads-up before Paradox <a href="https://www.paradoxinteractive.com/media/press-releases/press-release/paradox-interactive-to-close-down-paradox-tectonic" rel="noopener" target="_blank">posted about Tectonic's closure yesterday</a>.</p>
<p>According to Delventhal, no reason was given to him or his team regarding&nbsp;<em>Life by You</em>'s closure; instead, he says the devs "spent a month in purgatory", trying everything from finding potential new buyers to "going indie" in order to save&nbsp;<em>Life by You</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/life-by-you-dev-comments-conversation.jpg?itok=CdBum-dS 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/life-by-you-dev-comments-conversation.jpg?itok=K3qB1xO6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Paradox's&nbsp;<em>Life by You</em>&nbsp;was set to join the sparse field of The Sims&nbsp;competitors.</figcaption></figure><p>Rather cryptically, Delventhal says he has "guesses" about what happened to&nbsp;<em>Life by You&nbsp;</em>behind the scenes, and that while "some of them are understandable", many aren't.</p>
<p>He closes by saying he's "pretty pissed" about the situation with&nbsp;<em>Life by You</em>, and that the industry has become a place in which an AA game that "deliver[s] more than expected" can be shut down two weeks before launch.</p>
<p>In-development projects are canceled frequently, both <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/square-enix-financials-profits-down">behind the scenes</a> and in a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-codename-kestrel-canceled">public-facing manner</a>.&nbsp;<em>Life by You</em>'s <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sims-like-game-life-by-you-shows-tons-of-clothes-more-in-new-video">frequent communication</a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/early-access-release-of-sims-like-game-life-by-you-delayed-again-by-paradox">repeatedly announced</a> (albeit also <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/life-by-you-release-date-delayed-indefinitely">repeatedly delayed</a>) release dates arguably make it something of an anomaly in this area, though.</p>
<p>We may never know exactly why&nbsp;<em>Life by You&nbsp;</em>was canceled, but sadly, canceled it is, so it looks like nothing's knocking&nbsp;<em>The Sims 4&nbsp;</em>off its throne constructed from Simoleons anytime soon. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Mortal Kombat 1 Patch Adds 60FPS Option on PC But Not For Online Matches]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-mortal-kombat-1-patch-adds-60fps-option-on-pc-but-not-for-online-matches/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-mortal-kombat-1-patch-adds-60fps-option-on-pc-but-not-for-online-matches.905757/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-mortal-kombat-1-patch-adds-60fps-option-on-pc-but-not-for-online-matches/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>NetherRealm and Warner Bros. have rolled out a new Mortal Kombat 1 patch, adding a new 60FPS option on PC.</p>
<p>It took some time, but nine months after the game's release, those on PC can now enjoy a new graphics setting. Prior to this patch, various sections in the game were locked to 30FPS, but this new update removes that lock. Yes, there already was <a href="https://wccftech.com/unofficial-mortal-kombat-1-60fps-patch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">an unofficial patch</a> that removed the 30FPS lock, but we now also have an official patch. As mentioned in the <a href="https://mortalkombat1.bugs.wbgames.com/patch-notes?111" target="_blank" rel="noopener">release notes</a>, this new graphics option is intended for users with high-end setups, and the new setting won't affect pre-rendered movies. Additionally, the setting will automatically be disabled during online matches.</p>
<p>Also, this patch comes with various character tweaks, including adjustments for Reptile, Homelander, Peacemaker as well as Kameo fighters Janet Cage, Khameleon, and Cyrax.</p>
<p>Mortal Kombat 1 is available now worldwide for PC and consoles. Here's what we wrote about the game in our <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/mortal-kombat-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">launch review</a> last year:</p>
<p><em>"Speaking of cutscenes, like the last few entries in the series, Mortal Kombat 1 features a grand spectacle of a story and it’s the best ones NetherRealm has ever pulled off. Despite its title, Mortal Kombat 1 isn’t actually reboot, soft or otherwise. The game actually picks up after the events of Mortal Kombat 11’s time-traveling yarn, as Liu Kang – not just a&nbsp;god, but now&nbsp;the God – recrates the entire universe, with the notion that changing certain characters’ destinies will avoid the conflicts of the past. This means we get to see a number of classic characters in an interesting new light – Raiden is just a humble trainee, Mileena is now the honorable heir to Outworld’s throne, and Sub-Zero, well… Sub-Zero is an absolute prick. After decades of more or less doing the same thing, it’s fun to see these characters try on some different hats, and frankly, I actually like some of these new characterizations more than the original ones."</em></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Apple facing $1bn daily fines over alleged DMA breaches]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/report-apple-facing-1bn-daily-fines-over-alleged-dma-breaches</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-apple-facing-1bn-daily-fines-over-alleged-dma-breaches.905754/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/report-apple-facing-1bn-daily-fines-over-alleged-dma-breaches<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Firm says it's "confident" its policies comply with the European Commission's legislation</p>

    </div>


  

    

</header>
  <div>



            <p>Apple is reportedly facing $1 billion in daily fines from the European Commission over breaches of its Digital Markets Act.</p>
<p>This is according to a report by the <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/31a996d5-b472-4357-953e-ace078494604">Financial Times</a>, which alleged that the EU Commission had deemed Apple not to be complying with its DMA legislation.</p>
<p>If found guilty, the EU Commission could fine Apple with daily fines reaching 5% of the firm's average daily turnover, which is over $1 billion.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/apple-to-allow-alternative-app-stores-in-europe">Apple announced a change in its policies to comply with the DMA</a> which allowed the use of alternative app stores and payment systems on its platform.</p>
<p>These policies also included the addition of a "core technology fee", which would see developers pay €0.50 for each install of an app per year after the first install for apps distributed via the App Store and alternative storefronts.</p>
<p>"We're confident our plan complies with the DMA," Apple said in an earlier statement. "We'll continue to constructively engage with the EU Commission as they conduct their investigations."</p>
<p>In March, <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/eu-commission-investigates-google-meta-and-apple-for-possible-digital-markets-act-violations">the EU Commission began an investigation into Google, Meta, and Apple</a> for potential DMA infringements, with Apple being investigated for steering on its App Store.</p>



        </div>

        </article>

  
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Land Beneath Us Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/19/the-land-beneath-us-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-land-beneath-us-review.905742/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/19/the-land-beneath-us-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/06/19/the-land-beneath-us-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="The Land Beneath Us Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Dominic L">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2024-06-19">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2024-06-19">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>The Creator has been kidnapped – isn’t that always the way? – but thankfully all hope is not lost. You’re a clone whose role in life is to collect Soul Energy: a wondrous power source that’s capable of completely altering human life. The downside is that it only comes from one place, the Underworld known as Annwn (or just Hell, if you prefer). The inhabitants of Annwn aren’t too happy about this, hence the kidnapping, and so you travel below to save The Creator, and despatch a few hellspawn along the way. Wrapped up in a surprisingly tactical Roguelite, this indie game is a devilish delight. </p>
<p><iframe title="THE LAND BENEATH US - Launch trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3iTRg_2ASds?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You start each run into The Land Beneath Us with a randomly drawn weapon and accompanying relic, before you’re dumped unceremoniously into the lands of Hell to try and steal all that Soul Energy lurking down there. </p>


<p>What makes The Land Beneath Us stand out from the modern Roguelite crowd is that you assign a weapon to each direction of the D-pad. You then use that particular weapon when moving in that direction, so you can have a pistol equipped that will fire three squares upwards every time you move north, but a great sword that knocks your opponent backwards when you move right. </p>
<p>Each level is played out across a small grid, and part of the difficulty is moving yourself into the optimum position to take out each enemy. Even once you’ve picked up a weapon for every direction, there’s then the need to upgrade them, meaning that you’ll nearly always have a preferred direction to be heading. </p>


<p>Along your journey you’ll encounter various creatures willing to give you a hand, from a Weapons Merchant to a Blacksmith, and then there’s the Enhancer who upgrades your Relics. Some of them will do you a favour for no return, while others are there to make a profit. Guess which ones are the more useful? </p>
<p>The Land Beneath Us has all the standard trappings of the Roguelite genre, but they’re nicely presented and positioned to make progress seem incrementally rewarding, driving you to have just one more run. A run can take as little as a few minutes, but as you get more powerful and better equipped your runs will stretch ever longer. Still, it’s more respectful of your time than many others in the genre. </p>

<p>The visual design is both playful and futuristic, and your clone looks like a robotic Batman when out in the field. The pixel art does a good job of making things clear, while different enemy types each have their own character and respective attacks. At times, it can be difficult to see the block directly behind your character, and that can result in some frustrating losses of health, but overall things shouldn’t become too overwhelming if you stay alert. </p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">
				<p>Summary</p><p>
				The Land Beneath Us is a cool indie Roguelike that boasts that essential ‘one more go’ outlook, keeping you coming back for more. 			</p></div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Danganronpa Creators "Risking Their Lives" for New School-Based SRPG]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/danganronpa-creators-new-game-risking-lives</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/danganronpa-creators-risking-their-lives-for-new-school-based-srpg.905739/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/danganronpa-creators-new-game-risking-lives<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Danganronpa&nbsp;</em>creator Kazutaka Kodaka says that he and his team are "risking their lives" for their newest project, the PC and Switch-focused tactical RPG&nbsp;<em>The Hundred Line: Last Defense Academy</em>.</p>
<p>In an interview with Japanese news platform <a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202406/8386" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Famitsu</a> (with additional reporting by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/danganronpa-creators-are-risking-their-lives-for-their-upcoming-new-game-which-has-put-them-in-debt/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Automaton Media</a>), Kodaka says that his studio Too Kyo Games is in debt thanks to securing financing for the game.</p>
<p>Speaking <a href="https://x.com/kazkodaka/status/1803245722550296800" rel="noopener" target="_blank">on X (formerly Twitter)</a>, Kodaka elaborates that Too Kyo Games has "invested all [its] money and human resources" into the project, describing it as an "epic indie game", a comment on which he elaborates in the Famitsu interview.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-hundred-line-last-defense-academy-interview-combat.jpg?itok=KJgBN2dq 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-hundred-line-last-defense-academy-interview-combat.jpg?itok=O-N-Q1RE 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Unlike&nbsp;<em>Danganronpa</em>,&nbsp;<em>The Hundred Line: Last Defense Academy&nbsp;</em>is a tactical RPG.</figcaption></figure><p>In that interview, Kodaka says that he and his team had initially planned for&nbsp;<em>The Hundred Line&nbsp;</em>to be an "indie-scale game", but that they realized the scope of the project would need to be extended as its design and core concepts came into focus.</p>
<p>He notes that he and his team are still in debt from acquiring financing for the game, describing the process of development as "tough both financially and mentally".</p>
<p>Despite that, Kodaka seems to have come out of the experience with a positive overall opinion; he says that he "may never have another opportunity to put this much effort into a project".</p>

<p>Announced <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-june-2024">during yesterday's Nintendo Direct</a>,&nbsp;<em>The Hundred Line: Last Defense Academy&nbsp;</em>is a collaboration between&nbsp;<em>Danganronpa</em>'s Kazutaka Kodaka and&nbsp;<em>Zero Escape&nbsp;</em>creator Kotaru Uchikoshi.</p>
<p>The game revolves around Takumi Sumino, a "totally average teenager" who finds himself swept up in an apocalyptic battle in which he must protect the titular Last Defense Academy from monsters for a hundred-day period.</p>
<p><em>The Hundred Line&nbsp;</em>promises "100 extreme despair-filled endings", as well as tough tactical combat and plenty of opportunities to explore the school and meet with its students.</p>
<p>You can check out&nbsp;<em>The Hundred Line: Last Defense Academy&nbsp;</em>when it launches sometime next year on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3014080/The_Hundred_Line_Last_Defense_Academy/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor">PC</a> and Switch. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don’t expect Fallout 1 and 2 remakes from Bethesda any time soon - Todd wouldn’t want to “paste over” their charm]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-expect-fallout-1-and-2-remakes-from-bethesda-any-time-soon-todd-wouldnt-want-to-paste-over-their-charm</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/don%E2%80%99t-expect-fallout-1-and-2-remakes-from-bethesda-any-time-soon-todd-wouldn%E2%80%99t-want-to-%E2%80%9Cpaste-over%E2%80%9D-their-charm.905736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-expect-fallout-1-and-2-remakes-from-bethesda-any-time-soon-todd-wouldnt-want-to-paste-over-their-charm<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>“I think I'd like people to experience it the way it was”</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout2_KU93VtO.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Bethesda Softworks</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Like many I’m sure, I have extremely fond memories of the original <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout">Fallout</a> games, 2 especially. I bought my first laptop for uni, barely suitable for much except typing long literature essays in which I’d complete assignments using my favorite university trick of writing “ah, but to answer this question, we must first explore (whatever I actually wanted to write an essay about.)” Faltering, bricky turnip that it was, I still had some of my favourite gaming memories on that thing, mainly around aging <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a>s: Baldur’s Gate 2, Planescape: Torment, and the old Fallouts. </p>

<p>Well, old gaming memories <em>are</em> precious, agreed the man who re-released <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim">Skyrim</a> 18,000 times, as he shared a heartwarming “don’t mess with the classics” message in a recent interview with <a href="https://youtu.be/2ew8LQFGNWU">MrMattyPlays</a>, via <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/todd-howard-says-bethesda-wont-be-remaking-the-first-fallouts-because-some-of-the-charm-of-games-from-that-era-is-a-little-bit-of-that-age/">PC Gamer</a>.</p> <figure>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2ew8LQFGNWU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" height="113" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" title="Matty Interviews Todd Howard: Future Of Fallout, Starfield Year 2, Elder Scrolls VI Info, &amp; MORE!" width="200"></iframe><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</figure>
<blockquote><p>“A main priority for us is to make sure they're available and you can still play them on the PC, and making sure that they run OK. As far as beyond that, we've talked about it, but our priorities in terms of 'Hey let's go do dev work and make certain things work', they haven't been in those areas, so again priority is 'can people load it up and play it?'"</p>
<p>And I do think we want [the games] to load up and run well," says Howard. "The rest of it… I could argue that some of the charm of games from that era and the original Fallout is a little bit of that age. I would never want to sort of paste over some of that with, 'Well we changed how this works so it's more modern….as long as you can download it, as long as it loads up and runs, I think I'd like people to experience it the way it was."</p></blockquote>
<p>Oh Todd, you silver-tongued diplomat. This is a very long way to say “we don’t want to remake the mission where you become a fluffer at a porn studio and possibly catch an STD,” but I appreciate the sentiment. Elsewhere in the interview, Howard spoke about the future of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/starfield-tips-guide">Starfield</a> DLCs <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/starfield-will-get-at-least-one-more-expansion-after-shattered-space-todd-howard-says">after Shattered Space releases</a> - they’re planning on at least one more.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tales of the Shire Preview - The Hobbit Simulator We've Always Wanted]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/tales-of-shire-preview</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tales-of-the-shire-preview-the-hobbit-simulator-weve-always-wanted.905733/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/tales-of-shire-preview<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Lord of the Rings</em> is all about wizards, orcs, armies clashing, swords winging, bows a-shooting, right? <em>Tales of the Shire</em> is out to prove <em>LOTR </em>can be about good home cooking, fellowship, and just living the good life, too.</p>
<h2>Comfort, Vibin', Relaxin'</h2>
<p>Focusing on the good times and hanging out with other hobbits is exactly what the developers want the game to be as well. While playing, I was chatting with them and they said it was important for them to keep <em>Tales of the Shire </em>lighthearted and positive. No scouring this shire (yet).</p>
<p>There is no overarching story or objective in the game, so you're really free to do what you want how you want. That includes making your own hobbit, customizing them down to just how hairy their feet are.</p>

<p>That customization expands to a very robust set of tools to make your hobbit hole and garden just what you want it to be. There is a ton of furniture and decorations to choose from, as well as wallpapers, paintings, textures, and all sorts of stylings you can apply to the various beams, walls, trims, and more.</p>
<p>The amount of specific detail is incredibly impressive, so those that love decoration will easily find hours of entertainment. That detail extends to the garden, which you can spruce up and rearrange as you please as well.</p>
<p><em>Tales of the Shire</em> is set in Bywater, a small village to the east of Hobbiton. Hobbiton is the location featured in the films, though the famed inn, The Green Dragon, is actually in Bywater but brought to Hobbiton for the films. You'll spend time at The Green Dragon in the game, too.</p>
<p>However, that does mean that Hobbiton isn't too awfully far from Bywater (after all it is less than a 10 minute dash from Bilbo's home, we know), so that means a visit from some Baggins or other famed hobbit families isn't out of the question.</p>
<p>When I asked the developers if we may see some folks we know already, the answer I got was to the effect of "It sure is nice when friends stop by to visit, isn't it?"</p>

<p>I didn't get a definitive answer, but there are some two dozen or so hobbits in Bywater to interact with, each with their own routines. At any time you can open up a map and see what they're up to, so finding them is pretty simple. Setting waypoints will make a trail of birds pointing the way for you, too. The routines change based on the time of day, the seasons, and whether specific events are going on in the game.</p>
<p>Speaking of seasons, days do pass on <em>Tales of the Shire</em>, meaning you'll have to make your way to bed each evening. Time will keep pushing things forward and is the only real limitation placed on you, eventually leading to seasonal changes, festivals, and all sorts of things of that nature.</p>
<p>Plus, each day brings with it several meals to prepare.</p>
<h2>Food is the Way to a Hobbit's Heart</h2>
<p>While you can garden, forage, fish, and gather all sorts of things during your days as a hobbit, the real meat of<em> Tales of the Shire </em>is your interactions with the other hobbits. Building relationships with those hobbits through food, gifts, trade, and more is why you'll be putting in all this work.</p>
<p>In my brief time with the game, it was evident that the number one way hobbits communicate with one another is through food and cooking. A huge part of the gameplay is not just finding ingredients and recipes but actually cooking them as well.</p>

<p>Cooking is a simple process but has a lot going on to make your dishes just right. Just as with real cooking, the quality and choice of ingredients, the way you prepare them, and then just the means of cooking them all have huge effects on the overall dish.</p>
<p>Certain ingredients may be spicy, sweet, salty, or all different manner of flavors. Then you can add spices, affect ingredients through pickling, and a bunch of other options as well.</p>
<p>Once you pick ingredients, it's time to prepare them, like chopping onions. As you can see in the screenshot above, there's a box in the bottom right corner with Smooth, Tender, Chunky, and Crisp. You're aiming to hit the little star to really ace that recipe, and that other symbol is where you're at currently.</p>
<p>So, when you chop something, you'll have a bit of a progress bar with one end being Smooth and the other Chunky. You then have to aim to hit that sweet spot,</p>
<p>Same goes for Crisp or Tender. Preparing in the Frying Pan or the Pickling Jar can lean one way or the other, so you can fine tune it.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Prepare it properly to hit the star, and you've got it.</p>

<p>When it comes to the flavoring, however, that is going to matter more for who and why you're making the dish. Maybe the hobbit you're preparing it for likes sweet things, so choosing the right ingredients to make it sweet is important.</p>
<p>All of that isn't too complicated so far, right? Well, there is another element to cooking to consider if you're having someone over for a meal. Where and how are you going to eat it?</p>
<p>Some hobbits are, apparently, pretty particular on not only the preparation of certain foods but just how the table is set up to eat as well. I didn't get to see this feature too much, but it's another wrinkle that can affect the quality of your meal overall and adds just a little more personality to the hobbits you invite over.</p>
<p>The developers also hinted that we may see people other than hobbits from time to time we may remember. I do know one of the trailers certainly showed Gandalf making a visit to Bywater at some point.</p>
<h2>Tales of the Shire Preview | Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>One thing I wanted to shoutout that I think encapsulates the general approach and philosophy with <em>Tales of the Shire</em> is how the game handles your standard sprinting. You don't simply run faster, but you skip and frolic your way forward. As, you know, nothing you're up to really requires the urgency of sprinting now does it?</p>

<p>That laid-back vibe of hobbits just chilling in their community, cooking great food, meeting at the tavern to swap tales and friendship, soaking in the day as time passes by... An idyllic existence based around comfort.</p>
<p>It's criminal how few games are really set in the <em>Lord of the Rings</em> universe, and it is awesome to see one that lets us enjoy something we've really only had glimpses of. I think it will help us all understand what Sam was thinking of when he said: "There's some good in this world, Mr. Frodo, and it's worth fighting for."</p>
<p><em>Tales of the Shire </em>is everything you could want out of a game based around hobbits based on what I've seen so far, and I can't wait to get my hands on the full game.</p>
<p><em>Tales of the Shire</em> releases this holiday season for PC, Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S.</p>
<hr><p>Tales of the Shire <em>was previewed after about 30 minutes of gameplay at Summer Game Fest.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Andrew is the Editor in Chief at TechRaptor. Conned into a love of gaming by Nintendo at a young age, Andrew has been&nbsp;chasing the dragon spawned by Super… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/andrew-otton">More about Andrew</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Inside Out 2’s Lance Slashblade was inspired by a real-life secret video game crush]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24177919/lance-slashblade-inside-out-2-kingdom-hearts</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/inside-out-2%E2%80%99s-lance-slashblade-was-inspired-by-a-real-life-secret-video-game-crush.905730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24177919/lance-slashblade-inside-out-2-kingdom-hearts<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="vZXbkt">Pixar Animation Studios’ <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24131409/inside-out-2-preview-first-look-new-emotions-uncut-gems"><em>Inside Out 2</em></a> takes the audience back inside the mind of a young girl named Riley, expanding beyond the scope of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2015/6/5/8733925/inside-out-review">Pete Docter’s original 2015 movie</a>. The sequel, directed by <a href="https://www.polygon.com/interviews/2020/3/11/21174435/pixar-onward-story-supervisor-behind-the-scenes-interview-kelsey-mann"><em>Onward</em>’s Kelsey Mann</a>, takes Riley into her teen years, adding <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24155725/inside-out-2-character-design-same-face-female-characters-disney-princess">new emotion characters</a> and the physical manifestation of her sense of self as she navigates major changes in her life.</p>
<p id="hZ2NrJ">But outside of the drama Riley experiences around her friends and her social ambitions, the new Pixar movie also has one of the best video game character gags since <em>Tron</em>. </p>
<p id="CR3x0W">[<strong>Ed. note: </strong>This post contains some spoilers for<em> Inside Out 2.</em>]</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25490549/INSIDE_OUT_2_ONLINE_USE_i170_42_pub.pub16.155.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1718808054_4331_81466" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25490549,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iryOiGIdfw_DBpG58o6vVGTTuiA=/0x0:5625x2569/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:5625x2569):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25490549/INSIDE_OUT_2_ONLINE_USE_i170_42_pub.pub16.155.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t9gFVHz6OpIYEhzSxc1YFcbErq4=/0x0:5625x2569/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:5625x2569):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25490549/INSIDE_OUT_2_ONLINE_USE_i170_42_pub.pub16.155.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qat7mmml3d7ufs65CKRvL0jDKGQ=/0x0:5625x2569/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:5625x2569):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25490549/INSIDE_OUT_2_ONLINE_USE_i170_42_pub.pub16.155.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ppmfznCthMtznZ7fVtPVPnNjxxA=/0x0:5625x2569/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:5625x2569):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25490549/INSIDE_OUT_2_ONLINE_USE_i170_42_pub.pub16.155.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/I2keK7KTRAMbIklWh_OHAtnpOxs=/0x0:5625x2569/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:5625x2569):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25490549/INSIDE_OUT_2_ONLINE_USE_i170_42_pub.pub16.155.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gYz6M5scq2XDzwA48sRmeA_N1a0=/0x0:5625x2569/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:5625x2569):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25490549/INSIDE_OUT_2_ONLINE_USE_i170_42_pub.pub16.155.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nvxpjZU5mqPFnI99vKSfevVKfHg=/0x0:5625x2569/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:5625x2569):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25490549/INSIDE_OUT_2_ONLINE_USE_i170_42_pub.pub16.155.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BnVARtD3tTp3BH7GjSxJe4xASJc=/0x0:5625x2569/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:5625x2569):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25490549/INSIDE_OUT_2_ONLINE_USE_i170_42_pub.pub16.155.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sJIotSMHsTinJSQaOTeC7yHp5w0=/0x0:5625x2569/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:5625x2569):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25490549/INSIDE_OUT_2_ONLINE_USE_i170_42_pub.pub16.155.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Disney/Pixar</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="T8dKep">About half an hour into the movie, Joy (Amy Poehler) and the rest of the original <em>Inside Out</em> emotions — Fear, Anger, Disgust, and Sadness — wind up in a deep, dark vault of secrets, where they confront the manifestations of some things Riley has locked away inside herself. This includes Bloofy, a <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24147031/bluey-dad-baby-youtube">Bluey-type character</a> from a children’s cartoon Riley still secretly, shamefully likes, and a large, shadowy character known as Deep Dark Secret.</p>
<p id="DsLQob">But more importantly, the vault contains Lance Slashblade, a melodramatic video game character Riley knows from the in-universe equivalent of <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2019/10/2/20887994/the-smash-bros-community-an-oral-history">Super Smash Bros.</a> Riley has a <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24168972/haikyu-coach-ukai-best-anime-crushes">big ol’ crush</a> on him, but he’s locked away in the vault because, despite his debonair good looks, Lance has one of the lamest power attacks in his game, which makes Riley embarrassed about liking him so much.</p>
<p id="kJr1Mu">With his pixelated anime-style hair, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/gaming/24156714/league-of-legends-best-swords-lol">huge sword</a>, and comically serious voice (provided by veteran video game voice actor Yong Yea), Lance looks like he could fit right in with a lineup of Final Fantasy characters. And he’s absolutely the sort of character a 13-year-old would have an embarrassing crush on, after only knowing him from a team-up game. (That was <a href="https://www.ssbwiki.com/Marth_%28SSBM%29">Marth in <em>Super Smash Bros. Melee</em></a> for me.) According to director Kelsey Mann, Lance was the brainchild of story artist McKenna Harris.</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495267/LS_Mope.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1718808054_2211_81467" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25495267,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ziJpJ37D7-5G2Uud6Bu8SBftTJY=/0x0:2868x1175/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2868x1175):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495267/LS_Mope.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cwvh3DiEKDFDWT02bGJR5WmaaHA=/0x0:2868x1175/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2868x1175):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495267/LS_Mope.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/soFT_6ga05edexS9rWRSekEjzvg=/0x0:2868x1175/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2868x1175):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495267/LS_Mope.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uztyf0ZRjK1UsDrqOo0zEOq-oW0=/0x0:2868x1175/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2868x1175):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495267/LS_Mope.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/09W7iFuyhPBxGw-6YL8AsvYyy6M=/0x0:2868x1175/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2868x1175):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495267/LS_Mope.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/c57UAgQ9lYEAX9us847xDHDceyk=/0x0:2868x1175/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2868x1175):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495267/LS_Mope.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/hQ-mx-O5Kfms8rUKaoYzQhIftYQ=/0x0:2868x1175/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2868x1175):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495267/LS_Mope.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/tPiqfA3utFylnn0V45PrzvYpy_E=/0x0:2868x1175/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2868x1175):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495267/LS_Mope.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yhmy9AhwZgEge_6gSMI6fWbIeNk=/0x0:2868x1175/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2868x1175):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495267/LS_Mope.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Disney/Pixar</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="5VdodU">“They came up with this great idea of having a crush,” Mann told Polygon <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24131409/inside-out-2-preview-first-look-new-emotions-uncut-gems">at a junket ahead of the movie’s release</a>. “I had a crush on cartoon characters at this age, and you kind of don’t want to talk about it. We came up with the idea […] and we got so excited.”</p>
<p id="59eKeF">Harris told Polygon in a later interview that in order to create the character, they dove deep into their 13-year-old secrets. As an avid gamer, they were drawn to what they call “mysterious figures” like Cloud Strife from <em>Final Fantasy 7</em> or Auron in Axel from Kingdom Hearts<em>. </em></p>
<p id="mGOedY">“I distinctly remember feeling, though, that amongst all of my girlfriends at junior high, I knew no one who was into these games, knew who these characters were, much less would admit to have feelings about these characters,” Harris says. “So right away, I was pitching: ‘What if Riley has a crush on a video game character? That might be fun.’ It came from a very authentic place.”</p>
<p id="ebRzmd">All of the vault characters — Bloofy, Deep Dark, and Lance — blossomed from the first brainstorm the filmmakers had about Riley’s suppressed secrets. </p>
<p id="1sEqia">“I did a drawing of all three of them,” says Mann. “And Lance was always there. We always knew he’d be a warrior. Somebody’s like, ‘He should have a giant sword. Huge one.’”</p>
<p id="xwgSwY">As the storyboards progressed, story artist Jeff Cole asked Harris for input on Lance’s design, since he was unfamiliar with the touchpoints needed for an “emo beautiful boy.” So Harris homed in on three specific notes. </p>
<p id="kqQuGg">“He needs incredible hair, impractical armor, and Maybelline-esque beauty,” Harris says.</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495276/LS_Abs.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1718808054_9270_81468" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25495276,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ltvxePLOrNtCwenAr7jOEvGmYpg=/0x0:2864x1180/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2864x1180):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495276/LS_Abs.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AEs0Fjc01L2_1hPovk5rDULia7c=/0x0:2864x1180/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2864x1180):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495276/LS_Abs.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Y0hMtjkQXRAvJRMC6Zu9Wzrow20=/0x0:2864x1180/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2864x1180):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495276/LS_Abs.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TNcG1SXw4UMvkTYvXLqrWXzLeUw=/0x0:2864x1180/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2864x1180):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495276/LS_Abs.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3b0Dtw7e71-tAVfCgbRDGP6-UhE=/0x0:2864x1180/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2864x1180):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495276/LS_Abs.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/P9LkTe2dotj33hbPnGDVfhQNanU=/0x0:2864x1180/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2864x1180):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495276/LS_Abs.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sgKL__SOIVRq71NYwU2Yt4Kge1c=/0x0:2864x1180/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2864x1180):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495276/LS_Abs.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/jO-7x9b8Wsq4LjcXI4qYjopDUr4=/0x0:2864x1180/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2864x1180):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495276/LS_Abs.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eZ42M8CyR2ZVC10wQqAVi_ZHMhI=/0x0:2864x1180/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2864x1180):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495276/LS_Abs.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Disney/Pixar</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="BoGGJd">Lance’s visual look absolutely has a lot of Final Fantasy and Kingdom Hearts to it. But what makes him stand out isn’t just his design — it’s how he moves, and how he looks in relation to the rest of <em>Inside Out 2</em>’s world. His gestures and his walk are a bit janky and stilted, just like an old video game. (Or like some of the 8-bit-inspired characters in <em>Wreck-It Ralph</em>.) Even though he’s an epic warrior, he’s limited by whatever retro video game he hails from. </p>
<p id="9EXdWT">Animator David Torres tells Polygon that the animation team had to deliberately lower their visual standards in order to craft Lance. That meant keeping the frame rate lower, focusing on minimal motion and animation, and having Lance hold poses longer than the other characters. </p>
<p id="IK1zs3">“One of the things we knew we had to do — which was <em>really </em>difficult as an animator that’s worked at Pixar for so many years — is to allow things to penetrate, allow things to look a little rougher,” Torres says. “Take, for instance, the ponytail. We wanted the sense that the wind is always blowing in Lance’s hair and clothing — but that ponytail would go through his sword, or go through his shoulder.”</p>
<p id="KIoHkE">Instead of using Pixar’s typical simulation software, the animators had to hand-key Lance’s hair. Similarly, a lot of the other textures on Lance were done by hand, in order to make sure he looked distinctive. Torres worked briefly in games before he moved to feature animation, and cites his time working on <em>Metroid Prime</em> as a big influence for Lance’s ultimate look. But another key part of why Lance looks particularly specific to the PlayStation 2 era was the effort to make him look unique and out of place, especially since video game animation has come so far. </p>
<p id="tvsnFI">“We probably had to go at least 20 years back to get to the quality that we were looking at,” Torres says. “We just had to make some creative decisions to say, <em>OK, we really need to separate him out from the world</em>.”</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495272/LS_Game.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1718808054_199_81469" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25495272,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CWJmelaMqNajtVrsMR7p17udyeg=/0x0:2858x1179/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2858x1179):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495272/LS_Game.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vUZOSPoJhNkPFVPnGBSJJRwGz_Y=/0x0:2858x1179/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2858x1179):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495272/LS_Game.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IkjlNfFeMxZb-usoGvMKaLtoMR0=/0x0:2858x1179/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2858x1179):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495272/LS_Game.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Tcin6J5YDfpV4uZKcfyoiRjo7i0=/0x0:2858x1179/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2858x1179):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495272/LS_Game.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R8H2ONH74J0r_nLCn3UI9KNFE9Y=/0x0:2858x1179/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2858x1179):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495272/LS_Game.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/21qecD2vadpFu4lnDfGRPj8yaYU=/0x0:2858x1179/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2858x1179):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495272/LS_Game.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/55BIjthOeZl-P52UnVe_ym2j39I=/0x0:2858x1179/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2858x1179):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495272/LS_Game.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/TUL9CBJK2k3SdqzZmA0k0tjbuLs=/0x0:2858x1179/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2858x1179):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495272/LS_Game.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nXbCvq6Busv8kK1WySbsPKQWHts=/0x0:2858x1179/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2858x1179):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495272/LS_Game.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Disney/Pixar</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="i6XHLi">But what really seals the deal is Lance Slashblade’s perfect melodramatic voice-over performance. Yong Yea (<a href="https://www.polygon.com/24047430/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-review-pc-xbox-ps5"><em>Like a Dragon: Infinite Wealth</em></a>, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23841928/persona-3-reload-remake-hands-on"><em>Persona 3 Reload</em></a>), a veteran video game voice actor, knew the specific vibe the character needed — deep, overly serious, and dramatic. From the moment he read the materials for his audition, Yea clocked in on one key anime influence: Sasuke Uchiha from <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23617380/michael-b-jordan-creed-3-interview-anime"><em>Naruto</em></a>.</p>
<p id="kFzfaV">“[Sasuke] has got this very edgy ‘my past is so haunted’ kind of vibe to him,” Yea tells Polygon. “And I’m like, <em>I’m going to channel a little bit of that into the audition</em>. That was my first thought — I was like, <em>There’s a bit of Sasuke energy to him.</em>”</p>
<p id="Yxbyb9">At that point, Yea hadn’t seen any images of the character, so he was purely going off the script’s melodramatic vibes. When he saw the first concept art, he says he was pleased at how much the filmmakers leaned into the video game vibes. </p>
<p id="4ouas9">“It looked like Cloud and Sephiroth had a child, but more purple-themed,” he laughs. </p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495259/LS_Fist.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1718808054_8791_81470" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25495259,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/l59euXc8OtZUBp-3OBuRG8tLD3E=/0x0:2861x1182/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2861x1182):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495259/LS_Fist.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xQxi3uw8hxsHWJKi4CVHYjtHzos=/0x0:2861x1182/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2861x1182):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495259/LS_Fist.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-WJra74Deb5-GfTly4nBaPmTpFw=/0x0:2861x1182/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2861x1182):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495259/LS_Fist.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yVV5L1gr2Og4PtU5FAupPwimbug=/0x0:2861x1182/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2861x1182):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495259/LS_Fist.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gPU840BaOSKS-Am8w1qYu7Gpg_0=/0x0:2861x1182/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:2861x1182):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495259/LS_Fist.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_18_9pDK7v01eN3wPrpGchScP5c=/0x0:2861x1182/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:2861x1182):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495259/LS_Fist.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dvyBFIc4iA-AmCyr79k1hrB1Q7Y=/0x0:2861x1182/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:2861x1182):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495259/LS_Fist.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6KtXSdMG6w_XDwv1bAA3DuQ-PzM=/0x0:2861x1182/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:2861x1182):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495259/LS_Fist.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bSS8tKj5vcOljWQIvKbIFMugxDE=/0x0:2861x1182/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:2861x1182):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25495259/LS_Fist.jpg 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Disney/Pixar</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="xWRhM0">Yea tells us that Mann pretty much asked him to let loose in the recording booth and channel all the video game and anime energy he could. Yea drew from a lot of games and shows he loves, but he also had one unexpected touchpoint from his own career. </p>
<p id="CdV4PF">“There’s this character I play in <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22933124/cookie-run-kingdom-best-characters-valentines-day"><em>Cookie Run: Kingdom</em></a> called <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hmd04O7Kv6o">Madeleine Cookie</a>,” says Yea. “Now, he’s a very different vibe, but he’s equally melodramatic. So two sides of the same coin, I feel these two characters.”</p>
<p id="fl8GVz">Lance Slashblade is unique to the world of <em>Inside Out 2</em>, but the fact that he sparks so many specific comparisons from all the people who worked on him speaks to the strength of his concept. Having an <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22992939/turning-red-fan-art-culture-inspiration-creation-drawing-fandom-crushes">embarrassing fictional crush</a> is such a <a href="https://www.polygon.com/entertainment/22979927/turning-red-teen-lust-refreshingly-weird">milestone for young teenhood</a>, after all. </p>
<p id="kopJKo">“It’s just one of the small things that makes up becoming a teen and becoming who you are,” says Harris. “Understanding that you like certain things, and they’re different from what other people like, and it might be embarrassing. But hey, it’s actually a good thing that you’re unique, and not exactly the same as anyone else.” </p>
<p id="Jyhvyb"><em>Inside Out 2 </em>is out in theaters now. </p>
<p id="hgp1gW"><small><em>[</em></small><small><em><strong>Disclosure:</strong></em></small><small><em> Some quotes from this article come from an </em></small><small>Inside Out 2</small><small><em> early press day held at Pixar Animation Studios in Emeryville, California, on March 26 and 27. Disney provided Polygon’s travel and accommodations for the event. You can find additional information about </em></small><a href="https://www.polygon.com/pages/ethics-statement"><small><em>Polygon’s ethics policy here</em></small></a><small><em>.]</em></small></p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TimeSplitters Reportedly the Next PS2-Emulated Game to Hit PS5 and PS4]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/timesplitters-reportedly-the-next-ps2-emulated-game-to-hit-ps5-and-ps4</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/timesplitters-reportedly-the-next-ps2-emulated-game-to-hit-ps5-and-ps4.905727/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/timesplitters-reportedly-the-next-ps2-emulated-game-to-hit-ps5-and-ps4<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">All good things come to those who wait.</h2></div><section><p>Hot on the heels of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-announces-ps-plus-june-2024-lineup-and-ps2-emulated-games-as-part-of-return-of-days-of-play">the release of PlayStation 2 games Tomb Raider Legend, Star Wars: The Clone Wars, and Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus on PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 4 via the PlayStation Plus Classics Catalog</a> comes word of the next potential addition to the list: TimeSplitters.</p><p><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gematsu</a> spotted a rating for TimeSplitters on PS5 and PS4 in Taiwan, indicating Free Radical Design’s much-loved shooter is coming to the Classics Catalog soon.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">TimeSplitters has been rated for PS5 and PS4 in Taiwan. 99 percent likely it's the PS2 version for the PlayStation Plus Classics Catalog, considering the platforms. Search "TimeSplitters" here to see the rating yourself: <a href="https://t.co/kSQ7a9X1P4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/kSQ7a9X1P4</a> <a href="https://t.co/InFED7ihTx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/InFED7ihTx</a></p>— Gematsu (@gematsu) <a href="https://twitter.com/gematsu/status/1803186507974377868?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/timesplitters">TimeSplitters</a> first released in 2000 as a launch game for the PlayStation 2 and a spiritual successor to Rare’s GoldenEye and Perfect Dark. Indeed TimeSplitters was made by some of the people who worked on those iconic N64 shooters. It took place across multiple different time periods with 18 separate characters battling against the titular foe, creatures who can travel through time and wreck history using special crystals.</p><p>It got a sequel in TimeSplitters 2 in 2002, and a further entry in 2005 called TimeSplitters: Future Perfect. After Free Radical struggled to find a publisher for a fourth game, the rights languished at Crysis developer Crytek for years before Deep Silver parent Koch Media <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/08/15/timesplitters-ip-bought-by-koch-project-seemingly-in-the-works"><u>bought them up in 2018</u></a>. Eventually, as with so much video game intellectual property, TimeSplitters ended up in Embracer’s vault.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>The Best PS2 Games Ever</h3></div></output><p>In 2021, publisher Deep Silver <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-timesplitters-officially-announced-from-new-studio-founded-by-original-devs"><u>finally announced the return of TimeSplitters</u></a> alongside key original members of Free Radical Design, including founders Steve Ellis and David Doak, at a new studio set up in Nottingham, UK. However, in December 2023, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/free-radical-developers-mourn-as-timesplitters-studio-appears-to-shut-down"><u>Free Radical shut down</u></a> amid <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/embattled-embracer-group-confirms-more-than-900-staff-laid-off-so-far-and-warns-of-more-to-come"><u>the devastating restructure at embattled games company Embracer</u></a>. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/canceled-timesplitters-reboot-looks-a-lot-like-fortnite">Gameplay footage of the canceled project </a>showed similarities to battle royale Fortnite. Reportedly, TimeSplitters Next, as it was called, began as something of a Fortnite clone before it was shifted to more closely resemble TimeSplitters 2.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘No Xbox’ Trends as Fans Hit Out at Marvel vs. Capcom Collection Skipping Microsoft’s Consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/no-xbox-trends-as-fans-hit-out-at-marvel-vs-capcom-collection-skipping-microsofts-consoles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98no-xbox%E2%80%99-trends-as-fans-hit-out-at-marvel-vs-capcom-collection-skipping-microsoft%E2%80%99s-consoles.905724/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/no-xbox-trends-as-fans-hit-out-at-marvel-vs-capcom-collection-skipping-microsofts-consoles<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The announcement of <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/marvel-vs-capcom-fighting-collection-arcade-classics">Marvel vs. Capcom Fighting Collection</a> during <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-direct-june-2024-everything-announced">Nintendo Direct</a> delighted fighting game fans, particularly because it brings the much-loved <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/marvel-vs-capcom-2-new-age-of-heroes">Marvel vs. Capcom 2</a> to modern platforms for the first time in years. But while the collection is coming to Switch, PlayStation 4, and PC, the decision to skip Xbox altogether has caused backlash.</p><p>Capcom made its announcement without offering an explanation for the decision to skip Xbox, and the company declined to comment when contacted by IGN. This comes despite Capcom's same-day announcement that it's bringing <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ace-attorney-investigations-collection-revealed-remasters-two-spin-offs-nintendo-direct-2024">two Ace Attorney Investigations titles</a> to Switch, PS4, PC via Steam, <em>and</em> Xbox One in a similar collection. Indeed, the Marvel vs. Capcom series has a long history on Xbox platforms; Marvel vs. Capcom 2 itself launched on Xbox in 2002 and again on Xbox 360 via Xbox Live Arcade in 2009, and the last game in the series, Infinite, launched on Xbox One in 2017.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Xbox owners have reacted to the news with a mix of bewilderment and anger. The backlash was strong enough to cause the phrase ‘No Xbox’ to trend across social media, and there are angry comments on Xbox subreddits and Discords. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/xbox/comments/1dit6pr/comment/l96aauo/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">One redditor said</a>: “I have a Switch, but I play all my fighting games on Xbox with my arcade stick. It's an absolute gut punch it's not coming to Xbox, especially considering Ace Attorney Investigations was announced for Xbox.”</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It's an absolute gut punch it's not coming to Xbox, especially considering Ace Attorney Investigations was announced for Xbox.</p></div><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/xbox/comments/1dit6pr/comment/l9648fn/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Another added</a>: "The other Capcom collection announced on the presentation (Ace Attorney Investigations) is coming to Xbox, so they are clearly not against putting their games on the console. Then why is MvC not coming? I know I'm in a minority here, but I would buy it in a heartbeat and there are bound to be a few thousand other people like me. Now we won't have the chance to do this. Such a shame."</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">No Xbox? Garbage move <a href="https://twitter.com/CapcomUSA_?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@CapcomUSA_</a> <a href="https://t.co/5yVdFISej7" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/5yVdFISej7</a></p>— Keith Garlington (@KeithandMovies) <a href="https://twitter.com/KeithandMovies/status/1803117787222548821?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>I was hype af until I saw there is no Xbox version, why not???</p><p>A game like Marvel VS Capcom should be on as many platforms as possible. Previous Capcom collections has always been on Xbox too, why is this different? <a href="https://t.co/Eed0MdUNYT" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/Eed0MdUNYT</a> <a href="https://t.co/OdDXqoTfy9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/OdDXqoTfy9</a></p></div>— Bella Drive 🐯 Xbox Girlie 💚 (@Bella_Drive) <a href="https://twitter.com/Bella_Drive/status/1803084504703107162?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">No xbox version? <a href="https://t.co/1QmylYm7r8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/1QmylYm7r8</a> <a href="https://t.co/h0lto5Bxy5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/h0lto5Bxy5</a></p>— Cargonaut (@shisnoelite) <a href="https://twitter.com/shisnoelite/status/1803106933253009891?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Without an explanation from Capcom, fans are left to speculate about the reason for Marvel vs. Capcom Fighting Collection skipping Xbox. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/xbox/comments/1dit6pr/comment/l96up8q/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Some believe</a> it’s the result of Capcom’s MT Framework engine being depreciated on the Xbox One. As many have pointed out, this would explain why other Capcom collections, such as Megaman Battle Network Legacy Collection and Monster Hunter Stories, also skipped Xbox One. There is a feeling from some that Capcom has decided it’s not worth the time, energy, and resources that would be required to bring its MT Framework collections to Xbox One, but again, without word from Capcom, this is just speculation for now.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Starting to believe the "MT Framework for Xbox One is dead" theory. It explains all the skips for that platform.</p><p>Great Ace Attorney - MT <br>Monster Hunter Stories - MT <br>Monster Hunter Stores 2 - MT <br>Mega Man Battle Network - Unknown<br>Marvel vs. Capcom Collection - Likely MT <a href="https://t.co/16fDuJFI5a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/16fDuJFI5a</a></p></div>— Jawmuncher (@Jawmuncher) <a href="https://twitter.com/Jawmuncher/status/1803093113176490443?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>And so, the backlash continues, marring what would otherwise be universal excitement for the long-awaited return of some of the best crossover fighting games ever released.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Famitsu Review Scores: Issue 1854]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1854</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1854.905721/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1854<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>    

    <!-- AD: footer -->
           
            

    <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/" title="Gematsu"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="302" height="39.731" viewBox="0 0 302 39.731"><g transform="translate(0 0)"><g transform="translate(0 0.001)"><path d="M39.49,10.82c.13,0,.2-.05.2-.17V.17c0-.1-.07-.15-.2-.17H4.28A4.28,4.28,0,0,0,0,4.28V35.4a4.29,4.29,0,0,0,4.28,4.29H39.49c.13,0,.2-.06.2-.17V14.75c0-.11-.07-.17-.2-.19H15.94c-.09,0-.15.06-.17.19v10.3a.17.17,0,0,0,.17.16H27.7v3.65H12v-18Z" fill="#ed1d3b"></path><path d="M43.69.17A.17.17,0,0,1,43.88,0H83.29a.15.15,0,0,1,.16.17V10.65c0,.12,0,.17-.16.17H55.7v3.65H83.29a.155.155,0,0,1,.16.17V25.13a.14.14,0,0,1-.16.16H55.7v3.57H83.29a.155.155,0,0,1,.16.17V39.52c0,.11,0,.17-.16.17H43.88c-.13,0-.19-.06-.19-.17Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M103.26,25.27V10.93H99.44V39.52a.15.15,0,0,1-.17.17H87.65c-.13,0-.2-.06-.2-.17V.17a.19.19,0,0,1,.2-.17H127a.158.158,0,0,1,.17.17V39.52a.15.15,0,0,1-.17.17H115.32c-.11,0-.16-.06-.16-.17V10.93h-3.91V25.27Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M170.63,0h-39.3a.18.18,0,0,0-.19.17V39.52c0,.11.06.17.19.17H143c.11,0,.16-.06.16-.17V25.29h15.72V39.52a.15.15,0,0,0,.17.17h11.62c.13,0,.19-.06.19-.17V.17A.229.229,0,0,0,170.63,0ZM158.84,14.47H143.12V10.82h15.72Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M188.3,11.1H175c-.13,0-.2-.06-.2-.17V.17A.19.19,0,0,1,175,0h39.41a.15.15,0,0,1,.16.17V10.93c0,.11-.05.17-.16.17H201V39.52c0,.11-.07.17-.2.17H188.49c-.12,0-.19-.06-.19-.17Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M258.08,0c.13,0,.2.07.2.17V10.65c0,.12-.07.17-.2.17H229.41v3.54h28.67a.189.189,0,0,1,.2.2v25c0,.11-.07.17-.2.17h-39.3c-.12,0-.19-.06-.19-.17V29a.18.18,0,0,1,.19-.17h28.68V25.29H218.78c-.12,0-.19-.05-.19-.16V.17a.18.18,0,0,1,.19-.17Z" fill="#fff"></path><path d="M301.77,0H290.14c-.09,0-.14.06-.16.17V28.75H274.26V.17c0-.1-.06-.15-.17-.17H262.47a.17.17,0,0,0-.19.17V39.52c0,.11.06.17.19.17h35.21A4.29,4.29,0,0,0,302,35.4V.17C302,.07,301.9,0,301.77,0Z" fill="#fff"></path></g></g></svg></a>

    <section>
      <nav>
        <div><ul id="menu-footer-menu-one"><li id="menu-item-691230"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691231"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691232"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691233"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691234"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/c/industry">Industry</a></li>
</ul></div>      </nav>
      <nav>
        <div><ul id="menu-footer-menu-two"><li id="menu-item-691235"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about">About</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691236"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about#contact">Contact Us</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691237"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about#advertising">Advertising</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691238"><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/about#staff">Staff</a></li>
<li id="menu-item-691239"><a rel="privacy-policy" href="https://www.gematsu.com/privacy">Privacy Policy</a></li>
</ul></div>      </nav>
    </section>

    <section>
      <ul>
        <li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.facebook.com/gematsucom"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M9 8h-3v4h3v12h5v-12h3.642l.358-4h-4v-1.667c0-.955.192-1.333 1.115-1.333h2.885v-5h-3.808c-3.596 0-5.192 1.583-5.192 4.615v3.385z"></path></svg></a></li>
        <li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://twitter.com/gematsu"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M24 4.557c-.883.392-1.832.656-2.828.775 1.017-.609 1.798-1.574 2.165-2.724-.951.564-2.005.974-3.127 1.195-.897-.957-2.178-1.555-3.594-1.555-3.179 0-5.515 2.966-4.797 6.045-4.091-.205-7.719-2.165-10.148-5.144-1.29 2.213-.669 5.108 1.523 6.574-.806-.026-1.566-.247-2.229-.616-.054 2.281 1.581 4.415 3.949 4.89-.693.188-1.452.232-2.224.084.626 1.956 2.444 3.379 4.6 3.419-2.07 1.623-4.678 2.348-7.29 2.04 2.179 1.397 4.768 2.212 7.548 2.212 9.142 0 14.307-7.721 13.995-14.646.962-.695 1.797-1.562 2.457-2.549z"></path></svg></a></li>
        <li><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCcaswDIh-nrXYofcYQm6KTg"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24"><path d="M9 15V8.26l6.48 3.38L9 15zm14.76-7.8a5.17 5.17 0 0 0-1-2.38 3.46 3.46 0 0 0-2.41-1C17 3.56 12 3.56 12 3.56s-5 0-8.4.24a3.46 3.46 0 0 0-2.41 1 5.17 5.17 0 0 0-.95 2.4A36.53 36.53 0 0 0 0 11.09v1.82a36.22 36.22 0 0 0 .24 3.88 5.17 5.17 0 0 0 1 2.38 4.08 4.08 0 0 0 2.65 1c1.92.18 8.16.24 8.16.24s5 0 8.4-.25a3.46 3.46 0 0 0 2.41-1 5.17 5.17 0 0 0 1-2.38 36.22 36.22 0 0 0 .14-3.87v-1.82a36.28 36.28 0 0 0-.24-3.89"></path></svg></a></li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    

    <section>
      <p>© Copyright Gematsu 2008 to 2023. All rights reserved.</p>
      <p>Reproduction in whole or in part in any form or medium without acknowledgment of Gematsu is prohibited. Use of this site is governed by all applicable laws.</p>
    </section>

    <section>
      <p>Website by <a title="44 Bytes Ltd - Intelligent Internet Services" href="https://www.44bytes.net/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">44 Bytes</a></p>
    </section>

  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VR title Gorilla Tag has earned over $100 million since 2021]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/vr-title-gorilla-tag-has-earned-over-100-million-since-2021</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vr-title-gorilla-tag-has-earned-over-100-million-since-2021.905718/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/vr-title-gorilla-tag-has-earned-over-100-million-since-2021<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Gorilla Tag</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> developer Another Axiom claims the multiplayer parkour jamboree is the most popular title on the Meta Quest Store.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The studio explained its VR title has seen over 1 million daily active users and over 3 million monthly active users. Notably, it added its player community continues to expand.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Gorilla Tag</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> launched back in 2021 (initially via early acces) and became the first app to hit over 100,000 reviews on the Meta Quest Store. It's also available on SteamVR.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Another Axiom dished out those metrics during a recent fireside chat at the Augmented World Expo (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.anotheraxiom.com/news-posts/gorilla-tag-community-continues-to-grow?ref=uploadvr.com">available on the company website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">), and claimed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Gorilla Tag's</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> success shows that "the time for VR is in fact, here and now."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The studio said </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Gorilla Tag</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has attracted over 10 million lifetime players and generated over $100 million in revenue. "We're seeing an average of nearly 60 minutes per play session," it added.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Looking back at when the idea of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Gorilla Tag</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> came to fruition, it's mind-blowing to think so many people have decided to become Monke with us and joined us on this adventure. We can't thank our players enough for taking this fun idea and running to the forest with it."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Outlining how it cultivated that success, the studio noted </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Gorilla Tag</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has found an audience on social media–and especially&nbsp;TikTok. It explained the 'gorillatag' hashtag has over 10 billion views on the platform "and continues to grow."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a fascinating look at the success VR development can deliver to studios who choose to explore the rapidly evolving market. Of course, innovating in that arena can also be costly, as the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/extended-reality/meta-lost-16-1-billion-on-its-big-metaverse-bet-during-2023">billions of dollars lost each quarter by Meta's troubled Reality Labs division</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has repeatedly proved.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Banana game not a scam, says developer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/banana-game-not-a-scam-says-developer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/banana-game-not-a-scam-says-developer.905712/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/banana-game-not-a-scam-says-developer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Despite former team member's involvement in bitcoin.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Banana-5.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Pony, Sky, AestheticSpartan</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Banana has taken Steam by storm recently, yesterday <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/banana-clicking-game-now-9th-most-popular-of-all-time-on-steam-knocks-baldurs-gate-3-out-of-top-10">knocking Baldur's Gate 3 out of the top 10 most popular games on Valve's platform</a> (in terms of peak concurrent players).
</p>
<p>
In Banana, players click on the image of a banana - or simply leave the software running - to eventually get a banana dropped into their Steam inventory. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/more-than-100000-people-are-currently-playing-a-steam-game-where-you-click-a-banana">As we previously reported</a>, these bananas can be sold in Steam's marketplace, with some going for pennies while others have a much higher asking price. 
</p>
<p>
Since Banana started gaining popularity on Steam, there has been speculation this is all some kind of scam. This concern was exacerbated when it transpired one of the developers behind Banana had previously been involved in a "Steam market 'bitcoin' scam/bug". However, other team members have assured the community the game is not a scam, and more content will be coming soon. 
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: For Xbox, could this year finally be the one where it all pays off?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mPVhT_7O0iE" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
In a message shared on <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1225691328998936576/1236959941097558056">Discord</a> last night, Banana's CM/Co-Owner aestheticspartan released the following statement:
 
"As you all have heard by now Theselions used to be involved in a steam market 'bitcoin' scam/bug. We did not know about this until recent videos started to point this out and we had a talk almost immediately with the whole team about the situation. We gave him the chance to explain the situation to us and we know he is showing remorse and is sorry about what happened in the past."
</p>
<p>
Aestheticspartan said the Banana team has "parted ways" with Theselions because of this revelation, adding his "inventory has been cleared of any valuable bananas that could concern and/or worry the community". 
</p>
<p>
The Banana developer went on to state there is "no scamming/scam" going on, and the remaining members are currently working to update the game. "We cannot wait to turn this game into something bigger and better than just a clicker game," they wrote. "Please stay on the lookout as we have been and still are working on a large amount of updates to improve the game and let you all do much more with your bananas."
</p>
<p>
In an earlier conversation with <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-gb/entertainment/gaming/why-clicker-game-banana-the-legal-infinite-money-glitch-is-going-viral-on-steam/ar-BB1nPmuR">Polygon</a>, developer team member Hery admitted the game has a bot problem. "Since the game takes basically one percent to no resources of your PC, people are abusing up to 1000 alternative accounts in order to get Rarer drops or at least drops in bulk," they told the publication. This would not be a surprise, given Banana's monumental Steam numbers.
</p>
<p>
However, at the time of their conversation, they assured Polygon everything was above board. "I do believe that the reason why it mostly caught on is because it's a legal 'Infinite money glitch,'" Hery said. "Users make money out of a free game while selling free virtual items."
</p>
<p>
Eurogamer has reached out to members of Banana's team and Valve for further comment on the current discourse surrounding the game. 

</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Even the Elden Ring manga author is taking time off to play Shadow of the Erdtree]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/even-the-elden-ring-manga-author-is-taking-time-off-to-play-shadow-of-the-erdtree/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=even-the-elden-ring-manga-author-is-taking-time-off-to-play-shadow-of-the-erdtree</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/even-the-elden-ring-manga-author-is-taking-time-off-to-play-shadow-of-the-erdtree.905709/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/even-the-elden-ring-manga-author-is-taking-time-off-to-play-shadow-of-the-erdtree/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=even-the-elden-ring-manga-author-is-taking-time-off-to-play-shadow-of-the-erdtree<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="311" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">If you’ve been keeping up with <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-elden-ring/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Elden Ring</a></em>‘s spin-off manga, <em>Elden Ring: The Road to the Erdtree</em>, you may be disappointed to know that it will be skipping next month’s update. However, the author has a perfectly understandable and relatable reason… he wants to play <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shadow of the Erdtree</a></em>.</p> <p data-characters="539" data-current-count="539" data-injectable="true">For anyone who wasn’t aware, <em>Elden Ring: The Road to the Erdtree</em> is an adaptation of the game, but is more of a comedy story starring an original protagonist. It’s been getting new chapters biweekly; in fact, a new one dropped earlier today. As spotted by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/elden-ring-manga-author-goes-on-hiatus-to-play-the-dlc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Automaton</a>, author Nikiichi Tobita has opted to take some time off to enjoy the new<em> Elden Ring</em> DLC, which is <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/heres-when-you-can-start-playing-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-in-every-region/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">scheduled to launch tomorrow</a> (or on Friday depending on your timezone). This means the manga won’t be getting a new chapter on July 19 as initially expected.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"></figure> <p data-characters="548" data-current-count="848" data-injectable="true">You can’t be mad with him for his decision. How many of us have booked time off work to play a hot, new video game? How many of us have booked time off specifically for <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em>? People have been clamouring for more <em>Elden Ring</em> since the game launched in 2022 and, based on all the reviews, it sounds like the wait will be worth it. Plus, writing and drawing manga chapters on a regular basis must be exhausting work, so Tobita is probably due a break anyway. Playing the DLC may also give him new ideas for future manga chapters.</p>
 <p data-characters="543" data-current-count="543" data-injectable="false">Would you believe this isn’t even the only <em>Elden Ring</em> manga? Just last week, publisher Bandai Namco announced a second one titled <em>Elden Ring: Distant Stories from The Lands Between</em> (<a href="https://www.famitsu.com/news/202406/04340370.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">via Famitsu</a>) and while it’ll also be a comedy, the focus will be on the various NPCs players have met in the Lands Between. Serialisation will begin on July 4, but there’s no mention of an official English translation. Since <em>Elden Ring: The Road to the Erdtree</em> has been localised for Western fans, hopefully this second manga will follow suit.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unreal Engine 5.4 Forgotten Cemetery Tech Demo Struggles to Run Smoothly at Native 4K Resolution on an RTX 4080]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/unreal-engine-5-4-struggles-native-4k-rtx-4080/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/unreal-engine-5-4-forgotten-cemetery-tech-demo-struggles-to-run-smoothly-at-native-4k-resolution-on-an-rtx-4080.905703/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/unreal-engine-5-4-struggles-native-4k-rtx-4080/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Judging from another Unreal Engine 5.4 tech demo, native 4K resolution is increasingly looking like a resolution that only the absolute best GPUs will be able to handle with decent performance.</p>
<p>A few hours ago, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MxBenchmarkPC" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MxBenchmark PC</a> shared a new video showing the <a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/marketplace/en-US/product/scans-cemetery-forgotten-churchyard" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forgotten Cemetery demo</a> created by Scans Factory running at 4K and 1440p resolutions, Epic settings on an RTX 4080 GPU. As seen in other tech demos powered by the latest version of the engine by Epic, the NVIDIA GPU, which is still among the most powerful GPUs on the market, is not able to handle native 4K resolution properly in both daytime and nighttime only managing to hit the 50, 60 FPS mark in a few scenarios. Performance is definitely better at 1440p resolution, although framerate is not particularly stable.</p>
<p><iframe title="Unreal Engine 5.4 Forgotten Cemetery Tech Demo - A Glimpse Into Next-Gen Graphics | RTX 4080" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8iWjkpLwym8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>While these Unreal Engine 5.4 are definitely not optimized, they do show that the engine still needs plenty of work to reach an acceptable level of performance. The latest version of the engine brings significant performance improvements, but stability still leaves something to be desired, according to an <a href="https://wccftech.com/unreal-engine-5-4-performance-improvement-frame-time/">analysis</a> shared last month.</p>
<p>Besides performance improvements, Unreal Engine 5.4 brings a new Nanite Adaptive Tessellation option, Heterogenous Volumes, which can produce realistic and dynamic smoke and clouds, improved Temporal Super Resolution upscaling, easier implementation of AI and machine learning tools, performance and shared compilation improvements and much more. More information on the engine can be found on its <a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official website.</a></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Manga on Hiatus so Creator Can Play Shadow of the Erdtree]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-manga-on-hiatus-so-creator-can-play-shadow-of-the-erdtree</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring-manga-on-hiatus-so-creator-can-play-shadow-of-the-erdtree.905700/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-manga-on-hiatus-so-creator-can-play-shadow-of-the-erdtree<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The official Elden Ring manga has been put on hiatus as its creator has taken time off work to play expansion <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree">Shadow of the Erdtree</a>.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/elden-ring-manga-author-goes-on-hiatus-to-play-the-dlc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Automaton</a>, Nikiichi Tobita, the author of comedy manga Elden Ring: The Road to the Erdtree, announced on <a href="https://x.com/nikiichi_tobita/status/1803256529778553154?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter</a> he's skipping the July 19, 2024 release of the series so he can spend time playing Shadow of the Erdtree upon its June 21 release.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree DLC Review Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Tobita shared a drawing of himself sleeping alongside the announcement, showing him dreaming of the "glowy worm boy" — a new beastie in the expansion that became an instant hit upon its reveal by developer FromSoftware.</p><p>He's likely not the only Elden Ring fan taking time off work to play the expansion, which has been more than two years in the making.</p><p>Just like previous FromSoftware games Dark Souls and Bloodborne, however, accessing the DLC isn't as simple as selecting it on a menu, as players must tick off a handful of obscure feats beforehand, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-publisher-warns-fans-they-have-less-than-two-weeks-to-beat-mohg-so-they-can-play-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc">including beating an optional boss</a>. Thankfully, IGN has a guide on <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring/How_to_Prepare_for_the_Shadow_of_the_Erdtree_DLC">how to prepare for the Shadow of Erdtree DLC</a> if you need to scramble ahead of the expansion's release. And make sure to check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/maps/elden-ring/lands-between">our Elden Ring interactive map</a> to ensure you're not missing any <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/elden-ring/Scarab_Locations_and_Rewards">important collectibles</a>.</p><p>You can also check out IGN's <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/how-long-is-elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree">"How Long to Beat"</a> for Shadow of the Erdtree and kill some time ahead of its imminent release <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-review">by reading our extensive 10/10 review</a>.</p><p>"Like the base game did before it, Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree raises the bar for single player expansions," we said. "It takes everything that made the base game such a landmark RPG, condenses it into a relatively compact 20-25 hour campaign, and provides fantastic new challenges for heavily invested fans to chew on."</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zelda Fans Are Very Excited to Get Violent as Princess Zelda in Echoes of Wisdom]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/zelda-fans-are-very-excited-to-get-violent-as-princess-zelda-in-echoes-of-wisdom</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zelda-fans-are-very-excited-to-get-violent-as-princess-zelda-in-echoes-of-wisdom.905697/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/zelda-fans-are-very-excited-to-get-violent-as-princess-zelda-in-echoes-of-wisdom<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom">The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</a> was announced by Nintendo as a game without Link leading the way and fans seem very excited to instead get violent as Princess Zelda.</p><p>The game, which many are joking should be called The Legend of Link as players are tasked with saving the Hero of Time instead of the usual Zelda, sees the princess wield a weapon called the Tri Rod as an alternative to the usual sword and shield.</p><p>This is because Zelda holds the Triforce of Wisdom instead of Link's Triforce of Courage, and the rod fittingly employs more of a puzzle-solving approach to problems instead of hacking and slashing..</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="zxx" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/tdYEoLuZnG" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/tdYEoLuZnG</a></p>— bea (@SlLENTPRINCESS) <a href="https://twitter.com/SlLENTPRINCESS/status/1803110433282502815?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>But fans are having fun with this concept already by flipping it on its head, portraying a cold-blooded and savage Zelda in place of her usually cheerful and considered demeanor.</p><p>"Kill pig with rock," reads one post from @kurdupl on X/Twitter, alongside an image of a heartless-looking Zelda about to decimate a worried moblin.</p><p>"And here's Zelda with the folding chair," reads another post from @Stoic_Miiverse, showing Zelda jumping down from the top rope onto the big boss featured in the opening of the Echoes of Wisdom trailer, with Link cheering her on in the background.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Kill pig with rock <a href="https://t.co/EZtBJaEJK2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/EZtBJaEJK2</a></p>— Kifa🇺🇦 (@kurdupl) <a href="https://twitter.com/kurdupl/status/1803128461424238828?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Reddit user <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/zelda/comments/1divmxg/eow_new_key_art_revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">alsike</a> posted an image of "new key art" from Echoes of the Kingdom, which showed the Princess Zelda from Ocarina of Time holding a handgun.</p><p>All these and more have seemingly materialised as a result of the excitement for what's essentially the first game with the titular character herself as a protagonist.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-announced-for-nintendo-switch-with-zelda-as-protagonist">Echoes of Wisdom was announced at the June 2024 Nintendo Direct</a> with a September 26, 2024 release date.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">~AND HERE'S ZELDA WITH THE FOLDING CHAIR!~ <a href="https://t.co/ms7A6yX3va" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/ms7A6yX3va</a></p>— Stoic Seraphim (@Stoic_Miiverse) <a href="https://twitter.com/Stoic_Miiverse/status/1803214004954997101?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Players will wield the Tri Rod to replicate things using the Echo ability, letting Zelda duplicate monsters to fight alongside her, solve puzzles, and more. Echoes of water blocks can be used to swim up to new heights, for example, or old beds can be duplicated to create bridges.</p><p>Zelda series lead Eiji Aonuma also promised huge levels of variance between playthroughs, saying each player's experience will be different depending on the echoes they make.</p><p>Those particularly excited can pick up a limited edition, gold-colored Nintendo Switch Lite on launch day too.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">She's ready! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/zelda?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#zelda</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/echoesofwisdom?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#echoesofwisdom</a> <a href="https://t.co/EzgnL22eJz" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/EzgnL22eJz</a></p>— Fran @ Furanstore Open! (@furanchu) <a href="https://twitter.com/furanchu/status/1803202849712775236?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">June 18, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>"It’s up to Zelda and her wisdom to save the kingdom of Hyrule in a brand-new story in The Legend of Zelda series," Nintendo said. "The people of Hyrule are being stolen away by strange rifts that have appeared, with a certain swordsman among the missing."</p><p>The Nintendo Direct was full of other major announcements too. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-direct-june-2024-opens-with-mario-luigi-brothership">Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership was revealed</a>, while <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-prime-4-gameplay-revealed">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond surfaced for the first time</a> in seven years too. Read about every announcement, big and small, in <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-direct-june-2024-everything-announced">our Everything Announced article</a>.</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ranking the mainline Resident Evil games by sales figures]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/ranking-the-mainline-resident-evil-games-by-sales-figures/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ranking-the-mainline-resident-evil-games-by-sales-figures</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ranking-the-mainline-resident-evil-games-by-sales-figures.905694/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/ranking-the-mainline-resident-evil-games-by-sales-figures/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=ranking-the-mainline-resident-evil-games-by-sales-figures<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="393" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">When you think of horror gaming, chances are you picture <em>Resident Evil</em> in one of its many forms. From its humble beginnings as a puzzle-based zombie game that took cues from <em>Alone in the Dark</em> and <em>Sweet Home</em>, Capcom’s survival series has become almost the final word in scary video gaming. There’s not much that comes close to it in terms of worldwide success and brand recognition.</p> <p data-characters="248" data-current-count="248" data-injectable="false">With that, I’m going to attempt to <strong>rank all the mainline <em>Resident Evil</em> games</strong> that have been released over the decades (almost 30!) based purely on their sales figures. Now, there are a couple of things I want to clear up before I get started.</p> <p data-characters="325" data-current-count="573" data-injectable="true">First off: there seems to be some debate about whether the likes of <em>Revelations</em> and <em>Revelations 2</em> count as “main games” in the series. As such, I won’t be discussing them, as no one seems to agree. However, <em>Code Veronica</em> is unanimous when it comes to classing it as a canon <em>RE</em> game. So, in the list it goes.</p>
 <p data-characters="543" data-current-count="543" data-injectable="true">As for the sales numbers themselves, there doesn’t appear to be a consensus on that, either. It would make sense to use <a href="https://www.capcom.co.jp/ir/english/business/million.html#tab6" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Capcom’s own figures</a>, but they don’t match up with what other sources say. For example: it lists <em>RE4</em> (the original) numerous times, depending on the platform and release version. Given this, I’ll pull information from a number of places, but I will try to keep this as accurate as I can. Also, it ultimately doesn’t matter in the end. We’re all just trying to get through the week, yeah?</p>
 <h2 id="h-code-veronica-2000-2-54-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Code: Veronica</em> (2000) – 2.54 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot via Destructoid.</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="434" data-current-count="734" data-injectable="true">Taking place just before the military destruction of Raccoon city, <em>Code: Veronica</em> is smack-bang in between <em>Resident Evil 2</em> and <em>3</em>. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resident_Evil_%E2%80%93_Code:_Veronica" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wikipedia entry</a> for the game refers to it as the “fourth main installment” in the series, though if you’re not familiar with the franchise, you’d be forgiven for thinking it’s a spinoff, seeing as it’s not a numbered game. I’ve made that mistake in the past.</p>
 <p data-characters="396" data-current-count="396" data-injectable="false">It’s also considered one of the strongest entries, with pretty much universal acclaim across the board. <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/resident-evil-code-veronica/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metacritic</a> shows a review score of 94 and a user rating of 9.1 for the Dreamcast version. You’ll sometimes see it on lists of the top <em>Resident Evil</em> games of all time. With such praise, it’s no wonder there are high <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/capcom-confirms-more-resident-evil-remakes-are-on-the-way/">hopes that Capcom will remake <em>Code: Veronica</em></a> at some point.</p> <h2 id="h-resident-evil-3-nemesis-1999-3-50-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil 3: Nemesis</em> (1999) – 3.50 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="696" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Screenshot via Destructoid.</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="376" data-current-count="376" data-injectable="false">I still have fond memories of being in my teens and playing the 1999 release of <em>Resident Evil 3</em>. I loved the second game, and the third entry was just as fantastic to me. I was terrified of the prospect of bumping into Nemesis at unexpected intervals, but my sweaty hands and greasy face (teenager, remember) fought bravely. And that was the last time I truly felt free. Sigh.</p> <p data-characters="357" data-current-count="733" data-injectable="true">Anyway…three and a half million in sales is definitely noteworthy, especially for a time when gaming wasn’t quite the behemoth industry it is today. <em>Nemesis</em> was the <a href="http://archive.thegia.com/news/0001/n27e.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">third-best game in Japan for 1999</a> – where it was called <em>Last Escape</em> – according to data originally published by Famitsu. That placed it ahead of <em>Gran Turismo 2</em> and <em>Dino Crisis</em>.</p>
 <h2 id="h-resident-evil-2-1998-4-96-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil 2</em> (1998) – 4.96 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot via Destructoid.</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="387" data-current-count="687" data-injectable="true">Now we come to my favorite <em>Resident Evil</em> game of all time. Is this a nostalgia thing? Almost certainly, yes. But I still recall being blown away by its visuals and the fact that the game dropped you right in the middle of the action. Unheard of at the time, when I think about it. I played this game to death when it first came out, even attempting to unlock the ability to play as <a href="https://residentevil.fandom.com/wiki/The_Tofu_Survivor_(RE2)" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tofu</a>.</p>
 <p data-characters="442" data-current-count="442" data-injectable="true">Coming just a couple of years after the original, <em>RE2</em> seemed to fall just shy of its predecessor in terms of sales. But it absolutely (in my eyes, at least) took what made the first game such a hit and upped just about everything. Yes, two and a half decades later, it’s dated, but it’s a classic. But that first time Mr. X burst through a wall will go down as one of the most frightened I’ve ever been while playing a game.</p>
 <h2 id="h-resident-evil-1996-5-08-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil</em> (1996) – 5.08 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot via Destructoid.</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="453" data-current-count="753" data-injectable="true">There’s some debate about when the “survival horror” genre actually began. One thing that most would agree on is that it didn’t start with the original <em>Resident Evil</em>. However, it’s generally considered the first game to be described as a survival horror. Some would consider 1992’s <em>Alone in the Dark</em> – which influenced <em>RE</em> – to be the first. But the term can retroactively describe even earlier releases, it seems.</p>
 <p data-characters="345" data-current-count="345" data-injectable="false">That aside, it doesn’t detract from <em>Resident Evil</em>‘s impact on the gaming world. Its blend of exploration, puzzle solving, and a zombie infestation combined to make it one of the scariest games ever released at the time. For that alone, it’s gone down in the history books as probably the most important horror game of all time.</p> <h2 id="h-resident-evil-remake-2002-5-25-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil Remake</em> (2002) – 5.25 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="645" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via Steam/Capcom.</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="308" data-current-count="308" data-injectable="false">You could argue that this reimagining of the first <em>Resident Evil</em> installment was what kick-started Capcom’s keen interest in remaking the older games from scratch. However, this came out some 17 years before the <em>RE2</em> remake, which is a fact that hammers home just how long the series has been going for.</p> <p data-characters="359" data-current-count="667" data-injectable="true">This 2002 do-over of <em>RE</em> kept the third-person perspective and tank controls of its ancestor, but gave a boost to the visuals. It was a much darker version than the original, I found, but it retained the franchise’s position in the limelight a good few years before the fourth game would come along and absolutely smash the boundaries of survival horror.</p>
 <h2 id="h-resident-evil-zero-2002-5-45-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil Zero</em> (2002) – 5.45 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Steam/Capcom/</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="359" data-current-count="659" data-injectable="true">With the release of both a remake and a brand-new entry, 2002 was evidently a good year to be a <em>Resident Evil</em> fan. If you wanted to play the games in chronological order based on timeline, <em>Zero</em> would be the one to start with. Covering the events before the 1996 game, this one is a prequel and sees you playing as both Rebecca Chambers and convict Billy Coen.</p>
 <p data-characters="299" data-current-count="299" data-injectable="false">Sadly, I never finished this one, though I did enjoy the fact that you could switch between both characters at a moment’s notice. This was something of a departure from previous <em>Resident Evil</em> games, where you typically played one campaign before playing the story again as someone else. Novel.</p> <h2 id="h-resident-evil-4-remake-2023-7-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil 4 Remake</em> (2023) – 7 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="599" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via Steam/Capcom.</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="362" data-current-count="362" data-injectable="false">The numbers are starting to climb up, but we haven’t yet reached the tens of millions. Also, given that <em>Resident Evil 4 Remake</em> is the latest installment to be released – launching in March 2023 – this number is only going to change as time moves on. The previous entries on this list are probably not shifting many copies now, given their general ages.</p> <p data-characters="404" data-current-count="766" data-injectable="true">The original <em>RE4</em> is easily considered one of – if not <em>the</em> – best game in the series. So, you can imagine the pressure Capcom was under to make the remake nothing short of stellar. Fortunately, the studio pulled it off, bringing everything fans loved about the 2005 release, but — actually, you don’t need me to tell you how good it is. No doubt many of you have played the remake already.</p>
 <h2 id="h-resident-evil-3-remake-2020-8-70-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil 3 Remake</em> (2020) – 8.70 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Steam/Capcom.</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="372" data-current-count="672" data-injectable="true">Don’t be too surprised that this has (so far) sold more than <em>RE4</em>. Remember, the latter has only been out just over a year, while the remake of <em>Resident Evil 3</em> has had a good while longer to rack up the numbers. It’s not quite as high in terms of sales figures as some of the other games, but it’s still a sizeable chunk, especially for such a short game.</p>
 <p data-characters="326" data-current-count="326" data-injectable="false">That was largely the main criticism of <em>RE3</em>. That, and it dialed back the puzzles a tad. But even for a short horror title, it was able to capture the essence of its 1999 counterpart and inject some much-needed modernity into the mix. Of course, it also kept the Nemesis antagonist, which would have been criminal to leave out.</p> <h2 id="h-resident-evil-village-2021-10-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil Village</em> (2021) – 10 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="626" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via Steam/Capcom.</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="387" data-current-count="387" data-injectable="false">Now we’re into the juicy numbers. It was very recently that <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/resident-evil-village-hits-10-million-sales-the-fastest-in-the-series-to-do-so/">Capcom announced <em>Resident Evil Village</em> had smashed 10 million copies</a>, and is the fastest game in the whole series to achieve this. Much like <em>RE4 Remake</em>, we can expect the eighth installment to keep racking up those figures over time. But we can already see how successful the series continues to be after all these years.</p> <p data-characters="344" data-current-count="731" data-injectable="true"><em>Village</em> is – in a way – the second installment that is trying to do something different with the franchise, much like <em>RE7</em> before it. Gone are the classic zombies and third-person camera angles. Replaced instead by a much more involved perspective, grittier visuals, and a return to form for gamers who just want to <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/resident-evil-villages-lady-dimitrescu-is-more-than-just-a-fan-art-flavor-of-the-month/">ogle a digital matriarch</a>.</p>
 <h2 id="h-resident-evil-6-2012-13-10-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil 6</em> (2012) – 13.10 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Steam/Capcom.</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="379" data-current-count="679" data-injectable="true">This one might be a surprise to some. If you know the general trajectory of <em>Resident Evil</em> quality, you’ll be familiar with the sixth game’s reputation. Pretty much tacking on horror as an aside, the series was, by this point, almost entirely about bombastic action than tension. This 2012 installment is typically regarded as one of the weakest of the mainline games.</p>
 <p data-characters="392" data-current-count="392" data-injectable="false">Or so I thought. The fact that it’s sold over 13 million copies must be a testament to how well it did upon release, or some time after it. <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/221040/Resident_Evil_6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a> shows it as “mostly positive” for reviews, while <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/resident-evil-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metacritic</a> has it down as 67 out of 100. It seems weird, then, that the sales figures appear to be at odds with the overall reception of <em>RE6</em>. But that’s show business, baby!</p> <h2 id="h-resident-evil-4-2002-13-20-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil 4</em> (2002) – 13.20 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="692" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Screenshot via Destructoid.</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="445" data-current-count="445" data-injectable="true">I’m going to confess something right now. Please don’t hate me for this, but…I don’t consider the original <em>Resident Evil 4</em> to be the best in the series. I know, I know. It’s sacrilege. But I think it’s because I played it many years after it was released. By this point, the control scheme felt outdated and the voice acting felt too cheesy for something that had moved into darker and more sincere territory.</p>
 <p data-characters="424" data-current-count="424" data-injectable="true">That’s not to say I didn’t enjoy it. It’s a great <em>Resident Evil</em> game. Just not my favorite. But I could still see why everyone loved it so much. Its switch to an over-the-shoulder perspective was genre-defining and while being more action-orientated would be the later games’ detriment, it worked out pretty nicely in this case. It’s just a shame I was late to the party to truly appreciate it.</p>
 <h2 id="h-resident-evil-7-biohazard-2017-13-30-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil 7: Biohazard</em> (2017) – 13.30 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Steam/Capcom.</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="323" data-current-count="623" data-injectable="true">When I first saw the teasers and trailers for this, I was massively excited. Capcom was rewriting their own rules for <em>Resident Evil 7</em> and it was a decision that helped breathe new life into the waning series. It had lashings of <em>P.T.</em> (long-dead by this point) and <em>Outlast</em>, which did nothing to quell my thirst for this game.</p>
 <p data-characters="254" data-current-count="254" data-injectable="false">Going back to its horror roots, <em>Biohazard</em> seemed to be a way to undo what the last two or three entries had done. While <em>Resident Evil 2</em> is my favorite overall for both its gameplay and trip down memory lane, <em>RE7</em> is easily my favorite of the modern games.</p> <h2 id="h-resident-evil-2-remake-2019-13-90-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil 2 Remake</em> (2019) – 13.90 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="554" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via Steam/Capcom.</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="324" data-current-count="324" data-injectable="false">While we mustn’t forget the 2002 remake of <em>Resident Evil</em>, the 2019 modern take on <em>RE2</em> can be said to be the start of a new era for Capcom in terms of remaking classic games. Nearly 14 million in sales over the past few years is probably all the evidence you need to understand just how huge this game was upon release.</p> <p data-characters="443" data-current-count="767" data-injectable="true">Obviously, the game itself played a huge part in that popularity. Had it been a straight remake of the 1998 release, it probably wouldn’t have been as well-received aside from some appeal to older fans. But bringing back the over-the-shoulder camera from <em>RE4</em>, adding Mr. X from the offset, switching the puzzles and overall level design around to keep things fresh are the hallmarks of a great remake that still hits that nostalgia spot.</p>
 <h2 id="h-resident-evil-5-2009-14-60-million" data-injectable="false"><em>Resident Evil 5</em> (2009) – 14.60 million</h2> <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Image via Steam/Capcom.</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="420" data-current-count="720" data-injectable="true">Much like <em>RE6</em>, I was surprised to see that not only had the fifth <em>Resident Evil</em> game sold so many millions of copies, it’s actually the highest-selling entry in the series. Right at the start of this article, I posted a link to Capcom’s list of its top releases. I went through to double check these numbers. It turns out, yes, it does indeed add up to 14.6 million when you include all versions of the game.</p>
 <p data-characters="286" data-current-count="286" data-injectable="false">I never played <em>RE5</em> beyond the demo. The fact that it had a co-op mode – in <em>Gears of War</em> fashion – was a neat idea, but it’s shift towards heavy action was off-putting for me. Still, you know my views on <em>Resident Evil 4</em>, so what do I know, eh? The numbers speak for themselves.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Todd Howard rules out remakes of Fallout 1 and 2 since the originals are still available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/todd-howard-rules-out-remakes-of-fallout-1-and-2-since-the-originals-are-still-available/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=todd-howard-rules-out-remakes-of-fallout-1-and-2-since-the-originals-are-still-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/todd-howard-rules-out-remakes-of-fallout-1-and-2-since-the-originals-are-still-available.905685/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/todd-howard-rules-out-remakes-of-fallout-1-and-2-since-the-originals-are-still-available/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=todd-howard-rules-out-remakes-of-fallout-1-and-2-since-the-originals-are-still-available<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="430" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">Video game remakes are all the rage nowadays, and with the <em>Fallout</em> series enjoying a boon in popularity thanks to the Amazon TV show, some might think Bethesda should put out a remake of one of the older <em>Fallout</em> games. Especially since <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/is-fallout-5-confirmed-heres-everything-bethesda-has-said-about-the-next-fallout-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fallout 5</a></em> won’t be a thing for a very, very, very long time. Surprisingly, Bethesda’s own Todd Howard has shot down the possibility of remaking either of the first two <em>Fallout</em> games.</p> <p data-characters="433" data-current-count="433" data-injectable="true">Earlier this week, Howard spoke with <a href="https://youtu.be/2ew8LQFGNWU?si=ZH7hHPKQlTZ3b6yi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">YouTuber MrMattyPlays</a> about the future of the <em>Fallout</em> series (<a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/fallout-1-and-2-wont-be-getting-remade-todd-howard-says/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">via VGC</a>), where he was asked if Bethesda would ever remake the original <em>Fallout</em> games. Those first two games are quite different to their successors, being isometric turn-based RPGs. Ever since Bethesda bought the IP from InterPlay Productions, though, the <em>Fallout</em> games have been action-RPGs with real-time combat set in open worlds.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><p> <iframe title="Matty Interviews Todd Howard: Future Of Fallout, Starfield Year 2, Elder Scrolls VI Info, &amp; MORE!" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2ew8LQFGNWU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p></figure> <p data-characters="694" data-current-count="994" data-injectable="true">Newer fans more familiar with the current games may not find those first two <em>Fallout</em> titles as appealing, so Howard was asked if Bethesda has ever considered updating or modernising them. Turns out the answer is no, and it’s because, according to Howard, “the main priority for us is to make sure they’re available and you can still play them” (you can hear his comments from the 21:05 mark in the video above). As he pointed out, the first two <em>Fallout</em> games are currently on PC via Steam, so it’s not like they’re a nightmare to track down. They’re also very cheap, both costing only $9.99/£7.99, and you don’t need a super powerful PC to run them.</p>
 <p data-characters="393" data-current-count="393" data-injectable="false">Howard also suggested that any sort of major update to those early <em>Fallout</em> games would risk sanding off some of their charm: “I would never want to paste over some of that [charm] with “Well, we changed how this works so it’s more modern”. So as long as you can download it, as long as it loads up and runs, I think I’d like people to experience it the way it was.”</p> <p data-characters="640" data-current-count="1033" data-injectable="true">I honestly respect this approach to ensuring games can be played as originally intended. Even if the older games are a bit dated, it’s important that they remain available for the sake of preservation. Howard did add that console ports of <em>Fallout 1</em> and <em>2</em> aren’t a priority either, which is a bit of a shame, but such an effort would admittedly require a lot of time and resources. As Howard put it, “You have to ask yourself “Is that where we want to put our time right now or is it best played the way it was on PC?” and I think right now the best way to play it is on a PC [with a] mouse and keyboard.”</p>
 <p data-characters="343" data-current-count="343" data-injectable="false">If Bethesda would rather ensure its older games are simply available, rather than remaking them, this should hopefully mean the <em>Fallout</em> team is putting all its energy into new entries as well as more <em>Fallout 76</em> content. Even so, <em>Fallout 5</em> won’t be a thing until <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/the-elder-scrolls-6-whats-happening-with-the-skyrim-follow-up/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Elder Scrolls 6</a></em> has launched, and that game also lacks a release date. </p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more about our Affiliate Policy</a></i> </p>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>