<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:54:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Drag x Drive gets a new mode and an offline demo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/03/drag-x-drive-gets-a-new-mode-and-an-offline-demo/</link>
            <guid>1371559</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Nintendo has released an update for their wheelchair basketball multiplayer game, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/drag-x-drive">Drag x Drive</a>. Patch 1.2.0 adds a new game mode for the full game, while also revamping the Global Jam beta test into a regular demo for all to try.</p>
<p>The new game mode is Survival Tag, which is basically exactly what it sounds like. Survival Tag can be played throughout the park lobby with friends, local wireless and LAN, and needs to be started by the lobby host from the X menu.</p>


<p>Elsewhere there’s just some general bug fixed and improvements to the game, which are outlined in the patch notes below.</p>
<p>As for the demo, this allows you to check out the game offline, playing the tutorial, challenging bots in 3v3 matches, and exploring the park. You’ll generally be able to get used to the Joy-Con 2 mouse mode controls and how they work to play the game.</p>
<p>It’s nice to see the game getting some support still, but will it entice any new players to really dive into the game? Looking back on our review of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/08/13/drag-x-drive-review/">Drag x Drive</a>, I said, “Drag x Drive makes good use of the Joy-Con 2 mouse controls for a simple game of wheelchair basketball, but it lacks the charm and personality you’d expect from a Nintendo game.”</p>

<p>Here’s the full Drag x Drive 1.2.0 patch notes:</p>
<p><strong>General Updates</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added the chasing game Survival Tag to friend parks, local wireless parks, and LAN parks.
<ul>
<li>Note: To play Survival Tag when in the parks listed above, the player who created the park opens the X Menu, then selects <strong>Start Survival Tag</strong> on the Players tab.</li>
<li>Depending on the wireless environment, there may be times where player positioning does not perfectly match between users. For that reason, there may be cases where, even if it appears to one player as if contact was made, from the other player’s perspective no contact occurred. In order to limit unpleasant experiences in situations like these as much as possible, in basketball games this may be determined as no contact.</li>
<li>On the other hand, in Survival Tag, the question of contact is the whole crux of the game and is particularly important to game progression. Therefore, it has been designed such that a tag is considered successful if there was contact from either perspective (the tagging player, or the one who was tagged).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Corrected the calculation of Iso Wins on the Game Stats tab under Stats. Previously, it counted the total number of Isos, not just wins.</li>
<li>Added Rope Jumps to Other Stats tab under Stats.</li>
<li>Changed the target of the Focus Cam when near the sumo ring to the sumo ring itself.</li>
<li>Made some adjustments to bots in friend parks, local wireless parks, and LAN parks.
<ul>
<li>Note: We slightly lowered the strength level of the Easy and Standard bots that the player who created the park can add under the Players tab of the X Menu.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Added a feature to enable players to delete their own records.
<ul>
<li>On the screen that displays players’ records before starting time trials or shooting contests, simultaneously press and hold the ZL Button, left directional button, and right directional button on the Joy-Con 2 (L) for 10 seconds to delete the record.</li>
<li>Once deleted, records cannot be restored.</li>
<li>Obtained trophies will remain, even if records are deleted.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Fixed Issues</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed a very rare issue where, due to unintended behavior, the displays for level or total distance would reach the upper limit.</li>
<li>Fixed a rare issue in Circuit Sprint where players sometimes passed through terrain.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where bunny hops made it possible to accelerate to and maintain speed that exceeded top speed.
<ul>
<li>The intended design is that it is only possible to accelerate beyond the normal top speed when driving down a slope or successfully pulling off a halfpipe or ramp trick. However, unintended behavior occurred, such as players accelerating beyond top speed when landing after rotating, or not decelerating while in midair even if they had exceeded top speed. We fixed this because this issue required players to control their character in unintuitive ways in order to achieve good results.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Fixed various issues to create a smoother gaming experience.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: Version 1.1.1 for the <em>Drag x Drive Demo</em> (formerly <em>Drag x Drive: Global Jam</em>) was also released.</p>
<p><strong>General Updates</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Changed software title from <em>Drag x Drive: Global Jam</em> to <em>Drag x Drive Demo</em>.</li>
<li>Changed the software icon that displays in locations such as the HOME Menu.</li>
<li>Made it possible to play the tutorial and certain bot games any time.</li>
<li>Fixed various issues to create a smoother gaming experience.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68646/~/how-to-update-drag-x-drive">Nintendo</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/03/drag-x-drive-gets-a-new-mode-and-an-offline-demo/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MLB The Show Mobile Announced, Out Now In the Philippines]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/mlb-the-show-mobile-announced-sony-san-diego-studios/</link>
            <guid>1371556</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Sony and San Diego Studio are bringing MLB The Show to iOS and Android devices with MLB The Show Mobile. Published by Sony and developed by San Diego Studios, it's already available, though only in the Philippines. It's getting a limited regional release to start, and will roll out globally as development on the game expands.</p>



<p>The free-to-play mobile game will be "<em>a new standalone experience built from the ground up to deliver realistic baseball gameplay on mobile devices</em>," <a href="https://theshowmobile.com/">according to the game's website</a>. If you're keen to swing for the fences with MLB The Show Mobile but you don't live in the Philippines, you can sign up on the website to receive an email when it is available in your region.</p>



<p>The trailer showcases a bit of gameplay and the touch-control-optimized user interface. It also shows a bit of the card system, where players will be able to collect cards and create their all-star team, which will also likely be where the game makes its money.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Preview Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ctcq_G3UclA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>This is the latest mobile venture for Sony, and it's arguably the one that makes the most sense. Baseball lends itself to mobile devices better than other sports and definitely better than some of the other intellectual properties in Sony's portfolio. It's also the latest platform expansion for MLB The Show, which was the first PlayStation exclusive title <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-game-pass-early-march-2024-mlb-the-show-24-control/">to make the jump over to Xbox </a>after the MLB forced the issue to make it happen. </p>



<p>The limited regional release is perhaps the most interesting aspect of this. It feels like Sony and San Diego Studio are trying to take their time before bringing it elsewhere, like the United States, which is, of course, a significant chunk of the baseball market. Though this could just be a quick test ahead of a global launch that'll <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/11/06/goal-setting-mlb-the-show-26/">coincide with the release of MLB The Show 26</a>, which will arrive somewhere in its regular window of early 2026.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/mlb-the-show-mobile-announced-sony-san-diego-studios/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chrono Trigger Doesn’t Need A Remake But I’ll Definitely Play The Heck Out Of One]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/chrono-trigger-remake-dragon-quest-yuji-horii-rpg-2000650055</link>
            <guid>1371547</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Chrono Trigger</em> is very special. It’s a bold and beautiful RPG assembled by some of the best developers working in gaming at the time. Perhaps just as importantly, it holds up remarkably well for a game that <a href="https://kotaku.com/chrono-trigger-jrpg-snes-30th-anniversary-square-1851769192">released on the SNES over 30 years ago</a>. Go play it right now if you haven’t. I promise you it sill looks great, sounds amazing, and packs a neat, evocative, one-of-a-kind story into an incredibly streamlined but satisfying time-travelling structure. I mention all this because <a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-quest-3-remake-changes-horii-gender-elon-musk-1851665687"><em>Dragon Quest</em> creator Yuji Horii</a>, who was also one of the writers on <em>Chrono Trigger</em>, is once again playing coy about Square Enix’s plans for a remake.</p> <p>“I can’t talk about that,” Horii said on the latest episode of the ‘<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nq1II1jaiuA&amp;t=6628s">KosoKoso Hōsō Kyoku</a>‘ talk show livestream (translated by&nbsp;<a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/chrono-triggers-original-supervisor-yuji-horii-says-i-cant-talk-about-it-dont-ask-and-ill-get-in-trouble-when-asked-about-new-developments/">Automaton</a>) when asked if <a href="https://x.com/squareenix_jp/status/1899298993613791338?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1899298993613791338%7Ctwgr%5Edfec9381ad5a12d366a05615b17599a5209267ae%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.eurogamer.net%2Fsquare-enix-celebrating-chrono-trigger-anniversary-with-new-projects-sparking-re-release-hopes">anniversary events</a> for the SNES classic might be leading up to a bigger project. He continued to say he couldn’t talk about it in a way that heavily implied there was something to talk about. “Wait, if I say that, you’ll figure it out!” he added, followed by “Don’t ask!” and “I’ll get in trouble!”</p>

 <h2>Square Enix is in the middle of a remaster frenzy</h2> <p>This might feel like a bit of smoke with no fire if not for the fact that Horii has done this before. At Napoli Comicon, the designer appeared to let slip that <em>Chrono Trigger</em> was getting a remake before following it up with “You have heard nothing.” There <a href="https://x.com/buzz_95b/status/1918366504048804155">was video</a>, and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dragonquest/comments/1kd11di/comment/mq7liqb/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">first-hand accounts from attendees</a>, but it was all a bit messy to parse due to the translations and loud audience reactions. Square Enix later <a href="https://twitter.com/Genki_JPN/status/1923998070309781720?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1923998070309781720%7Ctwgr%5E96578349a12f5ffb6114b601fc5b0fd5fd94b346%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamesradar.com%2Fgames%2Frpg%2Fit-is-a-mistranslation-regarding-a-chrono-trigger-remake-says-square-enix-further-dashing-hopes-of-a-new-version-of-the-iconic-rpg-30-years-after-its-release%2F">followed up</a> to say that Horii had been “mistranslated,” which only convinced fans the remake was even more real.</p>

 <p>But while I absolutely believe at this point that Square Enix is working on something related to <em>Chrono Trigger</em>, what exactly it will be and when, if ever, it’ll see the light of day, is harder to pin down. Square Enix has released all sorts of remasters and remakes running from simple HD updates (<em>Chrono Cross</em>) to HD-2D glow-ups (<em>Dragon Quest III Remake</em>) to complete 3D overhauls (<em>Final Fantasy VII Remake</em>). There’s even Horii’s own upcoming <a href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-quest-7-remake-ps1-switch-2-graphics-chrono-trigger-2000625721"><em>Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</em></a>, which falls somewhere between those last two categories.</p>

 <p>In other words, <em>Chrono Trigger</em> could get a straightforward <em>Pixel Perfect</em>-style upgrade or a full-blown reimagining. My money’s on something simpler. Square Enix has shown a desire to remain pretty conservative when tampering with its classics, and doesn’t necessarily <a href="https://kotaku.com/square-enix-business-plan-multiplatform-1851472456">have the resources</a> to be throwing at a more ambitious remake. Then there’s the fact that things like a rumored remake of <a href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-9-remake-anniversary-merch-rpg-1851773483"><em>Final Fantasy IX</em> are still MIA</a>. As it pulls from its back catalog, Square Enix seems a bit less predictable with what will come out when and in what form.</p>

 <h2>Yes,<em> Chrono Trigger</em> really is that good</h2> <p>Maybe there’s also a little bit of trepidation with trying to “improve” on what’s widely considered to be one of the all-time greats. <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em> game director Brandon Adler was recently gushing about the game with zero caveats. “Let’s just take the actual visuals and the music on that thing,” Adler said on a recent episode of <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/04fCqmmagL4Nz56PAMcvA4?"><em>My Perfect Console</em></a>. “Just aesthetically, the game is gorgeous on so many different fronts. I can still hear the music. The characters, they made such an impact, and they did such interesting things, even in terms of the actual systems behind them, like the [techniques] that were being used.”</p>

 <p>He also complimented the pacing which remains unmatched in the genre. “It doesn’t get enough credit for, although I think the real RPG heads will know this, is the pacing on it is just amazing,” he said. “It’s one of the only JRPGs I can think of where you don’t actually have to grind. You can just play through the entire experience and you don’t have to worry about that aspect of JRPGs. Which, some people like that, but also it’s a grind.”</p> <p>This is the kind of stuff people think about when they call <em>Chrono Trigger</em> <a href="https://kotaku.com/chrono-trigger-the-kotaku-review-1826393914">a “perfect” game</a>, and the kind of thing that would be easy to mess up with a remake that starts reorganizing things at a deeper level than just the look and sound. Those things are precious too, though. Trying to remake that first glimpse of the Kingdom of Zeal would be like going in decades later and trying to monkey around with <em>Laurence of Arabia</em>. Good luck! But also I would 100 percent use it as an excuse to go back and replay<em> Chrono Trigger</em> either way. Some games are too good to be remade. Others are so good that no remake could ever take anything away from them.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/chrono-trigger-remake-dragon-quest-yuji-horii-rpg-2000650055]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[To The Moon Founder Promises To ‘Make It Better’ For 2026 Following Disastrous Expo]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/to-the-moon-founder-make-it-better-for-2026/</link>
            <guid>1371541</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>To The Moon’s inaugural event took place last month in the United Kingdom, and it was, by all accounts, a complete shambles. The images and clips shared on social media painted a picture of a sorry affair in every respect, and many creators made videos exposing the event as an utter failure.</p>



<p>Weeks after the event, To The Moon’s founder, Monty Stewart, has surfaced on LinkedIn with a lengthy statement about what comes next for the expo. He stressed that <strong>it will </strong>be back, and suggested that this year’s expo wasn’t all that bad.</p>







<h2 id="h-to-the-moon-will-return-in-2026">To The Moon Will Return in 2026</h2>



<p>Early in November, To The Moon was on a little marketing kick, and the materials provided suggested that it <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/to-the-moon-expo-recover-uk-games-expo/">planned to revive</a> the UK’s failing gaming expo scene. Fast forward to a weekday in the middle of November, and To The Moon had arrived, halted temporarily by bad weather, poor planning, and an almost empty conference hall in Birmingham, England.</p>



<p>On social media, creators wasted no time sharing images of the event, with some claiming they’d spent hundreds to reach the venue and were left feeling extremely sour and disappointed:</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Alright last little photo dump of To the Moon Expo. These feature the VR Arena, B2B Trade stage, the Indie ‘City’ and the LAN Zone</p><p>Honestly my favourite part is flat hall lighting considering we were meant to be in a (checks notes) Spaceship… <a href="https://t.co/yINWrmiGpW">pic.twitter.com/yINWrmiGpW</a></p></div>— 💽 CaptainAshtro🔜DreamHack (@CaptainAshtro) <a href="https://twitter.com/CaptainAshtro/status/1989293562169843739?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 14, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>







<p>There was almost nothing good to take away from To The Moon, but that’s not how the expo’s founder, Monty Stewart, put it on LinkedIn <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7401872276251631616/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in a recent post</a>:</p>



<blockquote>
<div><p>On a personal level I wanted to say thank you to every single person that has supported and continues to support the vision of To The Moon Expo and attended. Every speaker, exhibitor, attendee and the like.</p><p>Seeing the vast majority of posts on LinkedIn being positive, hearing that some of our indies acquired investment meetings and received invaluable feedback on their games is a check box for me; alongside gamers being able to interact with actual games and their favourite IP’s, not just merch stalls. And let us not forget, we were the largest gathering of unique studios and games under one roof nationally within the UK for 2025.</p><p>If we can help people realise their dreams, acquire the funding they need to shoot for the stars and follow their creative passion; that is a win.</p><p>Were there some learning curves? For sure. Definitely some curveballs with the weather and a couple other aspects, but we continued onwards and adapted with the hand we were dealt.</p><p>Can we make it better? Damn right. How are we going to do that? We are looking to 2026 and moving forward with experience that only progress can teach!</p><p>I cannot wait to share with you what is coming for next year. I am also incredibly grateful to not have to handle the mantle by myself moving forward into 2026.</p><p>Innovation has always belonged those willing to challenge the status quo, not those who cling to it. So to the certain few people who have spent more energy on blocking new ideas than building their own; don’t worry, we aren’t here to replace you. Time will handle that for us.</p><p>We will continue to stand at the Vanguard for our creative industry and our movement to ensure that exhibiting at events is not fiscally gatekept and that creative passion within the UK and the globe can thrive.</p></div>
</blockquote>



<p>Not only does Stewart think the event wasn’t all that bad, but he also intends to come back in 2026 with a new expo, seemingly expecting it to be better received just because he promises it will be.</p>



<p>Some reports came in ahead of the event that revealed how ill-planned it was, even before it landed:</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>I will not be speaking at To The Moon Expo next week</p><p>I was asked to be part of an Esports advisory group for the event some months ago; however, after the announcement, we were never consulted</p><p>The panel that I was put on last minute, had little to no structure &amp; a loose topic</p></div>— Jeff Simpkins (@HereLiesJeff) <a href="https://twitter.com/HereLiesJeff/status/1986463348821467570?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 6, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>







<p>Everyday gamers went to the expo at the NEC in Birmingham expecting a spectacle of an event because of bold marketing claims, but were met with almost nothing to do. One user wrote on X (formerly Twitter), <em>‘Went to see the To the Moon expo today as it was my first ever time heading to see one, it’s just disappointing how little there was to do there, legitimately one area just has consoles connected to monitors with Minecraft installed.’</em></p>



<p>This is a little first-person perspective, but I was invited to attend To The Moon and got cold feet in the morning before making the 2.5-hour drive to Birmingham, instructing my colleague to ‘stay in bed’ because I had some ill juju about the expo. Was that a lucky escape?</p>



<p>Sadly, as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/egx-death-uk-gaming-expo/">EGX has died a death</a>, Insomnia appears to be coming back under some distrustful banner, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/uk-gaming-expo-london-wasd/">WASD has also faded</a> into an abyss; there’s effectively nothing left in the United Kingdom for gamers.</p>







<p>Let us know on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord if you attended To The Moon</a> and what you thought about the event.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/burntpeanut-dr-disrespect-live-on-stream/">TheBurntPeanut lashed out at Dr Disrespect fans on stream</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/to-the-moon-founder-make-it-better-for-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Co-op ‘bullet-heaven’ first-person shooter POSTAL: Bullet Paradise announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/co-op-bullet-heaven-first-person-shooter-postal-bullet-paradise-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>1371538</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Play as multiple Dudes from across the POSTAL series.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Running With Scissors [23 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/running-with-scissors">Running With Scissors</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Goonswarm Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/goonswarm-games">Goonswarm Games</a> have announced <em><a title="Games > POSTAL: Bullet Paradise" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/postal-bullet-paradise">POSTAL: Bullet Paradise</a></em>, a <a title="Genres > Co-Op [354 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> online play-supported “bullet-heaven” <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,834 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a> coming to <a title="Platforms > PC [24,926 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4162690/POSTAL_Bullet_Paradise/" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date was not announced. <span id="more-1010871"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4162690/POSTAL_Bullet_Paradise/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>POSTAL: Bullet Paradise</em> throws the Dude straight into the Shitty Future, a world where every robot, psycho, mutant, and corporate goon wants you very, very dead. Good news: you don’t care. Even better news: there’s plenty of junk lying around that can be turned into guns, bombs, or whatever else makes things explode.</p><p>This is a bullet-heaven <a title="Genres > Shooter [4,343 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> with online cooperative play, an arsenal of improvised weapons, and more psychos than the Dude has unpaid parking tickets. Pick your favorite Dude from across the <em>POSTAL</em> multiverse and carve your way through waves of chaos, upgrades, and stupidly dangerous power fantasy moments.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Play as Multiple Dudes</strong> – Choose from iconic versions of the POSTAL Dude from across the entire series. Each one has unique stats, perks, and attitude problems.</li><li><strong>Online Cooperative Carnage</strong> – Team up with friends (or other unstable strangers) to survive the endless storm of enemies. Revive each other, stack builds, and ruin the future together.</li><li><strong>Bullet-Heaven Gameplay</strong> – Hundreds of enemies on screen. Thousands of projectiles. Zero shame. Movement and build choices matter… mostly because everything is trying to erase you.</li><li><strong>DIY Arsenal</strong> – Trash becomes firepower. Upgrade weird weapons, stack absurd modifiers, and turn broken scraps into overpowered monstrosities.</li><li><strong>The Shitty Future</strong> – A dystopian world filled with psycho, corporate cultists, malfunctioning robots, and way too much surveillance. If it moves, it probably wants to kill you.</li><li><strong>Progression That Actually Feels Good</strong> – Unlock new Dudes and other well-known <em>POSTAL</em> characters, weapons, abilities, and synergies as you survive longer. Die horribly, come back stronger.</li><li><strong>Multiverse Flavor</strong> – <em>POSTAL 1</em>, <em>2</em>, <em>3</em>, <em>4,</em> <em>Brain Damaged</em>… they’re all here. Easter eggs, references, and familiar faces for fans who know the chaos by heart.</li><li><strong>Stupid Jokes, Smart Explosions</strong> – <em>POSTAL</em>-style humor and a lot of things blowing up. Sometimes both at once.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="POSTAL: Bullet Paradise Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U3JIS9F2gdY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/co-op-bullet-heaven-first-person-shooter-postal-bullet-paradise-announced-for-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hello Kitty Skyland launches in Early Access on December 22]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/hello-kitty-skyland-launches-in-early-access-on-december-22</link>
            <guid>1371535</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Free-to-play social virtual reality game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [482 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">Free-to-play</a> social <a title="Genres > Virtual Reality [214 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/virtual-reality">virtual reality</a> game <em><a title="Games > Hello Kitty Skyland [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hello-kitty-skyland">Hello Kitty Skyland</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > Quest [162 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest 2 and Quest 3</a> via <a href="https://www.meta.com/experiences/hello-kitty-skyland/24351103704475532/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Meta Store</a> on December 22, developer <a title="Companies > Thirdverse [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/thirdverse">Thirdverse</a> announced. <span id="more-1010879"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Thirdverse:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Early Access Overview</strong></p><p>In Early Access, players will gain access to the central online lobby area of SKYLAND and experience core content, including the <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [647 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> competitive race game, “Sky Dash.”</p><p>The avatar dress-up system will also feature a variety of original outfits, as well as limited-time avatar costumes themed around Hello Kitty, Kuromi, and My Melody, allowing players to express themselves in unique and charming ways.</p><p>During the Early Access period, the development team will gather player feedback and continue adding content toward the full release.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>About the Game</strong></p><p><em>Hello Kitty Skyland</em> is a new social virtual reality game set in a virtual world called SKYLAND, where Sanrio characters appear. Players from around the globe can gather and enjoy a variety of activities and social interactions.</p><p>In addition to immersive encounters with Sanrio characters in VR, the game includes full-body multiplayer activities, avatar decoration features, and many other virtual reality-native experiences.</p><p>Players can enjoy a wide range of content through customization, cooperation, and discovery.</p></blockquote><p>Watch the launch trailer below.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Hello Kitty Skyland Early Access Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nT1xKssTTOE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/hello-kitty-skyland-launches-in-early-access-on-december-22]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Breaks Game Pass Records]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-breaks-game-pass-records/1100-6536666/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1371532</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536666">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 has been one of 2025's standout hits, and now it's been confirmed that the game broke records for Xbox Game Pass.</p><p>Microsoft announced that Expedition 33 has become the "biggest new third-party game launch on Xbox Game Pass of 2025" based on number of unique users in the first 30 days. It's not clear what title Expedition 33 took down to become No. 1 for third-party games on Game Pass.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1065774010" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466022,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Clair%20Obscur%3A%20Expedition%2033%20GameSpot%20Video%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:656,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/clair-obscur-expedition-33-gamespot-video-review\/2300-6466022\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466022\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466022\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466022\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466022&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466022,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6536666&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;clair-obscur-expedition-33&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-series-x,pc,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;kepler-interactive,maximum-entertainment&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466022},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466022\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4502935-expedition33_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/j1GGcoTJ.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1748876400,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="j1GGcoTJ" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 GameSpot Video Review</p>
      </div>
<p>Expedition 33 was developed by Sandfall Interactive, and it was the team's first game. Creative director Guilllaume Broche said, "This year has been so far beyond what any of us could have imagined, and it's down to how passionate and supportive our fans have been to make that a reality."</p><p>The game launched the same week this past April as Microsoft's own Oblivion Remastered, and some feared that Expedition 33 could be overshadowed by the RPG. However, Sandfall said this was not the case and that launching close to Oblivion Remastered <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/oblivion-remastered-didnt-steamroll-expedition-33-publisher-says/1100-6531269/" data-ref-id="1100-6531269">had no meaningful effect.</a></p><p>Guy Richards, who works for Xbox, said he understood Sandfall's ambition from the onset of meeting the team. "Once we played early builds, we experienced their gripping story, stunning visuals, and the mix of JRPG mechanics with French cultural themes that felt fresh and distinctive. It's the kind of experience we knew Xbox players would love to discover," Richards said.</p><p>Broche said taking a deal from Microsoft to put Expedition 33 on Game Pass worked out for the studio and the game in part because it allowed the game to reach people who "might not have" tried a title like it.</p><p>"The turn-based RPG genre has a lot of fans but sometimes it might put people who prefer more real-time action games off, but Game Pass lowered that barrier of entry," he said. "They could just try it and see how it feels. So a lot of curious players could start the game, explore Lumière and the early game, and realize there's a lot to enjoy here, even if they weren't expecting it at first."</p><p>Expedition 33 is available now with Game Pass Ultimate and PC Game Pass, or it can be purchased outright for $50, though it's on sale right now for $40. It's also available on PS5.</p><p>Expedition 33 is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/all-the-game-awards-2025-winners-nominees/2900-7258/" data-ref-id="2900-7258">nominated for 12 awards at The Game Awards</a>, which is the most nominations for a single game in the event's history. The biggest award it's up for is Game of the Year. Actor Charlie Cox, who plays Gustave, is nominated for Best Performance, but he wants to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/expedition-33-actor-says-hes-truly-grateful-for-outpouring-of-support-after-charlie-cox-spoke-out/1100-6536509/" data-ref-id="1100-6536509">share the credit with motion-capture performer Maxence Cazoria</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-breaks-game-pass-records/1100-6536666/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coffee Stain and Paradox veterans unveil new studio Feeble Minds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/coffee-stain-and-paradox-veterans-unveil-new-studio-feeble-minds</link>
            <guid>1371529</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/diego-arguello" data-discover="true">Diego Argüello</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Contributing Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">December 3, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>1 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Newsbrief</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">: Oscar Jilsén and Mikael Mård, two of the co-founders of Coffee Stain Studios—of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Goat Simulator</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Satisfactory</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> fame—have unveiled a new studio alongside a cohort that includes Paradox's former product owner and programmer manager, Johan Gustafsson.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Announced via a press release, Feeble Minds is a ten-person Swedish studio founded in 2022. The staff also includes </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Satisfactory</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> composer and Insert Coin founder Jannik Reuterberg and former PocApp Studios art director Sofie Irenheim.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">“At Feeble Minds, we have a mix of experienced people who worked on some big titles at places like Coffee Stain and Paradox, alongside fresh new talent," said Reuterberg, the CEO of the new studio. "In that image, we are working hard to create a rich world that combines the best elements of games we love with new ideas to create something new and amazing."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Feeble Minds' debut title is called </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Serpent's Gaze</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, introduced as a soulslike for up to four players that also draws inspiration from roguelikes. A demo will be available on Steam later today.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Diego Nicolás Argüello is a freelance journalist and critic from Argentina. Video games helped him to learn English, so now he covers them for places like The New York Times, NPR, Rolling Stone, and more. He also runs Into the Spine, a site dedicated to fostering and supporting new writers, and co-hosted Turnabout Breakdown, a podcast about the Ace Attorney series. He’s most likely playing a rhythm game as you read this.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/coffee-stain-and-paradox-veterans-unveil-new-studio-feeble-minds]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mini Review: Metroid Prime 4: Beyond (Switch 1) - An Impressive Version If You've Yet To Upgrade]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/metroid-prime-4-beyond</link>
            <guid>1371517</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<p>Smooth as a Morph Ball 'round a half pipe</p>
<p><strong>Version Reviewed:</strong> North American</p>
</section><section>
<p>After having completed <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> on Switch 2, booting the game up on the original Switch was an immediately familiar, if bizarre experience. The game was almost certainly made with Nintendo’s 2017 system in mind from the off given how long it’s been in development, and yet there’s something about playing it on the original Switch that just feels… odd.</p>
<p>Don’t leap to any mad conclusions. It plays very well at a very solid 60fps in both docked and handheld, but after getting used to seeing Viewros in stunning 4K (or an internal resolution approaching it), it’s surprising how much the art direction seems to have been built with this in mind. This also lacks the (<a href="https://www.digitalfoundry.net/reviews/metroid-prime-4-proves-retro-studios-prowess-on-switch-2#:~:text=In%20either%20resolution,of%20existing%20abilities.">excellent</a>) HDR support of the NS2 Edition.</p>
<p>Playing this on Switch 1 when docked feels fine enough, but that crispness, that pop, that ludicrously intricate, high-contrast detail, it’s just a bit fuzzy and pixelly by comparison. I personally feel it’s almost the direct antithesis to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Pokémon Legends Z-A</a>, which actually felt as though the art style was more cohesive on the weaker platform. Textures have taken an understandable hit, and models that are further away can look quite smeary, but overall the game still looks good. I just can't help but compare it unfavourably to Switch 2.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:194214 @ 1764773209 -->
<p>Handheld takes things further down, as you would hopefully have already guessed. Wide shots of Samus when she’s being loaded into the transport cannon thing just don’t look right, as though you’ve somehow mucked up some settings; you can taste the sub-720p-ness. It’s perfectly passable for such aged hardware, but I can’t help but feel that as time went on, the Switch 2 version became the focus. It's safe to say things in the final build aren't the crystal-clear examples we were shown in earlier trailers.</p>
<p>That’s another change you can expect: loading screens. They’re relatively brisk on Switch 2 to the point that Ollie rightfully didn’t feel the need to mention them in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">our primary review of the Nintendo Switch 2 Edition</a>, but on Switch 1 you really feel them. Some of them are easily double and even triple the length, which can be a pain if you’re doing a lot of jumping from one area to another in quick succession.</p>
<p>All that being said, the game runs just as smoothly as it does in the Switch 2’s quality mode. I wasn’t able to shake the 60fps target at all, bar perhaps one exception when out in the Sol Valley when I presume some enemy models were loading. It simultaneously feels like it’s pushing the old hardware to its absolute limit, and yet manages to run at 60fps without breaking a sweat.</p>
<p>If Switch 1 is your only means of playing Metroid Prime 4: Beyond, you’re not going to have <em>quite</em> the same experience, but if you’re not looking to upgrade anytime soon and you’re keen to jump into Samus’ latest adventure, it's well worth picking up, as there's a fantastic game to be had. Just keep your visual expectations in check after seeing all that delicious Switch 2 Edition footage.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/metroid-prime-4-beyond]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World’s New Update Does The Most Obnoxious Thing]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-world-update-1-4-0-patch-notes-track-volume-2000650066</link>
            <guid>1371508</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-sale-cyber-monday-mario-kart-world-walmart-amazon-2000649232"><i><span>Mario Kart World</span></i></a> <span>got a </span><a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68580/~/how-to-update-mario-kart-world"><span>major patch last night</span></a><span>, and most of the changes in the update are what you’d expect. There are some bug fixes, track tweaks, and some smaller stuff, like making specific items respawn faster. But on top of all this good stuff, Nintendo also did one of the most obnoxious, Nintendo-ass things it could have possibly done by making its audio settings a toggle, rather than a slider for players to adjust to their liking.</span></p> <p><span>As demonstrated by <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/kzxcellent.live/post/3m72cm4q6zk2t">this clip</a>, </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-world-patch-online-three-lap-2000628126"><i><span>Mario Kart World</span></i><span>’s</span></a><span> new update adds a “Music Volume” option in the racer’s settings that lets you adjust how loud the music is while you’re driving around and throwing blue shells at each other. However, the only options you have in this setting are “Normal” and “Loud.” You can’t tweak these presets at all, and most people who adjust the music volume in video games aren’t making it </span><i><span>louder</span></i><span>; they’re usually trying to balance it so they can hear audio cues, voice acting, or whatever they’re trying to hone in on.&nbsp;</span></p> <figure id="attachment_2000650068" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000650068"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000650068">© Nintendo / @kzxcellent.live on Bluesky / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p><span>Audio options can be helpful for a lot of reasons, but they are, at their core, an accessibility accommodation, and Nintendo has a history of weird oversights like this. </span><i><span>Pokémon Sword </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Shield </span></i><span>famously locked its audio settings behind </span><a href="https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Hi-tech_Earbuds"><span>an in-game item</span></a><span> you couldn’t get until you were hours into the game. Adding music volume settings and making it a toggle that only gets louder, rather than quieter, sounds like someone at Nintendo heard someone asking for audio options, then didn’t bother to ask why or what they should do. It’s annoying, but it’s also incredibly funny because it feels like Nintendo is so insistent that it isn’t going along with the rest of the industry that it won’t even look at other games or companies as a reference for how to handle basic quality-of-life settings.</span></p> <p><span>The full patch notes are as follows:&nbsp;</span></p> <p><strong>General</strong></p> <ul> <li>Added “Custom Items” to the item rules. <ul> <li>This is a feature that lets you set which items appear.</li> <li>This is supported in “VS Race”, “Balloon Battle”, “Coin Runners”, and “Room” in “Online Play” or “Wireless Play”.</li> </ul> </li> <li>Made it so that music track name and source title of the track that is playing will be displayed on the Pause Menu.</li> <li>Added “Music Volume” to “Settings/Controller”.</li> <li>Made it so players who gathered in a “Room” of “Online Play” can participate in “Race”, “Knockout Tour”, and “Battle”. <ul> <li>Up to 4 players can participate in “Race”, “Knockout Tour”, and “Battle”.</li> </ul> </li> <li>Made it so you can join in with friends who are playing “Knockout Tour” from “Friends” in “2p”, “Online Play” as well.</li> <li>Added “Restart” and “Next Race” in the Pause Menu for “VS Race” in “Single Player”.</li> <li>Made it so you can select “Photo Mode” from the Pause Menu in “Race against Ghost” in “Time Trials”.</li> <li>Changed the course layout of below courses for “VS Race”, or “Race” in “Online Play” or “Wireless Play”. <ul> <li> <ul> <li>Race that heads from “Koopa Troopa Beach” to “DK Spaceport”.</li> <li>Race that heads from “Koopa Troopa Beach” to “Crown City”.</li> <li>Race that heads from “Koopa Troopa Beach” to “Peach Stadium”.</li> <li>Race that heads from “Whistlestop Summit” to “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</li> <li>Race that heads from “Desert Hills” to “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</li> <li>Race that heads from “DK Spaceport” to “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</li> <li>Race that heads from “Crown City” to “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</li> <li>Race that heads from “Peach Stadium” to “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p>*Changed it so that, in all races heading toward “Koopa Troopa Beach”, including the above courses, you will cross the finish line after two laps once you arrive at “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</p></li> <li>You will now dash when riding on Manta Ramp’s back.</li> <li>Made it so the player will not hit Dragoneel when transformed into Bullet Bill.</li> <li>Made it so the player cannot use a second Boo while already using a Boo, when holding two Boos.</li> <li>When Dash Food is taken by someone, shortened the time until that Dash Food reappears.</li> <li>When a coin placed on water is taken by someone, shortened the time until that coin reappears.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Fixed Issues</strong></p> <ul> <li>Fixed an issue where the dash time was not correct after a Charge Jump.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through a wall when being stomped on from above by a vehicle driving on the road.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where a player would be squashed when touching a Thwomp that had landed.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where a Bullet Bill would not be displayed after using it.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where a character would be blurry even when making “Focus” “Character” when taking a photo in “Photo Mode” on the Pause Menu.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the screen would look distorted if entering a pipe at the same time as joining a Free Roam in “Online Play”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where player could not get in a UFO when multiple players tried to get in a UFO at the same time in Free Roam in “Online Play”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where a friend’s information would not be updated when looking at the list of friends in “Friends” in “Online Play”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where there would be a communication error when looking at a group ID in “View Room Info” when participating in a group in “Friends” in “Online Play”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where a player’s place would go down if retiring during “Knockout Tour” in “Online Play”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where a player that is seen when spectating looks like they are going off the course over and over during “Knockout Tour” in “Online Play” or “Wireless Play”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player’s own character or vehicle would change when starting “Online Play” or “Wireless Play” again after quitting a game after “Knockout Tour” in “Online Play” or “Wireless Play”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where a player would get stuck on a wall when using a Bullet Bill while falling off the course in “Sky-High Sundae”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where a Bullet Bill would go outside the course when using it on the final curve in “Boo Cinema”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through a bulldozer in “Toad’s Factory”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on a spotlight in the race that heads from “Toad’s Factory” to “Bowser’s Castle” when transformed into Bullet Bill.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where if the player used a Bullet Bill or Spiny Shell in the first curve of “Desert Hills”, it would get stuck on a rock.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on a tree when using a Bullet Bill on “DK Pass”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where, when the player was small because of Lightning, they would slip through the wall on the final curve of “DK Pass.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on a billboard when transforming into Bullet Bill in the race that heads from “Crown City” to “Desert Hills”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through the ring of stone when using a Bullet Bill or Mega Mushroom while falling in “Great&nbsp;? Block Ruins” right before the final curve.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on the ground on the meadows near “Big Donut”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through the wall if rewinding after wall riding in the special room you can go to from a pipe in “Shy Guy Bazaar”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would still fall into the lava even though they have “Smart Steering” ON in “Dry Bones Burnout”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course when using a Bullet Bill while rail riding in “Wario Stadium”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would not be able to glide if getting on a glide panel while gliding in the race that heads from “Wario Stadium” to “Airship Fortress”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on the ground while heading from “Wario Stadium” to “Airship Fortress”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the vehicle would float up from the rail when the player did a rail ride after a wall ride in a bike-type vehicle in “Wario Stadium”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course when using a Bullet Bill on the shortcut while heading from “Dandelion Depths” to “Cheep Cheep Falls” in the “Ice Rally” of “Knockout Tour”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course while gliding, while heading from “Dandelion Depths” to “Cheep Cheep Falls” in the “Moon Rally” of “Knockout Tour”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where a green shell would get stuck on the ground while heading from “Airship Fortress” to “Dry Bones Burnout” in the “Heart Rally” of “Knockout Tour”.</li> <li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course when they transformed into Bullet Bill on top of a building in “Crown City” in the below races: <ul> <li>Race that heads from “DK Spaceport” to “Crown City”.</li> <li>Race that heads from “Koopa Troopa Beach” to “Crown City”.</li> <li>Race that heads from “Faraway Oasis” to “Crown City”.</li> </ul> </li> <li>Several other issues have been addressed to improve the gameplay experience.</li> </ul>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/mario-kart-world-update-1-4-0-patch-notes-track-volume-2000650066]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Strikes Google Hard, Now Selling Fitbit Charge 6 at All-Time Low After Cyber Monday]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-strikes-google-hard-now-selling-fitbit-charge-6-at-all-time-low-after-cyber-monday-2000650049</link>
            <guid>1371505</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Amazon extended its Cyber Week deals into December with continued discounts on major brands including Fitbit, which Google acquired to strengthen its wearables lineup. The <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5847/">Fitbit Charge 6 fitness tracker dropped to $99 on Amazon, matching the Cyber Monday price and slashing $60 off the regular $159 tag</a> and this all-time low makes the Charge 6 accessible for anyone who wants detailed health tracking.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5847/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Heart Rate Accuracy</h2>
<p>The Fitbit Charge 6<strong> sends your heart rate in real time to exercise machines</strong> that can use Bluetooth which means that treadmills, ellipticals, and stationary bikes can show your actual heart rate instead of using their often-unreliable handlebar sensors. This connection is important for interval training or heart rate zone workouts where you need exact feedback to keep up the right level of intensity. Fitbit changed the heart rate sensor array on the Charge 6 to <strong>make it more accurate during high-intensity movements</strong>. This was done in response to complaints that previous models lost tracking during vigorous exercise.</p>
<p>The <strong>built-in GPS records your pace, distance, and elevation data</strong> while you run, walk, or ride your bike outside. You don’t need to bring your phone with you; the data will sync with the Fitbit app once you’re back in Bluetooth range. You can leave your phone behind while you work out and still get all the information about your route for later analysis. The GPS receiver locks onto satellites quickly, unlike older fitness trackers that sometimes took a few minutes to get a signal.</p>



<p>When you start directions on your phone, <strong>Google Maps integration shows turn-by-turn directions right on the Charge 6’s screen</strong>. This puts navigation prompts on your wrist so you can see them without taking out your phone. With Google Wallet support, you can tap to pay at checkout terminals with cards stored in your Google account. This means you don’t have to carry your wallet around when you run quick errands or go get coffee. When you play music through the app on your phone, music controls show up on the tracker’s display. This lets you control playback without having to touch your device while you work out.</p>
<p><strong>Sleep trackin</strong>g keeps track of how long you spend in light, deep, and REM sleep stages during the night. This gives you more information about the quality of your sleep than just the total hours you slept. The Sleep Score algorithm takes into account how long you slept, how restful it was, and how well it restored you to create a single number that tells you how well you actually slept. Morning readiness scores look at your recent activity, sleep, and heart rate variability to suggest whether you should work hard or take it easy during your workout today. Stress management tools check your heart rate variability and start guided breathing sessions when the tracker sees that your stress levels are too high.</p>



<p>The <strong>six-month Premium membership that comes with it</strong> gives you access to advanced analytics, guided programs, and detailed health metrics that help you see patterns in your data. Premium gives you daily readiness scores, advanced sleep analysis, and workout suggestions that are tailored to your fitness level and recent activity. You can keep using core tracking features after the trial period ends without paying for Premium, but you won’t be able to access the extra insights and guided content.</p>
<p>Depending on how often you use GPS and other power-hungry features,<strong> the battery can last up to seven days between charges</strong>. This is a huge improvement over smartwatches that need to be charged every night. When you don’t have much time, quick charging adds a full day of battery in just 12 minutes. Fitbit i<strong>ncludes both small and large bands in the box</strong>&nbsp;so the tracker can fit wrists that are 5.5 to 8.1 inches around without the need to buy extra bands.</p>
<p>The Charge 6 is now in the entry-level fitness tracker price range at $99, but it has features that are usually only found on devices that cost $150 or more. The $60 discount and six months of Premium included make this a great deal because Premium costs $10 a month on its own.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5847/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-strikes-google-hard-now-selling-fitbit-charge-6-at-all-time-low-after-cyber-monday-2000650049]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign DLC Release Times—All The Forsaken Hollows Start Times]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-dlc-release-times-the-forsaken-hollows/</link>
            <guid>1371502</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>It’s another huge whammy of Elden Ring Nightreign content as The Forsaken Hollows takes night-dwelling explorers into new realms of difficulty and discovery. The Elden Ring Nightreign DLC start times are essential for those seeking fresh challenges.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-the-forsaken-hollows-dlc-release-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Forsaken Hollows DLC</a> is the first full content for Nightreign. Updates have been supplied since day one, but The Forsaken Hollows adds new characters, a fresh Shifting Earth, and more.</p>



<p>If more hell and hellacious boss battles sound like your cup of tea, then read on for Elden Ring Nightreign’s The Forsaken Hollows DLC start times.</p>







<h2 id="h-what-time-does-elden-ring-nightreign-the-forsaken-hollows-dlc-start">What Time Does Elden Ring Nightreign The Forsaken Hollows DLC Start?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>It’ll be a long night. Credit to FromSoftware</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Elden Ring Nightreign’s The Forsaken Hollows DLC first goes live at 3 PM PST on December 3 for PC players, and then at 9 PM for console players.</strong></p>







<p>Yes, there are unique dual-start times for every region across PC and consoles—PlayStation and Xbox. If you need a full breakdown of a more specific region, Insider Gaming has been able to track down an extensive list of start times, regions, and on which platform they fall.</p>



<h2 id="h-all-elden-ring-nightreign-dlc-release-times">All Elden Ring Nightreign DLC Release Times</h2>



<p><strong>The global release times for Elden Ring Nightreign’s DLC include PST, CST, GMT, AST, and many more.</strong></p>



<p>Here’s the promised full list of global start times and time zones.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Elden Ring Nightreign The Forsaken Hollows DLC Release Times &amp; Dates On PC</th><th data-align="center">Elden Ring Nightreign The Forsaken Hollows DLC Release Times &amp; Dates On Console</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">PST</td><td data-align="center">3:00 PM—December 3</td><td data-align="center">9:00 PM—December 3</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">CST</td><td data-align="center">5:00 PM—December 3</td><td data-align="center">11:00 PM—December 3</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">EST</td><td data-align="center">6:00 PM—December 3</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">COT</td><td data-align="center">6:00 PM—December 3</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">BRT</td><td data-align="center">8:00 PM—December 3</td><td data-align="center">2:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">GMT</td><td data-align="center">11:00 PM—December 3</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">CET</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">EET</td><td data-align="center">1:00 AM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">SAST</td><td data-align="center">1:00 AM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">MSK</td><td data-align="center">2:00 AM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">AST</td><td data-align="center">2:00 AM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">GST</td><td data-align="center">3:00 AM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">UTC+7</td><td data-align="center">6:00 AM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">UTC+8</td><td data-align="center">7:00 AM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">AEDT</td><td data-align="center">10:00 AM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">JST</td><td data-align="center">8:00 AM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">KST</td><td data-align="center">8:00 AM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">NZDT</td><td data-align="center">12:00 PM—December 4</td><td data-align="center">12:00 AM—December 4</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>Are you getting Elden Ring Nightreign The Forsaken Hollows immediately? Does it look worth the price of admission? Let everyone know through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Official Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>To kill some time, make sure you know that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/you-can-learn-about-elden-ring-lore-through-a-new-400-page-book/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">You Can Learn About Elden Ring Lore Through A Stunning 400-Page Book</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/elden-ring-nightreign-dlc-release-times-the-forsaken-hollows/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leaks Confirm Pokémon Pokopia Post-Apocalyptic Fan Theory]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/leaks-confirm-pokemon-pokopia-post-apocalyptic-fan-theory/</link>
            <guid>1371496</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Pokémon fans appear to have hit the nail on the head with a huge fan theory regarding Pokémon Pokopia, with leaks confirming the speculation.</p>



<p>Pokémon Pokopia <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-pokopia-release-date-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">releases on March 5, 2026</a>, putting players in control of a playable Ditto that has transformed into a human, with the game’s setting showing islands filled with Pokémon but no humans in sight.</p>



<p>That has led to intense speculation that Pokémon Pokopia takes place in a post-apocalyptic world, and a fresh leak seems to confirm that environment.</p>







<h2 id="h-leaked-pokemon-pokopia-map-shows-post-apocalyptic-kanto">Leaked Pokémon Pokopia Map Shows Post-Apocalyptic Kanto</h2>



<figure></figure>



<p>Posting on X, <a href="https://x.com/CentroLeaks/status/1996007165002199320" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CentroLeaks</a> shared what is claimed to be the Pokémon Pokopia map, and the translation shows that a post-apocalyptic adventure through Kanto is on the cards.</p>



<p>Areas on the map include Fuschia, with “dried up and unfertilized fieldland,” Pewter, “an abandoned mine covered by rocks,” and, perhaps the most telling of them all, the Viridian Area with a “never-ending burning forest of ash.”</p>



<p>All of those areas are well known in the Kanto region, with Fuschia City being the home of the Safari Zone, Pewter City presenting the first gym badge test against Brock, and Viridian Forest being one of the first areas players explore in the world of Kanto.</p>



<p>Additional content, reportedly arriving in DLC or as part of post-launch updates, includes areas for Cerulean, Cinnibar, Lavender, and Celedon.</p>



<p>Ever since the first trailer of Pokémon Pokopia appeared, fans have theorized that the game’s setting would be a post-apocalptic version of Kanto, with major hints including a destroyed first-generation Pokédex and the remnants of buildings like Pokémon Centers.</p>



<p>Fans have also theorised that Peakychu, the mysterious ghost-like version of Pikachu, is the deceased version of Red’s partner Pokémon Pokopia, and Mosslax, a Snorlax covered in greenery, is the same Snorlax that players in the Kanto region are tasked with waking up by using the Pokéflute.</p>



<p>It remains to be seen whether those theories are true, and it could be that Pokémon Pokopia takes place in an alternate universe away from the main franchise. </p>



<p>While this may seem far-fetched, Pokémon has blown open the doors to craziness with the likes of time-travelling in Pokémon Legends: Z-A and wormholes in Ultra Sun &amp; Ultra Moon.</p>







<hr>



<p>What secrets do you think Pokémon Pokopia has in store? Share your theories in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Pokémon, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-ascended-heroes-secret-rares-revealed-in-japans-mega-dream-ex/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">secret rare cards revealed for the Ascended Heroes TCG set</a>, and take a look at <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-dlc-will-break-level-100-cap-for-first-time-ever/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how the franchise is breaking the level 100 cap for the first time</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/leaks-confirm-pokemon-pokopia-post-apocalyptic-fan-theory/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Co-op action RPG Serpent’s Gaze announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/co-op-action-rpg-serpents-gaze-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>1371493</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a title="Companies > Feeble Minds" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/feeble-minds">Feeble Minds</a>, a new studio founded by former Coffee Stain Studio founders, has announced <em><a title="Games > Serpent's Gaze [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/serpents-gaze">Serpent’s Gaze</a></em>, a <a title="Genres > Co-Op [354 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,875 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> that “blends the tactical combat and epic bosses of a Soulslike with the power creeping build-creation of <a title="Genres > Roguelike [400 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">roguelikes</a>.” A demo is available now for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,926 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3069050/Serpents_Gaze/" target="_blank">Steam</a>. <span id="more-1010741"></span></p><p>“We’re really excited to officially unveil our studio to the world, give you a first look at our new game, <em>Serpent’s Gaze</em>, and let you try it out right away with our demo,” said Feeble Minds CEO Jannik Reuterberg in a press release. “At Feeble Minds, we have a mix of experienced people who worked on some big titles at places like Coffee Stain and Paradox, alongside fresh new talent. In that image, we are working hard to create a rich world that combines the best elements of games we love with new ideas to create something new and amazing. We can’t wait to hear your feedback on the demo and share more as we continue to work on the game!”</p><div id="carousel_1010743"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Feeble Minds:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Serpent’s Gaze</em> is a punishing one-to-four-player cooperative third-person <a title="Genres > Action [3,248 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> where you fight tough enemies and relentless bosses, all while uncovering the secrets of an ancient desert.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>Serpent’s Gaze</em> features handcrafted levels, with no procedural generation, best enjoyed in up to four-player cooperative play, though the game can also be played in single-player. Every run is unique thanks to a “Curse” system that applies stacking difficulty modifiers to your runs, from invading enemies, to minibosses that will hunt you down. Construct powerful builds on each run to overcome the many challenges you will face.</p><p>You play as a scion—given life by the withering tree god Magnolia, with the sole purpose of vanquishing the opposing gods and usurpers who currently rule the lands. There is only one path towards that goal—violence. But you choose how to tread that path, and along the way you’ll learn more about the secrets of the desert and the truth behind your patron in a story that subtly unfolds as you play.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Soulslike Combat With a Roguelike Twist</strong> – Choose your favorite weapon and fight tough enemies in heavy, tactical combat, with a plethora of different upgrade possibilities. Fight your way through handcrafted levels, and face the bosses—as many times as you need.</li><li><strong>Play as a Team, or Face the Challenges Alone</strong> – With support for up to 4 players, you can face the challenges of the world together with your teammates, or play at your own pace alone.</li><li><strong>Gather Blessings and Choose Your Playstyle</strong> – As you progress through levels, you find upgrades along the way—blessings from strange deities, gifts from your patron and strange relics to utilize in your pilgrimage. Choose wisely and explore endless builds and strategies.</li><li><strong>Get Cursed by the Gods, and Adapt to New Challenges</strong> – The Curse system introduces random variables every run—everything from minibosses hunting you, to environmental hazards that keep new runs fresh and challenging. The Awareness system brings even more challenges, making each successful run progressively harder.</li><li><strong>Explore an <a title="Companies > Ancient [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ancient">Ancient</a> Desert and Its <a title="Games > Myst (2020) [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/myst-2020">Myst</a>eries</strong> – Battle through imposing environments inhabited by different factions. The desert and ruins belong to the nomadic Majin, while the city with its cathedrals is inhabited by the proud Attar’Esh.</li><li><strong>Uncover the Intent of Your Creator</strong> – You are a scion—brought to life by the withering tree god Magnolia, with the sole purpose of vanquishing the opposing gods and usurpers who currently rule the lands. There is only one way to make the desert bloom again—violence.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/serpents-gaze/december-3-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Serpent's Gaze - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BjY5VxGNeQA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/co-op-action-rpg-serpents-gaze-announced-for-pc]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New PS5 Update Out Now, Doesn't Do Much]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-ps5-update-out-now-doesnt-do-much/1100-6536665/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1371490</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6536665">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>A new PlayStation 5 system software update is out now, but don't expect a whole lot in terms of new features. This update, like many before it, is focused on system stability.</p><p>The new update, which brings the PS5 up to version 25.08-12.40.00, makes improvements to messages and usability on some screens, and also improves performance and stability generally.</p><p>Companies like Sony historically don't like to change things up too drastically with system updates around the holidays, and this new update is in keeping with that tradition.</p><h3>PS5 version: 25.08-12.40.00</h3><ul><li>We've improved the messages and usability on some screens</li><li>We've improved system software performance and stability</li></ul><p>If you're looking for a new PS5 game to play, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-black-friday-game-deals/1100-6536418/" data-ref-id="1100-6536418">plenty of top PS5 exclusives are still on sale</a>, even though Black Friday and Cyber Monday have concluded.</p><p>Sony has sold <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-5-sales-draw-even-with-ps4-and-ghost-of-yotei-has-a-big-debut/1100-6536128/" data-ref-id="1100-6536128">more than 84 million PS5 units worldwide</a> since the system launched in November 2020, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/playstation-5-sales-draw-even-with-ps4-and-ghost-of-yotei-has-a-big-debut/1100-6536128/" data-ref-id="1100-6536128">those sales put the system in line with the PS4.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

    
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536618&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/red-dead-redemptions-new-modern-upgrade-shown-off-in-first-gameplay-footage\/1100-6536618\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536599&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/nintendo-switch-2-mario-kart-console-bundle-is-discounted-for-cyber-monday\/1100-6536599\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536461&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-plus-essential-free-games-for-december-2025\/1100-6536461\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536608&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cyberpunk-2077-is-teasing-something-for-its-fifth-anniversary-heres-when-to-tune-in\/1100-6536608\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536596&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/wow-housing-is-finally-here-but-there-is-a-crack-in-the-foundation\/1100-6536596\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536635&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/after-120-hours-in-arc-raiders-i-finally-killed-another-player\/1100-6536635\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6524133&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-remake-deals\/1100-6524133\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536590&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/hollow-knight-silksong-creators-confirm-dlc-is-coming\/1100-6536590\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536603&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/heres-how-to-buy-a-house-in-wow-step-by-step\/1100-6536603\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536617&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/despite-past-viral-ai-fakes-this-grand-theft-auto-6-leak-looks-real\/1100-6536617\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534941&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2026-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6534941\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535971&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-echoes-of-victory-ridge-quest-guide\/1100-6535971\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536018&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-celestes-journals-quest-guide\/1100-6536018\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536648&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/red-dead-redemptions-new-version-launched-with-a-big-issue-on-xbox\/1100-6536648\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535922&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/all-arc-raiders-quests-full-mission-list\/1100-6535922\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535962&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-the-majors-footlocker-quest-guide\/1100-6535962\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6536647&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/avoweds-fall-update-has-been-pushed-to-2026-will-now-include-more-content\/1100-6536647\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6535965&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arc-raiders-keeping-the-memory-quest-guide\/1100-6535965\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-ps5-update-out-now-doesnt-do-much/1100-6536665/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rolling Stone's GOTY List Shows A Whole Lot Of Love For One Nintendo Mascot]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/rolling-stones-goty-list-shows-a-whole-lot-of-love-for-one-nintendo-mascot</link>
            <guid>1371466</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="9723cb0e65e17"><a title="Clair Obscur" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/9723cb0e65e17/clair-obscur.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Sandfall Interactive</em></figcaption></figure><p>How on earth is it that time of year again already? It feels as though we can still sense the tight elastic of our tiny <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-air-riders">Kirby</a> swimming trunks digging into our fresh summer sunburn, and yet <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming-lists/best-video-games-of-2025-1235469710/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-1235469717/">here comes Rolling Stone with its Best of 2025 list</a>, because it's nearly Christmas. Brace for impact!</p>
<p>Yes, Rolling Stone has dropped its 25 favourite gaming experiences of the year and, whilst the number one spot is absolutely no surprise (congratulations to <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/clair_obscur_expedition_33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>), we've been tickled pink to see that good old <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/donkey_kong">Donkey Kong</a> has managed to secure a number three spot via all that wrecking shop he did in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza-dk-island-and-emerald-rush">Bananza</a>. The big man has smashed his way onto a prestigious podium there, so well done, Mr. Kong. And nice tie!</p><div><figure data-videoid="fMx2XNyAq4E" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytfMx2XNyAq4E" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed5d98e4olxjuy&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>840k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Elsewhere on the list, some 10 spaces down in fact, you'll spot another Switch 2-shaped mention in the form of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a>. Honestly, we probably wouldn't have expected that DK would outdo Master Mascot Mario in this way if you'd told us in the summer, but we'd tend to agree on the placement rolling (no pun intended) the great ape's way here.</p>
<p>What else has delighted us in making the cut? Well, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/hundred_line_-_last_defense_academy">The Hundred Line: Last Defense Academy</a> dropping into a very nice 7th place is great, as that really was one of the year's big highlights on Switch, alongside the wonderful <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/absolum">Absolum</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/ball-x-pit-nintendo-switch-2-edition">BALL x PIT</a>, and, of course, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hades-ii-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hades 2</a>, which has pulled off a blinder by snatching the number 2 spot.</p>

<p>Oh, and look at <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Silksong</a>, all the way down (if you can be all the way down on a top 25 list) at number 12. That isn't perhaps where we'd have expected to see such a massively well-reviewed game, but personal taste is a wondrous and mysterious thing, innit!</p>
<p>With a total of 11 of these games available on Switch consoles, it's still a very strong showing for Nintendo gamers - and hopefully we'll see Switch ports of some of these soon!</p>
<p>Here's the full listing for your perusal, but check out <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming-lists/best-video-games-of-2025-1235469710/">the full article</a> for details and reasoning:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong></li>
<li><strong>Hades II</strong></li>
<li><strong>Donkey Kong: Bananza</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/dispatch">Dispatch</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/ghost_of_yotei">Ghost of Yōtei</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/blue_prince">Blue Prince</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>The Hundred Line: Last Defense Academy</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/death_stranding_2_on_the_beach">Death Stranding 2: On The Beach</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>BALL x PIT</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/arc_raiders">Arc Raiders</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-series-x/south_of_midnight">South of Midnight</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong</strong></li>
<li><strong>Mario Kart World</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/shinobi_art_of_vengeance">SHINOBI: Art of Vengeance</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/battlefield_6">Battlefield 6</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/ninja_gaiden_4">Ninja Gaiden 4</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/fatal_fury_city_of_the_wolves">Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>Absolum</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/despelote">despelote</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>The Séance of Blake Manor</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/split-fiction">Split Fiction</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/citizen_sleeper_2_starward_vector">Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/rematch">Rematch</a></strong></li>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/wVCaeyucLTE?si=hfKDOOCikGYJN5I4" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer ugc"><strong>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</strong></a></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/silent_hill_f">Silent Hill: F</a></strong></li>
</ol>
<hr>
<p><em>See anything you disagree with making the cut? Think something is too highly/lowly-rated, or even missing entirely? Let us know!</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194187 @ 1764773204 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming-lists/best-video-games-of-2025-1235469710" rel="noopener" href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming-lists/best-video-games-of-2025-1235469710">rollingstone.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/2d372532024192dd9bfbf9d313dd6b3e @ 1764773204 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/rolling-stones-goty-list-shows-a-whole-lot-of-love-for-one-nintendo-mascot]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Install Size on PC Shrinks by 85% Thanks to Nixxes]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-install-size-on-pc-shrinks-by-85-percent-thanks-to-nixxes/</link>
            <guid>1371463</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The millions of players who regularly enjoy Helldivers 2 on PC (sales estimates put Steam owners at between 13 and 21 million) can rejoice, as the game's install size on this platform <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/491583942944621371" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">can now be reduced by around 85%</a>. Helldivers 2 previously took roughly 154GB of space from a drive, but Nixxes (the Dutch PC port specialist that <a href="https://wccftech.com/sony-acquires-nixxes-playstation-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was acquired by Sony in July 2021</a>) helped Arrowhead shrink it down to just 23GB, saving you 131GB of space.</p>



<p>The developers have completed several rounds of internal QA and are rolling this out as a public technical beta. Internal testing shows that, in the worst cases, mission loading times have only increased by a few seconds for the small percentage of players still using mechanical hard disk drives.</p>



<p>Before doing this, Arrowhead measured the number of players actively playing Helldivers 2 on a mechanical HDD. As of last week, it was around 11% of the total. The majority of the loading time in the game is due to level-generation rather than asset loading. This level generation occurs in parallel with loading assets from the disk, making it the primary factor in loading time. Critically, testing showed that HDD users are only getting slightly worse mission loading times, in the order of a few seconds in the worst cases. This convinced Arrowhead to go ahead with the public technical beta.</p>



<p>If everything goes well during this testing phase, the developers plan to discontinue the legacy version sometime next year. Those interested in testing the reduced install size can opt in immediately by selecting the game in their Steam library, then navigating to Properties &gt; Beta Participation and selecting prod_slim from the dropdown list.</p>



<p>Helldivers 2 is by far Sony's most significant live service success. In the span of a month since its launch in February 2024, the game <a href="https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-has-reportedly-sold-way-more-than-5-million-units/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">had already sold more than five million units across PC and PlayStation 5</a>, with the former platform accounting for the lion's share. In August 2025, the game launched even on Microsoft's Xbox Series S and X consoles and <a href="https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-xbox-sells-more-gears-of-war-reloaded-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">immediately performed well over there</a>, too.</p>



<p>The most recent large update is September's Into the Unjust, which introduced new enemies, missions, and Hive Worlds.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-install-size-on-pc-shrinks-by-85-percent-thanks-to-nixxes/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We played Metroid Prime 4, ask us anything]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/836580/metroid-prime-4-ask-me-anything</link>
            <guid>1371460</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTAy"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Ash Parrish</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond </em>is one of those games <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/763698/delayed-games-silksong-metroid-prime-4-2025">that been a long time coming</a>. Fans have been waiting almost a decade for the next entry in Samus’ first-person adventures. Early previews painted an <a href="https://kotaku.com/metroid-prime-4-previews-trailer-ncps-companion-2000644368">alarming picture of overly chatty sidekicks</a> ruining what’s traditionally a lonely and moody experience. Meanwhile formal reviews <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/12/02/nx-s1-5627515/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review">run</a> <a href="https://www.pcmag.com/reviews/metroid-prime-4-beyond">a gamut</a> <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review-1235475679/">of</a> <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/metroid-prime-4-beyond/worth-the-wait">opinions</a>, leaving the game in the interesting if tiresome discourse-inducing “7 / 10” range — not perfect, not awful, but possessed of a certain<em> something</em> that makes it uniquely more interesting than many higher scoring games.</p><p>So what exactly is that something? Does <em>Metroid Prime 4</em> even have it and if it does, does it make it worth the eight-year wait? My colleague Andrew Webster (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/835325/metroid-prime-4-review-nintendo-switch">who reviewed the game</a>) and I want to answer those questions and more from <em>Verge</em> subscribers right here in the comments. Since the game isn’t out yet, we can’t answer anything too spoilery, particularly as it pertains to the story. But if you wanna know about Samus’ cool new bike, her new friends, new powers, and just what generally makes a <em>Metroid</em> game shine, just ask. We’ll pop on around 1PM ET to answer what we can in the comments.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTAy"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Ash Parrish</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/836580/metroid-prime-4-ask-me-anything]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Switch 2 Compatible Samsung microSDXC Card Is Still at Its Black Friday Pricing, Nintendo Owners Clearing Out Remaining Units]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-compatible-samsung-microsdxc-black-friday-deal-2000650000</link>
            <guid>1371457</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>There is nothing more annoying, frustrating, and heartbreaking than having to delete your old titles just to make room for new ones. We’ve all been in those situations, but there’s a simple way out. Investing in a microSD card can give your storage the boost it needs, and we just spotted a solid option going for a lot less.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5799/">The 512GB Samsung P9 Express microSD card, which is made for Nintendo Switch, is currently going at a 25% discount.</a> This brings its price down to just $75, saving you a nice $15. It’s the lowest we have seen it drop to since its release, but the offer is only around for a short time. Grab it while it’s still live, because once it’s gone, we don’t expect it to be back at this price anytime soon.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5799/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Spacious Capacity, Better Speeds</h2>
<p>Starting off with the storage; the 512GB capacity is more than enough to house all your favorite titles and other downloadable content (DLCs) that you can’t squeeze into the internal storage of your console. It’s not as massive as 1TB, sure, but unless you’re looking to store massive libraries, it’s going to be sufficient. Sequential read speeds of up to 800 MB/s make it easy to access games and get back into action (literally) up to four times faster than most other options in the same range. These speeds translate into quicker load times and much faster updates.</p>
<p>Installation couldn’t be simpler. Just turn your Nintendo Switch off, locate the kickstand on the back, and open it. Look for the dedicated slot and gently insert the card into it. Once it clicks into place, turn your console on and follow any on-screen instructions that pop up. It should be up and running within minutes!</p>



<p>The card plays nicely with Nintendo Switch 2, plus microSD UHS-I devices like computers, tablets, cameras, and select handheld consoles. It’s built to last you for years to come, thanks to its 6 layers of protection. It is waterproof (capable of withstanding up to 72 hours in seawater), temperature-proof with operating temperatures of -13 degrees Fahrenheit to 185 degrees Fahrenheit, X-Ray proof, magnetic-proof, plus drop-proof up to 16.4 feet. Even with all this, Samsung offers a limited warranty of 3 years that covers you if anything goes wrong. The card features a dynamic thermal guard that keeps it cool even during those intense sessions that demand a lot of power. To unlock its full performance, it’s best to use it with the Samsung Magician Software. It lets you verify the product’s authenticity, plus keep an eye on your drive’s health to ensure optimal performance.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5799/">All things considered, if you’ve been looking for a reliable, easy-to-use storage solution, this 512GB Samsung microSD card is an excellent option to consider, especially at this lowest price.</a> It gets you the storage you need, plus faster transfer speeds and exceptional compatibility. If 512GB is more than you need, there’s a 256GB version going for $55, but it’s not discounted. Getting your orders in now will also help you save on the delivery charges, whether you are a Prime member or not. Just be sure to act fast, as drops this massive don’t stick around forever. It’s one of the remaining Black Friday and Cyber Monday deals, and we’re expecting it to wrap within a few hours.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5799/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-compatible-samsung-microsdxc-black-friday-deal-2000650000]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Fortnite’s Long-Awaited Ninjago Collab Finally Arrives Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/lego-fortnites-long-awaited-ninjago-collab-finally-arrives-next-week/</link>
            <guid>1371454</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>LEGO Fortnite Odyssey is finally getting the long-awaited, and heavily rumored, Ninjago collab next week, with the official account posting the first teaser.</p>



<p>Fortnite’s LEGO-themed survival mode is now entering its second full year since release, and, after a period of a huge drop in updates to the mode, the biggest collab so far is poised to be introduced.</p>







<h2 id="h-lego-fortnite-ninjago-coming-december-11">LEGO Fortnite Ninjago Coming December 11</h2>



<figure><figcaption>New island? Image via Epic Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>In a teaser post on Twitter, the official LEGO Fortnite account told players to “get ready to master a new adventure in Odyssey,” which will arrive on December 11.</p>



<p>Although it did not mention Ninjago outright, there were big teasers in the emojis that were posted alongside the message, showing an ice cube, a lightning bolt, a cloud, and a Ninja.</p>



<p>The post also confirms when Fortnite’s first major update of Chapter 7 Season 1 will be, which will also see the return of Fortnite OG with a new season, and will set the scene ahead of the Winterfest event later this month.</p>



<p>Rumors of a Ninjago collab coming to LEGO Fortnite have been widespread for a while, and the arrival of the collab will be the biggest update since the Lost Isles update in September 2024.</p>



<p>Since then, the only major update to the mode was the addition of split-screen support, and there had been discontent among the community for the lack of content updates.</p>



<p>However, the Ninjago update on December 11 should appease those concerns with a host of new content, similar to what was introduced in the Lost Isles update and the LEGO Star Wars update.</p>







<hr>



<p>What other collabs would you like to see added to LEGO Fortnite? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Fortnite, read details about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-south-park-leak-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">upcoming South Park collaboration</a>, and check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-dark-voyager-quest-rewards-chapter-7-season-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to unlock all Dark Voyager (Reality Redacted) rewards.</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/lego-fortnites-long-awaited-ninjago-collab-finally-arrives-next-week/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MLB The Show Mobile announced for iOS, Android]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/mlb-the-show-mobile-announced-for-ios-android</link>
            <guid>1371451</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile">Mobile</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Available now via limited regional release in the Philippines.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [5,090 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > San Diego Studio [46 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/san-diego-studio">San Diego Studio</a> have <a href="https://theshowmobile.com/" target="_blank">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > MLB The Show Mobile" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mlb-the-show-mobile">MLB The Show Mobile</a></em>. It is available now via a limited regional release (soft launch) in the Philippines for iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/ph/app/mlb-the-show-mobile-baseball/id6474043167" target="_blank">App Store</a> and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.playstation.mlbtheshowmobile&amp;gl=ph" target="_blank">Google Play</a>. <span id="more-1010845"></span></p><p>The <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [482 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> <em>MLB The Show Mobile</em> is described as “a new standalone experience built from the ground up to deliver realistic baseball gameplay on mobile devices.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Step up to the plate and swing for the fences in <em>MLB The Show Mobile</em>. Loaded with all-time greats, new fast-paced game modes designed for mobile, and non-stop <a title="Genres > Action [3,248 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>, the most authentic, officially licensed MLB and MLBPI baseball experience is now in the palm of your hand!</p><p>Collect. Build. Dominate. Collect more than a thousand player cards and stack your dream team with today’s superstars and historic legends like Mickey Mantle, Hank Aaron, and Ken Griffey Jr. Put your skills to the test and prove you’ve got what it takes to rule the diamond!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Realistic Batting, Pitching, and Fielding</strong><ul><li>Hit a grand slam, strike out the side, and turn the perfect double play—<em>MLB The Show Mobile</em> gives you full control of the diamond!</li><li>Skill-based controls are easy to learn, but challenging to master—your inputs determine whether you hit a home run or whiff it for a strikeout</li><li>Whether stealing 2nd base or diving for a catch, YOU decide what happens in every play!</li><li>New “Risk It” feature lets you control runners in real-time</li></ul></li><li><strong>The Ultimate <a title="Genres > Sports [683 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/sports">Sports</a> Game <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a></strong><ul><li>Built from the ground up for mobile: the most detailed and realistic way to play on the go</li><li>Compete with true-to-life versions of your favorite MLB heroes!</li><li>Immerse yourself in the action with incredible graphics and more than 16,000 unique animations!</li><li>Play in all 30 real MLB stadiums!</li><li>Feel the depth in every mechanic whether you’re pitching, batting, or fielding</li></ul></li><li><strong>Strategize With the New Momentum System</strong><ul><li>Each player card has a Momentum Cost—start innings with 10 Momentum and spend it strategically to dominate the competition!</li><li>Maintain Momentum through performance—keep the hits coming, or run out of Momentum and risk a power drop</li><li>Player stats are paired with unique abilities, unlocking endless strategic choices!</li><li>Pick your batters and pitchers in real time—don’t just set your lineup, choose the right slugger for the situation and come through in the clutch!</li></ul></li><li><strong>Build the Perfect Squad</strong><ul><li>Collect big-league stars past and present to build your ultimate roster!</li><li>Fill your bullpen with aces, stack your bench and make your lineup explosive with a growing list of more than 1,100 player cards to collect</li><li>Earn XP, upgrade players, and craft attribute bonuses to perfect your collection</li><li>Buy and sell cards directly with other players in the Marketplace!</li></ul></li><li><strong>Play New Game Modes</strong><ul><li>Dominate your rivals in best-of-three player-versus-player matchups featuring an expanding list of quick new modes designed for mobile</li><li>Experience the most iconic MLB Moments and relive baseball history</li><li>Unlock rewards through wins, daily challenges, limited-time events and the Show Pass!</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Preview Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ctcq_G3UclA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/mlb-the-show-mobile-announced-for-ios-android]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia will own 93.4 percent of EA after buyout]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/saudi-arabia-will-own-93-4-percent-of-ea-after-buyout</link>
            <guid>1371445</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">December 3, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Saudi Arabia's sovereign Public Investment Fund (PIF) is poised to become the majority owner of EA as part of a $55 billon take-private that will see an investor consortium take control of the Battlefield and Apex Legends publisher.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The deal was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/saudi-arabia-is-taking-ea-private-alongside-other-investors">announced earlier this year</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and will result in EA being acquired by a group that includes PIF, Silver Lake, and Affinity Partners, the latter of which is the investment firm established by U.S. president Donald Trump's son-in-law Jared Kushner.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The ownership group will collectively contribute $36 billion to the buyout. JP Morgan Chase Bank will provide an additional $20 billion in debt financing.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Until now, it has been unclear how ownership will be divided between members of the consortium. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.wsj.com/business/deals/saudi-fund-to-own-almost-all-of-electronic-arts-after-buyout-661e92be">As spotted by The Wall Street Journal</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, however, a new filing submitted to regulators in Brazil indicates PIF will own 93.4 percent of EA post-buyout. &nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Silver Lake and Affinity Parters will own 5.5 percent and 1.1 percent, respectively.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA has discussed the potential impact of the deal at length in a series of SEC filings and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-says-55-billion-take-private-won-t-result-in-immediate-layoffs">claims the move won't result in "immediate" layoffs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The company also told employees it will </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-says-it-will-retain-creative-control-under-new-private-owners">retain "creative control" under its new owners</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">PIF made significant inroads into the video game industry before turning its attention to EA, having previously acquired stakes in high-profile companies such as Nintendo, Koei Tecmo, Capcom, Nexon, and Take-Two.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/coffee-stain-and-paradox-veterans-unveil-new-studio-feeble-minds" target="_self" data-discover="true">Coffee Stain and Paradox veterans unveil new studio Feeble Minds</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The investment fund is chaired by Saudi Arabia's de-factor ruler and crown prince, Mohammed bin Salman—who, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-45812399">as noted by The BBC</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, was linked to the murder of Washington Post journalist Jamal Khashoggi.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Advocacy groups such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amnesty.org.uk/saudi-arabia-human-rights-raif-badawi-king-salman">Amnesty International</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.hrw.org/world-report/2025/country-chapters/saudi-arabia">Human Rights Watch</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> have strongly criticised Saudi Arabia's human rights record under the leadership of bin Salman, who they claim has suppressed freedom of speech by outlawing protests and demonstrations, criminalising LGBTQ+ relationships and gender expression, and discriminating against women.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Communications Workers of America president </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/cwa-president-implores-u-s-regulators-to-scrutinise-ea-buyout-to-address-national-security-and-labor-concerns">Claude Cummings Jr</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-employees-and-cwa-slam-saudi-led-ea-buyout-call-for-regulatory-scrutiny">unionized workers at EA</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> have called on regulators to scrutinise the buyout to address labor and national security concerns.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Earlier this year, Game Developer&nbsp;columnist Nicole Carpenter </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-gaming-is-the-new-oil-how-the-ea-buyout-diverges-from-the-traditional-playbook-">spoke with a number of analysts</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to better understand how the seismic deal will impact EA and the wider industry.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/saudi-arabia-will-own-93-4-percent-of-ea-after-buyout]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samus' death screams are no longer Jennifer Hale, as Dispatch actress takes over role for Metroid Prime 4: Beyond]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/samus-death-screams-are-no-longer-jennifer-hale-as-dispatch-actress-takes-over-role-for-metroid-prime-4-beyond</link>
            <guid>1371442</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metroid-prime-4">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> has cast a new voice actress for Samus.</p>
<p>If (or should that be when) you succumb to the barrage of enemies that will be heading your way on Metroid Prime 4: Beyond's release tomorrow, it will not be Jennifer Hale that you will hear screaming in pain. </p>
<p>Rather for this release, Hale - who lent her vocal talents to the role of Samus in the original <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metroid-prime">Metroid Prime</a> trilogy - has instead been replaced with American stage and voice actress Erin Yvette.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>You may have already heard Yvette's voice in many of earlier works. Yvette's previous video game roles include Snow White in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/telltale-games">Telltale Games</a>' <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-wolf-among-us">The Wolf Among Us</a> and Alex in Night School Studio's debut Oxenfree.</p>
<p>More recently, the actress also voiced Blonde Blazer in AdHoc's brilliant (I honestly can't recommend this game enough) superhero workplace comedy, Dispatch.</p>
<p>It is worth noting though, that while Yvette is credited with voicing Samus in Metroid Prime 4: Beyond, the character doesn't exactly talk your ear off in the game. Rather, it is more about those all important effort noises when Samus is making her way through the world, and of course that death scream. To give more context, Yvette's performance in Metroid Prime 4: Beyond is on par with Hale's own performance as Samus in Metroid Prime 3, I am reliably told.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>AdHoc</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>For more on Samus' chatter (or lack thereof), our Alex recently shared his thoughts about Metroid Prime 4: Beyond's almost silent protagonist. You can check it out here: <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-chatty-companions-silent-samus-the-problem">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond's chatty space marine companions aren't so bad - it's Samus who is this game's narrative problem</a>.</p><p>As for the game more generally, well it comes out tomorrow, so there's not too much longer to wait until you can hear Yvette's grunts in action for yourself. "Metroid Prime 4: Beyond is enjoyable enough, and has glimpses of vintage Metroid shining through, but this game could and should have been so much more," reads <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review">Eurogamer's Metroid Prime 4: Beyond review</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/samus-death-screams-are-no-longer-jennifer-hale-as-dispatch-actress-takes-over-role-for-metroid-prime-4-beyond]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem Finally Gets First Combat Footage, But Leon is Nowhere to Be Seen]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-finally-gets-first-combat-footage-but-leon-is-nowhere-to-be-seen/</link>
            <guid>1371430</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The core survival-horror elements of Resident Evil Requiem have been showcased effectively in recent events (<a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/gamescom-2025-awards-resident-evil-requiem-capcom/">such as Gamescom 2025</a>), but a crucial part of the experience, combat, has remained unseen until today. Unfortunately, the reveal wasn't accompanied by the confirmation all fans are waiting for: <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-first-trailer-hides-leon-campaign-clues-insider-claims/">the presence of Leon Kennedy in the game. </a></p>



<p>A few hours ago, new Resident Evil Requiem combat footage started making the rounds online. The short clip was shown in a series' special program which aired in Japan earlier today. This clip showcases a brand-new area and Grace fighting multiple zombies using a handgun in some third-person sequences that are highly reminiscent of Resident Evil 4. <a href="https://x.com/AestheticGamer1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">As known insider Dusk Golem</a> stressed, having aired on Japanese television, the footage was captured from a censored version of the game, so blood and gore should be as usual in the international version of the game.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">One thing I'll clarify is since this aired on Japanese television, this is 100% the censored Japanese version. RE games get a "censored" version and a "Z-Rated" version released in Japan, things like headshots/dismemberment are always censored in the Japanese non-Z rated versions</p>— AestheticGamer aka Dusk Golem (@AestheticGamer1) <a href="https://twitter.com/AestheticGamer1/status/1996166803119349812?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<h2 id="h-the-leon-kennedy-speculation-continues">The Leon Kennedy Speculation Continues</h2>



<p>With the first Resident Evil Requiem combat footage not showing Leon Kennedy in action, the window for such a critical reveal is becoming tighter. </p>



<p>In the previous months, it was speculated that the protagonist of the second and fourth main entries in the series would be the focus of the game's combat elements, and revealing his presence alongside the combat mechanics would have made a lot of sense. Hopes haven't been dashed completely, as <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-producer-leon-playable-demo/">game producer Masato Kumazawa recently addressed the rumors without denying them</a>, though, so there's still a chance the beloved character will be the second protagonist of Resident Evil Requiem alongside Grace Ashcroft.</p>



<p>No matter what, there's no denying that Resident Evil Requiem is looking great in the new footage. <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-gamescom-hands-on-preview-turn-on-the-lights/">The new entry in the series felt really promising when I tried it out during this year's Gamescom</a>, and I look forward to delving deeper into the darkness when the game launches on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, and Nintendo Switch on February 27.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-finally-gets-first-combat-footage-but-leon-is-nowhere-to-be-seen/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign's pre-Forsaken Hollows DLC patch is out now, boosting melee attacks and fixing misbehaving churches]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-pre-forsaken-hollows-dlc-patch-is-out-now-boosting-melee-attacks-and-fixing-misbehaving-churches</link>
            <guid>1371427</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>It's also now easier to keep track of your relics and flasks</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>FromSoftware</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a>'s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-the-forsaken-hollows-dlc-drops-next-month-brings-back-a-beloved-dark-souls-bumkicker">Forsaken Hollows expansion</a> arrives tomorrow, December 4th. Ahead of letting folks dive into Limveld's big hole and try out the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-dlcs-first-new-class-looks-great-for-book-nerds-and-grubby-old-men-lovers">new nightfarer classes</a>, FromSoft have lobbed out the customary big patch.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>This patch, 1.03, is out now and decently beefy. Looking through the notes, the studio have taken the opportunity to add a a fair amount of new features, with most being minor tweaks which make certain menus easier to parse, allow you to quickly check which relics you're rocking or how many flasks you've got left, and ensure personal objectives don't impede teaming-up. Some shop inventories have also been rearranged or added to.</p>
<p>Arguably the most noteworthy thing about the patch is that FromSoft have opted not to make nightfarer-specific tweaks as part of their latest round of balancing. Instead, stock changes to passive, special and relic effects have been drafted in, with melee attacks made more powerful, while dashing and rolling strikes have also been boosted. Meanwhile, effects that help negate damage when you're already at low health have been made less effective, which is bad news for less tanky builds.</p>
<p>Given the Forsaken Hollows is supposed to be a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-forsaken-hollows-dlc-has-reignited-my-interest/1100-6536543/">slightly tougher cookie than the base game</a> anyway, you may want to go back to an old fashioned 'hit everyything with a big stick while cowering behind a tonne of armour plating' type of setup if you're keen to maximise your chances of not being forsakenly hollowed out.</p><p>Rounding out the patch are the usual bug fixes. FromSoft having "mitigated an issue where Sites of Grace or Churches would not activate and leveling up and adding charges to flask could not be performed under some conditions" is a welcome one. As is the rectifying of healing and enhancing effects not applying themselves to allies who happen to be busy dodging or unleashing their ultimate art.</p>
<p>You can check out the full notes rundown for the patch <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/elden-ring/news/elden-ring-nightreign-patch-notes-version-103">here</a>. The Forsaken Hollows is set to release on PC at 11PM GMT today, December 3rd. That's 6PM EST and 3PM PST.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-pre-forsaken-hollows-dlc-patch-is-out-now-boosting-melee-attacks-and-fixing-misbehaving-churches]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Girls’ Frontline 2: Exilium’s Anniversary Bash Is All About Huge Rewards and Hot New Features]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/girls-frontline-2-exiliums-anniversary-bash-is-all-about-huge-rewards-and-hot-new-features-2000646724</link>
            <guid>1371418</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p><span>There’s a great 1st anniversary party happening for <em>Girls’ Frontline 2: Exilium</em>, and new players and longtime franchise fans are all invited. Two huge new events, three powerful new dolls—as anniversary celebrations go, this is a big one.</span></p>
<p><span>The fireworks begin on Nov. 27 with a massive overhaul of the Crew Deck, the launch of the <em>Deep Oblivion</em> and <em>Intertwined Assault</em> events, and the debut of new dolls Leva and Lenna. <em>Deep Oblivion</em> is a two-part event, with part 2 dropping on Dec. 18 along with Robella, the third new doll. There are also huge player rewards to be found, including more than 130 pulls and over 13,000 Collapse Pieces. Needless to say, this is an event <em>GFL2</em> fans will not want to miss, and a golden opportunity for new fans to step up and experience this global phenomenon.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_2000646757" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646757"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646757">© Sunborn Games</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Inside the New Crew Deck</h2>
<p><span>The Elmo’s Crew Deck has been upgraded, and the brand-new gameplay is now live. In this updated space, Commanders will find not only fully realized 3D versions of the collectible cabinet and armory, but also a variety of new interactive story moments between Commanders and T-Dolls.</span></p>
<p><span>When the update goes live, Commanders will immediately find Makiatto’s exclusive story <em>Time Capsule: Pulse-Racing Night</em> in their inbox. If you already own Makiatto’s Embroidered Bamboo Blooming Shadows outfit, you can jump right into this free story. Klukai also gets in on the special features, with a Cerulean Breaker outfit (pictured above) that comes with a new Body Maintenance Technician item.</span></p>
<p><span>With more stories, outfits, and furniture for Commanders to invest in, the Crew Deck gets a little more homey and personalized with each addition. And with a brand-new holography function, players can actually embody select Dolls inside the Crew Dec, starting with Klukai, but with more to follow.</span></p>
<p><span>The Crew Deck is a completely new space, no longer just a menu, but an interactive showcase. Among the other anniversary-celebration innovations debuting on Nov. 27:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>3D Ornament Cabinet &amp; Armory</span></li>
<li><span>Memory Corridor for special scene collections</span></li>
<li><span>Crimson Arcade, a minigame zone</span></li>
<li><span>Interior decoration tools</span></li>
<li><span>Tea Break system to unlock extra interactions</span></li>
<li><span>Dreamscape, an atmospheric feature for additional world-building</span></li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_2000649570" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000649570"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000649570">© Sunborn Games</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Loot, Loot, and More Loot</h2>
<p><span>Normally an anniversary party involves gifts being given to the celebrants. But for <em>Girls’ Frontline 2: Exilium</em>‘s big celebration, it’s the players who will be the ones on the receiving end of a staggering amount of free stuff.</span></p>
<p><span>Commanders who participate in the full season of events are in for a serious haul, including over 130 free pulls, over 13,000 Collapse Pieces, 2 free outfits, and a massive array of other upgrade materials, tokens, and Crew Deck bonuses. When the Crew Deck Date Reward arrives on Nov. 27, that’s stacked with </span><span>35 Outfit Access Permissions, </span><span>10 Access Permissions, an Elmo Model Ornament, 300 Collapse Pieces, and multiple other growth materials.</span></p>
<p><span>Other goodies include a free Dragon Chef outfit for Qiuhua available in the Glory Store, and an automatic unlocking of Springfield’s Enjoy the Fragrance. There are more Access Permissions available by completing daily missions, through mail rewards, furniture exchange, gift packs, and the seasonal Battle Pass.</span></p>
<h2>Don’t Miss the Live-Action Trailer</h2>
<p><span>Even with all of these updates, new Dolls, and massive rewards, another exciting part of the <em>GFL2</em> 1st anniversary celebration is a live-action trailer featuring the legendary 404 Squad. The video showcases the characters’ relaxed daily life on the Crew Deck, while also featuring intense combat action.You’ll see the 404 Squad engage in desert firefights and blackout industrial battles, with Humvees, Gatling guns, and a heavily armed helicopter aiding their cause.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_2000646758" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646758"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646758">© Sunborn Games</figcaption></figure>
<p><span>Even before this giant anniversary party, it’s easy to see how <em>Girls’ Frontline 2: Exilium</em> has become such a worldwide success. Whether you’re a <em>GFL2</em> veteran or you’re just hearing all the rave reviews now and want to see what it’s all about, it’s an awesome experience on PC, or mobile on both Android and iOS devices. Commanders, join in and celebrate the anniversary!</span></p>
      </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/girls-frontline-2-exiliums-anniversary-bash-is-all-about-huge-rewards-and-hot-new-features-2000646724]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horses Is The New Viral Horror Game Banned On Steam & Epic Games Store]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/horses-is-the-new-viral-horror-game-banned-on-steam-epic-games-store/</link>
            <guid>1371412</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Horses was banned at the final hour by Steam and the Epic Games Store due to the game’s unsettling and controversial content, but you can still buy the viral horror title.</p>



<p>The initial premise of Horses seems quite simple: You’re on a two-week break working at a farm. You perform standard tasks, such as feeding the farmer’s dog and tending to the ‘horses.’ It becomes quickly apparent that they aren’t normal horses, and the game quickly descends into a host of horrifying and inhumane themes.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-indie-game-deals-holiday-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a> and Epic didn’t like this much.</p>







<h2 id="h-you-can-still-buy-horses-elsewhere">You Can Still Buy Horses Elsewhere</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Yes, a carrot. Credit to Santa Ragione Game Studio</figcaption></figure>



<p>Mere hours before its launch, <a href="https://www.horses.wtf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Horses</a> was banned from Steam and the Epic Games Store. If anything, this has furthered the game’s profile with people desperate to understand why.</p>







<p>Take a look at this content warning on the Horses website to get an idea of what to expect:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“This game contains scenes of physical violence, psychological abuse, gory imagery (mutilation, blood), depictions of slavery, physical and psychological torture, domestic abuse, sexual assault, suicide, and misogyny.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Insider Gaming has seen lots of the game’s footage and the aforementioned content—it’s just as perturbing and disturbing as you can imagine. The Epic Games Store says Horses is still “Coming Soon,” but you don’t have to wait, as the horror game is available to buy on GOG. </p>



<p>The ban decisions could be overturned in the future, especially if Santa Ragione Game Studio fights back, and popularity in the title explodes. Insider Gaming will continue to monitor Horses’ status.</p>



<p>If you’ve played Horses, now’s your chance to share. Is the full game as psychologically damaging as it’s made out to be? Was Steam and the Epic Games Store right to ban it? Share your experience with everyone through the free <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more news and content, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-artist-satisfied/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Artist Who Says Bungie’s Marathon Plagiarism Issue has Been ‘Resolved’</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-resident-evil-requiem-gameplay-shown-exclusively-in-japan-reveals-new-location/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">New Resident Evil Requiem Gameplay Shown Exclusively In Japan, Revealing A New Location</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/horses-is-the-new-viral-horror-game-banned-on-steam-epic-games-store/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Artist Says Bungie’s Marathon Plagiarism Issue has Been ‘Resolved to my Satisfaction’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-artist-satisfied/</link>
            <guid>1371409</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>An artist whose art was stolen by Bungie’s Marathon has now claimed that the issue with Bungie and Sony has been resolved to her satisfaction.</p>



<p>The news came more than six months after the artist took to <a href="https://x.com/4nt1r34l/status/1995907613004018047" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter) to say that Bungie had used the assets she created in 2017 without permission. Back then, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/artist-accuses-bungie-of-plagiarizing-work-for-marathon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">she claimed</a>, “The Marathon alpha released recently, and its environments are covered with assets lifted from poster designs I made in 2017.”</p>







<div><p>The claim was almost immediately picked up by Bungie, who said,</p><p>“We immediately investigated a concern regarding unauthorized use of artist decals in Marathon and confirmed that a former Bungie artist included these in a texture sheet that was ultimately used in-game.</p></div>



<p>This issue was unknown by our existing art team, and we are still reviewing how this oversight occurred. We take matters like this very seriously. We have reached out to @4nt1r34l to discuss this issue and are committed to do right by the artist.</p>



<p>As a matter of policy, we do not use the work of artists without their permission.</p>



<p>To prevent similar issues in the future, we are conducting a thorough review of our in-game assets, specifically those done by the former Bungie artist, and implementing stricter checks to document all artist contributions.</p>



<p>We value the creativity and dedication of all artists who contribute to our games, and we are committed to doing right by them. Thank you for bringing this to our attention.”</p>



<div><p> But now, the issue has been fully resolved, with the artist saying,</p><p>“The Marathon art issue has been resolved with Bungie and Sony Interactive Entertainment to my satisfaction.”</p></div>



<p>As to the extent the issue was resolved, that will likely never be shared, but Sony and Bungie have seemingly gone to great lengths to ensure the artist has been fully compensated and/or reached an agreement. </p>







<p>Bungie’s Marathon is scheduled to release by the end of this fiscal year (by April 1st, 2026).</p>



<p>What do you think the artist got to resolve the issue? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Official Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>There’s much more news to check out at Insider Gaming, such as&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-south-park-leak-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new Fortnite Leak detailing the upcoming South Park collaboration</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metroid-prime-4-beyond-is-the-lowest-reviewed-game-in-the-series/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond being the lowest-reviewed game in the series</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-artist-satisfied/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Of Course We're Not Going to Stop Here' — Monster Hunter Developers Talk About the Future of the Series at PlayStation Awards]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/of-course-were-not-going-to-stop-here-monster-hunter-developers-talk-about-the-future-of-the-series-at-playstation-awards</link>
            <guid>1371406</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"We want to let more people play."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">At the PlayStation Partner Awards 2025 Japan Asia held in Tokyo on December 3, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> won the Grand Award and the User's Choice Award. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview held before the award ceremony, Ryozo Tsujimoto, the producer of this work, and Yuya Tokuda, the director, answered questions from local media. IGN Japan was in attendance. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">When Monster Hunter Wilds was first released on February 28, some players left harsh feedback, but Tokuda said the team worked to improve the game by taking advantage of that feedback.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Immediately after the release, we apologized for the inconvenience caused by the volume of content and the difficulty level. Despite this, we were delighted to receive various awards, including Users' Choice awards. We would like to thank all the players who have given their opinions and spoken warm words even in this situation. The development team was able to turn everyone's feedback into an asset and work on the update with all our strength, and I think the result was also the reason why players voted for us," said Tokuda.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/03/img-3587-1764763663206.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Yuya Tokuda (left) and Ryozo Tsujimoto (right) at the PlayStation Partner Awards 2025 Japan Asia held in Tokyo on December 3. Image credit: IGN.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Monster Hunter has the characteristics of a title that gets regular updates, but player opinions were very helpful during the update process, and in order to make Monster Hunter Wilds better, the fans’ voices gave us power. There are still updates left to come, so we will continue to do our best," added Tsujimoto.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Monster Hunter series celebrated its 20th anniversary last year. The franchise was a hit in Japan, and after the release of Monster Hunter: World in 2018, it grew into a literal monster title overseas. According to Tokuda, the Monster Hunter Wilds team were more aware than ever of being accepted by newcomers or those who had trouble beating the games. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We analyzed what kind of places beginners were stuck in, including Monster Hunter: World. We have worked on these points in turn to make it easier for new users to clear hurdles such as being able to reach certain monsters or to craft certain types of armor. In addition, we have tried to adopt as many new elements as possible that are beneficial for both beginners and existing users, such as Focus Mode. This time, as a result of making the game easy to beat even for new players and players who could not clear it before, I think the difficulty curve was a little lacking for existing users,” said Tokuda. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Tokuda said the team has focused on creating more difficult content with each update. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"If you beat the game immediately after its release and stopped playing, I would appreciate it if you could pick it up again," said Tokuda.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Monster Hunter Wilds still has updates to come, but Tsujimoto also talked a little about the future of the series.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Of course, we don’t intend to stop the series here. We plan to continue, and we want to let more people play. In addition, I would like to think about things beyond the games so that we can further expand the potential of the Monster Hunter IP," said Tsujimoto.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">All Low Rank Armor in Monster Hunter Wilds</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">From Tsujimoto's remarks, it seems we can continue to look forward to new games and more in the Monster Hunter series. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tsujimoto was also asked where Monster Hunter stands within the overall catalog of Capcom IP, which he answered diplomatically. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Capcom is a company with various IPs, and every IP is very important. I'm in charge of Monster Hunter now, that’s all I can comment on, but as Capcom, we want to expand all our IPs,” he said. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Capcom is scheduled to release Resident Evil Requiem, Onimusha Way of the Sword, and Pragmata in 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/of-course-were-not-going-to-stop-here-monster-hunter-developers-talk-about-the-future-of-the-series-at-playstation-awards]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Partner Awards 2025 Japan Asia winners announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/playstation-partner-awards-2025-japan-asia-winners-announced</link>
            <guid>1371403</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO, Monster Hunter Wilds, and more take home the Grand Award.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [5,090 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> Japan Asia has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/12/03/playstation-partner-awards-2025-japan-asia-winners-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the winners of <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [49,096 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Partner Awards 2025 Japan Asia.</p><p>The winners are as follows:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Grand Award</strong></p><p>Awarded to the top three titles developed in the Japan / Asian regions with highest worldwide sales between October 1, 2024 and September 30, 2025.</p><p>Winners:</p><ul><li><em>eFootball</em> (<a title="Companies > Konami Digital Entertainment [1,154 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/konami">Konami Digital Entertainment</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-ball-sparking-zero">Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,800 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco Entertainment</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Marvel Rivals [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/marvel-rivals">Marvel Rivals</a></em> (<a title="Companies > NetEase Games [391 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netease-games">NetEase Games</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Monster Hunter Wilds [42 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Capcom [2,636 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/capcom">Capcom</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Zenless Zone Zero [29 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/zenless-zone-zero">Zenless Zone Zero</a></em> (<a title="Companies > miHoYo [216 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mihoyo">miHoYo</a>)</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Partner Award</strong></p><p>Awarded to titles developed in the Japan / Asia region with top-ranked worldwide sales between October 1, 2024 and September 30, 2025, with particularly noteworthy activity results.</p><p>Winners:</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Elden Ring Nightreign [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a></em> (<a title="Companies > FromSoftware [408 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kadokawa-corporation/fromsoftware">FromSoftware</a> / Bandai Namco Entertainment)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a></em>&nbsp;(Konami Digital Entertainment)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Path of Exile II [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/path-of-exile-ii">Path of Exile II</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Grinding Gear Games [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tencent/grinding-gear-games">Grinding Gear Games</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Silent Hill f [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/silent-hill-f">Silent Hill f</a></em> (Konami Digital Entertainment)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Wuthering Waves [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/wuthering-waves">Wuthering Waves</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Kuro Games [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kuro-games">Kuro Games</a>)</li></ul><p><strong>Accessibility Award</strong></p><p>Awarded to titles with outstanding accessibility features.</p><p>Winners:</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii">Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii</a></em> (<a title="Companies > SEGA [2,720 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a>)</li><li><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> (Capcom)</li></ul><p><strong>PlayStation Indies Award</strong></p><p>Awarded to the top titles chosen by users in the Japan / Asia regions. The title candidates are selected as outstanding independent titles produced in Japan or Asia.</p><p>Winners:</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > ENDER MAGNOLIA: Bloom in the Mist [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ender-magnolia-bloom-in-the-mist">ENDER MAGNOLIA: Bloom in the Mist</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Binary Haze Interactive [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/binary-haze-interactive">Binary Haze Interactive</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Nine Sols [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/nine-sols">Nine Sols</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Red Candle Games [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/red-candle-games">Red Candle Games</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Urban Myth Dissolution Center [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/urban-myth-dissolution-center">Urban Myth Dissolution Center</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Hakaba Bunko [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hakaba-bunko">Hakaba Bunko</a> / <a title="Companies > Shueisha Games [48 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/shueisha-games">Shueisha Games</a>)</li></ul><p><strong>Users’ Choice Award</strong></p><p>Awarded to the top titles chosen by users in the Japan / Asia regions. The title candidates are directly taken from the top 30 titles released between October 1, 2024 and September 30, 2025, ranked by the total number of hours played in the Japan / Asia region.</p><p>Winners:</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Sandfall Interactive [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sandfall-interactive">Sandfall Interactive</a> / <a title="Companies > Kepler Interactive [56 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kepler-interactive">Kepler Interactive</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Dynasty Warriors: Origins [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dynasty-warriors-origins">Dynasty Warriors: Origins</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Omega Force [1,254 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games/omega-force">Omega Force</a> / <a title="Companies > Koei Tecmo Games [3,114 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games">Koei Tecmo</a>)</li><li><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> (Capcom)</li><li><em>Silent Hill f</em> (<a title="Companies > NeoBards Entertainment [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/neobards-entertainment">NeoBards Entertainment</a> / Konami)</li><li><em>Wuthering Waves</em> (Kuro Games)</li></ul></blockquote></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/playstation-partner-awards-2025-japan-asia-winners-announced]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>