<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 20:46:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonic The Hedgehog Kicks Off 35th Anniversary Celebrations In Style]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/sonic-the-hedgehog-kicks-off-35th-anniversary-celebrations-in-style</link>
            <guid>1407577</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"Forever fast"</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Believe it or not, <strong>Sonic the Hedgehog</strong> is celebrating his 35th anniversary in 2026, and Sega is clearly planning something as it dropped a nostalgia blast of a trailer celebrating the blue blur's life and times.</p>
<p>The trailer highlights the range of Sonic over the franchise's storied history, from his pixel perfect start on the Mega Drive with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/megadrive/sonic_the_hedgehog">Sonic the Hedgehog</a>, to blockbuster movies in Paramount's Sonic the Hedgehog trilogy.</p>
<p>He's done everything you can think of — LEGO Sonic, the animated series <strong>Sonic X</strong>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/minecraft">Minecraft</a>, and obviously tons and tons of his own video games. So 2026 should be a big year for Sega and Sonic.</p>
<p>"For over three decades, Sonic has raced through generations and inspired fans with his unmatched speed, unstoppable energy and fearless spirit" Sega says on the <a href="https://www.sega.com/sonic-the-hedgehog?tab=35th-anniversary">newly-opened 35th anniversary website</a>. "Now, it’s time to honor his incredible journey and celebrate the blue blur’s countless adventures."</p>

<p>Additionally, Sega / Atlus' brand marketing vice president Marcella Churchill shared in a press release that “This milestone is not just a reflection of our past, but also a look toward the future as we continue to innovate and grow."</p>
<p>Sega will be revealing partnerships, collectibles, fan experiences, and more throughout the year. We hope there might be a game announcement in there, too.</p>
<p>21st June 2026 will be the official day of Sonic's 35th anniversary, but we're sure we'll hear a lot about Sega's iconic character over the coming months.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>What are you hoping for from Sonic's 35th anniversary? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/sonic/related-articles:196123,194633 @ 1768509001 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/01/sonic-the-hedgehog-kicks-off-35th-anniversary-celebrations-in-style]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon’s New World: Aeternum MMO will shut down next year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/862892/amazon-new-world-aeternum-mmo-servers-shut-down-delisted</link>
            <guid>1407574</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Amazon has <a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/news/articles/the-future-of-new-world-aeternum-what-to-expect">announced that</a> the servers for <em>New World: Aeternum</em>, one of the company’s MMOs, will be shut down on January 31st, 2027. The game will also be delisted and no longer available for purchase starting today, January 15th.</p><p>Last year, Amazon announced that it <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/808332/amazon-gaming-layoffs-mmo-aaa-first-party-games">would be</a> pivoting away from MMOs to put more of a focus on party games, and the company said at the time that it wouldn’t be releasing new content for <em>New World: Aeternum</em> and that the game’s servers would be active through 2026. But the longer-term future of the game was unclear, and now we know the official day everything will be shut down.</p><p>If you have already purchased <em>New World: Aeternum</em>, you can play it until it’s permanently taken offline. The Marks of Fortune in-game currency will be unavailable to purchase starting July 20th, 2026, and Amazon won’t offer refunds for it. And while there’s no new content coming to the game, “we will continue to monitor bugs and performance to ensure the game runs smoothly as things wind down,” Amazon says.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/862892/amazon-new-world-aeternum-mmo-servers-shut-down-delisted]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Reality TV Show Is Going To Put Actual People Inside A Fallout Vault]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fallout-amazon-tv-show-reality-vault-shelter-2000660254</link>
            <guid>1407559</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Amazon’s live-action <em>Fallout</em> show, <a href="https://kotaku.com/fallout-tv-series-season-two-reviews-prime-video-2000653876">which is currently in the middle of season two</a>, has been a big hit for the tech giant. Now it seems to be doubling down on the franchise with a <em>Fallout</em>-themed reality show, which is currently looking for contestants.</p> <p>While Amazon hasn’t yet put out a teaser trailer for any <a href="https://kotaku.com/best-fallout-games-3-4-5-76-bethesda-rpg-new-vegas-611408965/2"><em>Fallout</em></a> reality show, <a href="https://us.castitreach.com/ag/slus/fallout/welcome.html">it is starting to look for cast members via a casting website</a>, as spotted by <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/amazon-has-greenlit-a-fallout-reality-show-where-contestants-live-in-a-vault-for-a-huge-cash-prize/"><em>VGC</em></a>. The site has a big banner image that asks people if they have what it takes to “win a big cash prize.” The reality show, which currently has a working title of “Fallout Shelter,” will force a group of people to live together in a vault and will test their skills via different activities and competitions.</p>

 <p>Here’s how the site describes the show:</p> <blockquote><p>Fallout Shelter (working title) is a new reality competition series based on the hit Amazon drama and computer game of the same name. The dwellers (contestants) live together in a top-secret vault, where they will compete in a series of games that tests the seven core attributes from the Fallout world. Strength, perception, endurance, charisma, intelligence, agility and luck (S.P.E.C.I.A.L). The series will not only test dwellers’ core attributes, but also their loyalty and alliances. It’s a game of power dynamics, popularity and social strategy which will ultimately result in a huge cash prize, but do you have what it takes to be the most S.P.E.C.I.A.L.?</p></blockquote> <p>The site features a series of questions for folks who are interested in being a part of the reality show, including questions that ask people to rank how smart they are or how agile they might be on a scale of one to ten. So it sounds like contestants may provide Amazon and the producers with their own S.P.E.C.I.A.L. stats that could be referenced in the production.</p>

 <p>Honestly, this just sounds like Amazon trying to make a<em> Big Brother</em> knock-off, but using <em>Fallout</em> to lure in gamers who might not watch otherwise. As someone who enjoys some Survivor and <em>Big Brother</em> from time to time and who also likes <em>Fallout</em>, I’ll check this show out whenever it finally arrives. They should probably pick a different name, though, <a href="https://kotaku.com/i-cant-stop-playing-fallout-shelter-1711784648">as <em>Fallout Shelter</em> is already a thing</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fallout-amazon-tv-show-reality-vault-shelter-2000660254]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Subway Surfers Sequel Is Coming In February]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/subway-surfers-sequel-is-coming-in-february/1100-6537437/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1407553</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537437">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In 2012, SYBO launched the mobile sensation <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/subway-surfers/" data-ref-id="5000-142654">Subway Surfers</a>. That game went on to become one of most downloaded mobile titles of all time. Now, the sequel, Subway Surfers City, is set to launch next month on mobile devices.</p><p>The announcement of the game's release date was accompanied by a cinematic trailer that shows off the world of Subway Surfers City.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o-3sDXTaiEY" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/o-3sDXTaiEY" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>This endless runner takes place in Subway City across four unlockable neighborhoods: The Docks, Southline, Sunrise Blvd, and Delorean Park. New neighborhoods will be added each season, alongside additional characters, outfits, and hoverboards. Players will also be given new abilities, including a stomp move, and a bubblegum shield that can enhance jumps. There are also three new game modes:</p><p><strong>Classic Endless</strong>: The beloved fast-paced runner experience where players chase high scores and discover new paths, even on their thousandth run.</p><p><strong>City Tour</strong>: A new finite game mode where players progress through levels with distinct goals, exploring districts to find hidden stars and complete missions.</p><p><strong>Events</strong>: A rotation of finite runs and trials designed to challenge even the most advanced players’ skills.</p><p>"At its core, Subway Surfers City is the next chapter of Subway Surfers' nearly 15-year-long legacy," said SYBO CEO Mathias Gredal Nørvig in a statement. "Subway Surfers continues to experience remarkable success year after year, and we're thrilled to now provide players with an entirely new way to interact with the IP."</p><p>Subway Surfers City will be released on February 26, and interested players can <a href="https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=comments&amp;redir_token=QUFFLUhqbURMT29pVVBJY0R4MnpwUi1CNnFiYTdqWG5JZ3xBQ3Jtc0tsaVlNN0lhWjZxYTUwX3BtZkNTdU5aODMxN3BYX0VXR1BsUm5TSERVQzhfZngxdzR6NW9EOTRaZlUxcTNiOV9ST1VBMUFlOHIwM2lKNDRpRWZrYUJjc3J0ckF5NUhXaEdrR2NITExDbm9melQ5a2Jsaw&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fsubwaysurferscity.sng.link%2FDv4d0%2Fntk1" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">preregister on the game's official site</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/subway-surfers-sequel-is-coming-in-february/1100-6537437/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GOG Boss Says We May Get "Fewer Games" If Regulators Force Devs To Maintain Them Forever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gog-boss-says-we-may-get-fewer-games-if-regulators-force-devs-to-maintain-them-forever/1100-6537438/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1407550</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537438">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The boss of digital PC storefront GOG has weighed in on the conversation around <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/anthem/" data-ref-id="5000-465528">Anthem</a>'s demise, saying that there may be a future in which fewer games could be developed and published if regulators demand that creators keep them alive forever.</p><p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gog-weighs-complicated-riddle-of-multiplayer-game-preservation" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Eurogamer on January 15</a> after Anthem was laid to rest, GOG's managing director, Maciej Gołębiewski, said it's good that the discussion around game preservation is happening once again, but that the conversation gets a little tricky when talking about games that were designed as online-only experiences.</p><p>"There is a broader discussion to be had within the industry of what does an end-of-life cycle look like in games--what is a fair end-of-life cycle for a game?" he said. "Should it just be buried and killed and no one can access it any more, and people who spent five or seven years working on it cannot really look at their creation any more because the service turned off? There is a very interesting and very complicated discussion that Stop Killing Games probably kick-started out of frustration."</p><p>Referencing the lobbying group <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lobbying-group-says-stop-killing-games-petition-would-make-games-prohibitively-expensive-to-create/1100-6532989/" data-ref-id="1100-6532989">Stop Killing Games</a>, which was formed in April 2024 in response to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-crew/" data-ref-id="5000-183626">The Crew</a>'s delisting, Gołębiewski said regulation sounds like a good idea in the short term, but any statutes around game preservation--particularly regarding live-service games, which are becoming the norm these days--could potentially have adverse effects in the long term.</p><p>"We want to make games live forever," he said. "At the same time, if we put too many barriers on game creators and what the end-of-life cycle looks like, we might get fewer games, because people will be scared of, 'Okay, now I need to put up the funds to create it, promote it, and then upkeep it for 10 years, 20 years, because the regulator said so.' That might in turn cause there to be fewer cool games for gamers. I don't have the perfect answer yet, but it's good that the discussion is taking place."</p><p>As of January 12, developer BioWare's pretty-cool-but-ill-fated Iron Man-esque action-RPG is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/its-the-final-countdown-for-anthem-with-only-one-week-left-to-play/1100-6537170/" data-ref-id="1100-6537170">no longer playable</a>. With Anthem being an online-only multiplayer game, you can't boot up and fly around in the world of Coda now that publisher EA has pulled the server's plug. It's a bummer of a situation, and a blatant reminder that no game lasts forever, something <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/when-is-a-video-game-allowed-to-die/1100-6533393/" data-ref-id="1100-6533393">GameSpot examined in a July 2025 feature</a> when <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-crew-is-delisted-servers-shutting-down-at-the-end-of-march-2024/1100-6519967/" data-ref-id="1100-6519967">Ubisoft took the online racer The Crew permanently off the track in March 2024</a>.</p><p>Gołębiewski's comments come as Amazon announced its 2021 MMORPG New World: Aeternum <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazons-big-mmo-that-started-strong-is-shutting-down/1100-6537436/" data-ref-id="1100-6537436">will get Thanos snapped from all platforms on January 31, 2027</a>. And if I can get personal for a second, this further heightens my fears that Full Circle's 2025 skating sim <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/skate/" data-ref-id="5000-514265">Skate</a> could get pulled offline forever in some future as well. Skate is still doing relatively well--with <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/3354750/charts/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">a consistent player count of approximately 3,500</a>, according to player tracker SteamDB--but you can't help but wonder just how long until Electronic Arts decides to hang the skateboard up.</p><p>In the end, as Ubisoft CEO Yves Guillemot said in a July 2025 shareholders meeting about The Crew: "You provide a service, but nothing is written in stone, and at some point, the service may be discontinued. Nothing is eternal. Support for all games cannot last forever."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gog-boss-says-we-may-get-fewer-games-if-regulators-force-devs-to-maintain-them-forever/1100-6537438/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Puts the Nail in the Coffin: New World Aeternum Delisted Today, Will Go Offline January 2027]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-world-aeternum-delisted-go-offline-january-2027-amazon-game-studios/</link>
            <guid>1407529</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>After <strong>Amazon</strong> killed <strong>New World Aeternum</strong> by <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-world-gets-killed-off-amazon-just-as-people-were-returning/">cancelling new content for it, just as players were starting to return to the game</a>, it began putting the nails in New World's coffin today. First, by suddenly <strong><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1063730/New_World_Aeternum/">delisting the game</a></strong> as of today, <strong>January 15, 2026</strong>. Second, by announcing that the game will go <strong>offline on January 31, 2027.</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/news/articles/the-future-of-new-world-aeternum-what-to-expect">A blog post on the official New World website</a> begins explaining the news by saying it wanted to "<em>provide transparency on where the game goes from here.</em>" Which, essentially, is nowhere. "<em></em><em>New World: Aeternum</em> will officially be taken offline from all platforms on January 31, 2027," reads the next line. </p>



<p>If you already have the game in your Steam library, then you'll still be able to play it for the remainder of this year, which Amazon previously promised would be the case. After December 31, 2026, though, you'll only have one more month to enjoy the MMORPG. If you don't have it in your library, then you've already missed your chance to grab it, as the purchase option has already been removed from the store page.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>You can still purchase microtransactions, if you want, until <strong>July 20, 2026</strong>; however, Amazon Game Studios has made it clear that <strong>refunds will not be available</strong> for Marks of Fortune microtransaction purchases. Amazon Game Studios will also still monitor the servers and release bug fixes for the remainder of the game's life.</p>



<p>New content for New World was shut down after Amazon Game Studios was hit with "<em>significant</em>" layoffs as part of <a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-video-game-division-hit-significant-cuts-amid-mass-14000-layoff/">Amazon's mass <strong>14,000+ company-wide</strong> layoff last year</a>. After the studio was clear that it wouldn't be making new content for New World, it was clear that the game would be shut down at some point, so this news isn't exactly surprising.</p>



<p>It is, however, still disappointing. Amazon had succeeded where others failed by being a major company not previously involved in video games, which entered the industry and actually knocked it out of the park with a successful internally-built game. New World was putting up <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/new-world-has-hit-100000-concurrent-players-regularly-since-launch-of-fresh-start-servers/">huge player numbers</a></strong>, and while it had previously fallen into a bit of a low period, just prior to the announcement that no more new content would be developed for it, players were starting to really return to the game.</p>



<p>"<em>We want to thank the players for your dedication and passion</em>," the blog post from Amazon Game Studios reads. "<em>We are grateful for the time spent crafting the world of Aeternum with you. Together we built something special. While we are saddened to say goodbye, we’re honored that we were able to share so much with the community.</em>"</p>



<p>"<em>It has been our pleasure to work on </em><em>New World: Aeternum</em> and evolve this unforgettable adventure with you all. We look forward to one more year together, and giving this fantastic adventure a sendoff worthy of a legendary hero. From the bottom of all our hearts, thank you for sharing this world with us."</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/new-world-aeternum-delisted-go-offline-january-2027-amazon-game-studios/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kobold Press' New Night Hunters Kickstarter Brings Gothic Action to Dungeons & Dragons and Tales of the Valiant]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/kobold-press-new-night-hunters-kickstarter-brings-gothic-action-to-dungeons-dragons</link>
            <guid>1407526</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page-content">
  
          
      
<article>

  
    

  
  <div>
      
  
  
  <div>
      <div><p>Kobold Press has launched a new Kickstarter campaign. Their latest project, <em>Night Hunters</em>, is a gothic horror supplement that introduces new player options and GM tools for both <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/dungeons-dragons" rel="nofollow"><em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em></a> and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/tales-of-valiant-starter-set-review" rel="nofollow"><em>Tales of the Valiant</em></a>.</p><p>According to its <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/deepmagic/night-hunters-gothic-horror-for-tov-and-5e-dandd/description" rel="nofollow">campaign page</a>, <em>Night Hunters</em> contains new gothic horror and dark fantasy options for your RPG table, turning a story of fantasy adventure into a night of terror. The campaign centers on two rulebooks. <em>Night Hunters</em>, which includes both player options and GM Tools, and Night Terrors, which contains 12 prewritten adventures.&nbsp;</p><picture>
                  <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/night-hunters-monster-artwork.jpg?itok=VSRFkDCl 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg" width="700" height="748">
              <source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/night-hunters-monster-artwork.jpg?itok=GOEe7BaJ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg" width="700" height="748">
                  

  </picture><p>The new player options are a solid blend of familiar and new. These include new character subclasses like the Nemesis Fighter and the Cursebreaker Cleric, horror-themed lineages like the Frankenstein-esque Gravewrought, and new Backgrounds like the Monster Hunter and the Occultist. There is also an optional Shadow Oracle deck system, which enhances play through a 56-card tarot deck.</p><p>For GMs, the books include new potential story fuel. There's a new Shadow Token system, where players can be tempted with peril in exchange for rewards. For atmosphere, there is a Ghost Story generator, a d100 Haunting Manifestations table, 60 new curses, diseases, and hazards to horrify your players, and new story hooks to keep them pushing forward.</p><p>The stretch goals for the <em>Night Hunters</em> campaign are as follows:</p><ul><li data-list-item-id="e11d86a587d69fdd82f033b13443e0747"><strong>Night Terrors PDF for $26:</strong> A PDF of the Night Terrors adventure anthology book</li><li data-list-item-id="e854f656aef3edab9ed288fb425ff3c14"><strong>Shadow Oracle Tarot Deck for $26:</strong> The 56-card Shadow Oracle tarot deck</li><li data-list-item-id="e8dea88435d9bd5c7f55a573f0e7561d6"><strong>Night Hunters PDF for $36:</strong> A PDF of the Night Hunters supplement</li><li data-list-item-id="e17702852a1e483363596120d7d2d8a10"><strong>Night Terrors Hardcover + PDF for $39:</strong> A physical hardcover and PDF copy of the Night Terrors adventure anthology book</li><li data-list-item-id="e77875f8d1b76a340cb65db241249bf33"><strong>Both PDFs for $50:</strong> PDF copies of both books.</li><li data-list-item-id="e0144d97397331145be87bd8b81828ba5"><strong>Night Hunters for Hardcover + PDF for $57:</strong> A physical hardcover and PDF copy of the Night Hunters supplement</li><li data-list-item-id="e6f7eb7a41cddb1f17e73acd37b9e7b89"><strong>Print Only for $79:</strong> Physical hardcover copies of both books</li><li data-list-item-id="e326be531188d157f2449b5b1d59abe1d"><strong>Complete Digital for $90:</strong> PDF copies of both books and two VTT licenses for access to resources on your choice of Shard Tabletop, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/premium-vtt-fantasy-grounds-is-going-free-to-play" rel="nofollow">Fantasy Grounds</a>, or Foundry.</li><li data-list-item-id="e245771dedeae91753035b48252fc7970"><strong>Both Hardcover and PDF $93:</strong> Physical and PDF copies of both books</li><li data-list-item-id="e42050c2cf75c4a6df4a0597d189202c0"><strong>Limited Edition Hunters for $100:</strong> A Limited Edition hardcover and PDF copy of Night Hunters</li><li data-list-item-id="e052d72eebdafb3b35038c53240ffe9a1"><strong>Limited Edition Hunters and Terrors for $180:</strong> Limited Edition hardcover physical and PDF copies of both books</li><li data-list-item-id="e79b873f22bb89f2d18e792fdbf59af3f"><strong>Complete Print and PDF Bundle for $144:</strong> Physical and PDF copies of both books, a spirit board playmat, an embroidered dice bag, the Shadow Oracle deck, and a Gothic Character Journal</li><li data-list-item-id="ec15e62406ddab8d38ebb4f9cdd578d7e"><strong>Limited Complete Bundle of Terrors for $323:</strong> Everything in the Complete Print and PDF Bundle goal, plus Limited Edition Hardcover physical copies of both books</li></ul><p>At the time of writing, the Kickstarter campaign has raised $155,534, almost three times its initial funding goal of $53,948. The project concludes on February 13, 2026.&nbsp;</p></div>


<div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div>

    </div>
  
  
  
  <div>
  <ul>
    <p>Additional topics:</p>
          <p>
        <li><a href="https://techraptor.net/topic/announcement" hreflang="en">Announcement</a></li>
      </p>
          <p>
        <li><a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/rpg-0" hreflang="en">RPG</a></li>
      </p>
      </ul>
</div>
  

  </div>

</article>

  </div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/kobold-press-new-night-hunters-kickstarter-brings-gothic-action-to-dungeons-dragons]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Replaces Its Employee Library With AI ‘Learning Experiences’]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/microsoft-library-ai-copilot-errors-2000660247</link>
            <guid>1407517</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Last year, Microsoft committed over <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/jul/30/microsoft-q2-2025-earnings">$100 billion of new investment</a> toward AI. Part of that technological arms race has included training LLMs on <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/06/12/open-ai-microsoft-harvard-libraries-train-ai-models/">millions of books</a>, including some written 600 years ago. This year, Microsoft is paying back the favor by ditching its own employee library. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/862531/microsoft-library-closure-transition-changes-notepad"><em>The Verge</em> reports</a> that the company is closing it down and slashing news subscriptions in favor of “AI-powered learning experiences.”</p> <p>The onsite collection of books was allegedly so heavy, <a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20200204-00/?p=103394">it once was blamed</a> for cracking the underground parking lot pillars that supported it. That library, now housed in building 92, will now be closed, according to <em>The Verge</em>. The company’s roughly 220,000 employees have also reportedly lost access to checking out digital copies of business books and accessing news publications like <em>The Information</em>.</p>

 <p>Instead of learning about the world through the considered words of other human beings, they will now be engaging with a “more modern, AI-powered learning experience through the Skilling Hub,” according to an FAQ sent to staff. “The Library closed as part of Microsoft’s move toward a more modern, connected learning experience through the Skilling Hub,” it reads. “We know this change affects a space many people valued.”</p>

 <p>Contrast that with what Microsoft recently said after it was revealed that UK police had <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/software/ai/uk-police-apologise-to-parliament-after-admitting-a-major-and-controversial-policy-decision-was-based-on-ai-making-stuff-up/">relied on an AI hallucination</a> when making the controversial decision to ban fans from a certain soccer match. “Copilot combines information from multiple web sources into a single response with linked citations,” a spokesperson for the company told media outlets. “It informs users they are interacting with an AI system and encourages them to review the sources.” Remember, it’s not slop, it’s a “<a href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-ai-slop-satya-nadella-2000656473">bicycle for the mind</a>.”</p>

 <p>It’s unclear if Copilot will be the basis for these new “AI learning experiences” that employees are now being encouraged to utilize, or what other sources of information they will use to review them now that the library is shutting down. As the science fiction writer Ray Bradbury <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20131103101724/http://community.seattletimes.nwsource.com/archive/?date=19930312&amp;slug=1689996">once told the <em>Seattle Times</em></a> in Microsoft’s own backyard, “You don’t have to burn books to destroy a culture. Just get people to stop reading them.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/microsoft-library-ai-copilot-errors-2000660247]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[10 Things I Wish I Knew Before Starting Survival Sim Hytale]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/hytale-tips-guide-crafting-workbench-teleporter-2000660168</link>
            <guid>1407514</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>Chatting with an Ewok in the Ewok Village.</span> © Hypixel / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>Anyone who has ever played&nbsp;<em>Minecraft</em> at any point in its 17 years of existence already has a head start when it comes to playing&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em>. The two games are so similar that familiarity with one mostly sets you up for the other. However, this also means it can be easier to get tripped up by the smaller details that <em>are</em> different, those aspects of the cuboid survival game that aren’t quite where you might expect them to be. So to prepare you for the transition, here are 10 things I wish I’d known before I started.</p> <hr> <h2>Don’t look for&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em> on Steam</h2> <p>In a bold move, developer Hypixel has chosen not to release <em>Hytale&nbsp;</em>on Steam, nor indeed Epic or GOG. The early access game is only available to buy <a href="https://hytale.com/">via the game’s own site</a>, and then only loads through the game’s own installed loader. Why? Because of the fall of man? Or perhaps to avoid paying the 30-percent tithes? I dunno, but it’s annoying to have yet another bespoke loader to clutter up your desktop. The game’s also not yet on console, although that’s planned for the future.</p>

 <hr> <h2>Before anything else, head for the Forgotten Temple Gateway</h2> <figure id="attachment_2000660212" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000660212"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000660212">© Hypixel / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>The smartest thing to do at the start of a new game of <em>Hytale</em> is make your way to the Forgotten Temple Gateway. This is a magic portal under a ruined temple that will teleport you to the Forgotten Temple hub, a peaceful location in which you can register all the mobs you’ve encountered so far with a central statue. (As the game develops, it’ll also be the hub for a lot of new content.) Its location is marked on your compass at the top of the screen, and it should be pretty nearby. Every creature you meet for the first time, whether hostile or ambivalent, will send a blue spark called a Memory your way. The more of these you gather, the more unlocks you’ll get via the statue, gaining access to new craftable items on your workstations.</p>

 <hr> <h2>You get sticks from trees and bushes</h2> <p>I realize, out of context, that sounds like the stupidest piece of advice ever. “What next, John? You get bear shit from woods?” But the point here is in&nbsp;<em>Minecraft</em> sticks are crafted from wood blocks, and that’s&nbsp;<em>not</em> the case in&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em>. The ingredient, vital for crafting rudimentary tools, arrows and torches, instead falls when chopping down trees and whacking bushes. And they fall plentifully! However, given the speed with which crossbows go through arrows, you’re going to want stack after stack after stack of them, so get used to punching down every bush you walk past. And talking of which…</p>

 <hr> <h2>Trees are affected by gravity</h2> <p>“And Popes are affected by Catholicism?” Yes, cleverclogs, but if you’ve played&nbsp;<em>Minecraft</em> you’ll be familiar with the oddity that has blocks magically float in place if you remove those between them and the ground. Not so in <em>Hytale</em>, meaning chopping down trees for trunks, which are then crafted into wooden blocks, and then in turn into vast amounts of other items in the game, is a much faster affair. Chop down the very lowest bit of the trunk, and then rest of the tree will come cascading down around you in its various bits and blocks, complete with trunks, sticks, and the all-important sap which is used for crafting torches, candles and other lighting.</p>

 <hr> <h2>You’re going to need a BIG house for crafting tables</h2> <figure id="attachment_2000660213" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000660213"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000660213">© Hypixel / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>When I built my first modest log cabin, it was with the expectation that I’d have a nice little crafting table, perhaps an anvil, and with enough room for some chests and eventually whatever&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em>‘s equivalent of an enchanting table might be. Oh, poor sweet summer child that I am. I have since added two entire new&nbsp;<em>wings</em> to my home to fit in the <a href="https://kotaku.com/hytale-minecraft-hypixel-crafting-workbench-quests-2000660135">ridiculous array of different workbenches</a> you need to play the game. There are a total of eight workbenches that you’ll absolutely&nbsp;<em>need</em>, and then a further four more you can add, and most have a footprint three blocks wide and two blocks high. Why it’s like this is anyone’s guess, but plan ahead when building your starter home.</p>

 <hr> <h2>Put chests directly next to workbenches</h2> <p>One of the neatest elements of&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em> (and it’s somewhat damning that it’s a detail this granular) is that if you store items in a chest near to a workbench, the bench will source materials from the chests while you’re crafting. In <em>Minecraft</em> you need to have everything in your on-body inventory, which requires juggling items between chests before crafting. Here, you can keep the crafting materials you need the most often in nearby storage and do far less organizational drudgery. Those chests do need to be close, though. If they’re on the other side of the room the bench won’t recognize them.</p>

 <hr> <h2>Repair Kits let you fix tools and weapons on the fly</h2> <p><em>Hytale</em> doesn’t offer&nbsp;<em>Minecraft</em>‘s means of fixing a weakened weapon or tool via anvils, but instead through a bespoke Repair Kit. This is a craftable item that you can keep in your inventory, and then use to restore most of a tool’s durability while you’re out and about. This is especially helpful if your pickaxe breaks when you’re 40 blocks below ground and have lost the route you took to get down there. They don’t come cheap, however. While all you need to craft a Repair Kit is two Linen Scraps, one Light Leather, and one Iron Ingot, these are all items that you’ll only get from hard work. Leather comes from slain mobs, which must then be processed on your (very slow) Tanning Rack. Linen Scraps come from fallen enemies’ clothing. And Iron Ingots are iron you’ve put through your Furnace, and at this point are a bizarrely difficult resource to find. See the next tip for more on that.</p> <hr> <h2>Iron is hard to come by</h2> <p>You might think, given&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em>‘s hierarchy of metals going Copper &gt; Iron &gt; Thorium &gt; Cobalt &gt; Adamantite &gt; Mithril, that iron would be reasonable simple to find. In&nbsp;<em>Minecraft</em>, it’s pretty much the second ore you’ll ever find after coal, and sits pretty near the surface. Not so in&nbsp;<em>Hytale</em>, where iron doesn’t start showing up until you’ve gone a&nbsp;<em>long</em> way underground, and then almost always in caverns packed with very tough enemies for such an early point in the game. I imagine this is something that will be balanced out in the near future, but for now know that you want to dig until you’re seeing lava, and then spot the silver glints in the ceiling and walls in areas that aren’t packed with foes. Grab as much as you can and get out fast.</p> <hr> <h2>You don’t drop&nbsp;<em>everything</em> when you die</h2> <figure id="attachment_2000660217" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000660217"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000660217">© Hypixel / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>In another tweak to the&nbsp;<em>Minecraft&nbsp;</em>formula, <em>Hytale</em> doesn’t strip your entire inventory when you die and respawn. Instead you keep about two-thirds of what you had when you conked it, which is pretty generous in comparison. (Only cowards play&nbsp;<em>Minecraft</em> with “Keep Inventory” toggled on.) The rest will drop where you died, and the game will put a death marker on the compass to direct you back there to scoop it all back up.</p>

 <hr> <h2>You can build teleporters to speed up travel</h2> <p>I wish this were possible a lot earlier, given the ordeal it is to craft. <em>Hytale</em>‘s world of Orbis is enormous, and while movement is pretty swift, if you’ve been out exploring other biomes it’ll still take you a fair amount of time to return to your current home without taking the death route. But there’s a way to make Teleporters, and leave as many as six of them in the world. (That number can reach 12 if you unlock enough Memories in the Forgotten Temple.)</p> <p>The first thing you need to do is upgrade your main workbench to level 2. That requires 20 Iron, which as mentioned above is the biggest obstacle, alongside 30 Copper (easily found everywhere) and 20 Linen Scrap (kill a bunch of humanoid enemies). That done, you can then craft the Arcanist’s Workbench, but this in turn is a hefty challenge. For this you’ll need 20 Essence of the Void (kill monsters at night for these), 30 Linen Scraps, and toughest of all, 10 Thorium Ingots. This requires you to travel to the Howling Sands biome (in what’s called Zone 2), so it’s not something you’ll be doing straight away.</p>

 <p>With&nbsp;<em>that</em> done, you then need the Teleporter ingredients too! For this you need Azure Logs, Azure Kelp and some regular stone. For that you need to find the blue Azure Forest biome and chop down some of those blue, blue trees.</p> <p>So yeah, quite the fuss. But once done, you’ve got a way to leap around Orbis like a mad wizard.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/hytale-tips-guide-crafting-workbench-teleporter-2000660168]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Releases Two New Magic Puzzle Company Jigsaw Puzzles for 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/new-magic-puzzle-company-jigsaw-puzzles-series-five-2026</link>
            <guid>1407511</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">The Magic Puzzle Company is one of my <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-puzzle-brands">favorite jigsaw puzzle brands</a> on the market right now. Each puzzle is made up of 1,000 unique pieces and filled with fun little easter eggs throughout. Best of all, when you finally complete the puzzle you are treated to a secret ending that is different for each one. I personally love these puzzles because every image has some serious 'Where's Waldo' vibes and utilizes different artwork from popular artists I would have otherwise never known about.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you aren't already familiar with the earlier <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-magic-puzzle-company-jigsaw-puzzles">Magic Puzzle Company Puzzles</a>, I'd recommend checking out Series One to get started. However, if you're a seasoned veteran you'll be happy to know that Amazon has just released two new Series Five puzzles for 2026 and they look quite delightful.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">New Series Five Magic Puzzle Company Puzzles</h2><div id="234491"><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234491" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Golden Goose</h3></p></div></span></p></div><div id="234492"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234492" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Coveted Comet</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Series Five is the latest series in the Magic Puzzle Company lineup, and these two new puzzles are likely the last entries we'll see until Series Six. Each series has been comprised of three total puzzles, and the first puzzle in this series was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-series-five-magic-puzzle-company-jigsaw-puzzle-features-art-from-an-adventure-time-designer">actually released back in August 2025</a>. The first option is called The Drippy Trip and features artwork from one of the original Adventure Time artists. I own this puzzle and can confirm that it is an absolute delight to put together—especially as a big Adventure Time fan</p></div><div id="226763"><div><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="226763" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>The Drippy Trip</h3></p></div></span></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">As for the two new puzzles, the Golden Goose has sort of an early civilization vibe. The artwork is by <a href="https://www.anineillustration.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anine Bösenberg</a>, who cultivates a wonderful illustration style that does a great job of feeling cozy and alive without too much heavy detail. This puzzle is already available on Amazon, but in limited quantities. If stock runs out, however, you can purchase the Series Five bundle to get the full set later in February.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The second new puzzle is called The Coveted Comet and looks to feature a colony of aliens inhabiting  some sort of comet or asteroid. The overall design is reminiscent of those cross-section books that show you everything going on within a single building, but with a more organic feel. The artwork comes from <a href="https://www.instagram.com/samuelhayward_art/?hl=en" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Samuel Hayward</a>, who appears to have a knack for creating adorable prints. This puzzle isn't available until February 15, but you can currently preorder it on Amazon ahead of its release date.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">More Magic Puzzle Company Puzzles</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're looking for more puzzles from this brand, you can check out some of the more popular options from previous releases right here:</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jan 15, 2026 6:49 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/new-magic-puzzle-company-jigsaw-puzzles-series-five-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Universal Fan Fest Nights Returns in 2026 With Scooby-Doo Meets Universal Monsters, One Piece, Dungeons & Dragons, Harry Potter, and Super Nintendo Wo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/universal-fan-fest-nights-returns-in-2026-with-scooby-doo-meets-universal-monsters-one-piece-dungeons-dragons-harry-potter-and-super-nintendo-world-experiences</link>
            <guid>1407508</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Universal Fan Fest Nights is back again at Universal Studios Hollywood beginning on April 23, and this year it will feature Scooby-Doo Meets Universal Monsters, One Piece, Dungeons &amp; Dragons, Harry Potter, and Super Nintendo World experiences exclusive to this after-hours event.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a href="https://www.universalstudioshollywood.com/hhn/en/us/things-to-do/events-and-seasonal-activities/fan-fest-nights" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tickets are now on sale</a> for the second-ever Universal Fan Fest Nights at Universal Studios Hollywood, and it will run for 12 nights only: April 23-25; May 1-3, May 7-9, and May 14-16. </p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2026/01/15/5-ip-logos-key-art-ffn-2026-at-ush-1768500582005.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Universal Fan Fest Nights is a separately ticketed event and, alongside the experiences you can read about below, it will feature character interactions, cosplay and photo opportunities, and curated food, beverages, and merchandise. As for those exclusive experiences, they are as follows, directly from Universal:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li><strong>Scooby-Doo Meets The Universal Monsters: Mystery on the Backlot:</strong> This all-new, immersive walk through adventure is designed to give guests the sensation of stepping into a live-action mystery with the Scooby-Doo gang and the Universal Monsters. Guests will travel to the destination via Studio Tour tram where they have a chance to walk along a movie studio backlot with Scooby-Doo himself and his pals Fred, Daphne, Velma and Shaggy. The exciting escapade will challenge them to solve a mystery involving the most legendary Universal Monsters in cinematic history, including Frankenstein, Dracula, Bride of Frankenstein and Wolf Man, as they navigate portions of Universal’s world-famous outdoor film sets, from the cobblestone streets of Little Europe to the iconic Court of Miracles, the original filming locations for historic Universal horror films Frankenstein (1931) and The Wolf Man (1941).</li><li><strong>ONE PIECE: Grand Pirate Show:</strong> ONE PIECE returns to Universal Fan Fest Nights, but this time as a live show extravaganza at the WaterWorld show venue. Inspired by the success of the Universal Studios Japan production, ONE PIECE: Grand Pirate Show will invite guests to a whirlwind performance featuring a cast of ONE PIECE fan- favorite characters. With action, comedy and chaos taking center stage, guests will be transported to the very heart of the world of ONE PIECE – enveloped in friendship, freedom and mayhem.</li><li><strong>The Wizarding World of Harry Potter: </strong>This new, unique, walk-through experience will take guests into the depths of the Forbidden Forest in search of a lost Hippogriff. With guidance from a Hogwarts Professor, they will encounter magical creatures and familiar beasts as they face a series of obstacles which will require the guests to summon their bravery and spell-casting skills to help a Hippogriff in need.</li><li><strong>SUPER NINTENDO WORLD – Colorful Yoshi Celebration:</strong> This year’s Universal Fan Fest Nights introduces a vibrant, multi-colored Yoshi celebration in SUPER NINTENDO WORLD. This all-new adventure will welcome guests to explore the land, where they will have a chance to meet new, colorful Yoshis who can be found throughout the Mushroom Kingdom.</li><li><strong>DUNGEONS &amp; DRAGONS: Secrets of Waterdeep:</strong> This fan-favorite immersive experience returns due to popular demand, along with some enhancements. Inspired by the World’s Greatest Roleplaying Game™, Dungeons &amp; Dragons, this epic walk-through experience will welcome guests and fans to partake in a one-of-a- kind adventure and explore the fantastic world of D&amp;amp;D. Guests will join the Harpers—a heroic spy network—to foil a plot by the legendary beholder Xanathar and save the city of Waterdeep. This engaging experience features the legendary beholder Xanathar, uniquely created by the masterful puppeteer, Jim Henson’s Creature Shop. For over 40 years, Jim Henson’s Creature Shop has been a world-renowned innovator in puppetry, animatronics and digital animation.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">There are a lot of ticket options for Universal Fan Fest Nights, including some that get you into the park during the day before the event. These include General Admission, Universal Express, Universal Express Unlimited, After 2PM Day/Night, After 2PM Day/Night, 2-Night General Admission, Ultimate Fandom Pass, Early Access Ticket, Universal Fan Fest Nights VIP Tour, and Pass Member Special Pricing. Once again, you can check out <a href="https://www.universalstudioshollywood.com/hhn/en/us/things-to-do/events-and-seasonal-activities/fan-fest-nights" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the full details and purchase the tickets right here.</a></p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Universal Fan Fest Nights Images - IGN Fan Fest 2025</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In addition to all the fun planned for Universal Fan Fest Nights, guests will also be able to enjoy select attractions throughout the event, including Mario Kart: Bowser’s Challenge, Harry Potter and the Forbidden Journey, Flight of the Hippogriff, Jurassic World—The Ride, Despicable Me Minion Mayhem, TRANSFORMERS: The Ride—3D, Revenge of the Mummy: The Ride and The Simpsons Ride.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, check out <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/universal-fan-fest-nights-brings-the-worlds-of-nintendo-harry-potter-back-to-the-future-and-more-to-life-ign-fan-fest-2025">our interview from IGN Fan Fest 2025</a> with Stephen Siercks, the Senior Director of Entertainment at Universal Studios Hollywood, all about bringing this event to life for the first time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Adam Bankhurst is a writer for IGN. You can follow him on X/Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/AdamBankhurst" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@AdamBankhurst,</em></a><em> </em><a href="https://www.instagram.com/adambankhurst/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Instagram,</em></a><em> and </em><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@adambankhurst" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>TikTok,</em></a><em> and listen to his show, </em><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/talking-disney-magic/id1773431375" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Talking Disney Magic.</em></a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/universal-fan-fest-nights-returns-in-2026-with-scooby-doo-meets-universal-monsters-one-piece-dungeons-dragons-harry-potter-and-super-nintendo-world-experiences]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon's Big MMO That Started Strong Is Shutting Down]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazons-big-mmo-that-started-strong-is-shutting-down/1100-6537436/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1407505</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537436">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Amazon Games has <a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/news/articles/the-future-of-new-world-aeternum-what-to-expect" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">announced </a>that the MMO New World: Aeternum will go offline at the end of January 2027. The announcement isn't a total surprise, though, as some theorized this would be the case after the developer announced that the MMO would get <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-world-aeternum-is-ending-new-content-after-season-10/1100-6535786/" data-ref-id="1100-6535786">no more new content</a> after the Nighthaven seasonal update last year. In October 2025, Amazon <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-cuts-hit-video-game-division-reducing-work-on-mmos/1100-6535769/" data-ref-id="1100-6535769">cut more jobs at its gaming division</a> that specifically impacted the MMO teams.</p><p>Aeternum's final day on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S is January 31, 2027. As of today, January 15, the game is being delisted. Everyone who has the game can keep playing, and Amazon announced that the Nighthaven event is being extended until the eventual shutdown.</p><p>"We want to thank the players for your dedication and passion. We are grateful for the time spent crafting the world of Aeternum with you. Together we built something special. While we are saddened to say goodbye, we’re honored that we were able to share so much with the community," the developer wrote in the announcement.</p><p><span>New World launched in September 2021 for PC and came to consoles in October 2024. The game had a strong start, reaching a peak of more than 900,000 concurrent users. The game's playerbase on Steam ticked up with new updates, but has fallen down to about </span><a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1063730/charts/#3y" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">1,100 concurrent players on Steam.</a></p><p>Amazon also clarified that it will keep selling microtransactions for New World until July 19, 2026, after which the Marks of Fortune currency will be removed from sale, along with all other items. Refunds will not be provided to people who have a balance of Marks of Fortune.</p><p>While New World will not get any more new content, Amazon said it will monitor the game for "bugs and performance to ensure the game runs smoothly as things wind down."</p><p>Amazon has struggled with games in recent years. Amazon's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazons-crucible-is-shutting-down-for-good/1100-6483150/" data-ref-id="1100-6483150">free-to-play shooter Crucible stalled and was eventually canceled</a>, while the company was making a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-reportedly-cancels-its-lord-of-the-rings-mmo/1100-6490277/" data-ref-id="1100-6490277">Lord of the Rings MMO until a supposed contract dispute ended things</a>. Amazon also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-cancels-its-new-game-breakaway/1100-6457880/" data-ref-id="1100-6457880">had a game in the works called Breakaway that was canceled</a>.</p><p>A <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2021-01-29/amazon-game-studios-struggles-to-find-a-hit" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">report from Bloomberg</a> documented an apparent pattern of mismanagement at Amazon's video game division. In 2021, Amazon CEO Andy Jassy <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-ceo-replacing-jeff-bezos-wont-abandon-gaming/1100-6487107/" data-ref-id="1100-6487107">pledged a commitment to gaming</a>, but that was years ago. The company isn't abandoning games altogether, of course, as it's publishing Tomb Raider: Legacy of Atlantis and Tomb Raider: Catalyst.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazons-big-mmo-that-started-strong-is-shutting-down/1100-6537436/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new Life Is Strange will be announced next week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/15/a-new-life-is-strange-will-be-announced-next-week/</link>
            <guid>1407481</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Square Enix has set the date and time for the next <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/life-is-strange">Life is Strange</a> game reveal. Tune in next week on Tuesday 20th January at <span dir="auto">10am PST / 1pm EST / 6pm GMT / 7pm CET for the Life is Strange reveal livestream.</span></p>
<p><iframe title="Life is Strange Returns in 2026" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b2eHeCKYHJc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The blurb on the YouTube trailer just reads “Separate the real from the rumor… Join us for the exclusive reveal of the next Life is Strange game.” However, the more enticing fact is that the placeholder page is titled “Life is Strange Returns in 2026.”</p>


<p>Unfortunately for Square Enix, Life is Strange: Reunion was leaked last week by the PEGI ratings board. The synopsis for the game on the now removed listing read “Chloe Price was Max Caulfield’s partner in time… Losing her is Max’s greatest regret. Now Chloe has come to Caledon University. Haunted by nightmares and impossible memories, Chloe needs Max’s help. But Max is already in crisis: in three days, a deadly inferno will destroy the campus.”</p>
<p>Sounds pretty familiar, doesn’t it?</p>

<p>The Life is Strange series has been in the hands of Deck Nine for a good few years now, with the IP held by Square Enix and original developer Dontnod branching off to other projects since Life is Strange 2. Having bounced between new protagonists and settings, Deck Nine brought us back to Max Caulfield’s story with 2024’s <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/life-is-strange-double-exposure">Life is Strange: Double Exposure</a>.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/10/29/life-is-strange-double-exposure-review/">our review</a>, Reu said, “Life is Strange: Double Exposure is a very easy game to recommend. If you have enjoyed previous games in the series, this is doing enough of the same to scratch that same lowkey mystery vibes itch. The ability to shift between timelines can become a touch overwhelming at times, but there’s several things in place across the UI, accessibility options, and narrative flow to keep the gameplay smooth. What’s more, I think this game might have redeemed Max Caulfield for me too, so take that how you will.”</p>
<p><em>Source: YouTube, PEGI via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/a-rating-has-leaked-an-unannounced-life-is-strange-sequel-with-strong-language-and-drug-use/">VGC</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/15/a-new-life-is-strange-will-be-announced-next-week/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Card Shop’s First Community Event Ruined By Armed Anime Backpack Robbers]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-card-shops-robbed-100k-nyc-masked-thieves-anime-backpacks-recently-opened-2000660233</link>
            <guid>1407469</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Earlier this month, a group of masked thieves wearing anime backpacks and brandishing hammers and a gun ran into a New York City card shop and then smashed and grabbed over $100,000 worth of merchandise, including Pokémon cards, from the store.</p> <p><a href="https://abc7ny.com/post/pokmon-shop-robbed-100000-merchandise-armed-burglars-manhattan/18404893/">As reported by <em>ABC7</em></a>, police are currently investigating the armed robbery involving three masked individuals that took place at the Poke Court card shop in Manhattan’s Meatpacking District on January 7. An employee told the outlet that the thieves threatened everyone in the store as they smashed glass doors to access Pokémon cards and other related merch. According to the employee, the robbery happened suddenly and took only three minutes. Police arrived after someone called 911 and reported the robbery.</p>

  <p>There were around 40 customers in the store when the three armed robbers entered and started smashing up the place. They were there as part of the Poke Court’s first community event. The shop opened in November 2025.</p>

 <p>Poke Court owner Courtney Chin said that she has a detailed list of what was stolen and is hoping insurance will cover the loss. According to the owner, the store does have alarms, but she is unsure if they worked properly and plans to talk to her security company for more information. Chin is also contemplating hiring an armed guard to help protect the store.</p>

 <p>“That’s been the recommendation of the police and of other shops in the area to get an armed guard or like a doorman,” Chin told <em>ABC7.</em></p> <p>This isn’t the first armed robbery targeting Pokémon cards and merch. <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-theft-card-store-phantasmal-flames-2000651666">We’ve seen many other card shops</a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/card-shop-pokemon-robbed-100k-hammer-rare-cards-thief-1851786241">robbed by thieves</a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-card-stolen-charizard-attack-crime-1851778231">over the last two</a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-cards-theft-250-store-stolen-robbery-rare-minne-1848569785">years as Pokémon cards</a> continue to grow in value and the demand for them skyrockets. In one incident that happened in <a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-cards-robbery-crime-japan-valuable-thieves-70k-1851647292">September 2024,</a> thieves asked employees which cards were the most valuable while robbing the place.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-card-shops-robbed-100k-nyc-masked-thieves-anime-backpacks-recently-opened-2000660233]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New World: Aeternum To Be Taken Offline Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-world-aeternum-to-be-taken-offline-next-year/</link>
            <guid>1407466</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The time of New World: Aeternum is coming to an end. </p>



<p>After it was announced that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-world-development-cancelled-amazon-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">no new content was coming</a> to the game and that it would be taken offline after 2026, Amazon Games has given an update as to when New World: Aeternum will go dark.</p>







<h2 id="h-when-will-new-world-come-down">When Will New World Come Down?</h2>



<p>In a <a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/news/articles/the-future-of-new-world-aeternum-what-to-expect" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">blog post</a> on Thursday, Amazon Games announced that New World: Aeternum will be taken offline on January 31, 2027. From that point on, no one will be able to continue playing the game.</p>



<p>With this announcement also comes the news that as of today, January 15, the game will be delisted and no longer available for purchase. If you already own the game, you can still play it and reinstall it as much as you want until the January 31, 2027 date arrives. </p>



<p><strong>“We want to thank the players for your dedication and passion,” </strong>they said. <strong>“We are grateful for the time spent crafting the world of Aeternum with you. Together we built something special. While we are saddened to say goodbye, we’re honored that we were able to share so much with the community.”</strong></p>



<p>The end of New World comes after its development team was hit with layoffs back in October. At the time, the layoffs spanned across all of Amazon, including its game studios and Twitch.</p>







<p>It has been our pleasure to work on&nbsp;<em>New World: Aeternum</em>&nbsp;and evolve this unforgettable adventure with you all. We look forward to one more year together and giving this fantastic adventure a sendoff worthy of a legendary hero. From the bottom of all our hearts, thank you for sharing this world with us.</p>



<p>Are you going to jump back into New World: Aeternum before it goes offline? Leave your thoughts on the game’s legacy down in the comments, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read the exclusive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wwe-2k26-cm-punk-showcase-mode/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">details surrounding WWE 2K26’s Showcase Mode</a> and its feature star CM Punk. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        <div>
                  <p>
                    Mike has been covering the gaming industry since 2012, and has reported on some of the largest events in the industry while also working as an investigative reporter. Outside of…                  </p>
                  <p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/author/mike-straw/">
                    More from Mike Straw                  </a>
                </p></div>
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/new-world-aeternum-to-be-taken-offline-next-year/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New World: Aeternum is dead – game delisting and server shutdown confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/15/new-world-aeternum-is-dead-game-delisting-and-server-shutdown-confirmed/</link>
            <guid>1407451</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>With the writing already on the wall in red paint after the confirmation that no new content would be coming to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/new-world-aeternum">New World: Aeternum</a> after the current season, it’s now been confirmed that Amazon’s MMORPG will be shutting down in January 2027. The game is also being delisted today and is no longer available for purchase.</p>
<p>In a farewell message alongside the announcement, the team writes, “<span>We want to thank the players for your dedication and passion. We are grateful for the time spent crafting the world of Aeternum with you. Together we built something special. While we are saddened to say goodbye, we’re honored that we were able to share so much with the community.”</span></p>


<p>The game server shutdown is scheduled for 31st January 2027, and with the game being delisted from sale today, that means a full year’s notice is being given before service is removed for the game. Additionally, Marks of Fortune, the premium in-game currency, will be removed from sale on 20th July.</p>
<p>Because you’ll still be able to play the game, and as a kind of “why not?” the Nighthaven season will be extended through to the very end, however this game is just being left to sail into the night. There won’t be any content changes, and even as the player base inevitably dwindles, there also will not be any further server merges. The only exception is that they will monitor bugs and performance issues.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.newworld.com/en-us/news/articles/the-future-of-new-world-aeternum-what-to-expect">Catch the full FAQ here</a>.</p>

<p>New World’s failure is pretty significant. The game arrived with a huge bang in 2021, as Amazon brought its fantasy colonialist MMORPG to PC, racing to a huge peak of over 900,000 concurrent players that pushed the servers beyond the limit. After such a strong start, the playerbase (via <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1063730/charts/#max">SteamDB</a>) dwindled through early 2022, but enjoyed a new peak of over 130,000 for the first yearly expansion. Perhaps a lot of expectation was put internally on the potential of the console port, which arrived with a major game overhaul last September in the form of New World: Aeternum, but on PC at least, the game has spent much of 2025 with daily peak player counts below 10,000, jumping up to 50,000 with the new Nighthaven update.</p>
<p>However, since the announced end of new content updates, the player count has understandably fallen to new lows. It last cracked the 2,000 player mark on 7th December and has been around 1,300 the last few days.</p>
<p>I’m sure plenty will log in for one last hurrah next January, just <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/12/anthem-has-now-gone-offline-forever-servers-get-shutdown/">as was done for Anthem</a> in the last few days.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/15/new-world-aeternum-is-dead-game-delisting-and-server-shutdown-confirmed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Opinion: I'm Happy amiibo Survived The Console Jump, But These Unlocks Are Getting Silly]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-im-happy-amiibo-survived-the-console-jump-but-these-unlocks-are-getting-silly</link>
            <guid>1407445</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="7c4444b503b2e"><a title="Switch 2 amiibo" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/7c4444b503b2e/switch-2-amiibo.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>If there was one name I wasn't expecting to see crop up in the Nintendo Switch 2 reveal Direct, it was <del>Kirby Air Riders</del> amiibo.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_smash_bros_ultimate">Smash Ultimate</a> and its DLC fighters had propped up the amiibo release schedule for the best part of five years, and its conclusion lined up so neatly with us all boarding the Switch 2 hype train that I couldn't imagine a better way to tie a bow on the toys-to-life fad, albeit roughly 15 years later than the rest of the industry.</p>
<p>But no. If the first six months of Switch 2 have taught me anything, it's that amiibo are here to stay. Nintendo seems determined to keep pushing these things out, and they're coming at a frankly staggering cadence — we've had <em>13</em> newbies enter the fray since the console's launch, with another five already slated for this year (plus that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/all-amiibo-list-every-animal-crossing-zelda-smash-bros-street-fighter-metroid-mario-donkey-kong-amiibo#minerus-construct">Mineru's Construct</a> model that everyone seems to have forgotten about).</p><div><figure data-videoid="6TAq6m9hxyY" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt6TAq6m9hxyY" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6TAq6m9hxyY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed76f4celkispz&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>841k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>My shelf space can't keep up, but I've got to respect the grind. The figures themselves keep getting more and more detailed, and with additions like the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-air-riders">Air Riders</a> collection and its swappable components, Nintendo is still innovating on an increasingly expensive product that I assumed was firmly in the rearview.</p>
<p>The big question, then, is where have all the bright ideas gone when it comes to the figures' in-game unlocks? I'm not going to pretend that amiibo's scannability has always been its biggest draw, but are you really telling me that in the year of our lord 2026, a short Metroid jingle is considered a valid scan reward? Come on.</p>
<figure data-uuid="4f19029c3489f"><a title="Kirby Air Riders amiibo" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/4f19029c3489f/kirby-air-riders-amiibo.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Alex Olney / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>This is a bugbear that has been brewing for a few months now. Nintendo was pleased to announce that the pricy new <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_galaxy_plus_super_mario_galaxy_2">Super Mario Galaxy</a> amiibo (launching six months after the game, might I add) unlock a Life Mushroom or a 1-Up Mushroom when scanned — because <em>those</em> are hard to come by in the base game — while other figures in the collection cough up a few measly coins. And as cool as the Kirby Air Riders range is, who <em>really</em> wants to use it to train up a league of computer racers?</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</a> amiibo gave you a head start with the Diva Dress before you unlock it as standard at the end of the game, but every other relevant figure unlocked <em>a lump of terrain</em>. You can see my point here.</p>
<p>Yes, amiibo unlocks have often felt inconsequential at best, but <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-nintendo-switch-2-edition">TOTK</a> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-all-paraglider-fabrics-full-list-locations-how-to-change">Paraglider Fabrics</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wiiu/splatoon">Splatoon</a> gear, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/mario-kart-8-deluxe-amiibo-unlocks-mii-costumes-all-compatible-amiibo">Mii racing outfits</a>, and those <em>stunning</em> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_maker_2">Mario Maker</a> pixel sprites all felt like a neat little 'thank you' for picking up the new figure. Dropping £24.99/$39.99 on a Rosalina model for a 1-Up feels like a slap in the face.</p>
<p>But hey, at least features aren't being locked behind amiibo purchases in the Switch 2 era. That's a reli— oh wait.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_prime_4_beyond">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> arrived with three new amiibo to boot. Scanning the Sylux figure instantly unlocks a special flashback cutscene otherwise accessed only by getting 100% completion (scan entries and all), and that's the least grating of them. Both the new Samus and the Samus &amp; Vi-O-La amiibo unlock features that, if it were up to me, should have been in the game right from the jump. What do you mean, bike skins and an in-game radio are only available to those who have coughed up an extra £40/$70? Those feel like the kind of features that it would have been nice for everyone to play with, no?</p>
<p>The best part is what happens when you scan other Metroid figures into the game. In a move that even makes Galaxy's gold coins look attractive, whacking another amiibo onto your Joy-Con in Prime 4 rewards you with... you guessed it, a tiny little jingle! Oh, to be a fly on the wall during <em>that</em> amiibo integration meeting.</p>
<figure data-uuid="a093da535aef4"><a title="Metroid Prime 4 amiibo" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/a093da535aef4/metroid-prime-4-amiibo.large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Nice radio you've got there, Samus — <em><span></span> Image: Ollie Reynolds / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>The only example that feels like it's hitting the right balance in the Switch 2 generation so far is <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-tennis-fever">Mario Tennis Fever</a>, where scanning relevant amiibo will unlock unique ball designs based on that character. It's a paraglider fabric-level of inconsequential, but it's a nice touch — albeit one that isn't tied to any <em>new</em> amiibo (that we know of).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/animal_crossing_new_horizons">Animal Crossing: New Horizons</a> is in a similar boat, now that I think about it. Tapping basically any Zelda or Splatoon amiibo gives you the chance to invite one of the new <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/everything-included-in-the-animal-crossing-new-horizons-nintendo-switch-2-edition-and-free-3-0-update">ver. 3.0</a> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/animal-crossing-new-horizons-zelda-and-splatoon-villagers-all-compatible-amiibo">crossover Villagers</a> to your island. It's a little on the 'locking content behind amiibo side', perhaps, but the unlock is tied to so many different figures that I find it easier to overlook.</p>
<p>It's a tightrope that all amiibo have to walk, and I don't know that I can see the exact tipping point. Lean too far one way, and you fall into the trap of scan rewards feeling pointless; too far the other, and you start locking neat features behind yet another paywall — and lord knows Nintendo has had enough pricing drama this generation already.</p>
<p>Rewards should be attractive, but not so desirable that the base game feels marginally worse without them. Inconsequential, but not downright boring. It's a classic rock-and-a-hard-place situation for Nintendo where the 'rock' is a Disappointed Jim and the 'hard place' is an Angry Jim, but both Jims are a part of the problem because they'll pay the entry fee every time. Gosh, trying to please gamers must <em>suck</em>.</p>
<figure data-uuid="6d84f2078c6f5"><a title="Street Fighter amiibo" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/6d84f2078c6f5/street-fighter-amiibo.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Damien McFerran / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>I hope that the upcoming 2026 releases can strike that sweet spot. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/monster-hunter-stories-3-twisted-reflection">Monster Hunter Stories 3</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pragmata">Pragmata</a> are all getting in on the fun, each with a mystery unlock of their own, while Nintendo itself has the aforementioned jumbo Mario Galaxy figures, another three Kirby Air Riders racers, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/11/nintendo-reveals-three-more-super-mario-wood-block-amiibo-sets">My Mario wooden blocks</a>, and <em>presumably</em> the Mineru's Construct amiibo lined up in the next 12 months.</p>
<p>I'd like to think that the latter will give us something sweet, like a new weapon skin in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Age of Imprisonment</a>, or fresh Auto Build designs in Tears of the Kingdom, but I'm braced to hear a chirpy Direct announcer gleefully read the line “scanning Mineru’s Construct amiibo in Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment for the Nintendo Switch 2 will refill your Zonai battery charge once per day!”</p>
<p>All of those yet to come will look delightful, no doubt about it, and knowing me, I'll probably end up buying some of them, too. I just hope that purchase isn't tinged with the guilt that I've just spent 25 quid on a Power-Up Mushroom.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:196024,195170,193556 @ 1768507216 -->
<p><em>Do you want to see amiibo carry on down this path, or does something need to change? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-im-happy-amiibo-survived-the-console-jump-but-these-unlocks-are-getting-silly]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘It’s Time to Go Off Into the Sunset & Look at Selling Off Your IP; The Writing’s Just Gone Downhill’, Says FOLON Lead to Bethesda]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/fallout-london-lead-bethesda-sell-ip-fallout-elder-scrolls/</link>
            <guid>1407442</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Just a few days after renowned game designer <strong>Chris Avellone</strong> <a href="https://wccftech.com/they-just-dont-fully-understand-its-roots-and-arguably-dont-care-fallout-new-vegas-lead-chris-avellone-comments-on-series-direction/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> that <strong>Bethesda</strong> didn't truly understand the <strong>Fallout</strong> franchise, the lead developer of <strong>Team FOLON</strong> (the studio that <a href="https://wccftech.com/fallout-london-team-has-sent-multiple-builds-to-gog-and-is-waiting-for-the-green-light-to-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launched <strong>Fallout London</strong> in July 2024</a>), <strong>Dean Carter</strong>, <a href="https://www.esports.net/news/industry/fallout-london-creator-bethesda-elder-scrolls-vi-fallout-5-gta-london/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">told Esports.net</a> that he feels Bethesda should sell off their IPs (Fallout and also <strong>Elder Scrolls</strong>). His dissatisfaction stems mainly from the writing of the most recent games and from the release of Fallout 76, which obviously didn't cater to single player fans.</p>



<p><em>With the greatest respect to Bethesda, I feel like they’ve probably gone one game too far, if I’m honest. I feel like it’s time to go off into the sunset and look at selling off your IP because people like the franchise, I’m just honestly not sure it’s in the right hands, and it really hurts me to say that because I love Bethesda.</em> <em><strong>The writing has just gone downhill</strong>. I know as a company, they have to try new things, but Fallout 76 caters to an audience, but it doesn’t cater to the people who want to play a single-player Fallout game. </em></p>



<p>However, Carter does add that if Bethesda could add some talented writers to their team, their next games could still be great.</p>



<p><em>I think if they’re gonna stay on board, they can stay with what they’ve got. I don’t think Skyrim is the best game of all time, like some people. It’s a very, very good game. I just feel like they need to improve the writing, I really do. <strong>I reckon if they could inject in the quality of some good writers, then the next Elder Scrolls game will be great and the next Fallout game will be great</strong>, but they need better writers, honestly.</em></p>



<p>The TEAM FOLON lead then said he's 'worried' Bethesda will keep using the <strong>Creation Engine</strong> in future games, although he clarifies it's not actually a bad engine:</p>



<p><em>I understand that it is proprietary. Don’t get me wrong, there are a lot of pluses to it. I’m not just someone that’s going to sit there and lie and say it’s a terrible engine. It could be better, yes, but it’s not a bad engine but I do think it started to show its age. It needs to be overhauled somewhat.</em></p>



<p><em>If they can overhaul it, then there’s no reason why they couldn’t push its limits and start adding things like drivable cars, maybe even metro systems like what we built in Fallout: London. I mean, if we found a way, I’m sure they could bring some of this stuff back into Fallout 5.</em></p>



<p>After the successful release of Fallout London, Team FOLON has registered as an official game developer and is now working on a new indie project built on <strong>Epic's Unreal Engine</strong>. However, they'll still release the last two planned Fallout London DLCs: Last Orders and Wildcard.</p>



<p>As for Bethesda, in a recent Fallout 3 retrospective, Studio and Production Director at Bethesda Game Studios <strong>Angela Browder</strong> <a href="https://wccftech.com/bethesda-dev-speaks-fallout-3-pre-release-hate/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> that the pre-release skepticism following their acquisition of the IP was, to some degree, freeing. Needless to say, the team has absolutely no plans to follow Carter's suggestion <span>to sell their prized franchises and is instead doubling down on them, with <strong>The Elder Scrolls VI</strong>&nbsp;next in</span> the pipeline. Given the studio's track record and the fact that their previous game, <strong>Starfield</strong>, launched in September 2023, a debut between late 2027 and 2028 seems likely. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/fallout-london-lead-bethesda-sell-ip-fallout-elder-scrolls/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here’s Why Fans Are Convinced Fallout 3 And New Vegas Remasters Are About To Be Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/heres-why-fans-are-convinced-fallout-3-and-new-vegas-remasters-are-about-to-be-revealed-2000660161</link>
            <guid>1407433</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>A strange countdown clock. Missing games and weird glitches on Steam. Cryptic comments from Todd Howard. The end of <em>Fallout</em> season two fast approaching. All of this is feeding into an ongoing belief among many <em>Fallout</em> fans that long-rumored remasters of <a href="https://kotaku.com/review-fallout-new-vegas-5670346"><em>Fallout 3</em> and <em>New Vegas</em></a> are coming soon. But how much of this is true, and how much is just out-of-control hype from fans hungry for a new entry in the series?</p> <p><a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fallout/a-steam-glitch-convinced-some-fallout-fans-a-new-vegas-remaster-was-imminent-only-to-have-the-rug-yanked-out-from-under-them-slowly-turning-into-r-halflife/">As reported by <em>PC Gamer</em> on January 14,</a> <em>Fallout</em> fans on Reddit noticed something odd with <em>Fallout: New Vegas</em> and <em>Fallout 3.</em> When trying to leave a review, Steam would block it and say the games weren’t out yet. Considering the games have been out on PC for closer to 20 years than I want to admit, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fallout/comments/1qcc9xg/both_fallout_new_vegas_and_3_are_experiencing/">this confused people</a>. It also fueled the ongoing belief that a <em>Fallout 3</em> remaster, as well as a possible <em>New Vegas</em> remaster, are launching in the near future. People theorized that this was some backend snafu related to Bethesda getting ready to shadow-drop both remasters soon.</p>

 <p>And then someone noticed that if you search for <em>Fallout</em>, Steam lists 12 games, but there are actually only 10 games currently available. Curious! This further convinced a lot of people who frankly didn’t need much convincing to begin with that<em> Fallout 3</em> and <em>New Vega</em>s remasters were coming in hot.</p>

 <h2>Debunking the<em> Fallout</em> remaster theories</h2> <p>But let’s slow down and throw some cold water on all of this.&nbsp; First, the issue with being unable to review games on Steam despite them already being released, while strange, isn’t related to any upcoming remaster. Instead, it was an issue that has affected various Steam games over the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Steam/comments/1qcb7ak/this_is_a_first_for_me/">past 72 hours or so, including <em>Batman: Arkham City</em>.</a> It also seems like it has been fixed. I was able to leave a review for<em> Fallout: New Vegas,</em> no problem.</p>

 <p>As for the 12 <em>Fallout</em> games listed but only 10 being actually available on Steam, this is a common quirk on Valve’s storefront and often happens as a result of various editions and versions of games being available or not available depending on your region. For example, looking up <em>Call of Duty,</em> Steam lists 25, but there are only 24 on the franchise page. So I wouldn’t read too much into this piece of evidence either.</p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000660210" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000660210"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000660210">©Amazon / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Meanwhile, before Steam glitches and oddities got <em>Fallout</em> fans freaking out, there was all the hubbub about Amazon’s <em>Fallout</em> countdown clock. <a href="https://www.polygon.com/fallout-new-vegas-remaster-3-amazon-s2-show-bethesda-announcement/">As explained by <em>Polygon</em></a>, Amazon recently activated <a href="https://fallout-s2.amazonstudios.com/#main">a website that features a <em>Fallout</em>-like map</a> with different locations. Clicking on them lets you explore these places via 3D and 2D tours. It’s neat, but what caught people’s attention is that one location is locked and won’t open until the season two finale of <em>Fallout</em> airs on February 4. It didn’t take long for people to connect the dots between this date and some past comments from Todd Howard explaining that Bethesda is working <a href="https://kotaku.com/todd-howard-bethesda-fallout-day-fallout-5-tease-event-remaster-2000638661">on more <em>Fallout</em></a> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/elder-scrolls-6-tes6-shadow-drop-todd-howard-release-date-fallout-3-2000642434">that he thinks the shadow drop of <em>Oblivion Remastered </em>was a successful test.</a></p>

 <p>But once again, I’ve got some cold water to pour on all this, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fotv/comments/1q7ru1e/fallout_s2_interactive_website_final_location_and/">as according to one Redditor</a> who dug into the data of the Amazon site, the locked location is just the Lucky 38 Casino, and when the clock runs out, players will be able to explore it like the other spots on the map. That’s not to say that nothing else will be announced or revealed after the finale, but don’t expect that locked spot on the site to turn into a portal leading to <em>Fallout 3 Remastered</em>.</p>

 <h2>All the evidence that <em>Fallout 3 </em>R<em>emastered</em> is happening</h2> <p>Okay, so is there any actual evidence of a <em>Fallout 3</em> or <em>New Vegas</em> remaster? Or is it all just fan hype and rumors? Well, there is some hard proof that at least a <em>Fallout 3 </em>remaster is in the works.</p> <p>First up, in 2023, a remastered version of Bethesda’s popular wasteland RPG was listed in a leaked court doc that got out during the <a href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-activision-ftc-deal-court-call-duty-xbox-ps5-1850623628">FTC vs Activision/Xbox hearing.</a> That doc listed other unannounced games, including <em>Oblivion Remastered</em> and a <em>Doom</em> prequel, both of which did launch, though later than planned. So it seems very likely that, yes, <em>Fallout 3 Remastered</em> is a thing, and it is being worked on as we speak.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Fallout 3 Remaster, Ghostwire Tokyo Sequel, Dishonored 3, Oblivion Remaster, Doom Year Zero appear on a release schedule list<a href="https://t.co/xttFBM30wp">https://t.co/xttFBM30wp</a> <a href="https://t.co/A1sv7TAuL7">pic.twitter.com/A1sv7TAuL7</a></p> <p>— Wario64 (@Wario64) <a href="https://twitter.com/Wario64/status/1703996755560546707?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 19, 2023</a></p></blockquote>  <p><a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/7-years-after-it-was-announced-the-elder-scrolls-6-is-still-a-long-way-off-todd-howard-says/#google_vignette">In November 2025, <em>VGC</em> further corroborated</a> the leaked doc and confirmed it had heard that, yes, <em>Fallout 3 Remastered</em> was real and is currently being developed. The site didn’t share any other details, but did suggest this remastered version of the RPG will be similar to last year’s <em>Oblivion Remastered.</em> So I expect the original engine will still be running under some fancy new Unreal-powered visuals.</p>

 <p>As for a <em>Fallout: New Vegas</em> remaster? Well, there’s not really much evidence for that beyond <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/xbox/fallout-3-is-getting-a-remaster-after-all-and-new-vegas-is-too-but-thats-not-what-the-tv-shows-countdown-timer-is-for">pure speculation and some supposed leakers and insiders teasing it.</a> And while I know a lot of people would love both <em>FNV</em> and <em>Fallout 3</em> to be remastered, I can’t imagine both happening at the same time and both launching on the same day. That just seems too outlandish and would have likely leaked by now, especially if it is happening sooner rather than later.</p> <p>So, that’s where we are at. <em>Fallout 3 Remastered</em> is basically a confirmed real game that is happening, but we don’t know when it will launch, though it could be this year. Meanwhile,<em> Fallout</em>: <em>New Vegas Remastered</em> is more of an internet-created rumor that could happen one day; in fact, it probably will happen, but for now, it remains a pipe dream. So in short, everybody calm down, stop checking Steam for weird bugs, and enjoy the last few episodes of <em>Fallout</em> season two.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/heres-why-fans-are-convinced-fallout-3-and-new-vegas-remasters-are-about-to-be-revealed-2000660161]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia-Owned SNK Accused Of Loading Fatal Fury Trailer With AI Slop]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/fatal-fury-cotw-s2-trailer-ai-snk-saudi-arabia-2000660224</link>
            <guid>1407430</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Even before its release in 2025,</span><i><span> Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</span></i><span> has faced controversy. The revival of the long-dormant </span><i><span>Fatal Fury</span></i><span> series came after publisher SNK was purchased by the Saudi Arabian Public Investment Fund, and it’s suffered from accusations of sportswashing ever since. Now, SNK and </span><i><span>CotW</span></i><span> are getting called out for releasing a trailer full of alleged AI slop.</span></p> <p><span>On Thursday, SNK released a trailer for </span><i><span>Fatal Fury: CotW</span></i><span>’s upcoming second season, which launches on January 22. The trailer promises a pretty robust release schedule for the game’s anniversary with monthly character drops over a six-month period. Returning characters Kim Jae Hoon, Nightmare Geese, Blue Mary, and Wolfgang Krauser are slated to join the game’s roster, too. However, the excitement of fan-favorites returning has been almost entirely overshadowed by the game’s latest trailer incorporating apparent AI-generated clips.</span></p>

  <p><span>“I’m stepping down after this trailer, I’m thankful for what you guys did for us and all but this is too much for me to deal with, this is against what I stand for,” a moderator </span><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/spicysauce.bsky.social/post/3mchxy2n7uc2d"><span>wrote in their parting message to the official Discord server</span></a><span>.</span></p>

 <p><span>It’s easy to see why. The AI stuff is just really, really ugly. The shots of cities feature skyscrapers with the most inconsistent windows I’ve ever seen, and something about the character introduction clips just looks…very off. (It’s almost like SNK knew the clips looked bad because half of them are overlaid with big walls of text and graffiti-like flourishes.)</span></p> <div><blockquote data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:rd6vccsc22rzvny6byc3o6yz/app.bsky.feed.post/3mchxy2n7uc2d" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreiamudluymmnrigb3heteb3bgpjx2ajjvyjb5abgxtw34tfzpgipwa"> <p lang="en">i was a SNK moderator for 6 years and official Cotw Discord for a year, this trailer made me step down after all those years, i don't / i can't promote a product that i don't support,thanks for all of those years friends, it was fun 🫡 bsky.app/profile/wari…</p> <p>— <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:rd6vccsc22rzvny6byc3o6yz?ref_src=embed">Spicy Sauce (@spicysauce.bsky.social)</a> <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:rd6vccsc22rzvny6byc3o6yz/post/3mchxy2n7uc2d?ref_src=embed">2026-01-15T16:11:59.809Z</a></p></blockquote></div>  <p><span>It also just seems wildly inconsistent with the game itself. </span><i><span>CotW</span></i><span> has a pretty vibrant cel-shaded art style, and the trailer’s AI shots ignore that entirely for a false sense of edginess that looks pretty corny when juxtaposed with clips of colorful, cartoonish gameplay. The studio didn’t immediately respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>SNK was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/snk-saudi-arabia-mohammed-bin-salman-mbs-king-of-fighte-1848754233"><span>purchased by the Saudi Public Investment Fund in 2022</span></a><span>. Despite promises that the ownership change </span><a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/snk-saudi-arabias-96-ownership-doesnt-affect-us-in-any-way"><span>would have no impact</span></a><span>, </span><i><span>CotW</span></i><span> doesn’t seem to have been exempt from the effects of this. The country’s sovereign wealth fund also owns Al-Nassr FC, and its soccer star </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/cristiano-ronaldo-fatal-fury-city-wolves-saudi-arabia-1851772758"><span>Cristiano Ronaldo</span></a><span> was later added to <em>CotW</em> as a playable character. It’s a shame because the game itself is decent.&nbsp; It even took home the </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/game-awards-2025-tga-winners-losers-who-won-game-of-the-year-clair-obscur-2000652261"><span>Best Fighting Game award</span></a><span> at this year’s Game Awards.</span></p>

 <p><span>SNK’s problematic ties to Saudi Arabia aren’t going anywhere in the future, but it could avoid making things worse by not piling gen AI junk on top of them. This also doesn’t bode well for Saudi Arabia’s other massive game purchase. It’s currently on track to </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ea-saudi-arabia-ownership-trump-jared-kushner-2000649726"><span>own Electronic Arts by the end of the summer</span></a><span>. </span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/fatal-fury-cotw-s2-trailer-ai-snk-saudi-arabia-2000660224]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring: Nightreign Patch 1.03.2 Buffs All the Worst Nightfarers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-patch-1032-buffs-all-the-worst-nightfarers</link>
            <guid>1407424</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring: Nightreign</a> just got a big balance patch, and even if you're not someone who's great at parsing patch notes, you might want to tune into this one, because basically every character that's been widely regarded as terrible for months now got a big buff.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Patch 1.03.2 is simply billed as "Balance Adjustments and Feature Updates" but includes a very, very long list of Nightfarer, Relic, Equipment, Sorcery, Incantations, and other adjustments that should prove a major boon especially to a few Nightfarers that desperately needed some love: Raider, Guardian, Executor, and Revenant.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We've shared the patch notes below, but here's a quick summary for each of these four characters. Guardian, whose role is generally to "tank" bosses, guard hits, and keep enemy attention so their teammates can wail on them, got a buff to damage negation and to his Guard Boost ability. Raider, a big slow heavy attacker, has historically been a little<em> too </em>slow in attacking to be really viable, so he got a big boost to attack speed. Revenant, historically just weak all around if very fun to play, got a big attack power boost to her summoned spirits. And Executor, a speedy melee attacker who plays a bit like Wolf in Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice, got buffs to seemingly everything: damage, stamina, damage negation, and more.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The community, especially those who like to main those four Nightfarers, are especially thrilled. Several of these guys, especially Raider and Revenant, have been struggling for a while now, and their weaknesses were becoming even more evident next to the two newly-added Nightfarers in the Forsaken Hollows DLC.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Those aren't the only changes, just the biggest character-related ones. There have been a ton of tweaks and bug fixes to everything from how many of certain items can be bought in shops to how much FP certain spells cost to cast. There were also, quietly, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Nightreign/comments/1qdoatt/30_weapons_id_slots_added/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">30 new weapon ID slots added to the game</a>, as someone has pointed out, though it's unclear what those are for or even if they'll ever be used. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Nightreign players are still going strong almost a year after the game first came out, with a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-gets-its-first-dlc-next-month">new DLC having dropped in December</a> adding a new map, two new Nightfarers, new bosses, and more. There's also a challenge mode called <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fromsoftware-has-an-update-and-one-last-tease-for-us-before-elden-ring-nightreigns-challenging-deep-of-night-mode-arrives-check-out-the-patch-notes">Deep of Night</a> that some players are still delving into to push their skills as far as possible.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Every IGN FromSoftware Game Review</h3></div></span></output><h2 data-cy="title2">Elden ring Nightreign update 1.03.2 patch notes:</h2><h2 data-cy="title2">Balance Adjustments and Feature Updates</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Nightfarers Adjustments</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Duchess</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted the visibility of the phantom when Duchess's skill "Restage" is triggered.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Guardian</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased damage negation for physical and various elemental attacks.</li><li>Increased Guard Boost when guarding.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Raider</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased the speed of various attacks, except dual-wield and jump attacks, and adjusted the movement distance of some attacks when using weapons of the Greataxes, Great Hammers, or Colossal Weapons categories.</li><li>Added an effect to the passive ability "Fighter's Resolve" that increases attack power for a certain period when HP is significantly reduced.</li><li>Expanded the attack range when activating the Ultimate Art "Totem Stela".</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Revenant</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased the attack power of the special attacks performed by summoned spirits when the Revenant's Ultimate Art "Immortal March" is triggered with active summoned spirits.</li><li>Increased the attack power and damage negation of spirits summoned through the skill "Summon Spirit" in the Deep of Night mode, scaling with the depth level of Expeditions.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Executor</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased the attack power of critical hits while the “Cursed Sword” Character Skill is active.</li><li>Increased the Guard Boost while the “Cursed Sword” Character Skill is active.</li><li>Increased the stagger damage upon successful deflection while the “Cursed Sword” Character Skill is active.</li><li>Reduced the stamina reduction upon successful deflection while the “Cursed Sword” Character Skill is active.</li><li>Running out of stamina after a successful deflection no longer result in a guard break while the “Cursed Sword” Character Skill is active.</li><li>Changed the specifications to apply the effects of "Improved Skill Attack Power" and "Improved Melee Attack Power" to weapon arts while the “Cursed Sword” Character Skill is active.</li><li>Increased the power of attacks - except for "Roar" - while the Ultimate Art: “Aspects of the Crucible: Beast” is active.</li><li>Increased damage negation when performing the L2(PS5) /LT (Xbox) / Q (Steam) skill attack while the Ultimate Art: "Aspects of the Crucible” transformation is active, and added a short window where it is not possible to become critically wounded even if your HP reaches zero. If your HP reaches zero during the skill's activation, you will end the transformation with 1 HP remaining.</li><li>Increased the power scaling of attacks - except for "Roar" - in accordance to the depth level - while the Ultimate Art: “Aspects of the Crucible: Beast” is active and in the Deep of Night mode.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Scholar</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted the distance criteria that affect the progress rate against large enemies in the skill "Analyse".</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Undertaker</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted the movement distance of some attacks against stationary targets when using weapons of the Hammer category.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Relic Adjustments</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>The burn damage caused by the "[Wylder] Art activation spreads fire in area" Relic Effect now increases the art gauge.</li><li>Increased the effect of the "HP Recovery From Successful Guarding" Relic Effect.</li><li>Increased the effect of the "Draw enemy attention while guarding" Relic Effect.</li><li>Increased the power of the shockwaves generated by the "[Guardian] Successful guards send out shockwaves while ability is active" Relic Effect.</li><li>Increased the effect of the "Defeating enemies near Totem Stela restores HP" Relic Effect.</li><li>Increased the effect of the "Improved Poise Near Totem Stela" Relic Effect.</li><li>Increased the effect of the "[Executor] While Character Skill is active, unlocking use of cursed sword restores HP" Relic Effect.</li><li>Renamed and modified the “[Executor] "Character Skill Boosts Attack but Attacking Drains HP" Relic Effect to "[Executor] Character Skill Boosts Attack but Lowers Damage Negation While Attacking" and increased the effect amount of the attack power boost.</li><li>Increased the healing effect duration of the "[Executor] Slowly Restore HP upon Ability Activation" Relic Effect.</li><li>Increased the effect of the "[Undertaker] Attack power increased by landing the final blow of a chain attack" Relic Effect.</li><li>Increased the effect of the "[Undertaker] Physical attacks boosted while assist effect from incantation is active for self" Relic Effect.</li><li>Decreased the effect of the "Successive Attacks Boost Attack Power" Relic Effect.</li><li>Decreased the effect of the "Improved Bow Attack Power" and "Improved Attack Power with 3+ Bows Equipped" Relic Effects.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>*This addresses an intended bug where the increased effect of the "Improved ●● Attack Power" and "Improved Attack Power with 3+ ●● Equipped" Relic Effects in Patch 1.03 were mistakenly applied to the bow weapon category.</em></p><h3 data-cy="title3">Adjustments to Equipment, Sorceries, and Incantations</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Distance-related drop-off is now applied to status ailment accumulation, Ultimate Art gauge charging and near-death gauge depletion when attacking downed allies for attacks that take in account damage drop-offs, such as Ranged Weapons.</li><li>Changed the primary sorcery of the "Rotten Crystal Staff" from "Shattering Crystal" to "Crystal Release."</li><li>Increased the FP consumption of the "Shattering Crystal” sorcery.</li><li>Increased the FP consumption of the "Beast Claw" incantation.</li><li>Adjusted the visibility of the effects of some sorceries and incantations.</li><li>Reduced the "Reduced Maximum HP" effect of the "Primal Glintstone Blade" talisman.</li><li>Reduced the "Impaired Damage Negation" effect of the "Crucible Feather Talisman".</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Field Adjustments</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>"Fire Pots" and "Throwing Knives" now have a maximum amount that can be bought in shops.</li><li>Increased the number of Night Invaders that appear when the "Marsh" Key location experiences cataclysms.</li><li>Adjusted the number of some enemies appearing in the "Blacksmith Village" Key location.</li><li>Decreased the attack power of some enemies appearing in the "Blacksmith Village" Key location in "The Deep of Night."</li><li>Increased the amount of runes obtained by defeating some enemies in the "Marsh" and "Blacksmith Village" Key locations.</li><li>Increased the probability of rare weapons and items appearing in some treasure chests in the "Marsh" and "Blacksmith Village" Key locations.</li><li>Adjusted the spawn rate of special shops in "The Great Hollow" Shifting Earth.</li><li>Increased the effect of the "Beast's Hunt" special ability obtained in the "Tricephalos" Raid event to fully restore stamina for surrounding allies during continuous attacks.</li><li>Decreased the continuous damage received by player characters during the "Tricephalos" Raid event.</li><li>Adjusted the visibility during the "Tricephalos" Raid event.</li><li>Adjusted the visibility during the "Fissure in the Fog" Raid event.</li><li>Decreased the falling hail damage during the "Fissure in the Fog" Raid event in the Deep of Night mode.</li><li>Adjusted the number of enemies entering the Charm state at some points during the “Balancers” Raid event.</li><li>Decreased the amount of attack power boost for enemies in the Charm state during the “Balancers” Raid event.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Other adjustments</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted the appearance rates of the target bosses, key locations, and Shifting Earth added in the DLC "The Forsaken Hollows" in "The Deep of Night”.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>*This adjustment applies to Expeditions when matched only with players who also own the DLC.</em></p><h2 data-cy="title2">Bug Fixes and Improvements</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added an icon display and the description of Special Effects in the status menu for the "Improved Attack Power at Full HP" and "Improved Damage Negation at Full HP" passive effects while they are active.</li><li>Added an icon display and the description of Special Effects in the status menu for the "Switching Weapons Boosts Attack Power" Relic Effect while it is active.</li><li>Fixed an issue where some costumes for Scholar and Undertaker, as well as unique relics that can only be obtained once in the DLC, would disappear and made it possible to re-acquire them at the Roundtable Hold.</li><li>Fixed a bug where it was possible to obtain multiple copies of the relic "The Will of the Balancers" under certain conditions.</li><li>Additionally, if multiple copies of the relic "The Will of the Balancers" are equipped, only one of these relics will become activate.</li><li>Fixed a bug where, when the relic with the "[Raider] Hit With Character Skill to Reduce Enemy Attack Power" effect was equipped, the Raider's Character Skill: "Retaliate" would sometimes not stagger enemies even when hitting them while in an enhanced state.</li><li>Fixed an issue where spirits summoned by Revenant’s skill could be staggered by enemy attacks within the defensive area summoned by Guardian's Ultimate Art: Wings of Salvation.</li><li>Improved the partial appearance of some movements when Raider performs a critical hit.</li><li>Fixed a bug where, under certain conditions, Executor’s "Aspects of the Crucible: Beast" Ultimate Art would cause unintended damage related to Status Ailments when triggered.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the effect of reducing the near-death gauge using the level 3 “Warming Stone” item from Scholar's Passive Ability “Bagcraft” did not apply to the player who used the item.</li><li>Fixed a bug where activating Executor’s "Aspects of the Crucible: Beast" Ultimate Art while linked with Scholar's Ultimate Art “Communion” would cause unintended large damage to the linked enemies.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the attack hitbox of the "Beast Claw" Incantation could disappear during use.</li><li>Fixed a bug in the Whip weapon category where the first part of a normal attack did not apply the Passive Effects “Improved Melee Attack Power”.</li><li>Fixed bugs in some attack hitboxes of the following Weapon Arts where the effects of “Improved Skill Attack Power” and “Improved Melee Attack Power” from Relics or Passive Effects were not applied.<ul data-cy="list"><li>Waves of Darkness</li><li>Eruption</li><li>Lightning Slash</li><li>Golden Land</li><li>Ice Lightning Sword</li><li>Sorcery of the Crozier</li><li>Sacred Phalanx</li><li>Flame Dance</li></ul></li><li>Fixed a bug where of “Improved Skill Attack Power” effect from Relics or Passive Effects did not apply to the “Torch Attack” Skill.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the gravitational wave generated by the “Power of the Starscourge” of the Colossal Sword “Collapsing Stars Greatsword” Passive Effect did not apply the effect of “Improved Melee Attack Power” from Relics or Passive Effects.</li><li>Fixed bugs where effects triggered by continuous attacks from Relics or Passive Effects did not activate in some attack hitboxes of the following Weapon Arts.<ul data-cy="list"><li>“Kick”</li><li>“Charge Forth”</li><li>“Giant Hunting”</li><li>“Carian Greatsword”</li><li>“Carian Grandeur”</li><li>“Carian Greatsword”</li><li>“Miquella's Ring of Light”</li><li>“Spinning Wheel”</li><li>“Giant Hunting”</li></ul></li><li>Fixed a bug where the shockwave generated by the "Attacks Generate Golden Shockwave" Passive Effect did not leave an elemental mark when hitting enemies.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the attribute added to the weapon held in the opposite hand would disappear when the "Switching Weapons Adds an Affinity Attack" Relic Effect was active and the weapon was switched.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the attack power of the “Glintstone Scrap” and “Large Glintstone Scrap” Items did not increase with the "Improved Glintstone and Gravity Stone Damage" Relic Effect.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the following Relic Effects would not apply even when their activation conditions were met while the player character was in a near-death state.<ul data-cy="list"><li>“Max FP increased for each Sorcerer's Rise unlocked”</li><li>“Runes and Item Discovery increased for each great enemy defeated at a Fort”</li><li>“Attack power increased for each evergaol prisoner defeated”</li><li>“Attack power increased for each Night Invader defeated”</li></ul></li><li>Fixed a bug under certain conditions where player characters would not enter a near-death state or would die without entering the near-death state when HP reached zero due to an enemy's grab attack.</li><li>Fixed a bug where executing a critical hit from behind some enemies would cause damage to an adjacent allied player character.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the ice mist effect from the "Fissure in the Fog" Raid event would activate upon using Executor’s "Aspects of the Crucible: Beast" Ultimate Art under certain conditions.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the Untold Power would not appear even after reducing the HP of the "Albinauric Archers" powerful foes to zero in ruins.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the "Night's Cavalry" boss would not flinch significantly from certain arts and attacks while mounted.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the HP gauge of the "Royal Cavalryman" would not display when beginning combat with the bosses "Tree Sentinel, Royal Cavalryman" and "Draconic Tree Sentinel, Royal Cavalryman" when other field bosses' HP gauges are displayed.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the playback timing of some BGM in the battle against the boss "Divine Beast Dancing Lion" was not as playing as intended.</li><li>Fixed a bug where temporary Special Effects granted to the player character during the battle against the boss "Knight Artorias" would persist even after the battle ended.</li><li>Fixed a bug where some enemy skills would activate in unintended positions during the battle against the "Balancers" boss under certain conditions.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the volume of some sound effects would be lower than intended depending on the distance from the enemy during the battle against the "Balancers" boss.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the battle against the "Balancers" boss would not progress under certain conditions.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the effects of some attacks would not render when the distance from the enemy was too far during the battle against the Salvation’s Standard-Bearers "Balancers" boss.</li><li>Reduced the rendering load for some enemy attacks during the battle against the Salvation’s Standard-Bearers "Balancers" boss.</li><li>Reduced the unstable rendering of allied player characters' movements during the battle against the Salvation’s Standard-Bearers "Balancers" boss.</li><li>Fixed a bug where some parts of the combat would be skipped during the battle against the "Dreglord" boss under certain conditions.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the Weapon Art of the weapon "Nox Flowing Hammer" sold in shops was different than intended.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the objects required to solve the gimmicks in Sorcerer's Rise would be buried in the ground under certain conditions.</li><li>Fixed a bug in the "Tricephalos" Raid event where rewards could not be obtained if the event's completion and achievement occurred simultaneously.</li><li>Fixed a bug in the "Balancers" Raid event where the HP of the "Balancers" could be reduced from the start during multiplayer.</li><li>Fixed a bug in the "Balancers" Raid event where events might not occur in the "Great Church" Key location.</li><li>Fixed a bug where player characters could not move properly when the "Balancers" Raid event occurred under certain conditions.</li><li>Fixed a bug where obtaining the "Favor of the Great Hollow" Special Effect in The Great Hollow Shifting Earth did not increase the "Encounters with shifting earth" in the Visual Codex Menu's Battle Record.</li><li>Fixed a bug where multiple instances of the "Cold Mirage" Special Effects might be displayed in the Result menu.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the game could not progress if the session host left immediately after embarking on an Expedition.</li><li>Fixed a bug in the fight against the Salvation’s Standard-Bearers "Balancers" boss where some enemy actions would not occur if other players left at specific timings.</li><li>Fixed a bug in the fight against the "Dreglord" boss where some parts of the "Decayed Favor of the Rotted Woods" Special Effect would not become inactive after a session leave and rejoin at a specific timing.</li><li>Fixed a bug in the fight against the "Dreglord" boss where some field-wide effects would not be applied after a session leave and rejoin at a specific timing.</li><li>Corrected some text.</li><li>Fixed rendering bugs in some graphics and effects.</li><li>Fixed behavioral bugs with certain enemies.</li><li>Fixed several minor bugs and improved performance.</li><li>Fixed a bug in the Steam version where connection issues could occur immediately after matchmaking was completed.</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-patch-1032-buffs-all-the-worst-nightfarers]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloodborne’s 10th Anniversary Vinyl Soundtrack Is Now Available To Preorder]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/bloodborne-10th-anniversary-original-soundtrack-vinyl-where-to-buy</link>
            <guid>1407421</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">To celebrate <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/bloodborne">Bloodborne</a>'s 10th anniversary, Laced Records is gearing up to drop a Vol. I &amp; II vinyl set that includes the incredible soundtrack featured in both the base game and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/bloodborne/The_Old_Hunters_(DLC)">The Old Hunters DLC</a>. It's currently available for fans to preorder for $123.99 with a release date of May 15 this year (<a href="https://zdcs.link/z64q0d?object_uuid=669321f9-8820-4d3d-b184-2be5019ed39c&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0G3BBT2MC" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">see it here at Amazon</a>). I, for one, am already counting down the days until I can get my hands on it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Keep in mind that preorders like these can sell out fast, so be quick to get your order in before it's gone. Below, we've also detailed the full track list, for those interested in seeing what comes on each disc.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Preorder Bloodborne 10th Anniversary Vol. I &amp; II Vinyl</h2><div id="234487"><p><span data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><div id="234487" data-cy="solo-product-card"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Bloodborne 10th Anniversary Vol. I &amp; II Original Soundtrack</h3></p></div></span></p><p data-cy="paragraph">The box set has a very sleek black design with gold lining on the lettering and on the back. The covers for each of the volumes have great designs as well, with the first volume featuring a Hunter in blue and volume two featuring Lady Maria in red. Alongside the black LPs, it even comes with an exclusive Caryll Runes slipmat, which you can check out below.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Bloodborne 10th Anniversary Vol. I &amp; II Track List</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Disc One:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Omen</li><li>The Night Unfurls</li><li>Hunter's Dream</li><li>The Hunter</li><li>Cleric Beast</li><li>Blood-Starved Beast</li><li>Watchers</li><li>Hail the Nightmare</li><li>Darkbeast</li><li>The Witch of Hemwick</li><li>Rom, the Vacuous Spider</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Disc Two:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Moonlit Melody</li><li>The One Reborn</li><li>Micolash, Nightmare Host</li><li>Queen of the Vilebloods</li><li>Soothing Hymn</li><li>Celestial Emissary</li><li>Ebrietas, Daughter of the Cosmos</li><li>The First Hunter</li><li>Moon Presence</li><li>Bloodborne</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>Disc Three:</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Terror</li><li>Amygdala</li><li>Of the Pthumerian Line</li><li>Lullaby for Mergo</li><li>Ludwig, the Holy Blade</li><li>Laurence, the First Vicar</li><li>Living Failures</li><li>Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower</li><li>Orphan of Kos</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">Looking for even more vinyls to add to your collection? The IGN Store has quite a few worth checking out at the moment. <a href="https://store.ign.com/products/clair-obscur-expedition-33-original-soundtrack-2lp-vinyl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Clair Obscur Expedition 33's soundtrack on vinyl is currently available to preorder</a>, as is <a href="https://store.ign.com/products/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii-official-kingdom-come-deliverance-ii-soundtrack-vinyl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kingdom Come Deliverance 2's soundtrack on vinyl</a>. To see even more, check out the <a href="https://store.ign.com/collections/vinyl" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IGN Store's vinyl collection page</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jan 15, 2026 5:38 pm</p></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/bloodborne-10th-anniversary-original-soundtrack-vinyl-where-to-buy]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>