<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 11:36:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 May Release in the First Half of 2025 for $499]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-release-499/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-may-release-in-the-first-half-of-2025-for-499.954885/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-release-499/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 may not be released during the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-miss-early-2025-launch/">current fiscal year ending in March 2025</a>, but it may still launch in the first half of the year, according to a new report.</p>
<p>Tokyo Security analyst Hideki Yasuda said in a <a href="https://kabutan.jp/news/marketnews/?b=n202408150860" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new report</a> that the console should be released in the first half of the year for $499. As such, if the console won't indeed launch in the current fiscal year, it should become available between April and June.</p>
<p>As far as official information goes, very little is currently known about the Nintendo Switch 2, not even its official name. The system will deliver a level of performance <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-software-impact/">not too different from the Steam Deck</a>, although the console's stronger GPU and weaker CPU, compared to Valve's system, will make it run games at <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-higher-resolution-steam-deck/">a higher resolution but lower framerate</a>. The console is also said to support NVIDIA DLSS and Ray Reconstruction, which should give it an edge in a variety of situations, potentially making it superior to the PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X when it comes to ray tracing.</p>
<p>The Nintendo Switch 2 has yet to be officially revealed. We will let you know more about the system as soon as possible, so stay tuned for all the latest news.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite is back on the iPhone — with a whole app store in tow]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/16/24221361/fortnite-iphone-epic-games-app-store</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-is-back-on-the-iphone-%E2%80%94-with-a-whole-app-store-in-tow.954882/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/16/24221361/fortnite-iphone-epic-games-app-store<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Fortnite</em> is finally back on iOS, just over four years after Apple booted it from the iOS App Store — but it’s only available in the EU. The game is launching today on both a new iPhone version of the Epic Games Store and through AltStore PAL, another third-party app store. The Epic Games Store is also launching today for Android users worldwide.</p><p>The launch follows years of litigation between Epic and Apple, as well as regulatory changes ushered in by the EU’s Digital Markets Act, which forced Apple to allow <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/25/24050200/apple-third-party-app-stores-allowed-iphone-ios-europe-digital-markets-act">alternate app stores</a>. Epic plans to eventually bring its games to Aptoide’s iOS store in the EU and the ONE Store on Android and says<strong> </strong>in <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.epicgames.com%2Fsite%2Fen-US%2Fnews%2Fthe-epic-games-store-launches-on-mobile">a blog post</a> that “we look forward to bringing our games to other stores around the world.”</p><p>“We’re really excited and grateful for the European DMA law,” Epic Games founder and CEO Tim Sweeney said in a briefing with reporters. “<em>Fortnite</em> is finally returning to iOS in Europe.”</p><p>There is a catch: after scanning the <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/mobile">QR code from Epic’s website</a>, a popup appears saying “to install the Epic Games Store on your iPhone, update to iOS 17.6 or later.” This conflicts with <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/mobile/ios">Epic’s own FAQ</a> that says the Games Store can be installed on “iPhones running iOS 17.4 or later.”</p><p>Nevertheless, the revived iOS version of <em>Fortnite</em> is launching just in time for the new<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/15/24221374/fortnite-marvel-absolute-doctor-doom">Marvel-themed season</a>, giving EU players a potentially major reason to come back to the game on Apple’s mobile platform. Sweeney said that Epic foresees “absolutely no trouble of being able to update <em>Fortnite</em> simultaneously, worldwide.” In addition to <em>Fortnite, </em>European iPhone owners and global Android users will be able to download Epic’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22345184/rocket-league-sideswipe-android-ios-announced"><em>Rocket League Sideswipe</em></a> and a new title, a mobile version of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/5/21355586/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-pc-ps4-game"><em>Fall Guys</em></a>, from the Epic Games Store.&nbsp;</p><div><figcaption>Fall Guys<em> is now available on mobile for the first time.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Epic Games</cite></p></div><div><p>Since Epic announced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/25/24050800/epic-games-store-fortnite-apple-ios-launch-eu-dma">its plans</a> for an iOS store, Apple has repeatedly slowed the process down. In March, Apple <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/6/24092158/epic-apple-developer-account-terminated-digital-markets-act-alternative-ios-app-store">shut down an Epic developer account</a> and called the company “verifiably untrustworthy,” perhaps alluding to Epic knowingly breaking Apple’s rules with a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366259/epic-fortnite-vbucks-mega-drop-discount-iphone-android"><em>Fortnite </em>in-app payment system</a> that got it <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/13/21366438/apple-fortnite-ios-app-store-violations-epic-payments">kicked off iOS</a>. Apple reinstated Epic’s account <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/8/24094543/epic-games-ios-developer-license-apple-dma">after an inquiry from the European Commission</a>, but it later took issue with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/6/24193182/apple-approved-epic-games-store-notarized-eu-dma-fortnite">the Epic Games Store’s buttons</a>.&nbsp;</p></div><p>While the mobile Epic Games Store currently has just three first-party games, the company is already in discussions with third-party mobile developers. Epic aims to have a “curated” selection of third-party games on the mobile store in December, VP and Epic Games Store GM Steve Allison said, with self-publishing (which <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/3/9/23630864/epic-games-store-self-publish-tools-ratings">is already possible on PC</a>) set to arrive in early 2025. Epic also plans to bring over “everything” it offers on PC, like its 88 percent revenue share for developers, free games for players, and the option for developers to use their own payment platforms. It’s aiming for 100 million net new Epic Games Store mobile installations by the end of the year, Allison said, though that could be hampered by hurdles in Apple’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24100979/altstore-europe-app-marketplace-price-games">third-party installation process</a>.</p><p>To succeed, Epic will need developers to brave Apple’s fees for venturing outside the App Store. If a developer wants to list their app on a third-party store, they must pay Apple a “<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/26/24051823/apple-third-party-app-stores-50-cent-fee">Core Technology Fee</a>” of €0.50 per year for each install after the first million. This fee applies to app installs on both third-party app stores <em>and</em> the App Store, which could add up quickly if you have a successful app on the App Store and want to offer your app through an outside marketplace. “The effect of that is to dissuade any developer of a current, successful game from putting their game on any store that competes with the iOS App Store,” Sweeney said.</p><p>Apple also announced <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/9/24216181/apple-eu-app-store-services-fee-external-links">additional new fees</a> last week. “We’d like to use the walled garden terminology, but these core tech fees and the new things introduced last week made the wall a little bit higher, and maybe [Apple] put some barbed wire on top,” Allison said.</p><p>For Epic, it’s worth scaling that wall. According to court documents, <em>Fortnite</em> on iOS made <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/28/22407939/fortnite-biggest-platform-revenue-playstation-not-ios-iphone">more than $700 million</a> over the two years before Apple yanked it from the store. While <em>Fortnite</em> will certainly have a much smaller audience on an EU-only third-party store, Epic will get 100 percent of the revenues from in-app purchases instead of paying Apple’s usual 30 percent App Store cut. Some of that revenue will go toward Apple’s fees, but Epic is big enough to weather them. And if regulation, competitive pressures, or public sentiment force Apple to soften its byzantine rules for third-party app stores, Epic will be one of the biggest, earliest players in the field.</p><p>But so far, many third-party developers seem leery. Allison said that Epic is in active discussions with “just about every single one” of the top 250 mobile developers. And while the developers are “very enthusiastic” about the Epic Games Store on Android, “almost all of them” said they can’t make it work on iOS.</p><p>Epic knows it’s got a long way to go. The company has already spent hundreds of millions in its fight with Apple, according to Sweeney. And Allison acknowledged there’s still a huge amount of friction for players and developers. “But our vision for the future is we’re going to keep fighting,” Allison said. “We’re going to make progress. We are confident that over time, we will get these things eradicated. But we don’t know if it’s going to be two months or two years or longer, but we certainly hope it’s one of the shorter ones.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Chapter 5 Season 4 is Live: Here’s Everything New]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-is-live-heres-everything-new/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-is-live-here%E2%80%99s-everything-new.954876/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-is-live-heres-everything-new/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Fortnite Chapter 5 Season 4 kicked off today, August 16, and here’s everything new in the Absolute Doom season, including POIs, Marvel Weapons, Mythics, battle pass details and more.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Fortnite Battle Royale Chapter 5 Season 4 - Absolute Doom | Official Season Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5uE0XFJSVZA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<h2 id="h-fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-pois">Fortnite Chapter 5 Season 4 POIs</h2>



<p>In the latest season of Fortnite, Dr. Doom and his army are the main villains. Dr. Doom has introduced new points of interest (POIs) in Chapter 5, Season 4, to strengthen his control over the island. The first addition is Castle Doom, a towering structure casting a massive shadow over the island. Next is The Raft, a maximum security prison that Doom has brought to the island to recruit more evil characters. Lastly, there’s Doomstadt, a Latverian Village run by Doom. Players will also find a Fantastic Four easter egg in this area.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-marvel-weapons">Marvel Weapons</h2>



<p>Fortnite Chapter 5 Season 4 has unvaulted old Marvel weapons and introduced new ones. First is the return of Dr Doom’s Gauntlets and Captain America’s shield; both weapons have been updated with new capabilities. Then we see new additions to the Marvel weapons pool, which include Gwenpool’s Dual Micro SMGs and War Machine’s Arsenal, Auto Turret and Hover Jets.&nbsp;Moreover, we also saw Black Panther’s claws as a new melee weapon in the latest trailer.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-fortnite-chapter-5-season-4-medallions-and-mythics">Fortnite Chapter 5 Season 4 Medallions and Mythics</h2>



<p>Three new medallions and mythics in the latest Fortnite season can be claimed by defeating three bosses. First is Doombot in Castle Doom; defeating him will grant you the Siphon Medallion and the Monarch Pistol. Then we have Emma Frost at The Raft, who players can defeat to acquire the Reveal Medallion and the Striker Burst Rifle. Third, Mysterio at Doomstadt can be defeated for the Stealth Medallion and the Sovereign Shotgun.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-absolute-doom-battle-pass">Absolute Doom Battle Pass</h2>



<p>Fortnite Chapter 5 Season 4’s Battle Pass will cost players 950 V Bucks and let players earn up to 1,500 V Bucks as they level up. Players can earn XP across Battle Royale, Creator-Made Islands, LEGO Fortnite, Rocket Racing and Fortnite Festival. Levelling up through the latest battle pass will grant you skins like Gwenpool, War Machine, Peelverine, Emma Frost, Captain Jonesy, Mysterio and Shuri. Dr Doom will also be available later in the season through special Battle Pass Quests in September. The last day for progressing through the Absolute Doom Battle Pass is&nbsp; November 1 at 11 PM PT / November 2 at 2 AM ET.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>In other news, a Fortnite X Snoop Dogg collaboration is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-snoop-dogg-this-november-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rumoured to arrive this November</a>. Also, the All-Women’s Fortnite LAN event, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-milk-cup-all-womens-fortnite-lan-event-happening-in-la-this-october/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Milk Cup</a>, is coming to Los Angeles this October. What are your thoughts on Fortnite Chapter 5, Season 4? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/north-beach-stranded-deep-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">North Beach Games opening a new studio in Prague to develop Stranded Deep 2</a>&nbsp;and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming&nbsp;newsletter</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two Legacy of Kain games will be re-released for Evercade next month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/two-legacy-of-kain-games-will-be-re-released-for-evercade-next-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/two-legacy-of-kain-games-will-be-re-released-for-evercade-next-month.954867/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/two-legacy-of-kain-games-will-be-re-released-for-evercade-next-month<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/soul-reaver-legacy-of-kain.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Crystal Dynamics</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Two Legacy of Kain games are being re-released, but for the Evercade retro handheld console.
</p>
<p>
The Legacy of Kain Collection will include both Blood Omen: Legacy of Kain and Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver on one giga cart priced £22.49.
</p>
<p>
The collection will release next month and will be <a href="https://evercade.co.uk/cartridges/legacy-of-kain-collection/">available to pre-order</a> from 30th August. It's compatible with all Evercade and Super Pocket devices.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Evercade - Legacy of Kain Collection - Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zlSBRNk2fVY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Evercade - Legacy of Kain Collection - Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zlSBRNk2fVY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/zlSBRNk2fVY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Evercade - Legacy of Kain Collection - Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zlSBRNk2fVY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>

The two games mark the first entries in the Legacy of Kain saga, which began with Blood Omen in 1996. The follow-up, Soul Reaver, was helmed by Amy Hennig and has become a cult classic, with fans desperate for a re-release or remake.
</p>
<p>
Indeed, at last month's Comic-Con San Diego, logos for an unannounced "<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-2-remaster-hints-surface-at-comic-con">Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver 1 &amp; 2 Remastered</a>" were included on display plaques accompanying statues of characters from the games, leading to much speculation.

</p>
<p>
The games' developer Crystal Dynamics also released a survey to fans in 2022 to gauge interest in a potential revival of the series. It <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/crystal-dynamics-hears-legacy-of-kain-fans-loudly-and-clearly-following-huge-survey-response">received a huge response</a>.
</p>
<p>
"Rest assured," said Crystal Dynamics and Eidos CEO Phil Rogers, "we hear you loudly and clearly, and we'll continue to update you on the 'what if' possibilities ahead for Legacy of Kain in the future."

</p>
<p>
This Evercade re-release of the original games may not be the full remake fans were hoping for, but it's at least some movement in the right direction. Eurogamer's Ian Higton has <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-weve-been-playing-fitness-games-old-classics-and-dungeons-dragons">already got his hands on the Evercade versions</a>: "I know exactly what I'll be doing on my flight to Gamescom next week," he said. "Imagine it: playing a PS1 game on a plane on a handheld device. The future is now - the future is retro!"

</p>
<p>
The collection is the second release from Blaze Entertainment and Crystal Dynamics, following Tomb Raider Collection 1, which includes the first three of Lara Croft's adventures.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tim Sweeney: "No regrets" on Fortnite app store drama, as Epic Game Store launches on mobile in Europe]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/tim-sweeney-no-regrets-on-fortnite-app-store-drama-as-epic-game-store-launches-on-mobile-in-europe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tim-sweeney-no-regrets-on-fortnite-app-store-drama-as-epic-game-store-launches-on-mobile-in-europe.954864/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/tim-sweeney-no-regrets-on-fortnite-app-store-drama-as-epic-game-store-launches-on-mobile-in-europe<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"We've probably lost $1bn dollars... but what's the price of freedom?"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/14br-freefortnite-europe-newsheader-1920x1080-transparent-1280x720-a6a9cee868e8.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Epic Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Epic Games boss Tim Sweeney has said he has "no regrets" over his company's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-adds-cheaper-mobile-payment-option-to-circumvent-apple-google-fees">decision to break Apple and Google's terms of service back in August 2020</a> - something that saw the hugely-popular <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> booted off both iPhone and Android storefronts.
</p>
<p>
The carefully choreographed stunt sparked four years of legal wrangling over Apple and Google's app store policies - and has ultimately led to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-secures-ios-developer-account-europe-mobile-store-and-fortnite-launch-this-year">Epic Games launching its own mobile store today</a> on Android worldwide and on iPhone in mainland Europe, thanks to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-returning-to-ios-says-epic-as-apple-agrees-to-alternative-app-marketplaces-in-eu">policy changes demanded of Apple by the EU</a>.
</p>
<p>
"We've probably lost a billion dollars not having Fortnite on iOS the past four years," Sweeney said, in a briefing to press ahead of the Epic Games Store on mobile going live. "But what's the price of freedom?"
</p>
<p>
Today, Fortnite, Rocket League Sideswipe and a new <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fall-guys">Fall Guys</a> mobile version (cross-compatible with the existing PC and console editions) will be the first games available in the Epic Game Store on smartphones. Other, non-Epic Games titles will then become available later this year.
</p>
<p>
"We've set a goal of 100m new installs across Android and iOS before the end of the year," explained Steve Allison, Epic Game Store's VP, General Manager. "We think we could do that in a world where everything was a level playing field, and we're still trying to drive at that number. The only thing standing in our way is the friction Apple and Google are putting in front of us - and it's pretty significant."
</p>
<p>
Epic Games is still unhappy about a variety of things - including a fiddly process to install its alternative storefront on iPhone that it says requires 15 steps. This is in comparison to the handful of taps necessary to download a game from the in-built App Store. 
</p>
<p>
First, you'll need to head to Epic Games' website (again, this is if you're on Android, or on an iOS device in the EU - apologies, UK readers) and hit the install Epic Games Store button. On iPhone, this will bring up the first of several "scare screens" - ominous-looking warnings that tell you the process requires you to go change your device settings. It's not a difficult process, but it's fair to say Apple could make it more straightforward - and the warnings seem deliberately worded to dissuade casual users from continuing. 
</p>
<p>
Epic Games' hope, it seems, is that Fortnite (and also Rocket League and Fall Guys) are big enough draws that people push through the above 15 steps to get playing the company's games again on their phones. And, once again, there's more careful choreography at play - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-and-marvel-confirm-new-crossover-season-starring-doctor-doom-as-disney-integration-deepens">today also being the big launch of Fortnite's new Marvel-infused season</a>.
</p>
<p>
"We're going to invest in getting hundreds of millions of players through the gate," Allison continued, "and we're working super hard across the board to get third-party developers to join us". 
</p>
<p>
But, on iPhone especially, Epic Games faces an uphill battle still. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-returning-to-ios-says-epic-as-apple-agrees-to-alternative-app-marketplaces-in-eu">Sweeney has previously railed against Apple's "junk fees on downloads and new Apple taxes"</a> that are currently set to penalise any developers who want to launch an app on the Epic Games Store for mobile as well as on the App Store. (Memorably, Sweeney dubbed these fees as "hot garbage".) 
</p>
<p>
"Of the top 250 developers we've been targeting to bring their apps to the Epic Game Store, everybody's excited about coming to our store on Android because there's no imposition of 'junk fees' just for the purpose of going to a competing store," Sweeney told press this week. "Zero of them have expressed a willingness to come to the Epic Game Store on iOS - it's just uneconomical. 
</p>
<p>
"Apple has set these fees in order to make it vastly more expensive, not just to do business on the Epic Game Store, but if you come to the Epic Game Store you're penalised on the iOS App Store. They make their store terms worse for the privilege of trying to compete with them. Obviously it makes no competitive sense, its anti-competitive."
</p>
<p>Exactly how much further Apple will change its policies remains to be seen, but the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eu-opens-fresh-investigation-into-apple-following-further-non-compliance-claims">EU continues to take a close interest in how the mobile maker is implementing the changes it has been required to make</a> as a result of the bloc's Digital Markets Act (DMA). Today's launch gives Epic Games a foot in the door, for now, an the company says it is hopeful of further markets opening up next year, including the UK and Japan.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_cSMjsqI.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Epic Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
In the meantime, Apple has behaved "dishonestly and maliciously", Sweeney continued. "If you give Apple the arbitary power to block competitors' access to the platform, of course they can block whoever they want. That power needs to be taken away from them."
</p>
<p>
Today also sees Fortnite, Rocket League Sideswipe and Fall Guys also become available on the first of several other, smaller third-party mobile stores (<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-is-pulling-fortnite-from-rent-collector-mobile-stores-as-it-readies-own-eu-shop">though no longer major player Samsung</a>), as Epic Games seeks to demonstrate it is fighting for wider change, rather than just its own slice of the app store market.
</p>
<p>
So, you can also now nab the above three games from indie app store Altstore, an enterprise co-founded by Riley Testut, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-game-emulator-currently-top-free-download-on-iphone-app-store">creator of the Delta emulator</a>, which Apple initially blocked. Other apps from Altstore include a mobile Torrent app.
</p>
<p>
"I've no regrets, Apple had to be challenged," Sweeney concluded, reflecting on the past four years. "Before we directly challenged Apple and pointed out to the world exactly what their practices were, a lot of people just read Apple's marketing and thought the App Store was a normal store like any other. They didn't realise that it was, in effect, banning any other competition. And because all app developers passed on their 30 percent fees to their customers, no one understood the App Store inflated prices for anything users come into contact with. 
</p>
<p>"The way we challenged Apple and Google - we introduced Epic Direct Payment and passed on 20 percent savings to all our customers - immediately turned the conversation to these 'junk fees' increasing the cost of software and the monopoly nature of its App Store. By Apple blocking Fortnite from a billion devices they proved to the world they do have a monopoly to access to software for a billion users. Similarly by Google blocking Fortnite they established they did have a monopoly. 
</p>
<p>
"When you look at everything that's happened since, you can trace a lot of it back - not only to regulators, but also consumers coming to a really clear realisation of the insidious nature of what [Apple/Google] call 'walled gardens' but we should just simply call monopolies in the fields of software distribution and payment processing, and how they've really corrupted the whole digital ecosystem compared to the days of really open platforms, such as Windows and the open web."
</p>
<p>
  Epic Games isn't the only company launching a new mobile storefront. While delayed beyond its expected launch date, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-to-open-web-based-mobile-game-store-this-summer">Microsoft is still working on its own store for smartphones</a> - and it will be interesting to see if Fortnite will end up on there. "The standard for us is - great terms for all developers," Allison said, when asked. "We don't know their terms yet."
</p>
<p>"If [the terms] are great, we'll come," concluded Sweeney. "If they're not great, we won't come."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sam and Max: the Devil’s Playhouse Remastered Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/16/sam-and-max-the-devils-playhouse-remastered-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sam-and-max-the-devil%E2%80%99s-playhouse-remastered-review.954855/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/16/sam-and-max-the-devils-playhouse-remastered-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/16/sam-and-max-the-devils-playhouse-remastered-review/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Sam and Max: the Devil’s Playhouse Remastered Review">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Nic Bunce">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2024-08-16">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2024-08-16">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>When Telltale Games collapsed in 2018, four developers stepped in to acquire the rights to Sam &amp; Max. Skunkape Games, as they are known, set about rereleasing the Sam &amp; Max series — three seasons each of which was originally released in episodic form, following the sitular dog detective and his&nbsp;lagomorph pal. Now the third and final season has been rereleased, asking once again: “if any one of us could unlock the power of the mind, would we use it to unlock the powers of the infinite… or would we use it to destroy?”</p>
<p><iframe title="Sam &amp; Max: The Devil's Playhouse Remastered! Now available!" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RzXbwm0P65E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>If you have played either of the two previous seasons —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/01/20/sam-max-save-the-world-remastered-switch-review/">Sam &amp; Max Save the World</a> or Sam &amp; Max Beyond Time and Space, you can very quickly guess which one plays out.</p>


<p>If you haven’t had the pleasure, Sam &amp; Max are freelance police. Sam is a cool, calm and collected bipedal dog in a suit. Max is the embodiment of chaos, a hyperkinetic rabbity thing, and — naturally — the President of the US. The have relatively little regard for the law, and pretty much just stroll around performing an overly elaborate and complex set of point-and-click tasks in order to achieve their goals.</p>


<p>At the beginning of Chapter 1 of The Devil’s Playhouse, The Penal Zone, Max picks up a kid’s toy that allows him to see into the future. Little did he know that the Eyes of Yog Sogoth that he just grabbed would also unlock his psychic powers. As the game progresses, he picks up playing cards that grant mindreading, a telephone that transports them to another phone and a rhinoplasty toy that lets them shapeshift — all amusing little plays on what the item does for everyone else, and an insight into the playfulness of Sam &amp; Max creator Steve Purcell’s brain.</p>
<p>The problem is that these Toys of Power are being sought by an evil and powerful space gorilla, General Skun-ka’pe. He lands on your street, tries to claim the toys and even steal Max’s brain so that he can wield the Toys of Power for himself.</p>

<p>What follows is a joyous campaign of puerile humour and anarchistic problem solving. Case in point: when Skun-ka’pe brags to his queen that after locking Sam and Max in an intergalactic prison and blowing it up with an antimatter bomb, “I took care of the&nbsp;Penal Zone in one stroke”. Max walks past and snidely comments on the unfortunate choice of words.</p>
<p>But all of this was true when the game was first released in 2010. So how does 2024’s remaster shape up?</p>
<p>The answer is incredibly well. As with the previous remasters, most of the changes are technical, bringing the graphics from 1024×768 4:3 to high-res 16:9. The lighting, lip sync and audio have all been drastically improved, with the audio in particular shining through. That said, it’s not all just higher resolutions. Character models have been tweaked, new credits and menus have been added and the whole thing feels a little more connected as a result, and closer to Steve Purcell’s original vision. We know this because Skunkape said they had Purcell’s input along the way.</p>

<p>On top of this, a ‘new’ Toy of Power that didn’t make it to the original PC version is now available in the Nutri-Specs, along with a bunch of more spoiler-y additions that we won’t go into.</p>
<p>There’s not really much to complain about here. The intros are still unskippable, and the run button feels like it’s in the wrong place – I still don’t understand why running isn’t the default. Beyond that, there’s minor gripes with trophies not popping on the PS5, but that’s not the end of the world.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		Sam and Max: The Devil’s Playhouse is exactly what you want from a remaster. It has been faithfully rebuilt, adding improvements and things that make sense, and tightening the things that were a little leaky. I loved stepping back into Sam’s (lack of) shoes and holding the world to rights as a newly psychic Max. If you don’t mind a bit of juvenile humour, this is still one of the funniest point-and-click adventures I’ve ever played, but a little prettier than I remember.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>The lighting and resolution are worlds apart from the original</li>
														
								<li><i></i>It takes an excellent game and brings it to new systems</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Improved music and audio quality</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>The intro scenes are still unskippable</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Minor issues with trophies not popping up on the PS5</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
						
		<div>

			<h3>Related stories from TSA			
			</h3>
			
				
				
		</div>

	
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill: Ascension wins major award]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-ascension-wins-major-award</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-ascension-wins-major-award.954840/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-ascension-wins-major-award<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/unnamed_xbK11pB.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Genvid / Konami</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Genvid's experimental choose-the-outcome, episodic Silent Hill series, Ascension, has won an Emmy.</p>
<p>Genvid CEO Jacob Navok marked the award with a heartfelt post on Twitter/X, stating the Creative Arts Emmy Award for Outstanding Innovation in Emerging Media Programming for Silent Hill: Ascension was a "testament to the dedication" of the team.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="SILENT HILL: Ascension | Premiere Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Iud7gr9Y-ac?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>SILENT HILL: Ascension | Premiere Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Iud7gr9Y-ac?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Iud7gr9Y-ac?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>SILENT HILL: Ascension | Premiere Trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Iud7gr9Y-ac" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"This award is a testament to the dedication of team members around the world who worked on the project for years: the more than 300 writers, artists, developers, QA testers, mocap performers, voice actors, localisation editors who made Silent Hill: Ascension's interactive series possible as it streamed 168 choices across the entire series from October 31 2023 to July 15 2024," Navok said.</p>
<p>He then thanked a range of partners - including Bad Robot and Behaviour Interactive - as well as the "hundreds of Metahumans we used in the show".</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Genvid is honored to win the 2024 Creative Arts Emmy Award for Outstanding Innovation in Emerging Media Programming for SILENT HILL: Ascension.</p><p>This award is a testament to the dedication of team members around the world who worked on the project for years: the more than 300… <a href="https://t.co/r0DVzl4n0M">pic.twitter.com/r0DVzl4n0M</a></p></div>— Jacob Navok (@JNavok) <a href="https://twitter.com/JNavok/status/1823828594508095799?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Genvid's next project, DC Heroes United, is set to debut later this year. Like Ascension, the audience will determine the show's storyline.</p>
<p>Silent Hill: The Short Message – a two-hour free-to-play first-person horror shadow-dropped by Konami earlier this year – <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-the-short-message-has-been-downloaded-3m-times">has been downloaded over three million times</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Castaway Review - A Delightful Little Adventure]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/castaway-review-delightful-little-adventure</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/castaway-review-a-delightful-little-adventure.954828/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/castaway-review-delightful-little-adventure<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Castaway </em>is a game that wears its inspirations on its sleeve and knows exactly what it wants to be. Developer <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/lunark">Canari Games</a> markets it as a short but sweet experience you can complete in a few hours, but those few hours are packed full of wonderful fun.</p>
<p>Washing up on a beach of some forlorn planet, players take control of a nameless protagonist out to rescue his dog from a group of pesky pterodactyls. That's really the gist of the story, but it's all the background info you need to enjoy this experience.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/castaway-pterodactyls.png?itok=BgsQz19E 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/png"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/castaway-pterodactyls.png?itok=vw_KTQ6Q 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/png"></picture><figcaption>Man, don't you hate it when pterodactyls kidnap your dog?</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Castaway</em>'s Island of Adventure.</h2>
<p>Developer Johan Vinet explains <em>Castaway</em> as two mini-games in one, and that's a great descriptor. <em>Castaway</em> is split into two segments, the first of which is a brief island adventure, and the second acting as a subdued roguelite dungeon crawl through a perilous 50-floor dungeon.</p>
<p>The first portion of this adventure tasks players with rescuing their kidnapped companion. The island you explore is pretty small but very dense, meaning no enemy or obstacle is there to waste your time. Over the course of an hour or so, players gather new equipment to aid in their adventure, like a pickaxe and a grappling hook device.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/castaway-hook.png?itok=pozsp_aA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/png"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/castaway-hook.png?itok=IoYj4Iba 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/png"></picture><figcaption>Hook onto that rock and a gap is no longer perilous!</figcaption></figure><p>Along with your sword, these items work exactly as you'd expect. Both the overworld and the three dungeons players explore take advantage of these tools to the fullest, often involving simple sokoban puzzles (aka moving blocks around). These are largely easy to understand and shouldn't inhibit your progress, but it's still gratifying when you solve a puzzle.</p>
<p>Venturing from the overworld into a dungeon will put your equipment to the test. Using your pickaxe can crack open rocks and the hook shot allows you to travel across gaps. Of course, <em>Castawa</em><em>y</em>'s overworld and dungeons feature a few enemy types as well, and the combat is your standard one-button sword slash a la <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/legend-of-zelda-links-awakening"><em>Link</em>'s <em>Awakening</em></a>.</p>
<p>At the end of each dungeon is a boss battle to shake things up a bit. On the base difficulty, even bosses will pose no threat to players with even a moderate amount of experience in 2D, dungeon-crawling games. Nonetheless, you can take things up a notch by increasing the difficulty to Unfair, which gives you one heart and that's it -- get hit, you're dead for good.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/castaway-dungeon-1.png?itok=yLn9GMsv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/png"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/castaway-dungeon-1.png?itok=d0sO_E0N 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/png"></picture><figcaption>One of those rocks is not like the others.</figcaption></figure><p>Conversely, you can test your skills with the Speedrun mode and, if you're finding things difficult, Invincible and Pacifist modes. The former is exactly as it sounds, making you impervious to damage, while the latter removes enemies altogether.</p>
<p>These modes are a really neat inclusion because the audience for <em>Castaway</em> is meant for all ages and by including such modes, you could hand the controller to a child and they would have a blast. It's such an endearing notion that this may be a kid's first game, and I'm sure they'd love it.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/castaway-tower.png?itok=DCC8JkJr 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/png"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/castaway-tower.png?itok=g87q02XC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/png"></picture><figcaption>The tower's rooms are small, but they can be densely packed.</figcaption></figure><h2>A Towering Challenge in <em>Castaway</em></h2>
<p>Of course, if things seem a little too easy in the island adventure, there's also a 50-floor dungeon to power through. This doesn't have a difficulty mode, so you're more likely to be challenged here than anywhere else. The goal is to get to the top and beat the final boss battle, but that's easier said than done: die and you're back to the foot of the tower.</p>
<p>You're still equipped with the usual equipment for the tower, but it does strip you of two of your four hearts, making the stakes a bit higher. Thankfully, there's a level-up system in place that allows players to improve as they climb.</p>
<p>Killing enemies on floors of the tower drops gold, and that's used to fund your new upgrades. Upgrades range from increasing your sword or pickaxe's damage to adding more health. Survivability was a priority for me, so I opted for more hearts as well as armor that would take a hit without taking actual damage -- it would remove my armor, but that'd replenish on the next floor.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/castaway-upgrades.png?itok=4mAlhLSG 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/png"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/castaway-upgrades.png?itok=qf2gfN1x 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/png"></picture><figcaption>Upgrades are simple, and they'll make your life easier.</figcaption></figure><p>The first few times you climb the tower, things can get a little tricky. Spike traps and cleverly placed enemies are in the way and you might even get overwhelmed by foes if you're not careful. I constantly weighed my options as I lost more health -- all level-ups offer the ability to heal, but the trade-off is not getting an upgrade to your equipment. Hard choices must be made!</p>
<p>This mode is purely combat-based, though, which might not be as fun for some. I would have preferred to see a few puzzles thrown into the mix since the island adventure ends so soon. Though it'll probably take two or so hours after a few attempts of climbing, it can feel a tad repetitive seeing the same floors and having it be 100 percent combat.</p>
<p>Floors are also bite-sized, though, so it's not a terrible burden at the end of the day. However, I did get soft-locked a few times by getting stuck on a tile and some enemies bugged into the wall, causing me to reset. That repetition can get frustrating, but it isn't a dealbreaker when the rest of the experience is pleasurable.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/castaway-spikes.png?itok=l6v8P3J4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/png"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/castaway-spikes.png?itok=mYmaE6FA 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/png"></picture><figcaption>Watch your step!</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Castaway </em>Review | Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><em>Castaway</em> is one of 2024's most charming games. The passion from Canari Games is quite evident in the final product, and though it's a short experience with only a few slight frustrations near the end, it's an adventure anyone can enjoy. Whether you're nostalgic for the past or want something to distract you for the weekend, <em>Castaway</em>'s got you covered.</p>
<hr><p><em><strong>Castaway </strong>was reviewed on PC with a code provided by the developer over roughly 4 hours of gameplay. All screenshots in this review were taken by the reviewer during gameplay. </em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
<div>
<h2>Review Summary</h2>

<p>
Castaway doesn't reinvent the wheel, nor does it intend to. What Canari Games set out to do is to create a rock solid, short-but-sweet experience, and this endearing adventure game achieves just that. (<a href="https://techraptor.net/review-score-policy">Review Policy</a>)
</p>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<h3>Pros</h3>
<div><ul><li>Fantastic, Nostalgic Visual Style and OST</li><li>Tight Level Design</li><li>Accessible for Everyone</li></ul></div>
</div>
<div>
<h3>Cons</h3>
<div><ul><li>Tower Can Feel a Bit Repetitive </li><li>A Few Bugs in the Tower</li></ul></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></span></p></div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Austin cut his teeth writing various&nbsp; fan-fiction stories on the RuneScape forums when he was in elementary school. Later on, he developed a deep love for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/austin-suther">More about Austin</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The next Total War: Warhammer 3 update will let your dwarves play tall by delving greedily and deep]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-next-total-war-warhammer-3-update-will-let-your-dwarves-play-tall-by-delving-greedily-and-deep</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-next-total-war-warhammer-3-update-will-let-your-dwarves-play-tall-by-delving-greedily-and-deep.954822/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-next-total-war-warhammer-3-update-will-let-your-dwarves-play-tall-by-delving-greedily-and-deep<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Any gags I could make about an update that lets <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-warhammer-iii">Total War: Warhammer </a>3’s dawi play tall are far too obvious for the discerning comedic palette that brought you such bangers as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/overkills-the-walking-dead-review">that time I just wrote “(penis)” a bunch</a> so the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/overkills-the-walking-dead">Overkill’s Walking Dead</a> page wouldn’t quote me out of context, so let’s just dive right in to the details. The strategy game’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/total-war-warhammer-3-teases-new-content-this-month-and-a-hotfix-ensures-goblins-will-now-get-dismembered-correctly">5.2 update is on the horizon</a>, and tagging along with it are the first of the “extra bits” the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/colossal-squigs-all-but-confirmed-for-next-total-war-warhammer-3-dlc-plus-big-new-toys-for-ogres-and-khorne">team teased in June</a>. I’m very excited about them. They sit somewhere between the usual patch fare of stat tweaks and errata, and the weightier faction facelifts that come alongside paid DLC. They’re also focused right where <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/total-war-warhammer-iii-immortal-empires">Immortal Empires</a> needs them the most: depth, rather than width. In the dawi’s case, quite literally.</p>

<p>You can find the full breakdown of the three headline features <a href="https://community.creative-assembly.com/total-war/total-war-warhammer/blogs/29-total-war-warhammer-iii-patch-5-2-dev-blog">here</a>. But, broadly, there are updates for both chaos and the dwarves, plus “unusual locations”  - a sort of fleshed-out set of landmarks which you’ll discover as you explore the map. One of the examples given is a Bretonnian holy site called “Grail Knight’s Grave”. Initially, owning the settlement gives a small bonus to control and corruption, as well as some holy horse-fanciers for your garrison. When control is over 75, any characters in the region have a chance to gain a tantalising <em>mystery trait. </em> The blog doesn’t reveal this trait, but I hope it’s <a href="https://youtu.be/onxTQx8aPZA">cow-buchet</a> related.</p>
<p>There are a few more teasers shown off, but I’m mainly enthusiastic about what design director Mitchell Heastie has to say here. He’s “a huge fan of worldbuilding content in games,” and says that he’s “always wanted to make the world feel a bit more alive - this is hopefully a start to doing more for both of those things.” Again, Immortal Empires is already irresponsibly massive and stuffed with more units than any reasonable person can keep track of. It’s these fertile embellishments that elevate it from a map to a world.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Total War: WARHAMMER III - Immortal Empires teaser trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0HkK1ldsuVU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Total War: WARHAMMER III - Immortal Empires teaser trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0HkK1ldsuVU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0HkK1ldsuVU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0HkK1ldsuVU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Next up is a rework to chaos cults, long maligned for feeling far too flat and lifeless to represent the hives of corrupted activity they’re intended to be. “Ultimately the fantasy is that Cults create the corruption, not the other way around,” says Heastie. They’ll no longer spring up in corrupted areas - it’ll now be the task of cultists belonging to all four monogods to set them up, which was previously just a Slaanesh thing. The cult magus is a new campaign-only character that specialises in setting up unique cults that offer more options. You’ll get access to the magus through upgrading standard chaos cults.</p>
<p>I’m not initially sold on the idea of stripping away an entire method of spreading cults, but Slaanesh’s exponential cult play is really engaging, so I can see this working well. The cults themselves look much more interactive and varied, too. They’ll now be a version of the skaven undercity archetype, with various resource-sapping buildings and a few devastating rituals. Khorne’s leader teleportation is now available to each of the four gods, for example.</p>
<p>And finally, there’s a new Dwarf feature named ‘the deeps’, for dawi fans that want to play tall. After shelling out a pile of cash, you’ll be able to expand your settlements into the earth, giving you unique buildings and more slots to play with. There’s some lovely flavour you’ll discover as you dig(gy diggy hole), too, like blocked tunnels and “some stranger things you can discover in the Deeps.” Here’s a nifty one from the new ‘guild foundries’ building: “+5% settlement income per turn count”. I’ve not seen that one before across the whole game. So that’s 500% income on turn 50, presumably? Say short again. Go on.</p>
<p>The blog also mentions an update to Cathay’s ivory road, although doesn’t go into detail just yet. I’m really into the deeps specifically, but the real prize here is knowing the team have reached a place where they’re ready to start experimenting with these smaller, flavourful additions between paid expansions. Heastie described this as “pushing our own expectations for what new content for the game could be, to always be on the lookout for what special idea we could do next.” There’s obviously an incentive with these things to sound passionate, but this feels genuine to me.  If so, I’m chuffed that the team feel they’re in a good spot. Fair warning, though, the dawi are going to be unbearably smug fuckers about all this.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mellow mountain biker Lonely Mountains: Downhill is getting a wintry sequel about skiing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mellow-mountain-biker-lonely-mountains-downhill-is-getting-a-wintry-sequel-about-skiing</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mellow-mountain-biker-lonely-mountains-downhill-is-getting-a-wintry-sequel-about-skiing.954819/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mellow-mountain-biker-lonely-mountains-downhill-is-getting-a-wintry-sequel-about-skiing<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Lonely Mountains Downchill</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/lonely-mountain-snow-riders-announced-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Megagon Industries</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>The mountain biking of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/lonely-mountains-downhill">Lonely Mountains: Downhill</a> was sometimes a relaxing ride down gentle slopes, and at other times a hairy hurtle down declivitous cliffs. Alongside the likes of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/descenders">Descenders</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/riders-republic">Riders Republic</a>, it offered a more laid-back game, open to furious time trialling but always remembering to let you stop and appreciate the view. Both the stakes and the poly count were low. Happy news then, that it is getting a snowy sequel. In <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/lonely-mountains-snow-riders">Lonely Mountains: Snow Riders</a> you'll be swapping your bike for a pair of skis, and you'll be able to barrel down the mountainside with friends in co-op.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Lonely Mountains: Snow Riders - Announcement Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nPV7r1RY5bY?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Lonely Mountains: Snow Riders - Announcement Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nPV7r1RY5bY?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nPV7r1RY5bY?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nPV7r1RY5bY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>That looks just right. I seem to remember the camera in the first game always following the action from the front, but it looks like this time the view will sometimes let you look ahead. Probably for the best. I've broken enough bones in life already, thank you. </p>
<p>"Lonely Mountains: Snow Riders is a game about skiing down gorgeous mountain vistas. Slice through deep snow, skitter over ice lakes, and leap into the air in spectacular jumps," say developers Megagon Industries on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2545360/Lonely_Mountains_Snow_Riders/">the Steam page</a>. The other big change is that the game will allow for up to 8 players to race one another online, or tackle a mountain together in a chill-sounding co-op mode, "adding save points as you go". </p>
<p>That latter feature sounds quite tranquil. At least one screenshot shows eight players sitting together on the snowy banks of a cold lake, which suggests the hidden "resting places" of the original game are returning. As much as I enjoy a good <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-racing-games">racing game</a>, it'd be sweet to stop and enjoy these vistas with pals. It may also make Alice O happy - she thought these resting spots were pretty darn pleasant.</p>
<p>"Yet the greatest reward of exploration isn't speed, it's outright stopping," she said as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/lonely-mountains-downhill-goes-murderously-fast-but-appreciates-a-beautiful-view">part of her tour of cycling games</a>. "At hidden 'resting places', you can press Y to have your character dismount for a nice sit-down. They pick somewhere scenic to stretch their legs, shake out their arms, and take in the view. It is wonderful."</p>
<p>An exact release date hasn't been shared yet, but Lonely Mountains: Snow Riders is due out sometime in 2024, we're told.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Delta Force Pay-to-Win Elements Will ‘Absolutely Not’ Be a Thing]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/delta-force-pay-to-win-elements-no/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/delta-force-pay-to-win-elements-will-%E2%80%98absolutely-not%E2%80%99-be-a-thing.954816/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/delta-force-pay-to-win-elements-no/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a recent AMA on Reddit, Delta Force: Hawk Ops’ development team answered some key and pressing questions about the future of the free-to-play shooter. It recently launched into an alpha phase and, by all accounts, has been turning heads simply because it plays so nicely. </p>



<p>It might look like a Battlefield rip-off on the surface, but it has plenty of weapons, well-designed maps, and a solid gameplay loop that keeps you engaged for a good while. One of the things that prospective fans were eager to know about was the future of microtransactions in Delta Force, which the developer was quick to address.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-a-clear-standard">A Clear Standard</h2>



<p>In the recent AMA, which was dug up <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/delta-force-hawk-ops-will-absolutely-not-have-pay-to-win-elements-new-season-incoming-every-2-3-months-name-change-considered" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">by MP1st</a>, Team Jade’s ‘ShadowGuo’ spoke decisively about ‘pay-to-win’ mechanics in Delta Force: Hawk Ops. When asked if users will be able to exchange real-world money for in-game components that are considered pay-to-win, the developer said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>I can promise that this will&nbsp;<strong>absolutely not happen</strong>&nbsp;– this is a clear standard that we wanted to set for our game. The primary content we offer for our players to purchase includes weapon skins, character cosmetics, and battle passes. Our large-scale Havoc Warfare mode has no pay-to-win elements. We also promise that Tekniq Alloy and equipment in Hazard Ops will never be sold – they must be earned through gameplay, participating in events, or trading with other platers in the auction house.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The team also stressed that ‘all multiplayer content’ will be free to experience, with nothing being locked behind a paywall.</p>



<p>That could be a slight dig at Battlestate Games, which recently released the ‘PvE mode’ in Escape from Tarkov and proceeded to lock it behind a purchase requirement. It’s also a shot at MoreFun Studios, which just pushed Arena Breakout: Infinite into early access. It was quickly discovered by users that many elements of ABI are considered pay-to-win.</p>



<p>In <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/pcgaming/comments/1er6s48/delta_force_hawk_ops_dev_here_ask_me_anything/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the AMA on Reddit</a>, the team touched on plenty of topics. It was mentioned that the game’s name might change based on community feedback, audio elements are being worked on as the alpha unravels, and in-game ‘seasons’ should be delivered every two to three months.</p>



<p>Have you played the Delta Force alpha yet?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/blacknut-cloud-gaming-ubisoft-deal/">Blacknut has partnered with Ubisoft</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon launches adorable Japan plane safety video]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-launches-adorable-japan-plane-safety-video</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-launches-adorable-japan-plane-safety-video.954807/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/pokemon-launches-adorable-japan-plane-safety-video<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ANA-Safety-Video-featuring-Pok%C3%A9mon-2-2-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>ANA / The Pokémon Company</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Japanese airline ANA has revealed a new plane safety video starring a variety of Pokémon.
</p>
<p>
The Pokémon brand has a long-standing relationship with ANA, and has adorned several of its jets with Pokémon characters over the past few decades. But this safety video is the first of its kind - and it's worth a watch to see numerous Pokémon getting to grips with good airline etiquette.
</p>
<p>
While Pikachu and Pichu are the stars, of course, you'll also see a mildly disturbing Jigglypuff scold a man for vaping, Mr Mime appear to mime safety instructions, and Floatzle turn up to demonstrate its own in-built life vest. 
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="ANA Safety Video featuring Pokémon" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SAolvci7SeA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>ANA Safety Video featuring Pokémon</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SAolvci7SeA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/SAolvci7SeA?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>ANA Safety Video featuring Pokémon.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SAolvci7SeA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Meanwhile, Machoke not fastening his seatbelt over his 'pants' is likely going to open up the debate about whether he's wearing clothes or not again...
</p>
<p>
You'll only see the video if you're travelling on ANA's specially-decorated Pikachu and Eevee jets, which fly from Tokyo's Narita and Haneda airports to a range of around two dozen destinations, mainly in Australia, North America and Asia. There's just one European route - to and from London's Heathrow. Or you can watch via YouTube above.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blacknut Partners With Ubisoft in Cloud Gaming Deal]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/blacknut-cloud-gaming-ubisoft-deal/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blacknut-partners-with-ubisoft-in-cloud-gaming-deal.954798/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/blacknut-cloud-gaming-ubisoft-deal/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It has just been announced that Blacknut Cloud Gaming has partnered with Ubisoft in a fresh distribution-focused agreement. This means that some of Ubisoft’s games will wind up on the Blacknut platform, which at present offers subscribers more than 500 games to stream at will.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-in-the-clouds">In The Clouds</h2>



<p>Cloud gaming has been coming up in recent years, and many providers and operators have made their way into the concept of streaming games online. </p>



<p>Most recently, it seemed as though Xbox was making a push into ‘not needing’ a home console to play the best games by leaning on the streaming platform provided as part of Game Pass.</p>



<p>PlayStation has a cloud-based service, as does Nvidia and Amazon, and there’s even Antstream, a retro-focused streaming service.</p>



<p>Blacknut Cloud Gaming has been in the market for a while and has been working on expanding the library available to subscribers. This latest move will see Ubisoft’s games crop up on the platform. In a statement, Ubisoft’s Chris Early spoke on the deal:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Blacknut’s premium cloud infrastructure, broad reach, and device compatibility have made them a force in the cloud gaming market and will help bring Ubisoft’s many gaming universes to more players. This is just the beginning of our partnership, and we look forward to sharing more soon.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It has been confirmed that the likes of Assassin’s Creed and Far Cry will appear on Blacknut’s cloud streaming platform soon. In a statement celebrating the partnership, Blacknut’s CEO, Olivier Avaro, said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Bringing Ubisoft games to our platform represents a significant milestone in our growth strategy. We’re excited to offer our users an unparalleled gaming experience with one of the industry’s most iconic publishers, and some of the world’s most emblematic franchises. This endeavour significantly enhances our current offerings and we are excited to continue scaling our partnership with Ubisoft, both as a B2C distributor and for our global partnerships in the months to come.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Have you invested in a cloud gaming platform yet, or are you not interested?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exoborne-gameplay-trailer-released/">the Exoborne trailer is turning heads</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Flight Simulator Might Be The Next Xbox Game Coming to PS5]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-might-be-the-next-xbox-game-coming-to-ps5/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-flight-simulator-might-be-the-next-xbox-game-coming-to-ps5.954789/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-might-be-the-next-xbox-game-coming-to-ps5/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Once again, rumors have begun swirling about the next Xbox first-party game to be ported to PlayStation 5, and it might be one of the most iconic (albeit niche): Microsoft Flight Simulator.</p>
<p>Yesterday, leaker extas1s <a href="https://wccftech.com/forza-horizon-5-starfield-playstation-5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">suggested</a> it would be Forza Horizon 5. However, an earlier <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1etc9z9/the_next_xbox_port_will_be_flight_sim_according/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">leak</a> from January had mentioned Microsoft Flight Simulator, and it was right about everything it shared at the time.</p>
<p><em>Xbox will probably announce its multiplatform plans late next month or right before the fiscal year ends. ID Software's next game is no longer an Xbox exclusive and will be multiplatform. Bethesda's next few games that were exclusive have also been pushed to be multiplatform instead.</em></p>
<p><em>Microsoft Flight Simulator will be multiplatform, and a few other older 1st party games are also going to be multiplatform. Indiana Jones is a little weird cause he's modeled after Harrison Ford to the full extent but being voiced by Troy Baker. Most of the game is also 1st person, including whip combat.</em> <em>And Hideo Kojima is finally making a movie.</em></p>
<p>DOOM: The Dark Ages turned out to be multiplatform, and Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is a first-person game (except for rare instances during environmental interaction) with Harrison Ford's likeness and Troy Baker's voiceover. A few days after the leak, PlayStation also announced a partnership with Hideo Kojima on a new stealth IP called <a href="https://wccftech.com/physint-kojima-new-stealth-ip-playstation-transcend-film-video-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Physint</a>, which will include the production of a game and a movie.</p>
<p>If the leaker is right about Microsoft Flight Simulator, too, the question then becomes whether the 'old' 2020 game would be ported or the <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-flight-simulator-2024-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new</a> installment that is slated to launch on November 19. This new entry features several new mission types, new aircraft types, more environmental features (snow and tornadoes), a full-fledged season system, improved physics, better performance with multithreading, and even the ability to step out of the plane and walk around the environments, as <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/sim/flight-simulator-2024s-huge-ambition-means-you-can-now-exit-the-plane-walk-around-you-can-land-on-every-ship-and-it-looks-like-a-first-person-shooter-environment/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">confirmed</a> recently to PC Gamer.</p>
<p>Whether Microsoft Flight Simulator or Forza Horizon 5 gets to PlayStation 5 first, Xbox's multiplatform policy suggests both will eventually make it and if Sea of Thieves' success is anything to go by, they might thrive, too.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exoborne Gameplay Trailer Reveals An Intense, Energetic Extraction Experience]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/exoborne-gameplay-trailer-released/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exoborne-gameplay-trailer-reveals-an-intense-energetic-extraction-experience.954786/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/exoborne-gameplay-trailer-released/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Exoborne’s gameplay trailer is finally here, and it showcases a perfectly intense and high-octane extraction shooter experience that’s bursting at the seams with action-oriented sequences and futuristic combat elements. </p>



<p>In the short but punchy trailer, we get a glimpse at the upcoming first- and third-person shooter that fuses unpredictable weather patterns with high-tech exoskeletons to present an extraction shooter experience like no other.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-master-the-apocalypse">Master The Apocalypse</h2>



<p>Exoborne is a promising, post-apocalyptic extraction shooter set in a world torn apart. Players enter a series of environments armed to the teeth with technology, weapons, and abilities, seeking high-value rewards and loot, which they’ll then try to extract before the world around them becomes too much to bear.</p>



<p>It’s a PvPvE shooter, so it operates similarly to Escape from Tarkov and other extraction shooters, but it’s so much more intense and action-oriented.</p>



<p>Here’s the Exoborne gameplay trailer:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Exoborne - Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ehaixwsBHVg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>Players will be invited to explore expansive environments, making use of their traversal abilities to cut across the territory as efficiently as possible. They’ll be able to lean on vehicles, high-powered weapons, and a string of abilities including boost packs, grapple hooks, and deployable shields to ensure their survival.</p>



<p>Presently, the extraction shooter genre tends to lean towards slower-paced, realistic, and more ‘simulation-like’ elements than it does balls-to-the-wall action mechanics. Exoborne could be the disruptive title that shakes up the genre with reckless abandon.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/san-andreas-vr-project-on-hold/">San Andreas VR has been put on hold</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Epic Games Store Officially Launches on Mobile Devices]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/epic-games-store-mobile-version-fortnite-return-to-ios-android-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-epic-games-store-officially-launches-on-mobile-devices.954783/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/epic-games-store-mobile-version-fortnite-return-to-ios-android-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Worldwide launch on Android, while only EU iPhone users can access it.</h2></div><section><p>We already knew Epic Games plans to <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-will-return-to-ios-but-only-in-europe">release its digital storefront on mobile devices</a> via the iOS App Store and Android's Google Play later this year. Months after the initial announcement, the prolific game and technology company announced today that the Epic Games Store is now available for iOS and Android devices. </p><p>In a press release, Epic confirmed that the Epic Games Store is available to download on Android devices worldwide, in addition to iPhones, but only for Apple smartphone owners based in the EU. Epic also provided steps to install the Epic Game Store on mobile devices, citing that the process is long "due to Apple and Google introducing intentionally poor-quality install experiences" plagued with complex settings, lengthy steps, and "scare screens." </p><p>As Epic previously confirmed during the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/everything-announced-at-state-of-unreal-2024-amy-hennig-reveals-marvel-1943-rise-of-hydra-new-tools-coming-to-uefn-and-more">State of Unreal earlier this year</a>, the mobile version of the Epic Games Store (EGS), the digital storefront, is poised to become the "first-ever game-focused, multi-platform store," expanding its reach onto Android and iOS, alongside its already available apps on macOS and PC. Like the computer app and desktop version, mobile developers benefit "from the same fair terms," with an 88/12 split revenue share, among other incentives.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/15/en-esrb-egs-key-art-1723748107777.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>A render of the Epic Games Store running on mobile devices. | Image Credit: Epic Games</figcaption></figure></output><h2><strong>Fortnite is back on mobile devices</strong></h2><p>Beyond the release of the mobile version of the Epic Games Store, the company also revealed today that Fortnite is officially <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-will-return-to-ios-but-only-in-europe">back on mobile devices</a> through the company's digital storefront. In addition to launching on the Epic Games Store mobile version, EU Android and iOS owners can access Fortnite through the AltStore, a third-party digital storefront available thanks to the DMA. </p><p>This marks the first time Fortnite has been available natively on mobile devices after Apple and Google <a href="https://www.ign.com/videos/apple-removes-fortnite-from-ios-app-store">pulled the free-to-play battle royale app</a> from the App Store and Google Play in 2020. Previously, if you wanted to play Fortnite on mobile devices after its removal, you could only play it via two cloud gaming services: <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-cloud-gaming-fortnite-free-ios-pc">Xbox Cloud Gaming</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fortnite-ios-apple-mobile-devices-app-geforce-now-nvidia">Nvidia GeForce Now</a>. </p><p>Alongside Fortnite, Epic confirmed that <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fall-guys-ultimate-knockout-review">Fall Guys</a> and Rocket League Sideswipe are also available to download on Android devices worldwide and EU iPhones via the mobile version of EGS and the EU's AltStore. This is the first time Fall Guys has been made available on mobile devices, following its <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fall-guys-release-date-ps4-pc-august-4">initial release in 2020</a> for PS4 and Windows and subsequent <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fall-guys-free-to-play-xbox-switch-release">ports for PS5, Switch, and Xbox in 2022</a>.</p><p>"The tide is turning, and the mobile ecosystem is finally opening up to competition. We are grateful to the European Commission for making it possible to launch the Epic Games Store and offer our games to iOS users in the European Union," Epic Games Founder and CEO Tim Sweeney wrote in a press release. "Now, European iOS users and all Android users can access our store and games, as they've always been able to do on open platforms like PC and Mac. The fight is far from over, but this is tangible progress for developers and consumers who can begin to benefit from competition and choice."</p><p><em>Taylor is a Reporter at IGN. You can follow her on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/TayNixster" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@TayNixster.</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[San Andreas VR Project Put On Indefinite Hold By Meta]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/san-andreas-vr-project-on-hold/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/san-andreas-vr-project-put-on-indefinite-hold-by-meta.954771/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/san-andreas-vr-project-on-hold/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-53163">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Meta has finally confirmed that it’s shelving the GTA San Andreas VR project. After months of speculation that have unravelled more than three years after the team announced a VR remake of San Andreas, it has been put on indefinite hold as the company pivots to focus on other projects.</p>



<p>Despite the game having been in development for several years, it has been brought to a sudden and decisive stop by Meta, marking a disappointing confirmation for VR fans everywhere.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-grove-street-home">‘Grove Street… Home’</h2>



<p>I don’t like VR games at the best of times, but I would have played the heck out of GTA San Andreas VR. Imagine it – hopping on a BMX and cycling down into Grove Street, walking around the Johnson house, and performing brutal drive-bys against the opps. It would have been a fantastic way to experience <strong>again </strong>one of the best games ever made.</p>



<p>In a statement posted to YouTube, the Meta Quest team confirmed:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>GTA: San Andreas is on hold indefinitely while we both focus on other projects. We look forward to working with our friends at Rockstar in the future.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>That’s it – it’s the end of the era. It was back in 2021 that the Meta Quest team announced it was working on San Andreas VR, but by today, no solid gameplay or even screenshots of the game have surfaced, suggesting they didn’t get too far with the project.</p>



<p>Would you have played a GTA San Andreas VR remake if it had surfaced?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/india-gaming-prime-minister/">India’s Prime Minister wants the country to make waves in the gaming industry</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/india-gaming-prime-minister/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/india-gaming-prime-minister/">India’s Prime Minister Wants The Country To ‘Lead The World of Gaming’</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>India’s Prime Minister has spoken about gaming during an Independence Day celebration, urging his citizens to advance the industry.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-shuts-down-call-of-duty-modern-warfare-remastered-mod-aday-before-release/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-shuts-down-call-of-duty-modern-warfare-remastered-mod-aday-before-release/">Activision Shuts Down Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered Mod A Day Before Release</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A fan-made mod that would’ve added Modern Warfare 2 content to Modern Warfare Remastered on PC has been killed thanks to Activision. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-separating-warzone-from-call-of-duty-releases/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-separating-warzone-from-call-of-duty-releases/">Activision Separating Warzone From Call of Duty Releases</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Activision has announced that it’s going to separate Warzone from annual Call of Duty releases moving forward for players.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-snoop-dogg-this-november-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-is-collaborating-with-snoop-dogg-this-november-its-claimed/">Fortnite is Collaborating with Snoop Dogg this November, It’s Claimed</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>According to a credible Fortnite leaker, there will be a collaboration with popular hip-hop artist Snoop Dogg released this November.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slitterhead Horror Game Gets New Story Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/slitterhead-horror-game-gets-new-story-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/slitterhead-horror-game-gets-new-story-trailer.954765/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/slitterhead-horror-game-gets-new-story-trailer/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The horror game Slitterhead just received a new story trailer. Developed by Bokeh Game Studio (founded by former Silent Hill co-creator Keiichiro Toyama), Slitterhead is <a href="https://wccftech.com/slitterhead-gets-gameplay-trailer-pc-specs-and-november-8-launch-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">slated</a> to launch on November 8 for PC, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, and Xbox Series S|X.</p>
<p><iframe title="Slitterhead - Story Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4EENlMq23sE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Here's a detailed overview provided by Bokeh Game Studio, which is self-publishing Slitterhead:</p>
<p><em>Set in the cluttered streets of Kowlong, a city filled with darkness and chaos, this combat action-adventure game casts the player as "Hyoki," a being without memory or physical form. His sole motive is to eradicate the monstrous creatures known as "Slitterheads" that crawl through the city disguised as humans.</em></p>
<p><em>As players roam the vibrant, neon-lit cityscape, they must find allies among the humans known as "Rarities," infiltrate and track down dangerous organizations, and engage in battles harnessing the power of blood. As the suspenseful drama unfolds, delve into the mystery behind Hyoki's existence and the appearance of the Slitterheads.</em></p>
<p><em>The entity known as "Hyoki" finds himself wandering amidst the chaos of Kowlong, plagued by the enigmatic monsters known as "Slitterheads" that mimic humans. Though robbed of all memories, he has a single-minded purpose: to exterminate every last Slitterhead. Infiltrating the city, he embarks on a mission to hunt down those who have been hiding in human society.</em></p>
<p><em>Without a physical form, Hyoki's ability allows him to possess and control human bodies at will, turning those who wander the city into his pawns. With this power, he can pass through barriers, assume the identity of specific individuals, and infiltrate dangerous areas and organizations. He can also move through the city at high speed by quickly changing hosts.</em></p>
<p><em>While human bodies are fragile, Hyoki can burn their life force and turn blood into weapons to fight the ferocious Slitterheads. Even when critically wounded, he can continue to fight by efficiently switching hosts. By possessing "Rarities," special humans who share a high synchronization with Hyoki, he can unleash even more powerful attacks and activate various abilities. The cooperative relationship with these "Rarities" is the key to uncovering the deepest secrets in Kowlong.</em></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Activision are finally cutting down Call Of Duty's horrendous install sizes for Black Ops 6's release]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-are-finally-cutting-down-call-of-dutys-horrendous-install-sizes-for-black-ops-6s-release</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/activision-are-finally-cutting-down-call-of-dutys-horrendous-install-sizes-for-black-ops-6s-release.954762/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-are-finally-cutting-down-call-of-dutys-horrendous-install-sizes-for-black-ops-6s-release<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>They'll be "smaller and more customized" in future</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_VVEVdoV.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Microsoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>For years, our PC storage has wobbled and buckled beneath the tyranny of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activision-defend-modern-warfare-3s-larger-install-size-promising-to-shrink-it-before-launch">gigantic Call Of Duty installs</a>. Like 13th century peasants straining to convey huge, teetering loads of freshly quarried LMGs, our SSDs cry out for justice. Perhaps scenting imminent rebellion and a mass audience desertion to low-poly shooters with more civilised file sizes, Activision have relented. Future installations of the much-padded <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">FPS</a> will be "smaller and more customised", though in a last cruel stroke of villainy, they want you to download a large update to prepare the ground.</p><!--more-->
<p>Step one for Activision is "decoupling" the free-to-play live service battle royale Call Of Duty: Warzone from other aspects of the Call Of Duty experience. Makes sense - the Venn diagram of audiences for COD campaigns and Warzone isn't a perfectly circular aiming reticule. "When you purchase an annual title, you will only download the files for that game by default," explains <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/08/call-of-duty-optimizing-experience-roadmap">an Activision blog</a>. "On the free-to-play side, players can 'opt-in' to get Call of Duty: Warzone when they're downloading a new annual title or simply download it separately at any point in time."</p>
<p>Step two is "expanding our usage of texture streaming". This will allow the developers to "cycle content that is less frequently used by players to a streaming cache, avoiding the need to download it directly to your device's storage". The trade-off is that "you may see older content that briefly appears at a lower quality until the streaming cache has fully loaded", but you can always pick the new "Optimised" high fidelity graphics quality setting to spruce up the textures faster. There will also be a "Minimal" graphics quality for people who don't have internet bandwidth to spare.</p>
<p>To "pave the way" for all this, Activision want you to download a Call Of Duty update right now, a couple of weeks before <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-multiplayer-early-access-and-open-beta-dates-revealed">the Black Ops 6 beta</a> and a few months ahead of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-sets-a-release-date-for-the-end-of-october-open-beta-on-the-way">Black Ops 6 release date</a>. This will "[reorganise] game files and [add] new tech to prep the way for the full player interface arriving in October". It's a big file, but the developers promise that "this initial download will not permanently add the stated file size to the storage space that Call of Duty takes up on your device". Once you've installed it, you can expect Call Of Duty to take up less space over time.</p>
<p>I've fallen away from Call Of Duty for many reasons, but having to shovel hundreds of gigabytes into my PC each time is definitely a prominent one. On the other hand, I'm not confident my internet connection could handle the increased streaming load. What's your mileage?</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[India’s Prime Minister Wants The Country To ‘Lead The World of Gaming’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/india-gaming-prime-minister/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/india%E2%80%99s-prime-minister-wants-the-country-to-%E2%80%98lead-the-world-of-gaming%E2%80%99.954759/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/india-gaming-prime-minister/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>India isn’t the most wide-open region when it comes to video games. Historically, the nation’s government has banned plenty of games, including the likes of Fallout 3, PUBG Mobile, and Free Fire. It maintains an iron-fisted grip on the functionality of certain apps in the country, but all that hasn’t stopped the Prime Minister, Narendra Modi, from taking a positive stance on gaming in general.</p>



<p>Speaking recently during the nation’s 78th Independence Day celebrations, the Prime Minister of India made a bold pledge about the future of gaming across the country.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-to-the-entire-world">‘To The Entire World’</h2>



<p>Narendra Modi hasn’t ever been the biggest advocate for the gaming industry, but in recent years, he’s drifted a little closer to the concept of it all. </p>



<p>In April, he was snapped playing video games and interacting with some of the biggest influencers and competitive gamers in India, and now, he has made ambitious statements about the future of gaming in the country:</p>



<blockquote>
<p><strong>India has a very rich heritage. We can bring new talent to the world of gaming. I want every Indian child, youth, IT professionals, and AI professionals of India to lead the world of gaming — not just in playing, but also in taking our gaming products to the entire world. We can establish our dominance in the world of animation.</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<p>During his recent sit-down with influencers, Mr. Modi played Stumble Guys on mobile and Beat Saber through a VR headset. He also enjoyed Raji, an adventure game built in and propagated throughout India.</p>



<p>Many governments around the world are actively supporting the growth of gaming and esports, welcoming the revenue that this rapidly expanding industry brings. India could be the next power player looking to make an impact on the landscape.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/activision-shuts-down-call-of-duty-modern-warfare-remastered-mod-aday-before-release/">Activision has shut down the H2M Mod</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact version 5.0 update ‘Flowers Resplendent on the Sun-Scorched Sojourn’ launches August 28]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/genshin-impact-version-5-0-update-flowers-resplendent-on-the-sun-scorched-sojourn-launches-august-28</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-version-5-0-update-%E2%80%98flowers-resplendent-on-the-sun-scorched-sojourn%E2%80%99-launches-august-28.954738/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/genshin-impact-version-5-0-update-flowers-resplendent-on-the-sun-scorched-sojourn-launches-august-28<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Welcome to Natlan, the sixth major nation of Teyvat.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The version 5.0 update for <em><a title="Games > Genshin Impact [116 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/genshin-impact">Genshin Impact</a></em>, dubbed “Flowers Resplendent on the Sun-Scorched Sojourn,” will launch on August 28, developer <a title="Companies > miHoYo [169 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mihoyo">miHoYo</a> announced. The update will add Natlan, the game’s sixth major nation. <span id="more-906322"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the update, via miHoYo:</p><blockquote><p>Players will be able to reach the sixth major nation of Teyvat and ally with the warriors of the region, including Kachina, Kinich, and Mualani, as well as the Saurians of Natlan. Set off to discover diverse tribes, landscapes, mysteries, and legends.</p><p>The road to Natlan will open with an unlocked Teleport Waypoint that is accessible to players, even beginners and intermediates, who have completed the Prologue of the Archon Quest in Mondstadt. Known as the Nation of Pyro, Natlan is located west of the Sumeru desert. The people of this nation are divided into six main tribes. The dragons of Natlan, more commonly called Saurians, are the result of a long evolution and have evolved to coexist with humans, and they have even become their faithful companions. With Version 5.0, players will be able to explore three of the six tribes, as well as encounter three types of Saurians who live together with the locals.</p><p>Mastering the abilities of the different Saurians can prove decisive in exploring the towering cliffs and flowing springs, and players can transform into a Saurian by indwelling them. The Tepetlisaurus are Saurians good at tunneling undergrounds and climbing cliffs, and they are the companions of choice for the Children of Echoes who call the canyons their home. The Yumkasaurus can pull themselves in the chosen direction and reach great heights with ease. They have taken up residence among the Scions of the Canopy, a tribe living suspended from the walls of steep cliffs. As for the Koholasaurus, they can move quickly on water and liquid Phlogiston, which explains why they are commonly seen with the People of the Springs near the sea.</p><p>Natlan, also known as the Nation of War, honors her warriors at the Stadium of the Sacred Flame, where the Champion of each tribe is chosen through a tournament. This is where the main story unfolds, as the player, accompanied by local warriors Kachina, Kinich, and Mualani, travel to the Stadium. To begin Natlan’s Archon Quest, players need to reach Adventure Rank 28 and above, and have completed all of Liyue’s Archon Quests.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Natlan warriors are masters of skills and agility that reflect the lifestyle and traditions of their own tribe. Kachina, the four-star Geo polearm wielder from the Children of Echoes, is able to summon Turbo Twirly and ride on it to scale walls and cliffs, and also pound the ground to deal AOE DMG. She can be recruited for free by completing Act I of Natlan’s Archon Quest. Kinich, renowned for his hunting skills in the Scions of the Canopy, is a five-star Dendro warrior equipped with a claymore who wields the grappling hook to perfection, so as to swing and easily reach heights, or to link to enemies and perform powerful Loop Shots. His special companion, Ajaw, can also join the fray, unleashing his dragon breath against foes. Mualani, the watersports shop owner from People of the Springs, is a Hydro five-star catalyst wielder who can mount her reliable Sharky Surfboard and move at full speed on the water surface, liquid Phlogiston, and even on dry land. In combat, when Mualani is moving on her Sharky Surfboard and hits an enemy, she applies a mark and administers Sharky’s Bite, which inflicts more damage after several hits.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_906333"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p>Although Kachina, Mualani, and Kinich are all capable of locating regional specialties, they have different talents of restoring Stamina, accumulating Phlogiston, or increasing movement speed respectively, which can benefit all party members by interacting with certain harvestable items. However, to take full advantage of the powers and abilities of warriors and Saurians living in the Nation of Pyro, players will need to consume or utilize Phlogiston in different forms wisely. Through a mysterious ritual known as Phlogiston Engravings, the warriors of Natlan can further distinguish themselves in battle thanks to the Nightsoul’s Blessing.</p><p>In Version 5.0’s Event Wishes, Mualani and Kachina will debut in the first phase along with Kaedehara Kazuha’s rerun, and Kinich’s debut will come with the Raiden Shogun in the second half. In the meantime, the stories of Natlan’s three new characters will be available through the Tribal Chronicles, a new three-act quest for each tribe that replace the previous Story <a title="Platforms > Quest [113 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta/quest">Quest</a>s, to provide a comprehensive experience for players to gain a deeper understanding of the stories, people, and traditions. Players can visit each tribe’s “Obsidian Totem Pole” to start the Tribal Chronicles, as well as their Bounties and Supply Notices to earn Reputation EXP and valuable rewards.</p><p>As the fourth anniversary of <em>Genshin Impact</em> approaches, rewards, and bonuses will be offered to celebrate this event with fans and players during Version 5.0. The special daily login event returns with up to Intertwined Fate ×10 for players to claim, and players can check their in-game mail to receive Primogems ×1,600, two exclusive gadgets “Firstborn Firesprite” and “Kaboom Box,” as well as more bonuses. Furthermore, players can also invite a 5-star character from the Standard Wish lineup to their team for free. More updates on the Character Event Wish, Weapon Event Wish, and a new tool to redeem Artifacts with designated affixes will also arrive in the latest version.</p></blockquote><p>And here is a detailed explanation of Natlan:</p><blockquote><p><strong>■ 1. Three Characters in Natlan</strong></p><p><strong>1.1 Mualani</strong></p><p>Mualani is a five-star Hydro catalyst wielder from People of the Springs. This shiny and hot-hearted girl is a watersports store owner and a fan of multiple water sports, such as swimming, surfing, and beach volleyball. Mualani primarily deals Hydro damage with on-field movement to stack layers.</p><ul><li><strong>Surf to Explore</strong> – Her Elemental Skill makes her mount on her Sharky Surfboard to move on land, water and liquid Phlogiston with a greater speed. In addition, Mualani can surf onto the Spiritways, a flowing Phlogiston track that she can take for a fast trip.</li><li><strong>Surf, Mark, and Bite</strong> – Her Elemental Skill also converts her Normal Attacks into Sharky’s Bite of powerful Hydro damage. By making contact with enemies, Mualani can mark her enemies and gain stacks. Max 3 stacks, Mualani can unleash a reinforced bite with significant damage.</li></ul><p><iframe title="Genshin Impact - Version 5.0: Mualani" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Btbl2DlhGXI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>1.2 Kinich</strong></p><p>Kinich is a five-star Dendro claymore wielder from Scions of the Canopy. He is a well-known hunter with a special Saurian company, Ajaw.</p><ul><li><strong>Grappling Hook</strong> – With his Elemental Skill, Kinich can use a grappling hook to reach higher places and swing foward consecutively by latching onto Coilgrass Sigils during exploration.</li><li><strong>Loop Shoot</strong> – When using his Elemental Skill in the presence of nearby enemies, Kinich links to the target and initiates loop shots. In this state, he gradually accumulates Nightsoul Points, which, upon reaching their maximum, allow him to unleash a powerful shot, dealing significant Dendro DMG.</li><li><strong>Stand with Dragonlord</strong> – Upon his Elemental Burst, the Saurian buddy of Kinich, Ajaw, will unleash dragonbreaths to deal AoE Dendro DMG.</li></ul><p><iframe title="Genshin Impact - Version 5.0: Kinich" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zxqfr4jyry0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>1.3 Kachina</strong></p><p>Kachina is a four-star Geo polearm wielder from Children of Echoes.</p><ul><li><strong>Turbo Twirly</strong> – Kachina is able to summon Turbo Twirly and ride it to climb walls and cliffs in daily exploration, and also unleash ground-slam attacks to deal AoE Geo DMG in combat.</li><li><strong>Free to Get in Archon Quest</strong> – By completing the first act of Natlan Archon Quest, you can invite Kachina into your team for free.</li></ul><p><strong>■ 2. Phlogiston and Nightsoul’s Blessing</strong></p><p><strong>2.1 Phlogiston</strong></p><p>In the Nation of Pyro, the Pyro power can be found as a unique resource known as Phlogiston. Phlogiston exists in different forms and can be utilized by the locals as a brand-new resource to in movement and combat. Once you indwell a Saurian, you may notice that skills are consuming a separate Phlogiston bar on the right side of your Saurian body. For Natlan characters, a Phlogiston bar also appears above their health bar. In addition, the constant flowing Phlogiston can form a pathway named Spiritways, where Koholasaurus or People of the Springs can use for fast travels.</p><p><strong>2.2 Nightsoul’s Blessing</strong></p><p>Nightsoul’s Blessing state is unique for characters in Natlan, which will usually increase their mobility and combat abilities. For them, the Elemental Skill is the most convenient way to enter this state, and a Nightsoul bar will show on the left side of the character.</p><p><strong>■ 3. The First Three Tribes in Natlan</strong></p><p><strong>3.1 Children of Echoes</strong></p><p>The Children of Echoes is located in the canyons of northeast Natlan, giving rise to expert miners and talented dancers. There is a large stage that serves as the heart of their entertainment, where locals proudly showcase their dancing skills and passion for the arts.</p><p><strong>3.2 Scions of the Canopy</strong></p><p>If you’re an extreme sports enthusiast or simply want to take in breathtaking views, visit the Scions of the Canopy, the tribe cantilevered over the steep cliffs with cables. People there are highly skilled at navigating through jungles and forests and reaching high places with ease. These abilities make them exceptionally suited for the role of a courier.</p><p><strong>3.3 People of the Springs</strong></p><p>As a laidback tribe known for its hot springs, People of the Springs offers a relaxing vibe with various watersports and music. It’s an ideal place for locals to conquer the waves and enjoy beach volleyball. With the guidance of local guides, more stories and mysteries will be unveiled around this seaside tribe.</p><p><strong>■ 4. Three Types of Saurians and Saurian Indwelling</strong></p><p><iframe title="Genshin Impact - Version 5.0: Baby Saurian" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LgQNYVpVKKg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>4.1 Saurian Indwelling</strong></p><p>Saurian Indwelling is a unique transformation mechanism in Natlan. We can roam the land of Natlan in Saurian’s forms by indwelling them or respective Spiritscounces. In Version 5.0, players can indwell three types of Saurians, Teptlisaurus, Yumkasaurus, and Koholasaurus to experience their unique skills.</p><p>Check the video showcase of Indwelling and Saurian’s abilities in media kit –</p><p><em>—Teptlisaurus</em></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Genshin Impact - Version 5.0: Saurian Indwelling - Tepetlisaurus" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A3sO5WeTdts?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><em>—Yumkasaurus</em></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Genshin Impact - Version 5.0: Saurian Indwelling - Yumkasaurus" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tE8VusI8ud8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><em>—Koholasaurus</em></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Genshin Impact - Version 5.0: Saurian Indwelling - Koholasaurus" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U3MUK1UFxf0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>4.2 Tepetlisaurus</strong></p><p>The Tepetlisaurus can be a good helper of the Children of Echoes, renowned for its mining prowess. This Saurian may aid the tribe in excavating valuable minerals and carving pathways through rugged canyons. When indwelling a Tepetlisaurus, you gain the ability to burrow underground, climb cliffs, and even access hidden tunnels that swiftly transport you to the other side of obstacles.</p><p><strong>4.3 Yumkasaurus</strong></p><p>Beloved by the extreme sports lovers among the Scions of the Canopy, Yumkasaurus demonstrates unparalleled agility in reaching higher terrain. Yumkasaurus possesses a unique organ that drags it into the air with ease. Additionally, when it consumes some Natlan fruits, it can unleash explosive projectiles, making it a reliable force in both combat and exploration.</p><p><strong>4.4 Koholasaurus</strong></p><p>Koholasaurus shares the hot springs and flowing waters of joy and relaxation with the People of the Springs. After indwelling a Koholasaurus, you can take a dip in the hot springs and waters around this seaside tribe. This Saurian even can move on dangerous Liquid Phlogiston and a fast track made by flowing Phlogistons.</p><p><strong>■ 5. Bonus and Optimizations</strong></p><p><strong>5.1 Bonus to celebrate the fourth anniversary</strong></p><p>As <em>Genshin Impact</em> is approaching its fourth-year anniversary, bonuses and rewards are offered to celebrate this moment with fans and gamers during Version 5.0.</p><ol><li>Daily login event – Up to 10 Intertwined <a title="Series > Fate [64 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">Fate</a>s from daily login event.</li><li>In-game mails – Primogem x 1600, two exclusive gadgets “Firstborn <a title="Companies > Firesprite [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-interactive-entertainment/firesprite">Firesprite</a>” and “Kaboom Box,” and more bonuses.</li><li>A Free 5-star of your choice from the Standard Wish lineup.</li><li>Double crystal bonus for first purchase reset.</li></ol><p><strong>5.2 System Optimizations and Updates</strong></p><p>A series of important system updates and optimizations are introduced in Version 5.0 to provide better gaming experience.</p><ol><li><strong>Visit Natlan in Early / Mid-Game</strong> – Map unlock criteria: complete all Mondstadt Archon Quests and reach AR 19; Archon Quest unlock criteria – complete all of Liyue’s Archon Quests and reach AR 28.</li><li><strong>Limited-Time Bonus from Archon Quest</strong> – You can claim an extra 500 Primogems after completing Natlan Archon Quests during Version 5.0.</li><li><strong>More Nonus from Returning Travelers</strong> – the returnee event Stellar Reunion may give you up to 10 more Intertwined Fates.</li><li><strong>Artifact</strong> – A new tool “Sanctifying Elixir” to redeem artifacts with 1 designated main affix and 2 designated sub affixes. In addition, starting from Version 5.0, salvaging Artifacts can return you enhancement materials.</li><li><strong>Character Event Wish</strong> – A new mechanism “Capturing Radiance” that has a rate of appearing during a 50/50 in Character Event Wishes. When it happens, the 5-star you get will be the current event-exclusive 5-star character.</li><li><strong>Weapon Event Wish</strong> – The maximum amount of Fate Points in Weapon Event Wish is lowered from 2 to 1. Now, after you chart a course to a weapon, the second 5-star weapon will be guaranteed to be your chosen one if the first 5-star weapon is not.</li><li><strong>World Level 9 Launched Now</strong> – After you reach <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,668 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a> Rank 58, you can complete Ascension Quest to increase your World Level from 8 to 9, facing more challenging combat with richer combat rewards.</li><li><strong>Regional Specialty Tracking</strong> – By clicking on “Go to collect” at the source of regional specialties, you will be able to pinpoint the location range of regional specialties on the map.</li></ol></blockquote><p><em>Genshin Impact</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,680 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,055 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [20,921 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://ys-api-os.mihoyo.com/event/download_porter/link/ys_global/genshinimpactpc/default" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">client</a> and <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/p/genshin-impact" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, iOS via the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/genshin-impact/id1517783697" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">App Store</a>, and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.miHoYo.GenshinImpact" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Google Play</a>. A Switch version is also planned.</p><p>Watch a new set of trailers below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/genshin-impact/august-16-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Version 5.0 Update Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Version 5.0 &quot;Flowers Resplendent on the Sun-Scorched Sojourn&quot; Trailer | Genshin Impact #Natlan" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w1BaF4fd1UM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="【原神】Ver.5.0公式PV「栄華と炎天の途」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uWhRg224Bts?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="원신 | 5.0 버전 PV: 「영광의 꽃과 태양의 길」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-ClpebVIRNg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Simplified Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《原神》5.0版本PV：「荣花与炎日之途」 #原神 #版本PV #荣花与炎日之途 #GenshinImpact" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_ahiAGsSd2A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Version 5.0 Update Events Overview</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Version 5.0 &quot;Flowers Resplendent on the Sun-Scorched Sojourn&quot; Events Overview | Genshin Impact" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GAqgl1ONcbE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="【原神】Ver.5.0「栄華と炎天の途」イベントまとめ" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8nQpZlWoVFo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="원신 | 5.0 버전 「영광의 꽃과 태양의 길」 이벤트 총정리" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4C3XwHagGtY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Simplified Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《原神》5.0版本「荣花与炎日之途」活动汇总 #原神 #版本PV #荣花与炎日之途 #GenshinImpact" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eU6M2UhPlXQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Natlan Impressions Trailer: “Blaze to Natlan”</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Natlan Impressions Trailer - &quot;Blaze to Natlan&quot; | Genshin Impact #BlazetoNatlan" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WE5emhmgP78?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="【原神】ナタイメージPV——「駆け抜けろ、灼熱のナタへ」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WnHCqA97hMQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="원신 | 나타 아로새김 PV——「정열의 나타」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qAaL7W9nKc0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Simplified Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《原神》纳塔印象PV ——「燃动纳塔」 #原神 #纳塔 #印象PV #燃动纳塔 #BlazetoNatlan #Natlan #GenshinImpact" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YLfeJfdfnp8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Version 5.0 Special Program</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Genshin Impact Version 5.0 Special Program #NewVersion #SpecialProgram #GenshinImpact" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nyI9wCt6su0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Ver.5.0「栄華と炎天の途」予告番組" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nM8S2D3hDvc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="원신｜5.0 버전 특별 방송" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Tid-gGEPKIo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite’s next Marvel season features a whole lot of Doctor Doom]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/15/24221374/fortnite-marvel-absolute-doctor-doom</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite%E2%80%99s-next-marvel-season-features-a-whole-lot-of-doctor-doom.954714/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/15/24221374/fortnite-marvel-absolute-doctor-doom<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>After revealing <em>Fortnite’s</em> Marvel-themed “Absolute Doom” season last weekend, Epic Games is officially kicking off <em>Fortnite</em> Chapter 5 Season 4 by sharing <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/be-a-marvel-hero-in-fortnite-battle-royale-chapter-5-season-4-absolute-doom">a bunch of details</a> about what you can expect when you drop onto the island in battle royale. Spoiler: there’s a lot of Doctor Doom.</p><p>As already shown, the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/11/24217825/fortnites-next-marvel-collab-will-be-nothing-less-than-fabulous">Absolute Doom battle pass</a> will feature various heroes and villains you can obtain like War Machine, Gwenpool, and, of course, Doctor Doom himself. (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/30/24209499/marvel-robert-downey-jr-doomsday-russo-bros-salaries">Timely!</a>) But the battle royale island will also have Doom-themed locations you can visit like the town of Doomstadt and Castle Doom, where you can find Doom’s Arcane Gauntlets to use as weapons. Doom’s gauntlets aren’t the only Marvel-themed weapons available, though; you’ll also be able to find Captain America’s shield, which is making a return from an <em>Endgame</em>-themed mode <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/25/18515617/fortnite-avengers-endgame-limited-time-mode-thanos-infinity-stones-mythic-item">from 2019</a>.</p><p>This is actually <em>Fortnite’s</em> <em>second</em> Marvel-themed season; the previous, which launched <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21402707/fortnite-chapter-2-season-4-marvel-nexus-war-thor-iron-man">in August 2020</a>, featured characters like Iron Man, Storm, and another version of Doctor Doom in its battle pass. If you didn’t get the outfits in that battle pass, Epic won’t offer them again, but thankfully, Epic is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/7/24215375/fortnite-battle-pass-rewards-back-around-item-shop">changing that policy</a> starting with the pass for Absolute Doom.</p><p>There are also <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/12/24218732/honey-wheres-my-fortnite-suit">more Disney crossovers coming to <em>Fortnite</em></a><em>, </em>including three Disney villains and characters from <em>The Incredibles</em>. Given that Disney recently <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/7/24065281/disney-epic-games-investment-fortnite-metaverse">invested $1.5 billion into Epic Games</a>, I suspect we’ll see a bunch more Disney cameos on the battle royale island at some point — and there’s a whole Disney-themed universe inside <em>Fortnite </em>on the way as well<em>.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Downtime: When Will Fortnite Servers Be Back For Chapter 5 Season 4?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-downtime-when-will-fortnite-servers-be-back-up/1100-6525855/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-downtime-when-will-fortnite-servers-be-back-for-chapter-5-season-4.954702/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-downtime-when-will-fortnite-servers-be-back-up/1100-6525855/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525855">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fortnite/" data-ref-id="5000-125765">Fortnite</a> servers are down for routine maintenance, but soon, they'll be back up and ready for players to invade the game by the millions in Chapter 5 Season 4.</p><p>After a polarizing season of vehicular combat and those awesome Nitro Fists, Fortnite's Wrecked season has come to a close, and the new season, Absolute Doom, is imminent. But, for the moment, we're stuck in limbo with Fortnite offline while Epic Games deploys the season update. This is standard procedure--we get at least a few hours of downtime before each new season. It's just a matter of time now.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1315139271" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464758,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Fortnite%20x%20Fall%20Guys%20Launch%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:45,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/fortnite-x-fall-guys-launch-trailer\/2300-6464758\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464758\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464758\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464758\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464758&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1352\/13527689\/4346131-wherewefallin%E2%80%99_-launchtrailer.mp4.00_00_08_09.still001.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/2c8sIBmT.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1722961200,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="2c8sIBmT" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Fortnite x Fall Guys Launch Trailer</p>
      </div>
<h2>Fortnite servers down - When does Chapter 5 Season 4 start?</h2><p>When Fortnite's servers come back up, it'll usher in a new Marvel season--its first since 2020--complete with a battle pass full of Marvel icons, new map locations based on the comic book titan's decades of lore, and lots of new weapons.</p><p>But when will that be? Typically, you can expect to see a new Fortnite season to kick off between 4 AM and 7 AM PT / 7 AM and 10 AM ET on launch day--in this case, August 16--though there have been some exceptions in the past, usually tied to when a patch takes longer to deploy than Epic anticipated. Still, if all things go smoothly, like they <em>usually</em> do, it'll be on in the early to late morning for US players, or a bit later in the day overseas.</p><p>However, because last season saw some technical difficulties during the patch deployment, <strong>this season's downtime has started earlier than usual</strong>. Thast could mean the new season also launches sooner too. If that's the case, Fortnite may be back online as early as 1 AM PT / 4 AM ET.</p><p>Once the game does return, Season 4 will introduce a whole host of changes to the battle royale island, thanks to the Doctor Doom's arrival. Players should expect new bosses, plenty of new weapons, and more secrets to be discovered, both on launch day and throughout the season. Presumably, Chapter 5 Season 4 will also play host to Fortnitemares, the game's annual Halloween event. Last year, horror icon Michael Myers came to the game, and the year before, it saw Ash from Evil Dead debut. Should we expect another horror legend to arrive? It seems like a safe bet.</p><p>Once the servers do come back up, we'll give you a massive roundup of everything new in Fortnite Chapter 5 Season 4 on GameSpot.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Telebbit launches October 24]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/telebbit-launches-october-24</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/telebbit-launches-october-24.954687/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/telebbit-launches-october-24<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Teleportation-based fast-paced action platformer dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Teleportation-based fast-paced <a title="Genres > Action [2,084 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Platformer [510 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > Telebbit [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/telebbit">Telebbit</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,680 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,847 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,791 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,921 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2504250/Telebbit/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on October 24, publisher <a title="Companies > HYPER REAL [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hyper-real">HYPER REAL</a> and Korean developer <a title="Companies > IKINAGAMES [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ikinagames">IKINAGAMES</a> announced. <span id="more-906323"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via HYPER REAL:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Take the teleporter and escape the lab!</p><p>A simple device, it teleports the user to the location at which it’s fired, but the possibilities become endless when combined with in-stage gimmicks! At the end of each stage, a boss stands ready to fight.</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>The year is 3023.</p><p>Constant war, environmental destruction, and deadly pandemics have forced humanity underground, where they have been working hard to develop a new personal transportation known as a “Teleporter” to provide a safer and cheaper means of transportation that minimizes contact with the polluted ground and atmosphere.</p><p>To ensure the safety of the teleporter, tests were conducted using animals. During one such test, a glitch in the teleporter resulted in a rabbit’s head being fitted with a high-performance CPU. With its new-found intelligence, the rabbit vowed to take revenge on the humans who subjected it to painful experimentation.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>A fast-paced platformer utilizing teleportation.</li><li>A game that is easy to learn but hard to master, requiring lots of effort and determination.</li><li>Eight different underground areas presented in charming pixel art.</li><li>Complete time trial in the Speedrun Mode.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Telebbit | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4QpE5tQ6DYU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Modern Warfare 2 Multiplayer Mod Canceled the Day Before Launch After Activision Sends Devs Cease and Desist]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/modern-warfare-2-multiplayer-mod-canceled-the-day-before-launch-after-activision-sends-devs-cease-and-desist</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/modern-warfare-2-multiplayer-mod-canceled-the-day-before-launch-after-activision-sends-devs-cease-and-desist.954675/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/modern-warfare-2-multiplayer-mod-canceled-the-day-before-launch-after-activision-sends-devs-cease-and-desist<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered mod H2M, which sought to revive Modern Warfare 2 (2009) multiplayer on PC, has been canceled on the eve of its launch after its developers said they received a cease and desist letter from Activision.</p><p>The mod team’s official X/Twitter account <a href="https://x.com/H2Multiplayer/status/1824167247436542167" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>broke the news today</u></a>, letting players know that they are bringing their work to a halt after receiving the letter today. The date of the cease and desists arrival almost exactly coincides with H2M’s August 16 release date, which was <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VwBEmMPxuRU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>announced</u></a> last Friday. Its X account’s biography now only says “SHUTDOWN.”</p><p>“Today, our team members received a Cease &amp; Desist order on behalf of Activision Publishing in relation to the H2M-Mod project,” the team’s last post says. “We are complying with this order and shutting down all operations immediately and permanently.”</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets1.ignimgs.com/2020/03/31/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-2-campaign-remastered---screen-2-1585677001593.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 multiplayer revival mod H2M has been canceled.</figcaption></figure></output><p>The H2M team’s posts date as far back as July 2023 when they <a href="https://x.com/H2Multiplayer/status/1675434407560368128" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>announced the project</u></a>, noting that they had already been working on a Modern Warfare 2 multiplayer remastered mod for a while. At the time, the team said, “If Activision won’t do what the fans want, we the community will.” Although the Call of Duty publisher did remaster the original Modern Warfare 2 campaign and release it in 2020, it never went as far as to remaster its multiplayer component.</p><p>H2M aimed to fill the hole with not only upgraded visuals for maps, weapons, and characters fans have loved for more than a decade but also new content, too. It meant new gun camos and animations as well as a crate of new maps based on iconic Call of Duty locations and more. This blend of old and new driven from the perspective of fans had players excited enough to drive sales of Modern Warfare Remastered seeing as the game was needed to play H2M. According to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/393080/charts/#3m" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>SteamDB</u></a>, the 2017 title saw a sharp increase in player count in the last few weeks and even managed to climb Steam’s top selling list (via <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/call-of-duty/call-of-duty-4-is-one-of-the-best-selling-steam-games-right-now-but-only-because-you-need-it-to-play-an-ambitious-modern-warfare-2-multiplayer-mod-launching-this-week/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>PC Gamer</u></a>).</p><p>Now, however, Modern Warfare Remastered’s <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/393080/Call_of_Duty_Modern_Warfare_Remastered_2017/#app_reviews_hash" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>recent Steam reviews</u></a> read “Mostly Negative,” with many recent comments from players calling for Activision to reverse their cease and desist request. Call of Duty fans in general have taken to social media to express their sadness at H2M’s demise, with some prominent content creators asking for Activision to reconsider, too.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We are begging that you guys reconsider this decision <a href="https://twitter.com/Activision?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Activision</a>. To be clear we have zero involvement in this project outside of being massive fans. We were excited to produce an ILLCAMS on the H2 mod. Their team made it a requirement to purchase the original MW2 Remastered… <a href="https://t.co/M2hbKvYOE0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/M2hbKvYOE0</a></p>— FaZe Clan (@FaZeClan) <a href="https://twitter.com/FaZeClan/status/1824178743428125173?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 15, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Yet another reason to hate Activision</p><p>H2M looked so good, MW2 MP Remastered with new weapons, maps, camos etc. - a CoD that so many people had wanted to see for years...</p><p>And they cease and desist it despite it requiring a CoD4 remastered purchase, complete joke <a href="https://t.co/J7SloLaO14" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/J7SloLaO14</a></p></div>— Luc // HiddenXperia (@HiddenXperia) <a href="https://twitter.com/HiddenXperia/status/1824173196956041598?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 15, 2024</a></blockquote> <blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">H2m getting a cease and desist a day after the cod sale ends 🤔 still refunding but horrible timing. No chance I'm spending money on bo6</p>— .tom (@TypicallyTom) <a href="https://twitter.com/TypicallyTom/status/1824172473828413527?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 15, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>A few developers behind H2M have also posted their thoughts online, including X user @TheWatchfulWolf and @alstr_. The former posted <a href="https://x.com/TheWatchfulWolf/status/1824169716061180375" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>an apology</u></a> and then teased that the H2M will now <a href="https://x.com/TheWatchfulWolf/status/1824177213685764598" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>set out to create its own project</u></a>, saying, “Fine. We’ll just make our own unique game.”</p><p>“Genuinely heartbroken,” <a href="https://x.com/alstr_/status/1824169981074194703" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>@alstr_ said</u></a>. “Over a year of work from a dedicated group of people working for FREE to relive a fan favorite Call of Duty. Not a penny earned despite generating THOUSANDS OF SALES FOR ACTIVISON, all to get shut down AFTER PEOPLE SPENT THEIR MONEY. I'm sorry everyone.”</p><p><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He started writing in the industry in 2017 and is best known for his work at outlets such as The Pitch, The Escapist, OnlySP, and Gameranx.</em></p><p><em>Be sure to give him a follow on Twitter @MikeCripe.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>