<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:42:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DOOM: The Dark Ages Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/doom-the-dark-ages-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-the-dark-ages-review.1185321/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/doom-the-dark-ages-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>DOOM Eternal is one of my favourite games of all time, and easily my favourite entry in the long-running id Software franchise. It’s the only shooter I’ve played where the end of every encounter makes me feel like I just finished jogging up the stairs for an hour. It’s a game that tests all your senses and fires all your synapses and locks you into a gameplay loop where you never. stop. moving. In DOOM: The Dark Ages, you need to stop moving. The game has swapped the jump and dodge action of the last entry with a new combat loop focused more around universal weapon utility, slower and steadier battles, and a melee parry system. It’s a wildly different direction, and while the result is absolute demon-blasting ridiculousness that’ll make anyone smile, it never quite reaches the same constant highs of the last game.</p>
<p><iframe title="DOOM: The Dark Ages Review – Tear 'em an old one" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iuTCe5ZVKos?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Doom: The Dark Ages isn’t just a major shift for the series due to its new focus on stand and fight combat, it’s also far more story-focused and dialogue-heavy than the prior entries in this Doom reboot saga. Rather than telling a story that follows up on the events of the last game, we’re instead tossed deep into a prequel set hundreds of years earlier, in the time period only briefly touched upon in some of the story beats of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/03/17/doom-eternal-review/">Doom Eternal</a>. While the last game dipped a toe into those waters, this one does a triple-spin canon-ball dive right into the deep end. Back in this distant past, the titular Doom Slayer is in forced servitude to the Maykrs – a clan of robotic angels that are hardly concerned with the fate of anyone but themselves. The Doom Slayer gets to kill demons, but only when the Maykrs decide to let him. It’s clear their hold over him is waning, though, while the demonic threat facing the planet of Sentinel Prime grows and the Night Sentinel crew is thinned out in its defence.</p>


<p>And so, you rip and tear, but your reasons for doing so are muddier than ever in some ways, and more complicated than ever in others. The story of the Night Sentinels and Argent D’Nur is kind of eye-rolling sci-fi slop, but it’s the kind that’s so endearing in it’s cheesiness – and also endearing in how it never gets in the way of justifying the most ridiculous and heavy metal concepts for your growing arsenal of weaponry. Sure, this is some kind of Dark Ages adjacent sci-fi world where people ride mounts and swing axes, but they’re actually laser axes, and you get to pilot a giant robot, and also, does that dragon have jet-engines and shoulder mounted machine guns?</p>


<p>In the same sort of way a Godzilla fan might jump out of their seat when a new movie wheels out a reference to their favorite monsters, there’s something really exciting and endearing to the way this game builds up to reveals and moments tied into concepts and characters from the last game. At times it had me absolutely screaming. Just don’t expect an incredibly emotional or pathos-filled story to go along with those bits.</p>
<p>What you can expect, though, is a lot of action. Those frequent story scenes that bookend levels don’t take away from the fact that Doom: The Dark Ages is packed with over twenty chapters of demon-killing fun, even if the way you kill those demons has changed. Early encounters do a good job of introducing you to the new mechanics of combat, but it took hours to truly get used to them. I approached every battle expecting the same run-and-gun electricity of battles in Doom Eternal, but without a double-jump or a dodge button, I ran into frequent reminders that this Doom Slayer takes it slow and steady. Your general goal in battle is to mop up the grunts with gunfire, and then lock in your focus on the big, armoured enemy that you’ll have to engage with in a series of blocks, parries, and melee attacks. In the last game, you felt so much faster and stronger than anything you encountered, and the “rip and tear” tagline really made sense. Here, you’re engaging in rhythm-gaming and parry timing that feels far more methodical and measured – battles are no longer a sprint to the exit, but a consistent and evened-out journey to the end.</p>

<p>The thing is, it’s still so much fun. Parrying is satisfying with generous timings on standard difficulties, while and your gun options are more varied than ever, letting you mix and match tools for every encounter in almost any way you’d wish, though with key attacks attuned to each enemy. As you get deeper into the game and encounter larger hordes of enemies, that marathon of calculated parrying and pummelling becomes bliss. And while your tools of destruction are more measured in use, they are also the sickest tools ever – you’ll constantly sling your chainsaw-covered shield at opponents, then spraying projectiles into them from a gun that crushes skulls to use bone shards as ammo.</p>
<p>You have to applaud the reinvention, even if this change of pace never comes close to hitting the same hectic, exhilarating highs as the last game for me. It isfair to say that for a pretty vocal part of the fandom, that exhilaration I felt with Eternal registered more like exhaustion. Since this is a prequel, you don’t need to play Eternal at all to hop into Doom: The Dark Ages, and the massively improved accessibility options and weaponry make it easier than ever to get into the series. Each enemy has a particular weakness, but you’re never penalised for sticking to your two favorite guns beyond the constant need for ammo. Plus, alongside the usual string of colorfully-titled difficulty options, you can tinker with an array of meters that let you fine-tune everything from damage taken, to parry-windows and even the overall speed of the entire game. If Doom Eternal was a game for a specific kind of freak, this latest entry aims to welcome as many kinds of freaks as possible with open arms.</p>

<p>Now, on top of the experimental new boots-on-the-ground gameplay, there are also missions in Doom: The Dark Ages that go for more of a boots-in-the-mech or boots-riding-a-giant-cyber-dragon route. A major crowd will likely groan at the inclusion of non-shooting gameplay in Doom, of all games, and that’s totally valid. At some level, maintaining the integrity of that consistent non-stop shooter mayhem the series is known for is important, and it’s something I was just lamenting about this game lacking.</p>
<p>But, also… you get to pilot a literal mech and fly around on a dragon with armour and laser-wings and shoulder-mounted machine guns! These moments are silly as Hell, yet played so straight and tuned to the extreme that I can’t help but love them. In mech segments, you’ve got a far simpler toolkit of weaponry and a pretty simplified punch-and-dodge combat loop compared to the main gameplay. Mech attacks are intentionally slow, and while it adds to the experience of highlighting how huge these titans are, it’s definitely not as exhilarating as the already slower-paced gun combat.</p>

<p>Dragon segments are more mechanically dense, but also a bit rougher. You can fly at high speeds to track down moving targets and objectives, or you can enter Assault Mode to hover in place and fire your machine guns. You’ll be entering this mode a lot dodge the incoming attacks of enemies, but this locks you into an unnaturally rigid view where you can only dodge up, down, left, or right. It’s genuinely the one function in the entire game where I feel like the animation speed and weight is just entirely off. In comparison to the rest of the game’s gorgeously animated and masterfully paced cutscenes, combat animations, and glory kills, it’s a clear step below.</p>
<p>Another factor that PC gamers in particular will feel is the weight of idTech 8 and ray tracing on their gaming rig. We’ve played the game across two systems, one with a GeForce RTX 3080 and a Radeon RX 6800, and where these were capable of running Doom Eternal at 1440p, maxed settings (without ray tracing) and frame rates well above 200fps, the minimum bar for Doom: The Dark Ages now requires ray tracing support for the game’s core lighting. That puts a huge burden on the game, so that the 6800 is more of a 1080p60 card, and the 3080 wants DLSS upscaling to hit triple digits at 1440p. Obviously there’s newer and much more powerful cards out there now, but the use of DLSS and FSR upscaling with dynamic resolutions is going to be more prevalent here.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doom: The Dark Ages Review - All the Gory, None of the Glory]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/doom-dark-ages-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-the-dark-ages-review-all-the-gory-none-of-the-glory.1185318/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/doom-dark-ages-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>With the seemingly <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/doom-eternal-review" rel="nofollow">decisive conclusion of the Doom Slayer's story in <em>Doom Eternal</em></a>, id Software has decided to go back into the past to explore the origin of the only foe that Hell's demons ever feared in <em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em>. As one would expect, this means a change in scenery, more cutscenes, actual characters, and a positively medieval set of new weapons.</p>

<p>Thankfully, there's no drawn out process where you slowly work your way up from lowly grunt to demon slayer extraordinaire. In fact,&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em> throws you into the midst of yet another demonic invasion right from the get-go at the apparent height of the Slayer's notoriety. No time is wasted in getting the distinctive new Shield Saw into your hands either.</p>

<h2><em>Doom: The Dark Ages&nbsp;</em>- Fantastic Weapons and Where to Find Them</h2>

<p>Unlike the special weapons featured in the previous games, <em>Doom: The Dark Ages' </em>Shield Saw is fully integrated as a key part of the gameplay loop. You don't need to collect fuel for it like the chainsaw, there's no practical cooldown period when using its abilities, and its upgrades scale relatively well throughout the campaign.</p>

<p>Naturally, the Shield Saw can be used to block the vast majority of attacks. If an enemy is far away, you can use the Shield to charge at them and turn yourself into a makeshift missile. Entire rooms of low tier enemies can be cut down by a single throw of the Shield Saw. Mid-sized enemies can be stun-locked to death before they have a chance to pose a threat.&nbsp;</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-shield-upgrades.jpg?itok=biEXDoBc 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-shield-upgrades.jpg?itok=z_DwxeNP 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>With the right upgrades, you can turn into the most overpowered boss in video game history</figcaption></figure><p>Even higher tier enemies aren't safe as their armor can be weakened by gunfire and then stripped by a thrown shield. Other dangerous enemies can have their attacks reflected back at them. The best part is that all of this functionality is available to you without any need to touch the weapon wheel. In other words, it's a completely seamless experience that allows for incredibly aggressive gameplay.</p>

<p><em>Doom: The Dark Ages'&nbsp;</em>guns feel almost quaint by comparison. You've got returning favorites like the Super Shotgun, a regular shotgun, a plasma rifle, an assault rifle, and so on, and they more or less function as one would expect. The new melee weapons (including your fists) are much more interesting as they are capable of inflicting debuffs and have some combo potential with the shield.</p>

<p>The same principle can largely be applied to the demons that you're fighting. The classic demons are basically unchanged while the new demons have unique designs and attack patterns. Coincidentally, the new demons really promote the usage of the Shield Saw's abilities.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-bfg.jpg?itok=4oRgC7mJ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-bfg.jpg?itok=s-R5uG2L 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The BFG is back, now with 100% more flying limbs</figcaption></figure><p>Unfortunately, a lot of the mobility mechanics that were a key part of the previous <em>Doom </em>games are simply gone. There are almost no platforming segments and dodging mostly consists of walking sideways. The Shield Saw does offer some mobility options for both combat and exploring, but you may as well compare an acrobat with guns to a tank, ice skating to boxing, or <em>Mario </em>to <em>Mortal Kombat</em>.</p>

<p>Cinematic executions appear to have been drastically toned down too, seemingly relegated to boss and mini-boss kills. The combat is fundamentally still the same, you just lose a lot of vertical and horizontal mobility in exchange for extreme forward momentum. Either way, to say that it's a noticeable difference is an understatement.</p>

<h2><em>Doom: The Dark Ages&nbsp;</em>- The Doom Slayer Talks (Kind Of)!</h2>

<p>Speaking of noticeable differences, <em>Doom: The Dark Ages </em>has far more cutscenes than any of its predecessors. There's generally going to be an intro and outro cutscene for each of the game's 22 missions, chronicling the story of the Doom Slayer and his time among the Night Sentinels.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-mechs-in-combat.jpg?itok=f90J_wlV 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-mechs-in-combat.jpg?itok=3-9jAi4w 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Amusingly enough, the mechs in <em>Doom: The Dark Ages </em>use their fists as their primary weapons</figcaption></figure><p>Alas, there's only so much that the writers can do with the story given that <em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em> is a prequel. It doesn't help that the Night Sentinel characters are drier than a desert. Hell has begun a full-scale invasion of the mortal realm and demons are about to kill everyone, yet the named Sentinels sound like they're waiting in line at the grocery store and it's raining outside.</p>

<p>One particularly egregious scene shows one of the named Night Sentinels literally being dragged into Hell along with the entire building that they're in, and for all the emotion in their voice, you'd think that they forgot to eat their ice cream before it melted. If you weren't paying attention to the plot, you might even miss the fact that two of the Sentinels are supposed to be directly related as they're not exactly acting like it.</p>

<p>Ironically, the named demon and Maykr characters are far more personable on account of their design and voice acting. Sure, they're not exactly going to be showing much character development, but at least their voices match the mood of the scene.</p>

<p>Fortunately, the playable areas have more flavor to them. You get to go to Hell of course, and it's the same fire- and gore-filled wasteland that everyone loves. There's also the Night Sentinel territories, which heavily lean into the medieval aesthetic mixed with elements of sci-fi technology. Later missions let you explore the realm of ancient eldritch beings too, predictably filled to the brim with tentacles, eyes, and nautical themes.</p>

<p>Most notably, some of&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages'</em> campaign missions let you pilot a mech and a dragon. These segments aren't particularly complex, and are admittedly more of a novelty than anything else, yet they prove to be adequate at providing some gameplay and visual diversity.</p>

<h2><em>Doom: The Dark Ages&nbsp;</em>Review | Final Thoughts</h2>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-dragon-flight.jpg?itok=d0UxXqk_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/doom-the-dark-ages-dragon-flight.jpg?itok=xu7V9trC 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Wouldn't an aircraft with missiles or lasers be more practical?</figcaption></figure><p>One can't help but wonder whether <em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em> is a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/marty-stratton-dark-ages-like-nothing-players-have-had-their-hands-on-in-doom-game" rel="nofollow">testing ground for where id wants to take the series though</a>. The mech and dragon missions, tweaking the combat mechanics to encourage parrying rather than dodging, even some of the narrative elements involving ancient eldritch beings can all be signs that the developers want to try something new.</p>

<p>In this case, new is not a euphemism for bad.&nbsp;<em>Doom: The Dark Ages </em>is quite the opposite, retaining the modern fast-paced gameplay that made its predecessors famous. The developers tried adding some new features, and while the story and voice acting is in need of improvement, everything else feels like a natural upgrade. The execution kills and dodge mechanics will be sorely missed however, and only time will tell if the aggressive gameplay offered by the Shield Saw is a suitably satisfying replacement.</p>

<hr><p><em>Doom: The Dark Ages was reviewed on the Xbox Series X with a copy provided by the developer over the course of 25 hours of gameplay- all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Anson is a Writer at TechRaptor and has been playing games for as long as he can remember. As far as he's concerned, games are one of the greatest forms of… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/anson-chan">More about Anson</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doom: The Dark Ages: The Kotaku Review]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/new-doom-dark-ages-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-game-pass-1851779839</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-the-dark-ages-the-kotaku-review.1185306/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/new-doom-dark-ages-review-is-it-good-xbox-ps5-game-pass-1851779839<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Doom</em> as a franchise has evolved a lot over the decades since it first arrived in the ‘90s. But through all those changes, there remain a few things I need in a <em>Doom</em> game to feel satisfied with it. A <em>Doom </em>game checklist, if you will. It’s not long, but it does make up the core of <em>Doom</em>.</p><p>You need lots of monsters and demons to kill. Levels with secrets. A badass shotgun. And you gotta go to Hell at some point. That’s it. Those are the core pillars of <em>Doom</em>. As long as you have that, you can do anything you want. For example, you could make a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lets-rank-all-the-doom-games-from-worst-to-best-1846753672&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lets-rank-all-the-doom-games-from-worst-to-best-1846753672"><em>Doom </em>game</a></span> set in a techno-medieval fantasy world filled with <em>Game of Thrones</em>-like factions facing off against a demon prince and old gods using guns, swords, and robots. And well, that’s exactly what Id Software has done with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-the-dark-ages-multiplayer-open-world-dev-interview-1851746527&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-the-dark-ages-multiplayer-open-world-dev-interview-1851746527"><em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em></a></span><em>.</em> But if you were worried that this more open-world spin on the series wouldn’t feel like <em>Doom</em>, don’t be concerned. This is still a kickass and exciting <em>Doom </em>game through and through. It’s just that this time around, the Doomguy gets to punch, kick, and bash more of the demons than usual.</p><h2 id="h481498"><a id=""></a><strong>What is<em> Doom: The Dark Ages</em>?</strong></h2><p><em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em> is a prequel set before the events of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-the-kotaku-review-1777315801?_gl=1*beeggg*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NDY3MzMzNjIkbzM2NyRnMSR0MTc0Njc0MTY4NiRqNTgkbDAkaDA.&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-the-kotaku-review-1777315801?_gl=1*beeggg*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*czE3NDY3MzMzNjIkbzM2NyRnMSR0MTc0Njc0MTY4NiRqNTgkbDAkaDA.">Doom</a></span><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-the-kotaku-review-1777315801&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-the-kotaku-review-1777315801"> 2016</a></span> and its sequel, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-eternal-the-kotaku-review-1842471145&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-eternal-the-kotaku-review-1842471145"><em>Doom Eternal</em></a></span><em>. </em>In those two games, we learned a lot about the Doomguy, his history fighting Hell, and the great wars between demons, robot angels, and humans that happened across dimensions long ago. It was all a bit much in a franchise that usually has narratives that can be summed up in a single sentence. “Doomguy is on Mars and fights demons to save the day.” Done. But with the newer games and now <em>Dark Ages,</em> Id is trying to tell a bigger, more complicated story and sadly, it’s the weakest part of <em>Dark Ages.</em></p><p>There are some cool moments sprinkled throughout the numerous (and sometimes lengthy) cutscenes. The Doomguy only says one word and does so in a very action-movie way that I liked. There’s also a great moment in which he’s asked to pay a toll in some underworld by a creepy figure, and just shoots him instead. Love that stuff. But most of the story in<em> Doom: The Dark Ages </em>concerns itself with people hunting for macguffins or for powerful artifacts to get the macguffins, and you’ll likely forget most of it by the time you reach the credits.</p><p>This is a <em>Doom </em>game! I should be killing stuff! Not watching people chat about power, war, and family. Thankfully, the gameplay in <em>Dark Ages</em> overcomes the floppy narrative and mostly forgettable characters.</p><h2 id="h481499"><a id=""></a><strong>Big battles and new toys</strong></h2><p>Because the story involves a big invasion of demons, combat in <em>Dark Ages</em>—unlike in the 2016 reboot and <em>Eternal</em>—often takes place in large, open battlefields and big rooms. The game fills these places with dozens and dozens of demons and lets you slaughter them all using a collection of mostly new and gnarly medieval-inspired weapons. All of them are powerful, loud, and a joy to use, like a cannon that shoots rusty nails and a gun that fires giant cannonballs attached to chains. One of my personal favorites is a machine gun that shreds up skulls and spits them out in a wide cone of death that can clear 100 weak demons in just a few seconds as you sprint around the 22 levels found in <em>Dark Ages</em>.</p><p>More familiar guns are here, too, like a plasma rifle and the BFG, which is now a giant crossbow that can clear an entire battlefield in one big green flash. And yes, there is also a shotgun. <em>Two</em>,<em> </em>actually. The standard semi-auto combat shotgun, which is a solid workhorse I used throughout my 18-hour playthrough, and the returning Super Shotgun, which might be the strongest shotgun ever in a <em>Doom</em> game. This two-barrel death-dealing shotty is able to rip mini-bosses apart in two shots or less. It’s wonderful. So, shotguns; that’s checked off the checklist.</p><figure id="" data-id="00235ece94699021bd22db53dd83f0d0" data-recommend-id="image://00235ece94699021bd22db53dd83f0d0" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Id Software / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="00235ece94699021bd22db53dd83f0d0" data-recommend-id="image://00235ece94699021bd22db53dd83f0d0" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The big new addition to <em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em> is Doomguy’s shield. You have this thing from the jump, and it stays with you for the entire game. And it rules. Being a shield, you can use it to block gunfire and fireballs, but you can also throw it at demons like a nightmarish Captain America. And because this is <em>Doom</em>, the shield is covered in saw blades, so it rips demons apart or sticks in the bigger ones. The shield can also be used to parry powerful demon attacks and energy blasts. This becomes a big part of combat as you get swarmed by massive demons during later fights.</p><p>Being able to counter their attacks and stun them opens them up for counterattacks with your melee weapon, also new to the franchise, and that loop never gets old in <em>Dark Ages. </em>I smiled every single time I blocked a big hell knight’s attack and then slammed him in the face three times with my spiked mace.</p><p>All of this isn’t just fun, but also important to the combat loop in <em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em>. Melee attacks against demons generate ammo, letting you use your guns on tougher foes or far-away targets. Shield tosses can stun bigger foes while you focus on fodder. And the shield charge ability lets you zip across the battlefield and close the distance on demons, letting you more easily punch them for more ammo. Or blast them away with a gun for health and armor. It all works together, and with an hour or so of playing<em> Dark Ages</em>, I found myself getting into a bloody ballet-like flow of blocking, dodging, shield tossing, punching, and shooting. And I was more aggressive than usual as the game rewarded me with health, armor, and bullets for doing so.</p><p>Unlike in <em>Eternal</em>, most enemies can be defeated with most weapons, so you are freer to kill how you want and not forced to use specific guns on specific demons all the time. That is, until one of the few super tough demons arrives and forces you to change things up a bit. But in those moments, I wasn’t annoyed as I was in <em>Eternal </em>when facing baddies like the Marauder, as these battles against minibosses with powerful shields and more health helped break up the pace of <em>Dark Ages </em>and they could still be defeated using most of my tools. I just had to focus a bit more and be careful.</p><h2 id="h481500"><a id=""></a><strong>A whole new world…filled with dragons and mechs</strong></h2><p>Beyond a new focus on melee combat and your shield, the other big change in <em>Dark Ages</em> is the size of levels. To be clear: <em>Dark Ages </em>isn’t an open-world game. It is still a series of levels you run through. But some of these levels are massive and filled with optional secrets and demon bosses to kill.</p><p>Most of the time, these secrets aren’t too involved. You might have to toss your shield at a hidden gear to open a door or break down a wall to find some hidden gold and armor. You aren’t doing side quests for random NPCs like in most open-world games. The Doomguy isn’t killing five rats for some leather or whatever. The open-world-ish levels are just filled with more optional opportunities to enjoy the excellent combat and movement in <em>Dark Ages</em> while earning some rewards. And these rewards will let you upgrade, improve, and modify your armor, health, guns, shield, and melee weapons. You can make the Super Shotgun even more powerful, carry more ammo, or add an augment to your shield that electrifies enemies around you every time you counter an attack. This upgrade system feels more streamlined than the one in <em>Doom Eternal</em>, which I’m thankful for, but I still feel that upgrade trees shouldn’t be a thing in <em>Doom</em>. It ain’t on my checklist, that’s for sure.</p><p>Speaking of things not on my checklist, let’s talk about big mechs and dragons. <em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em> sprinkles in a few moments throughout the campaign that see the Doom Slayer ride a cybernetic dragon or operate a giant kaiju-killing mech. These aren’t a massive part of the game and are instead used to help add some variety between bigger maps and boss fights. I’ll admit that I was nervous about the addition of vehicle segments to the franchise, but Id has done a fantastic job of incorporating both dragon flying and mech fighting into the world of <em>Doom</em>.</p><figure id="" data-id="14b8a515f5c68deb0b02d9420d7c7ae8" data-recommend-id="image://14b8a515f5c68deb0b02d9420d7c7ae8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Id Software / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="14b8a515f5c68deb0b02d9420d7c7ae8" data-recommend-id="image://14b8a515f5c68deb0b02d9420d7c7ae8" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The two reasons these segments work are simple: they’re easy to understand and wonderful to play. In <em>Dark Ages</em>, flying a dragon or controlling a massive robot was straightforward enough that, within a few minutes, I completely understood the controls for each. And Id has made sure that swooping around on the back of a dragon feels just as smooth as running and killing as the Doom Slayer on foot. Likewise, the mech feels powerful but not slow and clunky. And I must say, getting to uppercut a skyscraper-sized demon lord with a mech is one of the coolest things I’ve done in a video game in some time.</p><p>Another great thing about these segments: they don’t last too long, so if you don’t like ‘em, don’t worry, you’ll be back to old-school running and gunning soon enough.</p><h2 id="h481501"><a id=""></a><strong>Endings are hard, huh?</strong></h2><p>Something that does last too long in <em>Dark Ages</em> is the ending. For some reason,<em> Dark Age</em>s basically ends twice. There’s a big boss finale that builds in difficulty and tension near the end of the game. There’s a moment which I won’t spoil that made me hate the bad guy so much and fired up the Doom Slayer even more. It was wonderful. I dug my fingers into my keyboard. I was ready to fucking kill this big bad final boss after what he did. And I had a blast fighting him and ripping him apart.</p><p>And then, instead of ending the game there, the devs at Id Software added <em>one more </em>very massive level and two more boss fights. It’s not that the level or the boss fights at the very end are bad; it just feels poorly paced. And cramming a lengthy cutscene in the midst of it all didn’t help.</p><p>For a game that built momentum so perfectly throughout its entire run, it’s unfortunate that it ends with a whimper. Note for the future: When you reach the finale, end the story. Don’t do a second finale. Considering the fact that this game will get some DLC in the future, it will one day have the equivalent of three climaxes. I need more shotguns in <em>Doom</em>, not more finales.</p><p>Regardless of that mistake, <em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em> is still a standout example of how to take an old franchise and do something with it that feels fresh while still being true to the lineage of the series. And while <em>Dark Ages</em> has one too many cutscenes and endings, none of that ruins the frenetic and ultra-smooth combat, not even some bits in which you ride a dragon and pilot a mech. <em>Doom: The Dark Ages</em> is a brilliant, bloody, and hyper-aggressive remix of the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-running-on-pdf-weird-port-id-software-fps-pc-mod-1851739634&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-running-on-pdf-weird-port-id-software-fps-pc-mod-1851739634"><em>Doom </em>formula</a></span> that works in more ways than it doesn’t. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot DLC ‘DAIMA: Adventure Through the Demon Realm – Part 1’ launches July 17]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/dragon-ball-z-kakarot-dlc-daima-adventure-through-the-demon-realm-part-1-launches-july-17</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-ball-z-kakarot-dlc-%E2%80%98daima-adventure-through-the-demon-realm-%E2%80%93-part-1%E2%80%99-launches-july-17.1185303/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/dragon-ball-z-kakarot-dlc-daima-adventure-through-the-demon-realm-part-1-launches-july-17<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Second part to follow in early 2026.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot [78 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-ball-z-kakarot">Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot</a></em> downloadable content “DAIMA: <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,262 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a> Through the Demon Realm – Part 1″ will launch on July 17, publisher <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,679 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> and developer <a title="Companies > CyberConnect2 [615 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cyberconnect2">CyberConnect2</a> announced. “Part 2” will follow between January and March 2026. <span id="more-964309"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the content, via Bandai Namco:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Explore the World of <em><a title="Series > Dragon Ball [78 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/dragon-ball">Dragon Ball</a> DAIMA</em></strong></p><p>“DAIMA: Adventure Through the Demon Realm Pack” invites you to relive the thrilling adventures of Goku (Mini) and his friends Glorio, Shin and Panzy. Traverse fields and maps that faithfully recreate the stunning world of the anime series, Dragon Ball DAIMA.</p><p><strong>Immerse Yourself in the Demon Realm</strong></p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [211 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the world of Dragon Ball DAIMA through the eyes of Goku (Mini). Walk through the intricate landscapes of the Demon World, meet new friends, fight new enemies, and discover new mysteries.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Engage in Battles with New Techniques</strong></p><p>Experience battles as they are depicted in the anime, utilizing new techniques with the Power Pole. Leverage the Medi-Bug to get various effects and get support from Panzi and others to add a strategic layer to your combat.</p><p>These new elements bring a fresh and exciting dimension to <em>Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot</em>.</p></blockquote><p><em>Dragon Ball Z: Kakarot</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,433 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,170 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,983 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,959 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,064 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,099 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/851850/DRAGON_BALL_Z_KAKAROT/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>“DAIMA: Adventure Through the Demon Realm – Part 1” Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="DRAGON BALL Z: KAKAROT | DAIMA - Adventure Through The Demon Realm Part 1 - Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/27QCyiLjKeo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="「ドラゴンボールZ KAKAROT」DLC「追加シナリオ：-DAIMA- 魔界の大冒険！ PART1」配信日告知PV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_tlDrV09sx8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact demo for PS5, PC launches in May]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-demo-for-ps5-pc-launches-in-may</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-demo-for-ps5-pc-launches-in-may.1185297/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact-demo-for-ps5-pc-launches-in-may<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Includes six playable characters.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Bushiroad Games [89 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bushiroad/bushiroad-games">Bushiroad Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Eighting [89 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/colopl/eighting">Eighting</a> will release a demo for fighting game <em><a title="Games > Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hunter-x-hunter-nen-x-impact">Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,433 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,099 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2456420/HUNTERHUNTER_NENIMPACT/" target="_blank">Steam</a> in May, the companies <a href="https://twitter.com/hunterNI_games/status/1920797765195452472" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-964315"></span></p><p>The demo will feature playable characters Gon, Killua, Leorio, Kurapika, Hisoka, and Netero, as well as access to both Battle and Training modes.</p><p><em>Hunter x Hunter: Nen x Impact</em> is due out for PlayStation 5, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2456420/HUNTERHUNTER_NENIMPACT/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on July 17.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breaking This New Nintendo Clause Could Make Your Switch 2 "Unusable"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/breaking-this-new-nintendo-clause-could-make-your-switch-2-unusable/1100-6531421/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/breaking-this-new-nintendo-clause-could-make-your-switch-2-unusable.1185294/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/breaking-this-new-nintendo-clause-could-make-your-switch-2-unusable/1100-6531421/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531421">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nintendo updated its user agreement and privacy policy ahead of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">Switch 2</a> launch next month, and while the company briefly listed a few of the changes in the email it sent out, one of the big changes might have escaped your notice. A new clause related specifically to "unauthorized use" and other keywords like "bypass" and "modify" in the <a href="https://accounts.nintendo.com/term/eula/US?lang=en-US" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">US version of the email</a> gives Nintendo the right to make your console "unusable" if it discovers that you've broken any of these rules.</p><p>As spotted by <a href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/nintendo-emulation-hacking-brick-warning-terms-of-service" rel="nofollow ">Game File's Stephen Totilo</a>, the wording for the Licence for Digital Products section has been amended. "You acknowledge that if you fail to comply with the foregoing restrictions Nintendo may render the Nintendo Account Services and/or the applicable Nintendo device permanently unusable in whole or in part," the text reads. Here it is, in full:</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1990154474" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465857,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%202%20%E2%80%93%20Official%20System%20Overview%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:330,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-2-official-system-overview-trailer\/2300-6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465857&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531421&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465857\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4469338-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/P7d0cUEb.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1743603600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="P7d0cUEb" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Nintendo Switch 2 – Official System Overview Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>Without limitation, you agree that you may not (a) publish, copy, modify, reverse engineer, lease, rent, decompile, disassemble, distribute, offer for sale, or create derivative works of any portion of the Nintendo Account Services; (b) bypass, modify, decrypt, defeat, tamper with, or otherwise circumvent any of the functions or protections of the Nintendo Account Services, including through the use of any hardware or software that would cause the Nintendo Account Services to operate other than in accordance with its documentation and intended use; (c) obtain, install or use any unauthorized copies of Nintendo Account Services; or (d) exploit the Nintendo Account Services in any manner other than to use them in accordance with the applicable documentation and intended use, in each case, without Nintendo’s written consent or express authorization, or unless otherwise expressly permitted by applicable law. You acknowledge that if you fail to comply with the foregoing restrictions Nintendo may render the Nintendo Account Services and/or the applicable Nintendo device permanently unusable in whole or in part.</p><p>In comparison (via <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-reserves-the-right-to-brick-your-console-following-unauthorised-use-in-bid-to-prevent-piracy" rel="nofollow ">Eurogamer</a>), the clause is different for people with a UK Nintendo account, as it specifically states that "unauthorised use of a Digital Product may result in the Digital Product becoming unusable."</p><p>This is likely a new measure by Nintendo to combat piracy and emulation of its games, and while it hasn't explained what it means exactly with its use of the word "unusable" here, it probably won't be good news for anyone caught pirating software or running an emulator.</p><p>Nintendo is known for being very litigious when it comes to protecting its IP, as it recently launched a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/palworld-update-adds-big-change-to-avoid-disruptions-amid-nintendo-patent-lawsuit/1100-6531394/">high-profile case against the makers of Palworld</a> over similarities to the Pokemon franchise and gaming accessory maker <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-sues-accessory-firm-genki-over-unauthorized-switch-2-lineup/1100-6531304/">Genki has also had a lawsuit filed against it</a> for what Nintendo calls "trademark infringement, unfair competition, and false advertising."</p><p>Last year, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-intensifies-crackdown-on-youtube-emulator-channels-report/1100-6526834/">Nintendo took action against YouTube channels</a> that showed off its games running on emulators and it even managed <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-had-to-play-detective-to-find-an-alleged-switch-pirate/1100-6527794/">to locate and identify an alleged Switch pirate</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Clarifies How And Why Switch 2 Could Collect, Monitor, And Record Your GameChats]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-clarifies-how-and-why-switch-2-could-collect-monitor-and-record-your-gamechats/1100-6531419/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-clarifies-how-and-why-switch-2-could-collect-monitor-and-record-your-gamechats.1185291/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-clarifies-how-and-why-switch-2-could-collect-monitor-and-record-your-gamechats/1100-6531419/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531419">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Nintendo recently updated its privacy policy to confirm that the company may <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-may-record-your-audio-and-video-chats/1100-6531383/" data-ref-id="1100-6531383">"collect, monitor, and record"</a> audio and video of users' chat sessions for the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-specs-display-price/1100-6520278/" data-ref-id="1100-6520278">Switch 2</a>'s new GameChat feature. Despite this being a common practice, it spooked some fans, and now Nintendo has offered a clarification.</p><p>A spokesperson for Nintendo told GameSpot that Nintendo may review recordings of audio and video chats from GameChat, but only in a situation where a conversation has been reported.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1252044462" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465857,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Nintendo%20Switch%202%20%E2%80%93%20Official%20System%20Overview%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:330,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/nintendo-switch-2-official-system-overview-trailer\/2300-6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465857\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465857&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6531419&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;nintendo-switch-2&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465857},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465857\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4469338-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/P7d0cUEb.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1743603600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="P7d0cUEb" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Nintendo Switch 2 – Official System Overview Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>"If someone experiences communication in GameChat for Nintendo Switch 2 not in line with the Community Guidelines, they can report it using the built-in reporting feature," Nintendo said.</p><p>The company also clarified that, apart from these scenarios, all recordings are "privately stored on device." No person recordings are sent to Nintendo "until a report is submitted."</p><p>Microsoft previously disclosed that it <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-live-will-let-you-share-voice-chat-clips-with-microsoft-to-fight-toxic-players/1100-6515906/" data-ref-id="1100-6515906">collects similar data</a>, claiming that it stores this securely. PlayStation party sessions and voice chat are also recorded to some extent for safety and security. In 2014, it came to light from the Edward Snowden leaks that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/british-spy-agency-considered-using-xbox-360-kinect-for-surveillance/1100-6418021/" data-ref-id="1100-6418021">a British intelligence agency identified the Xbox's Kinect camera as a potential surveillance tool</a>, but there is no evidence that any spying was ever done this way.</p><p>GameChat is one of the Switch 2's marquee new features. It allows groups of up to 12 people chat while playing games. They can share their screen with friends, and it doesn't have to be the same game. Players can also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-preorder-guide-mario-kart-world-bundle/1100-6530531/" data-ref-id="1100-6530531">use a USB-C camera</a> to see friends in real time. The <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-explains-why-switch-2-gamechat-frame-rate-looked-like-that/1100-6530653/" data-ref-id="1100-6530653">streaming video quality might not be great.</a></p><p>GameChat is free when the Switch 2 launches, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/what-happens-if-you-press-the-switch-2s-c-button-without-nso-now-we-know/1100-6530684/" data-ref-id="1100-6530684">it'll eventually be locked behind a paywall.</a></p><p>Nintendo previously discussed the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/switch-2-camera-nintendo-responds-to-safety-and-spying-concerns/1100-6530594/" data-ref-id="1100-6530594">many measures it's undertaking to ensure young people are safe and protected</a> while using GameChat.</p><p>The Switch 2 launches on June 5, and Nintendo is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-reveals-how-many-switch-2-consoles-it-expects-to-sell-during-its-first-year/1100-6531389/" data-ref-id="1100-6531389">expecting to sell 15 million units in the current fiscal year.</a> The console's biggest launch title is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/mario-kart-9-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6528874/" data-ref-id="1100-6528874">Mario Kart World</a>, which carries an <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-defends-mario-kart-worlds-80-price-tag/1100-6530643/" data-ref-id="1100-6530643">$80 price tag. </a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doom: The Dark Ages' financial fate rests on a parry mechanic]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/doom-the-dark-ages-financial-fate-rests-on-a-parry-mechanic</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doom-the-dark-ages-financial-fate-rests-on-a-parry-mechanic.1185288/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/doom-the-dark-ages-financial-fate-rests-on-a-parry-mechanic<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via id Software/Microsoft.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">id Sofware's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom: The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is the next big test of Microsoft's $7.5 billion purchase of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-buys-zenimax-media-and-i-the-elder-scrolls-i-dev-bethesda-for-7-5-billion">parent company ZeniMax</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. That purchase has turned out some wins like MachineGames' </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the Fallout TV show, and the recent sales success of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/oblivion-remastered-is-already-the-third-best-selling-game-of-2025-in-the-us-industry-analyst-says/">The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but also some stumbles.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The poor performance of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Redfall </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">(and the layoff of hundreds of developers after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/microsoft-closes-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-and-alpha-dog-studios">the closure of Arkane Austin</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) is high on the list. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Starfield</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/starfield-delivered-the-biggest-launch-in-bethesda-s-history">the biggest launch</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">" for Bethesda Softworks, but player feedback has indicated the new series hasn't built </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/bethesdas-todd-howard-addresses-mixed-reception-to-starfield">as fervent a following</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as the company's other big-budget franchises. And while </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hi-Fi Rush</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> pulled in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-i-hi-fi-rush-i-keeps-on-beat-with-3-million-players">over 3 million players</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, that didn't stop Microsoft from shuttering Tango Gameworks (only for Krafton to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/new-year-new-you-tango-gameworks-reborn-as-tango-gameworks-inc">quickly scoop it back up</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">). Microsoft has clearly scrutinized each part of the ZeniMax portfolio after a major launch, and now one week out from the debut of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom: The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, it's starting to feel like the studio's fate rests on the shoulder of one new gameplay feature: the parry mechanic.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom: The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is hardly the first game to demand players carefully time their blocks to stun or counter their enemies, but it may be one of the first big-budget first-person shooters with that game mechanic. Since </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom Eternal</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> the market has been flooded by a number of Doom-inspired games earning praise and drawing dollars for a fraction of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">' budget.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/it-s-time-for-gaming-awards-to-rethink-the-strategy-sim-category" target="_self" data-discover="true">It's time for gaming awards to rethink the strategy/sim category</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A decade ago, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> would roll over the competition. Today it's worth asking—is the crowd interested in games inspired by the original </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> the same playerbase that's grown to love parrying in games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Elden Ring</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Star Wars Jedi: Survivor</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and the recently-released </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">? Will they find this to be the right new direction for Doom or will this sole divergence make it easier to shrug off the rage of the Slayer?</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Doom: The Dark Ages"><span>Doom: The Dark Ages</span> is designed around the parry</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When players boot up their Xbox (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/11/14/this-is-an-xbox/">whatever form it takes</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) with a craving for first-person demon slaying, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will be just a click away from the faster-paced, parry-free forefathers. And players will quickly find in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that the entire game is rebuilt around that one button.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The changes are quite complex—the rank-and-file developers at id have put a lot of work into answering the question "what if Doom Guy had a shield?" and the answers don't just all come down to the timing of a simple button click. Gone is the "dash" seen in the last two Doom games, replaced by a shield charge that closes the gap between the player and monstrous foes. Parryable attacks are telegraphed with a glowing green visual effect, and most of them take the form of slower-moving projectiles inspired by the "bullet hell" genre—and of course the original </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">(in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/doom-the-dark-ages-development-details-shine-light-on-the-state-of-modern-triple-a-production">conversations with the press</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, game director Hugo Martin and executive producer Marty Stratton referenced a desire to revive gameplay where players weave around slow-moving shots moving in geometric patterns, a trend that vanished in the shift to ever-more "realistic" shooters).</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/valve-stakes-its-claim-to-pc-gaming-handhelds-with-steamos-s-arrival-on-lenovo-legion-go-s" target="_self" data-discover="true">Valve stakes its claim to PC gaming handhelds with SteamOS’s arrival on Lenovo Legion Go S</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">That design decision is where </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> stands out from its FromSoftware-inspired peers, but the gravity of that dynamic stretches into the architecture itself—Environments are more tailored for circle-strafing around enemy creatures than racing forward to stay one step ahead of the bullet that might kill you.</span></p><p>Image via id Software/Bethesda.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The digital architecture is also shaped by this feature. Microsoft's admirable commitment to accessibility is present here in the form of deeply-configurable difficulty controls that let players adjust the parrying window to one that fits their ability. It also lets them modify everything from enemy aggression to bullet speed, to general gameplay speed, and beyond. These settings that can stretch the game so far it raises the idea that two players might go through </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom: The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and have two very different experiences.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-last-humble-bee-postmortem-staying-sane-in-solo-development" target="_self" data-discover="true">The Last Humble Bee postmortem: Staying sane in solo development</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Then there's the biggest gamble: the decision to prioritize parrying over online multiplayer. Mechanics that monitor precise timing are a perilous thing in online environments. It's not impossible—FromSoftware has made its name on allowing players to visit each other's games, either to help or hinder them in their quest for power. But the foundation of the Doom multiplayer doesn't favor collaborative monster-slaying or careful one-on-one duels. Ejecting the multiplayer element allowed id Software to build out unique control schemes where the player switches to piloting a giant robots and heavy metal dragons, but those setpieces are supporting acts for the main game loop—made possible by eliminating online networking, but not the point of it.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">And forgoing online multiplayer is where we return to the business of investing four years of multimillion dollar development in a parry-heavy game like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom: The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Without the feature that usually drives ROI on titanic games like this—will this direction prove to be the right one for the next Doom game?</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Doom: The Dark Ages"><span>Doom: The Dark Ages</span>'s surprising competition: "boomer shooters"</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">While the id Software team heroically toiled away for four years making the next great Doom game, a sea of other titles inspired by the original 1993 </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> have flooded consoles and PCs.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These games—sometimes called "Boomer Shooters" include </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1592280/Selaco/">Selaco</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2005010/Warhammer_40000_Boltgun/">Warhammer 40k: Boltgun</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a rel="nofollow" target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/519860/DUSK/">Dusk</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and beyond. Plenty others have been flops, but the growing reception to them signals audiences have plenty of options to take in the gunplay of Doom games, but are drawn in by low-budget gameplay twists and unique settings.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If one of these "boomer shooters" hit the market with a parry system built from the ground up, it would be less noteworthy—another swing at innovation from a small team. But </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom: The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">' parry system is an </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>expensive</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> parry system, recalibrating years of code, animation, and design to match a popular emerging trend. The R&amp;D into this tech came with improvements to the quality of 3D models (and an amazing reduction in load times), but those advancements don't have the same time to shine.</span></p><p>Image via Altered Orbit Studios.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">id's other unique hook here is the promise of a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> prequel, telling the tale of the Slayer's time in captivity before the 2016 game. Given that boomer shooters have also played around with setting and minimalist narrative, there may have been room to search for a unique hook here too. If </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom: The Dark Ages</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> used the new setting to springboard a more ambitious story—one that gave its silent protagonist more to do than glower at his captors—that hook could drive word-of-mouth enthusiasm.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The medieval sci-fi/fantasy aesthetic is fresh, but still not that different than the straight sci-fi/satanic art direction of the last two games. The cinematics are traditional, not even packing the dark humor of the 2016 </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Doom</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> where the player character had comical disregard for all the powers that be issuing directives in his ear. That isn't necessarily a knock on the story's quality or direction, but the familiar tone and framing seem in service of keeping players focused on a new kind of combat.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's amusing. Just like the Doom Slayer, id Software is now trying to precisely time a big action in order to land a major blow.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Return to Silent Hill film will be "faithful adaptation" of Silent Hill 2, distributor promises]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/return-to-silent-hill-film-will-be-faithful-adaptation-of-silent-hill-2-distributor-promises</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/return-to-silent-hill-film-will-be-faithful-adaptation-of-silent-hill-2-distributor-promises.1185285/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/return-to-silent-hill-film-will-be-faithful-adaptation-of-silent-hill-2-distributor-promises<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"Created out of deep respect for a true masterpiece of a game."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Aleksandar Letic / Variety</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Return to Silent Hill, the forthcoming film based on Konami's horror franchise, will be a "faithful adaptation" of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/silent-hill-2">Silent Hill 2</a>.</p>
<p>That's according to distributor Cineverse, which has acquired the rights for the film in the US for theatrical release (thanks <a href="https://variety.com/2025/film/news/return-to-silent-hill-theatrical-release-1236391288/">Variety</a>).</p>
<p>Christophe Gans, who directed the 2006 Silent Hill film starring Sean Bean, will return for this new film, which was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/return-to-silent-hill-film-detailed">first announced back in 2022</a>.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Silent Hill 2 Review<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vOv1JTfPnuQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Said Gans: "I am delighted to partner with Cineverse, which has shown a genuine understanding of fanship. Return to Silent Hill is an adaptation created out of deep respect for a true masterpiece of a game, Konami's iconic Silent Hill 2. I hope fans will enjoy and be fulfilled with the experience this new film has to offer."</p>
<p>"Silent Hill is one of the best video game franchises period and Christophe Gans did a phenomenal job capturing the atmosphere of the games once again with Return to Silent Hill," said Cineverse executive director of acquisitions Brandon Hill.</p>
<p>As previously reported back in 2023, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/return-to-silent-hill-casts-war-horses-jeremy-irvine-as-james">Return to Silent Hill will star Jeremy Irvine as James</a>, known for his roles in Mamma Mia! Here We Go Again, Treadstone and War Horse.</p>
<p>The plot will follow "James, a man broken after his relationship with the love of his life, Mary, ends," reads a press release. "When a mysterious letter from her calls him back to Silent Hill, he finds a once-recognisable town transformed by an unknown evil. While James desperately searches for Mary he encounters terrifying creatures and begins to unravel the mystery of what happened to the town. But as he descends deeper into the darkness the secrets he uncovers lead to a horrifying truth, and James finds himself struggling to hold on long enough to save his one true love."</p>
<p>The film is yet to receive a release date.</p>
<p>Still, it's good timing following the success last year of Bloober's Silent Hill 2 remake, which faithfully recreated the PS1 horror classic.</p>
<p>"Against the odds, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/bloober-team">Bloober Team</a> has delivered a remake that both expands Silent Hill 2 in just the right places, and gives careful attention to what it preserves," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-review">Eurogamer Silent Hill 2 review</a>.</p>
<p>By January this year, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-passes-another-sales-milestone">remake had sold over 2m copies</a> following its release in October. As part of its latest financial report, Konami yesterday revealed the Silent Hill series had total cumulative sales of 11.5m.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2 Goes Gold, Kojima Celebrates With Daruma Doll]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-2-gold-kojima-daruma-doll</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2-goes-gold-kojima-celebrates-with-daruma-doll.1185264/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-2-gold-kojima-daruma-doll<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Hideo Kojima and his studio Kojima Productions have announced that upcoming open-world epic&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach&nbsp;</em>has gone gold, and Kojima is celebrating with a time-honored Japanese custom.</p>

<p>Over on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/hideokojimaen.bsky.kojimaproductions.jp/post/3lopyu7eyrk2u" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Bluesky</a>, Kojima posted a picture of the&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach&nbsp;</em>gold master disk. In case you're unaware, a gold master disk is the version of the game from which other copies are pressed, so Kojima's post essentially means&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>is ready to ship.</p>

<p>Alongside the shot of the disk, Kojima also posted a picture of himself filling in the right eye of a Japanese daruma doll. Again, in case you're not familiar with the custom, a daruma doll's left eye is filled in when a goal is decided on, and the right eye is filled in when the goal is completed.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/death-stranding-2-gold-running.jpg?itok=DrKGyApg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/death-stranding-2-gold-running.jpg?itok=qpkBjIVQ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>has gone gold, so it really won't be long until you can play it now.</figcaption></figure><p>In case you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</em>, it is, believe it or not, the sequel to 2019's&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding</em>.</p>

<p>While a number of trailers have been released for&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2</em>, the game's plot is characteristically abstract. It'll pick up after the events of the first game and will ask the question "should we have connected?", but the specifics and minutiae of the story are still unknown at the moment.</p>

<p>We also know that a number of characters will be returning from the first game, including&nbsp;Léa Seydoux's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hideo-kojima-explains-additional-hands-on-fragiles-shoulders-in-death-stranding-2-on" rel="nofollow">Fragile</a>, Troy Baker's Higgs, and, of course, protagonist Sam Porter-Bridges, portrayed by the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-2-confirmed-by-norman-reedus" rel="nofollow">rather loose-lipped</a> Norman Reedus.</p>

<p>They'll join new additions to the cast like George Miller's Tarman, Debra Wilson's Doctor, and Luca Marinelli's Neil, and we'll get to find out how they fit into the story when&nbsp;<em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>launches (although even then, given Kojima's past form, that isn't guaranteed).</p>




<p><em>Death Stranding 2&nbsp;</em>launches exclusively for <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a> on June 26th (although a version for PC will almost certainly arrive afterwards, if <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/death-stranding-is-coming-to-pc-after-all" rel="nofollow">the first game</a> is anything to go by).</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The New Pope Plays Wordle And Words With Friends, And He Just Watched Conclave]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-new-pope-plays-wordle-and-words-with-friends-and-he-just-watched-conclave/1100-6531417/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-new-pope-plays-wordle-and-words-with-friends-and-he-just-watched-conclave.1185252/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-new-pope-plays-wordle-and-words-with-friends-and-he-just-watched-conclave/1100-6531417/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531417">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Robert Francis Prevost, who just became Pope Leo XIV, is just like you and me: He plays video games.</p><p>His brother, John Prevost, told NBC Chicago that he and Robert recently played games like Wordle and Words with Friends to help take his mind off the decision about whether or not he would be elected the new pope. He didn't have to wait long, though, as Prevost was named the new pope on the second day of the conclave.</p><p>John also revealed that his brother just recently watched the 2024 movie Conclave, which tells the story of the appointment of a new pope.</p><p>"I wanted to take his mind off of it--laugh about something--because this is now an awesome responsibility," John said of his brother becoming the new pope.</p><p>Robert Prevost didn't play any video games during conclave, however, as all cardinals had to surrender their phones before voting at the Sistine Chapel earlier this week for who would become the new pope.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tbnZ8zz9_og" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tbnZ8zz9_og" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Pope Francis passed away on Easter Monday this year at the age of 88. He had been pope since 2013. Francis was known to own at least one video game, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-pope-now-has-at-least-one-video-game-this-one/1100-6441528/" data-ref-id="1100-6441528">a copy of Undertale given to him by a streamer.</a> It's also been confirmed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-mods-help-player-numbers-grow-and-someone-in-the-vatican-just-bought-a-copy/1100-6527834/" data-ref-id="1100-6527834">a copy of Baldur's Gate 3 was sold in Vatican City</a>, though we don't know who bought it.</p><p>Leo XIV is the first American pope and the 257th pope overall. He was born in Chicago and is a White Sox fan, even <a href="https://chicago.suntimes.com/religion/2025/05/08/pope-leo-xiv-robert-prevost-st-rita-high-school-chicago" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">attending the World Series in 2005.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve Completely Reworks Deadlock Item Shop, Adding "Many" New Items]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/valve-completely-reworks-deadlock-item-shop-adding-many-new-items/1100-6531413/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valve-completely-reworks-deadlock-item-shop-adding-many-new-items.1185246/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/valve-completely-reworks-deadlock-item-shop-adding-many-new-items/1100-6531413/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6531413">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The item shop in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/deadlock/" data-ref-id="5000-639448">Deadlock</a> will look significantly different the next time you log in to Valve's third-person MOBA. The developer has overhauled the shop, adding new items, icons, costs, and more. Despite the patch notes saying that the major update is "coming soon," it's already live in-game.</p><p>Item slots were previously tied to specific tree types, but they will now be universal. Item-specific slots being replaced with universal slots removes the problem of some heroes feeling weaker due to needing up to six items of a particular kind to efficiently launch a counterattack after falling behind. Formerly, you had the ability to unlock four flex slots which served the same purpose. With the total slot count being reduced from 16 to 12, we can assume these flex slots are no longer available for unlock.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4491115-deadlockshopreworkfirstlook%21%21newitems%2Cbuilds%2Cheroredesigns%2Candmore%210-41screenshot.png" data-ref-id="1300-4491115" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4491115-deadlockshopreworkfirstlook%21%21newitems%2Cbuilds%2Cheroredesigns%2Candmore%210-41screenshot.png" data-ref-id="1300-4491115"></a><figcaption>The new item shop interface</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4491115-deadlockshopreworkfirstlook%21%21newitems%2Cbuilds%2Cheroredesigns%2Candmore%210-41screenshot.png"></figure><p>There are "many" new items being added to the store according to the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1422450/view/524216645064852902" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">patch notes</a>, and all item icons have got new artwork which makes the items and their purpose more easily identifiable.</p><p>Tier bonuses will also see a rework and will no longer be based on each item you buy. Instead, bonuses are based on your total spend in that item tree. It's important to note that bonuses are not linear though, so fully completing one tree isn't optimal in terms of the bonuses you'll receive.</p><p>If you're curious about whether you can or can't buy a specific upgrade, those items will now glow if an upgrade is available.</p><p>While it's well-known that the closed alpha test is invite only, it was recently discovered that there's an even more <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/valves-deadlock-has-a-super-secret-invite-only-alpha-different-from-the-known-invite-only-alpha/1100-6531294/" data-ref-id="1100-6531294">hidden test version</a>, as a streamer accidentally launched the wrong version of the game in front of his viewers.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/100905401902076465889?rel=author">Cheri Faulkner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sumo Group’s founders announce retirement]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/sumo-groups-founders-announce-retirement/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sumo-group%E2%80%99s-founders-announce-retirement.1185228/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/09/sumo-groups-founders-announce-retirement/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The founders of Sumo Group have announced their retirement. CEO Carl Cavers, COO Paul Porter and Director of Excellence and Integration Darren Mills are all leaving the company after leading Sumo since 2003. Under their leadership, Sumo has released games such as Outrun 2, Sonic &amp; All-Stars Racing: Transformed, LittleBigPlanet 3, Snake Pass, and Sackboy: A Big Adventure.</p>
<p>“Stepping away from something we’ve built over two decades is never easy, but it’s the right time,” said Carl Cavers, outgoing CEO and co-founder. “We’re incredibly proud of what we’ve achieved together, and we’re confident that Sumo is in a strong position to continue evolving and thriving.”</p>


<p>With the retirement of the three founders there is obviously a change in leadership at Sumo Group. Gary Dunn will take on the role of COO and be co-CEO with &nbsp;Andy Stewart, who is also the Chief Financial Officer. Tim Repa-Davies has moved onto the company’s board of directors, while remaining as the Head of Legal and Business Affairs.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/04/sumo-group-stops-making-original-ip-to-focus-on-partner-titles/">Sumo Group announced it would stop making original IP to focus on partner titles</a>, due to the company’s position and need to maintain a long term strategy for the continued survival of the group. In March, Sumo Group sold off its publishing arm <a href="https://www.sumo-digital.com/news-insights/emona-capital-completes-acquisition-of-secret-mode/">Secret Mode to Emona Capital</a>, a financial investment firm which also has holdings in Relic Entertainment and Amber Studio. At the time of the sale, Ed Blincoe and James Schall remained in leadership positions within of the company. Sumo is currently working to support development of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/05/gears-of-war-reloaded-announced-for-pc-xbox-series-xs-and-ps5/">Gears of War: Reloaded</a>.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.sumo-digital.com/news-insights/sumo-group-announces-leadership-transition-as-founders-retire/">Sumo Group</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honkai: Star Rail Version 3.3 Release Date and More Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/honkai-star-rail-version-33-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/honkai-star-rail-version-3-3-release-date-and-more-revealed.1185225/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/honkai-star-rail-version-33-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>HoYoverse has announced the release date for&nbsp;<em>Honkai: Star Rail&nbsp;</em>Version 3.3, with the latest update for the turn-based gacha RPG landing later this month.</p>

<p>Following on from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/honkai-star-rail-version-32-release-date" rel="nofollow">last month's</a> Version 3.2,&nbsp;<em>Honkai: Star Rail&nbsp;</em>Version 3.3, also known as "The Fall at Dawn's Rise", will be arriving across all platforms on May 21st. As you'd expect, it'll bring a chunk of new story, plus two new characters for your team and more.</p>

<p>In story terms, you'll be taking part in the "final battle of Flame-Chase Journey", standing against the Sky Titan Aquila, which "controls the cycles of dawn and dusk" thanks to having "the sky as its eyelids". Good luck with that.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/honkai-star-rail-version-3.3-release-date-hyacine.jpg?itok=ysPR7mAg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/honkai-star-rail-version-3.3-release-date-hyacine.jpg?itok=j73OYLem 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Two new characters will be available in&nbsp;<em>Honkai: Star Rail&nbsp;</em>Version 3.3.</figcaption></figure><p>As is often the case, two new five-star playable characters will debut as part of the latest&nbsp;<em>Honkai: Star Rail&nbsp;</em>update. The first, Hyacine, is a healer who can restore her team's HP and boost "overall survivability" thanks to her Ultimate.</p>

<p>Joining Hyacine is Cipher, a Quantum character on the Path of Nihility. She's a damage-dealer who can analyse enemies in order to dish out additional damage based on punishment they've already taken.</p>

<p>Alongside these two, five-star limited fighters The Herta and Aglaea will be returning in the first and second halves of Version 3.3's event cycle, so if you missed your chance to grab them the first time around, be sure to seize this opportunity.</p>

<p>As well as the story,&nbsp;<em>Honkai: Star Rail&nbsp;</em>Version 3.3 also adds minigames like the new "Penacony Speed Cup Spheroid Racing Tournament" event, which gives you the chance to race your Spheroid Racer against opponents in "high-stakes showdowns".</p>




<p><em>Honkai: Star Rail&nbsp;</em>is available to play for free right now on <a href="https://hsr.hoyoverse.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC, PlayStation 5, and mobile devices</a>. Version 3.3, "The Fall at Dawn's Rise", launches across all of these platforms on May 21st.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[John Cena vs. Randy Orton: A Timeline of Their Iconic Feuds]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/john-cena-randy-orton-backlash-wwe-championship-1851779827</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/john-cena-vs-randy-orton-a-timeline-of-their-iconic-feuds.1185219/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/john-cena-randy-orton-backlash-wwe-championship-1851779827<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="7c5c928867ebc7299af89fef742e708c" data-recommend-id="image://7c5c928867ebc7299af89fef742e708c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Randy Orton (left) and John Cena (right) staring " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="7c5c928867ebc7299af89fef742e708c" data-recommend-id="image://7c5c928867ebc7299af89fef742e708c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Randy Orton (left) and John Cena (right) staring " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>John Cena vs. Randy Orton isn’t just a rivalry. It is <em>the</em> rivalry of a generation, and it will be rekindled again—perhaps for the final time—at WWE Backlash.</p><p>Born out of the Ruthless Aggression Era, their feud has spanned decades, titles, and turning points in the industry. Cena became the Hulk Hogan-esque face of the company, wearing bright colors, coining memorable catchphrases, always doing the right thing, and securing impossible underdog victories night in and night out.</p><p>Orton, meanwhile, embodied pure evil. Aptly nicknamed the WWE’s “Apex Predator,” his violent move set and remorseless attitude made him one of the most dangerous, despicable heels in the history of professional wrestling.</p><p>In the 2000s and early 2010s, they were two sides of WWE’s main-event coin: Cena the superhero, Orton the supervillain. They were meant for each other.</p><p>Now, in 2025, the roles are reversed, but the animosity remains. Ahead of the WWE Backlash pay-per-view, we examine the ins, outs, RKOs, and Attitude Adjustments of John Cena and Randy Orton’s historic rivalry.</p></div></div><div><p>John Cena and Randy Orton squared off long before the WWE Universe knew their names… and before Cena was literally “Cena.”</p><p>The Prototype, as he was dubbed in Ohio Valley Wrestling (OVW), the WWE’s former developmental territory, met his future rival multiple times in the promotion. Most notably, he defeated “Cowboy” Bob Orton’s son for the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sw7SgbM7i5w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sw7SgbM7i5w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OVW Championship</a></span> in the latter’s final match with the company. The WWE had plans for Mr. RKO.</p><p>Twenty-five years and 31 combined world championships later, Orton looks to return the favor. Orton may very well kill the legend of John Cena at Backlash by capturing the title and sending the GOAT into retirement empty-handed. The full-circle moment writes itself.</p></div><div><p>By this point, Cena had shed his Doctor of Thuganomics persona to be the superhero marine that embodied “Hustle, Loyalty, and Respect” and crashed <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcvJV5F1HM4&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcvJV5F1HM4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">live sex celebrations</a></span>. Orton leveraged his success as the “Legend Killer” in wrestling stable Evolution to become the youngest world champion ever, and nearly decapitate <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7xooL_QCFLI&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7xooL_QCFLI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Shawn Michaels</a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dtf8OcwFZ_0&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dtf8OcwFZ_0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Rob Van Dam</a></span>.</p><p>The stage was set for the WWE’s new face to cross paths with its most sinister heel.</p><p>Orton hit Cena with several patented “Outta nowhere!!” RKOs leading up to their bout at SummerSlam 2007, which Cena won thanks to a big comeback (shocker!). The following night on Raw, Orton ripped Cena’s father over the barricade and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7GETeK8ptPA&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7GETeK8ptPA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">punted the bejesus</a></span> out of him in a move that is still burned in every wrestling fan’s memory over 15 years later.</p><p>The two wrestled at Unforgiven a month later, which Orton won by disqualification seven minutes in when Cena ignored the ref’s calls to stop wailing on his opponent. A payoff match was set for No Mercy the following month, but Cena legitimately tore his pectoral muscle days before, and then was viciously attacked by the newly nicknamed “Viper.”</p><p>With Cena out, Orton won the title. While the feud teased the duo’s electric chemistry, it left a lot to be desired. Fortunately, it wouldn’t be long before the duo traded blows again in the squared circle.</p></div><div><p>In 2008, John Cena pulled off his most iconic Super-Cena feat. The same pectoral injury Cena suffered (thanks to Orton, in kayfabe) was supposed to put him on the shelf for at least 6 months. Instead, he shocked the world than 4 months later to win the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bNlObJjzoyk&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bNlObJjzoyk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Royal Rumble at Madison Square Garden</a></span>. If you ever want to know how deafening an audience pop can get, just listen to how the Madison Square Garden crowd roared when Super-Cena came from behind the curtains.</p><p>That meant Cena would face WWE Champion Randy Orton for the title he never lost. But, they didn’t wait until WrestleMania to pick up where they left off. The foes fought at No Way Out in an emotion-filled, physical contest that saw Orton eventually “throw in the towel” (or rather, a wet blanket) by slapping the ref and disqualifying himself to retain.</p><p>Shortly thereafter, Cena, Orton, and Triple H met in a Triple Threat match at WrestleMania XXIV. “The Viper” slithered to an underhanded victory, punting Triple H after his former mentor pedigreed Cena, then covering Cena for the 1-2-3 to retain the title.</p><p>Less than a month later, Orton pulled off a similar tactic in a Fatal 4-Way match at Backlash. He eliminated Cena with a punt after Cena forced JBL to tap. If the second John Cena and Randy Orton feud helped establish “Big Match John” as Superman, then Orton’s opportunistic constricting was his kryptonite.</p></div><div><p>Bald-headed Randy was a MENACE!</p><p>Early in 2009, Orton and his Legacy pals (Cody Rhodes and Ted DiBiase) locked horns with the McMahons. He punted Vince and DDT’d, then kissed Stephanie while she lay unconscious next to her helpless, handcuffed husband Triple H. Talk about a bad day at the office.</p><p>Orton attributed his uncontrollable violence to IED (Intermittent Explosive Disorder), claiming he wasn’t responsible for his actions… and you believed him. There truly seemed to be “voices” in his head; multiple personalities urging him to commit heinous act after heinous act. When the unforgivable deed of the day was done, he emoted both terror and exhilaration. He was deranged and may have deserved an Emmy for it.</p><p>By the time summer rolled around, Orton’s mental and physical transformation was complete. He shaved his head and became WWE’s Voldemort. VoldemOrton, if you will. Once handsome and charismatic, now sub-human and sadistic. He was pure evil, and the internet remembers.</p><p>Cue John Cena’s music. Cena and Orton renewed their rivalry, embarking on a five-matches-in-four-months odyssey for the WWE Championship, with Orton winning thrice and Cena winning twice.</p><p>Cena officially ended Orton’s reign in a 60-minute, anything-goes Iron Man bout at Bragging Rights. The feud solidified both men as inevitable.</p></div><div><p>Nothing brings WWE superstars together quite like a common enemy.</p><p>A tornado in the form of the Nexus ravaged through the WWE in the summer of 2010, destroying everyone and everything that stood in their path, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RcUrh7xUcqM&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RcUrh7xUcqM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">including John Cena</a></span>.</p><p>In his efforts to vanquish the group, Cena competed in a highly stipulated match with the faction’s leader Wade Barrett: if Cena won, the Nexus would disband. If Barrett won, Cena would join the “terrorist” organization. Barrett won and Cena became his lackey.</p><p>Barrett then embarked on a quest to capture the WWE title from Randy Orton, and enlisted Cena to be in his corner during their championship match at Bragging Rights. When that didn’t yield results, Barrett had Cena act as a special guest referee in his rematch against Orton with the understanding that if Barrett didn’t walk away champion, Cena would be fired.</p><p>The morally upstanding Cena counted the 1-2-3, giving Orton the win and costing himself his job. The next night on Raw, Cena made a farewell speech in the ring, and as he walked backstage out of the arena, Randy Orton shook his hand and they hugged. It was a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aN1OxTdN0JQ&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aN1OxTdN0JQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">surreal Thor and Loki</a></span> brotherly love moment.</p></div><div><p>Three years post-Nexus invasion, the WWE looked different. CM Punk’s pipe bomb promo catapulted him to icon status, The Shield wreaked havoc, Daniel Bryan became the most beloved star since Stone Cold, and The Authority—led by Triple H and Stephanie McMahon—called the shots.</p><p>Despite a new wave of A+ talent and storylines, John Cena and Randy Orton, their generation’s Rock and Austin, fought in a Tables, Ladders, and Chairs match to unify the WWE and World Heavyweight titles. Orton won the contest (and retained in a rematch at the Royal Rumble), but the “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SVfkSrk1QuY&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SVfkSrk1QuY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Championship Ascension Ceremony</a></span>” on the Raw prior to TLC remains the highlight of the feud.</p><p>As Cena and Orton stood face-to-face, former world champions packed the ring. Orton cheap-shotted Cena, sparking a domino effect brawl involving Triple H, Punk, Shawn Michaels, and Daniel Bryan. The melee ended with Orton accidentally knocking down Stephanie McMahon and Triple H retaliating with a Pedigree.</p><p>Like Daniel Bryan and the “YES” Movement hijacked Raw, they too will hijack this write-up, as the fans’ unrelenting desire for him to become the unified champ—strongly reinforced by this moment—eventually played out. The WWE Universe was ready for a changing of the guard.</p></div><div><p>Since the Elimination Chamber in March, we’ve been living in the Upside Down. John Cena is a heel.</p><p>The self-proclaimed unseen 17-time champion alleges he’s the victim of a decades-long abusive relationship with fans. He low-blowed Cody Rhodes to win the WWE title at WrestleMania and eclipse Ric Flair’s record. He says he’s raised the WWE Universe’s kids better than their own parents. He declares that he’s going to ruin wrestling.</p><p>For someone who hasn’t played the villain since 2003, Cena’s scarily good at it. His logic is so sharp, it’s hard not to think he’s been holding grudges against the fans for years. This isn’t Hollywood Hogan or Final Boss Rock. This is John Cena—hateful, bitter, living his heelish truth.</p><p>Randy Orton’s solution for Cena’s attitude adjustment? Have kids! WWE’s Apex Predator says it’ll help Cena grow up. If that isn’t <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E-Iveaww5WM&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E-Iveaww5WM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SpongeBob SquarePants Opposite Day</a></span>-level shenanigans, I don’t know what is. Somehow, it works. It’s two veterans with new outlooks clashing once again.</p><p>When Randy Orton and John Cena square off at Backlash, it may very well be the last time they do. The time is now to live in the moment and enjoy. We’ve only got a few of those left with Cena.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Patch 1.2.3 Is a Big One, Nerfs Maelle's Game-Breaking Stendahl Build]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-patch-123-is-a-big-one-nerfs-maelles-game-breaking-stendahl-build</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-patch-1-2-3-is-a-big-one-nerfs-maelles-game-breaking-stendahl-build.1185216/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-patch-123-is-a-big-one-nerfs-maelles-game-breaking-stendahl-build<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> developer Sandfall Interactive has released Patch 1.2.3 for its well-received role-playing game across all platforms.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The update makes a long list of fixes and, crucially, balance changes, including nerfing Clair Obscur’s most game-breaking build (patch notes below).</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sandfall had signalled this change was coming, saying it hadn’t planned to make any balance tweaks this early — just bug fixes, “unless something clearly stood out.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Well, Stendhal did,” the developer continued.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The build in question is (was!) for young fencer <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/clair-obscur-expedition-33/Maelle_Builds">Maelle</a> and a sword called <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/clair-obscur-expedition-33/How_to_Get_Medalum_(Maelle_Weapon)">Medalum</a>, which unlocks a Virtuose Stance that deals 200% bonus damage. Players were combining this with ability-stacking and the Stendahl skill, which deals extreme single target Void damage, to dish out billions of damage, enough to kill the final boss in just one hit.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It was underwhelming for most of development, so in our final pre-release balance pass, we gave it a big damage boost — and clearly overdid it. It ended up overshadowing most other options,” Sandfall said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We still want you to be able to break the game — and you absolutely still can — but Stendhal was making it a bit too easy.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The nerf is included in Clair Obscur: Expedition 33’s first full hotfix set. While Stendhal is still a strong single-hit skill with great synergy potential, it’s now more in-line with everything else.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, the patch fixes what sounds like a bug that was making Medalum third Lumina doubling all damage in Virtuose Stance, instead of doubling only Burn damage.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Here's the relevant points from today's patch notes:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed Medalum third Lumina doubling all damage in Virtuose Stance instead of doubling only Burn damage.</li><li>Stendhal: Reduced damage by 40%.</li></ul><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Maelle Outfits and Haircuts - Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Clair Obscur is a breakout hit for Sandfall, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/clair-obscur-expedition-33-hits-2-million-copies-sold-after-12-days-on-sale">and has already sold over 2 million copies</a>. It’s worth remembering that Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 was, alongside Bethesda’s Oblivion Remastered, a day-one Game Pass title. That makes this sales milestone all the more impressive.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">When Bethesda shadow-dropped <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered"><u>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</u></a> amid the launch of fellow role-playing game Clair Obscur: Expedition 33, most thought there could be only one winner. However, it turned out that there was plenty of room for both games to succeed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 has done so well that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/french-president-macron-congratulates-clair-obscur-expedition-33-developer-for-creating-one-of-the-best-rated-games-in-history"><u>French President Macron has praised the development team</u></a>. Be sure to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/clair-obscur-expedition-33/Tips_-_Things_Clair_Obscur_Doesn't_Tell_You"><u>check out our tips for the important things to know before </u></a>heading into the game.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 update 1.2.3 patch notes:</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Steam Deck</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed backgrounds of various menus not displaying properly on the Steam Deck</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Various Ultrawide Fixes</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Gameplay no longer becomes zoomed after a cutscene occurs in ultrawide resolutions</li><li>The Options menu image will no longer be stretched in ultrawide resolutions</li><li>Combat UI now adapts correctly to ultrawide resolutions</li><li>Game will no longer minimize upon changing settings in ultrawide resolution</li><li>Cutscenes won’t letterbox in 32:9 aspect ratio</li><li>Title screen now displays fullscreen when the game is launched in ultrawide resolution</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Mouse and Keyboard</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>UI button prompts in Expedition Menu are now visible and fully able to be triggered with Keyboard</li><li>Mouse buttons do not become unresponsive after first use</li><li>With mouse cursor on screen, using 'WSAD' or directional arrows to navigate in UI or trigger any other functionality will no longer hide the cursor instead of doing the intended action</li><li>Left Mouse-button click will no longer block the player from using Keyboard to navigate menus</li><li>Mouse input is not lost after the first Jump counter attack if it is pressed only once</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Fixed areas of the world map where you can get stuck:</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Between lanterns scattered on the ground near Stone Wave Cliff portal</li><li>While walking on the ship wreck near the Forgotten Battlefield level entrance</li><li>Between lanterns on the ground near Bourgeon encounter next to Stone Wave Cliffs level</li><li>Between two small rocks located between Spring Meadows and Abbest Cave</li><li>Between vases and corals when jumping from rooftopps</li><li>Between various rocks</li><li>In ruins behind Flying Manor level entrance</li><li>Near the bridge between Flying Waters and Spring Meadows</li><li>In the rocks on the World Map, near Flying Waters</li><li>Next to hardened land, close to the Flying Waters location exit</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Fixed situations where Esquie specifically would get stuck (poor guy):</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>When taking off from paint bridges, making him fall through the bridge and restrict movement</li><li>When flying into bottom parts of levitating structures near Visages</li><li>Near the Flying Waters entrance level</li><li>Near a giant hammer when traversing close to Blades' Graveyard level</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Weapon and skill fixes and tuning:</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed Lithelim attribute scaling not working at high level. Reduced initial Vitality scaling from A to C (will still end at S at max level). Added Luck scaling starting at D.</li><li>Fixed Blizzon attribute scaling not working at high level. Reduced initial Luck scaling from B to C (will still end at S at max level). Added Defense scaling starting at D.</li><li>Fixed Medalum third Lumina doubling all damage in Virtuose Stance instead of doubling only Burn damage.</li><li>Stendhal: Reduced damage by 40%.</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Other fixes</h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Boss encounter in Stone Wave Cliffs can now be finished on NG+</li><li>You will no longer be blocked by the Journal UI window after opening the first Journal in the Spring Meadows</li><li>Fixed being unable to shoot in Free aim while exploring levels due to worn triggers</li><li>Lune and Monoco no longer spawn in same place during end of theirs Level 6 relationship quests if they are completed without going to camp</li><li>If at camp you pick “remember the objective”, then quickly choose to "go to sleep" and immediately after press "leave", the screen no longer goes black</li><li>You can no longer trigger the "Discovering the truth" cutscene in Old Lumière a second time in a row, splitting the party forever with only Verso and Maelle in it.</li><li>Update to rolling credits</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Killing Floor 3 Has A July Release Date After Unexpected March Delay]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/killing-floor-3-has-a-july-release-date-after-unexpected-march-delay/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/killing-floor-3-has-a-july-release-date-after-unexpected-march-delay.1185210/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/killing-floor-3-has-a-july-release-date-after-unexpected-march-delay/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Killing Floor 3 was initially set to release on March 25, 2025, but the game was <a href="https://wccftech.com/killing-floor-3-release-date-delayed-to-later-in-2025/">delayed</a> with no new release date announced weeks before that initial date. On Friday, Tripwire Interactive finally announced the new release date for <strong>July 24, 2025,</strong> making it a four-month delay.</p>
<p>In a press release announcing the new date, Tripwire Interactive's creative director, Bryan Wynia, marked the "<em>incredible</em>" support the studio has seen from fans of the Killing Floor series, since Tripwire delayed Killing Floor 3 specifically to respond to feedback from the series' community.</p>
<p>It was after a closed beta for Killing Floor 3 that didn't go as well as Tripwire would have wanted, which largely influenced the decision to delay the game another four months. Tripwire noted in its March statement confirming the delay that the feedback from that closed beta made the team realize it had "<em>missed the mark</em>."</p>
<p>"<em>Since delaying the launch of Killing Floor 3, we've dedicated the additional development time to responding to the community's feedback, ensuring the next chapter in the much-loved cult action/horror franchise lives up to our shared</em> <em>vision,</em>" Wynia said in today's press release.</p>
<p>"<em>The support from fans has been incredible, and with the new July 24th release date in sight, we're thrilled to bring that vision to players not just at launch, but through the continued support of new features and content that is a hallmark of our studio.</em>"</p>
<p>Part of Tripwire's method of responding to community feedback during the delay period has been consistently updating fans on the progress the team made through the game's <a href="https://forums.tripwireinteractive.com/index.php?forums/kf-3-news-announcements.2333661/">official forums</a>. Updates and changes to the UI, design, and artwork have been posted nearly every few days since the delay was announced on March 7, 2025.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Killing Floor 3 Release Date Now Set for July]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/killing-floor-3-release-date-july-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/killing-floor-3-release-date-now-set-for-july.1185207/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/killing-floor-3-release-date-july-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Tripwire Interactive has announced a brand new&nbsp;<em>Killing Floor 3&nbsp;</em>release date, with the multiplayer-focused zed-slaying shooter now set to release in the summer.</p>

<p>Back in March (which is also when the game was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/killing-floor-3-release-date" rel="nofollow">originally intended to launch</a>), Tripwire <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/killing-floor-3-delayed-2025" rel="nofollow">delayed</a>&nbsp;<em>Killing Floor 3</em>, citing a need to implement changes suggested by user feedback from the game's closed beta test.</p>

<p>In a new press release, Tripwire says that its development team has been using the extra time from the delay to address that feedback, and so a new release date of July 24th has been set. In the interim, Tripwire says it will release more dev diaries showing off the ways in which it's implementing player suggestions.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/killing-floor-3-release-date-2025-sewer.jpg?itok=8xGqch3e 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/killing-floor-3-release-date-2025-sewer.jpg?itok=6wE4ABx3 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Killing Floor 3&nbsp;</em>now has a July release date.</figcaption></figure><p>Tripwire creative director Bryan Wynia says the studio has been taking the additional time to ensure&nbsp;<em>Killing Floor 3&nbsp;</em>"lives up to our shared vision", i.e. the one shared by the studio and the fans.</p>

<p>The new release date also means that pre-orders for the three different versions of&nbsp;<em>Killing Floor 3</em>&nbsp;- Standard, Deluxe, and Elite - are once again live.</p>

<p>In case you're wondering, pre-ordering the Standard version nets you the game, plus a weapon skin set, a weapon trinket, and a player card. The Deluxe edition gets you all of that plus two extra Shadow Agent skin sets, a Nightfall Supply Pass, and 1000 Nightfall Creds.</p>

<p>Finally, the Elite edition includes everything outlined above, but ups the Nightfall Supply Pass total to four and the Creds total to 3000. Pre-orders for all three editions are available across PC and consoles right now.</p>




<p>If you're wondering what&nbsp;<em>Killing Floor 3&nbsp;</em>is, it's the third mainline installment in the&nbsp;<em>Killing Floor&nbsp;</em>series of multiplayer-focused first-person shooters. Taking place 70 years after&nbsp;<em>Killing Floor 2</em>, it sees you and your buddies teaming up to take down an army of slavering monsters known as Zeds.</p>

<p><em>Killing Floor 3&nbsp;</em>launches for <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1430190/Killing_Floor_3/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/killing-floor-3/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/killing-floor-3/9pfzlckhc1vm" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a> on July 24th.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honkai: Star Rail version 3.3 update ‘The Fall at Dawn’s Rise’ launches May 21]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/honkai-star-rail-version-3-3-update-the-fall-at-dawns-rise-launches-may-21</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/honkai-star-rail-version-3-3-update-%E2%80%98the-fall-at-dawn%E2%80%99s-rise%E2%80%99-launches-may-21.1185201/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/honkai-star-rail-version-3-3-update-the-fall-at-dawns-rise-launches-may-21<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Embark on the final campaign of Flame-Chase Journey.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The version 3.3 update for <em><a title="Games > Honkai: Star Rail [39 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/honkai-star-rail">Honkai: Star Rail</a></em>, dubbed “The Fall at Dawn’s Rise,” will launch on May 21, developer <a title="Companies > miHoYo [195 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mihoyo">miHoYo</a> announced. <span id="more-964197"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the update, via miHoYo:</p><blockquote><p>In this update, Trailblazers will join forces with Chrysos Heirs as they enter a pivotal chapter of Flame-Chase Journey. In addition, this version also introduces two new playable characters—Hyacine and Cipher—each bringing their own compelling backstory and distinct flair to the unfolding saga. A wide array of limited-time events will also offer fresh excitement and challenges throughout the journey.</p><p>In the previous chapter, the Chrysos Heirs reclaimed the Coreflame of “Death” and “Reason.” Now, in Version 3.3, Trailblazers will stand alongside Chrysos Heirs for the final battle of Flame-Chase Journey—confronting the Sky Titan. According to ancient records, Aquila is a hundred-eyed giant bird. With the sky as its eyelids, it controls the cycles of dawn and dusk. In addition, “Echo of War: Glance of Twilight” will also become available in Version 3.3, offering players brand-new challenges and generous rewards.</p><p>While the people of Amphoreus pursue Era Nova from within their world, the geniuses beyond it are watching closely. At the end of Version 3.2, Madam Herta’s data spirit entity successfully reached the Vortex of Genesis. As the Geniuses delve deeper into their investigation, the root of Amphoreus’s tragedy will gradually come to light and its fate will intertwine with that of the galaxy. Yet, how the story unfolds from here is for players to discover in the chapters ahead.</p><p>In the upcoming story, a new 5-star character, Hyacine, will join the Trailblazer’s team as a vital ally. As the chief physician of the Twilight Courtyard, Hyacine has long been responsible for the medical care of Flame-Chasers. Her ideal is to leave a footnote for ordinary people on the blank pages of epic history, doing her utmost to heal every soul in need. A Wind character following the Path of Remembrance, Hyacine excels at restoring HP for the entire team and boosting overall survivability. By using her abilities and summoning Little Ica, she provides continuous healing to her allies. When she unleashes her Ultimate, Hyacine not only restores HP to all teammates but also increases their Max HP. Additionally, whenever any ally (excluding Little Ica) is attacked or voluntarily sacrifices their own HP, Little Ica will consume its own HP to automatically heal them. Beyond healing, Little Ica can also attack enemies, and the damage Little Ica deals scales with the amount of healing performed.</p></blockquote><!-- AD: content -->
        <div id="carousel_964199"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p>Another new 5-star playable character, Cipher, is one of the earliest Chrysos Heirs to join the Flame-Chase Journey alongside Aglaea and Tribbie. As the inheritor of Trickery’s divine authority, Cipher has wielded this power for years, yet her movements remain elusive and unpredictable. No one has ever been able to pin down her true whereabouts… A Quantum character following the Path of Nihility, Cipher specializes in targeting the enemy with the highest Max HP on the field, placing them under a special status that records all damage they take. She can also actively switch the marked target, allowing for adaptive tactics mid-battle. When allies attack the marked enemy, Cipher performs a follow-up attack. Upon using her Ultimate, she unleashes additional True DMG based on the total recorded damage!</p><p>Additionally, the limited 5-star characters The Herta and Aglaea will have their return in the first and second halves of the Version 3.3 warp event, respectively. Their formidable assistance makes them invaluable allies for your future journeys.</p><p>Beyond the compelling story, Version 3.3 also introduces a variety of exciting events that promise brand-new gameplay experiences. Registration is now open for the Penacony Speed Cup Spheroid Racing Tournament, where top racers will gather for high-stakes showdowns! Trailblazers will take the wheel of their Spheroid Racers and engage in thrilling speed challenges. In addition, thanks to Giovanni’s investment, Legend of the Galactic Baseballer: Demon King is officially launching! Based on player feedback during the previous beta test, the official release retains the raccoon’s quest for the bat while adding a host of exciting new elements that bring fresh challenges to the battlefield.</p></blockquote><p><em>Honkai: Star Rail</em> is available now for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,433 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [23,099 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://hsr.hoyoverse.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">client download</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/honkai-star-rail" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/honkai-star-rail/id1599719154" target="_blank" rel="noopener">App Store</a>, and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.HoYoverse.hkrpgoversea&amp;hl=en_US&amp;gl=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Play</a>.</p><p>Watch a new trailer and special program below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/honkai-star-rail/may-9-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Version 3.2 Update “The Fall at Dawn’s Rise” Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Version 3.3 Trailer - &quot;The Fall at Dawn's Rise&quot; | Honkai: Star Rail" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e8suWXD8jso?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="【崩壊：スターレイル】 Ver.3.3PV 「夜明け前に迎える崩落」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b86rpnKULps?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe title="3.3 버전 PV: 「여명이 틀 무렵의 추락」 | 〈붕괴: 스타레일〉" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aHIJUHT3yks?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《崩坏：星穹铁道》3.3版本PV：「‍在黎明升起时坠落」" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OSnfCNqPDMI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Version 3.3 Update “The Fall at Dawn’s Rise” Special Program</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Honkai: Star Rail Version 3.3 &quot;The Fall at Dawn's Rise&quot; Special Program" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9jYw7s4QWxg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『崩壊：スターレイル』Ver.3.3「夜明け前に迎える崩落」 予告番組" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/R-xKvF_Fpxo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Korean</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="〈붕괴: 스타레일〉 3.3 버전 「여명이 틀 무렵의 추락」 프리뷰 스페셜 프로그램" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jezh84BsDyw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="《崩壞：星穹鐵道》3.3版本「在黎明升起時墜落」預覽特別節目" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O3lP72ndsTM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Death Stranding 2: On the Beach goes gold]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-goes-gold</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-goes-gold.1185192/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-goes-gold<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Anticipated sequel ships on June 26.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Death Stranding 2: On the Beach [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach">Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</a></em> has gone gold, meaning that development is complete and the game is ready for mass production, developer <a title="Companies > Kojima Productions [554 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kojima-productions">Kojima Productions</a> boss <a title="People > Hideo Kojima [145 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/people/hideo-kojima">Hideo Kojima</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/HIDEO_KOJIMA_EN/status/1920751826485260335" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-964286"></span></p><p>The Kojima Productions team celebrated the achievement with a group photo:</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/DS2-Gold_05-09-25_Team.jpg"></a></figure><p>Here is an overview of the game, via publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,990 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Embark on an inspiring mission of human connection beyond the UCA.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Sam—with companions by his side—sets out on a new journey to save humanity from extinction.</p><p>Join them as they traverse a world beset by otherworldly enemies, obstacles and a haunting question: should we have connected?</p><p>Step by step, legendary game creator Hideo Kojima changes the world once again.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Unique and Explorable World</strong> – The large <a title="Genres > Open-World [627 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/open-world">open-world</a> environments of <em>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</em> are full of secrets to be found. They are also incredibly varied and pose unique challenges to navigate.</li><li><strong>Exciting and Adaptable Combat</strong> – Whether facing human foes or otherworldly entities, a range of options are at your disposal. Do you go in aggressively, sneak around enemies to achieve your goals, or try to avoid danger altogether? How you approach these situations is up to you.</li><li><strong>Compelling Story and Characters</strong> – Following on from the events of <em><a title="Games > Death Stranding [57 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/death-stranding">Death Stranding</a></em>, this new story follows Sam on a fresh journey. Expect the unexpected.</li><li><strong>Social Strand Gameplay</strong> – Your <a title="Genres > Action [2,718 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s can affect how other players interact with the game’s world, and vice-versa. Make sure you leave your mark.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,433 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> on June 26. If you missed it yesterday, watch the latest gameplay footage <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/05/death-stranding-2-on-the-beach-hands-on-previews-dualsense-wireless-controller-announced">here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GoldenEye 007 finally slides into the Video Game Hall of Fame]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/goldeneye-007-finally-slides-into-the-video-game-hall-of-fame</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/goldeneye-007-finally-slides-into-the-video-game-hall-of-fame.1185186/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/goldeneye-007-finally-slides-into-the-video-game-hall-of-fame<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Staying Onatopp of things.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rare</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>More games have been added to the Video Game Hall of Fame, including Rare's brilliant first-person shooter <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/goldeneye-007-review">GoldenEye 007</a>.</p>
<p>The Strong Museum's <a href="https://www.museumofplay.org/exhibits/world-video-game-hall-of-fame/">Video Game Hall of Fame</a> was established back in 2015, with a goal to recognise individual electronic games, from arcade to console and everything in between, which have "enjoyed popularity over a sustained period and have exerted influence on the video game industry or on popular culture and society in general".</p>
<p>And now, having missed out on being inducted to this Hall of Fame back in 2023, N64 classic GoldenEye 007 has finally made the cut.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The 7 Worst Game Franchise Revivals Ever - Bad Sequels, Worse Reboots" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4ZUj5JRey6E?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The 7 Worst Game Franchise Revivals Ever - Bad Sequels, Worse Reboots</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4ZUj5JRey6E?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4ZUj5JRey6E?autoplay=1" title="The 7 Worst Game Franchise Revivals Ever - Bad Sequels, Worse Reboots">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The 7 Worst Game Franchise Revivals Ever - Bad Sequels, Worse Reboots. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4ZUj5JRey6E" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"GoldenEye surpassed its contemporaries to become the third best-selling game on the Nintendo 64, beaten only by <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/super-mario-64">Super Mario 64</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mario-kart-64">Mario Kart 64</a>," the <a href="https://www.museumofplay.org/games/goldeneye-007/">Video Game Hall of Fame team wrote of GoldenEye 007</a>.</p>
<p>"Critics lauded it as the premier example of a first-person shooter to succeed on a console rather than a PC, and it is still considered one of the best multiplayer experiences ever produced on a Nintendo system."</p>
<p>This is honestly one of my favourite games of all time. When it was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/goldeneye-007-comes-to-nintendo-switch-online-xbox-game-pass-this-friday">released on Xbox in 2023</a>, I spent quite a bit of time besting my family in the multiplayer. And, thanks to the introduction of Achievements with this Xbox release, I can still look back at my unforgiving gaming dominance with pride... (see below)</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Victoria Phillips Kennedy</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Other games inducted into the Strong Museum's World Video Game Hall of Fame this year are Defender, Quake and Tamagotchi. Since its conception in 2015, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-first-video-game-hall-of-fame-selects-its-inaugural-class">49 games have been added to the Strong Museum's World Video Game Hall of Fame</a>. These include classics such as the original Tomb Raider, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-ocarina-of-time-is-finally-in-the-video-game-hall-of-fame">The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time</a>, Tetris and Pac-Man.</p>
<p>As for the future of James Bond games, Hitman developer <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/io-interactive">IO Interactive</a> has one in the pipeline, known for now as Project 007. This release will <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hitman-developer-says-james-bond-game-will-hopefully-be-the-start-of-a-trilogy">kick off a new trilogy of games</a>, IOI hopes. </p>
<p>For more, our Ed spoke to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/banjo-kazooie-sequel-chances-better-than-zero-but-not-much-says-composer-grant-kirkhope">GoldenEye 007 composer Grant Kirkhope earlier this year</a>. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Return to Silent Hill Movie Will Be a 'Faithful Adaptation' of Silent Hill 2, Cineverse Promises]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/return-to-silent-hill-movie-will-be-a-faithful-adaptation-of-silent-hill-2-cineverse-promises</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/return-to-silent-hill-movie-will-be-a-faithful-adaptation-of-silent-hill-2-cineverse-promises.1185168/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/return-to-silent-hill-movie-will-be-a-faithful-adaptation-of-silent-hill-2-cineverse-promises<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">According to Cineverse, which has acquired the rights for the third Silent Hill film in the U.S. when it releases later this year, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/return-to-silent-hill"><u>Return to Silent Hill</u></a> will be a "faithful adaptation" of the original Silent Hill 2's story. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Silent Hill is one of the best video game franchises, period, and Christophe Gans did a phenomenal job capturing the atmosphere of the games once again with Return to Silent Hill,” Cineverse executive director of acquisitions, Brandon Hill, told <a href="https://variety.com/2025/film/news/return-to-silent-hill-theatrical-release-1236391288/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Variety</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Director Christophe Gans added: “I am delighted to partner with Cineverse, which has shown a genuine understanding of fanship. Return to Silent Hill is an adaptation created out of deep respect for a true masterpiece of a game, Konami’s iconic Silent Hill 2. I hope fans will enjoy and be fulfilled with the experience this new film has to offer."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The film's plot will feel familiar to anyone who played the original <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/silent-hill-2-2001"><u>Silent Hill 2</u></a> or the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/silent-hill-2-remake"><u>2024 Bloober remake</u></a>. It follows "James (Jeremy Irvine), a man broken after being separated from his one true love (Hannah Emily Anderson). When a mysterious letter calls him back to Silent Hill in search of her, he finds a once-recognizable town transformed by an unknown evil" and "terrifying figures both familiar and new." <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/return-to-silent-hill-new-movie-from-original-silent-hill-director-confirmed"><u>It was unveiled in October 2022</u></a>, but it took until May 2024 for us to get our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/return-to-silent-hill-movie-first-look-pyramid-head"><u>first glimpse at Return to Silent Hill's version of Red Pyramid Thing</u></a> — AKA Pyramid Head.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/silent-hill"><u>Gans' first Silent Hill movie</u></a>, based loosely upon the first game, follows mother Rose as she searches for her missing daughter, Sharon, in a town where it snows during summer. Although the screenplay was written by Oscar-winning writer Roger Avary, who wrote Pulp Fiction, we thought Gans' first adaptation was a mediocre 5/10, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2006/04/21/silent-hill-2"><u>writing</u></a>: "So there we have it. Our worst fears realized yet again. The video game-to-film genre has endured more than a decade of mediocrity. Silent Hill is probably the smartest and best-looking video game adaptation yet, it just doesn't have much else going for it. After all, video games are about entertainment, and Silent Hill is a chore to sit through."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Silent Hill 2 (2024) Review Screens</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The second movie, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/movies/silent-hill-revelation"><u>Silent Hill: Revelation</u></a> — which was not directed by Gans but instead by Michael J. Bassett — was based loosely on sequel <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/silent-hill-3">Silent Hill 3</a>. That secured a less favorable 4.5 in our review: "Silent Hill Revelation 3D is an inferior sequel in every way, shape and form, a horror sequel that fails to either intrigue or scare, and one that just might have killed the franchise cold-dead."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Return to Silent Hill is slated to release sometime later this year, with Cineverse promising a "wide theatrical release in America."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter, critic, columnist, and consultant. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3><div data-cy="objectcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="article-subtitle">Not yet available for streaming.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>