<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 22:55:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Offloads Surface Pro (512GB SSD, X Plus) at a New Low, Black Friday Starts Early]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/microsoft-offloads-surface-pro-512gb-ssd-x-plus-at-a-new-low-black-friday-starts-early-2000639973</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-offloads-surface-pro-512gb-ssd-x-plus-at-a-new-low-black-friday-starts-early.1338781/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The laptop versus tablet debate has frustrated professionals for years, forcing compromises between portability and productivity that never quite satisfy either need. Microsoft’s Surface Pro eliminates that choice by delivering a fantastic <strong>2-in-1 device that excels as both a full-powered Windows laptop and a sleek tablet</strong> you can hold with one hand.</p>
<p>Early Black Friday deals have hit the entire Surface Pro lineup hard with discounts ranging from 20 to 30% across all configurations including LCD and OLED displays, Snapdragon X Plus and X Elite processors, and every storage and RAM combination. This <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5092/">particular model with a Snapdragon X Plus processor, 16GB RAM, and 512GB storage has dropped from $1,199 to $949</a>, which marks an all-time low for Microsoft’s latest Copilot+ PC.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5092/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>The Snapdragon Revolution Changes Everything</h2>
<p>The <strong>Snapdragon X Plus processor with 10 cores</strong> marks a major change in Windows computing: It offers performance that competes with Apple’s M3 chip while using less power. This ARM-based design runs cooler and more efficiently than traditional Intel or AMD processors. It <strong>leads to a 14-hour battery life</strong>&nbsp;which makes all-day work sessions feasible without searching for outlets.</p>
<p>The integrated NPU processes AI tasks locally on your device: It <strong>handles Copilot+ features without sending your data to the cloud,</strong> and keeps your information private and providing quick responses. Native ARM apps perform well and Microsoft’s updated emulation layer ensures that most x86 Windows software runs smoothly even if it hasn’t been recompiled. With 16GB of RAM, you can multitask easily across many browser tabs, multiple Office documents, and background apps.</p>



<p>The 1<strong>3-inch touchscreen boasts sharp 2880 x 1920 resolution</strong> at a comfortable 3:2 aspect ratio which shows more vertical content than typical 16:9 laptop displays. This extra height is important for reading documents, browsing the internet or working in spreadsheets as vertical space determines how much information is visible without scrolling. The display <strong>allows for use with the Surface Pen</strong> which is great for drawing, note-taking, and precise editing tasks.</p>
<p>The <strong>512GB SSD provides ample storage for your operating system</strong>, applications and files, so you won’t have to constantly manage cloud storage or external drives. This capacity easily holds your entire photo library, video projects, and software installations with extra space for future needs. Its read and write speeds far surpass traditional hard drives, making file transfers, app launches, and boot times feel instantaneous.</p>



<p><strong>Copilot+ PC features</strong> change how you interact with Windows through useful AI capabilities, rather than mere gimmicks: Windows Studio Effects improve video calls by enhancing lighting, canceling background noise and automatically blurring distractions without needing additional software or manual tweaks. <strong>Real-time translation offers subtitles in 44 languages during</strong> video calls or streaming, bridging language gaps for international work or entertainment. <em>Cocreate</em> generates artwork from text descriptions or image prompts, giving creative professionals quick tools for brainstorming and developing concepts.</p>
<p>The <strong>unique kickstand adjusts to almost any angle</strong> from nearly flat for digital art to steep angles ideal for watching movies on a plane tray table. This flexibility allows the Surface Pro to fit whatever space you’re using rather than forcing you to work within rigid laptop constraints. Fast charging through the proprietary Surface Connect port or standard USB-C adds options for power sources, and the 65W power supply can quickly recharge the battery during short breaks.</p>
<p>At a price of $949, this configuration offers fantastic value for early Black Friday shoppers seeking premium build quality and advanced AI features.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5092/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/microsoft-offloads-surface-pro-512gb-ssd-x-plus-at-a-new-low-black-friday-starts-early-2000639973]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia Kicks Off Black Friday, Asus RTX 5070 Ti Now at Its Lowest Price Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nvidia-kicks-off-black-friday-asus-rtx-5070-ti-now-at-its-lowest-price-ever-2000639954</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-kicks-off-black-friday-asus-rtx-5070-ti-now-at-its-lowest-price-ever.1338778/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Gaming has evolved into a visual spectacle where every frame matters and your graphics card is the engine that powers those immersive experiences. The Asus TUF gaming <strong>GeForce RTX 5070 Ti</strong> brings professional-grade performance to your setup, and right now, early Black Friday deals are making this powerhouse more accessible than ever.</p>
<p>Amazon <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4923/">has slashed the price from $999 to $849 which marks an all-time low</a> for this recently launched GPU that’s built on <strong>Nvidia’s cutting-edge Blackwell architecture</strong>. This is your chance to future-proof your gaming rig with 16GB of blazing-fast GDDR7 memory and DLSS 4 technology that transforms how games look and perform.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5090/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>The Blackwell Revolution Comes to Your Desktop</h2>
<p><strong>Nvidia’s Blackwell architecture</strong> marks a real advancement in graphics processing. The <strong>RTX 5070 Ti uses that power with 16GB of GDDR7 memory</strong>&nbsp;which provides the bandwidth that modern games need. <strong>DLSS 4 revolutionizes gaming</strong> by using AI to generate frames intelligently. This allows you to increase ray tracing settings without seeing a drop in frame rates. The card runs at 2588 MHz in default mode and can reach 2610 MHz in OC mode. This gives you extra performance when you need it. These <strong>specs translate to smooth 1440p gaming at ultra settings and good 4K performance</strong> in most games.</p>
<p>Asus put a lot of thought into the <strong>cooling solution</strong>: They designed a 3.125-slot card with three Axial-tech fans that move a lot of air through a large fin array. The phase-change GPU thermal pad is a smart engineering choice. It lasts longer than regular thermal paste and keeps temperatures optimal, even during long gaming sessions that push the card hard. This design keeps your GPU cool and quiet, and avoid the loud noises that cheaper cards make under load. The extra slot width may seem like a compromise, but it is really an investment in durability. Cooler components last longer and maintain their performance over the years.</p>



<p>Durability is a priority with military-grade components that provide solid power delivery and a longer lifespan compared to standard designs: The protective PCB coating offers another layer of <strong>defense against moisture, dust, and debris</strong> that can cause short circuits. These features matter a lot, especially if you’re building a system you want to keep for several years.</p>



<p>Connectivity is also strong, with <strong>PCIe 5.0 support, multiple DisplayPort 2.1 outputs, and HDMI</strong> for maximum flexibility with monitors and VR headsets. The GPU Tweak III software allows you to control performance easily. You can adjust clock speeds, voltages, and fan curves without getting into complicated BIOS settings. Thermal monitoring helps you keep an eye on temperatures in different GPU areas.</p>
<p>At $150 off, this deal is a real value in a market where graphics card prices can often feel unrealistic.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5090/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nvidia-kicks-off-black-friday-asus-rtx-5070-ti-now-at-its-lowest-price-ever-2000639954]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem pre-orders now available]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/resident-evil-requiem-pre-orders-now-available</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/resident-evil-requiem-pre-orders-now-available.1338775/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Switch 2 Pro Controller and amiibo also announced.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Pre-orders for <em><a title="Games > Resident Evil Requiem [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/resident-evil-requiem">Resident Evil Requiem</a></em> are now available across <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,726 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,205 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [615 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,679 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3764200/Resident_Evil_Requiem/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/resident-evil-requiem-4ead6d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, <a title="Companies > Capcom [2,629 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/capcom">Capcom</a> announced. <span id="more-1003544"></span></p><p>The game will be available in the following editions:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Standard Edition</strong> ($69.99 / £64.99 / €79.99 / ¥8,990)</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/RE-Requeim-Pre-Orders_2025_10-29-25_SE.jpg"></a></figure><ul><li>A copy of the game (game-key card on Switch 2)</li><li>Pre-order bonus: “Grace’s Costume: Apocalypse” (This content may be made available at a later date. This costume will change Grace’s appearance only.)</li></ul><p><strong>Deluxe Edition</strong> ($79.99 / £74.99 / €89.99 / ¥9,990)</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/RE-Requeim-Pre-Orders_2025_10-29-25_DE.jpg"></a></figure><ul><li>A copy of the game (game-key card on Switch 2)</li><li>Five costumes including “Grace’s Costume: Dimitrescu”</li><li>Two filters including “Filter: Apocalypse”</li><li>Four weapon skins including “S&amp;S <a title="Companies > M2 [91 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/m2">M2</a>32 Weapon Skin: Apocalypse”</li><li>Two charms including “Charm: Mr. Raccoon”</li><li>“Audio Pack: Raccoon City Classic”</li><li>“Files: Letters from 1998”</li><li>Pre-order bonus: “Grace’s Costume: Apocalypse” (This content may be made available at a later date. This costume will change Grace’s appearance only.)</li></ul><p><strong>SteelBook Edition</strong></p><ul><li>Deluxe Edition contents</li><li>SteelBook</li><li>Limited edition lenticular card</li></ul></blockquote><p>Here is a look at the special editions and pre-order bonus items:</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Resident-Evil-Requiem_2025_10-29-25_001.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Resident-Evil-Requiem_2025_10-29-25_004.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Resident-Evil-Requiem_2025_10-29-25_006.jpg"></a></figure><p>Capcom will also announced the following updates:</p><blockquote><p><strong><em>Resident Evil</em> Generation Pack for Switch 2</strong> ($89.99)</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Resident-Evil-Requiem_2025_10-29-25_007.png"></a></figure><p>A special pack featuring <em>Resident Evil 7 Biohazard Gold Edition</em>, <em><a title="Games > Resident Evil Village [43 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/resident-evil-village">Resident Evil Village Gold Edition</a></em>, and the all-new <em>Resident Evil Requiem</em>. All three games ship on game-key cards.</p><p><strong><em>Resident Evil Requiem</em> Switch 2 Pro Controller</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Resident-Evil-Requiem_2025_10-29-25_010.jpg"></a></figure><p>A <em>Resident Evil Requiem</em>-themed Switch 2 Pro Controller will launch day and date with the game on February 27, 2026.</p><p><strong><em>Resident Evil Requiem</em> x amiibo</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Resident-Evil-Requiem_2025_10-29-25_013.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>Resident Evil Requiem</em> protagonist Grace Ashcroft will become <em>Resident Evil</em>‘s first-ever amiibo in summer 2026.</p><p><strong><em>Resident Evil Requiem</em> x <em><a title="Games > Fortnite [26 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a></em></strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/Resident-Evil-Requiem_2025_10-29-25_016.jpg"></a></figure><p>When you purchase <em>Resident Evil Requiem</em> through <a title="Companies > Epic Games [353 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store, you will receive special <em>Fortnite</em> items such as the Grace outfit after the game launches. More information will be announced at a later date.</p><p><strong><em>Resident Evil</em> Showcase</strong></p><p>A <em>Resident Evil</em> Showcase will be held in early 2026, which will dive deeper into all things <em>Resident Evil Requiem</em>.</p></blockquote><p><em>Resident Evil Requiem</em> is due out for PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, Switch 2, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3764200/Resident_Evil_Requiem/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/resident-evil-requiem-4ead6d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> on February 27, 2026.</p><p>Watch a new “Road to Requiem” video below.</p><h2><span>Road to Requiem</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Resident Evil | Road to Requiem" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SQODLCylKbM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="BIOHAZARD | Road to Requiem" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zIOFmOtZX3M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/resident-evil-requiem-pre-orders-now-available]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox sales continue to tank]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/809532/xbox-sales-continue-to-tank</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-sales-continue-to-tank.1338754/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Xbox sales have been tanking for a while now — and the story hasn’t gotten any brighter. Microsoft just released its Q1 2026 earnings and Xbox hardware revenue was down 29 percent year-over-year. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/716191/microsoft-q4-2025-earnings-revenue-profits-windows-xbox-gaming-surface">Last quarter</a>, it was down 22 percent. Down 29 percent in the first two quarters of 2025, down 42 percent in <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/30/24209519/microsoft-q4-2024-earnings-revenue-profits-windows-xbox-gaming-surface">Q4</a> of 2024… You get the picture.</p><p>As tariffs and inflation take their toll, Microsoft has <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/797023/circana-video-game-consoles-switch-2-tariffs">dramatically increased the prices</a> on its gaming hardware, with the Series X now starting at $599.99. Microsoft’s response has been to deemphasize the console and pursue an “<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/12/24067370/microsoft-xbox-playstation-switch-games-future-hardware">Xbox everywhere</a>” strategy. That has yielded some success on the content and services front, though revenue there was largely flat this quarter, only growing one percent year over year.</p><p>Microsoft would obviously like to see more growth there. The company has reportedly been pursuing dramatic <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/805280/microsoft-xbox-gaming-profit-targets-layoffs">30 percent profit margins</a> there, leading to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/25/24049050/microsoft-activision-blizzard-layoffs">layoffs</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/696877/xbox-perfect-dark-everwild-cancelled-the-initiative-layoffs">cancelled projects.</a> But the company’s outlook for Q2 isn’t much rosier. It expects Xbox hardware revenue to continue to decline, and content and services to continue low-single digits growth.</p><p>Microsoft did see hardware growth from Windows OEM and Devices, with revenue increasing a modest 6 percent year over year. The company stopped reporting Surface earnings separately, so it’s unclear how those devices are performing. They had been on a steady decline for several years.</p><p>It’s Azure and cloud services that remain the driving force behind Microsoft’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/716783/microsoft-4-trillion-market-cap-valuation">ascent</a>. The growth of its intelligent cloud services is substantial. Revenue increased 28 percent year over year to $30.9 billion, with Azure specifically growing 40 percent.</p><p>More broadly, Microsoft Cloud revenue was $49.1 billion, an increase of 26 percent from Q1 2025. The company’s cloud divisions and Azure have been growing steadily for several years now.</p><p>In total, Microsoft reported $77.7 billion in revenue for the quarter, up 18 percent from the same time last year. And its net income was $27.7 billion, up 12 percent. While those increases are largely driven by the company’s various cloud offerings, its productivity and business processes still account for a significant portion of its income ($33 billion).</p><p><em><strong>Update, October 29th</strong>: This article was updated with details from Microsoft’s earnings call.</em></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6NjA5MzU0"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Terrence O'Brien</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/809532/xbox-sales-continue-to-tank]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Florist sounds like a lovely, cosy game right up until its a survival horror about killer plants]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-florist-sounds-like-a-lovely-cosy-game-right-up-until-its-a-survival-horror-about-killer-plants</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-florist-sounds-like-a-lovely-cosy-game-right-up-until-its-a-survival-horror-about-killer-plants.1338736/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-florist_UyR6NLL.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-florist_UyR6NLL.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-florist_UyR6NLL.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-florist_UyR6NLL.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-florist_UyR6NLL.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-florist_UyR6NLL.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-florist_UyR6NLL.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-florist_UyR6NLL.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/the-florist_UyR6NLL.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Unclear Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Right, what do we have here, a new game called <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-florist">The Florist</a>, 'ey? About a woman delivering a beautiful flower arrangement to a lakeside town? Well, surely this is one of those wholesome, cosy games I've been hearing about! Nope! It is, in fact, a survival <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-horror-games">horror</a>, and not the kind that's trying to trick you like I just made a less than half-arsed attempt at.
</p>
<p>
Those opening couple of sentences weren't lies though, it really is about a woman making a flower delivery in a lakeside town (called Joycliffe). It's just that the town is also suffering from some kind of "lethal affliction" that appears to be of the floral variety. The town is covered in plants and petals of all sorts, this infection turning its inhabitants into almost literally green thumb monsters.
</p>
<p>
So far the reveal is just a bit of a tease, but I must admit I'm quite curious about its approach to horror. Nature is scary! Yet the ways this can be explored in films and games can often lean towards an apocalyptic absence of nature. Here, nature is the thing that is becoming dominant, a force that we're normally quick to kill. Horror is often the genre best suited for looking at the ways people interact with the world, so I'm hoping The Florist pulls it off.
</p>
<p>
Details are generally quite limited, but there are a few to be found on the game's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3152440/The_Florist/">Steam page</a>. The game uses my beloved fixed camera angle, something bigger budget games just seem to be too afraid of using these days. There's puzzles, there's gun-based combat, and perhaps controversially, unlimited inventory space.
</p><p>
Lastly, the world also apparently "grows and changes throughout the game." I think a good survival horror that uses fixed camera angles is one that should force you to get to know a space, so a space that changes and becomes uncertain sounds quite intriguing - if the devs can pull it off.
</p>
<p>
The Florist is currently expected to launch sometime in 2026.
</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-florist-sounds-like-a-lovely-cosy-game-right-up-until-its-a-survival-horror-about-killer-plants]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Next Fest’s Most Unlikely Breakout Only Requires A Fraction Of Your Screen And Attention]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/steam-next-fests-most-unlikely-breakout-only-requires-a-fraction-of-your-screen-and-attention-2000639943</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-next-fest%E2%80%99s-most-unlikely-breakout-only-requires-a-fraction-of-your-screen-and-attention.1338733/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Desktop Defender</em> is a confoundingly compelling mix of <a href="https://kotaku.com/fuck-me-i-cant-stop-playing-cookie-clicker-1847794400"><em>Cookie Clicker</em></a> and <a href="https://kotaku.com/castlevania-roguelike-vampire-survivors-steam-itch-io-1848402308"><em>Vampire Survivors</em></a>. The game sits in a little corner of your computer screen whether you’re emailing people for work or paying your bills for the month. The action consists of a tiny triangle shooting other blips that arrive from offscreen to destroy it. It levels up and earns loot, briefly interrupting your other work as you choose upgrades and look for synergies to help the lo-fi automated ship survive its hostile confines a little bit longer, or at least until you power down your PC. Indie developer Conrad Grindheim made it on a whim in just a month. It wound up being one of the 50 most downloaded games <a href="https://kotaku.com/steam-next-fest-october-2025-might-magic-yapyap-half-sword-2000637407">during the October 2025 Steam Next Fest</a>.</p> <p>“We launched the demo with 200 wishlists and I was hoping for maybe 20 concurrent players,” he told <em>Kotaku</em> over email. “When we reached 36 I was super happy because we had basically doubled our goal. Lo and behold…we ended up reaching over 1,500, landing us in the top 4 most played Steam demos, as well as getting a special commendation and a feature from Steam. To say that this was unexpected would be selling it short, but I could not be happier.”</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">1 week ago we had 3 players, today I got this e-mail.</p> <p>Thank you all so much ♥️ <a href="https://t.co/AcG7Q9ltXi">pic.twitter.com/AcG7Q9ltXi</a></p> <p>— Conradical (@ConradicalGames) <a href="https://twitter.com/ConradicalGames/status/1980339314740588692?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><em>Desktop Defender</em> is part of a recent wave of Steam games that mostly play themselves while you do other stuff on your desktop. Some, like <em>Bongo Cat</em>, are minimally interactive. Others, like<em> Bao Bao’s Cozy Laundromat</em>, can be more complex. While some are just fun distractions, others play off the satisfaction many people innately get from watching a fictional measure of progress continually tick upwards. Grindheim wanted<em> Desktop Defender</em> to be slightly more engaging.</p>

 <p>“I made <em><span>Desktop Defender</span>&nbsp;</em>because I really enjoyed this new wave of “screen sitting” idlers, but I hadn’t found one with more integrated long-term strategies,” he said. “I’m thinking more like <em>NGU Idle</em> or <em>Cookie Clicker</em>‘s endgame. In combination with the extra tactility that the shooting tower adds, I felt that I could really bring something new to the genre. To many, the appeal of these games is to see numbers go up while doing something else, but I feel there’s an extra section of the playerbase that also really enjoys strategizing over long periods of time.”</p>

 <h2>Turning idling PCs into productive escapes</h2> <p>Grindheim (who you may remember <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/indie-dev-files-dmca-takedown-against-his-own-game-as-dispute-with-publisher-continues/">trying to DMCA his own game</a> during a public spat with the publisher back in 2023) spends much of his time working on the monster-taming action-RPG <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2421080/Synth_Beasts/"><em>Synth Beasts</em></a> which was Kickstarted with over $20,000 in pledged funds earlier this year. But he also finds time to experiment with shorter releases to try to understand how popular genres and tastes are evolving on Steam. He worked on <em>Desktop Defender</em> solo for about a month, only purchasing some assets for music and icons while making the rest of the UI elements, characters, and enemies in-house.</p>

 <p>“The aesthetics are really inspired by <em>SNKRX</em>, and the gameplay mechanics as well to a certain extent, although the two games still feel very different,” he said. <em>SNKRX&nbsp;</em>uses the elements of <a href="https://kotaku.com/auto-chess-took-over-my-life-in-a-single-afternoon-1835710673"><em>Auto Chess</em></a> to reimagine the classic arcade game <em>Snake</em>, and is a precursor to games like <em>Vampire Survivors</em>. “I really enjoyed playing <em>Rusty’s Retirement</em> and I felt like combining something like that with my interest in games with synergistic loadout building (e.g. roguelikes or RPGs) would make for a super fun time.”</p>

  <p>Where<em> Vampire Survivors</em> demands your full attention, <em>Rusty’s Retirement</em>, in which you occasionally help robots automate a <em>Stardew Valley-</em>like farming sim operation, provides bite-sized bursts of problem-solving nestled neatly beside real-life productivity. “These games can offer a happy medium between not staring at a textbook for eight hours straight and the mental exhaustion that can come with constantly getting ourselves back into the productivity zone,” mental health researcher Natalie Coyle recently <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/27/arts/desktop-games-rustys-retirement.html">told <em>The New York Times</em></a>.</p>

 <p>It’s the natural evolution of brief, session-based buildcrafting grindfests like <em>Balatro</em> which conveniently let players accrue little nuggets of satisfaction while waiting in line at the store or while sitting on the bus during a commute. But instead of punctuating the mundane moments in our lives, games like <em>Desktop Defender</em> interrupt our existing work flows with extra layers of progress.</p> <h2>The game you play while queuing for other games</h2> <p>Think of them as Pomodoro timers that double as Tamagotchi pets you can min-max in-between Excel sheet macros and anxiety-inducing Slack alerts. “I envisioned myself playing an idle game between work sessions or while compiling my games and how fun it would be to have a strategic throughline through that,” Grindheim said.</p> <p>But <em>Desktop Defender</em>‘s 15 minutes of Steam fame also points to the changing ways people play and discover games as the market becomes more and more flooded with them. “You look at games like<a href="https://kotaku.com/megabonk-vampire-survivors-clone-steam-pc-2000627591"><em> Megabonk</em></a> and while they launched with a sizeable wishlist count, it punched miles above its weight,” he said. “I think we’re seeing that smaller games, if designed well, can achieve more than before if they get that spark of visibility.”</p> <p>Grindheim credits an unexpected micro-community that popped up around the game for helping give it an extra bump, in addition to events like Steam Next Fest. “Tons of players on our Discord server and in community groups are constantly discussing the game’s most optimal builds and there’s a social aspect to that,” he noted. “Because people can play <em><span>Desktop Defender</span></em> and other idle games while in queue for online games, I feel it slots perfectly into how people are playing nowadays.”</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/steam-next-fests-most-unlikely-breakout-only-requires-a-fraction-of-your-screen-and-attention-2000639943]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Revenue Falls $113M Year Over Year]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-revenue-q1-2026-drop-113m-year-over-year/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-revenue-falls-113m-year-over-year.1338730/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Microsoft says that Xbox hardware sales have gone down 29%, leading to a roughly $113 million revenue loss year over year. The news comes after, earlier in October, the company increased <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-raising-game-pass-ultimate-price-by-50-and-changing-tier-features/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the price of Game Pass</a> to much controversy.</p>



<p>Xbox, despite having some well-received titles recently like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ninja-gaiden-4-world-record-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ninja Gaiden 4</a> and The Outer Worlds 2, has had a rough time recently. Massive cancellations of Game Pass and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/costco-has-reportedly-decided-to-stop-selling-xbox-consoles/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">even removal from Costco</a> have not done well for the gaming team at Microsoft. Unfortunately, it seems like it has spread to its sales, as the company reports a 2% loss in total revenue.</p>



<h2 id="h-microsoft-reports-notable-drop-in-sales-for-xbox-compared-to-last-q1">Microsoft Reports Notable Drop in Sales for Xbox Compared to Last Q1</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Image via Microsoft </figcaption></figure>



<p>In the Fiscal Year 2026 (FY26) Q1 report from Microsoft, <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/Investor/earnings/FY-2026-Q1/press-release-webcast" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the company revealed</a> that Xbox did not reach the same heights as it did last Q1 for FY25. Having made $5.621 billion last Q1, the gaming subcompany went down to $5.508 billion, losing around $113 million. This also marks a 2% loss in total revenue, which is not great, but not too bad. The press release does mention the drop, stating,</p>



<p><strong>“Xbox hardware revenue decreased 29% driven by lower volume of consoles sold,”</strong> the company said. <strong>“Xbox content and services revenue increased 1% on a strong prior year comparable with growth in Xbox Game Pass and third-party content, offset in part by a decline in first-party content.”</strong></p>



<p>It’s important to note that the mentioned 1% increase comes from splitting content and services away from hardware, showing how each specific subsector is performing.</p>



<p>Whether Xbox can regain ground from its loss remains to be seen. It recently announced that Halo: Campaign Evolved is coming to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/halo-campaign-evolved-remake-playstation-announcement-xbox-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation</a>, continuing the company’s third-party movement forward. Xbox is planning a big year in 2026 with releases like Forza Horizon 6, Clockwork Revolution, and Fable. It’ll be interesting to see how it pans out and whether it can save face, regardless of how good its new games could be.</p>



<p>Overall, for Microsoft, the numbers aren’t bad as the company announced its operating income was up 24% to $38 billion while it saw a  12% total net income increase to $27.7 billion.</p>



<p>What do you think about the revenue drop for Xbox? Are you surprised by it? What do you hope Microsoft does to fix it? Let us know in the comments and on <a href="https://discord.gg/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the official Insider Gaming Discord</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Xbox, check out Microsoft’s plan for <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-xbox-games-every-platform-playstation/">gaming on different consoles</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-removes-dlc-discounts-for-xbox-game-pass-members/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the removal of DLC discounts</a>. Make sure to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our weekly newsletter</a> for more!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-revenue-q1-2026-drop-113m-year-over-year/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fear Effect 2: Retro Helix coming to PS5, Switch in 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/fear-effect-2-retro-helix-coming-to-ps5-switch-in-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fear-effect-2-retro-helix-coming-to-ps5-switch-in-2026.1338727/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Hana Tsu-Vachel returns.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Limited Run Games [218 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/limited-run-games">Limited Run Games</a>, in cooperation with <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,402 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>, will release <a title="Genres > Action [3,162 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,663 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Fear Effect 2: Retro Helix (2026) [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fear-effect-2-retro-helix-2026">Fear Effect 2: Retro Helix</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,726 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [28,490 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [17,905 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,679 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam in 2026, the company announced. Physical editions will be available for PlayStation 5 and Switch. <span id="more-1003483"></span></p><p>Originally developed by Kronos Digital Entertainment, <em>Fear Effect 2: Retro Helix</em> first launched for <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [48,869 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> on February 21, 2001. This is the first time it is being ported to new platforms.</p><p>Here is an overview of the sequel, via the box of its PlayStation packaging:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Delve into the colorful histories of the original cast of mercenaries and the extraordinary circumstances that brought them together in <em><a title="Games > Fear Effect (2025) [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fear-effect-2025">Fear Effect</a></em>. Discover what drives Hana Tsu-Vachel, the beautiful assassin whose specialty lies in the dealings of love as well as death; Royce Glas, the master counter intelligence operative who is haunted by his past; Jakob “Deke” Decourt, the cold-blooded killer driven by money and murder. And meet Rain Qin, a stunning new character and close companion of Hana with unparalleled beauty wrapped around a dark secret core.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>New Motion FX 3D technology allows for the most breathtaking anime ever on a gaming console.</li><li>Unparalleled interaction with 8 new environments for mindbending puzzles and intense action.</li><li>Enemies react with cunning Al as you try to obliterate them with an expanded arsenal of weaponry such as tasers and flame throwers.</li><li>Gameplay and cinematics stream seamlessly, eliminating load times even after death sequences.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Fear Effect 2 | Implicit Conversions/Limited Run Games Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9ZRSdou8ap4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/10/fear-effect-2-retro-helix-coming-to-ps5-switch-in-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Battlefield 6 Honeymoon Is Over]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-season-one-small-map-battle-royale-reactions-negative-review-ea-2000639948</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-battlefield-6-honeymoon-is-over.1338718/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><em>Battlefield 6</em> launched on October 10 to <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-steam-record-login-queue-multiplayer-download-issue-2000634042">huge player numbers on Steam</a> and a lot of momentum from a super successful and well-received open beta. It seemed like most people were excited for the game and its future. Now, just a little over two weeks later, <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-update-redsec-season-1-download-free-ea-ps5-steam-2000639598">the game’s first season and its battle royale mode have launched</a>, and for many online, the honeymoon is over.</p> <p>There’s no one single issue or change to blame for the angry fans and negative Steam reviews. Instead, it’s a mix of problems. Some fans are disappointed about colorful new skins and the battle pass, claiming it’s ruining the game’s launch vibes. Others are mad that the latest map added to <em>BF6</em>, Blackwell Fields, is yet again a fairly small map, and the new mode added in season one is tiny, too. And then there are the <em>Battlefield 6</em> players who hate the game’s new battle royale mode, which features a big ol’ map, and fear that it might pull resources from the main game and its classic modes.</p>

 <h2><em>Battlefield 6’s</em> season one battle pass and new skins</h2>   <p>Before<em> Battlefield 6</em> even launched, the topic of its cosmetics was a hot one. Many players, <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-crossover-skins-rick-morty-call-of-duty-1851786919">myself included</a>, were tired of devs and publishers shoving crossover skins and other ugly cosmetics into nearly every modern online game. And the <em>Battlefield 6</em> devs promised that the then-upcoming game wouldn’t go down that road. This whole skins saga became such a big deal that eventually, <a href="https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-skins-black-ops-7-blops-6-carry-over-battlefield-6-2000620379">Activision announced the upcoming <em>Call of Duty Black Ops 7</em></a> would not let players bring skins over from <em>Black Ops 6</em> in order to prevent the FPS from instantly being flooded with goofy crap.</p>

 <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6s-first-new-map-review-season-1-blackwell-fields-eastwood-update-2000638228">Now, with the launch of season one,</a> <em>BF6</em> players online have access to the game’s first new skins since launch, and the reaction has been mixed. Some find the skins far too colorful or argue they don’t fit the military vibes. There are also some new skins that can be used with every class, which has frustrated players as they fear it will make it hard to quickly identify different classes during combat. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield6/comments/1oi9wvl/they_made_the_system_override_skin_more_toned/">EA seems receptive to the feedback</a>, as at least one skin’s bright green details were toned down with the season one patch. Funnily enough, there are also some people who find the new skins boring and ugly, lacking any reason to chase after them via <em>BF6</em>‘s new battle pass. Trying to thread the needle with <em>BF6</em>‘s cosmetics is going to be a nightmare.</p>

 <p>Speaking of the battle pass, a lot of players aren’t happy with it, either. I get the feeling a lot of players online don’t like how it changes the vibes of the game. Now it feels like a real live-service shooter, something more akin to a modern<em> Call of Duty</em>, with ads encouraging players to buy the new battle pass, goals to chase, and limited-time rewards to unlock. And for some, this isn’t what they wanted. A highly rated post on the <em>Battlefield</em> subreddit is a screenshot of a Steam review saying: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Battlefield/comments/1oj8hzd/lool/">“This whole season 1 update feels like ad blocker stopped working.”</a></p>

 <h2><em>Redsec</em>, <em>BF6</em>‘s new battle royale mode, has a negative rating on Steam</h2> <p>The biggest new addition in <em>Battlefield 6′</em>s first season is <em>Redsec</em>, EA’s stab at a large-scale free-to-play battle royale game. Anyone can now download <em>BF6</em> <em>Redsec</em> and start playing the game’s new battle royale mode. The general consensus seems to be that <em>Redsec</em> is pretty good. I’ve not played much of it yet, but it does seem fun enough. However, over on Steam, the new <em>Redsec</em> mode <a href="https://x.com/BFBulletin/status/1983566801913925824">has an overall negative review rating</a>. But a lot of people aren’t mad about the mode; instead, they’re upset about how it has been integrated into <em>BF6</em>.</p>

 <p>You see, the new battle pass brought with it weekly challenges. And some of these challenges require players to hop into <em>Redsec</em> to complete them. This isn’t going over well with some <em>BF6</em> fans who feel like EA is requiring them to play something they never wanted in the first place. While <em>BF6</em> lets you reroll a limited number of challenges, for those never planning on playing <em>Redsec</em>, it means they have to burn all their rerolls on challenges for a mode they have zero interest in. This has led to a lot of anger around <em>Redsec</em> and the new battle pass, too.</p>

 <p>And then there’s the issue of <em>Redsec</em>‘s map. It’s very, very big. This isn’t a bad thing at all. In fact, <em>Battlefield 6</em> players have been longing for bigger maps since the open beta. Battlefield Studios and EA promised bigger maps were coming. And then season one arrives, and the first new map added post-launch is a barren, bland oil field that feels overly cramped and isn’t what a lot of the online community wanted. Meanwhile, the free-to-play <em>Redsec</em> features a massive map. As you might expect, this hasn’t gone over well with many players clamoring for bigger maps.</p> <h2>The new map and mode are small and not very good</h2>  <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6s-new-map-is-very-bad-2000639647">The game’s first new map is Blackwell Fields</a>, a not-very-big level that is currently not much fun to play. You’ll likely get killed over and over again by snipers or blown up by AA guns if you try to fly around its limited skybox. Running around on foot is a chore, and the new map lacks any real landmarks or memorable spaces. And for many who were waiting for a bigger map to arrive post-launch, Blackwell Fields has shaken their confidence in the game’s future.</p> <p>A new mode, Strikepoint, also added in season one, is essentially<em>&nbsp;Call of Duty</em>‘s popular seek-and-destroy. Two teams of four compete in multiple rounds to capture an objective. And once you die, that’s it until the next round. This kind of mode can be a lot of fun in shooters like <em>Counter-Strike.</em> But in <em>Battlefield 6</em>, Strikepoint feels out of place. The game already supports some smaller, infantry-focused modes, like team deathmatch and king of the hill. I’m not sure it needed yet another small mode. In a franchise known for big and epic warfare, the new small map and tiny mode feel like misfires and have disappointed many players.</p>

 <p>It might be easy to write off a lot of this as just a small but vocal group of players online being angry about a video game. And that’s certainly part of what’s happening here. But anecdotally, I know some folks who play <em>BF6</em> and aren’t very online. These people don’t troll Reddit or share angry social media posts. Yet even they aren’t sure about this new season.&nbsp; None of them seem to like Blackwell Fields, the new mode, or how the battle pass was implemented. And most of them are confused about <em>Redsec</em>, as they already have a few battle royales they play from time to time. The last thing they needed was one more.</p> <p>So, where does that leave<em> Battlefield 6?</em> There will be those who claim the game is dying and done. That’s not the case. It still has a huge playerbase across console and PC who are playing the game daily. But it’s clear that the mood has shifted. <em>Battlefield 6</em> is no longer a just-launched FPS harkening back to<em> Battlefield 3</em> and older shooters. Instead, it’s now an active live-service game with multiple components, battle pass options, and even a full in-game cosmetic store. That might mean more money for EA, but it also means a lot more criticism and pushback from players. The question now is: Will EA be willing to change its roadmap for <em>BF6</em> to appease these angry players, or will the publisher move forward as planned?</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-season-one-small-map-battle-royale-reactions-negative-review-ea-2000639948]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Runescape's Future May Be Radically Reshaped After Fan Vote]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/runescapes-future-may-be-radically-reshaped-after-fan-vote/1100-6535811/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/runescapes-future-may-be-radically-reshaped-after-fan-vote.1338694/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535811">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The daily Treasure Hunter has been a part of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/runescape/" data-ref-id="5000-5022">Runescape</a> since 2014, and some of the game's players openly resent it as a pay-to-win feature that diminishes the experience for fans who don't utilize it. Jagex has been exploring its options for the feature, and now the developer is leaving Treasure Hunter's fate in the hands of the fans.</p><p>Jagex has started <a href="https://secure.runescape.com/m=poll/treasure-hunter-poll" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">an online poll</a> that will determine if Treasure Hunter will stay in Runescape. If 100,000 players vote to remove Treasure Hunter, it will be completely deleted from the game alongside 225 direct XP and skilling items that are related to it. That would leave the game with only two purchasable items: Bonus XP with capped storable limits per skill and cosmetics "with a more grounded visual identity."</p><p>"Today marks one of the most important moments in Runescape history," reads a statement on the site. "We are proposing a new future for the game led by integrity, where your achievements are based on merit, and the vast experiences offered within Gielinor can truly shine.This is an era-defining shift for Runescape where YOU will cast the deciding vote--just as we did for the birth of Old School."</p><p>Jagex has previously laid out <a href="https://secure.runescape.com/m=news/mtx-experiments-what-weve-learned" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">the results of its experiments with Treasure Hunter</a>, and earlier polling that indicated it was a valuable resource for "time-poor" players. To appeal to those players, Bonus XP will remain in the store, but the new skill caps for storable XP are meant to encourage players to engage in the regular gameplay rather than simply buying all of their experience.</p><p>If the vote goes forward to remove Treasure Hunter, Jagex stated that it will "invest in a year-long Integrity Roadmap that addresses the heart of issues that have long held Runescape back--from UI, to onboarding, to dailyscape, revisiting the combat status quo and beyond. We'll also be looking at the balance of our XP progression too, ensuring each skill is still a satisfying experience to level up with a significant reduction in MTX-relative skilling items."</p><p>To place a vote, players will have to be logged in as their Runescape characters. The voting period will run until November 12, and nearly 40,000 players have already voted in favor of removing Treasure Hunter.</p><p>Outside of the main game, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/old-school-runescape/" data-ref-id="5000-486787">Old School Runescape</a> recently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/old-school-runescape-is-more-popular-than-ever-breaks-concurrent-player-record/1100-6533697/" data-ref-id="1100-6533697">broke its concurrent-user record</a> with 241,016 players.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/runescapes-future-may-be-radically-reshaped-after-fan-vote/1100-6535811/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CEO of GTA 6 publisher Take-Two is surprisingly hesitant about AI usage for entirely unsurprising reasons]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ceo-of-gta-6-publisher-take-two-is-surprisingly-hesitant-about-ai-usage-for-entirely-unsurprising-reasons</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ceo-of-gta-6-publisher-take-two-is-surprisingly-hesitant-about-ai-usage-for-entirely-unsurprising-reasons.1338664/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-6-main-characters-hot-7.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rockstar Games / Take-Two Interactive</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Because that sacred line called profit must always go up, we are seeing more and more game studios announce their intention to incorporate various forms of AI tech. PUBG publisher Krafton just recently referred to themselves as an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pubg-and-inzoi-publisher-krafton-declares-itself-an-ai-first-company-placing-ai-at-the-centre-of-problem-solving">AI-first company</a>, the big wigs up top at EA are <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/inside-ai-divide-roiling-video-game-giant-electronic-arts-2025-10">reportedly pushing for it hard</a>, it is, seemingly, unfortunately, inevitable. Which makes Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick's comments on it ever so slightly surprising - but only slightly, we'll get back to that.
</p>
<p>
Zelnick made an appearance at <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/10/28/can-ai-create-next-grand-theft-auto-take-two-interactive-ceo-says-no.html">CNBC's</a> Technology Executive Council Summit on Tuesday, where he was asked about his thoughts on the "promise" of AI in game development. Right off the bat, the CEO reminds us that he is still the CEO of publicly-traded company, as he did make it clear he's not a "naysayer" of AI. But he does actually seem to understand how limited it currently is, and crucially, for him and Take-Two, how risky it is for their intellectual property.
</p>
<p>
"We have to be really careful not to step on other people's intellectual property, and we don't ours stepped on," Zelnick explained. "As you know, if you create intellectual property with AI, you can't protect it. We're in the intellectual property business, we care about our rights, we care about other people's rights, and we have to protect what we make."
</p>
<p>
That's where the comments aren't very surprising, as it just seems like Zelnick is the very rare CEO that doesn't want to force AI right this very second because it risks their precious IP, IP that includes giants like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto-vi">GTA</a> and NBA, as well as still very popular series like Borderlands.
</p><p>
This is where the surprising element comes in! Zelnick went on to note how in the event that AI has no constraints, he thinks whatever you'd make wouldn't be very good. "Could we push a button tomorrow and create an equivalent to the ‘<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto">Grand Theft Auto</a>’, and the marketing plan, and here it is? The answer is no. A, you can’t do that yet, and B, I am of the view that you wouldn’t end up with anything very good. You end up with something pretty derivative."
</p>
<p>
Zelnick goes on to say how AI is just big datasets, and defines them as "backward-looking," as in it's always working off of something else that's already been made rather than looking forward. Perhaps his most surprising line is this one: "there is no creativity that can exist, by definition, in any AI model, because it is data driven."
</p>
<p>
I'd like to be very clear that I really do think Zelnick is currently only hesitant about implementing the use of AI at scale because of his aforementioned concerns over IP. I'm just hoping (yes, a useless thing to do here) that maybe some other CEOs and shareholders might see the GTA guys holding off and think maybe we should too. Can't wait for that to not happen!

</p>

        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ceo-of-gta-6-publisher-take-two-is-surprisingly-hesitant-about-ai-usage-for-entirely-unsurprising-reasons]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders: Everything You Need To Know Before Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-pvpve-extraction-maps-embark-studios-2000639945</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/arc-raiders-everything-you-need-to-know-before-launch.1338658/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><i>Arc Raiders</i>, the next game from <i>The Finals </i>developer Embark Studios, launches on October 30, 2025 on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC.</p> <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/ark-raiders-embark-studios-server-slam-2000637325"><i>Arc Raiders</i> Is So Good I’m Worried It Will Completely Take Over My Life</a></p> <p>As a PvPvE extraction shooter, <a href="https://kotaku.com/ark-raiders-embark-studios-server-slam-2000637325"><i>Arc Raiders</i></a> sees you setting out to explore and loot the remains of a fallen civilization still under control of a lethal artificial intelligence system known as “Arc.”</p> <p>The game has already been in the hands of players via a few technical tests and the reaction has been overwhelmingly positive. Still, you might not know much about <i>Arc Raiders</i> or extraction shooters as a genre, and as someone who’s pretty excited about the game, I’d like to do what I can to make it as approachable as possible for potential players. So let’s break down everything you need to know about this game ahead of its release, from how many maps the game provides to the overall flow of your average match.</p>

  <h2>It’s you versus them, and also <i>them</i></h2> <p><i>Arc Raiders</i> is a PvPvE extraction shooter. That means you and a team of up to three are fighting real humans as well as the game’s computer-controlled bots, but your main “goal” is to leave the map alive within a certain time–which in theory you could do without firing a single shot. You can leave via multiple elevators on the map, each of which have a timer on them. You can also find or buy keys to escape hatches that make for an even speedier getaway.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-leaper-server-slam-pvpve-extraction-2000637774">Check Out This Really Awesome Moment From <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ Server Slam</a></p> <p>With both people and patrolling enemy AI in the mix, there are a wide variety of emergent possibilities as different players, each with their own playstyles and agendas, intersect with the threats on the map. It makes for an intense game in which you need to think a few steps ahead of each action you take, and always keep an escape route in mind should you realize you’ve gotten yourself in over your head.</p>

   <p>Get out alive, and you keep everything you came in with, plus whatever you found. Die, and you’ll lose everything. You do have access to a “safe pocket” in your inventory, however, where you can stash a lone precious item to make it to the other side should you perish.</p>

 <p>As you explore the maps, you’ll find countless places to loot. Abandoned cars, file cabinets and desk drawers from empty offices and facilities, storage containers, and much more.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000639951" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639951"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639951">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>You’ll also have a variety of quests you can take on, some of which ask you to loot specific items, while others ask you to take down some of the game’s bots, or “Arc” as they’re referred to in-universe. Quest progress is maintained even if you die, and you’ll earn XP after each match which can be used to improve your character’s stats, so death is not a total loss.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-server-slam-embark-studios-ferro-2000638324"><i>Arc Raiders’</i> Dev Addresses Graphics Downgrade, Enemy Difficulty, And More Ahead Of Release</a></p> <p>When you’re not out on the field scavenging for parts from a fallen world, you’ll be at home in “Speranza,” your hub for launching games, crafting, and trading. <i>Arc Raiders</i> has a thorough crafting system; you can build weapons, gadgets, restorative items such as shield rechargers and bandages, and more. You can also trade with a variety of NPCs.</p>

 <p>You als0 have a pet rooster named Scrappy who’s always happy to see you after a match, giving you some minor crafting supplies when you return. If you’ve had a bad streak of losses, Scrappy will give you extra crafting materials as a consolation for your repeat losses.</p> <p>Zoom out, and we see the loop of the game: Venture out onto the maps, find what you can, avoid or engage in battles with humans or machines, return home and build better gear for your next run.</p> <h2>A closer look at <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ maps on launch</h2> <p><i>Arc Raiders</i> launches with four main maps, each set in a post-apocalyptic Italy with their own unique difficulty levels and points-of-interest. These maps are: Dam Battlegrounds, Buried City, the Spaceport, and the Blue Gate. There’s also a practice range and a mysterious location called “Stella Montis” which we don’t know a whole lot about ahead of release.</p>

 <p>The maps offer up a nice level of variety. Dam Battlegrounds, with its thick swamps and forests, makes for some brutal, <i>Predator</i>-esque battles and chase scenarios.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000639952" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639952"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639952">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Buried City is a smaller, more urban setting with some excellent sightlines across the tops of its roofs (there are going to be some intense sniper battles here, I can already tell).</p> <figure id="attachment_2000639946" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639946"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639946">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>The Spaceport is another large map. My time on this map during a preview event was cut short due to, well, some very aggressive players. It’s very pretty though!</p>

 <p>Lastly, the Blue Gate is a gorgeous, mountainous map with tons of rolling hills that makes for some excellent battles with other players. It’s easily the toughest map, however, with aggressive Arc presence. There are also some lovely, labyrinthine mazes of steel and concrete under the surface to get lost in.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000639947" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639947"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639947">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Dam Battlegrounds is perhaps my favorite at the moment. As someone who prefers stealthy tactics, having bushes and trees to fall back to and hide in works well with my style. But I’d be lying if I said hunting down other players in the mountainous terrain of the Blue Gate didn’t give me a rush.</p> <h2>Which is worse, machines or other players?</h2> <p>The titular “Arc” come in <a href="https://arcraiders.wiki/wiki/ARC">a variety of forms</a>. With threats ranging from the different drone types who survey the ground below for human threats, to smaller patrolling orbs and little spiders (or “Ticks” as the game calls them) that monitor the insides of abandoned buildings, you’ll have to keep your eyes peeled. And they’re not afraid to just insert themselves into a skirmish with players, so don’t be surprised if you get swarmed by some once they see or hear you trading shots.</p>

   <p>There are also larger threats. The spider-like Leapers can, as the name implies, leap across incredible distances in their pursuit. There’s also the Queen, which often guards precious loot, particularly on the Dam Battlegrounds map.</p>   <p>These machines are resilient and aggressive in their desire to eliminate human threats, and you’ll have to place your shots well to destroy vulnerable parts and take them down.</p> <figure id="attachment_2000639950" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639950"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639950">© Gif: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Speaking of those human threats, you also have other players to contend with, who pose a challenge equal to their skills with the game and the quality of their gear. Kill a human and a flare launches up into the air, letting just about anyone nearby know that a fight just went down and there’s gear for the taking.</p> <p>Without universal objectives for every player, extraction shooters can make for some truly unexpected encounters with other humans. And admittedly, it can feel a little unfair when someone kills you from an unexpected hiding place.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-embark-extraction-virgil-watkins-interview-2000639879">I Asked <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ Design Director If Camping Makes Me A Bad Person</a></p> <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-embark-extraction-virgil-watkins-interview-2000639879">Speaking with <i>Kotaku</i></a>, <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ design director Virgil Watkins said that the game is designed in such a way that “you should always have time to understand and react to what is happening to you.” With a longer time-to-kill (TTK) than most games in the genre, the game is designed to give you time to react. On combat with other players, Watkins said:</p> <blockquote><p>On even footing, the way TTK is balanced, if you’re full health and full shields, and so am I, and you attack me first, there’s a very solid chance that I will probably be able to back away, disengage, and do something to mitigate that situation. We really like when our fights have a lot of back and forth rather than just instantaneous [death].</p></blockquote> <p>Each map is also full of opportunities to hear other players nearby. Players make noticeable sounds not only while walking or running, but also when breaking into loot caches, tripping security cameras and metal detectors in abandoned interiors, scaring birds in the wild who take flight, and attracting attention from Arc. All of these can signal to you that another player is nearby, or give your presence away to someone else.</p>

 <p>This all complicates any approach to stealthily moving through a map. But it also means that you can set up some solid ambush opportunities by keeping your ears open for nearby threats, especially with the generous hiding spots on the game’s maps.</p> <h2>Is <i>Arc Raiders</i> too hardcore?</h2> <figure id="attachment_2000639896" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639896"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639896">© Screenshot: Embark Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>I’ve long been <a href="https://kotaku.com/extraction-shooter-dmz-tarkov-cycle-battle-royale-1850287778">a fan of the extraction shooter genre</a>. It brings together a variety of different game systems in a unique way that makes for an unpredictable and irresistible experience. But I get that the genre is not everyone’s cup of tea, especially given how lethal and mean it can be. Losing all of your gear can be a painful setback that isn’t easy to bounce back from. Embark Studios is aware of this and has built <i>Arc Raiders</i> to be a more approachable take on an otherwise hardcore genre.</p>

 <p>“Approachability was a key design tenet,” Watkins told me during our interview. Maintaining quest progress even after defeat, earning crafting supplies from Scrappy, and having multiple ways to extract means that it’s very doable to plan your way to victory at your own pace while also having a solid safety net to fall back on should you lose.</p> <hr> <p>Defeat is a crushing experience in an extraction shooter. But <a href="https://kotaku.com/ark-raiders-embark-studios-server-slam-2000637325">as I’ve said before</a>, those deep lows make for exhilarating highs when you come out alive from a tense battle or manage to get away with a sweet amount of loot.</p> <p>Ahead of release, however, we’ve only gotten a taste of <i>Arc Raiders</i>’ maps, its arsenal, and its threats. How the full experience will evolve over time remains to be seen, but based on my time with the game during its technical previews, I’m eager to see what wild, unexpected moments will happen out there in post-apocalyptic Italy.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/arc-raiders-pvpve-extraction-maps-embark-studios-2000639945]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Worst COD League Game Mode is Finally Being Removed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/worst-cod-league-mode-finally-removed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-worst-cod-league-game-mode-is-finally-being-removed.1338655/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Call of Duty League 2026 season is shaping up nicely now that the full schedule and running order have been revealed. Next year, the Call of Duty League will go to <strong>three countries</strong> in an unprecedented global tour that takes the CDL further than ever. It was also revealed that, <strong>thankfully</strong>, Control is being removed from the CDL rotation and will be replaced with an all-new mode.</p>



<p>Control was never awful, but the slow tempo, limited map pool, and tricky mechanics have long stood in the way of the mode being a complete success with fans of the COD League. It became suffocating during the 2025 CDL season when it was confined to just <strong>two maps</strong>.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-what-mode-is-replacing-control-in-the-cdl">What Mode is Replacing Control in the CDL?</h2>



<p>Control is officially being replaced after <strong>many years </strong>by Overload, a brand-new mode released alongside Call of Duty: Black Ops 7. In Overload, players are forced to contend with dynamic objectives, rapid respawn timers, wider map compatibility, and much clearer win conditions, all wrapped up in a mode that’s not too different from Capture the Flag.</p>



<p>The 2025 CDL season wrapped a few months ago, and now that it is dead and gone, so too is Control.</p>



<p>Despite being a staple of the COD League since 2018, the popularity of the mode declined, and quite drastically so in recent years. It was a mode that didn’t accommodate too much strategy, and it was ultimately something too repetitive to be hugely enjoyable</p>



<p>Overload goes the other way entirely, revealing positive results in tests and drawing nice feedback from the fans that’s sure to make it a winning formula when the CDL 2026 season goes live on December 5.</p>



<p>In some social circles, Overload has been dubbed ‘the most CDL-ready mode in years’, given that it perfectly accommodates the competitive flow that users expect from the COD League.</p>



<p>Do you think Overload will be a nice reset to the COD League formula going into the CDL 2026 season? Let me know what you’re thinking on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-league-2026-going-to-eu-uk-usa/">CDL is headed back to the UK and France</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/worst-cod-league-mode-finally-removed/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rare NES Platformer 'Little Samson' Is Coming To Switch In 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/rare-nes-platformer-little-samson-is-coming-to-switch-in-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rare-nes-platformer-little-samson-is-coming-to-switch-in-2026.1338646/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"The Wildest Adventure of Them All!" returns</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>Limited Run Games has announced that it's bringing NES side-scrolling platformer <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/little_samson">Little Samson</a> to the Switch in 2026. The reveal took place during the company's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QK5Ow9zHA4U">10th anniversary stream</a>.</p>
<p>Originally released in 1992 for the NES and directed by former Capcom designer Shinichi Yoshimoto (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/strider">Strider</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/megadrive/ghouls_n_ghosts">Ghouls 'n Ghosts</a>), Little Samson sees you controlling one of four characters — the eponymous Samson, a dragon called Kikira, the golem Gamm, or a mouse called K.O.</p>
<p>Each character controls a little differently and has different abilities — Kikira can breathe fire, for example, while Samson can climb walls and throw bells. Outside of the first four stages, which act like tutorials, you can swap which character you control at any point during the game. There are 20 stages to beat, with a true final boss that's only accessible if you beat the game on Normal difficulty.</p>

<p>In more recent years, Little Samson has become something of a collector's item. It's infamously one of the more-expensive NES games out there, with copies going for hundreds (if not thousands) of dollars online.</p>
<p>Well, now that won't be a problem, as Limited Run Games' Carbon Engine port will make it more accessible to all. Amazingly, we actually asked LRG's Josh Fairhurst about Little Samson when <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/how-limited-runs-new-engine-respects-the-legacy-of-classic-games">we interviewed them way back in 2022</a>, and here's what he had to say then:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"It’s super high on games I want to do but no one knows where the rights are. We reached out to Taito and they said “They might be with the owner.” So we found the owner (who was really hard to find) and he said “I don’t know who has the rights.” So now we’re basically at a dead end. Who has the rights to Little Samson? No idea."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We're glad the team made something work!</p>
<p>Though it's worth highlighting that Limited Run Games has come under fire in recent months due to delays on physical products, some items being below-standard, and NES cartridges that may damage your console. Josh also spoke to our sister site <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/features/interview-werve-certainly-made-mistakes-limited-runs-boss-on-winning-back-the-trust-of-the-community">Time Extension more recently about those issues</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Are you looking forward to Little Samson on Switch? Ever played it before? Let us know in the comments</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:130013,181825,178795 @ 1761777928 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/rare-nes-platformer-little-samson-is-coming-to-switch-in-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Team Behind One Of 2017’s Most Underrated Games Is Back With Another Banger]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battle-suit-aces-review-impressions-chef-brigade-trinket-2000639931</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-team-behind-one-of-2017%E2%80%99s-most-underrated-games-is-back-with-another-banger.1338640/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>2017 was one of the all-time great years for video games, with major tentpole games like </span><i><span>Super Mario Odyssey</span></i><span>, </span><i><span>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</span></i><span>, and </span><i><span>Persona 5 </span></i><span>dominating GOTY conversations. So if you missed out on some of the hidden gems of that year, I wouldn’t blame you. </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/battle-chef-brigade-the-kotaku-review-1820617722"><i><span>Battle Chef Brigade</span></i></a><span> is one of those precious games that might have gotten lost in the shuffle, and Trinket Studios’ match-three/brawler/cooking game still holds up in 2025. However, the studio didn’t just try and make lighting strike twice with its latest project that’s out now on PC, PS5, and Switch. </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces </span></i><span>is a much different game than its predecessor, but it’s no less stylish, endearing, and compelling.</span></p> <p><span>I want to rely on some easy lexicon to describe </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces</span></i><span>, but I fear calling it a deckbuilder might give you the wrong impression. The game’s strategic battles are played with a deck of cards, each representing a different member of its mech-piloting crew, but these conflicts are less about getting mired in the mechanical complexities of individual cards than they are solving a puzzle with a randomized set of tools. Each card pulls from a different set of colored energies that replenish each turn to unleash attacks on the opposing team, and they all have different attack patterns on the game’s 5v5 field. So card placement on the board is just as important as your deck composition, and can be the difference between gaining the upper hand in a match or being outplayed.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <p><span>Firepower isn’t enough to win every time, though, and that’s where secondary effects and synergy come into play. Each pilot has additional perks, such as how Felix, the carefree white-haired hottie whom I’ve been lusting after my whole playthrough, is able to unleash a more powerful attack after his teammates destroy a certain number of enemy units. Yan’s mech is able to pierce through enemies, meaning it can fire a beam through an opposing card while also directly hitting their ship, which is similar to attacking your foe’s Life Points directly in a game of </span><i><span>Yu-Gi-Oh</span></i><span>. If you can destroy an enemy ship, you automatically win a duel. You don’t need a piercing ability to do it, as leaving any of the five spaces on the field empty leaves you and your enemies vulnerable to a direct attack. So, having units that can attack multiple spaces or really take advantage of an opening is a pretty reliable strategy, but more often than not, your foes will have more cannon fodder to put between your crew and their ship.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000639933" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639933"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639933">© Trinket Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p><span>At first, I didn’t quite see the depth of </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces</span></i><span> until I started playing around in the simulations on my ship that would give me only a few cards and challenge me with something like winning the fight it set up in one turn. These typically required me to take advantage of passive perks in order to set off a chain of attacks that relied on precise positioning and an order of operations to activate. I could read the card descriptions, such as the explanation of Daciana’s passive ability to proc a free attack every time one of her allies destroyed an enemy, but seeing the cards in action is what made the game click for me. These plays are why I’m more inclined to describe </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces</span></i><span> as a turn-based strategy game rather than a deck builder, because you only have a handful of units, and the game doesn’t make you create decks of dozens of cards with a ton of minutiae to memorize. Once you see a lot of these characters playing off each other on the field, those bespoke mechanics naturally weave themselves into your strategies without the game becoming too overwhelming.</span></p>

 <p><span>In the five or so hours I’ve put into </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces</span></i><span> so far, the game has pretty gently eased me into its whole deal, and the simple but satisfying card battles are only one slice of it. Those cards have names and faces, and the crew you’ll recruit into your deck is a big reason the game is so breezy. </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces </span></i><span>stars Heathcliff, the captain of a starcraft called the USS Zephyr. In his spaceflight adventures, he and his crew meet several other mech pilots who are all typically game to join their cause as they investigate ancient cosmic secrets. Recruiting these characters gets you a new card for your deck, but it also puts another misfit on your ship. They chat with you, but also with each other, so there’s a constant sense of camaraderie and community between the group. Thus far, everyone’s pretty likable, and I’m interested to see their relationships grow not only with me as the player, but with each other, as well.&nbsp;</span></p>

 <figure id="attachment_2000639932" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639932"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639932">© Trinket Studios / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p><span>These relationships are elevated by </span><i><span>Battle Suit Aces</span></i><span>’ incredible character art and best-in-class voice acting. The anime-inspired art style looks straight out of classic mech anime like </span><i><span>Gundam </span></i><span>and </span><i><span>Evangelion</span></i><span>, though its chipper tone helps differentiate it from the latter. Everyone is hot and wearing a plug suit, so there’s something for everyone here. The game is full of memorable performances from some talented voice acting veterans, and I’ve really enjoyed listening to their interactions between duels, which help give the whole thing an authentic classic anime feel.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><i><span>Battle Suit Aces </span></i><span>has a lot to offer without ever getting too in the weeds that it becomes overwhelming. Much like </span><i><span>Battle Chef Brigade</span></i><span>, it manages to hit the sweet spot between tactical and approachable without ever veering too far into one or the other. Its skill expression is vast, its characters are easy to love, and it marries both sides of its world in a way that keeps me playing for just one more match. I’m looking forward to seeing where the USS Zephyr’s crew takes me as our journey through space continues.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battle-suit-aces-review-impressions-chef-brigade-trinket-2000639931]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty League 2026 is Going To Europe, UK, and USA with All-New Format]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-league-2026-going-to-eu-uk-usa/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-league-2026-is-going-to-europe-uk-and-usa-with-all-new-format.1338637/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Call of Duty League’s grand reveal has just taken place for the 2026 season, and fans are immensely excited. The new season starts on December 5, and in the months that follow, the CDL 2026 season will greet fans in three countries. Majors are set to take place in the United States, England, and France, all wrapping up with a grand COD Champs event in <strong>Las Vegas</strong>.</p>



<p>Plenty of changes are coming for the new season, including the first 10-team Major, the return of Minor tournaments, and beefed-up Challengers opportunities at <strong>every LAN event in the season</strong>.</p>



<h2 id="h-cdl-2026-schedule-looks-insane">CDL 2026 Schedule Looks Insane</h2>



<p>The <a href="https://callofdutyleague.com/en-us/news/2026-season-announcement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Call of Duty League 2026</a> schedule is already running wild. It confirms my <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-league-return-to-europe-and-uk-2026/">earlier exclusive reports</a> that the COD League is coming to the United Kingdom, as well as hosting a Major in Paris, France. It also confirms the placement of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cod-champs-2026-hosted-faze-las-vegas/">COD Champs in Las Vegas</a>, which I exclusively revealed earlier this year.</p>



<p>Here’s the schedule for the 2026 Call of Duty League:</p>



<ul>
<li>Opening Weekend: December 5 – 7</li>



<li>Major I (Dallas, Texas): January 29 – February 1</li>



<li>Major II (DreamHack UK): March 27 – 29</li>



<li>Minor I: April 24 – 26</li>



<li>Major III (DreamHack Atlanta): May TBC</li>



<li>Minor II: June 5 – 7</li>



<li>Major IV (Paris, France): June 25 – 28</li>



<li>COD Championship (Las Vegas, Nevada): July 16 – 19</li>
</ul>



<p>Major III at DreamHack Atlanta will be a Pro-Am event, and the Minor tournaments will feature teams <strong>outside </strong>the core CDL structure, as will Major II in Birmingham, UK.</p>



<p>It has already been too long since the end of the last season, during which OpTic Texas claimed the top spot and won the first back-to-back COD Champs in Call of Duty esports history. The team would then go on to win at the Esports World Cup in Riyadh, solidifying a spot in the history books.</p>



<p>The team is set to host Major I in Dallas, Texas, at the end of January – will the winning streak continue on home turf?</p>



<p>Let me know what you think about the CDL 2026 season schedule on the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming esports, stay tuned to our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/esports/">latest news feed</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-league-2026-going-to-eu-uk-usa/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy CEO Steps Down Following FBC: Firebreak's Sales Flop]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/remedy-ceo-steps-down-following-fbc-firebreaks-sales-flop</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-ceo-steps-down-following-fbc-firebreaks-sales-flop.1338631/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"Our first multiplayer product launch was technically successful."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Remedy Entertainment's CEO has resigned, leaving the new CEO of the developer of Control and Alan Wake to reassure investors after weak sales of FBC: Firebreak left the company significantly lowering its revenue expectations for the year and writing off the game's development costs.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In its quarterly earnings report issued today, Remedy revealed that it recognized a €14.9 million ($17.4 million) impairment charge representing most of the development costs as well as purchased publishing and distribution rights for FBC: Firebreak.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In total, Remedy's revenue decreased 32% year-over-year, to €12.2 million ($14.2 million). Remedy says this was largely driven by lower development fees coming in than last year at this time, during which it received revenue from Annapurna related to development work it did on Control 2. Remedy also revealed that it was revising its revenue expectations for the year: while previously Remedy expected revenue and operating profit to increase year-over-year and be positive, it now expects revenue to increase, but its operating profit to decrease and be negative. No exact numbers were shared.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Alongside this, CEO Tero Virtala has stepped down after nine years in the position. He is succeeded in the interim by board chairman Markus Mäki, who has stepped down from his chairman role and been replaced by Henri Österlund.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In comments by Mäki shared with investors, he stated that while Remedy would continue "working on features which enhance player value" and would keep true to its shared roadmap for Firebreak, the studio has moved development resources elsewhere going forward. Mäki also attempted to reassure investors that Firebreak was not a total loss:</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We have also found positive sides from FBC: Firebreak," he said. "Our first multiplayer product launch was technically successful in a cross-platform environment, and our publishing team has built capabilities which support the releases of our future self-published titles."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">FBC: Firebreak was Remedy's first ever self-published game, and while the studio claims it technically succeeded, it also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/remedy-admits-fbc-firebreak-underperformed-commercially-we-were-unsatisfied">admitted last quarter</a> that it "underperformed" on Steam and that the company was "unsatisfied" with its commercial reception. In today's earnings, Remedy stated that Breakpoint improved the game's sales only "marginally."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">We <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/fbc-firebreak-review">gave FBC: Firebreak a 6/10</a>, saying that it was a "compelling co-op shooter that, despite its good looks, doesn't have the depth to keep things interesting long-term."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/remedy-ceo-steps-down-following-fbc-firebreaks-sales-flop]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield REDSEC Launches to 'Mostly Negative' Steam Reviews as Battlefield 6 Players Push for Battle Pass Changes and Bigger Maps]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-redsec-launches-to-mostly-negative-steam-reviews-as-battlefield-6-players-push-for-battle-pass-changes-and-bigger-maps</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-redsec-launches-to-mostly-negative-steam-reviews-as-battlefield-6-players-push-for-battle-pass-changes-and-bigger-maps.1338628/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">“This is not why I bought Battlefield 6.”</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">EA just introduced its new, destructive take on battle royale with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-redsec">Battlefield REDSEC</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/battlefield-6">Battlefield 6</a> base game players are already slamming it with “Mostly Negative” Steam reviews.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">PC users who head to Steam to check out the standalone Battlefield experience, which <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-redsec-launches-alongside-battlefield-6-season-1-with-battle-royale-gauntlet-and-portal-modes-heres-everything-you-need-to-know">launched across PC and consoles for free yesterday</a>, will be met with a flood of negative <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3028330/Battlefield_REDSEC/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam reviews</a> across the board. At the time of this piece’s publication, just 35% of REDSEC Steam user reviews were positive, with positive reviews in all languages fairing just slightly better at 39%. Both measurements result in a dark red, Mostly Negative label.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">A wave of negativity for Battlefield’s latest crack at battle royale arrives as Battlefield 6 players continue to express their dissatisfaction with the premium experience. Calls for changes to the base game reached a boiling point with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-season-1-trailer-highlights-blackwell-fields-and-eastwood-maps-ahead-of-next-weeks-launch">the launch of Season 1</a> yesterday, and now, criticism is spilling into REDSEC.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Although Battlefield 6 and REDSEC exist as separate multiplayer offerings, both EA and Battlefield Studios games share unlocks tied to many challenges, cosmetics, and battle pass unlocks. Where this has evolved into a problem is how one experience might affect another, with many Battlefield 6 players complaining of weekly challenges that require them to play battle royale.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I wouldn't hate it so much if I wasn't forced to play it for challenges in the main game,” one <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/SirDoombox/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>negative Battlefield REDSEC Steam review</u></a> says. “But I am. So I do.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“This is not why I bought Battlefield 6,” they add.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Oh, but you just can reroll the challenges!" another <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561197986653939/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">negative review</a> says. "Yeah and 3 of them are sill for the BR because they are pushing it hard on people that would not touch it even once..."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Other PC players agree that challenges granting large amounts of Battlefield 6 battle pass XP shouldn’t be tied to another experience, but dissonance isn’t the only thing tanking REDSEC Steam reviews. Some base game players are using Valve’s digital storefront to air out grievances related to multiplayer map sizes.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Battlefield REDSEC Launch Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Early Battlefield 6 adopters have called for larger multiplayer maps as far back as the August beta tests, with the October 10 launch only adding fuel to the fire, as launch locations failed to live up to expectations for the community. At least a few negative Steam reviews even praise REDSEC’s exclusive battle royale map, Fort Lyndon, with their frustrations mostly summed up with one question: Why does the free-to-play game get the map sizes that premium players are asking for?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Oh wow a nice big map with lots of POIs and flanks,” another <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/idiedonetime/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>negative REDSEC review</u></a> says. “If only we could get something like this for the main game.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It's trying to be too much all at once,” another <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/JC_3223/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Steam user review</u></a> adds. “The map in this Battle Royale is so good it's criminal that it's not being used for Conquest right now.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As Battlefield 6 players aim to leave their mark with REDSEC Steam reviews, there are plenty of comments actually related to the new standalone experience itself, too. Many are positive, applauding how BF Studios blends classic Battlefield mechanics with other popular battle royale experiences, like Call of Duty: Warzone. Launch also ushered in a spike in activity, with <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/2807960/charts/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Steamdb</u></a> recording a 24-hour peak of 549,766 Battlefield 6 players yesterday.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">REDSEC, which encompasses Gauntlet and Portals modes in addition to its battle royale mode, is getting love in the Battlefield community, but there is still a general feeling that the experience is incomplete. Specifically, it’s the lack of a solo queue option and battle royale fatigue that many are calling out – both in negative and positive reviews.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“No solo Mode... When will they learn the overwhelming majority of players play solo?” one <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/koiruus/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>negative review</u></a> asks. “It doesn't feel good to play with randoms against premade coordinated squads.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Fun update, the battle pass is not half bad,” a <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/ZedAway/recommended/3028330/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>positive review</u></a> adds. “Only problem with me is not having a solo battle royal mode.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">REDSEC is just 24 hours into its time in the public’s hands. Seasonal updates will continue to offer shared experiences between REDSEC and Battlefield 6. Season 1 launched yesterday, introducing the new Blackwell Fields map for multiplayer, with more mid-season maps and guns set to follow in November and December.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">EA has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-recently-patched-conquest-mode-to-make-the-matches-shorter-the-community-complained-and-now-the-developers-have-reversed-the-decision">addressed fan feedback</a> in the past, with the latest update <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-won-battlefield-6-fans-rejoice-as-ea-tones-down-bright-colors-on-monster-energy-skin">introducing fixes for a controversial green skin</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/flashbang-battlefield-6-lighting-is-so-bright-that-players-feel-like-they-have-to-fight-the-sun">some of the bothersome lighting effects</a> that have distracted players since launch. In the meantime, some players have been <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-6-engineers-are-becoming-in-game-artists-instead-of-capturing-the-objective">content simply using their time to draw on walls with the Engineer repair tool</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance writer with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/battlefield-redsec-launches-to-mostly-negative-steam-reviews-as-battlefield-6-players-push-for-battle-pass-changes-and-bigger-maps]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Talking Point: When Did 'Good Enough' Become Good Enough For Pokémon?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-when-did-good-enough-become-good-enough-for-pokemon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/talking-point-when-did-good-enough-become-good-enough-for-pok%C3%A9mon.1338610/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="85a947ad7c8ab"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/85a947ad7c8ab/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Gemma Smith / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Over the weekend, we republished our reader-ranked list of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-pokemon-games-of-all-time">all the Pokémon games</a> after everyone had had a chance to spend some quality time with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Legends: Z-A</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-what-review-score-would-you-give-pokemon-legends-z-a">vote accordingly</a>.</p>
<p>That's 22 mainline games by our count. The entries at the top of the table probably won't surprise you, as the inventiveness and sheer novelty (and nostalgia) of earlier entries dominate the higher ranks, although it may surprise you to see OG <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/pokemon_red_and_blue">Red/Blue</a>/<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gameboy/pokemon_yellow_version_special_pikachu_edition">Yellow</a> outside the top 10.</p>
<p>However, scrolling down from low to high, one thing becomes immediately obvious: the Switch generation hasn't been a great one for Pokémon.</p><div><figure data-videoid="2LcP6TZzqhM" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2LcP6TZzqhM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2LcP6TZzqhM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2LcP6TZzqhM?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed635c59kiywrp&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>837k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>The Pokémon Company's accountants would beg to differ, I'm sure. ZA <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/pokemon-legends-z-a-scored-us-biggest-physical-game-launch-since-totk">reportedly</a> turned in the biggest physical launch figures in the US since <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_zelda_tears_of_the_kingdom">Tears of the Kingdom</a>, and it's gone down similarly well in Japan. The UK and European launches seem to have been <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/uk-charts-pokemon-legends-z-a-is-the-smallest-retail-launch-since-lets-go-in-europe">a mite less enthusiastic</a>, but <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/round-up-the-reviews-are-in-for-pokemon-legends-z-a">the critical reception</a> was positive, and the game is rocking a "Generally Favourable" Metascore of <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/pokemon-legends-z-a/">78</a> on Switch 2, <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/pokemon-legends-z-a/critic-reviews/?platform=nintendo-switch">76</a> on Switch 1.</p>
<p>And yet, with nearly 500 NL user ratings at the time of writing, there it languishes at the very bottom of our Pokémon list.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:79484 @ 1761774782 -->
<figure data-uuid="61fc2aec9fbed"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/61fc2aec9fbed/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>It's an odd one. Recency bias can present the opposite issue when a fervent fanbase is all-in on the new hotness, but after an initial period, we find things settle down nicely. Yes, it turns out <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_odyssey">Mario Odyssey</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_zelda_breath_of_the_wild">BOTW</a> really are all-timers that deserve their spots at (or near) the very, very top of their rankings. We've had it so good with other Nintendo series since 2017, which makes all these Switch Pokémon games in the nosebleeds stand out all the more.</p>
<p>Naturally, you'll always have extremes with reader-voted polls: some will slap on an 'Outstanding' 10/10 to try and elevate their favourites; others will troll games they've taken against with a 1/10 to knock them down a peg. (Seriously, the five people currently rating <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/bokura-planet">BOKURA: planet</a> 'Abysmal' need to have a word with themselves, but that's another article.) But bombers and bootlickers and genuine outlier opinions aside, a good sample size soon balances things out and games settle into their groove.</p>
<p>And there's no getting around it: the consensus shows a paucity of truly great, recent Pokémon games. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_sword_and_shield">Sword and Shield</a> sits at #18, followed by <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_lets_go_pikachu_and_lets_go_eevee">Let's Go, Pikachu and Eevee</a> at #19, the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_brilliant_diamond_and_shining_pearl">Diamond and Pearl</a> remakes at #20, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_scarlet_and_violet">Scarlet and Violet</a> slotting in just before ZA at the bottom.</p>
<p>The exception is <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_legends_arceus">Pokémon Legends: Arceus</a> at #5; a game which dared to try something a <em>little</em> different, blending nostalgia for a past generation with some innovative touches — for Pokémon, at least — and hinting at a bright future if Game Freak dared to be different.</p>

<p>It's worth clarifying that none of the Switch Pokémon games are straight-up bad. The average score from nearly 500 NL readers currently stands at 7.0, coincidentally bang on with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Alana's 7/10 review score</a>. As per our own scoring rubric, it's patently a 'Good' game.</p>
<p>But is 'Good' or 'Generally Favourable' sufficient for one of the most beloved series in all of video games? Imagine the headlines, the think pieces, the <em>confusion</em> if Nintendo fumbled the next 3D Mario and it settled on a Metascore in the late 70s. It's possible, but also, somehow, unthinkable. Would Koizumi even let it out the door if he thought someone could give it a 4 with a straight face? 'Good' doesn't cut it for the greatest series.</p>
<p>Yet it seems that, at some point, we've gotten used to 'good enough' from Pokémon, a sorry state for a series that fires up such formative passions. When did it happen?</p>
<p>I remember <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/pokemon_x_and_y">X &amp; Y</a> launching without support for the 3DS' namesake, flagship feature. Was that it? I don't think so. Rarely has a Pokémon game been a visual tour de force, and that game was genuinely great. No, that wasn't it.</p>
<figure data-uuid="6de7165e83781"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/6de7165e83781/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Alex Olney / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Sword and Shield felt like a very safe first step into a new realm, although in that context, as the first home-console entry, Game Freak still had the benefit of the doubt. No, no, the <em>next</em> one will be the big one...</p>
<p>Not that one. Or that one. Hmm. Look, maybe Gen 10 is when they'll really bring out the big guns, Timmy.</p>
<p>The Pokémon fanbase extends far beyond the games, of course, so you're not relying on the near-annual mainline schedule for your Pokémon fix. However, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/pokemon-tcg-community-engulfed-in-potential-fraud-scandal">discord in the physical TCG sphere</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-one-year-on-every-positive-pokemon-tcg-pocket-update-still-comes-with-a-catch">dissatisfaction</a> with the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pokemon_trading_card_game_pocket">Pocket</a> version, in particular, have seen the fanbase become more vocally unhappy than ever. Throw in major disappointment around Scarvi's performance (which, for the record, performs much better on Switch 2 - it only took two-and-a-half years and totally new hardware!) and it feels like Pokémon stories come in just four flavours: 'random 'mon distribution in Game X', '<em>OMG terrible tech!!1</em>', 'scandalous card-pack prices', and 'crossover merch'.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:182656,161218 @ 1761775303 -->
<p>Given the series' success, the dev resources allocated are a popular discussion topic, too. If Pokémon is the biggest franchise on the planet, why isn't The Pokémon Company putting Naughty Dog-level budgets on these games? <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/pokemon-z-as-source-code-and-beta-builds-have-now-supposedly-leaked">A recent (still-unverified) leak</a> of various Pokémon-related material <a href="https://www.polygon.com/pokemon-franchise-budget-leak-game-freak-nintendo-switch-graphics/">reportedly suggests</a> that Scarlet and Violet's budget was $21.8 million.</p>
<figure data-uuid="4632c24f7ec23"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/4632c24f7ec23/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Gemma Smith / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Now, many a small developer would kill for a budget like that, but for games that sell <em>this</em> well, a budget of $22 million is modest compared to many AAA games on other consoles. Perhaps there's something there: whatever triple-A means exactly in 2025, Pokémon...just isn't. Has it ever been?</p>
<p>Modern Pokémon's problem is a lack of ambition. Say what you like about <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pokemon_go">Pokémon GO</a>, but it injected something totally fresh and captivating. And it did so nearly a decade ago, eight months before Switch launched. I gave myself an RSI playing that in Hong Kong, such was the curiosity and joy it inspired, the ol' surprise and delight. <em>[insert tasteless joke about more recent Pokémon games inspiring personal injury of a different nature here]</em></p>
<p>TPC giving the mainline series a breather last year felt like tacit acknowledgement that they'd made too many trips to the well and had come back with a muddy bucket. A year to regroup seemed prudent to prevent an MCU-style glut of product and waning enthusiasm.</p>
<figure data-uuid="634de2828d339"><a title="Pokemon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/634de2828d339/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>But is enthusiasm <em>actually</em> waning for Pokémon? ZA's early sales figures suggest 'nope', although speaking to the NL team, there's a general sentiment which doesn't bode well. A sampling:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Modern entries try to convey a sense of freedom, yet constantly stop you in your tracks to explain something excruciatingly simple step-by-step. They've lost that sense of discovery."</p>
<p>"I’m always more excited to boot up Ruby/Sapphire or Black/White than the latest entry — and I think that’s because I always need to clarify the newbies with a “Yeah, it’s pretty rough, <em>but</em>…” to justify my enjoyment."</p>
<p>"There are no surprises anymore."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Then again, we're not kids anymore; naturally, they're the franchise focus. There's an influx of fresh players every generation, and no impetus for TPC to push the envelope when the base proposition of catching 'em all is still so addictive and profitable. Candy doesn't go out of fashion, does it? We're not kicking down doors at Cadbury's or Hershey's demanding they reinvent chocolate.</p>
<p>But just contrast this to Nintendo's own approach to Mario. Just the other day, we saw <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/shigeru-miyamoto-is-confident-mario-will-be-around-for-a-long-time-to-come">Nintendo luminaries stressing</a> that Mario will only survive if his games evolve and the developers continue to innovate. What's the last mainline Mario game that surprised me? <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_bros_wonder">Wonder</a>, probably. The last one. Perhaps to a fault (<em>"Okay, what's <strong>this</strong> zany Wonder Flower going to do?"</em>), but who could deny being surprised and fairly delighted?</p>
<p>Looking further afield, I wonder (heh) if <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/palworld">Palworld</a>'s success is partly attributable not to its 'Pokémon-with-guns' flavour — as if dropping a cache of firearms into Pokémon was the only way to appeal to adults — but its ambition to take the formula in a different direction. Looking like a proper next-(current-)gen game doesn't hurt, but at least Pocketpair is trying something, risking <em>something</em>.</p>
<figure data-uuid="1e2ce8caa2e05"><a title="Palworld" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1e2ce8caa2e05/palworld.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Pocketpair</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Likewise, with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/cassette_beasts">Cassette Beasts</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/temtem">Temtem</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/best-pokemon-likes-on-nintendo-switch-games-to-play-after-youve-finished-pokemon">many other excellent monster catchers</a>, indie devs have picked up the <strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/news/2023/06/chicory-team-is-making-a-turn-based-rpg-called-beastieball">Beastieball</a></strong> and run with it. I remember thinking that the brilliant <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/wii/okami">Okami</a> was a death knell for traditional Zelda in 2006. I've likened it in the past to outside devs finally mastering the grammar Nintendo established with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/n64/legend_of_zelda_ocarina_of_time">Ocarina</a>. It took a decade, but Nintendo did finally respond - they <em>did</em> reinvent chocolate with BOTW. (Yes, I know a Toblerone and a video game are very different things; please let me have this laboured metaphor.)</p>
<p>It's worth acknowledging that Game Freak does try new things, too, even if the pace of progress is glacial. As Alana said, ZA's battle mechanics are the best thing about it, and while the many and various Pokémon spin-off games can feel like free-to-play potshots, or half-baked ideas not intriguing enough to sustain a whole game, TPC does experiment with Pokémon. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-pokopia">Pokopia</a> looks fun! If only the mainline series could inspire such excitement.</p>
<p>What does the future of Pokémon look like, then? Well, the leaks are out there if you're curious. But it feels to me that lapsed Trainers and uberfans alike are starting to align in their 'it is what it is' resignation. 'Phoned-in' isn't fair to the developers who work so hard on these games, but from the outside looking in, they deserve more time and resources.</p>
<p>That the games look like they'd run fine on a PS3 isn't the point; Pokémon conquered the world from a Game Boy in 1996. The real issue is that the series itself feels like a fund-sucking machine fuelled by 'that'll do' energy more than an endeavour to surprise and delight. It could — and really <em>should</em> — be so much more.</p>

<figure data-uuid="aa76bbfb98cab"><a title="Pokémon" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/aa76bbfb98cab/pokemon.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Gemma Smith / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:192371,188830,192851 @ 1761775303 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-when-did-good-enough-become-good-enough-for-pokemon]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This magnetic controller brings Game Boy-style controls to your smartphone]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/809274/abxylute-m4-snap-on-mobile-wireless-smartphone-controller-magnetic-magsafe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-magnetic-controller-brings-game-boy-style-controls-to-your-smartphone.1338607/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><p><a href="#content"><span>Skip to main content</span></a></p><nav aria-label="Sticky Nav"></nav><div><main id="content"><div><article><div><div><p>﻿The M4 Snap-On mobile controller is much smaller than clamp-on gamepads and easier to slip into a pocket.</p></div><div><p>﻿The M4 Snap-On mobile controller is much smaller than clamp-on gamepads and easier to slip into a pocket.</p><div><p><span><span>by</span> <!-- --> <span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"></span></span></p><p><span><time datetime="2025-10-29T18:37:08+00:00">Oct 29, 2025, 6:37 PM UTC</time></span></p></div></div></div><div><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter who’s been covering and reviewing the latest gadgets and tech since 2006, but has loved all things electronic since he was a kid.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><div><p>Abxylute, a company known for its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/report/763957/abxylute-will-actually-sell-intel-and-tencents-gigantic-glasses-free-3d-handheld">Android-based handhelds</a>, has announced a new compact mobile controller for smartphones. Unlike controllers from companies like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/661382/the-new-backbone-pro-could-be-the-one-controller-for-all-your-gaming">Backbone</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/25/24279435/8bitdo-ultimate-mobile-gaming-controller-android-hall-effect">8BitDo</a> that use an expanding mechanism to clamp onto phones, <a href="https://abxylute.com/products/abxylute-snap-on-mobile-gamepad">Abxylute’s smaller and lighter M4 Snap-On controller</a> uses a Q-shaped mount to magnetically attach to mobile devices that are compatible with Apple’s MagSafe or the Qi2 standard, which <a href="https://www.theverge.com/analysis/762711/pixel-10-qi2-magnets-pixelsense">now includes Google’s Pixel 10 series</a>.</p></div><p>Like clamp-on controllers, Abxylute’s new game pad is designed to be used with phones in a horizontal orientation, but it positions the controls beneath the screen, instead of splitting them up on either side. Those controls include a D-pad, ABXY action buttons, a pair of shoulder buttons, two tiny joysticks, and additional navigation buttons including quick access to a home screen.</p><p>Abxylute says the controller’s rechargeable battery will be good for up to 13 hours of use, and that magnetic mount can be removed entirely if you want to use the M4 as a standalone wireless controller with other devices. Exactly which devices and consoles the M4 will be compatible with aren’t known yet, but more details will be revealed when the company launches a <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1932181238/m4-snap-on-magnetic-phone-controller-for-anytime-pocket-play">Kickstarter crowdfunding campaign</a> in early November. Pricing for the earliest backers is expected to be as low as $39, <a href="https://www.notebookcheck.net/Abxylute-s-Snap-on-Controller-to-launch-on-Kickstarter-for-39-and-be-available-in-orange.1148691.0.html">according to <em>Notebookcheck</em></a>, but <em>The Verge</em> has reached out to Abxylute to confirm what pricing will be for those who’d rather wait until general availability, and will update this story accordingly.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><div><form><div><h2>The Verge Daily</h2><p><span>A free daily digest of the news that matters most.</span></p></div></form></div></div></article></div></main></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/809274/abxylute-m4-snap-on-mobile-wireless-smartphone-controller-magnetic-magsafe]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Outage Temporarily Derails Outer Worlds 2 Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/azure-outage-xbox-game-pass-outer-worlds-2-microsoft-2000639920</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-outage-temporarily-derails-outer-worlds-2-launch.1338601/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><a href="https://kotaku.com/outer-worlds-2-review-rpg-xbox-ps5-2000638368"><em>The Outer Worlds 2</em></a> is out today and finally available to play for anyone who didn’t pay for the early access edition. That includes tons of <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-october-november-2025-powerwash-sim-2-2000638198">Game Pass subscribers</a> across Xbox Series X/S and PC. There’s just one problem: A sudden Microsoft Azure outage is causing issues as another slice of the internet faces unexpected downtime.</p> <p>“Starting at approximately 16:00 UTC, we began experiencing Azure Front Door issues resulting in a loss of availability of some services,” the company <a href="https://azure.status.microsoft/en-us/status">announced on Wednesday</a>. “In addition, customers may experience issues accessing the Azure Portal.” Microsoft is currently blaming a “configuration change error” for the downtime.</p>

 <p>Customers impacted include Xbox and its first-party game studios, who rely on Azure systems to distribute their games digitally across console and PC.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">The issue affects Shared Worlds and Online mode in Grounded and Grounded 2. We sincerely apologize for the inconvenience and will update players when we have more information.</p> <p>— Obsidian Support (@OESupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/OESupport/status/1983601153746333773?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 29, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>“Due to an ongoing Azure service outage, <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em> may be temporarily unavailable to purchase or install on Xbox Series X|S, the Xbox app on PC, and with Xbox Game Pass Ultimate or PC Game Pass,” developer Obsidian Entertainment <a href="https://x.com/OESupport/status/1983582678306975855">wrote on X</a>. “We’re working with Microsoft to resolve the issue and will update players when we have more information.”</p>

 <p>“The pre-installed game just vanished from my Xbox App today,” replied one fan. “How’s that even possible?” Another user on Steam wrote, “I can’t launch my copy on Game Pass. So it’s not working even if you have it installed. Just says something about not being able to sign you in.” Ahhh, the power of the cloud!</p>

 <p>This hiccup comes <a href="https://kotaku.com/robox-fortnite-outage-amazon-aws-explained-single-bug-god-of-war-xbox-forza-2000639249">a week after the major AWS outage</a> that briefly brought down major games like <em>Fortnite</em> and<em> Roblox</em>. It seems bad that just three companies are responsible for the modern infrastructure of the internet. Ah, well, nevertheless.</p> <p><strong>Update 10/29/2025, 6:07 p.m. ET:</strong> Microsoft says Xbox should be functioning normally again now.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Users should once again be able to access the Xbox Store, manage their accounts, launch Game Streaming sessions across all platforms, and access <a href="https://t.co/6DxzuMLtkS">https://t.co/6DxzuMLtkS</a>. Xbox Support services are continuing to recover. We'll provide updates here and on <a href="https://t.co/SoIhwJAdqC">https://t.co/SoIhwJAdqC</a> as…</p> <p>— Xbox Support (@XboxSupport) <a href="https://twitter.com/XboxSupport/status/1983655394745393209?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 29, 2025</a></p></blockquote> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/azure-outage-xbox-game-pass-outer-worlds-2-microsoft-2000639920]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI Can’t Create Next Grand Theft Auto, Take-Two CEO Says]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/ai-cant-create-next-grand-theft-auto-take-two-ceo-says/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ai-can%E2%80%99t-create-next-grand-theft-auto-take-two-ceo-says.1338598/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Grand Theft Auto 6 hasn’t been released yet, but people are already asking about the franchise’s future. Specifically, how will AI change the development of Grand Theft Auto 7 and beyond?</p>



<p>During an interview this week in New York City, Take-Two Interactive CEO Strauss Zelnick was asked about AI and its place in game development. While he’s not fully against the idea of AI, Zelnick remains skeptical about just how much it can and will help game development and general production. That includes making sure that what his company builds remains with the company. </p>



<p><strong>“We have to protect our intellectual property, but more than that, we have to be mindful of others,” </strong>Strauss <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/10/28/can-ai-create-next-grand-theft-auto-take-two-interactive-ceo-says-no.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">told CNBC</a>. <strong>“If you create intellectual property with AI, it’s not protectable.”</strong></p>



<p>When talking specifically about Grand Theft Auto, Zelnick said even if there were no constraints on how AI can be used, it wouldn’t be able to produce what the team at Rockstar has been able to do.</p>



<p><strong>“Let’s say there were no constraints [on AI],”</strong> he said. <strong>“Could we push a button tomorrow and create an equivalent to the Grand Theft Auto marketing plan? The answer is no. </strong></p>



<p><strong>“A, you can’t do that yet, and B, I am of the view that you wouldn’t end up with anything very good. You end up with something pretty derivative.”</strong></p>



<p>As far as why, Zelnick said that AI is “backward looking”. AI productions, he said, can “feel new” because of the predictive models, and though there are things the data it’s built on can solve for, there are still areas that it simply can’t.</p>



<p><strong>“Anything that involves backward-looking data compute, it’s really good for that and that applies to lots of things,” </strong>Zelnick said. <strong>“What we do at Take-Two, anything that isn’t attached to that, it’s going to be really, really bad at.”</strong></p>



<p>Grand Theft Auto 6 is currently scheduled to launch on May 26, 2026, for Xbox Series X|S and PlayStation 5. </p>



<p>What do you think about AI being used to build games like Grand Theft Auto? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ea-employees-mock-company-mandate-to-use-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">EA employees mocking the company’s mandate</a>&nbsp;to use AI tools for development and creative works. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/ai-cant-create-next-grand-theft-auto-take-two-ceo-says/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shujinkou Has Been Updated On Switch, Here Are The Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/shujinkou-has-been-updated-on-switch-here-are-the-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shujinkou-has-been-updated-on-switch-here-are-the-patch-notes.1338571/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Even better visuals? Oof, yes please</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="9b4e55ffb85fd"><a title="Shujinkou" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/9b4e55ffb85fd/shujinkou.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Rice Games</em></figcaption></figure><p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/shujinkou">Shujinkou</a>, the DRPG that also offers up some excellent Japanese language-learning tools, has been <a href="https://ricegames.net/2025/10/30/shujinkou-nintendo-switch-1-0-2-patch-notes/">updated to version 1.0.2</a> on Switch.</p>
<p>The biggest improvement here is in the graphics. A new Visual Fidelity option has been added to the menu to enable the game to run at an even crisper resolution on Switch and Switch 2. Developer Rice Games has stated that this may result in some unsavoury frame drops on the original Switch, but those on Switch 2 can expect the same performance.</p>
<p>We've also got a whole bunch of bug fixes based on player feedback, so without further ado, let's get into it...</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067rqjwno&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>837k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<hr>
<h2>New Features</h2>
<ul>
<li>There is now a new “<strong><em>Visual Fidelity</em></strong>” setting in the Options Menu that improves visual graphics at the cost of performance on the Nintendo Switch. The performance is largely unaffected on stronger devices, and we strongly recommend enabling this setting on <em>Nintendo Switch 2</em>.</li>
<li>This is the best that we can do regarding improving graphic quality without a Nintendo Switch 2 development kit.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Bug Fixes</h2>
<ul>
<li>Fix issue where Kaifuku Ball could not be used outside of battle.</li>
<li>Fix a game softlock/freeze when approaching a certain boss battle from a certain position and angle in the final area of Labyrinth 2.</li>
<li>Fix an issue with button input sometimes not working smoothly when selecting party members for a special battle.</li>
<li>Fix an issue with button input in the Tsuri (fishing) minigame occasionally causing the game to stall after a completed reel.</li>
<li>Fix an issue with camera clipping in the Omikuji system.</li>
<li>Fixed a few typos and accidental usage of kanji in certain furigana-only fields.</li>
<li>Fix a rare bug where a character’s Onsen outfit could stay in place even in dialogue taking place outside of the Onsen.</li>
<li>Fix rare case of game freezing (harmless, but for too long) when saving the game.</li>
<li>Fix issue with being unable to interact with Kunihiko in Fuu Underground when playing Okkake no Osakenori.</li>
<li>Fix harmless error that may appear when a Yajuu joins a normal battle.</li>
<li>Fix input error that could take place when spamming inputs in the Fuu Underground.</li>
<li>Fix residual errors that may pop up when finishing Okkake no Osakenori.</li>
<li>Fix the equipment type of two late game equipment pieces.</li>
<li>Fix very small navigation issue with buttons and controllers for a couple dozen spots.</li>
<li>Fix typos and other issues found in a few dialogue scenes.</li>
<li>Fix a progression bug that only occurs for some players in Labyrinth 10.</li>
<li>Fix an equipment duplication error.</li>
<li>Fixed a few instances of graphical clipping in certain labyrinths.</li>
<li>Players can no longer access the Enemy View menu while the Kanakae UI is active.</li>
<li>Remove “No Extra Notes” text from Okkake no Osakenori to prevent text overflow.</li>
<li>Reduce special effects intensity of certain battles to improve overall performance.</li>
<li>Unity vulnerability fix has been implemented.</li>
<li><strong>Nintendo Switch-only Bug Fix</strong>: When pulling from the Omikuji, the camera will clip with a 3D model.</li>
<li><strong>Nintendo Switch-only Bug Fix</strong>: Some graphical clipping of some assets in the second area of Labyrinth 5.</li>
<li><strong>Nintendo Switch-only Bug Fix</strong>: Fishing minigame (Tsuri) can sometimes soft-lock due to button input navigation issues.</li>
<li><strong>Nintendo Switch-only Bug Fix</strong>: Game crashing in Labyrinth 7 due to memory management issues.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>Shujinkou is available now via the Switch eShop for <strong>£26.99 / $29.99</strong>. Interestingly, Rice Games has confirmed that one player has already surpassed 200 hours of in-game time, which is quite the feat after under a month.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:188940 @ 1761776532 -->
<p><em>Are you currently playing Shujinkou, or are you interested in picking it up? Let us know with a comment in the usual place.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://ricegames.net/2025/10/30/shujinkou-nintendo-switch-1-0-2-patch-notes/" rel="noopener" href="https://ricegames.net/2025/10/30/shujinkou-nintendo-switch-1-0-2-patch-notes/">ricegames.net</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/6b402343098e02c5ea2e57d784892b2b @ 1761778198 --></div></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/shujinkou-has-been-updated-on-switch-here-are-the-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Azure Outage Is Affecting Xbox Game Downloads, Minecraft and More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-azure-outage-is-affecting-xbox-game-downloads-minecraft-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-azure-outage-is-affecting-xbox-game-downloads-minecraft-and-more.1338568/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Microsoft's Azure cloud service is experiencing a massive outage affecting multiple services, including Xbox game downloads and Minecraft.</p>



<p>Microsoft confirmed the cause in an <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://azure.status.microsoft/en-us/status">Azure status update</a>, stating the widespread connectivity issues began around 16:00 UTC. The company attributed the trigger event to <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">"an inadvertent configuration change" </em>in the Azure Front Door (AFD) service.</p>



<p>Several concurrent actions are being taken to solve the issue, but the Azure outage is still ongoing at the time of writing, and Xbox game publishers have started warning users about potential problems. On <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:h4x5o4kfgwgqm4enepisxtid/post/3m4dx2pwsik2j?ref_src=embed">Bluesky</a>, Obsidian Entertainment confirmed that due to the continuing outage, The Outer Worlds 2 may be temporarily unavailable for purchase or installation on Xbox consoles and PC. The publisher added that the issue is affecting all Xbox games, including online games such as Minecraft, whose down status is confirmed by <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Minecraft/comments/1ojbiqf/how_long_will_minecraft_be_down/">multiple online reports</a> as well as by <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://downdetector.com/status/minecraft/">Down Detector.</a> </p>



<p>Unfortunately, no estimation of when the services will return online has been provided. We will update this post once more information is available and when the outage has been resolved.</p>



<p>Today's Microsoft Azure cloud service outage follows last week's <a href="https://wccftech.com/aws-outage-snaps-chatgpt-fortnite-down/">massive AWS outage</a>, which took down almost half the internet, including PSN, Fortnite, and Roblox. The issues that led to the outage were resolved in a matter of hours, and <a href="https://wccftech.com/psn-fortnite-roblox-gaming-services-starting-to-recover-aws-outage/">all affected services were promptly brought back online</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> or <a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q=wccftech.com">add us as a preferred source</a>, to get our news coverage and reviews in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/microsoft-azure-outage-is-affecting-xbox-game-downloads-minecraft-and-more/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Outer Worlds 2’s satire has a Microsoft-shaped problem]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/809022/the-outer-worlds-2-corporate-satire-interview-xbox</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-outer-worlds-2%E2%80%99s-satire-has-a-microsoft-shaped-problem.1338565/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Almost immediately in <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em>, the player receives news of a corporate shake-up: Auntie Cleo and Spacer’s Choice, two of the in-game retail brands, have merged to form Auntie’s Choice. Less a chain of stores and more a feudal power, Auntie’s Choice manages its employees — serfs, really — with the cruelty of the balance sheet, its military business far more important than the faux-cheery public-facing purveyor of somewhat-useful crap customers can’t get from anyone else.</p><p>The fictional business news parallels real-world business news. Right before developer Obsidian Entertainment began work on <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em> in 2019, the studio was acquired as part of Microsoft’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/10/18082922/microsoft-xbox-inxile-obsidian-entertainment-studio-acquisition">game developer shopping spree</a>. Less than a decade later, Microsoft’s gaming division doesn’t seem to be flourishing despite its incredibly deep bench of talent; in 2025, the company’s games efforts have largely been characterized by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/790658/microsoft-xbox-game-pass-console-price-hikes-notepad">price hikes</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/25/24049050/microsoft-activision-blizzard-layoffs">layoffs</a>, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/805280/microsoft-xbox-gaming-profit-targets-layoffs">lopsided priorities</a>, and an all-consuming interest from the company’s top brass in <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/799768/microsoft-windows-ai-copilot-voice-vision-launch">becoming an AI company</a>.</p><p>Yet Obsidian is still here, and it has something to say about this stuff. At least, its new role-playing game, which casts players as an agent in a cheerily fascist organization that becomes embroiled in a conflict between a megacorporation and a totalitarian government, might have a few things to say about it. The studio itself? It’s a little less clear.</p><p><em>The Outer Worlds 2</em> creative director Leonard Boyarsky and game director Brandon Adler are not in the business of making games that respond to any specific moment — games take so long to make, after all, and fun is their fixation. They do acknowledge that their game’s scenario can feel quite topical. “Tim [Cain, co-creator of the<em> Outer Worlds </em>franchise] and I have always made games that are about what happens when people get power,” Boyarsky told me in a Zoom interview alongside Adler. “We’re expanding on that continually.”</p><p>Boyarsky and Cain (who announced his “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cdHqBi1IPOY">semi-retirement</a>” in 2023 but still does contract work for Obsidian) are co-creators of the <em>Fallout</em> franchise and have deep roots in the computer RPG scene, having worked on a string of cult classics like <em>Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines</em> and the little-played but deeply beloved <em>Arcanum: Of Steamworks and Magick Obscura</em>. Their influence is everywhere, establishing modern RPG trends where factional conflicts and institutional mistrust are leveraged to generate interesting problems for players to solve.</p><p>The <em>Outer Worlds</em> games are best understood as another run at <em>Fallout</em>. Both franchises use a divergence in American history to spin out bizarre far futures defined by lopsided institutions. <em>Fallout</em> imagines a nuclear golden age post-World War II, where the science fiction of the ’50s became science fact, before a 21st-century thermonuclear war turns the world into <em>Mad Max</em>-style wasteland in which players eke out a mean, odd existence. In <em>The Outer Worlds</em>’ fictional history, President William McKinley is never assassinated, an antitrust movement never materializes, and the robber barons of the early 20th century run rampant for hundreds of years. Hence the heavy layer of corporate satire, which Obsidian expands in <em>Outer Worlds 2 </em>to become something darker.</p><p>In the first 15 minutes of the game, players are hit with:</p><div><ul><li><span>a glib conversation with a mascot for one of those retail companies owned by a defense contractor;</span></li><li><span>a TV show clip that suggests a level of <em>Starship Troopers</em>-esque propaganda;</span></li><li><span>an overt <em>Starship Troopers</em>-esque propaganda ad encouraging citizens to rat on each other.</span></li></ul></div><p>There’s a meaner undercurrent to the sequel’s iteration on <em>The Outer Worlds</em>’ corporate humor, one that tugs at a thread linking corporate overreach to fascism’s rise. At least, I think there is. Maybe Obsidian thinks so too?</p><p>“We don’t talk about the fascist aspect of it, but we all end up in situations where we don’t have control. Even people in power, whether it’s the real world or these games, I think people in power are as much victims of the system as anybody else,” Boyarsky said. “They think they’re in control of these things, but no one person can actually wield as much power as people want. Because you’re grown up in the system, you react based on how you were raised in the system, your beliefs that have come up through being told what’s right and wrong by your parents or society in general. So we all find ourselves in situations where it’s just like:<em> I have no idea how I got here. I guess I gotta make the best of it</em>.”</p><p>I tell Boyarsky that sounds like a very video game-y view of the world, and ask why he thinks games are an ideal medium to tackle these quandaries. He tells me that, at least when it comes to <em>The Outer Worlds</em>, the themes came from a convergence of his and Cain’s interests. Cain, he says, loved the idea of a <em>Futurama</em>-inspired setting, leaning into the silliness. Boyarsky says he wants this game to keep that, but push toward something more difficult and less goofy.</p><p>“My thing was always — and this is something that we really continue to dig into — we all tell ourselves stories,” Boyarsky said. “That’s how we cope with the world, with reality. That’s built by how you’re raised and what people tell you when you’re younger. But when people co-opt that story, they can control you very easily.”</p><p>These are all potent ideas, but they’re also thick with irony thanks to events largely out of Obsidian’s control. Some of them involve geopolitical issues well outside the games industry. But others lie closer to home for developers that are now owned by Microsoft.</p><p>“All I can say is that the irony was not lost on us when we were in the middle of making the first game. Railing against corporate power and all this stuff — and we were bought by Microsoft!” Boyarsky says. “But we’ve only had support from them. They liked what we were doing with the first <em>Outer Worlds</em>, and they support us making this game. We’ve had absolutely no pushback or messages from on high telling us <em>don’t do this</em>, or <em>make sure you do this</em>.”</p><p>While it may be true that Microsoft has not interfered with Obsidian’s creative processes on <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em>, the company certainly had preferences on how the leads at the studio discussed it. The game, with Boyarsky’s interests in exploring the plight of what happens to those who aren’t in power when people with base interests come into power, seemed particularly relevant to <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/785733/microsoft-block-israeli-military-cloud-ai-services-palestine-protests">Microsoft’s business entanglements with the Israeli Ministry of Defense</a>.</p><p>Before we get further, a Microsoft rep interrupts to note that the company’s latest statements on the matter <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/on-the-issues/2025/09/25/update-on-ongoing-microsoft-review/">can be found online</a>, and that they wanted to keep the conversation with Obsidian “focused on the game.”</p><p>So let’s focus on the game: Early on you can accept a quest that, depending on your choices, might send you to retrieve something from the Ministry of Accuracy. Like the name suggests, it’s a propaganda outfit. Read through the terminals found there and you’ll see how it works: Reports from all over the region are funneled through the Ministry, where workers “sanitize” them to make sure they align with the messaging of the space colony’s ruling power, The Protectorate. Art imitating life for Obsidian, once again. Or maybe it’s the other way around.</p><p><sub>The Outer Worlds 2 <em>is out now on the PS5, Xbox, and PC.</em></sub></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6Mzc2NDc="><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Joshua Rivera</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/809022/the-outer-worlds-2-corporate-satire-interview-xbox]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[30 Years Ago, Homer Entered The Third Dimension]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/homer-cubed-3d-treehouse-horror-fox-30-years-ago-1995-2000639909</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/30-years-ago-homer-entered-the-third-dimension.1338559/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>On October 29, 1995, just over 12 million viewers tuned into the newest episode of Fox’s hit animated (and very 2D) comedy, <em>The Simpsons</em>, and were shocked to see Homer become 3D. Pulling this off was incredibly challenging, but the end result is a wonderful time capsule of early computer animation.</p> <p><em>The Simpsons Treehouse of Horror VI</em> is one of the best installments of the show’s annual Halloween special. In fact, <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-13-best-simpsons-treehouse-of-horror-segments-1850470445">two parts of the episode made our top 13 best <em>Treehouse of Horror</em> segments list</a>. One of those two segments is perhaps the most ambitious and wildest thing <a href="https://kotaku.com/the-simpsons-best-episodes-characters-top-to-watch-list-1850309544"><em>The Simpsons</em></a> has ever done. In the segment <em>Homer</em>³<em> (Homer Cubed),</em> we see the famous cartoon father and husband leave his 2D dimension via a portal behind a bookcase and enter a 3D computer-generated landscape. What follows is about four minutes of a 3D, computer-generated Homer exploring an odd world filled with simple objects, random pools of water, and even the library from the game <em>Myst</em>.</p>

  <p>At one point while exploring this bizarre 3D world, Homer says, “Man, this place looks expensive. I feel like I’m wasting a fortune just standing here.” And he wasn’t joking. As explained in the fantastic oral history of this segment, <a href="https://ew.com/tv/2018/10/19/the-simpsons-homer-cubed-treehouse-of-horror-vi/">written up by <em>Entertainment Weekly</em> in 2018</a>, it was estimated that the four minutes of 3D animation seen in <em>Treehouse of Horror VI</em> cost “hundreds of thousands of dollars.” However, Fox only paid <span>Pacific Data Images–the CG studio behind the animation–a measly $6,000 for the work.&nbsp;</span>Tim Johnson, the head of PDI’s character animation group, broke the news to the company’s founder, Carl Rosendahl.</p>

 <p>“Here’s the good news: <em>The Simpsons</em> has this amazing script, and we can participate,” said Johnson. “Carl just got up out of his chair and paced the room—he was so excited. I said, ‘Well, here’s the <em>bad</em> news: They don’t have any money to pay for it.’ So Carl sat back down and ran the numbers.”</p>

 <p>Ultimately, the company agreed to do the animation because it was seen as a big opportunity for the company. And it did pay off, in the end. Not long after this episode aired, Dreamworks bought up a big chunk of PDI, and Johnson would end up co-directing <em>Antz</em>. The company even helped on <em>Shrek</em>. PDI was still making CG shorts for Dreamworks up until it shut down in 2015.</p> <p>The end result was something that hadn’t really been seen on TV before, and it blew people’s minds. Today, this kind of thing could be created by a single person with one computer in a few days or hours. But back in October 1995, a month before <em>Toy Story</em> hit theaters, this kind of 3D animation was incredibly rare. And the only reason it happened was because PDI decided to do it basically for free. The end result is something very special. 30 years later, this segment is still great, even if the then-impressive tech has aged a lot since it first aired in the ’90s. Sure, it’s not the scariest or funniest segment in <em>The Simpsons’</em> long history, but it’s one of its most memorable, even three decades later. (<a href="https://ew.com/tv/2018/10/19/the-simpsons-homer-cubed-treehouse-of-horror-vi/">Oh, and you should totally read the full <em>EW</em> history of this segment if you are a Simpsons nerd. So much good stuff in there!</a>)</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/homer-cubed-3d-treehouse-horror-fox-30-years-ago-1995-2000639909]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DHS will continue using game and pop culture iconography in messaging]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/dhs-will-continue-using-game-and-pop-culture-iconography-in-messaging</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dhs-will-continue-using-game-and-pop-culture-iconography-in-messaging.1338553/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Screenshot via Halo Studios/Microsoft. Logo via DHS.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The United States Department of Homeland Security (DHS) is </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/alyssamerc.bsky.social/post/3m4dt3spux22d">promising</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to continue its campaign of posting memes and recruiting material based on pop-culture imagery, including those from the world of video games. This comes days after it and the White House promoted images on social media depicting </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://kotaku.com/donald-trump-halo-gamestop-console-wars-meme-ai-images-2000639237">President Trump as player character Master Chief</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and recruitment ads </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://kotaku.com/department-homeland-security-halo-ice-pokemon-video-dhs-2000639308">encouraging would-be ICE agents to "Destroy the flood"</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> [sic] (a reference to the Flood, the zombie-like antagonists of the Halo series).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This promise suggests that more game developers and industry professionals may see the US government use the games they work on for recruitment purposes, or to push </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.npr.org/2024/03/08/1237103158/immigrants-are-less-likely-to-commit-crimes-than-us-born-americans-studies-find">unproven claims</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> of high crime rates driven by undocumented immigrants. Game File spoke with a number of former Halo franchise developers who </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamefile.news/p/halo-ice-developers-react?r=5i0nln">condemned the posts</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, with former series Jaime Griesemer calling the DHS ad "ought to offend every Halo fan, regardless of political orientation."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Word of DHS' plans comes from a comment sent to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/alyssamerc.bsky.social/post/3m4dt3spux22d">independent journalist Alyssa Mercante</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, who sought comment from the agency over its impromptu ad campaign. "We will reach people where they are with content they can relate to and understand, whether that be Halo, Pokémon, Lord of the Rings, or any other medium," an agency spokesperson stated, adding that it was "laser focused" on pushing messaging spotlighting the aforementioned unproven claims about immigrant crime rates.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/amazon-is-ending-active-development-on-new-world" target="_self" data-discover="true">Amazon is ending active development on New World</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to Mercante and other journalists, Microsoft declined to comment on the Halo-themed posts.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The Trump administration continues to embrace game-adjacent 'meme culture'">The Trump administration continues to embrace game-adjacent 'meme culture'</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Mercante had previously received comment from the White House celebrating the President's overseeing of the end of "the console wars," which was proclaimed by the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/gamestop/status/1982213786221109263">GameStop X account</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on Friday after Microsoft announced </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Halo: Campaign Evolved</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> would debut on the PlayStation 5 as well as Xbox Series X|S. GameStop posted a number of celebratory manipulated images of President Trump with the Master Chief in the hours afterward.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The DHS previously invoked the spirit of video games in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.polygon.com/pokemon-ice-dhs-nintendo/">a number of social media messages in September 2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> drawing on imagery and slogans from the Pokémon franchise. The Pokémon Company (which is partially owned by Nintendo), distanced itself from these posts, saying that "it was not involved in the creation or distribution of this content, and permission was not granted for the use of our intellectual property."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These posts followed</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.npr.org/2025/08/18/nx-s1-5482921/memes-white-house-dhs-social-media-trump">&nbsp;a number of promotional images earlier in 2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> promoting President Trump's agenda through the lens of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-news/trump-star-wars-may-fourth-memes-1235331075/">Disney's Star Wars series</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, AI-generated images inspired by Studio Ghibli. Neither company issued any statement following these posts, though a number of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.npr.org/2025/08/28/nx-s1-5506215/politicians-using-music-memes-issues">musicians</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> have consistently pushed back against their work being used by the Administration.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/cwa-president-implores-u-s-regulators-to-scrutinise-ea-buyout-to-address-national-security-and-labor-concerns" target="_self" data-discover="true">CWA president implores U.S. regulators to scrutinize EA buyout to address national security and labor concerns</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Given the DHS' pattern of jumping from pop culture reference to pop culture reference, other developers may find their work used to promote its policies in the next few years.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Game Developer has reached out to Microsoft for comment on this story and will provide an update when the company responds.</span></span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/dhs-will-continue-using-game-and-pop-culture-iconography-in-messaging]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>