<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 17:38:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering – Bloomburrow Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/12/mtg-arena-bloomburrow-review-magic-the-gathering/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/magic-the-gathering-%E2%80%93-bloomburrow-review.951147/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/12/mtg-arena-bloomburrow-review-magic-the-gathering/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
													
				<p>Art by Narendra Bintara Adi</p>			</div><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>The start of August saw the release of Magic: The Gathering – Bloomburrow, the seventh set of the year, and there’s plenty yet to come with the addition of Foundations to the release calendar in November pushing up the next set, Duskmourn, up to be just seven weeks away. But as anti-cute as Duskmourn promises to be, it’s time to appreciate the fluffy and adorable Bloomburrow.</p>
<p><iframe title="Tiny Tails, Big Adventure | Bloomburrow Official Trailer | Magic: The Gathering" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NGNHxIP3PIo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Bloomburrow is, as we said, incredibly cute. MTG is, at its core, a game where we visit different planes of existence that each have their own rules, lores, histories and so on. Bloomburrow’s shtick is that there are no humans, and any humans that do make their way here are turned into animalfolk for the duration of their visit. The majority of players seem to agree that this is a nice change of pace, but the impact that it has had on gameplay is unfortunate.</p>


<p>This focus on creature types creates what it known as a tribal set, which tends to be quite shallow when it comes to building your deck. This is certainly true when it comes to the draft experience – while experienced players can eek out win percentage by knowing when to pivot, the difficulty level of this set is really quite low, making it very accessible to newer players.</p>


<p>Each creature type in Bloomburrow represents two of Magic’s five colours. Otters, for example, are red and blue-aligned. Mice are Red and White, while squirrels are Green and Black. This is fantastic when it comes to new players learning the game —&nbsp;in Draft (where you pass packs of cards around the table, taking one at a time and adding it to your deck), you can simply pick all of the cards that say Lizard or Frog and put them into a deck, rather than stopping to read each card and see what it does — something vital to more complex sets.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, some animals are more equal than others – how very Animal Farm – and a clear tier list has emerged on Arena. Rabbit (Green-White) and mice decks are hyper-aggressive and win quickly, with slower otter decks struggling to keep up. When one deck is winning on turn three of four and you’re looking at cards you can’t cast until turn five, it feels pretty bad.</p>
<p>It’s rare this early into a set that the format feels like it has been ‘solved’ by players, but the replay value in Draft appears rather… limited.</p>

<p>So, how does Sealed shape up? This is a game of opening six packs at once and seeing what you have. The problem here is much more acute: you either have the cards for a hyper-aggressive deck or you lose. Without much synergy between species, this isn’t a format where you can simply chuck all of your blue cards into a pool and hope for the best. Your frogs will care about returning creatures to your hand, while your birds will care about what has flying and the otters are counting how many non-creature spells you are casting. You can get it to work if you try, but when others can quickly flood the board while you do backflips trying to get your deck to work, you’re fighting an uphill battle.</p>
<p>Fortunately, playing with these cards is more than just Draft and Sealed. Standard, for example, takes all of the Standard Sets (usually four per year, but five in 2024 thanks to Foundations) from the past three years and asks you to build the best deck you can. We’ve just had the rotation where old sets cycle out, which means that until late 2025, we’re looking at everything from Dominaria United onwards. For newer players and those who dip in and out, working with a shallower card pool is always helpful.</p>
<p>Generally speaking, you don’t want a set to come in and completely shake up Standard — this is a sign that the set is overpowered and something has gone horribly wrong. This happened for Modern in June with Modern Horizons 3, when <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/mh3/193/nadu-winged-wisdom">Nadu</a>’s release broke the format so badly that almost nobody wants to play.</p>

<p>So how has Bloomburrow affected Standard? While it hasn’t completely shaken up the format, it has had a sizeable impact. The top deck in the meta, Golgari Midrange, takes <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/blb/180/innkeepers-talent">a new card</a> and creates a turn-five instant win <a href="https://scryfall.com/card/one/115/vraska-betrayals-sting">Vraska, Betrayal’s Sting</a>. Mono-red Aggro (my current pet deck) is around 50% Bloomburrow cards (excluding lands), but that is an outlier since it’s focused on Mice — most decks at the top of the meta that aren’t Bloomburrow decks add a couple of cards and call it a day. And unlike modern, there’s no one deck that really dominates the meta with an outsized win rate. With Bloomburrow in the fold, Standard is quite a lot of fun at the moment, and in a really good place — helped of course by the recent rotation.</p>
<p>Modern won’t be affected by Bloomburrow until Nadu is gone, and even then its expansive card pool isn’t dented by this set –&nbsp;the relative power levels just don’t compare. Timeless and Explorer, by the same token, lie effectively untouched.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone Officially Announced for 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-officially-announced-for-2025.951144/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-announced<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer The Farm 51 has announced&nbsp;<em>Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone</em>, a sequel to 2021's survival game <i>Chernobylite</i>. The sequel is set to debut on PC and consoles in 2025.</p>
<p>Per the game's official Steam page, you'll play as a planewalker (yes, that is someone who travels between parallel reality, so don't worry, you didn't turn over two pages at once) on the hunt for the mysterious titular resource.</p>
<p>You'll find yourself trapped in the Exclusion Zone and fighting for your life against hordes of monsters. The Farm 51 describes&nbsp;<em>Chernobylite 2</em>'s environment as a "big and realistic open world" which has been taken over by the Chernobylite resource, with the inhabitants of the Zone trying to fight back using "prototype technology".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-portal.jpg?itok=m-7BVX5I 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-portal.jpg?itok=FkVyzvgl 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone&nbsp;</em>promises to expand on the gameplay elements that made the first game so well-liked.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Chernobylite 2&nbsp;</em>will allow you to create your own character, and you'll be able to make choices about how your character approaches situations. The Farm 51 gives the examples of an "arrogant muscle man with a big sword" intimidating everyone he meets, as well as a "smart sniper who always finds the right arguments", so it sounds like you'll be able to diversify pretty extensively.</p>
<p>You'll also be able to choose whether you approach combat with melee weapons or firearms, and The Farm 51 says you can opt for stealth or "ask[ing] others for help" if you prefer. The planewalking system allows you to switch builds on the fly, so you can switch up your approach depending on what the situation calls for.</p>
<p>According to&nbsp;<em>Chernobylite 2</em>'s Steam page, the game will also feature a cast of party members to meet and talk with, each of whom is "a potential teacher, ready to impart their knowledge and skills". It sounds like The Farm 51 is taking a more RPG-centric approach to this followup.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-walkers.jpg?itok=EXA70SOO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-walkers.jpg?itok=7wImteoa 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Some of the creatures you'll encounter in&nbsp;<em>Chernobylite 2&nbsp;</em>look pretty creepy.</figcaption></figure><p>Between everything outlined above, a base you can expand, and factions you'll meet (and potentially influence),&nbsp;<em>Chernobylite 2&nbsp;</em>sounds like a significantly more ambitious undertaking than <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/chernobylite">the first game</a>, which was already pretty expansive.</p>
<p>You'll be able to check out&nbsp;<em>Chernobylite 2&nbsp;</em>on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2075100/Chernobylite_2_Exclusion_Zone/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor">PC</a> and "consoles" (which presumably means PS5 and Xbox Series X|S, at the very least) next year. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Do We Know the Terminator: Survivors Release Date?]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/do-we-know-the-terminator-survivors-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/do-we-know-the-terminator-survivors-release-date.951126/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/do-we-know-the-terminator-survivors-release-date/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>The survival genre is undoubtedly one that’s overflowing with new projects, and most of them wind up flopping hard. But with an IP like this, how could Terminator: Survivors follow suit? It’s likely to make it big in the scene, but we’ll have to wait a bit longer. So, do we know the Terminator: Survivors release date?</p>



<h2 id="h-when-does-terminator-survivors-come-out">When Does Terminator: Survivors Come Out?</h2>



<p>Initially, Terminator: Survivors was scheduled to launch on October 24. Unfortunately for every one of us excited fans, Nacon revealed it’s delaying the game until sometime in 2025. They said:</p>



<p>“Dear Survivors,</p>



<p>We are working very hard to bring the post-apocalyptic world of Terminator to life. Our goal is to create a deep immersive experience where each decision you make is crucial to your surviving.</p>



<p>Over the past few months, we’ve been really impressed by your enthusiasm and amazed by the response to our announcements, and we know how eagerly fans are awaiting Terminator: Survivors. To realize our vision, we need some additional time. Thus, we will be pushing the launch to 2025.</p>



<p>We know that this will be a disappointment to many, but we want to do right by this universe, its fans, and our community. In the long term, we believe this is the right call.</p>



<p>We are grateful for your understanding and support.</p>



<p>We’ll be back.”</p>



<p>Sadly, they don’t even provide a release window for the game. So, for the time being, we don’t know the official release date of Terminator: Survivors. The moment one pops up, we’ll let you know!</p>



<h6 id="h-related-terminator-survivors-offline-first-person-unreal-5-and-story-rich">Related: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/terminator-survivors-offline-story-first-person/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Terminator: Survivors – Offline, First-Person, Unreal 5, and Story-Rich</a></h6>



<h2 id="h-what-systems-does-terminator-survivors-support">What Systems Does Terminator: Survivors Support?</h2>



<p>Once it launches worldwide, you can play Terminator: Survivors on PC, first and foremost, but eventually on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S. For now, Nacon is focusing all of its efforts on the PC (Steam) release of the game, which will hit sometime in 2025. Once it’s out, they’ll look to current-gen consoles for a follow-up launch there.</p>



<hr>



<p>If Terminator: Survivors looks enticing, you might also like to know that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/robocop-rogue-city-devs-working-on-new-action-rpg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Robocop: Rogue City development team is hard at work on an action RPG</a>!</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chornobyl – 36-minute developer deep dive]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-36-minute-developer-deep-dive</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/s-t-a-l-k-e-r-2-heart-of-chornobyl-%E2%80%93-36-minute-developer-deep-dive.951123/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-36-minute-developer-deep-dive<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>An in-depth look at the sequel ahead of its November 20 release.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Developer <a title="Companies > GSC Game World [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/gsc-game-world">GSC Game World</a> has released a 36-minute developer deep dive for <em><a title="Games > S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chornobyl [18 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl">S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chornobyl</a></em>. <span id="more-905189"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via GSC Game World:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Chornobyl Exclusion Zone has changed dramatically after the second massive explosion in year 2006. Violent mutants, deadly anomalies, and warring factions have made the Zone a very tough place to survive. It turned out that the center of the Zone hides the source of incredible power. Nevertheless, artifacts of unbelievable value attracted many people called S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s, who entered the Zone for their own risk striving to make a fortune out of it or even to find the Truth concealed in the Heart of Chornobyl.</p><p><strong>Epic Nonlinear Story in a Seamless Open World</strong></p><p>Take over a role of the lone stalker and explore photorealistic seamless open world in a 64-km² radioactive zone with a variety of environments that reveal post-apocalyptic atmosphere from different angles. Make your way through the Zone to define your destiny as you choose your paths within highly branching epic story.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Variety of Enemies and Hundreds of Weapon Combinations</strong></p><p>Meet members of different factions deciding who of them worth your friendship and who deserve a bullet. Engage intense gunfights with a variety enemies that follow different tactics trying to outsmart you. Choose your preferable firearms from 30+ types of weapons with numerous modifications that allow creating hundreds of distinctive lethal combinations.</p><p><strong>Legendary <a title="Companies > MUTAN [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mutan">Mutan</a>ts with Different Behavior Models</strong></p><p>Prepare to encounter horrifying mutated creatures that will try to slaughter you following different behaviour model. Each mutant may appear in different subtypes which makes their behavior less predictable. Truly extreme danger represent regions with lairs with numerous mutants hunting in large groups.</p><p><b>Artifacts of Incredible Value and Unforgiving Anomalies</b></p><p>The most valuable artifacts and secrets of the Zone are hidden in the most dangerous places. Beware of the hazardous anomalies and unique devastating arch-anomalies as you hunt for highly valuable artifacts scattered around the Zone. Will you dare to unveil the mysteries of the Zone that took lives of many others before you?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Unique gameplay built on a blend of <a title="Genres > First-Person Shooter [2,510 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter/fps">first-person shooter</a>, <a title="Genres > Horror [453 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a>, and immersive sim.</li><li>Non-linear story with the variety of paths that lead to one of the several endings.</li><li>Benchmark-setting graphics developed using cutting-edge photogrammetric and scanning technologies.</li><li>Advanced artificial intelligence systems that will keep engaged even the most hard-boiled players.</li><li>Life-simulating system “A-life 2.0” that makes the game world feel alive as never before.</li><li>Immersive <a title="Genres > Survival [301 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> mechanics like hunger, sleeping, bleeding, and radiation effects that enrich the gameplay.</li><li>Dynamic day-night cycle and weather will add even more realism to the gameplay experience.</li><li>Mod support giving the freedom to the creative players to extend and enrich the game universe.</li><li><a title="Genres > Multiplayer [360 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">Multiplayer</a> mode, that will be added soon after release as a free update.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chornobyl</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,815 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,855 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1643320/STALKER_2_Heart_of_Chernobyl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/store/p/stalker-2-heart-of-chernobyl" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a>, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/stalker_2_heart_of_chornobyl_standard_edition" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GOG</a> on November 20. It will also be available via <a title="Platforms > Xbox [24,524 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> Game Pass.</p><p>Watch the video below.</p><h2><span>Developer Deep Dive</span></h2><p><iframe title="S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Серце Чорнобиля — Developer Deep Dive" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bi17nPEG7jw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stalker 2 Deep Dive Highlights Vast Player Freedom]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/stalker-2-deep-dive-highlights-vast-player-freedom/1100-6525721/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/stalker-2-deep-dive-highlights-vast-player-freedom.951120/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/stalker-2-deep-dive-highlights-vast-player-freedom/1100-6525721/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525721">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl/">Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl</a> is due out this fall on PC and Xbox Series X|S, following many years of waiting from the fans, as well as obstacles, including some as non-traditional as real-life war, challenging the Ukrainian team along the way. Today, GSC Game World is ready to provide a lengthy look at the game, particularly as it pertains to its massive open-world setting filled with real-life landmarks, sci-fi oddities, irradiated monsters, and a multitude of secrets to discover.</p><p dir="ltr">The 35-minute video showcases plenty of gameplay, often highlighting the freedom bestowed to the player. Many of a game's traditional upgrades, such as new equipment, weapons, and accessories, are not gifted to the player for simply progressing through the Stalker 2 story. Instead, they will often be tucked away in various corners of the eastern European setting, and require curious players to seek them out.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="2059746036" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464807,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;S.T.A.L.K.E.R.%202%3A%20Heart%20of%20Chornobyl%20%E2%80%94%20Official%2035%20Minute%20Developer%20Deep%20Dive&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:2154,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/s-t-a-l-k-e-r-2-heart-of-chornobyl-official-35-minute-developer-deep-dive\/2300-6464807\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464807\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464807\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464807\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464807&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464807,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6525721&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;s-t-a-l-k-e-r-2-heart-of-chornobyl&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,first-person,shooter&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;gsc-game-world&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;s.t.a.l.k.e.r.&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;s-t-a-l-k-e-r&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464807},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464807\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4349106-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/PLlurUVY.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1723480620,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="PLlurUVY" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> S.T.A.L.K.E.R. 2: Heart of Chornobyl — Official 35 Minute Developer Deep Dive</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">The team also boasted that some locations returning from previous games in the series are now available to explore for the first time ever, such as a church cellar that was seen from the outside but never accessible. In Stalker 2, however, it and other places like it can be entered and scavenged. This level of detail is owed to the team's mission to outdo itself. "We constantly had to look back on the success of the first games' development," game director Ievgen Grygorovych said, "because we can't produce anything worse than that. We can only do better."</p><p dir="ltr">To that end, the behavior of AI enemies is also a point of emphasis. In the developer diary, GSC Game World illustrates how enemies won't easily key in on where a stealthy player may be hiding. Some stealth games script AI behaviors to approach a hiding player and directly challenge them to stay out of sight, but in Stalker 2, a well-hidden player who gives no clues as to their whereabouts can remain hidden. If enemies do get a whiff of a stealthy stalker, they will first hypothesize where they may be hiding, going on to make assumptions that may be right or wrong. These more nuanced behaviors sound as though they'll still drive emergent moments, and perhaps do so even better than some games like it given the more unpredictable pathing of the enemies.</p><p dir="ltr">GSC Game World admits creating a game with a level of freedom that Stalker 2 possesses is, on a technical level, "very difficult" and "time-consuming," as the team must account for every possible step the player may take in the open world, and then reward them appropriately for doing so, in the form of new challenges or rewards.</p><p dir="ltr">That massive world is built, in part, using real-life locations, some of which are presented in the game exactly as they are in real life, while others have been redesigned to suit the world. Due to the branching nature of some story beats, a player can't actually see every mission, meet every character, or discover every location in one playthrough. Subsequent experiences with the game will be needed for even the most diehard completionists.</p><p dir="ltr">"We didn't want to make the game easy for the player," a developer said, as it would "kill the grip of reality." If the player can easily make mistakes, then it's "not a Stalker experience."</p><p dir="ltr">The lengthy video goes on to showcase the Exclusion Zone's mutants, the team's motion-capture studio, and the attention to detail when creating the game's soundscapes in different languages, such as English and Ukrainian.</p><p dir="ltr">In the end, the team acknowledges the unique hardships it's had to overcome due to the Russian invasion of Ukraine to even make a game of any kind, never mind one that it is especially proud of.</p><p dir="ltr">"Even if all the complications never happened, starting and finishing this project still would have been a fantastic achievement. But now, considering all these challenges, I think we are superheroes," a developer concludes. "You can't create something like this world, this plot, this game on your own or when there are only a few of you. Teamwork and cooperation of talents and professionals in their respective fields, only under such conditions, after a number of failures and victories, there may come a moment when something new and great, grand and far-reaching is really created and starts its life. I am really proud to be part of that."</p><p dir="ltr">Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl launches on Xbox Series X|S, PC, and Xbox Game Pass on November 20. If you've seen enough to jump in for yourself, you can <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/stalker-2-heart-of-chornobyl-preorder-guide/1100-6505939/">preorder Stalker 2</a> today.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/111003174123010839883?rel=author">Mark Delaney</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Terminator: Survivors Early Access Release Delayed Until 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/terminator-survivors-early-access-release</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/terminator-survivors-early-access-release-delayed-until-2025.951102/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/terminator-survivors-early-access-release<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nacon has announced a&nbsp;<em>Terminator: Survivors&nbsp;</em>delay, pushing back the upcoming survival game from October this year to an indeterminate point in 2025.</p>
<p>Per <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2617340/view/4360132896063376891" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a Steam post</a>, the launch will be pushed back to next year in order for Nacon to "realize [its] vision" and to give it time to "deliver the game that fits your expectations". The studio says it recognizes the delay will be disappointing, but that in order to "do right by this universe, its fans, and our community", it's a necessary delay.</p>
<p>Sadly, no new release date has been announced yet, so it looks like you're going to have to wait a little while to get your chance to prove whether you'd last in a world controlled by Skynet.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/terminator-survivors-early-access-release-date-guns.jpg?itok=LnadpSuR 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/terminator-survivors-early-access-release-date-guns.jpg?itok=XZ0GIy-H 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Terminator: Survivors&nbsp;</em>needs a little more time in the oven.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Terminator: Survivors&nbsp;</em>was originally unveiled during this year's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nacon-connect-2024-announced">Nacon Connect presentation</a>, which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/terminator-survivors-and-more-unveiled-at-nacon-connect">took place back in February</a>. The game is set during the "aftermath" of Judgment Day, the event during which artificial intelligence system Skynet gained sentience and wiped out billions of human beings in the world of the&nbsp;<em>Terminator&nbsp;</em>movies.</p>
<p>Four years after the bombs fall, you (and, optionally, your friends, if you're playing in co-op) must scour&nbsp;<em>Terminator: Survivors</em>' open world for resources in order to survive, upgrade your base, and perhaps mount a counterattack against the machines.</p>
<p>You will be able to fight machines if you so desire, but it might be better to find a way to sneak around them in order to conserve resources (and, perhaps more importantly, your life).</p>
<p>You won't just be going up against Skynet's machines, either; you'll also have to contend with other scavengers, who will be competing with you for resources and space.</p>

<p>Sadly, we no longer know exactly when&nbsp;<em>Terminator: Survivors&nbsp;</em>will be launching, but we do know it'll be arriving sometime in 2025. Stay tuned for more as and when we get it.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every Big Disney Announcement At This Year's D23 Fanfest]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/d23-2024-disney-trailer-star-wars-avatar-inside-out-1851619627</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-big-disney-announcement-at-this-years-d23-fanfest.951087/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/d23-2024-disney-trailer-star-wars-avatar-inside-out-1851619627<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Disney’s “D23" fanfest is basically part E3, part Nintendo Direct, and this year’s event featured lots of trailers, vague announcements, and even concept art teasers. It was an extended content roadmap of big-budget productions hitting theaters and Disney+ in the months and years ahead, with a few surprises and gaming tie-ins to boot.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194644" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Return To Hyrule" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="165" data-playlist="194644,195670,195358" data-current="194644"><div><p>The Week In Games: Return To Hyrule</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194644/194644_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20101.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The magic of Disney was so strong at the event that at one point fans even cheered Bob Iger, the CEO who made $30 million last year and recently announced a Dinsey+ price hike and password sharing crackdown, as he walked out on stage. What has the executive helped engineer since coming out of retirement to win hearts and minds?</p><p>The answer is tons more sequels and spin-offs from the series and franchises people already love, from <em>Star Wars</em> and <em>Marvel</em> to <em>Snow White</em> and <em>Avatar</em>, with one or two gambles on entirely new stuff from the minds at Pixar and other places in the mix. Here’s all of the major announcements from this year’s D23:</p><h2 id="h3050"><a id=""></a>Here’s the <em>Moana 2</em> trailer</h2><p>If you have kids like me, then you’ve watched the original <em>Moana</em> a hundred million times. It’s still great, but I’m ready to see the seafaring princess and her side-kick Dwayne “The Rock” Johnson discover some new adventures.<em> Moana 2</em> hits theaters November 27, 2024. </p><h2 id="h3051"><a id=""></a>And our first-look at the live-action <em>Snow White</em></h2><p>Rachel Zegler as Snow White and Gal Gadot as the Evil Queen. How do you like them apples? This movie looks like it was made in Unreal Engine 6.<em> Snow White</em> is out March 21, 2025. </p><h2 id="h3052"><a id=""></a><em>Avatar 3</em> has an official title now</h2><figure id="" data-id="260a5bd3aaa02998ead49adffb60fd0b" data-recommend-id="image://260a5bd3aaa02998ead49adffb60fd0b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1080" data-height="607" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Avatar 3 is called Fire and Ash. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Avatar 3 is called Fire and Ash. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="260a5bd3aaa02998ead49adffb60fd0b" data-recommend-id="image://260a5bd3aaa02998ead49adffb60fd0b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1080" data-height="607" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Avatar 3 is called Fire and Ash. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>It took director James Cameron over a decade to make the sequel to the first <em>Avatar</em>. Fortunately, fans won’t have to wait long for the sequel to <em>Avatar 2</em>. The third movie is officially called <em>Avatar: Fire and Ash</em> and is out in theaters December 19, 2025. </p><h2 id="h3053"><a id=""></a><em>Inside Out </em>is getting a spin-off</h2><p> Dream Productions is a new Disney+ series that takes place between <em>Inside Out</em> 1 and 2 and begins streaming in 2025. Pixar also revealed its newest original movie called <em>Win or Lose</em>, which looks like a modern-day CGI twist on <em>The Sandlot</em>. That comes to Disney+ on December 6, 2024. </p><h2 id="h3054"><a id=""></a><em>Wall-E </em>writer teases <em>Toy Story 5</em></h2><p>Writer and director Andrew Stanton revealed that the big crisis in <em>Toy Story 5</em> is screentime. Woody, Buzz, and the rest of the gang will be fighting for their lives against the algorithm and the devices that power it, which is also what everyone will be watching the movie on. How meta. It’s coming in the summer of 2026. </p><h2 id="h3055"><a id=""></a>There’s an <em>Incredibles 3</em> in the works</h2><figure id="" data-id="e6b7bc06f131e6dcaee974bad0ef940c" data-recommend-id="image://e6b7bc06f131e6dcaee974bad0ef940c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1753" data-height="1373" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A logo shows Incredibles 3. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A logo shows Incredibles 3. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Disney</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e6b7bc06f131e6dcaee974bad0ef940c" data-recommend-id="image://e6b7bc06f131e6dcaee974bad0ef940c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1753" data-height="1373" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A logo shows Incredibles 3. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This was one of those extremely video-gamey announcements. Six years after <em>The Incredibles 2</em>, Disney announced the family of superhumans is doing another sequel, though we didn’t get a release date or even a teaser, just a logo. I wonder if it will make it out before<em> Kingdom Hearts 4</em>?</p><h2 id="h3056"><a id=""></a><em>Frozen 3 </em>concept art looks straight out of <em>Sleeping Beauty</em></h2><p>The <em>Frozen</em> universe lives on, and it’s looking heavily Eyvind Earle-inspired. A gorgeous piece of concept art flashed on screen during the presentation showed Elsa and Anna riding horses through the woods as a horned figure casts its shadow behind them. <em>Frozen 3</em> isn’t coming until around 2027, but Disney is already plotting for <em>Frozen 4</em> as well.</p><h2 id="h3057"><a id=""></a><em>Star Wars: Skeleton Crew</em> gets a teaser</h2><p>Steven Spielberg has never directed a<em> Star Wars</em> movie, but if he did it might look something like Skeleton Crew. It’s a coming-of-age tale about a grizzled Jude Law helping a rag-tag group of kids find their way home to the suburbs in a galaxy far, far away. It’s set in the New Republic era after <em>Return of the Jedi</em>. </p><h2 id="h3058"><a id=""></a><em>Andor </em>season 2 shows <em>Star Wars: Rogue One</em> cameos</h2><p>I need <em>Andor</em> season 2 and I need it now. Instead, I’ll have to subsist off the excitement of other people getting a sneak peak at cameos from returning characters like Ben Mendelsohn’s Orson Krennic and Alan Tudyk’s K-2SO. The single best piece of <em>Star Wars</em> storytelling from the past 20 years returns sometime in 2025. </p><h2 id="h3059"><a id=""></a>Grogu gets armor in the <em>Mandalorian </em>movie</h2><p>A teaser for <em>The Mandalorian &amp; Grogu</em> reportedly showed the titular characters facing down AT-AT’s on an ice planet, and this time around Grogu is decked out in a full set of Mando armor. The TV series’ jump to the big screen doesn’t come out until May 22, 2026. </p><h2 id="h3060"><a id=""></a><em>Black Panther 2</em> spin-off<em> Ironheart </em>gets a teaser</h2><p>Dominique Thorne’s Riri Williams from <em>Black Panther 2 </em>will be toiling away on new inventions at MIT in the spin-off <em>Ironheart</em>. Ryan Coogler made the announcement with a teaser showing Riri putting together a new suit of armor. </p><h2 id="h3061"><a id=""></a><em>Daredevil: Born Again</em> lands in March 2025</h2><p>Netflix’s <em>Daredevil</em> is finally being revived next year with the original cast. Matt Murdock will once again be taking on the Punisher and Kingpin when the series returns to Disney+ in March, 2025. </p><h2 id="h3062"><a id=""></a><em>Agatha All Along</em> has a final trailer</h2><p>The<em> WandaVision</em> sequel is just around the corner, and Kathryn Hahn’s witch Agatha Harkness will be facing a series of trials in order to get her powers back in time for her next Marvel cameo. <em>Agatha All Along</em> starts streaming September 18, 2024. </p><h2 id="h3063"><a id=""></a><strong><em>Lilo &amp; Stitch </em>movie teases live-action alien</strong></h2><p>I’m saving one of the best for near the end. Everyone’s favorite aughts alien  furball is getting extra furry in hi-def CGI. Here’s your first taste of “live-action” Stitch. The <em>Lilo &amp; Stitch</em> live-action movie arrives in summer 2024. </p><h2 id="h3064"><a id=""></a>There’s a new <em>Tron</em> movie coming</h2><p>If you thought Disney was going to let the Tron universe rest in peace, then you don’t know Bob Iger. Jeff Bridges and Jared Leto were on stage to present <em>Tron: Ares </em>with Trent Reznor and Atticus Ross’ Nine Inch Nails doing the soundtrack for it. We have no idea what it’s about but my money’s on an unstoppable generative-AI takeover. The third <em>Tron</em> movie is aiming for October 10, 2025, which is 15 years after <em>Tron: Legacy </em>and a whopping 40 years after the original. </p><h2 id="h3065"><a id=""></a><em>Fortnite</em> x Marvel: Absolute Doom is the battle royale’s next big event</h2><p><em>Fortnite</em>’s next season is all Marvel-focused. In addition to X-Men skins themed around the Disney + retro revival<em> X-Men 97 </em>that lets players turn into Cyclops, Jubilee, and Colossus, the next battle pass is a Dr. Doom takeover kicking off on August 16. I hope <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/robert-downey-jr-dr-doom-mcu-pay-controversy-1851609881&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/robert-downey-jr-dr-doom-mcu-pay-controversy-1851609881">Robert Downey Jr.</a></span> is one of the rewards. Moff Gideon and IG-11 from <em>Star Wars </em>as well as the<em> Incredibles</em> characters also got added over the weekend. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands Might Be 2024's Biggest Box Office Flop]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-box-office-flop-bomb-2024-gearbox-1851619588</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-might-be-2024s-biggest-box-office-flop.951084/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-box-office-flop-bomb-2024-gearbox-1851619588<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-review-rotten-tomatoes-cast-release-1851616912&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-review-rotten-tomatoes-cast-release-1851616912">The <em>Borderlands</em> movie</a></span> finally hit theaters this past weekend and quickly became one of the worst-reviewed movies of 2024. So it’s probably not surprising that <em>Borderlands </em>is bombing hard at the box office and might end up being the biggest flop of the year. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196049" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="134" data-playlist="196049,196163,196653" data-current="196049"><div><p>This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21580.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-3-movie-new-update-auto-sell-loot-max-level-1851617206&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-3-movie-new-update-auto-sell-loot-max-level-1851617206"><em>Borderlands</em></a></span>, out now in theaters, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-reviews-impressions-bad-good-negative-1851615664&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-reviews-impressions-bad-good-negative-1851615664">has received mostly negative reviews</a></span> and debuted on Rotten Tomatoes with a horrific O%, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/borderlands&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/borderlands" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">which has since increased to 9%</a></span>. The <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-r-rated-pg-13-eli-roth-interview-1851618411&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-r-rated-pg-13-eli-roth-interview-1851618411">PG-13 live-action adaption</a></span> of Gearbox’s popular sci-fi FPS franchise has been criticized for bad action, unfunny jokes, and a bizarre cast led by horror director Eli Roth. And after its first big opening weekend, <em>Borderlands </em>made less than $17 million globally. Yikes. <br></p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://variety.com/2024/film/box-office/box-office-it-ends-with-us-beats-exectations-borderlands-flops-1236103106/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://variety.com/2024/film/box-office/box-office-it-ends-with-us-beats-exectations-borderlands-flops-1236103106/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">As reported by <em>Variety</em></a></span>, Lionsgate’s <em>Borderlands </em>movie landed in theaters at number four, behind <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/twisters-regal-4dx-theater-experience-tornado-1851598749&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/twisters-regal-4dx-theater-experience-tornado-1851598749"><em>Twisters</em></a></span>,<em> It Ends With Us</em>, and the newest <em>Deadpool</em> film. In the United States, <em>Borderlands </em>brought in just $8.8 million from over 3,000 theaters, which makes it one of the worst opening weekends for a video game movie in a long time. </p><p>To put that number in perspective,<em> </em><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.boxofficemojo.com/genre/sg316600577/?sort=openingWeekendGross&amp;ref_=bo_ge__resort#table&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.boxofficemojo.com/genre/sg316600577/?sort=openingWeekendGross&amp;ref_=bo_ge__resort#table" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Assassin’s Creed, Angry Birds 2,</em> and the first <em>Hitman</em> adaptation</a></span> all made more than <em>Borderlands </em>in their first weekends at the box office. (<em>Borderlands </em>had the added advantage of IMAX screens, which cost more and tend to help modern tent poles pull in bigger returns.) </p><p>Outside the US, <em>Borderlands </em>was a bigger flop, earning just $7.7 million from foreign theaters. Add it all up and <em>Borderlands </em>made just $16.5 million after its opening weekend. It’s not a great start for a movie that reportedly cost around $150 million to produce and market.</p><p>Most big blockbusters tend to make a ton of money in the first weekend or so and then drop-off happens. Considering how little <em>Borderlands </em>has made so far and how bad reviews have been, it’s very possible that we might see the new video game film make less than $5 million globally next weekend which would be pretty embarrassing for Lionsgate. Video game adaptions are hot right now in Hollywood and yet, <em>Borderlands </em>has failed to connect with anyone it seems.</p><p>Let’s all take bets on how quickly this thing arrives on streaming as its box office returns get smaller and smaller in the coming weeks. </p><p> .</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone announced for consoles, PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-announced-for-consoles-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-announced-for-consoles-pc.951081/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone-announced-for-consoles-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Post-apocalyptic action RPG due out in 2025.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > The Farm 51 [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/the-farm-51">The Farm 51</a> has announced post-apocalyptic <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,280 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> sequel <em><a title="Games > Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone">Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone</a></em> for unspecified consoles and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,855 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2075100/Chernobylite_2_Exclusion_Zone/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch in 2025. <span id="more-905164"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2075100/Chernobylite_2_Exclusion_Zone/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone</em> is a post-apocalyptic action RPG game, mixing free exploration of huge and extremely realistic open world, challenging combat, unique crafting, team and base management with non-linear storytelling. You’re a planewalker who travels through parallel worlds in search of the precious, high-energy material called Chernobylite. Cut off from the world, trapped in the Zone, attacked by hordes of nightmare creatures, you must fight for survival and unite the handful of remaining survivors.</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_905176"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Open World Exploration</strong> – Explore the big and realistic open world of the real Chornobyl Exclusion Zone. <a title="Games > Chernobylite [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/chernobylite">Chernobylite</a> has taken over the zone, transforming many of its elements, and people are trying to defend themselves against it using prototype technology.</li><li><strong>Character Development</strong> – Create and develop your hero. Attributes and skills will affect the effectiveness of combat, as well as the style of conversation. An arrogant muscle man with a big sword trying to intimidate everyone? Or a smart sniper who always finds the right arguments? The choice is yours.</li><li><strong>Diverse Combat</strong> – Fight for <a title="Genres > Survival [301 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> with an advanced melee combat system, or keep your enemies away with a diverse arsenal of firearms. You can also use the <a title="Genres > Stealth [66 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a> approach or ask others for help.</li><li><strong>Team Building</strong> – Embark on the exciting journey of team building. Each of your mates is a potential teacher, ready to impart their knowledge and skills. Assemble your team and discover the unique strengths and abilities they bring. The question is, will you earn their trust and unlock their full potential?</li><li><strong>Planewalking</strong> – Adapt your build and equipment to the situation with planewalking, which allows you to change things on the fly. You’re free to develop more than one character skill set. Are you encountering a situation that your previously prepared heavy melee build will solve better than your current ranged sniper? Planewalk and use another one.</li><li><strong>Base Development</strong> – Develop your base. There, you can create valuable items and upgrade your weapons every day. Assign your people to tasks, and they will take care of your equipment and supplies.</li><li><strong>Factions</strong> – Fight for influence and negotiate with factions. The Exclusion Zone is a battlefield that changes every day and reacts to your every <a title="Genres > Action [2,072 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>. Can you help them defeat the army of vicious monsters? And when old conflicts are revived, whose side will you be on?</li><li><strong>Cooperative Missions</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> online <a title="Genres > Co-Op [188 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> missions embedded in a single-player campaign allowing players to interact in various ways to achieve the goal.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/chernobylite-2-exclusion-zone/august-12-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Chernobylite 2: Exclusion Zone – Official Reveal Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VJGew7S6pZc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Valve's New Game Hasn't Been Announced, Already Has Almost 17,000 Concurrent Players]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/valves-new-game-hasnt-been-announced-already-has-almost-17000-concurrent-players/1100-6525718/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/valves-new-game-hasnt-been-announced-already-has-almost-17-000-concurrent-players.951078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/valves-new-game-hasnt-been-announced-already-has-almost-17000-concurrent-players/1100-6525718/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525718">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Valve's apparent next project, Deadlock, already has a concurrent player count and the game hasn't even been announced.</p><p>On <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1422450/charts/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">SteamDB</a>, Deadlock is sitting at a concurrent player count of 16,947, with a little more than 13,000 players playing right now, which is more than games like Payday 2 and NBA 2K24 <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/mostplayed" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">at the moment.</a> The issue is that Deadlock hasn't been announced or revealed in any capacity. When trying to install the game through clicking the button on the SteamDB page, Steam returns with a screen that says, "An error occurred while launching this game: Game configuration unavailable."</p><p>Footage of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/footage-of-valves-rumored-moba-shooter-deadlock-leaks-online-showing-off-steampunk-action/1100-6523639/" data-ref-id="1100-6523639">Deadlock surfaced earlier</a> this year when it was leaked online. It's reportedly a multiplayer hero shooter similar to Overwatch, and has influences from other games like Valorant and Smite, as well as Valve's own games such as Dota 2 and Team Fortress 2.</p><p>Deadlock isn't the only project Valve could be working on. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dataminer-thinks-half-life-3-is-in-development-after-resume-leak/1100-6525527/" data-ref-id="1100-6525527">Half-Life 3 is reportedly</a> in development after an actress's resume listed a Valve project as "Project White Sands."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525498&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-advent-calendars-2024-star-wars-spider-man-harry-potter-disney\/1100-6525498\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525539&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/house-of-the-dragon-season-two-blu-ray-preorders-game-of-thrones\/1100-6525539\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525128&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-make-a-fence-in-minecraft\/1100-6525128\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525552&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dead-by-daylight-and-five-nights-at-freddys-are-finally-crossing-over\/1100-6525552\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525553&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/black-myth-wukong-development-is-done-and-devs-ask-fans-not-to-spoil-the-game\/1100-6525553\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525557&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-pc-requirements\/1100-6525557\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525451&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/jeff-vandermeer-absolution-southern-reach-annihilation-preorder-guide\/1100-6525451\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525545&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fall-guys-invades-fortnites-battle-royale-modes\/1100-6525545\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525558&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/constantine-2-producer-explains-why-the-character-still-resonates-with-fans\/1100-6525558\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525542&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/m-night-shayamalan-trap-4k-blu-ray-preorder-amazon\/1100-6525542\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525560&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cod-black-ops-6-leaks-reveal-a-controversial-warzone-map-with-caldera-2-0-vibes\/1100-6525560\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525565&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cod-warzone-and-mw3-patch-notes-include-nerfs-for-the-rpk-and-superi-46\/1100-6525565\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525562&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/balatro-creator-stipulates-in-will-that-game-cant-be-used-for-gambling\/1100-6525562\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525566&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/descenders-next-is-a-full-sequel-coming-in-2025-day-one-to-game-pass\/1100-6525566\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525569&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/review-roundup-for-steamworld-heist-2\/1100-6525569\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525572&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cod-black-ops-6-zombies-terminus-map-trailer-reveals-new-story-details\/1100-6525572\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525567&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/metal-gear-solid-nendoroid-preorders-restocked-at-amazon-low-poly-snake-and-naked-raiden\/1100-6525567\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525570&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/transformers-gi-joe-movie-isnt-a-crossover-exactly-producer-explains\/1100-6525570\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525564&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/jack-black-finished-recording-his-borderlands-role-before-filming-began\/1100-6525564\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525571&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/jenna-ortega-revisits-her-controversial-wednesday-comments\/1100-6525571\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Obituary: Rachael Lillis, iconic Pokémon voice actor, has died at age 46]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/obituary-rachael-lillis-iconic-pok-mon-voice-actor-has-died-at-age-46</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/obituary-rachael-lillis-iconic-pok%C3%A9mon-voice-actor-has-died-at-age-46.951075/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/obituary-rachael-lillis-iconic-pok-mon-voice-actor-has-died-at-age-46<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Rachael Lillis, a voice actor best known for playing Jessie and Misty in Pokémon's anime dub, has passed away from cancer. She was 46.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Per voice actor </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/TheVeronicaT/status/1823000035883438271">Veronica Taylor</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (the original dub voice of Ash), Lillis passed on Saturday, August 10. Taylor went on to describe her as "an extraordinary talent, a bright light that shone through her voice whether speaking or singing.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Born July 8, 1978, Lillis landed her first principal voice acting role in 1997's Takegami: Guardians of Darkness. Throughout her career, she provided voices for series such as Revolutionary Girl Utena, Hunter x Hunter, and the 2003 Ninja Turtles cartoon.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game-wise, she reprised the role of Misty and Jessie in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Pokémon: Puzzle League. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">She voiced Jigglypuff in that game and the Super Smash Bros. series, and also did voices for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Lego Jurassic World </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ape Escape 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In addition to voice acting, Lillis also adapted and translated scripts for Apocalypse Zero and Cleopatra DC.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">After news of her passing, various voice actors eulogized her on social media. "An icon gone too soon," wrote </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Mortal Kombat 1 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">actor </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/KaijiTang/status/1823013498659459319">Kaiji Tang</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "Rachael was responsible for so many happy Saturday mornings for so many kids, myself included. We will always remember your voice."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"While she had many other incredible roles, growing up with the Pokémon anime wouldn’t have been the same without her and her amazing talent," added voice actor </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/LeonhartYT/status/1823007944511770882">Leonhart</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "My condolences."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Please know that Rachael saw your messages and contributions and was so touched and so grateful," said </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/TaraSandsVO/status/1823005535245144556">Tara Sands</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Bulbasaur's original dub voice. "A wonderful person gone way too soon."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"[Rachael] worked hard and cared deeply," continued </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/TheVeronicaT/status/1823000039138205802">Taylor</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "Like the shooting stars in the Perseids, she was a magnificent wonder and truly special. She burned bright and vanished too soon. She will live on in our memories for eternity."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Following her cancer diagnosis in May, a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-my-sister-rachael-with-medical-needs">GoFundMe</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was launched to help raise money for her care. Payments will now go toward remaining medical bills, a memorial, and causes in her name to combat cancer.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"My heart breaks losing my dear little sister, though I am comforted knowing she is free," wrote Laurie Orr. "We ask for peace, for now, as her family grieves this loss."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[John Carpenter's Halloween is getting two games from Evil Dead publisher]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/john-carpenters-halloween-is-getting-two-game-adaptations-from-evil-dead-publisher</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/john-carpenters-halloween-is-getting-two-games-from-evil-dead-publisher.951072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/john-carpenters-halloween-is-getting-two-game-adaptations-from-evil-dead-publisher<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Carpenter "intimately involved" in one project.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/halloween-the-game-art.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Boss Team Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
John Carpenter's seminal horror movie franchise Halloween is getting two new video game adaptations from Boss Team Games, the publisher behind 2022's Evil Dead: The Game.
</p>
<p>
That's <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/halloween-unreal-engine-5-john-carpenter-boss-team-games">according to IGN</a>, which says both titles will be based on Carpenter's original 1978 Halloween movie, which saw Jamie Lee Curtis' Laurie Strode taking on masked serial killer Michael Myers. Specifics are scarce, but the games will reportedly enable players to "relive moments from the film and play as classic characters".
</p>
<p>
The projects - which will be the first proper video game adaptations of Halloween since it appeared on the Atari 2600 back in 1983 - are being developed in conjunction with the franchise's producers, with Carpenter said to be "intimately involved" in one of the titles.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PlayStation live-service Concord won't sell you a battle pass - would it be better if it did?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PlayStation live-service Concord won't sell you a battle pass - would it be better if it did?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>PlayStation live-service Concord won't sell you a battle pass - but would it be more successful if it did?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1LcpqnUgV5E" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
"As a huge gamer myself," Carpenter wrote in a statement provided to IGN, "I'm thrilled to help bring Michael Myers to life again in this game, and my hope is to scare you silly".
</p>
<p>
There's no hint of a release date for either Halloween project just yet, and the only other bit of detail to be gleaned from the announcement is that the game Carpenter will be involved in is being developed using Unreal Engine 5.
</p>
<p>
Boss Team Games' previous horror movie adaptation, Evil Dead: The Game, was developed by Saber Interactive and recieved a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/evil-dead-the-game-understands-evil-dead-the-movies-better-than-i-expected">positive reception</a> when it launched back in 2022. However, the asymmetrical multiplayer title received only sporadic post-launch support, and Saber announced it was cancelling the Switch version and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/last-years-multiplayer-evil-dead-game-wont-get-new-content-switch-version-canned">ending all development</a> 18 months later.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Terminator: Survivors early access will now release in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/12/terminator-survivors-early-access-will-now-release-in-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/terminator-survivors-early-access-will-now-release-in-2025.951066/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/12/terminator-survivors-early-access-will-now-release-in-2025/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Terminator: Survivors will not hit its early access target of October 2024, NACON has confirmed. Instead, Terminator: Survivors early access is now set for 2025 though a more specific release window has not been given. The reason for the delay is that NACON Studio Milan needs more time to develop and have the game ready for early access.</p>
<p><iframe title="Terminator: Survivors | The Aftermath Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LepEDOgw0Ec?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p dir="ltr">Marco Ponte, CEO &amp; Creative Director of NACON Studio Milan, made the following statement:&nbsp;<em>“This deferral of the game’s release was a tough decision to make, however we believe that this additional time will enable us to ensure that our vision of the post-apocalyptic world of Terminator meets the expected level of quality. </em><em>On behalf of the NACON Studio Milan team, I would like to thank all the players and fans of the franchise for their enthusiastic reception of Terminator: Survivors. We are extremely proud to have this opportunity to work on such an iconic franchise as Terminator, and are eager to reveal more of it to you. Thank you all for support… We’ll be back.”</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Terminator: Survivors is a sequel to Terminator 2. The story is set in 2009, a time before John Connor’s resistance has risen up against the machines. You are a survivor and do not have much information as to what brought about the apocalypse. However, as you build up your base and scavenge through the surrounding areas, the narrative running through the game will see you learn about SkyNet, about the emerging resistance and more. The game will be playable both solo or co-op, working together to survive the in newly formed wasteland against humans and machines.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Fans Pay Tribute As Original Misty Voice Actor Dies At 46]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-misty-jessie-jigglypuff-voice-rachael-lillis-1851619597</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-fans-pay-tribute-as-original-misty-voice-actor-dies-at-46.951054/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/pokemon-misty-jessie-jigglypuff-voice-rachael-lillis-1851619597<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="f8b4e26d50a9aaf515818a69aa1d9fb2" data-recommend-id="image://f8b4e26d50a9aaf515818a69aa1d9fb2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Misty extends her hand out during a battle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Misty extends her hand out during a battle." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->The Pokémon Company</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f8b4e26d50a9aaf515818a69aa1d9fb2" data-recommend-id="image://f8b4e26d50a9aaf515818a69aa1d9fb2" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Misty extends her hand out during a battle." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>After a battle with breast cancer, Rachael Lillis, the original English voice actor for some of <em>Pokémon</em>’s most iconic characters, has died at 46. News of this came from a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/TheVeronicaT/status/1823000035883438271&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/TheVeronicaT/status/1823000035883438271" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">social media post from Veronica Taylor</a></span>, who originally voiced <em>Pokémon </em>anime protagonist <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-anime-ash-ketchum-pikachu-final-episode-netflix-1850805389&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-anime-ash-ketchum-pikachu-final-episode-netflix-1850805389">Ash Ketchum</a></span> and co-starred alongside Lillis in the early seasons of the show. Lillis was best known for her work as Ash’s traveling companion Misty, Team Rocket’s Jessie, and several Pokémon throughout the series.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196165" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="95" data-playlist="196165,192873,192995" data-current="196165"><div><p>What’s Coming Out Beyond Pokémon: The Indigo Disk | The Week In Games</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196165/196165_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21711.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Taylor’s post confirmed that Lillis passed on August 10. Lillis’ breast cancer diagnosis was announced in May and a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-my-sister-rachael-with-medical-needs?utm_campaign=p_cp+share-sheet&amp;utm_content=v2_shareai_control&amp;utm_medium=copy_link_all&amp;utm_source=customer&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-my-sister-rachael-with-medical-needs?utm_campaign=p_cp+share-sheet&amp;utm_content=v2_shareai_control&amp;utm_medium=copy_link_all&amp;utm_source=customer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GoFundMe campaign</a></span> was set up to help raise money for her medical care. Donors helped raise over $96,000.</p><p>“Rachael was so thankful for all of the generous love and support that was given to her as she battled with cancer,” Taylor wrote in her post. “It truly made a positive difference. Her family also wishes to thank you as they take this time to grieve privately.”</p><p>As news of Lillis’ passing spread online, <em>Pokémon </em>fans and other voice actors paid tribute to her with posts of their own, recounting how her voice work colored so many of their childhood memories watching the early seasons of the anime.</p><p>Lillis’ work as Misty and Jessie ended in 2006 after the <em>Pokémon </em>anime dub production shifted from 4Kids to The Pokémon Company, resulting in the recasting of nearly every character in the show. However, Lillis’ voice has persisted through much of <em>Pokémon </em>media, as she also voiced Jigglypuff, and her performance as the singing Normal/Fairy-type Pokémon has been used in more recent games and appearances like 2018’s <em>Super Smash Bros. Ultimate </em>and the 2019 <em>Detective Pikachu </em>film. <br></p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kiborg: Arena Is a Brutal Cyberpunk Beat-’Em-up with a Roguelite Twist]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/kiborg-arena-is-a-brutal-cyberpunk-beat-em-up-with-a-roguelite-twist</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kiborg-arena-is-a-brutal-cyberpunk-beat-%E2%80%99em-up-with-a-roguelite-twist.951051/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/kiborg-arena-is-a-brutal-cyberpunk-beat-em-up-with-a-roguelite-twist<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Developer Sobaka Studio's sci-fi brawler takes players through a cyberpunk gauntlet.</h2></div><section><p>The cyberpunk subgenre has been a visually and conceptually compelling backdrop for RPGs, first-person shooters, and narrative-driven mysteries. But the upcoming Kiborg from Sobaka Studios looks to turn the high-tech, low-lives conceit into a vehicle for a high-octane action brawler—with a roguelite twist. Leaning into the intense body modification and grotesque horrors that advanced technology can bring, Kiborg focuses on fast-paced, crunchy combat that's all powered by some bizarre yet intriguing upgrades that can light up the battle zone.</p><p>Just ahead of the release of the upcoming playable prologue that sets the stage for the main game, I forged through a gauntlet of mutants, cyborgs, and giant robots with an assortment of deadly upgrades to tear through the competition in this roguelite beat-em-up spin on cyberpunk fiction.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Kiborg sees you take on the role of Morgan, a resistance fighter who outfits himself and his clones with tech upgrades to even the odds in his fight against rival factions on a wartorn prison planet. The protagonist will have to prepare himself for his descent into the carnage by training in the Arena, a VR combat simulator that supplies an endless array of foes and deadly traps in a battle zone that feels inspired by the spectacle of Mad Max: Beyond Thunderdome.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The Arena does a great job of establishing the mood of this hyper-violent grim world.</p></div><p>Kiborg: Arena and its ladder-style progression are a prologue to the main game, which features a more robust roguelite campaign across different locales. The Arena not only does a great job of establishing the mood of this hyper-violent grim world, but also chucked me into the deep end to get me accustomed to the intriguing blend of beat-em-up action and randomized roguelite-style upgrades. Along with an extended tutorial, which helped me get into the flow and learn the basics of its brawler-style combat, you also have an AI companion who will offer Morgan tips on how best to move up the ladder of the Arena.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>The combat arena focuses on the familiar wave-based encounters, with each proceeding wave adding new enemies and traps and even arranging the layout of the zone itself. The core combat of Kiborg focuses primarily on Morgan's moveset of punches, kicks, pulverizing strikes, and parrying. Morgan also wields an upgradable firearm that's exceptionally vital against enemies too far out of the way. You can also earn permanent boosts for Morgan's core skills and attributes in the upgrade menu outside of the Arena, which adds buffs and extends his health.</p><p>Like any brawler, mastering Kiborg's combat is all about having a strong offensive strategy while keeping you ready to play defense. Kiborg is packed with grit and a lot of style, making the act of tearing through foes very satisfying when you get into a rhythm. However, combat can be quite unforgiving if you don't find that flow. This is especially evident when facing a mob of enemies, each requiring specific strategies. Added to this is the game's somewhat unpolished attack timing and visual, which knocked me out of step in some encounters.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>However, what makes Kiborg and its approach to a cyberpunk brawler truly come together is the satisfying array of cyborg upgrades that modify Morgan's body parts with specialized attributes. The tech upgrades gained from elite foes after pulling off a finishing move similar to Raiden from Metal Gear Rising Revengeance add a whole new layer to the combat. In roguelite fashion, you'll need to decide which upgrade from the selection that will help you go all the way.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Some of my favorite moments came from diving into a crowd of enemies and unleashing a flurry of strikes that were amplified by chained lightning, homing razor blades, and even cyborg legs that left a streak of flames on the ground.</p></div><p>Some of my favorite moments came from diving into a crowd of enemies and unleashing a flurry of strikes that were amplified by chained lightning, homing razor blades, and even cyborg legs that left a streak of flames on the ground. One of the great thrills of a roguelite is seeing your modest hero evolve into a death-dealing warrior, and Kiborg's building transformation into a super soldier with every round was so exciting to see unfold.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Kiborg and its Arena prologue show a promising, modest take on a cyberpunk action beat-em-up, even if it's rough around the edges as of this preview. Still, I had a ton of fun with being able to rip and tear through enemies with some pulverizing cybernetic upgrades, and each attempt felt so different from the last. With the full game set for later release, Kiborg: Arena is just the teaser that'll give players a solid sampling of this sleek blend of beat-em-up action and the cyberpunk mystique.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EXCLUSIVE: Halloween Is Getting Its Own Unreal Engine 5 Game With John Carpenter 'Intimately Involved']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/halloween-unreal-engine-5-john-carpenter-boss-team-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exclusive-halloween-is-getting-its-own-unreal-engine-5-game-with-john-carpenter-intimately-involved.951048/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/halloween-unreal-engine-5-john-carpenter-boss-team-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Evil Dead: The Game studio Boss Team Games are working on two games based on the 1978 horror classic.</h2></div><section><p>Two new games based on the 1978 horror classic Halloween are in development at Boss Team Games, IGN can exclusively reveal.</p><p>While details are limited, both games are apparently being developed in conjunction with the producers of the Halloween franchise. What's more, one of the games is being developed in Unreal Engine 5, and will include input from original director John Carpenter.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/09/halloweengame-poster-square-v1-no-fold-copy-1723247067624.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>The first promo image from Boss Team Games' Halloween game. Image source: Boss Team Games</figcaption></figure></output><p>"<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/horror-legend-john-carpenter-just-wants-to-play-video-games-watch-basketball-and-eat-popsicles">As a huge gamer myself</a>, I’m thrilled to help bring Michael Myers to life again in this game, and my hope is to scare you silly," said Carpenter, who will be "intimately involved" with the development of the new project. </p><p>According to the official release, the games will allow players to "relive moments from the film and play as classic characterse from one of the most iconic and important horror films of all time." The two new games are being developed in association with Compass International Pictures and Further Front, with the Unreal Engine 5 project still early in development. </p><p>While Halloween is now more than 45 years old, there have been few video games based on the legendary slash franchise. The closest the series has seen to an actual adaptation 1983's Halloween on the Atari 2600 in which you play as a babysitter — presumably Laurie Strode — trying to find a safe room while being hunted by Michael Myers. <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/dead-by-daylight/The_Shape_Perks">The Shape is also one of many villains to appear in Dead by Daylight</a>, Behaviour Interactive's popular multiplayer horror game.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The Top 31 Horror Movie Villains</h3></div></output><p>Boss Team Games, for its part, returns to the horror genre after previously working on Evil Dead: The Game. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/evil-dead-the-game-review">In our review we wrote</a>, "Evil Dead: The Game is an awesome asymmetric multiplayer game that, like its source material, is far better than it has any right to be given its frustrating lack of polish and being somewhat light on maps and modes."</p><p>“Everyone at Boss Team Games are huge fans of horror and <em>Halloween</em> obviously holds a special place in the hearts of all horror fans,” said Boss Team Games CEO Steve Harris  “Getting to work with iconic characters like Michael Myers and build on John Carpenter’s original vision is literally a dream come true.  Everyone at Boss Team is thrilled and honored to be working with Malek Akkad and John Carpenter to deliver a one-of-a-kind experience that fans of the movie and video games will love.”  </p><p>Neither Halloween project has a release date yet. For more, be sure to check our list of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-horror-games-on-pc">best horror video games on PC</a>.</p><p><em>Kat Bailey is IGN's News Director as well as co-host of Nintendo Voice Chat. Have a tip? Send her a DM at @the_katbot.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft hints at longer Assassin's Creed development times ahead of Shadows debut]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-hints-at-longer-assassins-creed-development-times-ahead-of-shadows-debut</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-hints-at-longer-assassins-creed-development-times-ahead-of-shadows-debut.951042/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-hints-at-longer-assassins-creed-development-times-ahead-of-shadows-debut<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"We always want to go better."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/shadows-header_rKxn1pw.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Ubisoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Ubisoft is set to release the latest entry in its long running Assassin's Creed series in a few months, and ahead of this has suggested future games will see a longer development time.</p>
<p>When <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/assassins-creed-codename-red">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a> launches this November, it will have been in development for four years. This will mark the longest development period for the series to date, coming in at a year longer than that of previous series tentpole <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/assassins-creed-valhalla">Assassin's Creed Valhalla</a> (which released in 2020).</p>
<p>However, according to Shadows' lead producer Karl Onnée, four years is "the right balance to go from conception to production and get the feedback necessary to adapt" an Assassin's Creed game.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Assassin's Creed Shadows Official World Premiere Trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-Ae1eEOpUvo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"It's great to work on a game that comes after something with the pedigree of Valhalla... but obviously there are great expectations," Onnée told Eurogamer's sister site <a href="http://gamesindustry.biz/">GamesIndustry.biz</a>. "We always want to go better, which is what we're trying to do with Shadows.</p>
<p>"We are pushing the limits of what we can do."</p>
<p>This desire to keep making the series better than any given predecessor and the various iterations a game goes through is something the Assassin's Creed developer said can't be hurried. While Onnée appreciated there is - of course - a balance that needs to be struck between time and overall costs, he said the more time developers have, the "more you can iterate" on the end product. This is regardless of if the team is big or small.</p>
<p>"Yes, you can put more people on a project and do it in a shorter time, but that doesn't give you more time to iterate, because it takes time to get the feedback from your players, your team... and then see what works and what doesn't and how to improve it," he said.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Yasuke-fights-Assassins-Creed-Shadows.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Ubisoft</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for Shadows' setting of feudal Japan, Onnée said it was "something [Ubisoft has] always wanted to do", but it was about finding the right time to do it.</p>
<p>"I'm sure the other teams would have liked to do it, too. We had the opportunity because we had done Assassin's Creed Odyssey [set in Greece], so we had the experience," the developer explained. "But it also felt like the right moment, because we have the power in terms of the hardware, but also our new version of the engine, so we could really deliver our vision."</p>
<p>The Shadows team now hopes its setting will allow the game to reach a wider audience. "Since we are making a game in Japan, we do hope to appeal to more Japanese players. So, it is very important that we try to be as authentic as possible," Onnée said. "We come from a humble position of we don't know anything and we need to learn everything from scratch. We are making sure we respect things, because that is something very important to Japanese people, as it is in many other countries.</p>
<p>"When you come in, you don't want to come in as if you know everything. We want to build something that when they see and play it, they will recognise their own country."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Assassins-Creed-Shadows-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Ubisoft</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Onnée's comments come following discourse surrounding Shadow's co-lead Yasuke, an African samurai. When Ubisoft unveiled Assassin's Creed Shadows in May, there was backlash directed at the inclusion of this historical character.</p>
<p>In July, the Shadows development team <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-shadows-team-acknowledges-elements-that-have-caused-concern-among-japanese-fans">apologised for elements in the game's marketing campaign</a> that jarred with some Japanese fans - and said the game will "keep evolving" as it heads towards launch in November. It specifically mentioned Yasuke in its post.</p>
<p>Prior to this apology, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-boss-condemns-malicious-developer-abuse-after-assassins-creed-shadows-reveal">Ubisoft boss Yves Guillemot spoke out to condemn "malicious and personal online attacks" directed at Assassin's Creed Shadows' development team</a> following its May reveal.</p>
<p>Assassin's Creed boss Marc-Alexis Coté also addressed the matter, and discussed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/assassins-creed-shadows-boss-explains-why-he-ignored-elon-musk-after-backlash-over-african-samurai-yasuke">how he reacted to a post from billionaire X and Tesla owner Elon Musk criticising diversity in game design</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney Spent All That Money On… Fortnite Skins?]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/disney-fortnite-d23</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-spent-all-that-money-on%E2%80%A6-fortnite-skins.951039/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/disney-fortnite-d23<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>On Saturday night–and also an interminable half an hour late, maybe because of <a href="https://x.com/Jwhitbrook/status/1822484276388270296" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">too many musical numbers</a>–Disney revealed <a href="https://thewaltdisneycompany.com/disney-and-epic-games-fortnite/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the first phase of its 1.5 billion dollar collaboration with Epic</a>. What was all that money and waiting for? So far, another <em>Fortnite</em> Marvel season and some skins.</p><p>At the D23 Disney fan expo’s <em>Fortnite</em> event, which took place live and also in the game, various Disney people announced various Disney things. The next <em>Fortnite</em> season, starting August 16, will be Doctor Doom-themed, a callback to <a href="https://kotaku.com/i-wont-miss-fortnites-marvel-season-1845768727" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2020</a>’s first Marvel season. Disney villains will also be coming to <em>Fortnite</em> in the fall, as well as Pixar characters, in the form of The Incredibles. And there’ll also be <em>Mandalorian</em> characters, including a Grogu back bling you can get today.</p><p>According to <a href="https://variety.com/2024/gaming/news/marvel-doctor-doom-fantastic-four-d23-fortnite-epic-games-1236100375/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Variety</a>, 1.2 million concurrent players watched the event inside <em>Fortnite</em>, which pales in comparison to<a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1235632/fortnite-biggest-live-events/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> previous events</a> like the Travis Scott concert (12.3 million) or the first Marvel season’s Galactus finale (15.3). This isn’t necessarily an indictment–actually <em>playing</em> the game is far more interesting than watching some corporate guys announce some things–but I think it does speak to what a dud the event felt like.</p><p>No shade if you’re excited for Disney characters, but the fact that all this hype and money was building toward licensed skins, something <em>Fortnite</em> already has in droves, felt disappointing. As several people on stage said, this is only the beginning of the Disney/Epic partnership–there’s <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-is-getting-its-own-in-game-disney-store-according-to-leak/1100-6525674/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rumors</a> about a dedicated Disney store coming to <em>Fortnite</em>, which is still just skins but at least in a slightly different format–so we’re likely to see more robust offerings in the future.</p><p>But none of this felt very creative, or new, or special. As Chris Franklin said on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/campster.bsky.social/post/3kzg5jyezxy2b" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bluesky</a>, “How do you unite Star Wars, Marvel, Princesses, Pixar, Theme Parks, etc under one banner in the context of<em> Fortnite</em>? I'm really curious what their vision is. And this was...This was announcing Mr. Incredible is going to be able to shotgun you and then dance to Gangnam Style.”&nbsp;</p><p>Marvel Studios' Kevin Feige maybe inadvertently hit the nail on the head in his portion of the event:&nbsp;</p><blockquote><p>A lot of people learn about our characters for the first time–Thanos, Galactus–through <em>Fortnite</em>, so we get a chance that everybody can learn about our heroes and our villains for the first time, and that inspires them to then go look at our comics, go on Disney Plus, go to our movies. So this new collaboration is really remarkable: games have become an extension of our storytelling, and I can’t wait for everybody to see what we have in store in the future with this amazing collaboration.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>So: marketing, basically, getting people sucked into the Disney universe and shelling out money for its movies and streaming service, which are <a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/disney-layoffs-television-1236091773/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">laying off employees</a> and <a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/marvel-daredevil-born-again-ironheart-trailers-the-bear-disney-upfront-bob-iger-1236003036/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">churning out content</a>, as Disney does. But it also feels petty to say this whole thing was just about marketing, because <em>obviously </em>that’s what it is. That’s what so much of <em>Fortnite</em>’s metaverse is, and what Disney’s <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/campster.bsky.social/post/3kzg5cojp5s2d" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">other games</a> are. More and more things are <a href="https://aftermath.site/wb-earnings-zaslav" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">just IP</a> these days, and all that IP is just about funnelling money back into shareholder and CEOs’ pockets.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Again, it feels petty to dunk on a thing for so nakedly being what it obviously is. And again, it’s likely all this will come to look different as the collaboration continues. Or at least, I <em>hope</em> it will: $1.5 billion for skins wouldn’t be a great use of Disney’s money. But it felt hard to watch a bunch of people try to make the <a href="https://aftermath.site/ken-levine-judas-interview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">very old, very standard seem new and exciting</a>.</p><p>I’m <a href="https://aftermath.site/fortnite-cant-go-home-again" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">on the record</a> as disliking <em>Fortnite</em>’s crossover content, but I was hoping for something a little more interesting. The actual most interesting part of the event for me was that I caught it on the YouTube channel of some streamer I’d never heard of, who hooked the event to trying to reach 15 million subscribers. The delayed start worked in his favor, letting him drum up hype by trying to time his goal to the start of the event. He made it, too, early in the boring preliminary speeches. I’ll admit to subscribing to help him get those last numbers out, but then immediately unsubscribing. Sorry, buddy! Congrats on having a more triumphant evening than Epic and Disney.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered Recieves H2M Mod]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-remastered-recieves-h2m-mod/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-remastered-recieves-h2m-mod.951006/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-remastered-recieves-h2m-mod/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Despite being released in 2016, Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered has skyrocketed in sales. As a result, it has become the second best-selling game on Steam, behind Counter-Strike 2.</p>
<p>Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered has shot back up the rankings due to the H2M mod, which is set to be released this week. This Modern Warfare 2 revival mod utilizes Modern Warfare Remastered as a foundation.</p>
<p>This highly ambitious mod essentially ports the entirety of Modern Warfare 2 multiplayer to Modern Warfare Remastered. It includes all of the maps, modes, weapons, and some of the newer content released for the game, utilizing single-player environments.</p>
<p>While the mod is free, you must own Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered to play it. This game is currently on sale with a hefty 50% discount, which explains the hefty resurgence in people purchasing the game.</p>
<p>When Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered was first released, it did not perform as well as Activision may have been expecting. Instead, it only had an all-time high of 1,409 players. This was quite a shock, especially since Modern Warfare was one of the older-generation consoles' most favored Call of Duty games. However, with the release of the H2M mod, it's shaping up to surpass the number of 1,409 players.</p>
<p>The H2M mod for Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered is set to release on August 16. While Activision did release <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/call-of-duty-modern-warfare-2-remastered-both-aged-and-timeless/">Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2 Remastered</a>, it wasn't received well by fans of the game. This is because they stripped it back completely, removing the multiplayer modes, which is a huge reason people played Call of Duty in the first place. Between that and the hefty price tag, it disappointed many players worldwide.</p>
<p>Luckily, on August 16, those who own Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered can play this free H2M mod, allowing players to relive the nostalgia of the Modern Warfare 2 multiplayer game modes.</p>
<p>For those wanting to explore the H2M mod, there is an official website where you can download it, which also includes the <a href="https://h2m-mod.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">H2M mod installer</a>. However, it isn't available for download at the moment, as the mod isn't released until August 16. Additionally, this mod can only be used on the Steam version of Call of Duty: Modern Warfare Remastered.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Halloween is Getting Two New Games and One Uses Unreal Engine 5]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/halloween-games-unreal-engine-5</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/halloween-is-getting-two-new-games-and-one-uses-unreal-engine-5.951003/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/halloween-games-unreal-engine-5<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Two new games based on the horror movie franchise&nbsp;<em>Halloween&nbsp;</em>are currently in development, a new report reveals, and one of them is being built on Unreal Engine 5.</p>
<p>According to a new <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/halloween-unreal-engine-5-john-carpenter-boss-team-games" rel="noopener" target="_blank">IGN</a> report,&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/games/evil-dead-game">Evil Dead: The Game</a>&nbsp;</em>publisher Boss Team Games is currently working on two projects based on&nbsp;<em>Halloween</em>.&nbsp;While details are scarce right now, the report does say that one game will be built in Unreal Engine 5 and will feature input from original&nbsp;<em>Halloween&nbsp;</em>director and legendary auteur John Carpenter.</p>
<p>Per IGN, Carpenter, who says he's a "huge gamer", is "thrilled" to be bringing Michael Myers and the&nbsp;<em>Halloween&nbsp;</em>franchise to the world of video games. Carpenter goes on to say that he hopes the games will "scare you silly", which doesn't sound like a difficult mission for a game based on a legendary franchise like this one.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/evil-dead-the-game-halloween-games-boss-team.jpg?itok=sqJcqiwU 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/evil-dead-the-game-halloween-games-boss-team.jpg?itok=uyHflk63 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Boss Team Games is responsible for&nbsp;<em>Evil Dead: The Game</em>.</figcaption></figure><p>Right now, Boss Team and Carpenter are remaining relatively tight-lipped regarding what the&nbsp;<em>Halloween&nbsp;</em>games in question will actually be.</p>
<p>However, a press release does state that they'll allow you to "relive moments from the film" and "play as classic characters" from&nbsp;<em>Halloween</em>. Given Boss Team's involvement, it's fair to speculate that we could be getting a&nbsp;<em>Halloween</em>&nbsp;spin on the&nbsp;<em>Evil Dead: The Game&nbsp;</em>formula.</p>
<p>Apparently, the Unreal Engine 5 project is still fairly early in development, which presumably means the other game is moving ahead at full steam. If that's the case, we'll probably hear about it sooner rather than later.</p>
<p>These two games would, remarkably enough, be the first titles to be based on&nbsp;<em>Halloween&nbsp;</em>since 1983's Atari 2600 game, which was, as you can probably imagine, pretty basic by today's standards. Myers has also appeared in&nbsp;<em>Dead by Daylight&nbsp;</em>as a killer, alongside the likes of&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dead-by-daylight-castlevania-crossover-release-date"><em>Castlevania</em>'s Dracula</a>,&nbsp;<em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>' <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dead-by-daylight-crossovers-spinoffs">Vecna</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dead-by-daylight-chucky"><em>Child's Play</em>'s Chucky</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/halloween-michael-myers-dead-by-daylight.jpg?itok=EwWEck_Y 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/halloween-michael-myers-dead-by-daylight.jpg?itok=1JV1MLYa 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Michael Myers has appeared in other games like&nbsp;<em>Dead by Daylight</em>, but he hasn't had his own game for a while.</figcaption></figure><p>We'll have to wait and see what sort of games Boss Team is cooking up for&nbsp;<em>Halloween</em>, as it were, but we'll probably hear more in the coming months. Stay tuned for more on this one as and when we get it.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nacon Delays Terminator: Survivors Launch to 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nacon-delays-terminator-survivors-launch-to-2025/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nacon-delays-terminator-survivors-launch-to-2025.950988/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nacon-delays-terminator-survivors-launch-to-2025/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In a new <a href="https://x.com/SurviveTheT800/status/1823011706836029701" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post on X</a> today, Nacon announced that it will now delay the Terminator: Survivors launch until 2025, previously expected to release in October 2024.</p>



<p>Nacon broadly cited the need for “some additional time” in order to realize its vision for the game. The studio also wants to “deliver the game that fits your expectations.” </p>



<p>Nacon did not break down the exact cause for delay, nor offer a more concrete release window. </p>



<p>However, the devs say they are impressed by fan enthusiasm, and thanked the community for their understanding and support. Although fans are dismayed by Terminator: Survivors’ delay, they did support the decision to await a smooth launch.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Nacon first <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/terminator-survivors-open-world-game/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed Terminator: Survivors</a> in February 2024, during the Nacon Connect showcase.  A couple of months later, Nacon <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/terminator-survivors-offline-story-first-person/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confirmed more details</a> about the game during a Q&amp;A session.</p>



<p>Terminator: Survivors is an open-world survival game and first-person shooter, built in Unreal Engine 5. It will support co-op, as well as offline single-player gameplay.</p>



<p>According to the official <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2617340/Terminator_Survivors/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam page</a>, players will “meet iconic characters of the franchise as well as original ones.” It will also feature “an unexplored storyline” about Judgment Day.</p>



<p>Terminator: Survivors previously planned to launch on PC on October 24, 2024, with console versions releasing later on. Most recently, Nacon shared a development video late last June, explaining the game’s inspiration from James Cameron’s original two films.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming news, you can read about Motorsport Games revealing an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/motorsport-games-confirms-revenue-increase-le-mans-ultimate-console-plans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">optimistic financial report</a> and console plans for Le Mans Ultimate, and sign up for the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Snezhinka: Sentinel Girls 2 launches August 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/snezhinka-sentinel-girls-2-launches-august-27</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/snezhinka-sentinel-girls-2-launches-august-27.950985/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/snezhinka-sentinel-girls-2-launches-august-27<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Marfusha: Sentinel Girls sequel dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Marfusha: Sentinel Girls [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/marfusha-sentinel-girls">Marfusha: Sentinel Girls</a></em> sequel and high-tempo shooting game <em><a title="Games > Snezhinka: Sentinel Girls 2 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/snezhinka-sentinel-girls-2">Snezhinka: Sentinel Girls 2</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,855 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2608350/SnezhinkaSentinel_Girls2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on August 27 for $7.99, developer <a title="Companies > hinyari9 [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hinyari9">hinyari9</a> announced. It will support English, Japanese, Korean, and Simplified Chinese language options. <span id="more-905159"></span></p><p>In addition to the base game, the official soundtrack and an art book will be available as downloadable content. The soundtrack includes all in-game background music tracks composed by Zukio. The art book features 60 pages of illustrations and in-game parameters.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2608350/SnezhinkaSentinel_Girls2/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>You play as Snezhinka, an employee of a private military company, defending various targets against enemy onslaughts in a dystopian 2.5D pixel art world.</p><p>Prepare for increasingly stronger enemies by purchasing cards using your meager paychecks after taxes and middlemen’s fees to strengthen your character.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>More than 100 types of cards, including characters, power-ups, and chance events.</li><li>More than 30 types of weapons.</li><li>Eight unique characters.</li><li>Score attack rankings.</li></ul></blockquote><p>If you missed it, watch the announcement trailer <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2023/12/snezhinka-sentinel-girls-2-announced-for-pc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>. Visit the official website <a href="https://snezhinka.ltt.jp/en/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>