<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 17:19:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[17 Of The Year’s Biggest PS5 Games Are Up To 50 Percent Off]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ps5-deals-soulslike-rpg-goty-discount-sale-2000656129</link>
            <guid>1394479</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>2025 is almost over. The internet is full of <a href="https://kotaku.com/game-awards-2025-tga-winners-losers-who-won-game-of-the-year-clair-obscur-2000652261">GOTY lists</a> recommending dozens of stellar releases. You can find many of the games on those lists currently on sale on the PlayStation store. It’s not a bad time to catch up on that game or two you missed that everyone was buzzing about this year and see what all the fuss is about while you’re nursing that New Year’s hangover.</p> <p>Below is a quick rundown of some of the biggest releases of 2025 that are all currently discounted on PSN:</p> <ul> <li><em><strong>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</strong></em> – $35 (50 percent off)</li> <li><em><strong>Elden Ring Nightreign</strong></em> – $30 (25 percent off)</li> <li><em><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong></em> – $40 (20 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>Battlefield 6</em></strong> – $49 (30 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>Arc Raiders</em></strong> – $32 (20 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>Death Stranding 2: On the Beach</em></strong> – $50 (29 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em></strong> – $16 (20 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>Borderlands 4</em></strong> – $56 (20 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>Dying Light: The Beast</em></strong> – $48 (20 percent off)</li> <li><em><strong>Digimon Story: Time Stranger</strong></em> – $56 (20 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>Split Fiction</em></strong> – $37.50 (25 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>Silent Hill f</em></strong> – $42 (40 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>The Outer Worlds 2</em></strong> – $49 (30 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</em></strong> – $33.50 (33 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>Final Fantasy Tactics</em></strong> – The Ivalice Chronicles – $40 (20 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em></strong> – $38.50 (45 percent off)</li> <li><strong><em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</em></strong> – $35 (50 percent off)</li> </ul> <p>Standout deals include <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em>, and <em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance II</em> which are all essentially half off. <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em> is the cheapest overall on the list at $16 and probably has the best player value quotient when it comes to how many times a game can kill you without making you quit. Games that didn’t get as much fanfare in 2025, like <a href="https://kotaku.com/digimon-story-time-stranger-the-kotaku-review-2000630341"><em>Digimon Story: Time Stranger</em></a>, <a href="https://kotaku.com/outer-worlds-2-review-rpg-xbox-ps5-2000638368"><em>The Outer Worlds 2</em></a>, and <a href="https://kotaku.com/silent-hill-f-review-horror-konami-hinako-ryukishi07-2000627505"><em>Silent Hill f</em></a> are all well worth a look, too.</p>

 <p>If you didn’t catch <em>Gears of War</em>, <em>Forza Horizon 5</em>, or <em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em> when they launched on Xbox, they’re all on sale as well. <em>Gears of War: Reloaded</em> is $20 (half off), <em>Forza Horizon 5</em> is $36 (40 percent off), and<em> Indiana Jones</em> is $49 (30 percent off). If you’re looking for some Soulslike action, <a href="https://kotaku.com/first-berserker-khazan-review-anime-soulslike-rpg-1851771917"><em>The First Berserker: Khazan</em></a> is $42 (30 percent off) and <a href="https://kotaku.com/wuchang-fallen-feathers-gooner-souls-pc-steam-reviews-1851786856"><em>Wuchang: Fallen Feathers</em></a> is $40 (20 percent off); both of those are very good. Finally, there’s <em>Hell Is Us</em>, a sci-fi horror action-adventure about war and time-loop monsters <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games-review/767993/hell-is-us-review-ps5-xbox-steam">that’s more than the sum of its parts</a>. At just $36 (40 percent off), it’s currently at its lowest price yet.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ps5-deals-soulslike-rpg-goty-discount-sale-2000656129]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ASUS Clears Out Prime Graphics Card, GeForce RTX 5060 Gets Even Cheaper Overnight After Another Price Drop]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/asus-clears-out-prime-graphics-card-geforce-rtx-5060-gets-even-cheaper-overnight-after-another-price-drop-2000656038</link>
            <guid>1394476</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Looking to improve your gaming PC? You may need a new graphics card. The latest and greatest may be a little expensive, but you could always do with a sale-priced upgrade so you can save a bit. We found one that’s heavily discounted now, and you can not only get it for a low price, but it should do your computer some good.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6615/">You can find the SFF-Ready ASUS Prime GeForce RTX 5060 Ti 8GB GDDR7 OC Edition Graphics Card on Amazon right now for $318</a>. In comparison to the original retail price of $470, that’s a discount of $152 and represents about a 32% savings.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6615/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A powerful GPU that can enhance all your gaming goals</h2>
<p>This ASUS Prime GeForce RTX 5060Ti is a powerful graphics card that includes all the features you’d need to play the newest games at 144Hz, do photo and video editing at high resolution, and still have room left over to run other (usually demanding) applications.</p>
<p>Based on NVIDIA Ampere Architecture, the 8 GB of GDDR7 memory will allow you to maintain high frame rates at both 1080p and 1440p resolutions with less lag. Even at higher resolutions you should be able to achieve frame rates above 60 FPS. You’ll also see lower power consumption when running with this card.</p>
<p>To support the unique demands of small form factor systems, ASUS has engineered this product to fit within most mini ITX and micro ATX enclosures. While this card does occupy two and a half slots, it’s much smaller than most other graphics cards and leaves ample room to install additional hardware inside your enclosure. It does a great job at balancing both airflow and cooling to maintain stable performance during heavy loads, and uses axial-tech fans and carefully located heat sinks to ensure that this card runs quietly and maintains low operating temperatures.</p>



<p>For the gamer, this graphics card provides a significant upgrade over both integrated and older discrete graphics cards. With this card you’ll get faster load times, smoother frame rates, and better management of modern features like ray tracing when you play supported titles. For creators, the increased memory and processing power of this graphics card will help with tasks such as video editing, 3D modeling, and multitasking, especially when your workloads require more than what a typical GPU can provide.</p>
<p>Overall, with its superior performance, compact size, and highly efficient cooling, the SFF-Ready ASUS Prime GeForce RTX 5060 Ti 8GB GDDR7 OC Edition Graphics Card is an ideal graphics card for upgrading to for many PC builds. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6615/">Given the current sale price of $318, this graphics card is an affordable option to consider if you want to increase your PC performance without spending too much money.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6615/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/asus-clears-out-prime-graphics-card-geforce-rtx-5060-gets-even-cheaper-overnight-after-another-price-drop-2000656038]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Excuse Me, But What The Hell Is This?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/goat-trailer-fart-joke-jackass-sony-zootopia-funny-teaser-2000656133</link>
            <guid>1394473</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Over the weekend, I went out to the theater and saw <a href="https://kotaku.com/avatar-3-fire-ash-runtime-revealed-three-hours-long-sega-outer-worlds-2-2000643471"><em>Avatar: Fire and Ash</em></a>. Even as a big <em>Avatar</em> sicko, I walked out disappointed. But I don’t want to talk about that. Instead, I want to highlight a moment I was forced to watch <em>twice</em> due to some snafu at my local AMC. The moment in question involves some children hooking up a tube to a monkey’s face and farting into the other end. Hey Hollywood, what the fuck?</p> <p>We arrived to see <a href="https://kotaku.com/avatar-3-fire-and-ash-trailer-fire-clan-james-cameron-1851787146"><em>Avatar: Fire and Ash</em></a> about 15 minutes before the movie started, and to our surprise, my wife and I noticed the trailers were already playing. Strange! We sat down and I caught a new trailer for Sony’s upcoming <a href="https://kotaku.com/zootopia-2-nick-judy-relationship-romance-abortion-comic-2000649147"><em>Zootopia</em></a> knock-off, <em>GOAT</em>, which is a basketball movie about talking animals or something. Approximately one minute and 49 seconds into this trailer, I was surprised to see two young rhino girls using a tube and a gas mask to funnel a fart from one of the animals’ asses to the face of a sleeping monkey man.&nbsp; Here’s the moment in question.</p>

  <p>I looked around the theater, which was basically empty as we’d arrived fairly early, and questioned if I’d actually seen what I thought I’d seen. I mean, sure, animated movies for kids are filled with fart jokes, so it hardly seemed impossible that Sony’s <em>GOAT </em>would feature one. But having cartoon animal kids basically recreate <a href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/7c_GK40Dsjg">the fart mask stunt from <em>Jackass 2</em></a>&nbsp;as a silly moment caught me off guard. I shook it off and soon was lost in the opening minutes of <em>Fire and Ash</em>, the&nbsp;<em>GOAT&nbsp;</em>trailer a distant memory. Or so I thought.</p>

 <p>About 10 minutes later, someone seemingly complained that the movie had started early, and so the AMC restarted everything, trailers included. Mildly annoying, but it did make me giggle at all the people who had arrived late specifically to avoid trailers then being forced to watch them anyway. It also meant that I’d have a second chance to catch the fart joke. And yup, to my surprise, <em>GOAT</em> does indeed include a recreation of<em> Jackass 2’s</em> fart mask bit, complete with the victim retching and losing it.</p>

 <p>Folks, I’m not a prude. I love the <em>Jackass</em> movies. And I’m not above laughing at a fart joke or someone getting hit in the groin. But it feels like <em>GOAT </em>and the people involved were desperate to one-up all the other fart jokes in kids’ movies these days and, in the process, created something that feels like it crosses a line that I’m not even sure I can properly put my finger on. At the very least, moving forward, I’d like a warning before any trailers that feature kids recreating gross-out pranks from <em>Jackass</em> movies, okay?</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/goat-trailer-fart-joke-jackass-sony-zootopia-funny-teaser-2000656133]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arise, Sir Idris! Actor Idris Elba Knighted in New Year Honours]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/arise-sir-idris-actor-idris-elba-knighted-in-new-year-honours</link>
            <guid>1394470</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Actor Idris Elba is knighted in the New Year Honours. The 53-year old Hollywood star from Hackney, London can now officially be called Sir Idris.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sir Idris, who rose to prominence for playing Stringer Bell in HBO series The Wire and DCI John Luther in BBC series Luther, more recently played the British Prime Minister and the President of the United States, in Heads of State and A House of Dynamite respectively, both of which came out in 2025. Elba is no stranger to the world of video games, either, having played Solomon Reed in the Cyberpunk 2077 expansion, Phantom Liberty.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">He was knighted for services to young people in recognition of his charity work at the Elba Hope Foundation, which supports community empowerment, education, youth advocacy, and sustainable development. In particular, Elba has been outspoken on knife crime. He said: “I hope we can do more to draw attention to the importance of sustained, practical support for young people and to the responsibility we all share to help them find an alternative to violence.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, the actor and comedian Meera Syal (The Kumars at No 42) is being awarded a Damehood for services to Literature, Drama and Charity, while the composer Max Richter is being awarded a CBE (Commanders of the Order of the British Empire) for his services to Music. Actor Warwick Davis is also being recognised for services to Drama and Charity with an OBE (Officers of the Order of the British Empire). Davis said: "This is the best thing that's ever happened to me — and I've been in Star Wars."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">An MBE (Members of the Order of the British Empire) went to Wicked star Cynthia Erivo, and the author and television presenter Richard Osman (Thursday Murder Club) is being awarded an OBE for his services to literature and broadcasting.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">1,157 recipients have been awarded from every part of the UK, with a particular focus this year on those who have gone above and beyond for their communities.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Photo by Daniele Venturelli/Getty Images for The Red Sea International Film Festival.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/arise-sir-idris-actor-idris-elba-knighted-in-new-year-honours]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gender-Swapped Lady Loki Skin Comes To Marvel Rivals For The Month Of January]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/30/gender-swapped-lady-loki-skin-comes-to-marvel-rivals-for-the-month-of-january</link>
            <guid>1394467</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>Marvel Rivals has been getting increasingly creative with its skins, but today's reveal pushes the game to a new level. Lady Loki, a female version of the god of mischief, is coming to the in-game shop later this week, complete with a new voice lines from a (presumably) new voice actor. You can see the skin in action below.</p><blockquote data-media-max-width="560"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>🐍 Lurking and ready to strike!</p><p>"The fates do have their little surprises, do they not? No less so for me than you, as my appearance gives stark testimony."</p><p>Be reborn as a reckoning force and show the battlefield what true power is with the striking Lady Loki costume, first… <a href="https://t.co/qkJtJ6jd3j">pic.twitter.com/qkJtJ6jd3j</a></p></div><p>— Marvel Rivals (@MarvelRivals) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarvelRivals/status/2006032816249909267?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 30, 2025</a></p></blockquote><p>Loki's magically fluid nature has been a fascinating part of his character, especially since he introduced the concept of variants was through his MCU TV series, but no version is as popular as Lady Loki. While the TV series' Sylvie is a popular take on the character in her own right, Lady Loki is typically depicted as a woman with long black hair, like we see in NetEase's shooter.</p>



<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="2beb8c37-edfa-4939-a5d1-dff0049a4cf5" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="view_mode:file.none_original_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;Lady Loki in Marvel Rivals&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

  
      

  
  
      <p>Lady Loki in Marvel Rivals</p>
  
</article>

<p>While past cosmetics have put filters on voice lines or included alternate sound/visual effects, this is the most transformative skin Marvel Rivals has seen to date, and raises the question of other potential character variants that could be included as cosmetic overhauls. That said, as far as I know, no one else on the roster has an alternate version as popular as Lady Loki that would require re-recorded voice lines. And I'd prefer characters who have taken up existing heroes' mantles (like Miles Morales, Shuri, or Kate Bishop) to get their own spot on the roster, rather than a reskin.&nbsp;</p><p>Future speculation aside, Lady Loki is real, but will only be available from January 2 to January 30, so if you're interested, make sure to pick her up while you can. For more Marvel Rivals, <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/marvel-rivals/a-super-shooter" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="8f09e23a-48e2-4d0a-a386-20a50ce4722b" data-entity-substitution="canonical">check out our review from earlier this year</a>.</p><hr><p><em>What other cosmetic overhauls do you hope to see in Marvel Rivals? Let us know in the comments!</em></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/2025/12/30/gender-swapped-lady-loki-skin-comes-to-marvel-rivals-for-the-month-of-january]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: It's Time To Say Goodbye To The Lovely Felix-From-Nintendo-Life]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/video-its-time-to-say-goodbye-to-the-lovely-felix-from-nintendo-life</link>
            <guid>1394449</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Hej hej Felix!</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>As the new year approaches, it's the season of goodwill and change, new things and new horizons (and not just <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/animal-crossing-new-horizons-nintendo-switch-2-edition">NS2 Editions</a>), which means it's time for some news we've been sitting on for a little while. Yes, as you probably guessed from the headline, our lovely video producer Felix Sanchez is disembarking the good ship Nintendo Life.</p>
<p>Felix — gentleman, scholar, musician, Mario Party devotee, and thoroughly top chap — joined Alex and Zion <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=24mflsHQuFs">at the start of 2022</a> and has been an absolute joy to work with over the past four years. While he's moving on to work for a company in his native Denmark, you can be sure the entire NL crew will be keeping in touch with this particularly lovely person.</p>
<p>Please check out his farewell video above, where he goes into a little more detail about his next chapter. We wish you nothing but the best, Mr Felix, and we hope to catch up with you IRL soon!</p>
<p>Ah, time. Let's close out this end-of-an-era post (<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/video-after-six-wonderful-years-zion-is-leaving-nintendo-life">the second one</a> in only a handful of months, no less!) on a less-sad note: Here's 30 minutes of Felix chatting with Alex about his personal top five games of the year.</p>

<hr>
<p><em>We'll have more to announce soon on the future of the NL YouTube team (don't worry, Alex isn't going anywhere!), so keep an eye out for exciting news on the video front. Until then, we love you, Felix!</em></p></section></article><div><p>Gavin first wrote for Nintendo Life in 2018 before joining the site full-time the following year, rising through the ranks to become Editor. He can currently be found squashed beneath a Switch backlog the size of Normandy.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/dartmonkey"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('dartmonkey');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/video-its-time-to-say-goodbye-to-the-lovely-felix-from-nintendo-life]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloodborne PC Online Play Is No Longer a Dream: ShadPS4 Developer Showcases Working Multiplayer Milestone]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-pc-online-play-is-no-longer-a-dream-shadps4-developer-showcases-working-multiplayer-milestone/</link>
            <guid>1394446</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">A few years ago</strong>, no one thought the day would come when <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Bloodborne</em> would break away from its <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">PlayStation 4 jail</strong> to become playable on PC. After months of updates, the popular <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">FromSoftware</strong> hardcore action RPG is now <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">fully playable</strong> thanks to the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">ShadPS4 emulator</strong>, even on <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-60-fps-4gb-vram-rx-580/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">dated hardware</strong></a> and handheld systems like the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/shadps4-version-0-12-6-massive-performance-boost-bloodborne/">Steam Deck</a></strong>.</p>



<p>Emulation, however, still isn't perfect, as <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">online features</strong> are not accessible - but that may be about to change. A new video shared on YouTube by <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@gmoralistube">George Moralis</a></strong>, one of the emulator's lead developers, shows <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Bloodborne</em> running on PC with <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">online features enabled</strong>.</p>



<p>While this is an <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">early technical test</strong>, and many issues still need to be ironed out, it's hard not to get excited about the prospect of <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">co-op play</strong>, searching <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">glyph Chalice Dungeons</strong>, and accessing the asynchronous features such as messages and bloodstains that make FromSoftware's titles so unique. With fully <span data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">functional online features,&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/dark-souls-remastered-seamless-co-op-download/">seamless co-op may also become a reality</a>,</strong>&nbsp;fur</span>ther elevating the emulated version over the original PS4 release, which can <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-patched-by-modder-to-run-at-60-fps-on-playstation-4-pro/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">only run at 60 FPS on the system with a fan-made patch.</strong></a></p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="bloodborne online , the future of shadPS4" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4oqkDeWhV5g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>As for how <em>Bloodborne's</em> online features will function in future versions of <strong>ShadPS4</strong>, it is too early to say. According to George Moralis, the development team is <strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4oqkDeWhV5g&amp;lc=Ugx0oiPx3VLoeDEw0VB4AaABAg.ARJJ8ekVjhrARJN3dkWPbQ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">examining several options</a></strong>, including <strong>dedicated community servers</strong> or <strong>local servers</strong>. One thing, however, is certain: users playing on the emulated version will <strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4oqkDeWhV5g&amp;lc=UgzvNpnDQCtzxPeQ-fd4AaABAg.ARJM4Pn3JqpARJMu_zF1QS" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">never be able to connect to Sony's official servers</a></strong>.</p>



<p>Besides perfecting <em>Bloodborne's</em> emulation, the <strong>ShadPS4 development team</strong> is continuing to expand the list of <strong>PlayStation 4 exclusives</strong> playable on PC. More information on the emulator's progress can be found on its <a href="https://shadps4.net/"><strong>official website</strong>.</a></p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-pc-online-play-is-no-longer-a-dream-shadps4-developer-showcases-working-multiplayer-milestone/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[River City Ransom: Underground Is Being Delisted from Steam Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/river-city-ransom-underground-steam-delisting</link>
            <guid>1394443</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Developer and publisher Conatus Creative has announced that its retro side-scrolling beat-'em-up <em>River City Ransom: Underground </em>is being delisted from Steam soon, so if you want it, grab it while you can.</p><p>In a <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/422810/view/524236943144258012" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">rather brief post</a> on Steam, the developer says that the delisting is happening "due to the expiration of a licensing agreement", and that the delisting process "is currently underway", which likely means you can expect the game to disappear from Steam in the next week or two.</p><p>If you already happen to own <em>River City Ransom: Underground</em>, then, as Conatus says, "nothing changes". You'll still be able to play the game, and it'll still appear as part of your Steam library. It's worth saying that the game is also currently on sale at an 85% discount, so now's the time to pick it up.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>River City Ransom: Underground </em>is vanishing from Steam soon.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It's not clear whether this delisting also applies to the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gog-acquired-original-co-founder" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="ac0fe303-b1f6-4fb9-85b5-0996e982944e" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">under-new-management GOG</a>, where <em>River City Ransom: Underground </em>is also currently available (although the Steam discount doesn't apply there, so you'll be paying full price for the game if you pick it up from GOG).</p><p>Conatus also hasn't been clear about exactly what the "licensing issue" in question is, but it's possible it relates to a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/river-city-ransom-underground-changing-soundtrack-alex-mauer-saga" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="b63edfed-3fed-4ec0-8058-2670c03f1458" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">dispute with music creator Alex Mauer</a> back in 2017, which saw the creator issuing DMCA claims not only to Conatus, but also to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/updated-another-week-more-sets-of-dmcas-alex-mauer-saga" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="e2e1c438-2fdb-407b-885c-ad191b1b159c" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">other creators on YouTube</a>.</p><p>If you're not familiar with <em>River City Ransom: Underground</em>, it's a beat-'em-up in the <em>River City </em>series, which is known in Japan as <em>Kunio-kun</em>. Unlike 2023's <em>River City: Rival Showdown</em>, this one <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/river-city-ransom-remake" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="e10f316f-6ac8-4a1e-b2d7-9d8209ad5f21" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">isn't a remake</a>; rather, it's a completely new title in the franchise.</p><p>Like its forebears and successors, <em>River City Ransom: Underground </em>is a story-driven side-scrolling fighter in which you'll control one of 10 playable heroes across a campaign that will let you explore 140 different levels and upgrade your characters across 22 shops.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>You can still get <em>River City Ransom: Underground </em>on GOG...for now, at least.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>For the time being, <em>River City Ransom: Underground </em>is available on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/422810/River_City_Ransom_Underground/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">PC via Steam</a> at a hefty discount, and it's available on <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/river_city_ransom_underground" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">GOG.com</a> as well. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/river-city-ransom-underground-steam-delisting]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GameSir put a tiny force feedback steering wheel on its new Swift Drive controller]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/851259/gamesir-switch-turbo-drive-controller-steering-wheel-wireless-force-feedback</link>
            <guid>1394440</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter who’s been covering and reviewing the latest gadgets and tech since 2006, but has loved all things electronic since he was a kid.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>GameSir is no stranger to experimenting with unique controller features — its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/8/24262029/gamesir-tarantula-pro-controller-switch-pc-ios-android-steam">Tarantula Pro</a> can automatically swap its face button labels to accommodate alternate layouts, and its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/843605/gamesir-pocket-1-smartphone-android-wireless-bluetooth-controller">Pocket 1</a> clamps Game Boy controls onto your phone. What sets its new Swift Drive controller apart is a small steering wheel located smack-dab in the middle of the gamepad that’s connected to what GameSir calls the “world’s smallest direct drive motor” providing force feedback effects for racing games.</p><p>Pricing and availability hasn’t been announced yet, but GameSir has revealed plenty of details about the Swift Drive’s features and functionality. The steering wheel uses a “high-precision” Hall effect encoder with “up to 65,000 levels of resolution for ultra-accurate steering.” Its movement can be adjusted between 30 and 1080 degrees of rotation, and the wheel itself can be removed and swapped with alternate styles. Hall effect sensors are also used in the Swift Drive’s joysticks and buttons, while its triggers are further enhanced with individual haptic motors to simulate the feeling of ABS braking and wheel slip.</p><p>The Swift Drive will rely on a 2.4GHz wireless connection to your gaming machine and, even with reactive RGB lighting effects and its various haptic motors, battery life is estimated to be between 20 to 30 hours between charges.</p><p>For racing sim fans not as concerned with portability, GameSir’s new Turbo Drive provides a more traditional steering wheel and pedal setup with a yoke-style wheel that clamps to a desk. Like the smaller Swift Drive controller it features 2.4GHz wireless connectivity, Hall effect sensors in the wheel’s encoder, throttle controls, and shifting paddles, plus extensive customizability including limiting the wheel’s rotation. Its most unique feature is a built-in turbine fan that simulates airflow and enhances the feeling of speed. With the fan on, the Turbo Drive’s battery life is estimated to be around 15 hours, but turning it off will let you play for up to 50 hours before a charge is needed.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/851259/gamesir-switch-turbo-drive-controller-steering-wheel-wireless-force-feedback]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance Remaster Now Rumoured to Arrive in February 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-remaster-release-date-february-2026/</link>
            <guid>1394422</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			<div data-nosnippet="">
		
		<ul>
			<li>0-20%: Unlikely - Lacks credible sources</li>
			<li>21-40%: Questionable - Some concerns remain</li>
			<li>41-60%: Plausible - Reasonable evidence</li>
			<li>61-80%: Probable - Strong evidence</li>
			<li>81-100%: Highly Likely - Multiple reliable sources</li>
		</ul>
	</div>


			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-remaster-early-2026/">Back in October, a rumour popped up</a> claiming that Warhorse Studios was working on a remaster of the first <strong>Kingdom Come: Deliverance</strong> game. There wasn't a lot to go off, since the rumour came from a lone source on Reddit, and while this source, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1pxp5od/kingdom_come_1_upgrade_info/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">bertik11</a>, has previously been reliable about unreleased information from Warhorse Studios, it was still worth taking the news with a huge grain of salt.</p>



<p>That's still true, of course, though bertik11 has now added to his previous claim. They now specify that the remaster will arrive in February 2026, and that while players might've been hopeful for what a remaster of a game that is now seven years old (soon to be eight) at the time of this writing will look like, we shouldn't expect too much.</p>



<p>"<em>Two months ago I wrote about the upgrade of the first Kingdom Come and new game. Today I wanna share info about upcoming upgrade for next gen consoles</em>," bertik11 began <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1pxp5od/kingdom_come_1_upgrade_info/">in a post on the GamingLeaksandRumors Reddit</a>. "<em>From what I’ve heard, a remaster of the original Kingdom Come is supposedly coming in February. Don’t expect too much, because as far as I’ve heard, it’s just going to be a port from PC. It won’t bring anything groundbreaking or entirely new — it’ll mostly just be a port for the new consoles</em>."</p>



<p>Again, this is all still just stemming from one unknown source who has previously been right when it comes to information on Warhorse Studios. Warhorse has not officially announced that it is making a remaster of the first Kingdom Come game, nor has it acknowledged its future plans now that Kingdom Come: Deliverance II <a href="https://wccftech.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-free-on-steam-xbox-for-next-four-days/">is out, and all of its DLCs are available</a>.</p>



<p>That said, it would make perfect sense for Warhorse to work on an update like this, something to bolster the first game for current-gen consoles, and to capitalize on the success its sequel has enjoyed all year. Kingdom Come: Deliverance II <a href="https://wccftech.com/arc-raiders-schedule-i-hollow-knight-silksong-battlefield-6-steam-best-selling-new-games-2025/">was one of the top-selling new games on Steam for 2025</a> and was one of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-game-awards-2025-winners-full-list/">nominees for multiple awards, including Game of the Year at The Game Awards 2025</a>. </p>



<p>It's also high on end-of-year lists for several publications, including Wccftech, as we have it on our <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-games-of-2025-year-of-the-indie-ish/">Best Games of 2025</a> list,<a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-role-playing-games-of-2025-another-incredible-year/"> Best Role-Playing Games</a> list, and even its DLC Mysteria Ecclesiae on our <a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-dlc-expansion-of-2025-expanding-the-fun/">Best DLC/Expansions</a> list. All this to say that Kingdom Come: Deliverance II has been one of 2025's defining titles, so it makes perfect sense for Warhorse to try and keep the series in players' minds by inviting them to return to the original.</p>



<p>Though if bertik11 is correct that the remaster will be closer to a port of the PC version to current-gen platforms instead of a deeper remaster, then how Warhorse handles it will be a huge element to how it is received. If it is just a port of the PC version, but there's no upgrade path for current owners, and they have to buy the full game all over again, or even worse, it's released as an entirely new game that everyone - PC players included - will have to buy again if they want all of the new graphical features, then that likely won't go over well with players who played and loved the game back in 2018. Nor will those who got into the series through the sequel be too enthused.</p>



<p>Of course, it's Warhorse's right to make those decisions if it likes, but it may go against capitalizing on the success of the sequel. Regardless, this whole rumor might not even be accurate, so we'll have to wait and see what happens in 2026.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-remaster-release-date-february-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Govee’s 1.8ft LED Backlight Is Back at Nearly 50% Off, RGBIC Wi-Fi Lighting for 55–65″ TVs]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/govees-1-8ft-led-backlight-is-back-at-nearly-50-off-rgbic-wi-fi-lighting-for-55-65%e2%80%b3-tvs-2000656052</link>
            <guid>1394416</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Need to give your home a visual upgrade? A set of colorful lights is a great way to do exactly this. And here’s the good news: you don’t have to spend an arm and a leg to do it. In fact, we’ve found a way to do it without spending too much to kick off 2026, and we’ve brought that idea here to you in the form of a deal.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6614/">Get the Govee Envisual TV LED Backlight T2 with Dual Cameras at Amazon for only $74.98, which saves you $65.02 (or approximately 46%) when compared to the normal retail price of $140.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6614/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A simple setup for enhancing your TV with backlights</h2>
<p>Govee’s Envisual TV LED Backlight T2 with dual cameras gives you a new level of immersion when it comes to how you watch TV. The Envisual utilizes dual cameras to capture the colors of your TV screen in real-time, then sends those color captures to LED backlight effects behind your TV.</p>
<p>If you’re looking for a way to add excitement and energy to the shows, movies, and games you watch on TV with exciting lighting effects that change with the content being displayed on screen, the Envisual T2 does exactly that. The best part is that you don’t have to learn a difficult setup just to attach some lighting to your TV. Nothing should be that complicated, and this setup doesn’t follow that convention.</p>



<p>To that end, installing the Govee Envisual TV LED Backlight T2 is super quick and easy. The installation package comes with the exact LED strip components that go around the back of your TV and also two smaller cameras that you can install on to your TV frame. But despite seeming intimidating, the setup isn’t all that bad, so you’ll be up and running in no time.</p>
<p>There are several ways you can control the lighting for your TV, too. The app allows you to adjust the intensity of the lighting, select various color effects that can be used for different viewing experiences, or choose a specific mode depending upon your viewing preferences. There’s a lot you can change here, and you’re really only limited by your creativity. That’s about it, especially if you’re willing to try a lot of different ideas.</p>
<p>We can’t really say it enough. This special backlight setup is a great way to make your TV feel that much more immersive. It’s a great viewing experience for anyone who wants to take their TV sessions to the next level. And when you factor in how much money you can save right now, that makes it an even better idea to go ahead and grab it right now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6614/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/govees-1-8ft-led-backlight-is-back-at-nearly-50-off-rgbic-wi-fi-lighting-for-55-65%e2%80%b3-tvs-2000656052]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Insider Gaming’s Biggest Surprise Hit of 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/insider-gamings-biggest-surprise-hit-of-2025/</link>
            <guid>1394413</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>You expect well-known AAA franchises to land as they’ve established themselves for years. New games are always entering the limelight, and certain ones stand above the rest. 2025 has seen its fair share of newbies, and Insider Gaming has selected one surprise hit above all.</p>



<p>When a new year begins, while they might not necessarily be in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-vote-game-awards-2025-all-categories-nominees-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GOTY</a> running, the annual Call of Duty, EA FC, etc, are going to sell like hotcakes and remain popular all year round. There will also be the games that are hyped up for an eternity, such as Hollow Knight: Silksong. So let’s honor the less-talked-about/hyped games and the impact they’ve had.</p>







<h2 id="h-biggest-surprise-hit-of-2025-winner-dispatch">Biggest Surprise Hit of 2025 Winner—Dispatch</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to AdHoc Studio</figcaption></figure>



<p>There have been workplace comedies about an office, a family, an American school, and many other things, but a superhero workplace comedy sounds like untapped potential. The Boys has been a breath of fresh air, changing the usual superhero narrative and perception. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/interview-dispatch-adhoc-studio/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dispatch</a>, being a playable, customizable version of this, is terrific on paper.</p>



<p>When developer AdHoc Studio is comprised of various devs from Telltale Games, the chances of Dispatch’s success go up. Over 2 million copies sold in its first month and an 89/100 score on Metacritic later, and Dispatch has fought off all opposition to be one of 2025’s biggest breakout hits. The developer has said Dispatch will beat its estimated three-year sales target in three months—which is ridiculous.</p>



<p>Dispatch is replayable, fun, makes you think carefully about every decision you make, and it has more depth and things to do than even the best Telltale games. A subsequent AdHoc game won’t claim this award again, because people know the developer means business now, but it’s a worthy 2025 winner.</p>







<h2 id="h-best-surprise-hit-game-of-2025-nominations">Best Surprise Hit Game of 2025 Nominations</h2>



<h3 id="h-clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Sandfall Interactive</figcaption></figure>



<p>Many Insider Gaming 2025 lists feature Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 in some capacity or another, to the point it’s almost boring! It would be wrong (borderline impossible) to ignore the game’s success, from breaking all-time The Game Awards records to selling 5 million units. Not many people really had Clair Obscur on their radar at the beginning of 2025, let alone knew who Sandfall Interactive was.</p>



<p>Now, at the end of 2025, even the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/french-president-applauds-clair-obscur-expedition-33/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">French President</a> knows about the game’s success. The uniqueness of Dispatch gives it the edge over Dispatch—and the fact that Sandfall features various former Ubisoft employees—but Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is close.</p>



<h3 id="h-donkey-kong-bananza">Donkey Kong Bananza</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Pauline has unique abilities to help DK. Image via Nintendo </figcaption></figure>



<p>Hear us out: The Donkey Kong franchise is legendary and loved. It’s been around for over 40 years, and the majority of its formula has been established. Nintendo decided to do something bold and make Bananza a fully 3D platformer with a destructible environment. Realistically, the game was never going to be bad, but you’d be hard-pressed to find anyone who would confidently claim that Bananza would be a landslide knockout.</p>



<p>Donkey Kong Bananza is the highest-rated DK game ever; it’s been nominated for umpteen awards and was even up for many Game of the Year accolades. The franchise name carries an exceptional amount of weight, but the release has surely given Nintendo some serious food for thought about the direction of the series moving forward.</p>



<h3 id="h-arc-raiders">ARC Raiders</h3>



<figure><figcaption>Credit to Embark Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p>A few have tried to crack the extraction shooter nut that Escape From Tarkov has selfishly clung to like Scrat in Ice Age. Call of Duty’s MWZ barely laid a scratch. Gray Zone Warfare is great, but its numbers nosedived off a cliff, and Escape From Duckov is hilariously quite close in terms of popularity, but <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-flickering-flames-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders</a> is something else. Wow.</p>



<p>The reception to ARC Raiders has been nothing but positive from testing to launch. It’s quite a rare feat, and Embark has caught lightning in a bottle with ARC Raiders. The developer is also achieving the difficult task of supporting the game well, adding the right content, and making changes befitting of the community. If you (the reader) say this is the biggest surprise hit of 2025, Insider Gaming would find it hard to argue.</p>



<p>Which leads nicely onto the conclusion of this article: What was your biggest surprise hit of 2025? Is there an easy winner or nomination left off of this list? You know where to go to comment: The <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Please check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-games-like-escape-from-tarkov/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">5 best games like Escape From Tarkov</a>, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/7-best-games-to-play-like-ninja-gaiden-4-top-hack-and-slash-games-to-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">top hack and slash games to play</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-battlefield-games-ranked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">all Battlefield Games, ranked from worst to best</a>, for more fun lists.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/insider-gamings-biggest-surprise-hit-of-2025/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Switch 2 Has Already Surpassed the Wii U's Lifetime UK Sales]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/switch-2-sales-wii-u-vita-dreamcast</link>
            <guid>1394401</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>New data has revealed that the Nintendo Switch 2 has already surpassed the lifetime sales of one of the Japanese gaming giant's previous pieces of hardware in the UK, as well as two other consoles from the annals of history.</p><p>As pointed out by <a href="https://x.com/Chris_Dring/status/2006017882128285792" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">analyst Chris Dring on X</a> (citing data from the analytics firm NielsenIQ), the Switch 2 has now passed the lifetime sales of the Wii U, which was released back in 2012 (and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-cans-project-giant-robot-wii-u-production-ceases" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3f5a85c7-dec2-4131-b5e3-122748abca15" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">discontinued in 2017</a>) in the UK.</p><p>Admittedly, the Wii U was largely considered to be a commercial failure, but the Switch 2 managing to surpass its entire sales total in the UK within just six months or so is still a fairly impressive achievement, even if the competition isn't particularly fair.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>Ah, Wii U. We hardly knew, er, U.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>According to Dring and NielsenIQ, the Switch 2 has also managed to pass the UK's lifetime sales total for the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/days-of-playstation-vita-are-over" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="4acfe571-2451-4f5a-a457-7180f86e895c" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">PlayStation Vita</a> and the Sega Dreamcast, although, again, it's fair to say both of those machines were fairly ill-fated.&nbsp;</p><p>Again, though, fewer people bought those consoles across their entire life cycles than the Switch 2 in its first six months (in the UK, at least). Whether or not figures are similar across the world is hard to say, but I wouldn't be surprised if the picture is the same in the US and elsewhere.</p><p>Nintendo released the Switch 2 <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-release-date" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="c11b67d9-d8b1-4556-871d-041c5101dcf0" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">back in June this year</a>, and within the console's first two months on sale, it had managed to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-financials-q1-2026" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="0df1a582-9b9c-40ce-97e3-524ba446cf4f" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">pass the six million sales mark</a>. Reportedly, Nintendo has asked its Switch 2 manufacturing partners to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/switch-2-25m-production-report" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="7d44c0b0-340a-4585-9a19-51b01545f6f9" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">produce 25 million units of the console</a> by March 2026.</p><p>Many popular games will be making their way to the Switch 2 in the coming months, too, including the likes of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/elden-ring-switch-2-delayed-2026" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="e7fa2ba9-4e00-4f97-a4ff-d9244ef5b612" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Elden Ring</em></a>, ghost-hunting game <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/phasmophobia-switch-2-version-on-way-next-year" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="159fca3c-8df3-41ad-98da-95af3a28123c" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Phasmophobia</em></a>, and choice-based adventure title <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dispatch-switch-2-switch-eshop-listing" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="1bcf2169-2693-40a4-ab6c-88b2398c75da" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Dispatch</em></a>.</p>
<p>You can nab a Nintendo Switch 2 for yourself via official channels right now. The same sadly can't be said for the Wii U, the Vita, or the Dreamcast, although I'm sure second-hand markets have their fair share of machines if you're interested. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/switch-2-sales-wii-u-vita-dreamcast]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zack Zwiezen’s Top 10 Games Of 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/zack-zwiezens-top-10-games-of-2025-2000656033</link>
            <guid>1394395</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    © Kotaku / EA / Xbox / Activision / 2K / Universal / Panic / Lunar Software / Compulsion Games / Shutterstock (Anton Ivanov)
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>….And we’re back. Sorry about last year. Our previous owners, G/O Media, were <a href="https://deadspin.com/the-adults-in-the-room-1837487584/">a pack of idiots</a> with more money than brains, who decided to stop anyone at <em>Kotaku</em> from <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/shepardcdr.bsky.social/post/3ldmmw2n25c2x">writing personal top ten lists</a>. Why? Pretty simple, really: <a href="https://tedium.co/2025/07/03/go-media-jim-spanfeller-gawker-influence/">They had no idea what they were doing and nearly destroyed this place</a>. Anyway, they’re all gone now, and I’m still here. So let’s talk about my 10 favorite games of 2025!</p> <p>This 2025 list was an odd one to put together. I started with over 20 games that I played this year that I liked a lot. But whittling this list down to 10 was shockingly easy. Nothing felt like it had to be on here or screamed “Zack’s Favorite Game!” <a href="https://kotaku.com/best-video-game-moments-scenes-2025-clair-obscur-ending-2000655769">It was a year in which I played so many good games</a>, but few that stuck with me in the same way <em>Control</em> did in 2019, or<em> Half-Life: Alyx</em> the following year.</p>

 <p>I won’t waste any more time. You can go scroll to the list now and nod in agreement with some picks and shake your head at others.&nbsp; As usual, this list is in no particular order until the very end, where I’ll drop my personal favorite game of the year! (<a href="https://kotaku.com/spider-man-2-robocop-alan-wake-2-best-games-2023-1851124842/3">And</a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/zack-zwiezen-s-top-10-games-of-2022-1849916027">here</a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/zack-zwiezens-top-10-games-of-2021-1848267109">are</a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/zack-zwiezens-top-10-games-of-2020-1845735344">my past</a> <a href="https://kotaku.com/zack-zwiezens-top-10-games-of-2019-1840540510">lists</a>.)</p>

 <p>Oh, wait, one more thing: If you scroll <em>all</em> the way to the end, you’ll find my top 10 games of 2024. <a href="https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2019/11/jim-spanfeller-is-a-herb-rise-fall-blog-post-deadspin.html">Take that, Jimbo</a>.</p> <hr> <h2><em><strong>Battlefield 6</strong></em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000616054" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000616054"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000616054">EA / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>Yeah, I wish EA’s big online FPS had some bigger maps. And, yup, there are still some vehicle balancing issues that need fixing. And, okay, sure, Redsec isn’t great, and the best thing I can say about the single-player campaign is that it’s short. But whatever, none of that has stopped me from investing nearly 150 hours into <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-reveal-la-event-behind-the-scenes-brie-larson-ea-2000614190"><em>Battlefield 6</em></a> since it launched in October. This is the kind of chaotic but tactical combat that I love in multiplayer games. The kind of online shooter where you can spend all night driving around in tanks and then the next day grab an SMG and clear rooms with your friends. And then a tank blows up the room you were in, and the building collapses, and you scramble outside into a nearby jeep and escape, only to be sniped by a bastard on the other side of the map. It’s <em>Battlefield</em>, baby, and I love it.</p>

 <h2><em><strong>Routine</strong></em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000649265" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000649265"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000649265">©&nbsp;Lunar Software</figcaption></figure> <p>When I wrapped <a href="https://kotaku.com/routine-alien-isolation-sci-fi-horror-review-creepy-scary-moon-xbox-pc-2000649242"><em>Routine</em>, a creepy photorealistic sci-fi horror game</a>, I liked it a lot, but I wasn’t convinced it would make my game of the year list. But then it did something not many games can do: It stuck with me. It has an incredibly oppressive and scary atmosphere that evolves in some interesting ways over the course of its runtime, before ramping up the horror to 11. And it does all of this while not being filled with cheap jump scares or bathtubs of blood. The fact that it’s all set it in mundane but incredibly realistic spaces, like kitchens and offices, just makes it all the easier to fully lose yourself in the experience. One scare in particular shook me up so bad that I’ll never forget it.</p>

 <h2><em><strong>Avowed</strong></em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000004852" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000004852"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000004852">© Obsidian Entertainment</figcaption></figure> <p>I will forever be a sucker for big RPGs that let me wander aimlessly and discover new quests. Bethesda’s RPGs have been doing that for decades. <a href="https://kotaku.com/avowed-xbox-pc-rpg-game-pass-skyrim-review-kotaku-1851761525">Obsidian’s <em>Avowed</em></a> smartly condenses the Bethesda formula while replacing some of that lost bloat with well-written companions and interesting hand-crafted sidequests. The end result is an RPG that lacks the simulation elements of <em>Skyrim</em> and the scale of <em>Fallout 4,</em> but features memorable characters and moments that stood out in a year filled with both.</p>

 <h2><em><strong>THPS 3+4</strong></em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000001310" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000001310"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000001310">© Activision</figcaption></figure> <p>Few games feel as good as a well-made<em> Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater</em> title. And this year’s remake of <em>THPS 3 </em>and <em>THPS 4</em> is very well-made indeed. This is just a perfect little package of skateboarding shenanigans. Yes, I know people got mad about the open-world quests being removed from <em>THPS 4,</em> but I’ve always preferred the two-minute format for these classic <em>Tony Hawk</em> titles. Leave the big spaces and quests to <em>Underground</em> or <em>Wasteland</em>, y’know? That minor quibble aside, what Iron Galaxy created with <em>THPS 3+4</em> is marvelous. It looks like I remember those old games looking, plays fantastically, and features enough challenges and extra content to keep you grinding and flipping for many late nights. Now, someone convince Activision to remake <em>Tony Hawk’s Underground,</em> please.</p>

 <h2><em><strong>Despelote</strong></em></h2> <figure><figcaption>© Panic</figcaption></figure> <p>I don’t care much for soccer. But I loved <em>Despelote</em>, a game that uses soccer as a throughline connecting different moments from a young boy’s life as he grows up in Quito during Ecuador’s qualification for the 2002 FIFA World Cup. This is a story about being a kid, dreaming big, getting into trouble, lying to your parents, growing up, and going back to where you once lived, only to find a much different place. You’ll be able to finish this one in a single extended sitting, and by the end, you’ll likely be won over by its storytelling, voice acting, visuals, and heart.</p> <h2><em><strong>Dispatch</strong></em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000647392" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000647392"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000647392">© AdHoc Studio / Kotaku</figcaption></figure> <p>I played a lot of Telltale narrative games (like <em>Wolf Among Us </em>and <em>The Walking Dead</em>) back in the day and enjoyed them, but I wasn’t sure if that formula would work again in 2025. I mean, I’m not sure it really worked back then either, but the writing was strong enough to win most folks over. <a href="https://kotaku.com/dispatch-review-adhoc-studios-all-8-episodes-finale-2000644106"><em>Dispatch</em></a>, a narrative-driven episodic game about a superhero agency, shows that with some tweaks and upgrades, the Telltale formula can still kick ass. Strong voice acting, a focus on narrative over fluff gameplay, and some truly funny moments help this strange workplace superhero comedy succeed in a way that, I’d argue, most Telltale games didn’t. Now, where’s season 2?</p> <h2><em><strong>Mafia: The Old Country</strong></em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000655161" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000655161"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000655161">© 2K</figcaption></figure> <p>When I sit down to play a game, I don’t always want to invest 400 hours into an RPG or grind away filling up meters or fight random people online. Sometimes, I just want a linear, 10-to-15-hour cinematic experience featuring solid gameplay and gorgeous visuals. <a href="https://kotaku.com/mafia-the-old-country-rare-big-game-you-can-finish-weekend-short-aaa-2k-2000655148"><em>Mafia: The Old Country</em> is that kind of game</a>. The kind of game that we don’t get much of anymore. A big-budget AAA linear action adventure game that lacks crafting, RPG skill trees, or other guff. It’s just the classic mobster story of a dude who goes from nothing to everything, but it all costs him so much. Except this is set in 1904 Italy and ditches Tommy Guns and big cities for rolling fields and horses. The end result is beautiful.</p>

 <h2><em><strong>South of Midnight</strong></em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000003790" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000003790"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000003790">© Compulsion Games</figcaption></figure> <p>If <em>South of Midnight’s</em> combat was better, it might have been able to slide into my top spot because everything else around the action-platformer is just that damn good.<em> South of Midnight</em> is a stop-motion-style adventure through a magical version of the South that deals head-on with topics like racism and slavery. But it also celebrates the unique culture that exists in the deep southern portion of the United States. And what screenshots of this game don’t reveal is that it’s packed with some of the best music of 2025, with songs that made me dance and others that made me cry. If you want to feel something, <a href="https://kotaku.com/south-of-midnight-game-pass-xbox-series-pc-south-review-1851775149">play <em>South of Midnight.</em></a></p> <h2><em><strong>Jurassic World Evolution 3</strong></em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000000700" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000000700"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000000700">© Universal</figcaption></figure> <p>One night, while playing<a href="https://kotaku.com/jurassic-world-evolution-3-best-jurassic-park-game-ever-pc-park-sim-baby-dinosaurs-2000639737"><em> Jurassic World Evolution 3</em></a>, I spent nearly three hours creating a massive paddock filled with various dinosaurs and a jeep tour. When I realized I had spent that much time on one part of the map, I felt a bit weird. Then I burned another hour while making that paddock look amazing and ensuring the adult and baby dinos inside were happy and healthy. A great game doesn’t have to tell some epic story or be filled with important themes and ideas. A great game can just take what came before it, expand on all of that, and then offer you a newly perfected prehistoric park builder that will suck away weeks of your life if you aren’t careful. This is one of the best simulation games around, and easily the best<em> Jurassic Park</em> game ever made.</p>

 <h2><strong>And my top game of 2025…<em>The </em></strong><em><strong>Outer Worlds 2</strong></em></h2> <figure id="attachment_2000639922" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000639922"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000639922">© Obsidian Entertainment</figcaption></figure> <p>I went back and forth on this a lot. I bet if you ask me in like two months what my top game of 2025 is, I might say something else. Truly, this was a strange year. But, I must admit that the more I think about it, the more convinced I am that <em>The </em><em>Outer Worlds 2</em> (from <em>Avowed</em> studio Obsidian) was my game of the year.</p> <p>As someone who has put an embarrassing number of hours into<em> Fallout 3, New Vegas, and 4</em>, I’m always craving an RPG that can provide similar experiences. The original <em>Outer Worlds</em> got close, but <em>The </em><em>Outer Worlds 2</em> finally nails and then improves on the open-ended FPS RPG action found in those past<em> Fallout</em> games. Gone are the stilted conversations from <em>Fallout</em> and the wonky combat and visuals. Instead, <a href="https://kotaku.com/outer-worlds-2-flaws-system-great-how-it-works-rpg-xbox-obsidian-2000653910"><em>The Outer Worlds 2</em></a> looks marvelous, feels like a joy to play, and still makes sure to include enough quirky moments and silly bits to satisfy any <em>Fallout</em> fan. Obsidian even included an in-game radio with ads and songs just like Bethesda’s <em>Fallout</em> games.</p> <p>I can’t wait to come back to <em>The Outer Worlds 2</em> in a few years, after forgetting most of it, and replay it as a new character. And to me, that’s the ultimate proof that a game has done something right. Now, one more thing…</p> <h2>Zack’s Top 10 Games Of 2024</h2> <ul> <li><em><strong>Astro Bot</strong></em></li> <li><em><strong>Silent Hill 2</strong></em></li> <li><em><strong>Star Wars Outlaws</strong></em></li> <li><em><strong>Helldivers 2</strong></em></li> <li><em><strong>Balatro&nbsp;</strong></em></li> <li><em><strong>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</strong></em></li> <li><em><strong>Thank Goodness You’re Here</strong></em></li> <li><em><strong>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</strong></em></li> <li><em><strong> Dungeons of Hinterberg</strong></em></li> <li><em><a href="https://kotaku.com/indiana-jones-great-circle-review-is-it-good-pc-xbox-1851717174"><strong>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</strong></a> – </em>My Favorite Game Of 2024!</li> </ul>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/zack-zwiezens-top-10-games-of-2025-2000656033]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phantom Blade Zero clocks up over 1 million wishlists in just 2 weeks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/phantom-blade-zero-clocks-up-over-1-million-wishlists-in-just-2-weeks</link>
            <guid>1394392</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2-(1)-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2-(1)-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2-(1)-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2-(1)-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2-(1)-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2-(1)-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2-(1)-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2-(1)-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2-(1)-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>S-Game</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Chinese action game Phantom Blade Zero has amassed over a million wishlists in the two weeks since its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/eagerly-awaited-chinese-action-game-phantom-blade-zero-finally-gets-a-release-date-and-yes-its-still-a-ps5-console-exclusive">September 2026 release date was confirmed</a>.</p>
<p>The dev team thanked everyone for "the overwhelming support", and wished players happy new year.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Phantom Blade Zero - Release Date Announcement Trailer | PS5 Games" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q89X4nOzxGw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Phantom Blade Zero - Release Date Announcement Trailer | PS5 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q89X4nOzxGw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Q89X4nOzxGw?autoplay=1" title="Phantom Blade Zero - Release Date Announcement Trailer | PS5 Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Phantom Blade Zero - Release Date Announcement Trailer | PS5 Games.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q89X4nOzxGw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"1 MILLION WISHLISTS!" developer S-GAME announced on Twitter/X yesterday. "In just 15 days since opening on Dec 12,<a href="https://x.com/hashtag/PhantomBladeZero?src=hashtag_click"> #PhantomBladeZero</a> has hit 1,000,000+ wishlists.</p>
<p>"From everyone on the dev team, thank you for the overwhelming support. Wishing you all a Happy New Year!"</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>That release date has been eagerly anticipated. The game was first revealed back in 2023 at a Sony showcase, but since then, details have come in drips and drabs, with a new <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/phantom-blade-zero-trailer-shows-fresh-gameplay-but-its-still-without-a-release-date">Year of the Snake trailer shown at the start of this year</a>.</p>
<p>As for how it plays? Ed went <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/phantom-blade-zero-is-speedy-stylish-and-absolutely-not-a-soulslike">hands-on at Gamescom in 2024</a> and loved its fast and stylish combat, stressing that no, it is <em>not</em> a Soulslike.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/phantom-blade-zero-clocks-up-over-1-million-wishlists-in-just-2-weeks]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[“We’ll Cross the Oceans of Time to Make This” – Simu Liu’s Sleeping Dogs Movie Taps Timo Tjahjanto to Direct]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/simu-liu-sleeping-dogs-movie-taps-timo-tjahjanto-to-direct/</link>
            <guid>1394380</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>It's been nearly a decade since we started to hear about <strong>Sleeping Dogs</strong>, the award-winning action-adventure game <a href="https://wccftech.com/sleeping-dogs-united-front-games-closed/">from the now-defunct United Front Games</a>, getting <a href="https://wccftech.com/donnie-yen-star-movie-adaptation-sleeping-dogs/">a film adaptation</a>. While for years, it seemed like the project, like the studio that made the original game, was dead in the water, Shang-Chi star <strong>Simu Liu</strong> has made it his personal mission to revive the film. Now, Liu has achieved a crucial step in that revival journey: by signing <strong>Timo Tjahjanto</strong> to be the film's director.</p>



<p>Liu and Tjahjanto both confirmed the news on <a href="https://x.com/Timobros/status/2005248175159050363">X (formerly Twitter)</a> with an exchange that began with a user asking Liu for an update on how the film is progressing. Liu pointed the user to Tjahjanto, who followed up with a gif from the game and the caption "<em>We'll cross the oceans of time to make this</em>."</p>



<p>Liu then responded with, "<em>Ladies and gents, the director of Sleeping Dogs</em>."</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>It's still unclear who will be penning the script, but it's good to see the film adaptation getting some momentum with Liu seemingly being the driving force behind any movement the film has. Liu is working on the film as a producer and will also ultimately star in it as Wei Shen, <a href="https://wccftech.com/sleeping-dogs-movie-still-on-donnie-yen/">essentially taking over the roles that the legendary Donnie Yen had all those years ago when we first heard of the adaptation</a>.</p>



<p>For his own part, <a href="https://x.com/Timobros/status/2005605017731178792">Tjahjanto added</a>, "<em>I’m excited to be developing SLEEPING DOGS with</em> <em>Simu Liu. We both are hungry and passionate about the material &amp; have plenty to prove. It's no secret that both TNCFU &amp; The Shadow Strays took inspiration from Sleeping Dogs, heck, I even based a character in TSS straight outta SD down to his name. This will take time, but we’ll make the best version out of it, Cleaver, chopsticks n' all.</em>"</p>



<p>Of course, the film still has a long way to go before we can look forward to seeing it in theatres, but it's clear that Liu is not giving up on it any time soon. The more he puts the pieces of it together, the closer we are to seeing the film in theatres, and then hopefully, the closer we are to getting another Sleeping Dogs game.</p>



<p>After all, that's always been Liu's plan. "<em>First a movie, then a sequel game for everyone...that's always been the dream</em>," he wrote on X (formerly Twitter) at the beginning of 2025. </p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>So few film projects make it from pitch phase to greenlight. Pitching execs who don’t understand the game has been tiring. Everyone’s overwhelming love of Sleeping Dogs here has really given us life!</p><p>First a movie, then a sequel game for everyone… that’s always been the dream. <a href="https://t.co/g84r9Lf0SI">pic.twitter.com/g84r9Lf0SI</a></p></div>— Simu Liu (@SimuLiu) <a href="https://twitter.com/SimuLiu/status/1885252869483340236?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 31, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/simu-liu-sleeping-dogs-movie-taps-timo-tjahjanto-to-direct/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘We’re Trapped in This Containment Field’: Former Sony Exec Proposes Single Gaming Format to Expand Console Market]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/were-trapped-in-this-containment-field-former-sony-exec-proposes-single-gaming-format-to-expand-console-market/</link>
            <guid>1394377</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>Shawn Layden</strong> <a href="https://wccftech.com/sony-worldwide-studios-chairman-shawn-layden-to-depart-the-company/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">retired</a> from his <span>position as Chairman of&nbsp;<strong>Sony Interactive Entertainment Worldwide Studios</strong>, Sony's gaming division responsible for creating PlayStation exclusives, in 2019, after spending 32 years&nbsp;</span>at the company in various roles.</p>



<p>Since then, the former executive has often commented on industry-related topics. Earlier this year, he <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-6-discless/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">suggested</a> that the <strong>PlayStation 6</strong>, Sony's next console, is unlikely to be completely discless as the physical market is still a sizable one for the company.</p>



<p>A few days ago, Layden <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cwH_otOCDmQ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was featured in a video interview</a> with YouTubers Naomi Kyle and Pause for Thought. During the 47-minute conversation, the executive admitted that the total install base of console users hasn't changed all that much in the past few generations, and proposed the creation of a 'consortium', like those used for the VHS, DVD, or Blu-ray, to create a <strong>unified gaming format</strong> that can then be licensed out.</p>



<p><em>We talk about gaming as being this $250 billion industry, which it is, and have hundreds of millions of users, which it does. But of course, that includes, if you're playing Wordle, you're a gamer. If you're playing Candy Crush, you're a gamer in that number. But the number of discrete consoles sold over any particular generation caps out at about 250 million. </em></p>



<p><em>If you line up all the PS1s, Sega Saturns, and N64s, and you go by generations, it's all about 250. The one time it popped to almost 300 was the generation that had the Wii, and people thought you could buy Wii Fit and lose weight. So, we got some non-traditional gaming audience to buy into the gaming industry at that time, but that was an anomaly and we've still flattened out. We need to crack that cap, that barrier. The only way we can do that is if, and I know people call me crazy and throw stones at me when I say this, but you know, Sony's Betamax format lost to VHS for one reason only: VHS licensed its format across many different manufacturers. </em></p>



<p><em>Sony held the unique Betamax patent trademark and everything. There was a license we did with Toshiba towards the end of the life cycle, but it never went wide like VHS and people didn't understand the need of having the same machine as your neighbor. You could have an RCA TV and you have a Sony TV and that's all fine. But once your neighbor has picked VHS and you want to watch that tape of that movie, but you have Betamax all of a sudden… So the industry coalesced around VHS. Then, later on, Sony and Philips created the compact disc consortium. They created the patent and then they licensed it out to all the other manufacturers. The same thing happened with DVD. The same thing happened with Blu-ray. They said that we'll compete on the device. So if you get a Bang &amp; Olufsen Blu-ray player, it's going to cost you more than the Sano version. Even though they'll both support the platform, but they'll have different bells and whistles. </em></p>



<p><em>I think we need to get in a world where we have a gaming format, and maybe it just comes from PC. Maybe we find a way just to do it all, you know, in a Linux kernel or something. And then we have a consortium around that. We have licensing programs which allow other manufacturers to build into that space and then you can talk about real numbers moving. That's how you get to the ubiquity of the toaster. But right now, I think we're kind of trapped in this containment field.</em></p>



<p>This is exactly the same problem that Microsoft has been shouting to the four winds for several years now, as it desperately reaches for the billions of potential gamers who could, in theory, be interested in games but have no intention of buying a specific console system. </p>



<p>Layden's vision also sounds pretty close to the single gaming platform ecosystem, which, personally, I've been advocating for several years. And yes, if it ever happened, it would have to be based on the PC. For Microsoft, it wouldn't be a big stretch, as they have already admitted they want to be everywhere the user is. Sony itself is also bringing its games to PC (albeit a bit late) and even to Xbox, as shown with Helldivers 2. The only major player in the console space that exclusively develops games for its own platform is Nintendo. </p>



<p>Their policy appears unlikely to change any time soon. Still, Layden's proposition is worth considering. Would you embrace such a change? Let us know below.</p>



<div id="democracy-1503" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1503,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Are we going toward a single platform future?</strong></p></div>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/were-trapped-in-this-containment-field-former-sony-exec-proposes-single-gaming-format-to-expand-console-market/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gun-Fu Action Game Spine Delayed as Dev Explains Lack of Release Date]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/spine-gun-fu-release-date-delay</link>
            <guid>1394374</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Gun-fu action game <em>Spine </em>was supposed to get a release date this year, but, as you've probably already noticed if you're following its progress, that didn't happen. Now, developer and publisher Nekki has taken to social media to explain why.</p><p>In <a href="https://x.com/playspine/status/2005664237407145990" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">a message</a> on X, Nekki acknowledges that they promised to reveal a release date for <em>Spine </em>this year, but that the team wasn't "ready" to announce a date or even a rough window.</p><p>Nekki says that since <em>Spine </em>is the team's first PC and console game, the project is "setting a new bar for quality, scope, and production values", and that the team's top priorities are <em>Spine</em>'s "product quality and...overall gameplay experience".</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Spine </em>didn't get a release date this year, and developer Nekki has explained why.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Nekki says that <em>Spine </em>is now "entering the final stages of development", and that the team is currently polishing the game's "content, locations, animations, voice acting, and interface". Developer diaries will continue between now and whenever <em>Spine</em>'s release date ends up being.</p><p>Sadly, you're not going to get that date today, either; Nekki says the team doesn't want to "name a release date [it isn't] fully confident in", but that you'll be hearing the date "in the near future". Expect more in the new year.</p><p>If you're not familiar with <em>Spine</em>, Nekki describes it as "a single-player action game about close-quarters gunfights with aesthetics of Gun-Fu movies", so you can expect inspiration from the likes of <em>John Wick </em>and the <em>Matrix </em>movies, as well as games like <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/cyberpunk-2077" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="c4cdcb94-eb27-4726-bc08-ac26ee9ad89e" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Cyberpunk 2077</em></a><em> </em>and the tragically-dormant <em>Deus Ex </em>series.</p><p>The game casts you as "rebellious street artist Redline and her sentient combat implant Spine", and together, the two must battle an "autocratic AI regime". What else, after all, does one do in a cyberpunk setting?</p>
<p>When <em>Spine </em>does eventually launch, you'll be able to check it out on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1731290/SPINE__This_is_Gun_Fu/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">PC</a>, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, and Nintendo Switch 2. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/spine-gun-fu-release-date-delay]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Drops the 27″ Odyssey Gaming Monitor to Black Friday Pricing, Now as Cheap as a Portable Monitor]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-drops-the-27%e2%80%b3-odyssey-gaming-monitor-to-black-friday-pricing-now-as-cheap-as-a-portable-monitor-2000656027</link>
            <guid>1394368</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The big gift-giving holidays have come and gone. If you didn’t find the gaming monitor you were hoping for under the tree, then its time to take matters into your own hands. If you’re looking for a reliable display for gaming or general everyday use, the Samsung Odyssey G5 27-inch QHD monitor is an excellent option. Not only does it check all the key boxes for performance and visual quality, but right now, it’s also available at a significant discount. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6613/">Amazon is offering a 28% price cut, bringing the cost down from its usual price of $250 to just $180, saving you a full $70.</a></p>
<p>The 27-inch size of the Odyssey G5 offers the perfect balance between ample screen space and a size that doesn’t overwhelm your desk. The 2560 x 1440 QHD resolution delivers crisp and clear images. While 4K resolution would offer even more detail, it would also come with a much higher price tag for a barely noticeable difference at this screen size. The monitor also supports HDR, enhancing color vibrancy and ensuring that whites appear bright and clean, while shadows are rich and deep. With a fast 200Hz refresh rate, it provides smooth and fluid motion, and the inclusion of AMD FreeSync technology eliminates screen tearing, helping ensure that your visuals stay seamless.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6613/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Real-Time Reaction Speed</h2>
<p>What truly sets this monitor apart is its ultra-fast 1ms response time, making it incredibly responsive during fast-paced gameplay. This rapid response allows you to react instantly, which is crucial for gaming where split-second decisions can make all the difference. As someone who switched from console gaming to PC, I can personally attest to how much input lag affects gameplay. I didn’t realize just how much of an impact it had until I tried playing <em>Silksong</em> on my old 2017 TV and compared it to playing the same game on my gaming laptop. The difference was night and day. On the TV, the game felt sluggish and nearly unplayable, but on the laptop, combat and platforming were much more manageable.</p>
<p>The Samsung Odyssey G5 is incredibly versatile, offering compatibility with a wide range of devices. Whether you’re connecting a gaming PC, laptop, Nintendo Switch, Steam Deck, or almost any other device, this monitor can handle it. It features two HDMI 2.0 ports and a DisplayPort connection, giving you plenty of options to set up your ideal gaming or work station.</p>



<p>The stand on this monitor is also fully adjustable, allowing you to modify both the height and tilt. This ensures you can find the perfect viewing angle for maximum comfort, whether you’re working for hours or diving into extended gaming sessions. Your neck and back will definitely thank you after long periods of use.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6613/">Even if you’re not a hardcore gamer, this monitor still provides great value, especially with the current 28% discount.</a> Whether you’re using it for gaming, work, or general multimedia, the Samsung Odyssey G5 is an excellent choice at just $180 for a limited time.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6613/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-drops-the-27%e2%80%b3-odyssey-gaming-monitor-to-black-friday-pricing-now-as-cheap-as-a-portable-monitor-2000656027]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo 3DS Prices Are Going Through The Roof And No One’s Sure Why]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nitnendo-switch-2-3ds-xl-used-ebay-prices-2000656110</link>
            <guid>1394365</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A New 3DS XL.</span> © Nintendo
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>Root through your drawers, and check that cardboard box in the attic: 3DS prices are going through the roof. As spotted by X account <a href="https://x.com/Pirat_Nation/status/2005564455271490030">Pirat_Nation</a>, the old Nintendo handheld is now selling secondhand for as much as or more than they did at launch.</p> <p>The 3DS, originally released in 2010, was officially discontinued in 2020. A successor to the massively successful Nintendo DS, it matched its predecessor’s two-screen clamshell design, but this time with a stereoscopic 3D screen on the top half that didn’t require wearing magic glasses. It was, despite how you might remember things, a <em>phenomenal</em> success, selling a wild 75.94 million units across its ten years and various incarnations. Yet, despite this apparent ubiquity, demand for the devices is currently skyrocketing such that a used 3DS XL—which you could have picked up a year ago for under $100—can right now fetch you upward of $250.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">3DS Prices Are Spiking</p> <p>This Decade-Old Nintendo Handheld Is Now Worth Almost as Much as a Switch 2</p> <p>New 3DS XL models are often selling for $200 to $350 used.</p> <p>Prices are likely to keep climbing. <a href="https://t.co/s0SZJecvzM">pic.twitter.com/s0SZJecvzM</a></p> <p>— Pirat_Nation 🔴 (@Pirat_Nation) <a href="https://twitter.com/Pirat_Nation/status/2005564455271490030?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 29, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Given the larger 3DS XL cost $200 on release (which itself was $50 cheaper than the original 3DS at launch), this is a massive price. It goes even higher if you’re looking for the so-called New Nintendo 3DS XL, the 2014 version of the handheld that added a new C-Stick and a better CPU, which you’ll struggle to pick up in good condition under $280. (If you scour eBay you might at first declare, “This idiot so-called ‘journalist’ has it all wrong!” until you look a bit closer and notice the lower prices will be for Japanese-only LL models, or listings that eventually reveal details about damaged LCD screens and the like.) It’s not entirely clear what’s driving this new interest; there hasn’t been a significant jump in piracy techniques since custom firmware superseded the need for flashcarts a few years back. Still,&nbsp;the 3DS remains an <em>amazing</em> gaming device.</p>

 <p>While the 3D effect was never something that really worked for me (with imperfect eyesight, it just looked blurry and unconvincing, and I’d inevitably just switch the effect off in every new game), it’s essentially a faster, bigger, and better Nintendo DS (the best console ever made, obviously), and is backwards compatible with the wonderful archive of DS games that preceded it. My 3DS XL sits proudly on the shelves behind me, secure in the knowledge that I’ll never sell it (well, unless prices spike an <em>awful</em> lot more), a copy of <em>Pokémon Ultra Moon</em> in the cart slot as nature intended. But it’s tempting!</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/nitnendo-switch-2-3ds-xl-used-ebay-prices-2000656110]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Logan Paul Talks About Pokémon Cards Like He’s Running A Ponzi Scheme]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/logan-paul-most-valuable-pokemon-card-auction-2000656107</link>
            <guid>1394338</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Will <em>Cyberpunk 2</em> be a PlayStation 7 game? Is <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> really going to be playable on Switch 2 next year? And why is Logan Paul so good at making everything he talks about, including Pokémon cards, sound so sleazy? It’s another edition of Morning Checkpoint, <em>Kotaku</em>‘s daily roundup of gaming news and culture.</p> <p>Ex-Sony Interactive Entertainment chairman Shawn Layden is apparently pitching <a href="https://gamerant.com/shawn-layden-playstation-new-project/">a <em>Mad Men-</em>style show</a> about game development. It will probably never get made but I would definitely watch the hell out of that. Bobby Kotick could play Bobby Kotick, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MovieDetails/comments/h0fo5r/in_moneyball_2011_bobby_kotick_the_ceo_of/">again</a>. For now, <em>Mythic Quest</em> remains a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MythicQuest/comments/105byyf/are_we_apologizing_for_the_nazis_or_on_their/">pretty great parody</a> of the video game industry.</p>

 <h2>Logan Paul sounds desperate to sell his $5.3 million Pikachu</h2>   <p>“Pokemon as an asset class has outperformed the stock market by upwards of 3,000 percent in the last 20 years.” That’s how the online content hustler recently hyped up the upcoming auction for his PSA 10 Illustrator Pikachu card, which he claims is the most valuable Pokémon card in the world, during a segment on Fox Business.</p>

 <p>Prior to promoting the upcoming auction, Paul <a href="https://kotaku.com/logan-pauls-latest-stunt-paying-6-million-for-rare-pi-1848743633">had been wearing</a> the nearly $6 million piece of paper around his neck during wrestling matches. If anyone can pop the insane bubble around Pokémon cards coming out of the covid-era lockdown, it’s the guy who, just a couple of years ago, had to <a href="https://kotaku.com/youtube-logan-paul-cryptozoo-nft-game-refund-lawsuit-1851143787">refund fans</a> for his failed NFT game.</p>

 <h2>Could <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> be the next big Switch 2 port we see in 2026?</h2> <p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/monsterhunterleaks/comments/1pxw8id/potential_new_info_on_t_gog_possible_switch_2/#lightbox">Data mining of the recent Title 4 Update</a> hints that development might currently be underway on a Switch 2 version. Considering <em>Resident Evil Requiem</em> and <em>Pragmata</em> are also coming to the new console, that’s not completely unexpected; Capcom has been supporting Switch 2 in a big way, though <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>‘ performance struggles on PC and console don’t instill a ton of confidence about how it might fare on the weaker platform.</p>

 <p>It might not be the only big new third-party port we see next year, either. Leaker NateTheHate <a href="https://imgur.com/YnfBIbY">reports</a> that a rumored ongoing shortage around Switch 2 dev kits has “largely been resolved.”</p> <h2>When will we see <em>Cyberpunk 2</em>?</h2> <p>Polish analytics firm Noble Securitie <a href="https://strefainwestorow.pl/analizy/noblesecurities-cdprojekt-wiedzmin-dlc-orion-cyberpunk">predicts</a> it could arrive as early as 2030 with a budget of roughly $420 million. That seems to wildly overestimate the speed and efficiency of modern AAA development. My own guess is we don’t see it until 2032 and it costs over half a billion before marketing.</p>

 <h2>Zack Snyder is a fan of the Kim Kardashian skin in <em>Fortnite&nbsp;</em></h2>   <p>The <em>Justice League</em> director recently wrote on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DS1aM6VEd1R/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;ig_rid=fea529be-5c29-42dd-90ce-d2129577d360">Instagram</a>, “Big thanks to @kimkardashian for carrying me to all those Royales on @fortnite over Christmas break.” The Kardashian cosmetic is <a href="https://kotaku.com/kim-kardashian-fortnite-skin-item-shop-most-used-2000655163">reportedly</a> the most popular skin in all of season 7.</p>

 <h2><em>Front Missions 3: Remake</em> is right around the corner and has a free demo</h2> <p>The overhaul of the tactical mech RPG classic for PS1 arrives on January 30 and recently got a free demo for fans to try. Unfortunately, the<em> Front Mission</em> series remakes have been some of the worst around, and I’m not holding my breath that <em>Front Mission 3</em> will reverse the trend. <a href="https://x.com/senhorcorvo/status/2003901159921360908">Early reports</a> from the demo are that the game still rocks but it feels like it was thrown together on a shoestring budget.</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-chinese-rpg-sword-fairy-trailer-remake-2000655947">Fans debate<em> Clair Obscur</em> becoming the new “Boss Baby Vibes” meme</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-legends-za-leak-video-old-build-teraleak-window-2000655988">In-development footage shows the version of <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em> we didn’t get</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/gta-5-voice-actor-ned-luke-swatted-police-live-streaming-twitch-2000655992">Cops know <em>GTA 5</em> voice actor by name because he’s been swatted so many times</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch this:</h2> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/logan-paul-most-valuable-pokemon-card-auction-2000656107]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forget Budget Tablets or PCs, HP Practically Gives Away Its 15.6″ Laptop at 80% Off to Offload 2025 Inventory]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/forget-budget-tablets-or-pcs-hp-practically-gives-away-its-15-6%e2%80%b3-laptop-at-80-off-to-offload-2025-inventory-2000656059</link>
            <guid>1394335</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Sometimes you need a computer that doesn’t have a thousand bells and whistles driving up the price. Still capable of being a daily driver, but not beholden to a massive price hike. We’ve found a great one that you can rely on without having to spend an arm and a leg. And it’s on sale now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6612/">Go to Amazon to purchase the HP 15.6 inch Laptop Computer for $399, which is $1600 lower than the retail price of $1999. That’s a discount of 80%.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6612/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A rugged and dependable laptop with plenty of screen real estate</h2>
<p>The HP 15.6 inch Laptop Computer integrates solid performance with a large display screen and rugged dependability into one budget-friendly unit. It’s great for all your work-related tasks, school projects, streaming and other general usage, without causing you to have to slow down.</p>
<p>The 15.6 inch display gives you plenty of much-needed screen real estate. The display gives you more space to stay browsing websites, watching movies etc., without making you feel like it’s too cramped. The keyboard is well-spaced too, not too loud that it’ll wake the dead, and sufficiently clicky. Plus, the touch pad will respond to swipe and click commands without a lot of pressure or effort.</p>
<p>Under the hood, the HP 15.6 inch Laptop Computer’s performance is far superior to most users’ expectations for general usage. The laptop turns on quickly, does not lag or slow down excessively with various applications open, and allows you to transition between applications seamlessly. That’s more than we can say about some models that leave you waiting a little too long between different apps, or lagging when typing when you need to get things done.</p>



<p>The connectivity options available on the laptop are simple and functional. There are ports for connecting external USB devices (such as flash drives), additional external hard drives or other devices, eliminating the need to look for converters. This option is useful for sharing files, attaching another monitor, or connecting printers.</p>
<p>The laptop also features Wi-Fi, enabling you to remain connected to the internet for school, work and entertainment purposes regardless of where you may be within your home or office.</p>
<p>Battery life on the HP 15.6 inch Laptop Computer is sufficient for everyday usage. You should be able to complete a standard day of browsing, streaming and productively working without needing to be plugged in to charge..</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6612/">For a full-featured laptop, the HP 15.6 inch Laptop Computer is an exceptional value at its discounted price of $399 on Amazon, down from its original price of $1999.</a> The HP 15.6 inch Laptop Computer is a great choice for anyone who wants a lot of performance without breaking the bank.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6612/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/forget-budget-tablets-or-pcs-hp-practically-gives-away-its-15-6%e2%80%b3-laptop-at-80-off-to-offload-2025-inventory-2000656059]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Trump’s Culture Of Corruption Allows A Bot To Make $230,000 Betting On Video Games]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/polymarket-betting-dota2-bot-trump-truth-predict-2000656106</link>
            <guid>1394332</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="featured-image">
                              <figure id="attachment_featured" aria-describedby="featured-caption">
                                                                          <figcaption id="featured-caption">
                    <span>A DOTA2 shot with a line going up.</span> © Valve / Kotaku
                  </figcaption>
                </figure>
                                                      </p><div>
              
              <p>When the U.S. gambling laws <a href="https://www.espn.com/sports-betting/story/_/id/23561576/chalk-line-how-got-legalized-sports-betting">loosened in 2018</a>, the <a href="https://www.espn.com/sports-betting/story/_/id/23561576/chalk-line-how-got-legalized-sports-betting">many and various ways it would destroy people’s lives</a> were widely predicted. It wasn’t hard to guess: you just had to look at every other country where it was allowed, <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c0mp0dp71ryo">not least the UK</a>. But perhaps few would have bet on (sorry) this resulting in a situation seven years later where bots were making small fortunes betting on online video games. One such bot, named TeemuTeemuTeemu, has made $230,000 in just five months gambling via Polymarket on games like <em>Counter-Strike</em>,&nbsp;<em>Dota 2</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>League of Legends</em>.</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Bot made $900 -&gt; $208k in 3 months on polymarket</p> <p>one of the most talked about bots on polymarket right now<br>farmed $208,521 pure profit in a quarter</p> <p>focus exclusively on esports<br>mainly LoL and Dota 2</p> <p>bot monitors live game<br>parses stream and official data faster than market… <a href="https://t.co/YTueu8U3Dm">pic.twitter.com/YTueu8U3Dm</a></p> <p>— Archive (@ArchiveExplorer) <a href="https://twitter.com/ArchiveExplorer/status/2005688246815146183?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 29, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>As noticed by X user ArchiveExplorer, the bot has made the majority of this money in the last three months, making observations of live games faster than any human could, and getting its bets in before the market can react to events in games. As such, it’s able to get bets in at far lower or higher odds than humans trying to react to in-game kills or objectives, and thus to game the market for maximum profit.</p>

 <p>Scrolling through <a href="https://polymarket.com/@TeemuTeemuTeemu">the bot’s history of bets</a>, it wins far more often than it loses, putting fairly large sums (routinely between $200 and $20,000) on very marginal improvements, bringing in modest wins of a few bucks up to around $1500. But it does this a&nbsp;<em>lot</em>—1,127 times over the months—with its biggest win being $89.3k in one bet.</p>

 <h2>You’ll never guess who let this happen</h2> <p>Of course, using bots to predict markets and make <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-12827752">light-speed decisions</a> isn’t anything new when it comes to gambling. That’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultra-low_latency_direct_market_access">how the stock markets have worked</a> for years. Given the recent rise of Polymarket, a crypto-scam-based prediction market where anyone can place bets on pretty much anything, it’s inevitable that it will eventually be entirely dominated by bots and algorithms, racing to be the fastest and most precise.</p>

 <p>Polymarket’s recent success is largely down to the Trump administration’s relaxing of regulations surrounding such an enterprise, driven—you’ll be astonished to learn—by a desire to allow Trump’s farcical Truth Social platform to offer the same sort of prediction gambling. Announced a couple of months ago, Truth Predict is the Trump Media &amp; Technology Group’s attempt, in partnership with Crypto.com, to muscle in on the market. Fun fact: <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/485594b3-5a72-4ae1-aa93-8ee987be1569">according to the <em>Financial Times</em></a>, Crypto.com donated $11 million to “Trump causes,” shortly followed by the closing of an investigation by the Securities and Exchange Commission into the company.</p>

 <p>Oh, and guess what! Donald Trump Jr. sits on the board of Polymarket! It so happens that back in July, investigations into whether Polymarket had been acting illegally were dropped by Trump’s government, after the company had previously stopped operating in the U.S. when the Biden administration suggested it might be running “an illegal exchange.”</p>

 <p>Quick aside: any small part of the above would have been enough to end a presidency at any previous point in history. Now, this is just one of many, many schemes, scams, and grifts the current president is running, out in the open, with no consequences at all.</p>

 <p>La la la, everything’s fine, do bee do bee doo, ArchiveExplorer suggests there’s now a lot of competition to build similar and faster bots than TeemuTeemuTeemu, all designed to exploit the ways in which games like&nbsp;<em>Dota</em> and&nbsp;<em>LoL</em> are competitively played. Money isn’t real, capitalism is a grift, and <a href="https://frac.org/hunger-poverty-america">47.4 million Americans live with food insecurity</a>.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/polymarket-betting-dota2-bot-trump-truth-predict-2000656106]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anker Goes Full Clearance on Its Charging Station, Nano Power Strip (7-in-1, USB-C) Drops to All-Time Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/anker-goes-full-clearance-on-its-charging-station-nano-power-strip-7-in-1-usb-c-drops-to-all-time-low-2000656056</link>
            <guid>1394323</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>When you have multiple devices to charge, it isn’t always fun trying to find a way to keep them all juiced up. Where did you put that cable, again? Do you actually know where that charging block is? We’re tired of having to figure all of this out, so we looked for an affordable solution. Turns out there is one, and you can save big on it right now!</p>
<p>The Anker Nano Charging Station is a great option that won’t bankrupt you. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6611/">Right now, you can buy it on Amazon for just $59.99, down from its normal price of $90</a>. So if you act now, you’ll get a savings of $30.01, which comes out to about a 33% discount.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6611/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A multi-port charging station that means business</h2>
<p>The Anker Nano Charging Station is an innovative multi-purpose power hub that offers several different ways to charge your devices using a single device. So say goodbye to having to figure out multiple adapters and chargers all at once.</p>
<p>This multi-port power hub provides users with the ability to charge their phones, tablets, laptops, watches, etc. by combining fast charging technology with a space-saving design. With the Anker Nano Charging Station, 7-in-1, you will be able to easily charge multiple devices at once using a single power source, eliminating the need to juggle multiple adapters and cords.</p>



<p>You’re covered, no matter what kind of charging you need to do. There are plenty of different types of ports available, including USB-C and USB-A ports that collectively allow for a maximum of 100 watts of power output. This allows you to charge higher demand devices such as laptops and tablets along with lower-demand devices such as smartphones, earbuds, etc., all at the same time. Because the Anker Nano Charging Station has a large number of ports, you don’t have to decide which device to charge first, and you won’t have to constantly switch between adapters.</p>
<p>Whether you’re preparing for a trip and need to charge your devices before leaving, or you simply want to charge all of your devices during the course of a typical night’s sleep, the Anker Nano Charging Station has got you covered. The Anker Nano Charging Station is designed to keep all of your essential devices charged and ready to use at all times.</p>
<p>For just $59.99 on Amazon, down from $90, the Anker Nano Charging Station, 7-in-1 represents good value. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6611/">For the cost of $59.99, the Anker Nano Charging Station, 7-in-1 is a practical choice for adding to your charging system.</a> And it’s a good way to make sure you’re always ready with additional power should you need it.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6611/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/anker-goes-full-clearance-on-its-charging-station-nano-power-strip-7-in-1-usb-c-drops-to-all-time-low-2000656056]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Hytale Be On Steam? How To Buy Hytale, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-steam-how-to-buy-hytale/</link>
            <guid>1394320</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Hytale will be one of 2026’s most in-demand early access games, and buying it will be a priority for lovers of sandbox and casual games, with the odd deadly monster here and there. You’d think Hytale being on Steam would be a guarantee, but the only guarantee in life is that there are no guarantees.</p>



<p>A new year normally gets off to a slow start. January 2026 doesn’t have a plethora of huge titles, but there’s one that catches the eye—<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-early-access-release-date-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale</a>. The resurrected and rejuvenated project is back on track, and Hypixel Studios is working hard to deliver the most complete game over the next few years.</p>



<p>If you want to buy it and support it, knowing if it’s on Steam will be a huge help.</p>







<h2 id="h-can-you-buy-hytale-on-steam">Can You Buy Hytale On Steam?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Flamingo? Bingo. Credit to Hypixel Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Hytale will not be available to purchase from Steam once it launches into early access in January 2026.</strong></p>



<p>‘But this would help Hytale succeed and bring more attention, surely?’ If this is your sentiment, it’s correct. But if you’re wondering why Hypixel Studios has made the call to skip Steam, there’s a very clear and respectful reason:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“No, not initially. We want to spend our time in Early Access working with our existing community to improve the game, rather than chasing a flood of cold first impressions that could overcorrect the game’s direction. We don’t shy away from honest, negative criticism; we have been very critical of the state of the game ourselves on social media. We simply want the first steps of our journey to be influenced by informed players rather than large-scale first impressions from those unfamiliar with the game’s development background.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>So, Hytale will be on Steam at some point, but only once the developer feels comfortable that the game is in a good-enough state to be purchased and reviewed on the platform. Negative reviews or review bombing can be destructive for any game, so this move makes a lot of sense and should be respected.</p>







<h2 id="h-how-to-purchase-hytale">How To Purchase Hytale</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Intruder. Credit to Hypixel Studios</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>The only way to buy Hytale right now is to make an account through the game’s website, verify your details, and complete the purchase.</strong></p>



<p>Check out these quick and handy instructions if you want to buy Hytale now:</p>



<ol>
<li>Go to the <a href="https://hytale.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Hytale</a> website.</li>



<li>Click one of the <strong>Pre-Purchase</strong> buttons.</li>



<li>Choose the edition you want, and click <strong>Pre-Purchase</strong> underneath it.</li>



<li>Create an account and verify it.</li>



<li>Accept the <strong>I Understand</strong> prompt for the Pre-Purchase notice.</li>



<li>Complete your Hytale order.</li>



<li>Once it’s done, you can download Hytale early access close to launch and start playing once it’s live.</li>
</ol>



<p>You’ll be met with this message before you continue with the purchase, just as a warning:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“This version represents the core of the game while development continues. Features will grow, evolve, and sometimes change direction based on your feedback. You may encounter bugs, unfinished content, or occasional instability, and saved games may need to be reset as we update systems. If you’re looking for the full experience, we recommend waiting for a later release; but if you’d like to help shape Hytale’s future, we’d love to have you with us.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Has Hytale done enough to convince you to buy it? If you’re thinking about buying it or have already purchased it, you can say why and discuss all things Hytale through the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>Before you purchase the game, ensure you’ve checked out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-system-requirements/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hytale’s PC Performance &amp; System Requirements</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/hytale-steam-how-to-buy-hytale/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Game With Rocket Trucks, Yakuza, And Sentient Mascots Is 2025's Most Radically Kind And Empathetic Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-game-with-rocket-trucks-yakuza-and-sentient-mascots-is-2025s-most-radically-kind-and-empathetic-game/1100-6536979/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1394317</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="">

            
          
  

<section><p>It exemplifies the unsexy and tedious work of building bridges and community in its quest design, upgrade systems, and writing.</p></section>
        
        
                    
              <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Throughout the events of Promise Mascot Agency, I was Pinky's ride. Anywhere that she needed to go, I had to ferry her in my crappy little truck. As a matter of fact, I was responsible for the transport of any and every mascot that stumbled through the doors of the Promise Mascot Agency and came under my employ. When Kofun needed to go to a nearby graveyard, I was the guy for the job. When Trororo needed a lift to the local adult store, I begrudgingly told him to hop in. Be it by land, air, or sea, it became my responsibility, and mine alone, to make sure everyone got where they needed to go.</p><p dir="ltr">Promise Mascot Agency is a game filled to the brim with chores and mundane tasks like this. As I traveled across the isle of Kaso-Machi, drifting in and out of decrepit villages and farm fields, I found that Promise Mascot Agency's cast was filled with folks in need of some assistance. The English teacher who worked unpaid overtime shifts to put on a night school at her underfunded workplace. The nearby mechanic with an insatiable curiosity for the occult, and no time between his job and family. If a shrine needed to be swept, I was there with a broom in a split second. Whether it was the local barkeep in a gimp suit, the streamer-turned-farmer, or of course, the disenfranchised youth, I was there with an olive branch to extend.</p><p dir="ltr">Promise Mascot Agency probably sounds like a convoluted game. It is. In one breath, it is a title about an ex-yakuza--handsomely voiced by the same actor behind Kiryu in the Yakuza games--driving around a countryside, rounding up seemingly endless collectibles and upgrades, and sending living mascots (like a giant crying tofu block) out on jobs via a simplistic management system and card-based minigame. In the latter, you must play support cards with differing strengths and weaknesses as a mascot performs a job in order to beat a troubling interference that arises and assure the job is a success. In another breath, it is a full-throated exercise in the lengths of compassion and empathy. It is rarely sleek and sexy about it--Promise Mascot Agency doesn't feature over-the-top set pieces or hide slick new super moves to reward the player for completing its long list of chores. But real, tender empathy for your fellow man rarely does look so good, and Promise Mascot Agency's unglamorous honesty is something I've come to admire from one of 2025's best and brightest games.</p><p dir="ltr">When you first arrive in Kaso-Machi and take on stewardship of the mascot agency, your primary goal is to drive better foot traffic to the formerly popular tourist destinations around town. Due to the dwindling economic status of the island, most of the people who have survived its trials and tribulations have moved on from it. All that's left behind are pockets of increasingly poorer people who are either too proud to leave or simply stuck. The economy needs a shot in the arm, and so it falls on you as Michi--who has been cast out from the yakuza for a job gone wrong--to send in mascots to the few businesses still operating, drum up interest, and invest your earnings into other ventures and mascots around Kaso-Machi.</p><p dir="ltr">Progress is slow but steady. Before you know it, districts that once seemed destined to fade into nothingness begin displaying faint signs of life again. A long-dormant festival is resurrected and, with time, this energy ripples outward to the rest of the island. The largely abandoned train station in the heart of town, which is presided over by a charming man and his cat-with-a-hat, is brought back from the brink of redundancy. A few towns over from Kaso-Machi's central hub, you revive an arcade. As the cultural centers and infrastructure of Kaso-Machi are resurrected, life in the reportedly cursed isle begins to flourish once more, and its residents invest that good will and energy back into you, the catalyst for this change.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1748/17481584/4623273-promisemascotagencytruck.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4623273" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1748/17481584/4623273-promisemascotagencytruck.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4623273"></a><figcaption>Pinky isn't the only weirdo you help out across Kaso-Machi.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1748/17481584/4623273-promisemascotagencytruck.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Sure, what I'm describing is a fairly standard upgrade system, but something about the way Promise Mascot Agency conveys them makes it stand above its peers. The "power-ups" gifted to Michi and Pinky aren't really the kind of skills that the player can then turn around and use for their own benefit like a standard skill tree or progression system. For example, you get a turbo upgrade for your truck, but it doesn't benefit you alone to use it. There are no races in Promise Mascot Agency, though a post-launch update did add time trials. It is, however, useful in getting you, and whomever you're carrying, to your destination more quickly and continuing to help and delegate tasks around the island. The same goes for the eventual boat and flying upgrades you gain as well.</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>Spoilers for Promise Mascot Agency follow.</strong></p><p dir="ltr">The cannon upgrade you receive partway through Promise Mascot Agency almost appears like the moment the game might introduce some kind of vehicular combat. Instead, you use it to launch Pinky, Promise Mascot Agency's sociopathic companion character, at piles of trash, since one of the side-activities you're invited to take part in is to clear Kaso-machi's abundance of garbage You can additionally fire her at reelection signs for the corrupt mayor, whom Pinky winds up running against in the game's final act! Otherwise, the cannon is almost comically useless: It will just launch Pinky straight up into the sky to the benefit of no one at all.</p><p dir="ltr">It is kind of funny how mundane Promise Mascot Agency turns out to be. It's a lot like the Yakuza games in that sense, which feature no shortage of oddball characters on sometimes incomprehensible journeys that often resolve themselves in deeply humane, relatable, and sometimes abjectly dull ways. It is a perspective on the human condition I resonate with on a profound level, and it is one I was so happy to find beneath the surface of Promise Mascot Agency. It's why I reveled in the simplistic motivations of its cast, and why I found myself entranced by the busywork they constantly dropped on me, as well as the mission of bettering the lives of everyone in Kaso-Machi. Of building a community that could withstand the corruption of local governance, overcome its grisly and tragic past, and forge a brighter future together.</p><p dir="ltr">All of the community-building the player spends the game toiling away at--all the garbage you clean, signs you take down, and businesses you bring back to Kaso-Machi--comes to a head in the game’s rousing finale. To make a complicated matter short, the continued existence of your agency, which has provided a home to mascots, economic stability to the island, and exposed local corruption, is being threatened. The only way to assure it continues is to win a national competition that is, as becomes obvious, rigged against you.</p><p dir="ltr">You lose, and you lose quite badly. But at Michi's lowest point, he retreats to a mind palace of sorts (Pinky dubs it a "metaphysical nightmare") and comes face to face with everyone he's helped--that you, the player, have helped. Every mascot we employed, every business owner we aided, every teenage thug we straightened out, and even members of the yakuza family that had tossed us out appeared to Michi. An island's worth of friendly faces propped us up, dusted us off, and reminded us that we weren't alone.</p><p>The end of the game plays out like a gauntlet of Promise Mascot Agency's card-based minigame. Only, by the game's end, all of your allies' support cards have been consolidated into a handful of overpowered ones that wipe out any threat with a single play. And as I cruised to Promise Mascot Agency's end on the back of the community that I'd spent 20+ hours building and fortifying, I couldn't help but think that of course the strongest power of them all was the power of friendship. Who would've thought that I'd find one of the richest examples of community in one of the most bizarre games about driving a human-sized, sentient (and not to mention, homicidal) thumb around town?</p>
  
                                                              </div>
    

              <div>
  <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>
  
    </div>
      
        
        
  
  
        
                    
        
        
          
                  


  

    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/this-game-with-rocket-trucks-yakuza-and-sentient-mascots-is-2025s-most-radically-kind-and-empathetic-game/1100-6536979/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After M4 MacBook Air Deals, Apple Slashes the iPad Mini (A17 Pro) to Its Lowest Price in a Clearance Move]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/after-m4-macbook-air-deals-apple-slashes-the-ipad-mini-a17-pro-to-its-lowest-price-in-a-clearance-move-2000656021</link>
            <guid>1394299</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p data-start="0" data-end="476">If you’ve ever wanted a device that’s easier to handle than a full-sized tablet but still larger and more capable than your phone, the iPad Mini fits perfectly into that sweet spot. It’s designed for people who want portability without giving up power or versatility. Whether you’re a creative professional, a student, or someone who just enjoys relaxing on the couch while scrolling for hours on end, the iPad Mini delivers a balanced experience that works in almost any situation.</p>
<p data-start="478" data-end="806">Right now, the 2024 Apple iPad Mini is even more appealing thanks to a solid discount. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6610/">The 128GB device is currently available at 20% off, which means you save $100 off the original $499 price</a>. That brings the cost down to just $399, making it one of the best times to grab Apple’s most compact tablet.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6610/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2 data-start="808" data-end="841">Big Power in a Compact Design</h2>
<p data-start="843" data-end="1253">The iPad Mini features an 8.3-inch Liquid Retina display that packs all the quality you expect from an iPad into a smaller, more comfortable form factor. It’s light enough to hold with one hand, making it ideal for reading, browsing, or sketching on the go. The display itself is sharp, vibrant, and designed with ultra-low reflectivity, so it remains easy to see even in bright lighting or outdoor conditions.</p>
<p data-start="1255" data-end="1689">Under the hood, the iPad Mini is powered by Apple’s A17 Pro chip. This processor delivers solid speed and efficiency, allowing the device to handle demanding tasks without slowing down. From multitasking to creative work, everything feels smooth and responsive. Apps launch quickly, transitions are fluid, and performance stays consistent whether you’re editing photos, watching videos, or bouncing back and forth between multiple apps.</p>
<p data-start="1691" data-end="2121">On the front, you’ll find a 12MP Ultra Wide camera with Center Stage. This feature is especially useful for video calls on FaceTime, Zoom, or other conferencing apps, as it automatically keeps you centered in the frame—even if you move around or someone else joins you in view. On the back, the 12MP camera supports 4K video recording and makes scanning documents quick and easy.</p>


<p data-start="2123" data-end="2436">Thanks to the A17 chip, the iPad Mini also offers fast Wi-Fi connectivity and smooth performance for everyday tasks like taking notes, marking up documents, editing photos or videos, and even gaming. With iPadOS, you can boost productivity further by running two apps side by side using split-screen multitasking. It runs a number of apps such as Microsoft 365 and Adobe Photoshop, as well as graphics-heavy games, without any issues.</p>
<p data-start="2438" data-end="2949">Optional accessories like the Apple Pencil Pro and Smart Folio (sold separately) enhance the experience even more. The Apple Pencil Pro allowing you to write, draw, or edit with precision, while the Smart Folio protects the screen and doubles as a stand for hands-free viewing.</p>
<p data-start="2951" data-end="3376" data-is-last-node="" data-is-only-node="">To top it all off, the iPad Mini is available in four stylish colors—purple, starlight, space gray, and pink. You can also choose between 128GB, 256GB, or 512GB of storage, along with Wi-Fi-only or Wi-Fi + Cellular models. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6610/">With Wi-Fi-only versions discounted by $100, this sale makes it possible to pick up the latest iPad Mini for as little as $399,</a> making it an excellent value for a powerful, ultra-portable tablet.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6610/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/after-m4-macbook-air-deals-apple-slashes-the-ipad-mini-a17-pro-to-its-lowest-price-in-a-clearance-move-2000656021]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Opinion: I Reviewed 25 Switch 2 Games In 2025, And These Are My Top 3 Picks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-i-reviewed-25-switch-2-games-in-2025-and-these-are-my-top-3-picks</link>
            <guid>1394284</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="83ca465de1d21"><a title="25 games, 3 top picks" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/83ca465de1d21/25-games-3-top-picks.large.jpg"></a></figure><p>Yes, yes, I know. Only 25 games since June. I am a lazy sod.</p>
<p>Regardless, I've had quite the ride thus far with my Switch 2. We're still not that far out from launch, and I expect super-duper exciting things in 2026. Loads of 'em. I can smell it. Oh no, wait, that was just my dog.</p>
<div><p>Now, while I haven't had the opportunity to review <em>all</em> of the biggest and best games released for the console in 2025, the ones I have cast my eye over make for a super solid list - with a few absolute stinkers thrown in for good measure. There's always at least one stinker thrown in for good measure. <strong>*points at dog*</strong></p><p>

With all of this in mind — and having recently revealed <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/games-of-the-year-2025-nintendo-life-staff-picks">our cumulative NL staff picks</a> — I thought it might be useful to take a look at my top three Switch 2 games of 2025, in no particular order, selected from <em>just</em> the titles that I personally spent time reviewing. Yeah? Might as well give it a go now I've gone this far, eh. I'll even give it a jaunty title. Let's go!</p></div><div><figure data-videoid="KK3nTYgZ9yY" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KK3nTYgZ9yY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytKK3nTYgZ9yY" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KK3nTYgZ9yY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KK3nTYgZ9yY?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed6205b9nlzpqw&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>841k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<h2>PJ's Top 3 Games From The 25 Switch 2 Games Wot He Reviewed On Switch 2 In 2025 (In no particular order)</h2>
<h3><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a></h3>
<p>I'm not having any more of this "Musou games are braindead button-mashers" patter out of you, son. I don't care if it's Christmas; that tired old line has been wrong for a while now, and in case you weren't aware, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Age of Imprisonment</a> makes this very clear.</p>
<p>Long gone are the days of bland, barren maps populated by one-trick CPU enemies. No more are the tired side quests, lack of challenge, lack of variety, lack of combat strategising...and all that other guff that people <em>say</em> us Musou fans have had to endure over the years. This is a big, bold, and beautiful <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Zelda</a> adventure that earns every bit of its "official canon" legitimising from the Big N.</p>

<p>This entry learns lessons and takes stock from what went a little wrong last time out, namely that crucial balance between story and combat. The rectifying of this one crucial aspect would have been enough for me, but with the extra grunt of the Switch 2 we also get an absolute looker that's always a pure joy to sit down and blast through. It's so slick and smooth!</p>
<p>My favourite Musou game thus far? Yep, it knocks that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/fire_emblem_warriors_three_hopes">Fire Emblem</a> effort out of pole position and everything.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:192867 @ 1767113339 -->
<h3><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</a></h3>
<p>Boof! I knew that <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-nintendo-switch-2-edition">The Ivalice Chronicles</a> was going to be good. Very good, even. I did not, however, expect to be swept away quite as hard as I was.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gba/final_fantasy_tactics_advance">Final Fantasy Tactics</a>, you may be surprised to learn, is actually my favourite FF of the lot. It's just exactly everything I want in terms of combat, vibes and story. The trifecta...she complete! Yes, I know some folk have issues with the reframing and reorganising of the War of the Lions content in this latest cut, but I am actually a big fan of what they've done with this new version.</p>

<p>It feels cleaner, and in all honesty, I don't really need any more combat once I'm done with the main story as it was originally. The combat in the War of the Lions, well, it was just more gravy, nothing new. This snazzy new effort also does vitally important stuff like make cameras and controls easier and better to navigate with.</p>
<p>Battlefield views, tagging enemies, smarter CPU strategising all much-improved...this is genuinely making an already fantastic game a notably better one. It knocks the experience from <strong>Very Good Game™</strong> territory into the realms of things that are actually, genuinely, very difficult to find any fault with. And all of this in the palm of your hand on Switch 2. Hold me, mammy.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:188132 @ 1767113339 -->
<h3><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-air-riders">Kirby Air Riders</a></h3>
<p>I know I said this is in no particular order. But I sort of lied. The more I consider it, the more it becomes clear that nothing grabbed me in my pure gamer heart quite as much as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-air-riders">Kirby Air Riders</a> did this year. It feels like the purest of pure sort of Nintendo magic that we Nintendo fans are forever pining after. Gies a wee sniff, mate. Go on. I just need one hit on that magic, son. Wheeeeeeee!</p>
<p>What has got me so engrossed in and excited about a semi-automated racer? Well, first of all, it's properly hard to fully master. Kirby's latest has depth for those who like it deep (phrasing), whilst also providing for the button-mashers and the low-attention-span fans. Stick at it, get used to its chaotic way of doing things, and you'll find a finely tuned racing beast purrs beneath the horror of giant neon pick-up icons. Yes, they are very big. I love them.</p>

<p>I've had some real sweaty finales (phrasing) during online matchups in this one, and all it takes is one other pro racer (or a whole bunch of you get lucky) to really awaken the magic. Once you've tasted the sweetness of a victory snatched from the jaws of defeat, a victory at what feels like 1000s of kilometres per hour through a cosmic chaos of Masahiro Sakurai's creation, it's very hard not be get fully hooked.</p>
<p>If I manage one thing this year — and really, I'm leaving it seriously late in the day but there's always hope — I'd be quite happy it be turning someone, anyone, on to the delights of Air Riders. It's a game that's easy to look at and nope out of. It's also a game that's easy to pick up, play, and walk away from as something that's just a big colourful mess for kids. But what's here beats out <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> for me in terms of online fun <em>and</em> competitiveness. It does <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/sonic-racing-crossworlds-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Sonic Crossworlds</a> in as well. Kirby just has it exactly where it matters, and in exactly the right manner and style for me this year. So suck on that.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:193790 @ 1767113339 -->
<hr>
<p><em>Have you got a top three you've been maining on Switch 2 you'd like to share in the comments? A top two? Just the one? Want to shout at me for something? Go ahead, it's Christmas!</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:192376,194331 @ 1767113436 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/opinion-i-reviewed-25-switch-2-games-in-2025-and-these-are-my-top-3-picks]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google Pixel Watch 4 LTE Crashes to Record Low Despite Being the Latest Android Smartwatch, Now Priced the Same as the Wi-Fi Model]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/google-pixel-watch-4-lte-crashes-to-record-low-despite-being-the-latest-android-smartwatch-now-priced-the-same-as-the-wi-fi-model-2000656014</link>
            <guid>1394278</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Got yourself some lofty fitness goals as we enter the new year? It’s common to set a news years resolution that involves getting into better shape, but it can be hard to maintain these new routines past the first couple months of the year. The best way to stick to a fitness regimen is by collecting data. Seriously. Getting yourself a good GPS watch can provide you with the health insights and personal coaching that can keep you motivated to hit the gym all year long.</p>
<p>Right now, the Google Pixel Watch 4 is available for a solid discount. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6609/">The 41mm model (LTE) usually sits at about $450, but Amazon has it marked down to $350 for a short window.</a> That works out to a 22% price cut, putting an extra $100 back in your pocket. Additionally, you can grab the 45mm option also for $100 off, bringing it from $500 to just $400.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6609/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p data-start="413" data-end="654">The Pixel Watch 4 has a sleek, refined design with the functionality you’d expect from a daily wearable.&nbsp;As a fitness companion, the Google smartwatch functions like a personal coach. It suggests running workouts tailored to your goals, training history, and daily readiness. These customized plans help runners monitor their progress, making it easier to tackle longer distances and improve times. You can even create your own workouts, including warm-ups, cooldowns, and pace targets. Plus, saved runs let you track improvements and set new personal records.</p>
<p data-start="1113" data-end="1316">Beyond fitness, the watch tracks various health metrics like daily readiness scores, cardio load, and the FitBit Morning Brief, which offers insights into your recovery and helps you plan your day ahead. The Pixel Watch 4 also offers useful features like offline Google Maps, the ability to pay with Google Wallet, and seamless integration with other Pixel devices and smart home gadgets like a Google Nest hub.</p>


<h2 data-start="1527" data-end="1562"><strong data-start="1527" data-end="1562">What’s New in the Pixel Watch 4</strong></h2>
<p data-start="1564" data-end="1837">While the changes from the Pixel Watch 3 are subtle, there are some notable upgrades. The most noticeable difference is the curved display. While the Pixel Watch 3 did have curved glass, the screen beneath the glass on the Watch 4 is also curved, giving it a more distinct look.</p>
<p data-start="1839" data-end="1977">Battery life has also improved. The Pixel Watch 4 lasts up to 30 hours with the always-on display or up to 48 hours in Battery Saver mode.</p>
<article dir="auto" data-turn-id="5a507e93-d283-4e0c-857d-9461129aa758" data-testid="conversation-turn-1" data-scroll-anchor="false" data-turn="user">

</article>
<article dir="auto" data-turn-id="request-WEB:a9d22697-a59a-4d7e-ba38-c654ed79ccb1-0" data-testid="conversation-turn-2" data-scroll-anchor="true" data-turn="assistant"></article>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/google-pixel-watch-4-lte-crashes-to-record-low-despite-being-the-latest-android-smartwatch-now-priced-the-same-as-the-wi-fi-model-2000656014]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘In This Age of Diversity, The Manufacturer Stubbornly Refused To Offer The Option’: Hideki Kamiya’s Solution To A Critical Nintendo Switch 2 Issue]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/in-this-age-of-diversity-the-manufacturer-stubbornly-refused-to-offer-the-option-hideki-kamiyas-solution-to-a-critical-nintendo-switch-2-issue/</link>
            <guid>1394272</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The <strong>Nintendo Switch 2</strong> launched this year after an extremely long wait that left much of the industry baffled, but this wait didn't prevent the system from becoming a <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-2m-units-sold-in-us-ea-sports-college-football-tops-july-us-sales-charts/"><strong>smashing success</strong>.</a></p>



<p>However, it's undeniable that the new generation console by Nintendo <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-below-average-hdr/"><strong>comes with some issues</strong></a>, including a <strong>long-standing controls issue</strong> which forced legendary game creator <strong>Hideki Kamiya</strong> to go to some <strong>extreme measures</strong> to fix: the <strong>lack of D-Pad on the Joy-Con controller</strong>.</p>



<p>Speaking with <strong><a href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/999/G999905/20251219044/index_3.html#clo_kam">Japanese publication 4Gamer</a></strong> as part of its now traditional end-of-year wrap up with Japanese game developers, the creator of the <strong>Devil May Cry, Okami and Bayonetta</strong> series, among others, recounted his experience with the Nintendo Switch 2, finally managing to get his hands on a system only recently after purchasing a second system for his <strong>niece</strong>, who took his launch system for herself. Spending time with the system made Kamiya-san frustrated by the <strong>lack of a proper D-pad</strong> on the Joy-Con controllers.</p>



<p><em>"Even after it finally came back to me, for some reason, <strong>in this age of diversity, the manufacturer itself has stubbornly refused to offer the option of a 'Joy-Con with a D-pad'</strong> since the Switch 1. This just didn't fit into my gaming lifestyle, where I usually <strong>play while lying down</strong>, so I have no choice but to use the Joy-Con when playing games,"</em> he said, as translated by <strong><a href="https://x.com/stealth40k/status/2004712820403999129">Stealth</a></strong>, touching upon an issue many <strong>old-school gamers</strong> have had with the Nintendo Switch systems.</p>



<p>After continuing to use the original Switch for his daily <strong>Tetris 99</strong> fix and taking advantage of <strong>third-party peripherals</strong> with a proper D-pad, Kamiya-san decided to take matters into his own hands to make the <strong>Nintendo Switch 2 his primary hardware</strong>. </p>



<p><em>"I purchased a new <strong>Cyber ​​Gadget 'mini grip with D-pad,'</strong> which I use with the Switch 1, and after some <strong>sanding and modifying</strong> it so that it could be attached to the Switch 2, where the <strong>button layout is slightly different</strong>, I was able to make my own <strong>'D-pad Joy-Con 2,'</strong> which finally allowed me to play titles from <strong>'Arcade Archives 2.'</strong>"</em></p>



<p>As someone who frequently plays old-school 2D games, I have long felt Hideki Kamiya's pain. Hopefully, Nintendo or third-party manufacturers will eventually address the issue and provide <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">more controller options</strong> for those who think a <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">solid D-pad is an essential part</strong> of any controller. As the Japanese company itself offers access to a catalog of older games via the <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Nintendo Switch Online</strong> subscription, it would make <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">considerable sense</strong>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/in-this-age-of-diversity-the-manufacturer-stubbornly-refused-to-offer-the-option-hideki-kamiyas-solution-to-a-critical-nintendo-switch-2-issue/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>