<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 14:36:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frostpunk 2 Console Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/17/frostpunk-2-console-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/frostpunk-2-console-review.1300374/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>The world came to an end in 1887. That’s a sobering line to start any game with, but here you already feel the seeping cold and unflinching hardness of Frostpunk. Launched last year on PC, this survival city builder imagines a past where a new ice age arrived, and where humanity is on the brink of extinction. It’s your task to keep the remaining people alive, and it’s fair to say that this is one of the most gruelling, most intensive and most involving survival games of all time. It is, for want of any other word, a masterpiece.</p>
<p><iframe title="Frostpunk 2 - Console Date Reveal Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OMyxKNAqpnQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You begin Frostpunk 2 with The Wanderers, a prologue designed to get you up to speed, and one which hardens the narrative strands dangled in front of you at the start of the game’s narrative mode. Here, you get a sense of how people have survived this stricken, frozen planet, with nomadic groups returning to the hulking great furnaces that they huddle around when a whiteout comes. The need for survival, and the need for everyone to pull in the same direction, is immediately hammered home, and the hammering won’t stop the further you go.</p>


<p>Frostpunk 2 has to be the most cinematic city builder I’ve ever played. The sense of drama, emotion and gravitas shouldn’t be possible when you’re placing down structures, setting jobs and tinkering with menus, but there’s something about Frostpunk 2 that’s immediately affecting.</p>
<p>The ravening wind, the shouts of the workers as they build, the clank of extraction units pulling oil from the ground; there’s a constant soundscape at play here that brings the world to life, enhanced by the strains of the plaintive orchestral soundtrack. It feels real and imposing, and that sense of realness, of the thin line between life and death, permeates every aspect of the game.</p>

<p>Key within that are the politics and factions at work within your city. When things are going wrong, they look for someone to blame, and when things are going right, someone somewhere will still be unhappy. While it might be set in an imagined post-apocalyptic timeline, Frostpunk 2 still offers one of the most realistic takes on politics and public life we’ve seen in gaming. You might be able to pacify a couple of communities with your decisions, but there will always be an outlier, or a wrinkle provided by a new faction within them, and you have to navigate the ebb and flow of popularity, patience and penance, as you try to maintain your role as Steward of this frigid cityscape.</p>

<p>You need to maintain forward motion in Frostpunk 2, otherwise, you will, quite literally, find yourself frozen in place. Expansion and research play a significant role in preparing for the harsher moments, when temperatures drop dangerously low, and your populace huddles slightly closer to the furnaces.</p>
<p>While you begin from a single central point in New London, you must identify the weaknesses in your supply chains, whether that’s food, oil or other commodities, and then prepare expeditions to break through the frostbitten ground to clear a path that will allow you to extract the necessary natural resource from the ground.</p>
<p>That’s all dictated by time. From the tutorial’s hurried push to build enough food surplus, Frostpunk 2 sets you on a path that requires split-second action and decisiveness. Every act takes time, and just as with your political standing, you have to find the balance between pushing further out into the wilderness or cementing what you have, pushing forward with better technologies that will make what little you do have go further, rather than hitting upon a new but finite vein.</p>
<p>Playing Frostpunk 2 is clawing and claustrophobic. You feel a constant weight of expectation and tension while playing, and that sensation hasn’t been lost in its transition to console. The navigation with a controller does, in some way, enhance it. That’s down to the slightly unwieldy nature of the tool you’ve been given, and, like one of your citizens swinging a spade into the ice rather than a pickaxe, it will get you somewhere, but it’s much harder work.</p>

<p>Playing on console, the central control mechanisms of moving, building and frostbreaking, are handled quite elegantly with a touch of the right shoulder button bringing up the main interface while you cycle through the resulting menus with the D-pad. You soon become accustomed to shifting between different areas, and the readouts and resource markers are very clear and easy to parse, even on a TV at distance, letting you build an expand your cityscape with some certainty.</p>
<p>It’s the wider menus where the ice gets a little bit slushy. Pressing the Square button brings up the Extended City View, and from here you’re able to move between a variety of different sections with the analogue stick or D-pad, but choosing the particular area you need to access isn’t always handled properly, and I found myself having to back in and out having made the wrong selection again, while occasionally making additional buildings in districts didn’t register correctly.</p>
<p>That’s then compounded by some odd freezing in certain menus, which would only be slightly ironic if it wasn’t quite so frustrating. In a game where you’re fighting for survival and where every moment matters, it’s not just an annoying speedbump, it’s a block in the road. Despite how good Frostpunk 2 is, I’d currently hold off on buying the game on console until there’s confirmation that it’s been remedied with an early patch.</p>
<p>The controller implementation overall is satisfactory, but I’d like to see more development time given to it in the long run. It’s never going to match the ease of interacting with a mouse, but then there are some things that a controller simply can’t match a mouse for, and city builders and RTS games sit at the top of the pile. I hope that we might see a Switch 2 port for Frostpunk 2 at some point, but I do wonder what sacrifices would have to be made to get it running there.</p>

<p>Frostpunk 2 benefits from a strong visual identity, and though there’s clearly a lot of snow, frost and a reliance on the colour white, the burgeoning lights of the city, and its glowing infrastructure really make it pop from the screen, while the detailed portraits emphasise the human element at play. Those visuals are at their best in Fidelity mode, and on the base PS5, performance is good, albeit at 30fps, with things staying steady as you sweep and spin across your city, zooming in and out to different districts and expansions.</p>
<p>You can occasionally make things skip a beat if you’ve filled the landscape and you’re shifting around at speed, but it doesn’t diminish the game in any way. You also have the option of a zippy 60fps Performance Mode, or a Balanced 40fps option if your screen supports 120Hz. This was definitely the best of both worlds, and makes everything feel considerably smoother, but I still missed the sheer glory of the Fidelity Mode, and in a city builder, it’s more than possible to live with 30fps.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/17/frostpunk-2-console-review/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Review For Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist & The White Guardian Is In]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/the-first-review-for-atelier-resleriana-the-red-alchemist-and-the-white-guardian-is-in</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-review-for-atelier-resleriana-the-red-alchemist-the-white-guardian-is-in.1300371/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Famitsuits you, sir</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Atlier reserlianana nananam famitsu score" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/b0168e87dbb5e/atlier-reserlianana-nananam-famitsu-score.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Gust Corporation</em></figcaption></figure><p>The latest Famitsu scores have hit the inter tubes (thanks, <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1915">Gematsu</a>) and in amongst all the excitement, we've got our very first score for the upcoming <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/atelier_resleriana_the_red_alchemist_and_the_white_guardian">Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist &amp; the White Guardian</a>.</p>
<p>The popular Japanese gaming magazine has awarded Gust's latest 8/8/8/8 [32/40], which ain't too bad at all considering that this writer's pick of the franchise, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/atelier_ryza_3_alchemist_of_the_end_and_the_secret_key">Atelier Ryza 3</a>, got itself a 34 from the same weekly mag, and it was a cracker (as we go into <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/atelier-ryza-3-alchemist-of-the-end-and-the-secret-key">lots more detail on in our 9/10 review</a>).</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/features/atelier-resleriana-the-red-alchemist-and-the-white-guardian-devs-on-the-series-evolution-ai-and-de-stressing-with-dk">We recently spoke with the folks behind Atelier Resleriana: The Red Alchemist &amp; the White Guardian</a> about the game, AI, and a bunch of other things, and we'll be bringing you our own thoughts on the latest Atelier adventure a little down the line.</p>
<p>In the same issue, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/super_robot_wars_y">Super Robot Wars Y</a> (which released in the West at the end of August), Bandai Namco's grid-based combat RPG, also got itself a score of 8/8/9/8 [33/40] on Switch.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Looking forward to the latest Atelier adventure? Have you been enjoying Super Robot Wars? Be sure to let us know.</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:187013 @ 1758119403 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1915" rel="noopener" href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/famitsu-review-scores-issue-1915">gematsu.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://mynintendonews.com/2025/09/17/latest-weekly-famitsu-review-scores-2/" rel="noopener" href="https://mynintendonews.com/2025/09/17/latest-weekly-famitsu-review-scores-2/">mynintendonews.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/8a4e905f75e6ddf70a7165fae624b656 @ 1758117251 --></div></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/the-first-review-for-atelier-resleriana-the-red-alchemist-and-the-white-guardian-is-in]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Little Nightmares 3 has a pint-sized bad dream demo out now, ahead of its arrival next month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/little-nightmares-3-has-a-pint-sized-bad-dream-demo-out-now-ahead-of-its-arrival-next-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/little-nightmares-3-has-a-pint-sized-bad-dream-demo-out-now-ahead-of-its-arrival-next-month.1300368/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Half an hour or so of eerie puzzling awaits you</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/little-nightmares-3-demo-out-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/little-nightmares-3-demo-out-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/little-nightmares-3-demo-out-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/little-nightmares-3-demo-out-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/little-nightmares-3-demo-out-01.jpg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Supermassive Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/supermassive-games">Supermassive Games</a> have put out a demo for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/little-nightmares-iii">Little Nightmares 3</a>, so you can give the spooky co-op puzzler a whirl before it arrives in October. "Step into the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/necropolis">Necropolis</a>", the studio say. Go on then, that sounds like it has zero potential to end badly.</p>
<p>As our Nic conveyed earlier this year, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/supermassives-little-nightmares-3-is-out-this-october-reanimal-still-looks-much-better">Little Nightmares 3's coming out October 10th</a>. That date was unaffected by Supermassive <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/until-dawn-devs-supermassive-lay-off-up-to-36-workers-delay-interstellar-horror-directive-8020">laying off up to 36 people</a> and delaying interstellar horror Directive 8020 in July.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Little Nightmares III - The Necropolis | Demo Available Now" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zq-Pp9KqaeM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Little Nightmares III - The Necropolis | Demo Available Now</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zq-Pp9KqaeM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Zq-Pp9KqaeM?autoplay=1" title="Little Nightmares III - The Necropolis | Demo Available Now">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zq-Pp9KqaeM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>As you can see above, the demo's come with a quick trailer heavy on sinister humming. The two titchy protagonists Low and Alone wind levers, climb through flaps, and otherwise platform. Oh no, this platforming has attracted the attention of a giant baby monster with grubby fingers that can reach for the duo like they're the last Bourbon cream in the cupboard (other biscuits are available). Its gaze can also turn them to stone, which is a power alll babies have, they just hide it very well.</p><p>As in the full game, you and a mate can wield the bow and wrench of Little Nightmares 3's pair, or you can play alone with an AI companion. Maybe give them the bow, I bet their aim's pretty good. 30 minutes of small nightmaring await you either way.</p>
<p>If you've not given the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/little-nightmares">Little Nightmares</a> series a go before, here are a couple of extracts from former RPSers Adam and Alice B about the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/little-nightmares-review-pc">first</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/little-nightmares-2-review">second</a> games in the series respectively:</p>
<blockquote>It's a grotesque, horrid and eventually hopeful in its own morbid fashion, and despite many moments that feel like reimaginings or echoes from elsewhere, it has enough extraordinary images and sequences to stand alone. It's precisely the kind of horror game I love – grotesque but not gross, and interested in thoughtful pacing and escalation rather than jumpscares and shocks. Also, linear though it is, there are some collectibles I'd like to hunt for and the whole game is short enough that I'll happily play it again, or watch someone else playing.</blockquote>
<blockquote>These flaws are small enough that I'm happy to place Little Nightmares II up on my shelf of excellence right next to the first one. Childhood fears are such a rich vein to slice open, and Tarsier Studios do it in a very thoughtful way. Little Nightmares II is such a splendid mix of cute and creepy, beautiful and awful, that it sort of defies categorisation. A childhood terror gothic, perhaps?</blockquote>
<p>You can find Little Nightmares 3's demo on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1392860/Little_Nightmares_III/">its Steam page</a>.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/little-nightmares-3-has-a-pint-sized-bad-dream-demo-out-now-ahead-of-its-arrival-next-month]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5 Metroidvania Games To Play If You’ve Been Defeated By Hollow Knight: Silksong]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/metroidvania-hollow-knight-silksong-islets-ori-2000626458</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/5-metroidvania-games-to-play-if-you%E2%80%99ve-been-defeated-by-hollow-knight-silksong.1300362/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Look, it’s OK. Some games are just incredibly hard, and not everyone has the skills or patience required to conquer them. Many people are finding their limit with&nbsp;<em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em>, reaching a boss that just cannot be bested or realizing their fingers just aren’t capable of the dexterity required to master the super-hard platformer. But don’t wallow! Pick yourself up and try any of these games that offer a similar experience, without being quite so brutal.</p> <p><em>Silksong</em> has <a href="https://kotaku.com/game-difficulty-hollow-knight-easy-mode-2000624441">re-opened the wound of gaming difficulty discourse</a>, causing friction over the topic of how hard a game can reasonably be without offering difficulty options for less skilled players. Of course, for all the debate and discussion, one core truth always remains: developers are allowed to make their games any way they want. Some choose to do this by responding to feedback from players, but others have a fixed vision for their creation and aren’t going to be moved from that. There’s no sense fighting this, not least when the vast banquet of video games already offers so very many fantastic alternatives.</p> <p>I dearly wish I were better at <em>Hollow Knight: Silksong</em> because it’s the so-called “metroidvania” format that so attracts me. The genre, whose name is somewhat awkwardly based on the franchises of <em>Metroid</em> and&nbsp;<em>Castlevania</em>, generally refers to platform games in which you gain a growing number of skills and abilities which, over time, give you access to previously inaccessible areas. Along the way, regenerating enemies attempt to thwart your progress, while one-time bosses are stationed at key points. The more skills you get, the easier those earlier areas become, and the better prepared you are for the later challenges. All that’s true of <em>Silksong</em>, of course! But there are very many games that offer it all without the punishing difficulty. Here are a few worth picking up if&nbsp;<em>Silksong</em> is getting you down.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/metroidvania-hollow-knight-silksong-islets-ori-2000626458]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anker’s 60,000mAh Power Bank Has Never Been Priced Lower Than Now, Blackout and Camping Charger-Light Combo]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ankers-60000mah-power-bank-has-never-been-priced-lower-than-now-blackout-and-camping-charger-light-combo-2000626100</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anker%E2%80%99s-60-000mah-power-bank-has-never-been-priced-lower-than-now-blackout-and-camping-charger-light-combo.1300356/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>When one device can address several inconveniences and annoyances while putting a pile of money back in your pocket, it’s well worth a look. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4144/">The Anker 548 Power Bank 60,000mAh portable power station cost $250 two years ago, but right now at Amazon it’s only $80 — its lowest price ever, and a 47% reduction from its most recent retail price of $150</a>. It’ll be the best $80 you’ve spent in a long while after just one camping trip or one blackout.</p>
<p>What are those annoyances it can eliminate for you? How about when the power goes out and you reach into the junk drawer for a flashlight, only to discover it’s dead and has likely been dead for a long time, leaving you to scramble for a handful of D-cell batteries. Or when you buy a “portable” power station only to discover it might be portable if you’re a powerlifter, but otherwise it’s a ginormous device that you’d really rather not have to carry around. The Anker 548 Power Bank is the $80 solution to those woes, and many more.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4144/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Truly, Amazingly Portable</h2>
<p>Unless you enjoy the workout of lugging a “portable” power station that tips the scales at 25 or more pounds, the first thing you’ll notice about the Anker 548 Power Bank is that it’s really, truly portable for everyone. It’s barely over 5 pounds, and has a built-in handle atop its compact 4.6 x 4.6 x 8.2 inch body. It’s power on the go literally anywhere you need it — ideal for stashing in your bedroom for a power outage, keeping in the car for powering devices on long trips, or occupying a very small space in your vehicle on your next outdoor adventure.</p>
<p>The built-in light at the top of the Anker 548 Power Bank is retractable so it can give you either a little glow or a full-on light source, and there’s also an SOS mode for emergencies — ideal for roadside breakdowns. The Anker 548 is also ready when you need it, even if that’s months away — after a full year without being recharged, it retains an amazing 85% of its charge.</p>



<h2>Multi-Device Power</h2>
<p>The Anker 548 Power Bank has an enormous 60,000mAh capacity, and two USB-C and two USB-A ports ready for your devices. That’s enough to fully charge a MacBook Air almost 3 times, and an iPhone 14 Pro Max 7.4 times, and a 3W LED emergency lamp will stay lit for over 42 hours. The LED Smart Display shows you all the vital stats, including the power level of the 548 Power Bank itself. Recharging the Anker 548 Power Bank is a simple USB-C operation, or you can attach it to a compatible solar panel with an XT-60 connector for clean, endlessly renewable recharging.</p>
<p>It’s safe to say <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4144/">the Anker 548 Power Bank massively overperforms the $80 price tag it’s carrying during this limited-time Amazon deal.</a> It’ll take just one power outage or one fun camping trek for it to easily pay for itself, and since it has a projected lifespan up to 10 times longer than most competing models, you’ll have plenty of time to reap the rewards.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4144/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ankers-60000mah-power-bank-has-never-been-priced-lower-than-now-blackout-and-camping-charger-light-combo-2000626100]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skate Players Find Flopping Is Faster Than Actual Skateboarding]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/skate-players-find-flopping-is-faster-than-actual-skateboarding/1100-6534811/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/skate-players-find-flopping-is-faster-than-actual-skateboarding.1300350/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534811">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>In real life, a skateboard is generally a quick way to get around town, but in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/skate/">Skate</a>, you can leave your fellow skaters in the dust by rag-dolling to your destination. With the game now out in early access on PC and console, players have begun to discover several physics-defying glitches--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/skate-glitch-lets-you-cheat-gravity-by-clapping/1100-6534797/">like clapping being better than a parachute</a>. On social media channels, you can find numerous examples of players flopping around, building up some impressive speed with their asphalt nipple-surfing around the city of San Vansterdamn.</p><p>In related news, <a href="https://x.com/SkateStatus/status/1968048173492081010" rel="nofollow ">developer Full Circle has confirmed</a> that it is looking to address the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/skate-server-queues-lead-to-complaints-about-always-online-requirement/1100-6534790/">lengthy waiting times</a> to hop into the game. "Our team is hard at work adding more servers and getting more skaters into San Van," the studio said. Earlier this week, Full Circle said there are "a LOT" of players attempting to jump into Skate, leading to the congested server issues. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/eas-new-skate-game-is-always-online-reconfirmed-for-2025-launch/1100-6531121/">Since the game is designed to be always online</a>, eager players currently have no choice but to wait until space frees up, leading many players to request an offline mode be added to Skate.</p><p>The launch week of Skate has gotten off to a strong start--<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/mostplayed" rel="nofollow ">with a peak concurrent players figure of 81,340 users</a> on Steam so far--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/skate-season-1-start-and-end-dates-what-you-can-expect/1100-6534794/">and the game's first season</a> kicks off in October. If you're looking to play, you can check out our guides to gain a quick advantage, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-make-money-in-skate-and-get-free-rewards/1100-6534796/">like how to get free rewards and easy money in Skate</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-add-friends-in-skate-crossplay-and-cross-saves-explained/1100-6534792/">how to add friends in Skate</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

        
  
</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534740&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/skate-release-times-revealed-for-early-access-launch\/1100-6534740\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6533833&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-4-shift-codes-all-active-keys-and-how-to-redeem-them\/1100-6533833\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534776&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fortnites-megazord-is-delayed\/1100-6534776\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534737&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/tony-hawk-just-remade-tony-hawks-underground-kind-of\/1100-6534737\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526471&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2025-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6526471\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534774&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/first-new-skate-game-in-15-years-is-out-now-and-its-free\/1100-6534774\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534754&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/overwatch-2-persona-5-crossover-skins-are-ready-to-steal-your-heart-and-wallet\/1100-6534754\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534733&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-4-devs-arent-planning-to-nerf-your-favorite-busted-build-yet\/1100-6534733\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534726&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-witcher-season-4-see-liam-hemsworth-as-geralt-plus-release-date-confirmed\/1100-6534726\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534780&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-ps5-system-update-arrives-wednesday-with-power-saving-mode-and-dualsense-sync-upgrade\/1100-6534780\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534783&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/escape-from-tarkov-on-steam-will-require-you-buy-it-again\/1100-6534783\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534790&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/skate-server-queues-lead-to-complaints-about-always-online-requirement\/1100-6534790\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534750&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-decade-ago-the-taken-king-saved-destiny-and-then-cursed-it\/1100-6534750\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534710&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dying-light-the-beast-launch-times-revealed-release-date-moved-up\/1100-6534710\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534676&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/evercade-alpha-taito-bartop-arcade-cabinet-preorder-buying-guide\/1100-6534676\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534761&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/madden-nfl-26-football-game-deals-ps5-switch-2-xbox-series-x\/1100-6534761\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534744&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/shudder-10th-anniversary-collectors-edition\/1100-6534744\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534784&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/psa-new-borderlands-4-bug-may-steal-all-your-skill-points\/1100-6534784\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534752&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-battlefield-6-is-approaching-locked-vs-open-class-weapons\/1100-6534752\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6534746&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/borderlands-4-boss-calls-people-4k-stubborn-disputes-reports-of-performance-issues\/1100-6534746\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/skate-players-find-flopping-is-faster-than-actual-skateboarding/1100-6534811/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic: The Gathering's Next Secret Lair Drop Features Art Built With Play-Doh]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/magic-the-gatherings-next-secret-lair-drop-features-art-built-with-play-doh/1100-6534810/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/magic-the-gatherings-next-secret-lair-drop-features-art-built-with-play-doh.1300344/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534810">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Wizards of the Coast routinely releases a special limited-time Secret Lair drop as a fundraiser for <a href="https://www.extra-life.org/home" rel="nofollow ">Extra Life</a>--the gaming-centric charity that supports Children's Miracle Network hospitals--ahead of the charity's annual 24-hour gaming marathon. This year will be no different, but the drop will feature a unique twist: Play-Doh.</p><p dir="ltr">The drop, called Secret Lair x Play-Doh: Squishful Thinking, features reprinted cards sporting artwork taken from real-life Play-Doh sculptures. The four cards included in the Secret Lair x Play-Doh: Squishful Thinking drop are as follows:</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Greensleeves, Maro-Sorcerer</li><li dir="ltr">Polyraptor</li><li dir="ltr">Academy Manufactor</li><li dir="ltr">Wurmcoil Engine</li></ul><p dir="ltr">This marks the seventh straight year Wizards of the Coast has released a Secret Lair drop benefitting Extra Life. Previous Extra Life drops from Secret Lair include cards with art hand-drawn by patients from Seattle Children’s Autism Center in 2021 and 2022, two separate My Little Pony-themed drops in 2019 and 2023, and last year's drop featuring pixel art from longtime MTG artist Mike Burns.</p><p dir="ltr">Magic: The Gathering Secret Lair x Play-Doh: Squishful Thinking will be available on the Secret Lair website September 29 to November 9, both in non-foil for $40 and in rainbow foil for $50. The drop will also be available in limited quantities at MagicCon: Atlanta September 26-28.</p><p dir="ltr">This isn't the only drop coming to Secret Lair soon, as a new superdrop themed around the Marvel's Spider-Man set will begin on September 22. The superdrop features six drops of five cards each, and they will feature reprinted cards from MTG history with art highlighting Spider-Man and some of his most fearsome archenemies.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/magic-the-gatherings-next-secret-lair-drop-features-art-built-with-play-doh/1100-6534810/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix's Splinter Cell animated series arrives next month, but there's no sign of a new game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/netflixs-splinter-cell-animated-series-arrives-next-month-but-theres-no-sign-of-a-new-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflixs-splinter-cell-animated-series-arrives-next-month-but-theres-no-sign-of-a-new-game.1300335/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>The Witcher Season Four also out soon.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tom-Clancy's-Splinter-Cell_-Deathwatch-_-Official-Trailer-_-Netflix-0-10-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tom-Clancy's-Splinter-Cell_-Deathwatch-_-Official-Trailer-_-Netflix-0-10-screenshot-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tom-Clancy's-Splinter-Cell_-Deathwatch-_-Official-Trailer-_-Netflix-0-10-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tom-Clancy's-Splinter-Cell_-Deathwatch-_-Official-Trailer-_-Netflix-0-10-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tom-Clancy's-Splinter-Cell_-Deathwatch-_-Official-Trailer-_-Netflix-0-10-screenshot-(1).png?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Netflix</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Netflix has released a full trailer for its forthcoming Splinter Cell animated series, ahead of its release next month.
</p>
<p>
From Derek Kolstad, writer of the John Wick franchise, Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Deathwatch will of course follow series protagonist Sam Fisher - here looking a little older and more grizzled, though still with his iconic night-vision goggles.
</p>
<p>
Liev Schreiber (who's been in a tonne of films, from Scream to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/10-men-origins-wolverine">X-Men Origins: Wolverine</a> and Isle of Dogs) provides the voice of Fisher, and the whole thing has been produced by Ubisoft Film &amp; Television.
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Deathwatch | Official Trailer | Netflix" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4A9iFjaKeMk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Deathwatch | Official Trailer | Netflix</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4A9iFjaKeMk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4A9iFjaKeMk?autoplay=1" title="Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Deathwatch | Official Trailer | Netflix">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Tom Clancy's Splinter Cell: Deathwatch official trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4A9iFjaKeMk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>
The series will be available from 14th October and also stars Kirby Howell-Baptiste (Killing Eve, The Sandman) as new Splinter Cell agent Zinnia McKenna.
</p>
<p>
News of a Splinter Cell animated series came <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/netflix-is-reportedly-working-on-an-animated-splinter-cell-series">back in 2020</a>, so this series has been a long time coming. A separate <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisofts-splinter-cell-movie-cancelled-after-producer-admits-they-just-couldnt-get-it-right">Splinter Cell film was cancelled last year</a> as the production team "just couldn't get it right".
</p>
<p>
October is a busy month for Netflix video game adaptations, as the fourth season of The Witcher also arrives on 30th October. It now stars Liam Hemsworth as Geralt of Rivia, instead of Henry Cavill. Check out a trailer below to see him in action.
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Witcher: Season 4 | Official Teaser | Netflix" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kQGshAJmdBU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Witcher: Season 4 | Official Teaser | Netflix</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kQGshAJmdBU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kQGshAJmdBU?autoplay=1" title="The Witcher: Season 4 | Official Teaser | Netflix">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Witcher: Season 4 official teaser.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kQGshAJmdBU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>
As for new Splinter Cell games, Ubisoft announced a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/ubisoft-announces-splinter-cell-remake">remake of the first game in the series back in 2021</a>, but we've heard nothing since.
</p>




        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/netflixs-splinter-cell-animated-series-arrives-next-month-but-theres-no-sign-of-a-new-game]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hands on Reach – Impossible VR action made real]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/17/hands-on-reach/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hands-on-reach-%E2%80%93-impossible-vr-action-made-real.1300314/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Watching the trailer for Reach, nDreams Elevation’s latest VR game, it wasn’t the visuals or the story that grabbed my attention and made me want to play the game, but that it seemed to be filled with leaps and dives that would make even me, someone who doesn’t suffer from VR motion sickness, reach for the sick bag. It honestly looked almost unplayable at points, but Elevation is a special team within nDreams that has the time to research and prototype new ways of playing in VR, so I was intrigued to see how they were advancing the format.</p>
<p><iframe title="Reach - Gameplay Trailer | PS VR2 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lOuzzp4V9HQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The game is described as an action-adventure and we’ve had that sort of game in VR before, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/02/16/horizon-call-of-the-mountain-review-psvr-2/">Horizon: Call of the Mountain</a> springs to mind, but that always felt quite staid and constrained – you were either moving, climbing, or shooting, one at a time. Reach is much more like a non-VR action adventure where you are performing multiple actions at the same time, chaining together movement and actions to really live in that fantasy.</p>


<p>The first mission, which acts as a tutorial, sets our heroine clambering up city walls, shooting bad guys and running for her life. Rather cleverly, she is a stuntwoman and so the whole first mission is an elongated sequence where she is acting in a movie. Of course there’s a big set piece moment that she’s tasked with performing, to escape from a helicopter, make death defying leaps through windows, clamber around the side of buildings and try and stay on your feet as the building collapses around you. It’s quite exhilarating and reminded me of the chase sequence in the James Bond movie, Spectre.</p>


<p>Skipping ahead a few levels my demo moved deep underground to a mysterious ancient city filled with robots that are not keen on a human poking around. There’s a lot more puzzling in the sections, some of which requires you to work mechanisms to open doors, and other times just to sit and wonder how on earth you are going to reach a certain ledge or doorway. The mechanical puzzles felt satisfying as they usually involve using a weapon rather than just pulling a series switches and there’s lots of audio and visual feedback to let you know if you are getting things right.</p>
<p>The main weapon in Reach is a bow which can be upgraded to fire four different types of arrow, but while a full frontal assault on the enemy robots can work you are also encouraged to use stealth. By sneaking up behind the automatons you can go full Predator and rip their spines out, taking them down in one move and saving your precious arrows. You will also need to work tactically when there are multiple robots, taking them out in an order that will not get you caught.</p>

<p>Adding an extra layer to the platforming and puzzling is your shield, which also lets you play out your Captain America fantasies by flinging it ahead and watching it ricochet with improbable accuracy as it takes out multiple enemies. It can also slotted in to sections of walls to create an extra platform. If that wasn’t enough, yet another upgrade lets you zoom up to the ceiling like Batman using a grapple gun.</p>
<p>Adding all these tools and abilities together creates something rather special. You get to play your way, rather than in a prescribed fashion. In fact you will want to experiment as during playtesting the testers were performing moves that the team didn’t realise were possible, so they added a few extra secrets to discover if you manage to pull off some spectacular.</p>
<p>Looking at screenshot of Reach and you may not be that impressed – it’s certainly pushing the Meta Quest 2 or 3 to its limits, but missing the extra detail allowed by the power of the PSVR 2. It really is a game you have to play to be impressed by, or at least read a glowing preview about. It may not look like it’s doing anything particularly new, we’ve all played VR games with bows and clambering ledges, but it really is one of the most immersive games I have played. All the old ways of making VR comfortable that took you out of the game have been peeled away, and once you have got the hang on the controls it just feels natural.</p>

<p>It’s an odd comparison but to me it feels just as ‘real’ as Beat Saber. That’s the only other game where I have felt completely absorbed in the world and not like I”m playing a VR game. The biggest compliment I can give the game is that I was meant to play it for about 45 minutes but they eventually yanked me out of VR after an hour and a half, and it honestly felt like half that time. If you have been wanting to dust off your VR headset then Reach may just be the game to tempt you.</p>
<p><em>Reach launches on 16th October 2025 on <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/concept/10012024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PS VR2</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=video_description&amp;redir_token=QUFFLUhqbFpjTDVtb2dkcTlRdjllRVR6RC01YUhJMjB4QXxBQ3Jtc0tuUHpHN3p2OFFiRnlmTzJKUWtwLUhoOG5NSFBfdk43Sm9aWEJCZGFwbFV6YmdrQ2d1aDNBc1phbExXYVpZUmExZnpOWDhuOHVDRFZDdVVSbGdYUjMxSjVFSVhoVkZIcWZUX2x1VmlzazROTkVweDhvMA&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fbit.ly%2F43Z4b5o&amp;v=N1gKZBhIABE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MetaQuest</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/redirect?event=video_description&amp;redir_token=QUFFLUhqa29NUEdSS3UxZjVhYmprS1luQ3pWODdYY3NuZ3xBQ3Jtc0ttVVpvZkYtNmkwSnZodm1Fcl90MGo5Z2t4ZXFSSU8wWkJHMkp1WTAwcDRWMG9TaFRldFotRUpPODlXOXNfemZEQmJ2TFYybG9ocWowQi0tOVRGV1RSTWU4dzcyZGduYmVxSklaSEt2c2EzTDk2QmQySQ&amp;q=https%3A%2F%2Fbit.ly%2F3FRuyBX&amp;v=N1gKZBhIABE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">and PC VR.</a> Players who pre-order from the <a href="https://www.meta.com/en-gb/experiences/reach/9707487579328855/">Meta Horizon Store</a> or <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/UP2985-PPSA25045_00-0865705303155937">PlayStation Store</a> any time from now until launch will receive the Ferran cosmetic set which includes &nbsp;a Traditional Ferran outfit, Ornate Bow, &nbsp;Ferran Guard Shield, Traditional Gauntlets and Ornate Drone.</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/17/hands-on-reach/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Madden NFL 26 Updated On Switch 2, Here Are The Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/madden-nfl-26-updated-on-switch-2-here-are-the-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/madden-nfl-26-updated-on-switch-2-here-are-the-patch-notes.1300311/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Defensive tweaks, new playbooks, more Limp Bizkit!</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="madden big patch" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/c10fce3ee4b2e/madden-big-patch.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: EA Sports</em></figcaption></figure><p>EA Sports has dropped a huge new update for the recently released <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/ea-sports-madden-nfl-26">Madden NFL 26</a>. The September 17th patch introduces a large number of fixes, adjustments, and other bits and bobs to a game that does a very solid job of bringing the full Madden experience to handheld - so long as you can take the frame rate hit.</p>
<p>Focusing in on highlights here, this patch (which brings the game to version 1.7) brings defensive adjustments in the midfield that should make runners a little easier to catch, whilst a new mechanic that's been brought over from EA's <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/ea_sports_college_football_26">College Football</a> franchise allows you to make your own default pass protection system to suit your chosen coach philosophy. Audio and visual effects, some quirky animations and other bugs also see fixes.</p>
<p>You can check out the full, and very long, patch notes over at <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/madden-nfl/madden-nfl-26/news/title-update-september-17-2025">EA's site</a>, but here are some highlights for your perusal:</p>
<h2>Gameplay</h2>
<h3>Pass Blocking</h3>
<ul>
<li>Added a new Coaching Adjustment option allowing you to set your default pass protection scheme—choose from Base, Empty, Half Left, Full Left, Half Right, Full Right or Default.</li>
<li>Enhanced QB Contain logic to ensure defenders contain more effectively</li>
</ul>
<h3>Run Game</h3>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue allowing a short, artificial speed boost to the ball carrier when using Truck in open space (Air Truck).</li>
</ul>
<h3>Passing Game</h3>
<ul>
<li>Increased the minimum for ‘stemmed down’ routes from 1 yard to 3 yards.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pass Coverage</h3>
<ul>
<li>Added a new Coaching Adjustment setting to set the safeties depth at 16 yards.</li>
<li>Updated hook-defender depth with underneath coverage adjustment to play at 5 yards of depth to be in better position to play short routes like drag routes.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Animation &amp; Visuals</h3>
<ul>
<li>Adjusted Small Agile Back hit stick animations to look more realistic and grounded.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue sometimes causing defenders to warp back to their feet when mid-lunge in tackling.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue allowing late hurdle attempts to cause missed tackles.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Franchise</h2>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where certain Players would be playing out of position</li>
</ul>
<h2>Superstar Mode</h2>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where Season stats were not accessible</li>
<li>Adjusted QB Combine drills</li>
<li>Resolved an issue where selected Gear would appear on the wrong uniform</li>
</ul>
<h3>Stability &amp; Disconnects</h3>
<ul>
<li>Fixed multiple soft locks in NUX scenarios, Field Pass purchases, and Preseason Events.</li>
<li>Addressed crashes when loading into Squads crossplay sessions with multiple PC players.</li>
<li>Corrected disconnects during ready-up transitions in H2H and Squads lobbies.</li>
<li>Resolved desyncs in 6v6 and Sick Six modes.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Audio</h2>
<ul>
<li>New music added: Limp Bizkit - “Morgan Wallen”</li>
<li>Fixes for various issues: in-game commentary firing improperly, stadium music adjustments, SFX volume adjustments, mix adjustments for the Halftime Show, &amp; a fix for unintended audio dropouts when adjusting unrelated volume sliders.</li>
</ul>
<h2>UI</h2>
<ul>
<li>Fixed crash when entering Custom Playbooks</li>
<li>Fixed issue with avatar portraits not showing in the Halftime Report</li>
</ul>
<h2>Art</h2>
<ul>
<li>Added additional NFL Player &amp; Coach Likeness Heads</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>Indeed, a glance over to the game's forums in the wake of the news of this update, and players seem very happy with the laundry list of changes in the patch notes, most of which have been in response to feedback. So well played there, EA.</p>
<p>In our <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/ea-sports-madden-nfl-26">8/10 review</a>, we said Madden NFL 26 is "a very solid port of one of the best outings for this franchise in recent memory. Yes, you'll need to get used to a drop in the frame rate to 40fps on Switch 2, but it's a reasonable downgrade in order to get this type of game running as well as it does on a portable machine."</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:186166 @ 1758116702 -->
<p><em>Enjoying Madden 26? Got used to the frame rate on Switch 2?</em><em><br></em></p></section></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Hookshot Media. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, which is ages ago. Favourite genres include RPGs, puzzle games and lovely big single player adventures of all kinds. The weirder the better.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/madden-nfl-26-updated-on-switch-2-here-are-the-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open-World Sanbox Racing Game Wreckreation Arrives This October]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wreckreation-release-date-open-world-sandbox-racing-game/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/open-world-sanbox-racing-game-wreckreation-arrives-this-october.1300308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Wreckreation is the latest game from Three Fields Entertainment, a studio that was founded by <a href="https://wccftech.com/ex-criterion-devs-reveal-first-details-on-their-new-game-coming-out-soon-has-couch-co-op/">former Criterion developers</a> who worked on the beloved Burnout series. Published by THQ Nordic, after Wreckreation was first announced back in <a href="https://wccftech.com/wreckreation-is-a-sandbox-racing-game-set-in-a-400km%c2%b2-open-world/">2022</a>, three years later we have a release date to look forward to, with the open-world driving sandbox arriving on October 28, 2025.</p>



<p>The news was announced alongside a new trailer that showcases the bright vistas and the insane tracks that are possible for players to create in this sandbox title, as Wreckreation is as much about building your own dream tracks as it is racing them.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Wreckreation | Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kEMB3PehB38?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>What makes building your own tracks as core to Wreckreation as the actual driving is the fact that you're not swapping from one mode to another if you want to make a change or adjustment to the road in front of you.</p>



<p>Changes to the track, your environment, like the weather or time of day, adding loops, and even adding a slew of decorations can all be done on the fly at the press of a button. With more than 50 cars, and 400 square kilometers of sandbox to run around in, there are plenty of ways you can create your own racing paradise.</p>



<p>Wreckreation will launch on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S on October 28, 2025, for $39.99/€39.99.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/wreckreation-release-date-open-world-sandbox-racing-game/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest Smash/Grow Is a Mobile Roguelite RPG Coming Next Year]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-quest-smash-grow-mobile-rpg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-smash-grow-is-a-mobile-roguelite-rpg-coming-next-year.1300305/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Square Enix has officially revealed&nbsp;<em>Dragon Quest Smash/Grow</em>, a mobile roguelite RPG that features classic&nbsp;<em>Dragon Quest&nbsp;</em>enemies and aesthetics, and you could get a chance to try it out soon.</p>

<p>According to the game's new <a href="https://smashgrow.dragonquest.com/en/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">official website</a>,&nbsp;<em>Dragon Quest Smash/Grow&nbsp;</em>is a game in which you'll "smash your way through hordes of monsters", using "<em>Dragon Quest</em>'s signature Coup de Grace attacks" to deal huge damage to them.</p>

<p>Each run will bestow random Blessings on you to augment certain parts of your playstyle, so you'll need to "adapt your battle strategy to match an ever-changing tactical situation", according to Square Enix. The studio says that "no quest is ever the same" in the game.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dragon-quest-smash-grow-mobile.jpg?itok=kdZ4Fpiu 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dragon-quest-smash-grow-mobile.jpg?itok=hAneOuCg 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Dragon Quest Smash/Grow&nbsp;</em>brings the series' trademark aesthetics to the mobile roguelite RPG realm.</figcaption></figure><p>Each run of&nbsp;<em>Dragon Quest Smash/Grow&nbsp;</em>will see you sprinting through a linear level in which groups of enemies will attack you, and you'll need to dispatch them, collecting their crystals to gain Blessings and upgrade yourself.</p>

<p>Since&nbsp;<em>Smash/Grow&nbsp;</em>is a roguelite, it's likely that there will be some element of permanent progress as well; perhaps you'll unlock new Blessings for future runs, or maybe you'll progress through a story as each run concludes.</p>

<p>Either way, you may well get a chance to try the game out sooner than later, because a closed beta test is taking place between October 14th and October 21st. Since it's a closed beta, though, you'll need to <a href="https://smashgrow.dragonquest.com/en/cbt/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">apply to enter</a>.</p>

<p>The test will require you to have either an iOS device that's equivalent to the iPhone XR or later or an Android device with a Snapdragon 855 SoC (or better, of course). There are 30,000 places available, so make sure to get your application in quickly!</p>




<p>It's all go for&nbsp;<em>Dragon Quest&nbsp;</em>right now. During <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-direct-september-2025-recap" rel="nofollow">last week's Nintendo Direct show</a>, Square Enix announced a full 3D remake of&nbsp;<em>Dragon Quest VII</em>, and work is apparently <a href="https://gamerant.com/dragon-quest-12-update-may-2025/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">continuing</a> on&nbsp;<em>Dragon Quest XII</em>, although we still don't know too much about the game.</p>

<p><em>Dragon Quest Smash/Grow&nbsp;</em>is set to come to Android and iOS devices sometime next year, and the closed beta is scheduled to take place in October. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-quest-smash-grow-mobile-rpg]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bandai Namco Condemns Mockups Of Gunpla Models Of Charlie Kirk’s Assassination]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/charlie-kirk-assassination-bandai-namco-ai-model-gunpla-2000626472</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bandai-namco-condemns-mockups-of-gunpla-models-of-charlie-kirk%E2%80%99s-assassination.1300296/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>We’re a week out from the assassination of right-wing commentator Charlie Kirk, and the internet is still running wild with new information, commentary, and, as the internet often does, dark jokes. That includes AI slop, and one particular brand of it became so viral that Bandai Namco, or more specifically, the company’s toy division, has released a statement about its logo being used in fake mockups of Gunpla models depicting Kirk’s assassination.</span></p> <p><span>The statement was released on the company’s </span><a href="https://x.com/BandaiCollect/status/1968140558959882612"><span>social media channels</span></a><span>, and while it doesn’t reference Kirk’s death by name, it says that it has been made aware of “AI-generated images circulating online that depict the Bandai Namco Toys &amp; Collectibles America Inc. logo on packaging associated with graphic or violent content, including references to recent events.” The images, which </span><i><span>Kotaku </span></i><span>has verified, include a fake model of the moment Kirk was shot on September 10 at the Utah Valley University campus with a fake Bandai-branded box in the background. The full statement reads as follows:</span></p> <blockquote><p><span>We have recently been made aware of AI-generated images circulating online that depict the Bandai Namco Toys &amp; Collectibles America Inc. logo on packaging associated with graphic or violent content, including references to recent events.</span></p> <p><span>We want to make it unequivocally clear: Bandai Namco Toys &amp; Collectibles America Inc. strongly condemns any form of violence and does not support or endorse the use of our brand, products, or logo in any such context. These images are not created, approved, or affiliated with our company in any way.</span></p> <p><span>We are actively investigating this matter and are taking steps to report and remove any unauthorized or misleading content. The misuse of our intellectual property in a way that misrepresents our values and intentions is deeply concerning and will not be tolerated.</span></p> <p><span>We thank our community for bringing this to our attention and encourage anyone who sees similar misuses to report them to us directly.</span></p></blockquote> <p><span>Kirk’s death has sparked a whirlwind of controversy that has bled into various industries as </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/ghost-yotei-charlie-kirk-joke-playstation-sony-2000625478"><span>public figures have reacted to the event</span></a><span>. </span><i><span>Helldivers 2 </span></i><span>has even been dragged into the entire ordeal after it was reported that a reference to the Arrowhead Game Studios game was </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/charlie-kirk-shooter-helldivers-bullet-engraving-2000625439"><span>engraved on the bullet casings used in the fatal shooting</span></a><span>. Naturally, this has led to a rehash of long-debated discussions on whether </span><a href="https://kotaku.com/charlie-kirk-shooter-tyler-robinson-discord-reddit-memes-2000625746"><span>violent crimes can be linked to video games</span></a><span>.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/charlie-kirk-assassination-bandai-namco-ai-model-gunpla-2000626472]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mutant Football League 2 launches December 10 for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/mutant-football-league-2-launches-december-10-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mutant-football-league-2-launches-december-10-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.1300290/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently in Early Access for Xbox Series and PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Arcade [89 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">Arcade</a>-style sports game <em><a title="Games > Mutant Football League 2" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mutant-football-league-2">Mutant Football League 2</a></em> will leave Early Access and launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,383 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,915 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,263 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1657320/Mutant_Football_League_2/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on December 10 for $29.99, developer <a title="Companies > Digital Dreams Entertainment" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/digital-dreams-entertainment">Digital Dreams Entertainment</a> announced. <span id="more-993176"></span></p><p><em>Mutant Football League 2</em> first launched in Early Access for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1657320/Mutant_Football_League_2/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 31, 2024, followed by Xbox Series on January 30, 2025. The Early Access version is currently priced at $24.99.</p><p>“<em><a title="Companies > MUTAN [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mutan">Mutan</a>t League</em> is my bastard child that I’ve loved since its inception in the early nineties,” said <em>Mutant Football League 2</em> creative director Michael Mendheim in a press release. “And now, against all odds, our small team of passionate and dedicated developers has managed to resurrect it for a new generation. At its core, it’s fun, hard-hitting, and unpredictable—easy to pick up and play, yet layered with depth and strategy. We’re thrilled that on December 10, 2025, <em>Mutant Football League 2</em> will bring joy, laughter, and maybe a few bruises among friends to players worldwide.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Digital Dreams Entertainment:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Mutant Football League 2</em> is the outrageous, over-the-top successor to the 2017 cult-classic created by Michael Mendheim, the mind behind <a title="Companies > Electronic Arts [1,782 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/electronic-arts">Electronic Arts</a>‘ ’90s <a title="Companies > SEGA [2,694 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a> Genesis hits <em>Mutant League Football</em> and <em>Mutant League Hockey</em>. His team is back in <a title="Genres > Action [3,043 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> and hittin’ harder than Swift’s post-engagement half-time show.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>This is not your parents’ football game or a bloated <a title="Genres > Simulation [834 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation</a> that chases realism at the expense of fun. <em>Mutant Football League 2</em> is a brutal, darkly comedic eight-on-eight arcade-style action-packed football game. Teams of Mutated Super-Humans, Monstrous Orcs, Skeletal Deadheads, and Armored BruiserBots are pit against each other in fantastical arenas packed with deadly traps and sinister hazards like buzzsaws and giant mutant worms. This “anti-Madden” blends the pick-up-and-play accessibility of arcade <a title="Genres > Sports [652 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/sports">sports games</a> with strategic depth and a buttload of monstrous mayhem. Referees don’t just blow calls—they get blown up. Players don’t just fumble—they explode into limbs and pink mist.</p><p>In <em>Mutant Football League 2</em>, you’ll create your dream team of dirty dudes and customize your team’s player composition and tactics. The right team is your ticket to gridiron glory, and you’ll have to define their playing style. Will you deploy a relentless offensive by mutilating the opposition? Or will you slice through the enemy’s defense with razor-sharp, brainy maneuvers? It’s up to you to show the world your prowess and become a true MFL legend. Under your guidance, these mutants will rise from scrubs to legends, crushing the competition with style and savagery across <em>Mutant Football League 2</em>‘s single-player Season, Dynasty Supreme franchise mode, and online <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [601 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a>.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Bloody Sunday! Sunday! Sunday!</strong> – Brace yourself for exploding body parts, comically horrific deaths, and blood splatters that paint the field red. Whether getting blitzed by a rampaging monster or succumbing to a trap-laden end zone, every game is a symphony of unpredictable chaos. Dirty Trick plays even allow teams to commit bannable atrocities; those poor refs… Nothing and no one is safe.</li><li><strong>Monster Squad</strong> – Choose from over 36 MFL teams composed of maniacal mutant versions of pro football superstars—32 pro-league teams like the Karcass City Creeps, Killadelphia Evils, and Blitzburgh Steelheads, and 4 minor league teams like the Orcs of Hazards and Tokyo Terminators. MFL player cards also unlock historic players who can be signed in Free Agency; So, if you’d prefer to be a special snowflake, you can create an original team and craft a legacy of your own.</li><li><strong>Mutantmaxxing</strong> – Evolve your mutant baddies to unlock new armor sets, mutations, and weapons such as chainsaws, shotguns, and more. Hell, you can even use SkillRoid Boosts to give your players special abilities during a game. We ain’t natty out here.</li><li><strong>Dynasty Supreme</strong> – Become the ringleader of the freakshow in MFL2’s franchise mode. Start at the bottom of the league and claw to the top, turning pro by beating the competition across several seasons and winning Mayhem Bowls. Draft rookies every season and train them up to build a powerful roster.</li><li><strong>Doom Field Designer</strong> – Design your team’s arena, strategically placing lethal hazards and manipulating the weather—buzz saws to trim the competition, fire geysers to turn up the heat, or drop a blizzard on those fools. Make your stadium into the kind of place where only your team loves to play, and everyone else just prays to survive.</li><li><strong>The Voice of the MFL</strong> – Tim Kitzrow, the iconic voice of your favorite sports franchises—<em>NBA Jam</em>, <em>NFL Blitz</em>, <em>NHL Hitz</em>, and <em>MLB Slugfest</em>—commentates MFL 2, reciting plays and talking all kinds of smack. BOOMSHAKALAKA!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Mutant Football League 2 Launch Date Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u0TuUGt_GoM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/mutant-football-league-2-launches-december-10-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yakuza Kiwami 3 mention spotted on series official website]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/yakuza-kiwami-3-mention-spotted-on-series-official-website</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yakuza-kiwami-3-mention-spotted-on-series-official-website.1300287/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Reveal set for RGG Summit 2025?</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>The <a href="https://ryu-ga-gotoku.com/info/" target="_blank">official Japanese website</a> for the <em>Yakuza</em> / <em><a title="Series > Yakuza (Like a Dragon) [58 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/yakuza">Like a Dragon</a></em> series listed, then removed, a news category for the unannounced <em><a title="Games > Yakuza Kiwami [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/yakuza-kiwami">Yakuza Kiwami</a> 3</em> earlier today. <span id="more-993168"></span></p><p>Although the news category was removed, <a href="https://twitter.com/Renka_schedule/status/1968302714133311738" target="_blank">multiple</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Z64Gaming/status/1968275359000142163" target="_blank">users</a> spotted it before it disappeared, and a <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=%22%E9%BE%8D%E3%81%8C%E5%A6%82%E3%81%8F%E6%A5%B53%22+site%3Aryu-ga-gotoku.com" target="_blank">Google search</a> still features the category in its meta description.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Yakuza-3-Kiwami-Spotted_09-17-25_Meta.jpg"></a></figure><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > SEGA [2,694 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a> and <em>Yakuza</em> / <em>Like a Dragon</em> series developer <a title="Companies > Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio [504 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega/ryu-ga-gotoku-studio">Ryu Ga Gotoku Studio</a> will host <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/event/rgg-summit-2025">RGG Summit 2025</a> on September 23, where the studio is expected to reveal its latest titles.</p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/yakuza-kiwami-3-mention-spotted-on-series-official-website]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Canceled Xbox Game Perfect Dark Eulogized By Top Boss: "I Leave With Nothing But Pride"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/canceled-xbox-game-perfect-dark-eulogized-by-top-boss-i-leave-with-nothing-but-pride/1100-6534809/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/canceled-xbox-game-perfect-dark-eulogized-by-top-boss-i-leave-with-nothing-but-pride.1300281/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534809">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Microsoft recently cut thousands of jobs as part of its latest round of mass layoffs, and as part of the drawback, the company also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xboxs-aaaa-perfect-dark-reboot-canceled-developer-shutting-down/1100-6532921/" data-ref-id="1100-6532921">canceled the new Perfect Dark and closed its developer, The Initiative.</a></p><p>The studio's top boss, Darrell Gallagher, has now written a eulogy of sorts for Perfect Dark and The Initiative, while also confirming his own departure from Microsoft.</p><p>"After an incredible journey, my time at Xbox has come to a close with the wind-down of Perfect Dark and The Initiative. I couldn't be prouder of the talented and passionate team I had the privilege assemble and lead," Gallagher said on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7373350179040714752/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">LinkedIn</a>. "Together, we set out to reimagine an iconic franchise and poured creativity, craft, and dedication into every step of the way. The public reception and excitement for what we were building has been inspiring and deeply appreciated by all of us."</p><p>Gallagher said the "spirit, talent, and achievements" of the developers will live on "well beyond the project."</p><p>"I leave with nothing but pride in what we accomplished together and excitement for what's next--both for myself and for the amazing developers I was fortunate enough to work with. Here's to new adventures and to celebrating the journey we've shared," Gallagher said.</p><p>Gallagher has worked in the video game industry for decades, having spent time at Rockstar Games as a lead artist, then at THQ as studio art director. He later joined Crystal Dynamics and was the art director and later head of studio before being promoted to become head of product development and studios at Square Enix. He joined Activision in 2016 and was a senior vice president and head of development for various Call of Duty games. In 2018, he joined Xbox to establish The Initiative and kick off work on the reimagining of Perfect Dark.</p><p dir="ltr">A report from shortly before the debut of Perfect Dark's gameplay trailer stated the reboot of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/perfect-dark-reboot-is-allegedly-in-bad-shape/1100-6523261/" data-ref-id="1100-6523261">spy FPS was in bad shape</a> and that the project hadn't "really come together" despite co-developer Crystal Dynamics being brought in to help development. GTA parent company Take-Two apparently <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/perfect-dark-reboot-almost-got-a-second-chance-at-take-two-report/1100-6534419/" data-ref-id="1100-6534419">almost stepped in to save Perfect Dark</a>, but a deal didn't come together in the end.</p><p dir="ltr">Perfect Dark and The Initiative are just a few of the games and studios to be affected by the latest wave of layoffs at Microsoft. The Initiative was the only studio that was closed, but other studios like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/xbox-cancels-new-mmo-from-elder-scrolls-online-team-in-latest-wave-of-cuts-report/1100-6532915/" data-ref-id="1100-6532915">The Elder Scrolls Online developer ZeniMax Online</a>, Blizzard, Forza developer Turn 10, and even <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-7-forza-studios-impacted-by-xbox-layoffs/1100-6532918/" data-ref-id="1100-6532918">Call of Duty Black Ops 7 developer Raven Software also saw layoffs</a>. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/after-a-decade-rares-everwild-canceled-as-part-of-xbox-layoffs-report/1100-6532912/" data-ref-id="1100-6532912">Rare's Everwild</a> was also canceled.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/canceled-xbox-game-perfect-dark-eulogized-by-top-boss-i-leave-with-nothing-but-pride/1100-6534809/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Getting A Borderlands 4 Refund? Why Not Spend It On This Game, Dev Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/getting-a-borderlands-4-refund-why-not-spend-it-on-this-game-dev-says/1100-6534808/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/getting-a-borderlands-4-refund-why-not-spend-it-on-this-game-dev-says.1300278/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534808">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Borderlands 4 boss Randy Pitchford is encouraging people to request refunds if they aren't enjoying the newly launched game, and now one publisher known for being cheeky has weighed in and offered up an alternative.</p><p>Devolver Digital said anyone who gets a refund for Borderlands 4 can spend that money on one of its games, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3247750/Mycopunk/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Mycopunk</a>, which launched in July and costs $15. The game bears some stylistic resemblances to Borderlands 4, and, like that game, is also a co-op shooter set on an alien planet.</p><p>You can buy Mycopunk from GameSpot sister site Fanatical.</p><p>Devolver is known for capitalizing on wider games industry talking points to promote its own games. For example, the publisher has maintained that it will <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/devolver-re-commits-to-releasing-a-game-on-the-same-day-as-gta-6-after-delay/1100-6531291/" data-ref-id="1100-6531291">intentionally launch a game the same day as GTA 6</a>, something the company re-committed to after GTA 6 was delayed to May 2026.</p><p>For anyone just catching up, Pitchford has been posting non-stop since Borderlands 4 launched on September 12. He's involving himself in the discussion about Borderlands 4's PC version, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-boss-calls-people-4k-stubborn-disputes-reports-of-performance-issues/1100-6534746/" data-ref-id="1100-6534746">calling people "4K stubborn" and disputing reports of performance issues.</a> In <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/randy-pitchford-remains-defiant-about-borderlands-4-pc-issues/1100-6534798/" data-ref-id="1100-6534798">one highly publicized post</a>, Pitchford said, "Please get a refund from Steam if you aren't happy with it."</p><p>Exactly how many people are getting Borderlands 4 refunds is unknown. As of September 17, the game remains <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/topselling/US" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam's No. 1 best-selling game in the US.</a> It's also in the top 10 for most-played games on Steam right now, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/charts/mostplayed" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">exceeding 200,000 peak concurrent users today.</a></p><p>Borderlands 4 has a "mixed" aggregate rating on Steam. Developer Gearbox has sent out an alert about <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/psa-new-borderlands-4-bug-may-steal-all-your-skill-points/1100-6534784/" data-ref-id="1100-6534784">a bug that may erase all of your skill points</a>. Gearbox has also noted the PC performance problems <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/having-borderlands-4-pc-issues-or-crashes-gearbox-has-some-advice/1100-6534674/">and offered several suggestions for players</a> to manage them. But if you're already knee deep in the game and looking for help, check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/borderlands-4-guides-hub/1100-6534629/" data-ref-id="1100-6534629">Borderlands 4 guides hub</a> for several helpful features, tips, and tricks.</p><p>Borderlands 4 is out now for Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC. The Switch 2 port will be released on October 3.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/getting-a-borderlands-4-refund-why-not-spend-it-on-this-game-dev-says/1100-6534808/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twilight Imperium Digital Brings the Legendary Tabletop Game to PC]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/twilight-imperium-digital-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/twilight-imperium-digital-brings-the-legendary-tabletop-game-to-pc.1300266/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Red Square Games and Asmodee have announced&nbsp;<em>Twilight Imperium Digital</em>, and it is, as you've probably already guessed, a Steam version of the popular (if extremely weighty) tabletop game.</p>

<p>In an <a href="https://x.com/RedSquare_Games/status/1967984321970540682" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">announcement post</a> on social media, Red Square says the digital version of&nbsp;<em>Twilight Imperium&nbsp;</em>has been made "with love by fans at Red Square Games and Asmodee", and that the game is for both "the old guard" and "the new heirs".</p>

<p>The game's Steam page describes it as an adaptation of what the two studios call a "legendary board game of galactic conquest" which has been "reimagined for digital play", so there should be a few concessions to make it a little more streamlined on Steam (steamlined?).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/twilight-imperium-digital-board.jpg?itok=FWy1wyn4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/twilight-imperium-digital-board.jpg?itok=K9xAsUQn 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Twilight Imperium Digital&nbsp;</em>adapts the legendary strategy game for Steam "soon".</figcaption></figure><p>If you're familiar with&nbsp;<em>Twilight Imperium</em>, you'll probably know how this one's going to play out. Expect a vast game of diplomacy, combat, and exploration in which you'll need to decide whether to trade peacefully with your other players or dominate them with military might.</p>

<p><em>Twilight Imperium Digital&nbsp;</em>will offer 17 unique factions, each of which boasts "asymmetric powers and playstyles", and it also promises "massive replayability" thanks to its randomized galaxies and objectives.</p>

<p>If you can't convince anybody else to play this one with you, there's a solo mode in which you can take on a computer opponent, but naturally,&nbsp;<em>Twilight Imperium Digital&nbsp;</em>will thrive best in multiplayer. The game also supports hotseat and asynchronous play so you can enjoy it "at your own pace".</p>

<p>You can check out the announcement trailer for&nbsp;<em>Twilight Imperium Digital</em>, which should give you a decent sense of how the game will play out in comparison to the tabletop experience, right here.</p>




<p><em>Twilight Imperium Digital&nbsp;</em>doesn't have a release date yet, but you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3669430/Twilight_Imperium_Digital/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">wishlist it on Steam right here</a>. Hey, who knows? Maybe this will lead to a digital version of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/twilight-imperium-spinoff-twilight-inscription-announced" rel="nofollow">spinoff&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/twilight-imperium-spinoff-twilight-inscription-announced" rel="nofollow">Twilight Inscription</a>&nbsp;</em>somewhere down the line.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/twilight-imperium-digital-announced]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony’s PS5 update adds controller swapping and Power Saving mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/779837/sony-playstation-5-ps5-update-power-saving-mode</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony%E2%80%99s-ps5-update-adds-controller-swapping-and-power-saving-mode.1300263/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6OTU="><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jess Weatherbed</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a news writer focused on creative industries, computing, and internet culture. Jess started her career at TechRadar, covering news and hardware reviews.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>PS5 users can now run select games in “Power Saving” mode and pair DualSense controllers with multiple devices. Sony started beta <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/712212/sony-ps5-power-saver-handheld-rumors">testing these features in July</a>, but they’re now rolling out to everyone today in the <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/support/hardware/ps5/system-software-info/">version 25.06-12.00.00</a> console software update.</p><p>The new Power Saver mode will reduce the power consumption of PS5 consoles in exchange for scaling back game performance, according to Sony’s PS5 update notes, which could come in handy for the company’s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/25/24305337/sony-handheld-gaming-console-playstation-nintendo-microsoft">rumored PlayStation handheld</a>. Power Saving mode can be toggled on or off for supported games by heading into Settings &gt; System &gt; Power Saving &gt; Use Power Saver. When enabled, an icon will appear next to the supported game in Switcher or the control center, according to Sony.</p><p>The software for DualSense and DualSense Edge wireless controllers has also been updated to make it easier to switch them across connected devices. Controllers can now be paired with up to four devices simultaneously, preventing users from having to go through the cumbersome process of manually reconnecting the controller when switching between consoles, PCs, and cloud streaming devices.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/779837/sony-playstation-5-ps5-update-power-saving-mode#comments"><span>0<!-- --> <!-- -->Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6OTU="><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jess Weatherbed</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/779837/sony-playstation-5-ps5-update-power-saving-mode]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Assassin’s Creed Black Flag remake will release early 2026 and swaps modern-day sections for more piracy, claims report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-will-release-early-2026-and-swaps-modern-day-sections-for-more-piracy-claims-report</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-black-flag-remake-will-release-early-2026-and-swaps-modern-day-sections-for-more-piracy-claims-report.1300260/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Also rumoured: RPG-style mechanics similar to Valhalla and Shadows</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-seemingly-teased-voice-actor-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-seemingly-teased-voice-actor-01.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-seemingly-teased-voice-actor-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-seemingly-teased-voice-actor-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-seemingly-teased-voice-actor-01.jpg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Ubisoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Yaaarrr. There be a fresh report about the long-rumoured <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/assassins-creed-iv-black-flag">Assassin's Creed: Black Flag</a> remake Ubisoft have still yet to publicly acknowledge. It claims the publisher are currently looking to release the retooled piracy game in early 2026, as well as providing more alleged details as to how the remake'll differ from the original.</p>
<p>This Black Flag remake's been <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ubisoft-might-be-remaking-their-swashbuckling-pirateventure-assassins-creed-iv-black-flag">reported to be in development</a> several times over the past couple of years, with the voice actor of original protagonist Edward Kenway <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-4-black-flag-voice-actor-claims-ubisoft-threatened-to-sue-him-over-remake-tease">alleging that he got in trouble</a> for <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rumoured-assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-seemingly-teased-by-actor-whos-pretty-chill-about-loose-lips-sinking-ships">being recorded teasing it at a convention</a> earlier this year.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="EXCLUSIF Assassin's Creed 4 Black Flag Remake : Nos 1ères INFORMATIONS INÉDITES sur le jeu 🔥" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qngrBQnukFc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>EXCLUSIF Assassin's Creed 4 Black Flag Remake : Nos 1ères INFORMATIONS INÉDITES sur le jeu 🔥</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qngrBQnukFc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qngrBQnukFc?autoplay=1" title="EXCLUSIF Assassin's Creed 4 Black Flag Remake : Nos 1ères INFORMATIONS INÉDITES sur le jeu 🔥">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qngrBQnukFc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>Enter this video report from French publication Jeux Vidéo Magazine. They cite sources as having told them that Ubisoft are currently aiming to release the remake early next year, with March being the month it's most likely to make port. That said, Jeux Vidéo Magazine also cite some sources as having cast doubt over that and indicated it could be pushed towards the end of 2026, due to there allegedly being a lot of work left to do at this point.</p><p>The report also details a number of tweaks that developers Ubisoft Singapore, along with support studios Ubisoft Bordeaux and Ubisoft Belgrade are supposedly making to the original, mostly to bring Black Flag in line with the series' more recent entries. Parts of the present-day sections that saw you coming out of the Animus and wandering around the office of Abstergo Entertainment are reportedly being swapped out for more adventures set in the past, with cut content involving pirate Mary Read making up part of that.</p>
<p>It wouldn't be too big a surprise, given the series has moved away from hefty present day elements of late, having adjusted to life without early protagonist Desmond Mason spearheading the non-past assassin/templar bickering. This year's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/assassins-creed-codename-red">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a> features very little to take you out of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/assassins-creed-shadows-review">murdering your way through feudal Japan</a>, unless you're prepared to muck about in the Animus Hub menus or spend too long staring at a warning about fragmented memories.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Jeux Vidéo Magazine report that the inventory and combat systems have been overhauled in a more RPG-style fashion that'll bring them closer to the likes of Shadows and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/assassins-creed-valhalla">Valhalla</a>. Tech-wise, we can apparently expect improvements like load-screenless sailing, smaller islands being less barren, and the use of Shadows' engine making things look a bit less dated.</p>
<p>We reached out to Ubisoft for comment, and the publishers responded that they "haven’t got anything to share" right now.</p>
<p>My feelings are a bit mixed at the moment as to whether this Black Flag remaster'll have much to offer over just firing up the original again for some very good piracy and assassining that's also there. Then again, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remake">Oblivion Remastered</a>, a revamp which left me quite on the fence about its deliberately minimal tweakage outside of the obvious facelift, proved plenty popular earlier this year.</p>

        </div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-assassins-creed-black-flag-remake-will-release-early-2026-and-swaps-modern-day-sections-for-more-piracy-claims-report]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Seems to Be Clearing Out the 2025 M4 MacBook Air at an All-Time Low Before Amazon Prime Big Deal Days]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-seems-to-be-clearing-out-the-2025-m4-macbook-air-at-an-all-time-low-before-amazon-prime-big-deal-days-2000626103</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apple-seems-to-be-clearing-out-the-2025-m4-macbook-air-at-an-all-time-low-before-amazon-prime-big-deal-days.1300254/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Greater minds than ours have been driven crazy trying to predict what’s coming out of Cupertino, and when it’s coming. Now that Apple’s gotten the iPhone 17 and new AirPods drops out of the way, will there be new MacBooks on the horizon? One set of tea leaves to keep an eye on is the deals they’re offering on their current models, and right now seemingly out of nowhere, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3761/">the 13-inch 2025 M4 MacBook Air is just $800 at Amazon — its lowest price ever.</a></p>
<p>Does that mean there’s a new MacBook Air right around the corner? Who knows — early 2026 is a better bet. But this $800 deal on the current flagship of the MacBook Air fleet is very real, and we can’t imagine it going much lower if at all when the 2025 holiday rush starts.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3761/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>M4 For the Win</h2>
<p>One day there will be an M5 chip driving a new line of MacBooks, but until then, you cannot beat the M4 for speed and sheer processing power. This M4 MacBook Air runs twice as fast as the M1 models that were all the rage more recently than we realize, and a staggering 23 times faster than the last Intel powered models of the MacBook Air.</p>
<p>Of course, the one consistent calling card of any MacBook is the display, and this MacBook Air’s 13.6-inch Liquid Retina screen supports a billion colors, all delivered with brilliance and sharpness. Pair that screen with the 12MP Center Stage camera, three microphones, and four Spatial Audio speakers built into the MacBook Air, and your video calls will always be peak. The M4 processor, Spatial Audio speakers, and Wi-Fi 6E and Bluetooth 5.3 connections make the 2025 MacBook Air a streaming and gaming superstar.</p>



<h2>Apple-Style AI</h2>
<p>The 2025 M4 MacBook Air comes with Apple Intelligence built in, with incredible speed and ability as an assistant for research, productivity, or pretty much anything else you want it to do for you. All those searches are yours and yours alone too, because Apple Intelligence has some of the best and most robust privacy features of any AI system — so private that even Apple can’t get to your search history.</p>
<p>Trying to read the smoke signals from Apple about how and when to jump on&nbsp;<em>the</em> best deal is, honestly, often a waste of time. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3761/">What we can tell you is that this $800 deal on the 13-inch 2025 M4 MacBook Air is the lowest price ever for this laptop at Amazon</a>, and that the M4 MacBook Air is worth every penny of the price regardless of when the next-gen MacBooks drop.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3761/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-seems-to-be-clearing-out-the-2025-m4-macbook-air-at-an-all-time-low-before-amazon-prime-big-deal-days-2000626103]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blood of Mehran launches October 7]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/blood-of-mehran-launches-october-7</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/blood-of-mehran-launches-october-7.1300248/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Join Mehran on his quest for vengeance.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Action [3,043 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,560 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Blood of Mehran" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/blood-of-mehran">Blood of Mehran</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [10,383 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,915 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [24,263 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1714530/Blood_of_Mehran/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/blood-of-mehran-0f68d3" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> on October 7, publisher <a title="Companies > Blowfish Studios [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/blowfish-studios">Blowfish Studios</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Permanent Way [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/permanent-way">Permanent Way</a> announced. <span id="more-993156"></span></p><p>“<em>Blood of Mehran</em> offers an immersive journey inspired by Persian fantasy tales and the mystique of One Thousand and One Nights,” said Permanent  CEO and game director Emad Rahmani in a press release. “We’ve woven a fast-paced, action-packed adventure and we look forward to sharing just how far Mehran will go to claim his vengeance.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Blowfish Studios:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Blood of Mehran</em> tells a story of love, loss and loyalty, drawn from “Arabian Nights” folk tales.</p><p>The legendary warrior Mehran sets down his sword in search of peace – but his restful existence is set ablaze by the cruel ambitions of others, leaving him no choice but to take up his blade once more.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Hack and slash your way through enemies, choosing from a variety of weapon combinations:</p><ul><li>Sword and shield.</li><li>Double swords.</li><li>Bow and arrow.</li></ul><p>Or slip by like a ghost with intuitive <a title="Genres > Stealth [97 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a> and cover mechanics.</p><p>Explore a realistic recreation of <a title="Companies > Ancient [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ancient">Ancient</a> Mesopotamia. Gallop across rolling sand dunes and through city streets. Scour the world for collectibles and secrets. Level up and ascend through the skill tree, extending the legendary prowess of your hero.</p><ul><li>Rewarding hack and slash combat system.</li><li>Experiment with stealth, ranged and mounted options.</li><li>Explore a world filled with wonders and collectibles.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch anew trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Blood of Mehran | Release Date Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iPTk65s7SWI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/blood-of-mehran-launches-october-7]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest Smash/Grow launches in 2026, closed beta test set for October 14 to 21]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/dragon-quest-smash-grow-launches-in-2026-closed-beta-test-set-for-october-14-to-21</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-smash-grow-launches-in-2026-closed-beta-test-set-for-october-14-to-21.1300245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Registration available now.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > Dragon Quest Smash/Grow [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-quest-smash-grow">Dragon Quest Smash/Grow</a></em>, the newly announced mobile game in the <em><a title="Series > Dragon Quest [107 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/dragon-quest">Dragon Quest</a></em> series, will launch for iOS and Android in 2026 worldwide, <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,382 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> announced. A closed beta test will run from October 14 to 21, with pre-registration available now via the <a href="http://smashgrow.dragonquest.com/en/cbt/" target="_blank">official website</a>. <span id="more-993033"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via</p><blockquote><p><strong>About the Game</strong></p><p><em>Dragon Quest Smash/Grow</em> is an intuitive and exhilarating <a title="Genres > Roguelite [287 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">roguelite</a> <a title="Genres > RPG [17,622 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> where players smash their way through hordes of monsters to gain strength and then finish them off with <em>Dragon Quest</em>‘s signature Coup de Grace attacks. Players can choose between random Blessings skills to enhance their character growth and battle strategy, allowing them to match an ever-changing tactical situation. No quest is ever the same in this unique <em>Dragon Quest</em> experience.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Dragon-Quest-Smash-Grow_09-17-25_002.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Dragon-Quest-Smash-Grow_09-17-25_003.jpg"></a></figure><!-- AD: content -->
        <figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Dragon-Quest-Smash-Grow_09-17-25_004.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Closed Beta Test</strong></p><p><em>Dragon Quest Smash/Grow</em> will be running a closed beta test from Tuesday, October 14 (UTC) until Tuesday, October 21 (UTC). Pre-registration for the closed beta test is now available on iOS via TestFlight and on Android via Google Play until Thursday, October 2 (UTC). Apply now <a href="http://smashgrow.dragonquest.com/en/cbt/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Dragon-Quest-Smash-Grow_09-17-25_005.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Giveaway</strong></p><p>From September 19 (UTC) until September 26 (UTC), the game is running a special giveaway campaign on its Twitter and Facebook pages. To apply, players must follow the <a href="https://twitter.com/DQSG_EN" target="_blank">official Twitter account</a> and repost the giveaway campaign post. For Facebook, like the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/DragonQuestSmashGrow" target="_blank">official Facebook page</a> and leave a comment. Prizes include a <em>Dragon Quest</em> <a title="Platforms > Meta [155 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta">Meta</a>llic Monsters Gallery (Erdrick Sword &amp; Shield) for one winner, a <em>Dragon Quest</em> Pixelight (Slime) for one winner and a <em>Dragon Quest</em> Smile Slime Plush (Medium Slime) for two winners.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Dragon-Quest-Smash-Grow_09-17-25_006.jpg"></a></figure></blockquote><p>Watch the teaser trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Teaser Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Dragon Quest Smash/Grow - Announce Teaser Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oipMRCDiA10?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『ドラゴンクエストスマッシュグロウ』ティザーPV" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cSGARTAoddA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/dragon-quest-smash-grow-launches-in-2026-closed-beta-test-set-for-october-14-to-21]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest Smash/Grow Lets You Smash Enemies To Grow Your Character]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-quest-smash-grow-lets-you-smash-enemies-to-grow-your-character/1100-6534805/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-smash-grow-lets-you-smash-enemies-to-grow-your-character.1300242/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534805">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">During last week's Nintendo Direct, Square Enix surprised Dragon Quest fans with <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-quest-7-remake-announced-after-months-of-speculation/1100-6534696/">Dragon Quest VII Reimagined</a>, a remake of the classic PlayStation RPG from the year 2000. It seems Square Enix was not done with the surprise Dragon Quest reveals, as today the company announced Dragon Quest Smash/Grow, a roguelite RPG for mobile devices that will enter a closed beta test next month.</p><p dir="ltr">Dragon Quest Smash/Grow tasks players with fighting hordes of enemies at once, "smashing" through their ranks in order to "grow" their characters with experience and loot. Once powerful enough, players can then unleash powerful Coup de Grace attacks in order to finish the enemy armies off.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6U3mPefOfho" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6U3mPefOfho" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">The roguelite mechanic in Dragon Quest Smash/Grow is called Blessings, which are chosen from randomly generated options throughout the course of a run. Each run will depend on the Blessings made available to a player throughout the adventure; as is typical with roguelite games, no two runs will feel exactly alike.</p><p dir="ltr">Dragon Quest Smash/Grow will be available for both iOS and Android devices. A closed beta test for Dragon Quest Smash/Grow has been announced for October 14-21. Players can pre-regiser for the beta test on iOS using TestFlight, Android via the Google Play Store, and at the <a href="https://smashgrow.dragonquest.com/en/cbt" rel="nofollow ">game's official website</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Square Enix has been busy with reveals over the past few months across many of its RPG franchises. Along with Dragon Quest VII Reimagined and Smash/Grow, Final Fantasy VII Remake Intergrade was confirmed for a January 22 release on Nintendo Switch 2, while Octopath Traveler 0 and The Adventures of Elliot: The Millennium Tales were both announced over the summer.</p><div data-embed-type="html"><p><i>Click the button below to add GameSpot as a preferred source on Google</i></p></div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-quest-smash-grow-lets-you-smash-enemies-to-grow-your-character/1100-6534805/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report Finds Nearly All Gamers Have Played A Remaster Or Remake In Last Year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/report-finds-nearly-all-gamers-have-played-a-remaster-or-remake-in-last-year/1100-6534807/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-finds-nearly-all-gamers-have-played-a-remaster-or-remake-in-last-year.1300239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534807">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>If you've played any PC or console games over the last 12 months, there's a good chance that at least one of them was a remake or a remaster. That's according to new research, which found that not only have these games been popular with the people they polled for this research, they've also been "desirable" diversions.</p><p>Specialist strategy and insights consultancy firm MTM (<a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/90-of-gamers-have-played-a-remake-or-remaster-finds-new-report" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">via GamesIndustry.Biz</a>) polled 1,500 people--750 people each in the US and the UK--who play games regularly. "Our report shows that there is a strong appeal for remakes and remasters, but it's a tight balancing act for studios to get right," said Martin Bradley, head of gaming at MTM. "Many of these games are far out-selling their original release."</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1988585869" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466270,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Metal%20Gear%20Solid%20Delta%3A%20Snake%20Eater%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:817,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-review\/2300-6466270\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466270\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466270\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466270\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466270&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466270,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6534807&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,playstation-5,playstation-4,xbox-series-x,xbox-one,nintendo-switch-2,nintendo-switch&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466270},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466270\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4553381-review_mgsdeltasnakeeater_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/id5frSUr.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1755846060,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="id5frSUr" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater Review</p>
      </div>
<p>MTM also revealed that 85% of the people who played a remaster or remake in the last year had not even played the original version of the game, so this wasn't entirely a case of nostalgia guiding their choices. That being said, MTM added that nostalgia is still a powerful influence, even when gamers understand that they might be missing out on fresher and novel gameplay experiences by choosing reimagined games over newer titles.</p><p>It hasn't been difficult to find a remastered game either, as publishers have focused their efforts on reviving classic games in addition to new projects. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/elder-scrolls-iv-oblivion-remastered-review/1900-6418359/">The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion Remastered</a>--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/2025-best-selling-games/2900-6281/">one of the best-selling games of the year so far</a>--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-review-youre-pretty-good/1900-6418396/">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a>, Tony Hawk's Pro Skater 3 + 4, and the House of the Dead 2: Remake were all released this year, and looking ahead, remakes of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/persona-4-remake-sounds-like-its-still-a-long-ways-away/1100-6532621/">Persona 4</a>, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/prince-of-persia-the-sands-of-time-remake-delayed-indefinitely/1100-6487180/">Prince of Persia: The Sands of Time</a>, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-celebrates-splinter-cell-20th-anniversary-shares-remake-concept-art/1100-6509255/">Splinter Cell</a> are also on the way.</p><p>Nintendo has also been keenly aware of the value of its older games for years now, and while it has produced several remakes and remasters, it's even going a step further this year by remaking its flop Virtual Boy console--sort of.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-online-expansion-pass-is-adding-nintendos-biggest-flop-virtual-boy/1100-6534695/">Virtual Boy functionality is coming</a> February 17, 2026, to Nintendo Switch Online + Expansion Pass, and to play these games, you'll need a new accessory modeled after the original console that you can slot your Switch or Switch 2 device into.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/report-finds-nearly-all-gamers-have-played-a-remaster-or-remake-in-last-year/1100-6534807/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here are the four games leaving PS Plus next month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/here-are-the-four-games-leaving-ps-plus-next-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here-are-the-four-games-leaving-ps-plus-next-month.1300236/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Battlefield! Ghostbusters!</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-1-psplus.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-1-psplus.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-1-psplus.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-1-psplus.png?width=570&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 570px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/battlefield-1-psplus.png?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>EA / Sony / Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
    <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Four more games will be leaving PS Plus next month, as part of the subscription service's latest catalogue refresh.
</p>
<p>
From 21st October, the following games will no longer be available to subscribers:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Battlefield 1 (PS4)</li>
<li>Ghostbusters: Spirits Unleashed (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>Tour de France 2023 (PS4, PS5)</li>
<li>The Last Clockwinder (PSVR2)</li>
</ul>

<p>
The loss of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/battlefield-1">Battlefield 1</a> will mostly be redeemed by the release of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/battlefield-2025">Battlefield 6</a> on 10th October. Today, we reported <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/battlefield-6-players-on-ps5-and-xbox-can-block-pc-users-from-crossplay-as-studio-takes-cheating-extremely-seriously">console only cross-play has been confirmed</a>. Battlefield 1 is also getting on for nine years old, and if you really want to play it can be bought cheaply.
</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/ghostbusters-spirits-unleashed">Ghostbusters: Spirits Unleashed</a>, an asymmetrical multiplayer game that essentially simulates what it would be like to be a Ghostbuster, didn't review that well on release but has gone on to carry plenty of positive sentiment amongst players.</p>
<p>
However, the loss of a PSVR2 game in The Last Clockwinder is another small blow for Sony's ailing VR device.
</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Sony / Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
Last week Sony announced the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/here-are-our-ps-plus-extra-and-premium-games-for-september">games joining the PS Plus catalogue for Extra and Premium subscribers this September</a>, including Legacy of Kain: <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/defiance">Defiance</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/persona-5-tactica">Persona 5 Tactica</a>, and Crow Country.
</p>
<p>
For more, check out our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-plus-games-list-premium-extra-this-month-6300">guide on all the games available on PS Plus</a>.
</p>



        </div>


      </article>



  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/here-are-the-four-games-leaving-ps-plus-next-month]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>