<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:30:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Biggest Reason To Buy The Xbox Ally Handheld Just Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-rog-ally-x-windows-handheld-app-leak-2000626934</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-biggest-reason-to-buy-the-xbox-ally-handheld-just-leaked.1302099/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Windows may prove a perfectly suitable platform for gaming on a traditional PC, but on handheld devices like the ROG Ally, Legion Go, or even the Steam Deck, it’s another story. Microsoft’s operating system is often too clunky and frustrating when you’re restricted to a gamepad for input. The upcoming Xbox-branded Ally from Asus, however, has promised a solution with a dedicated, controller-friendly user interface for running PC games on the go. These devices have yet to hit shelves, but a downloadable preview of a new version of Windows 11 is giving folks access to the new interface on just about any Windows handheld device.</p> <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/valve-microsoft-steam-deck-steamos-xbox-pc-handhelds-1851735440">Steam Ate Microsoft’s Lunch On PC, It’s About To Do The Same On Handhelds</a></p> <p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/780388/microsoft-xbox-fullscreen-mode-windows-11-handheld-leak">As noted by <i>The Verge</i></a>, The upcoming 25H2 update for Windows 11 lets you launch the new gaming-focused, fullscreen Xbox app for Windows with just a few tweaks to the registry and the help of a third-party tool (<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ROGAlly/comments/1niwsfi/guide_for_enabling_the_full_screen_experience_on/">a Reddit post by user Gogsi123</a> outlines the whole process). Unlike the overlay that software companies like Asus provide for their Windows handhelds, this new Xbox app skips the entire Windows desktop environment in favor of a fullscreen, controller-friendly experience. And people are finding, by way of the preview workaround, that it seems to lead to marginal performance gains as well.</p>

 <p><b>Read More:</b> <a href="https://kotaku.com/rog-xbox-ally-price-pc-gaming-handheld-asus-pre-order-2000622751">The Xbox Ally PC Gaming Handheld Feels Great, But At What Price?</a></p> <p>While this version of the fullscreen Xbox app requires some legwork to get working, its availability across Windows handhelds undercuts one of the main appeals of the <a href="https://kotaku.com/rog-xbox-ally-price-pc-gaming-handheld-asus-pre-order-2000622751">upcoming ROG Xbox Ally and Xbox Ally X</a>–which is <a href="https://kotaku.com/asus-ally-x-review-steam-deck-sd-card-battery-windows-1851600340">distinctly different from Asus’ ROG Ally X</a>–which is expected to arrive on October 16, 2025.</p> <h2>The ROG Xbox Ally X is less than a month away, and we’re still not sure of pricing</h2> <p>Though the best graphical experiences are still had on well-kitted PCs and cutting-edge consoles, we are in the midst of a handheld arms race kicked off by Valve three years ago when it launched the Steam Deck. Since then, other PC manufacturers have jumped in with Windows-based options. More recently, <a href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-outlaws-switch-2-port-patch-is-it-good-2000624465">the power of the Switch 2</a> has made it something of a competitor in this space as well.</p>

 <p>It’s all the stranger, then, that we’re not actually sure exactly how much Microsoft and Asus’ collaboration is going to cost. According to a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-rog-ally-retailer-leak-suggests-surprising-price-point">report from former <i>IGN</i> writer Destin Legarie</a>, a local Best Buy indicated that a $549 version and an $899 one would be available when he called to ask about it. If this is accurate, that puts the lower-tier version of the Xbox Ally at the same price as the smaller-capacity Steam Deck OLED, and within competitive pricing range of the current ROG Ally and Ally X, which retail for about $649 and $899, respectively.</p>  <p>Having enjoyed my time with the ROG Ally X, I can definitely attest to the value of having more games available on a handheld that’s running Windows instead of Valve’s Linux-based SteamOS, though I typically prefer the form factor and controller-focused interface of the Steam Deck. Now, if a few tweaks to the Windows registry can also give people that experience on a non-Xbox Ally X, I imagine it’ll be harder to find a use case for the Xbox Ally for those who already own a handheld gaming device and aren’t afraid to tinker with their machines.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/xbox-rog-ally-x-windows-handheld-app-leak-2000626934]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hey James Gunn: Is Peacemaker Season 2 About A Nazi Alternate Universe?]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/peacemaker-alternate-universe-nazi-gi-robot-james-gunn</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/hey-james-gunn-is-peacemaker-season-2-about-a-nazi-alternate-universe.1302093/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If there’s one thing that we can all say for sure about director James Gunn’s political beliefs, it’s that he hates Nazis. I wasn’t sure how he was going to incorporate that into the second season of <em>Peacemaker</em>, but viewers are pretty sure he’s found a way.</p><p>As someone who has a very high tolerance for James Gunn’s whole thing—<a href="https://www.troma.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Troma Entertainment</a> levels of gore, dumb dirty jokes, extremely chatty characters, endlessly rehashing complicated feelings about your dad—I’ve come to understand that his politics are pretty simple. He doesn’t like that <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HETgzbkvwuw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Louis CK&nbsp; jerked off in front of a lot of women</a>, he <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kebqC4vxxdY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">loves animals</a>, and he <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WYYvhiNLZ-8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fucking <em>hates</em> Nazis</a>. In <em>Creature Commandos</em>, a cartoon he wrote after being given the keys to the DC cinematic universe, he dedicated an entire episode to the origins of GI Robot, a robot who was designed with the sole directive of killing Nazis. And kill Nazis he does!</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="GI Robot’s Fate (Coin-Operated Boy) | Creature Commandos" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xEZAMa5MqLI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>How does this connect to <em>Peacemaker</em>? Peacemaker, played by John Cena, keeps trying to <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/peacemaker-was-a-comic-book-show-in-all-the-right-ways/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">make amends for the kind of man he was raised to be</a>. His dad was a white nationalist—and Peacemaker killed him at the end of the last season. However, at the start of this season, Peacemaker found a portal to a seemingly perfect universe where his dad and also his deceased brother Jason are still alive, and the three of them are heralded as heroes. In this universe, Peacemaker might be able to get together with a version of Amelia Harcourt, who wants nothing to do with him in his original universe despite their intense sexual tension and mutual affection for each other. Peacemaker repeatedly calls this universe the “best universe ever,” and so far, it seems like it is—were it not for one detail.</p><p>Any universe where Peacemaker’s dad, an open white supremacist, is heralded as a hero is probably one I, and plenty of other people, would not be welcome in. More than that, I was struck by the way Peacemaker’s brother pronounced the name of the city “Blüdhaven.” Most of the time, characters in the DC Universe pronounce this city’s name as “Bloodhaven,” hilariously. But Jason pronounced “Bluthaven,” which is closer to how it would be pronounced in German, and, well….</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="That's what a nazi would say meme GI Robot" width="710" height="533" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C3dFP6s9txQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Most telling for me, though, is the absolute lack of people of color. It’s actually chilling once you start to notice it. As Peacemaker ventures out into this alternate universe, I was not able to spot a single Black, Latino, or Asian person, nor any other race other than white. In fact, there doesn’t appear to be any <em>extras</em> who are people of color, something corroborated by an extra who posted to the show’s subreddit.</p><p>“Everyone I remember seeing was at least white-presenting,” a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PeacemakerShow/comments/1ncrj9r/i_was_a_background_actor_in_peacemaker_s2e3_ama/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">background actor wrote</a> on Reddit.&nbsp; “I think the Nazi/white supremacist dimension theories have credibility.”</p><p>There are some other little tells that something is at least off with this universe. Jason doesn’t know who the Kardashians are—perhaps because OJ Simpson never existed, meaning that Robert Kardashian would never have been catapulted to national recognition for representing Simpson at his murder trial. Amelia Harcourt also appears to not know what the phrase “what’s happening?” is a reference to. <em>What’s Happening!! </em>was a sitcom about a Black family from the 1970s, and <a href="https://www.today.com/popculture/what-s-happening-star-ernest-thomas-show-s-impact-race-t215884" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a landmark in terms of depicting Black families</a> on television. Weirdest of all, the show goes out of its way to <em>not</em> show the audience a hot dog vendor. Like, it feels bizarre to watch the lengths that the show goes to in order to shoot around this hot dog vendor’s body. Is it because many people who own and operate food trucks in real life and in filmed media are often not white? Who’s to say, but it’s <em>fucking strange</em>.</p><figure><figcaption><a href="https://press.wbd.com/us/image/pm220509042024jm6080" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Photograph by Jessica Miglio/HBO Max </a></figcaption></figure><p>This is all the more notable because the rest of <em>Peacemaker</em> is almost self consciously racially diverse. Peacemaker’s best friend is Leota Adebayo, a Black lesbian played by the hilarious Danielle Brooks. This season has added two more characters of color in ARGUS agents Langston Fleury (Tim Minear) and Sasha Bordeaux (Sol Rodriguez), who also team up with last season’s Judomaster, a Vietnamese character played by Nhut Le. The universe that Peacemaker comes from has its characters of color front and center, impossible to ignore, which makes their absence feel even more conspicuous in the alternate universe.</p><p>Of course, having something be subtly wrong with an alternate universe that appears perfect is just sensible writing for the journey that Peacemaker has gone on in these two seasons of television. Peacemaker has already rejected his father’s teachings once, but he’s still looking for the easy way out in terms of making amends for the harm he has caused. It would be <em>easy</em> to escape to this seemingly perfect universe—but if fan theories are correct, it would mean rejecting the humanity of Leota Adebayo, who has stood by his side and always believed in him, even when he was at his lowest. In Peacemaker’s quest to be a better man, can he reject a world where his happiness would come at the expense of people like Adebayo? It’s a test of character that would demonstrate how far Peacemaker has come from his first appearance in <em>The Suicide Squad</em>, where he declared “I cherish peace with all of my heart. I don't care how many men, women and children I kill to get it.”</p><p><em>Peacemaker</em> fans will learn if their suspicions about this alternate universe are correct tonight, as Adebayo is poised to go there for the first time—we’re all going to find out if this is a white supremacist universe pretty fucking quick. As for me, I’m hoping Gunn can squeeze in another appearance from GI Robot.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/arma-trans-platoon"><h3>Arma Can Be A Boys Club, But This Trans Women-Only Platoon Aims To Change That</h3></a><p>'It’s a community that is made for the trans community... I’ll never find another place that I feel more safe.'</p></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/peacemaker-alternate-universe-nazi-gi-robot-james-gunn]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Critical Role Campaign 4 Trailer Introduces Us to the Land of Araman]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-campaign-4-trailer-introduces-us-to-land-of-araman</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/critical-role-campaign-4-trailer-introduces-us-to-the-land-of-araman.1302063/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The trailer for <em>Critical Role</em> Campaign 4 has arrived. The newest campaign by the acclaimed actual play series will introduce a new expansive cast of characters, a different face behind the GM screen, and a brand new fantasy setting. All of this and more are teased in this trailer.</p>



<p>The official <em>Critical Role</em> Campaign 4 trailer is light on artwork, but heavy on atmosphere. It is carried with voice-over by GM Brennan Lee Mulligan, dropping events and proper names like the Falconer's Rebellion, the Sundered Houses, and the Revolutionary Council, and stating that the players' grandparents have defied the gods.</p>


<p>This worldbuilding is crucial since the major selling point of Campaign 4 is that it is not set in Matt Mercer's world of Exandria. Instead, it is set in the world of Araman, a world that has recently seen the death of their gods. Because of this, the trailer is helping set the world of Araman apart from the land that hosted the heroics of <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/legend-of-vox-machina-season-3-review-darker-season-of-dd-twists" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Vox Machina</a> and the <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-announces-mighty-nein-release-date-first-image-of-yasha" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Mighty Nein</a>.</p>

<p>When paired with the video description, the <em>Critical Role</em> Campaign 4 trailer seems to confirm where this story will begin. The party is brought together to uncover the truth of the fate of hero Thjazi Fang, who has been marked for execution. To this end, they will journey across the fractured world and connect in ways never imagined.</p>

<p>This campaign is one packed with firsts for the actual play series. This is the first long-form campaign not GM'd by <a data-entity-substitution="canonical" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a9a9913f-42e9-4189-bbde-08061c01a7e8" href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/features/matthew-mercer-interview" rel="nofollow">Matt Mercer</a>; instead, it will be helmed by Dimension20's own Brennan Lee Mulligan. In addition, the campaign will be done West Marches-style, spanning three tables of characters set in different locations across the vast fantasy setting of Araman.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/critical-role-campaign-4-character-art.jpg?itok=MpFPbcbN 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/critical-role-campaign-4-character-art.jpg?itok=Mh0Qqtu9 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Alongside the Critical Role Campaign 4 trailer, the official <a href="https://critrole.com/campaign4/" rel="nofollow"><em>Critical Role</em> website</a> posted official art of the characters featured in this new adventure.&nbsp;The cast featured is as follows:</p>

<ul><li>Laura Bailey as Thimble</li>
	<li>Luis Carazo as Azune Nayar</li>
	<li>Robbie Daymond as Kattigan Vale</li>
	<li>Aabria Iyengar as Thaisha Lloy</li>
	<li>Taliesin Jaffe as Bolaire Lathalia</li>
	<li>Ashley Johnson as Vaelus</li>
	<li>Matt Mercer as Sir Julien Davinos</li>
	<li>Whitney Moore as Tyranny</li>
	<li>Liam O'brien as Halandil Fang</li>
	<li>Marisha Ray as Murray Mag'Nesson</li>
	<li>Sam Riegel as Wicander Halovar</li>
	<li>Alexander Ward as Occtis Tachonis</li>
	<li>Travis Willingham as Teor Pridesire</li>
</ul><p><em>Critical Role</em> Campaign 4 will premiere October 2 Youtube, Twitch, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-announces-beacon-fall-line-up-including-new-season-of-rooster-teeth" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Beacon</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/critical-role-campaign-4-trailer-introduces-us-to-land-of-araman]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Devs Have A Button That Blows Up Everything In A Map And It’s ‘Fun’ To Press]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-devs-have-a-button-that-blows-up-everything-in-a-map-and-its-fun-to-press-it-2000626898</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-devs-have-a-button-that-blows-up-everything-in-a-map-and-it%E2%80%99s-%E2%80%98fun%E2%80%99-to-press.1302057/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>I recently got to play more <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-framerate-fps-xbox-series-s-ps5-2000626043"><em>Battlefield 6</em></a>, but this time on the game’s two biggest maps, and <a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-bigger-maps-leak-datamine-eastwood-mirak-ea-bf-labs-2000618202">I had a blast playing in these big ol’ stages.</a> But when I got a chance to speak to the devs behind <em>Battlefield 6</em>, I had to ask a strange question: Do you all have a button that lets you blow up everything that is destructible in the franchise’s famously destructible maps? The answer was yes, and there’s a good reason why.</p> <p>During a Zoom interview with DICE producer Jeremy Chubb and design director Shashank Uchil, we talked about all the work that goes into making a big<a href="https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-devs-struggled-xbox-series-s-60-fps-switch-2-2000625487"><em> Battlefield</em></a> map and how much effort they put into remaking the iconic and beloved Operation Firestorm map, which will be available in <em>BF6</em> at launch. But, when our conversation veered into talking about how to balance maps that can blow up in all kinds of ways, I had to ask if they had a tool or button that lets them destroy everything in one click. So I asked and got a blunt answer:</p> <p>“Yeah,” said Chubb. I then asked if it was fun to hit that button, and both Chubb and Uchil replied, with laughter in their voices, that yes, it was indeed fun to hit that big button.</p>

 <p><span id="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d7e0" tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d7e1"><span title="Play starting at 21:44"><span data-start="1303560" data-end="1315620">“It is fun!” Chubb told <em>Kotaku</em> while laughing more. “It usually causes some big meltdowns in teams working on performance because we designed the maps not to be instantly triggered, like every instance of destruction [all at once]. </span></span></span><span id="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d7ec" tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d7ed"><span title="Play starting at 21:56"><span data-start="1315620" data-end="1317120">And [the button was pressed] a few times, and t</span></span></span><span id="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d7f8" tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d7f9"><span title="Play starting at 21:57"><span data-start="1317380" data-end="1321860" data-active="">here were some raised eyebrows about what we were doing for sure.”&nbsp;</span></span></span></p> <p>When I mentioned that EA should release GIFs of the maps completely blowing up after hitting that button, Uchil said that was a “good idea.” So you’re welcome, EA marketing team.</p>

  <h2>The reason for <em>BF6</em>‘s big red button</h2> <p>You might be wondering why there’s a button in Frostbite, the engine <em>BF6</em> is built on, that lets you blow up an entire map instantly. The answer is so that the team can easily playtest the map in its most destroyed state to make sure it’s still fun and balanced.</p> <p><span id="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d894" tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d895"><span title="Play starting at 22:36"><span data-start="1356460" data-end="1360900" data-active="">“So…think of the map as [having] three different states, right,” explained Uchil. “</span></span></span><span tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d8a1"><span title="Play starting at 22:41"><span data-start="1361360" data-end="1366080">The map starts out in a pristine state, or however it is meant to be at the beginning. </span></span></span><span id="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d8ac" tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d8ad"><span title="Play starting at 22:47"><span data-start="1367020" data-end="1369560">And then, as the map progresses, it gets more and more destroyed. </span></span></span><span id="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d8b8" tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d8b9"><span title="Play starting at 22:51"><span data-start="1370780" data-end="1375980">And towards the end, if everybody’s using a rocket launcher or C4, you hit peak destruction. </span></span></span><span tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d8c5"><span title="Play starting at 22:58"><span data-start="1377640" data-end="1383740">And like I said, the game has to be good in all three phases, the pristine phase, the in-between phase, and the final phase.”</span></span></span></p>

 <p>According to Uchil, the “big red button” is the best tool for quickly testing that final phase of each map.</p> <p>“You can see what is the worst-case scenario,” said Uchil.&nbsp; “<span tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d8e9"><span title="Play starting at 23:11"><span data-start="1390500" data-end="1391460">Is there enough cover? </span></span></span><span id="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d8f4" tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d8f5"><span title="Play starting at 23:12"><span data-start="1391800" data-end="1393320">Do we need to add some more things? </span></span></span>Do we need to bring some more assets s<span tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11d90d"><span title="Play starting at 23:15"><span data-start="1394920" data-end="1397200">o in the final stage, it’s still fun to play? </span></span></span>So yeah, that’s why we have the big button.”</p> <p>At this point, I was fully distracted by the idea of the button, and asked if anyone had ever pressed it by accident. That doesn’t seem to have happened, and because the maps weren’t built to instantly explode, it could lead to problems if it did.</p>

 <p><span id="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11da80" tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11da81"><span title="Play starting at 25:11"><span data-start="1510520" data-end="1522440">“I mean, we have times when you can crash a bunch of things,” said Uchil. “The destruction is meant to happen in parts. </span></span></span><span id="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11da8c" tabindex="-1" aria-describedby="L-BihKRdJcs9lwQgBgHKX9eA11da8d"><span title="Play starting at 25:24"><span data-start="1523580" data-end="1527720">But if everything explodes at the same time, then it would melt down your computer.”</span></span></span></p> <p>Now I hope someone is able to mod <em>Battlefield 6</em> after it launches on October 10 and either activate this button as part of a wild mod or recreate its functionality. I really just want to hit a big button and make an entire map go ka-boom. That sounds like a blast. And after talking to the devs, it seems they agree.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/battlefield-6-devs-have-a-button-that-blows-up-everything-in-a-map-and-its-fun-to-press-it-2000626898]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Remaining Unannounced Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds DLC Collaborations Have Leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-remaining-unannounced-dlc-leaked-sega/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-remaining-unannounced-sonic-racing-crossworlds-dlc-collaborations-have-leaked.1302033/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds is officially out next week, on September 25, 2025, but that official release date hasn't stopped physical copies of the game from finding their way out into the wild early. While physical copies of a racing game don't exactly mean big narrative spoilers are about to hit the wire the way it would for other titles getting out early, in this case, it does seem to mean the rest of the DLC collaborations SEGA had planned getting leaked early.</p>



<p>A photo of a postcard that came with physical copies of the game, which is stored inside the case, shows the remaining three collaborations that SEGA has yet to announce for Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds. The image was posted to the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SonicTheHedgehog/comments/1nkh9h8/so_about_the_final_unannounced_collab_dlc/">Sonic the Hedgehog Reddit</a>, revealing that the next three collaborations after the already announced Minecraft, Pac-Man, and Spongebob collaborations are: Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, Avatar Legends, and Mega Man.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Of course, this doesn't necessarily reveal which characters from each of the above series will be included. The <a href="https://asia.sega.com/SonicRacingCrossWorlds/en/racers.html">official website</a> for Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds shows eight mystery spots in the roster of DLC characters. Half of those could be filled by the Turtles, but the image specifically lists TMNT: Mutant Mayhem, so we could see other characters beyond the four teenage turtles, and that's before mentioning that there might be a greater focus on including characters from the other three series.</p>



<p>At the very least, we know to expect new tracks, characters, and vehicles related to Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Mutant Mayhem, Avatar Legends, and Megaman. Also, since this information was featured in a postcard coming with physical copies of the game that will be officially available in just a few days, it's likely we'll hear a proper announcement from SEGA regarding these DLC collaborations soon.</p>



<p>In the meantime, you can check out <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/sonic-racing-crossworlds/">Wccftech's review</a> of Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds from Nathan Birch, who writes, "<em>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds is a solid alternative to other games in the mascot-racer space, offering speedy, stripped-down action, a few clever twists, and perhaps most importantly for some folks, courses that feel more like those in Mario Kart 8 than the less universally-beloved Mario Kart World. A general lack of content and originality keeps CrossWorlds from fully breaking away from the pack, but it’s at least in striking distance of the winner’s circle.</em>"</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-remaining-unannounced-dlc-leaked-sega/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[George A. Romero’s Daughter Is Making A Zombie Drag Queen Movie And It Looks Great]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/george-a-romeros-daughter-zombie-drag-queen-movie-queens-trailer-2000626904</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/george-a-romero%E2%80%99s-daughter-is-making-a-zombie-drag-queen-movie-and-it-looks-great.1302030/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Tina Romero, the daughter of the late filmmaker and creator of the modern zombie, <a href="https://kotaku.com/that-time-george-romero-almost-directed-a-resident-evil-1766259870">George A. Romero</a>, is making her directorial debut with, appropriately enough, a movie all about an invasion of the undead. But <em>Queens of the Dead</em> shakes up the formula by having the zombies attack an NYC party featuring drag queen performers and their friends.</p> <p><em>Queens of the Dead</em> is a new horror comedy mixing together drag queens and zombies, and it’s set to hit theaters in October. The first look at this upcoming flick is out now, and the movie looks fun. It also looks like a movie that might greatly upset and confuse your conservative grandpa, who loves Fox News. Here’s the trailer:</p>  <p>The new movie stars the always excellent <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Katy_O%27Brian">Katy O’Brian</a>, Nina West, Jack Haven, and others, and looks to split its action between a group of clubgoers and drag queens stuck in a warehouse party, and the happenings at a hospital in New York City during the zombie uprising. After watching this trailer, I’m on board for this spin on the classic zombie movie. It’s also great to see Romero continuing her father’s legacy of making zombie movies that aren’t just gory and scary, but also filled with characters and ideas that feel extremely relevant. Romero’s iconic horror movie, <em>Night of the Living Dead,</em> essentially created modern-day zombies, or ghouls as he often called them, and laid out the basic framework most zombie movies follow: People stuck in a place fight back the dead while dealing with each other.</p> <p>Here’s the official description for the film courtesy of IFC Films:</p> <blockquote><p>When a zombie apocalypse breaks out in Brooklyn on the night of a giant warehouse party, an eclectic group of drag queens, club kids, &amp; frenemies must put aside their drama and use their unique skills to fight against the brain-thirsty, scrolling undead.</p></blockquote> <p>In 2025, with <a href="https://kotaku.com/surprise-press-conference-reveals-trump-still-not-dead-2000622401">President Trump</a> and <a href="https://translegislation.com/">other Republicans cracking down on LGBTQ people</a> and anything they deem “different,” a movie about a horde of nasty zombies trying to destroy a safe place for drag queens and queer folk seems pretty dang perfect. I’d bet George would be proud of his daughter’s first theatrical film. Before this, she had done TV and smaller projects. I’m excited to check out <em>Queens of the Dead</em> when it arrives in theaters on October 24. Just in time for Halloween.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/george-a-romeros-daughter-zombie-drag-queen-movie-queens-trailer-2000626904]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dream-casting and finding character with your own voice - Unlocking the Vault #2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/dream-casting-and-finding-character-with-your-own-voice-unlocking-the-vault-2</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dream-casting-and-finding-character-with-your-own-voice-unlocking-the-vault-2.1302027/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>In Unlocking the Vault, Game Developer editor-in-chief Danielle Riendeau dives into the rich archives of the GDC Vault in order to uncover timeless game development advice, anecdotes, and hard-learned lessons tucked away within the hundreds of talks from decades of GDC shows preserved within the Vault. Every other week, this curated overview will feature key takeaways from a vintage or classic GDC Talk with the goal of helping today's developers unearth new lessons from the past.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In week ten (of a twelve week quarter) in my Game Design Principles class at Berklee, we focus on writing &nbsp;characters for games. My students craft game design documents for a blue-sky project of their own design, and for most folks, there is some element of character creation (except for those opting for the most abstract puzzle or strategy games, and they have heavier assignments in other areas!)</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In preparing for the week ten lecture, I often like to take inspiration from the fine minds at GDC, especially for narrative design and strong, iconic character writing. One talk that I've enjoyed re-discovering recently (and showing to my students) is this GDC 2021 banger Finding Character Voice With Your Voice. In it, Wooga Senior Writer and voice actor Cyrus Nemati gives a short-but-action-packed talk on using elements of performance to really make characters pop off the page, even at early stages of writing.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/nintendo-spells-out-why-player-communication-should-only-happen-in-game" target="_self" data-discover="true">Nintendo spells out why player communication should only happen in-game</a></p><p><iframe title="Embedded content" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HUD3BNK-S7Y" height="nullpx" width="100%" allowfullscreen="" data-testid="iframe-video" loading="lazy"></iframe></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Cast your characters (in your dreams)">Cast your characters (in your dreams)</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">After warning writers off of the temptation to just write oodles of lore, Nemati showcases a Mike Bithell (of Bithell Games) gem on writing for games. In a 2019 tweet, Bithell notes "My writing gets 10x better once I've settled my dream casting for the character I'm working on."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Mentally assembling a cast of actors who could play your characters is already providing characterization," says Nemati. "Imagine you are struggling with a character on making their dialogue sound consistent and iconic, and you realize 'huh, you know, Sylvester Stallone kinda sounds like this, and the dialogue starts to flow naturally,'" he drops into a Stallone-drawl as he makes the last point. "At least, as naturally as Sylvester Stallone's dialogue does, because you know what he sounds like."&nbsp;</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The most animated table reads are the best (and most fun)">The most animated table reads are the best (and most fun)</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">After presenting a few case studies on characters and performance, Nemati stresses the importance of having some fun in the writer's room. "Most of us can recognize when writing is uninspired, or when it's done just to fulfill some sort of narrative checkbox. If your studio acts as though writing is just the thing one must do to push the player along, it is up to you to bring that enthusiasm for writing, and the best way to do that is really to have fun with it!"</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/digging-into-the-combat-design-of-cronos-the-new-dawn-game-developer-podcast-ep-54" target="_self" data-discover="true">Digging into the combat design of Cronos: The New Dawn - Game Developer Podcast Ep. 54</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">He calls up a clip of a table read with his team, where the writers get very animated in their read of a parrot character holding the keys to a mystery. There are voices (oh boy, are there ever!) and a lot of laughter, and Nemati himself, giving the talk and watching the clip, is overjoyed by the goofy energy.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This is just us having a good time," he begins, happily. "But that good time helps us bond as a team, which is certainly a good thing to have in your writer's room. The comfort that comes with a strong bond allows you to explore and find a character's unique voice, and voice makes your characters unique."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"My holy grail for written dialogue is for the reader to know exactly who is speaking, without a name tag."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">After a brief segue revolving around Kreia's memorable performance from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Nemati goes back to the fundamental topic of the talk: "Use your voice!"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"There's absolutely no reason not to do this in your writer's room," he says, encouraging writers to perform, have fun, and truly get into it. "Even if you're the only writer on your team, perform your dialogue... just get those voices out there, they will help you." Nemati offers a few pathways to hiring voice actors for this early stage as well, if your project is of a scope that supports that.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/grounded-2-exists-because-players-really-wanted-to-ride-bugs" target="_self" data-discover="true">Grounded 2 exists because players really wanted to ride bugs</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Unlocking the key takeaways">Unlocking the key takeaways</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In case you want the sparknotes version of the talk—or you're just outlining some of the major lessons in your notes—don't worry, I've got you!</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The key takeaways here are </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Lesson #1: Don't rely on oodles of lore</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to write memorable characters, think of who you'd like to play that character (call it dream-casting) and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Lesson #2: Perform that dialogue</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, whether by yourself, for your writer's room, or by hiring a voice actor. You'll find layers and depth no matter what direction you go in here.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Editor-in-Chief, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Danielle is the editor-in-chief of Game Developer, with previous editorial posts at Fanbyte, VICE, and Polygon. She’s also a lecturer in game design at the Berklee College of Music, and a hobbyist game developer in her spare time.</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/dream-casting-and-finding-character-with-your-own-voice-unlocking-the-vault-2]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leaked Casting Calls For Amazon’s Mass Effect TV Series Stir Speculation the Adaptation Will Feature Male Shepard]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/mass-effect-tv-series-leaked-casting-calls-male-shepard/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/leaked-casting-calls-for-amazon%E2%80%99s-mass-effect-tv-series-stir-speculation-the-adaptation-will-feature-male-shepard.1302009/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/mass-effect-tv-series-deal-nearly-completed-by-amazon-says-report/">Four years ago</a>, we first heard a report that Amazon was crossing the 't's on a deal with EA and BioWare to make a Mass Effect TV series adaptation. Now, we know the deal went through, that <a href="https://wccftech.com/mass-effect-tv-series-in-development-at-prime-video-with-fast-and-furious-9-writer/">Daniel Casey</a> was tapped to write the show, followed by<a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-mgm-studios-mass-effect-tv-series-taps-star-trek-beyond-writer-doug-jung-to-be-the-showrunner/"> Doug Jung</a> being selected to be its showrunner, and we've even had a <a href="https://wccftech.com/amazon-mass-effect-tv-show-same-production-team-behind-fallout-tv-show/">confidence-boosting confirmation</a> that the same production team of artists who excellently brought Fallout to life will also be working on Mass Effect.</p>



<p>All of that still leaves a whole pile of unanswered questions, but a recent leak might've just begun to answer one of the most major questions in the series: which Shepard will it be?</p>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effect-tv-series-casting-calls-leak-sparking-speculation-male-shepard-is-canon">Eurogamer</a>, entertainment reporter and insider <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/mass-effect-138895669">Daniel Richtman</a> leaked five casting calls for Amazon's Mass Effect TV series. The calls don't explicitly say which character they're casting, but anyone familiar enough with the series can make educated guesses, and one of the calls points to Amazon choosing to go with Male Shepard for its iteration of the story.</p>



<p>The five calls are, per Eurogamer, "<em>a young Colin Farrell-type male (30-39) with open ethnicity, a female co-lead alien character requiring prosthetics (34-39), a female human providing a parallel narrative from Earth, a Doug Jones-type male villain (40-60), and a male wrestler-type soldier (30-49).</em>"</p>



<p>Fans of the series have speculated that the 'male wrestler-type' is a casting call for James Vega, while the villain casting call points to Saren Arterius. The female co-lead is very likely a casting call for Liara T'Soni, while the other female casting call could be Emily Wong, a reworked version of Ashley Williams story, or a twin Shepard, by fans best approximations.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Of course, it's the first call listed that's causing the most ruckus, as fans are speculating that it is pointing to the show's lead, Commander Shepard, and casting for a male means Amazon has chosen to go with Mark Meer's Male Shepard over Jennifer Hale's FemShep.</p>



<p>When Casey spoke about having the Fallout production team work on Mass Effect earlier this year, he confirmed that the writer's room has been in full swing since the beginning of 2025. Which Shepard they would go with was likely one of the earliest decisions they made, so unless they restart the process, if fans are correct in their speculation for these casting calls, then we are locked in to the series featuring Male Shepard.</p>



<p>How that'll go over with fans remains to be seen, since there are plenty within the community who look to FemShep as the canon choice. The other side to this is that deciding which Shepard it'll be is only one of the many decisions that Casey and Jung will have to make that could alienate fans from the series. Which former BioWare lead writer, <a href="https://wccftech.com/mass-effect-tv-show-criticized-bioware-lead-writer-david-gaider/">David Gaider, predicted would happen three years ago</a>.</p>



<p>In fairness, Gaider didn't need any prescient abilities to point out that some fans will dislike the decisions made for the coming adaptation, but as we learn more about the adaptation, it'll be interesting to see if by the time we're closing in on its premiere date, if it is starting on its back foot, needing to win over fans instead of successfully getting them excited for what's to come.</p>

			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/mass-effect-tv-series-leaked-casting-calls-male-shepard/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Charlie Kirk Shooter Suspect’s Steam Gaming History Under Review By Secret Service]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/charlie-kirk-shooter-steam-library-valve-discord-radicalization-2000626897</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-charlie-kirk-shooter-suspect%E2%80%99s-steam-gaming-history-under-review-by-secret-service.1302006/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>It didn’t take long after law enforcement officials publicly identified a <a href="https://kotaku.com/charlie-kirk-shooter-helldivers-bullet-engraving-2000625439">suspect in the Charlie Kirk assassination</a> for people online to begin combing the internet looking for his digital footprint. One of the profiles they found appeared to be his Steam account which, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-09-18/suspected-kirk-shooter-s-gaming-history-probed-by-secret-service?srnd=undefined&amp;embedded-checkout=true">according to <em>Bloomberg</em></a>, is now being investigated by the Secret Service.</p> <p>That’s because 22-year-old Tyler Robinson, who was charged earlier this week with murdering Kirk at a speaking event last week, reportedly used Donald Trump’s name as an alias on the Valve-owned gaming storefront at one point. Sources told <em>Bloomberg</em> the reference to the president is what led to the Secret Service’s involvement despite the Homeland Security agency having no role in protecting Kirk at the time of the assassination.</p> <p>The Steam account many believe to belong to Robinson shows thousands of hours spent playing games like <em>Sea of Thieves</em>, <em>Deep Rock Galactic</em>, and <em>Counter-Strike</em>. The handful of public Steam reviews he seemingly authored were indistinct from the thousands of others posted for those games. People have also been combing through his apparent Steam inventory, which includes hats, trading cards, and other unlockables.</p>

 <p>Steam is among those gaming-affiliated internet platforms <a href="https://kotaku.com/charlie-kirk-shooter-discord-politics-helldivers-memes-2000626029">which have been called to Congress</a> next month to testify about online radicalization. The CEOs from Twitch, Discord, and Reddit have also been asked to participate. Despite a reference to <em>Helldivers 2</em> appearing on one of the casings left behind near the crime scene, there’s been little publicly disclosed evidence so far that gaming, memes, or any other part of the modern internet played much of a role in driving Robinson to allegedly assassinate the right wing podcaster.</p> <p>“The politically motivated assassination of Charlie Kirk claimed the life of a husband, father, and American patriot. In the wake of this tragedy, and amid other acts of politically motivated violence, Congress has a duty to oversee the online platforms that radicals have used to advance political violence,” House Oversight and Government Reform Committee Chairman James Comer (R-Ky.)&nbsp;<a href="https://oversight.house.gov/release/chairman-comer-invites-ceos-of-discord-steam-twitch-and-reddit-to-testify-on-radicalization-of-online-forum-users/">announced on Wednesday</a>.</p> <p>But <a href="https://www.kenklippenstein.com/p/exclusive-leaked-messages-from-charlie">leaked Discord chats and interviews</a> with friends have so far offered little that would suggest Robinson’s history with gaming and the internet were uniquely worrying, or different from those of most other people his age.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/charlie-kirk-shooter-steam-library-valve-discord-radicalization-2000626897]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anniversary: Celebrate Unova As Pokémon Black & White Turns 15]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/anniversary-celebrate-unova-as-pokemon-black-and-white-turns-15</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anniversary-celebrate-unova-as-pok%C3%A9mon-black-white-turns-15.1301991/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure><a title="Reshiram and Zekrom Black &amp; White" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/796e4fe77916b/reshiram-and-zekrom-black-and-white.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p><strong>Pokémon</strong>'s fifth generation kicked off 15 years ago today with the release of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/pokemon_black_and_white">Pokémon Black &amp; White</a> in Japan.</p>
<p>On 18th September 2010, the world first stepped foot into Unova, a brand new Pokémon region based on North America, specifically New York City's metropolitan area, with a mix of landmarks inspired by the area <em>and</em> other part of the whole country.</p>
<p>Pokémon Black &amp; White changed the rulebook of the Pokédex for the first time. Introducing a mammoth 156 new Pocket Monsters, the largest amount ever in the series, trainers were forced to adapt and use <em>only</em> those new 'mons. Want to whip out a Zubat in battle? Well tough; here's a Woobat for you, though.</p><div><figure data-videoid="Mh1U8qC_TUE" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mh1U8qC_TUE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Mh1U8qC_TUE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mh1U8qC_TUE?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed38e70bmhtzsk&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><figcaption><p><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mh1U8qC_TUE" rel="noopener">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></p>
<p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>834k</span></a></p>
</figcaption></figure></div>
<p>At the time, Black &amp; White weren't particularly well loved — you couldn't use previous Gen Pokémon unless you could trade with a friend who'd beaten the game and unlocked the National Dex <em>or</em> beaten the game yourself. Pokémon such as Trubbish and Vanillite were criticised for being based on objects or food (as a note, this write <em>loves</em> the Vanillite line; it's so stupid). Complaints about stagnant gameplay were abundant. And many features in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/pokemon_heartgold_and_soulsilver">HeartGold &amp; SoulSilver</a> remakes were absent here.</p>
<figure><a title="Unova" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/102bf804e826b/unova.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: The Pokémon Company</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Yet time has been extremely kind to Generation 5, and today, many consider it one of the best in the franchise. N, the puppet head of the villainous Team Plasma, has become a fan-favourite character, and 'mons such as Chandelure, Zoroark, Krookodile, and Volcarona among the most-beloved.</p>
<p>And, if nothing else, the duo spawned direct sequels that eschewed the usual third-game formula: <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/pokemon_black_and_white_2">Pokémon Black 2 &amp; White 2</a>. No Pokémon Grey for you folks.</p>
<p>In recent years, however, there's been much talk of a potential Black &amp; White remake coming to the Switch — or, more likely the Switch 2 at this point. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_brilliant_diamond_and_shining_pearl">Brilliant Diamond &amp; Shining Pearl</a> were the most-recent, so if we're going in chronological order, then it absolutely makes sense.</p>

<p>Plus, The Pokémon Company hasn't been shy about teasing and sharing Black &amp; White related media; events focused on the Unova-era 'mons have popped up in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/mobile/pokemon_go">Pokémon GO</a> and the <strong>Trading Card Game</strong>. Fans thought they spotted a tease in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_scarlet_and_violet">Pokémon Scarlet &amp; Violet</a>, and a character from Black &amp; White turned up in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_legends_arceus">Legends: Arceus</a>.</p>
<p>So, on Gen 5's 15th anniversary, is now the time for a Pokémon Black &amp; White remake? We've got <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Legends: Z-A</a>, focusing on Gen 6's Kalos, around the corner, and 2026 delivering <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/pokemon_champions">Champions</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-pokopia">Pokopia</a>. But what about Unova?</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Let us know if you want to see a Black &amp; White remake in our poll below, and why not share your favourite Black &amp; White memories in the comments, too!</em></p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/pokemon/related-articles:178516,133457,187968 @ 1758229194 --></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/anniversary-celebrate-unova-as-pokemon-black-and-white-turns-15]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 Developer Says Fixing PC Performance and Crashes Is ‘Top Priority’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-developer-says-fixing-pc-performance-is-top-priority/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-developer-says-fixing-pc-performance-and-crashes-is-%E2%80%98top-priority%E2%80%99.1301988/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Borderlands 4 developer Gearbox Software has officially <a href="https://x.com/Borderlands/status/1968451501803651131">communicated</a> with the community for the first time since launch. To start with, the studio thanked all those millions who purchased the games, indirectly confirming Alinea Analytics' report that <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-sold-2-million-units-earned-150-million/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Borderlands 4 has already sold (at least) two million units</a> (and earned at least $150 million in revenue). Players have already looted 764 million items, driven 65 million kilometers, and beaten 55 million bosses, failing 7 million times.</p>



<p>The message then moved to address the main outstanding issues, such as performance and crashes, especially on PC. This is Gearbox's current top priority.</p>



<p><em>We're reading every piece of feedback you share. Some of the things we've already begun to take action on are: </em></p>



<ul>
<li><em>We know some PC players are running into bugs and crashes. We hear you. Updates to improve stability and performance already started rolling out over the weekend and another is coming this Thursday. This is our top priority.</em></li>



<li><em>A Field of View (FOV) slider option for consoles is in testing right now and more information is coming very soon on that. Some console players have reported concerns with performance and we're investigating those with planned updates coming.</em></li>
</ul>



<p>Users have pointed out that this somewhat contradicts the <a href="https://wccftech.com/gearbox-boss-tells-4k-stubborn-players-switch-1440p-use-dlss/">counterclaims of Gearbox president and CEO Randy Pitchford regarding performance in Borderlands 4</a>. Regardless, the studio as a whole has now declared its commitment to delivering 'an incredible experience'. Launch is just the beginning for the game, with two Story Packs and four Bounty Packs <a href="https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-endgame-post-launch-roadmap-detailed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">already planned for the next year</a>, in addition to several free updates. </p>



<p>Meanwhile, Gearbox has shared a new SHiFT code that will provide access to the following items:</p>



<ul>
<li>1 new Vault Hunter Skin usable by Vex, Rafa, Amon, and Harlowe</li>



<li>1 Legendary Ripper Shield, which scales to your Vault Hunter's level (with a minimum of Lvl 25) when you redeem it via the Reward Center section of your Inventory screen, under Equipment.</li>



<li>2 ECHO-4 Drone Skins: "Break Free" and "Kn0x"</li>
</ul>









			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/borderlands-4-developer-says-fixing-pc-performance-is-top-priority/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead By Daylight Devs Say The Game Won’t Use AI Assets After GenAI Job Listing Appears Online]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dead-by-daylight-behaviour-interactive-ai-art-jobs-2000626902</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dead-by-daylight-devs-say-the-game-won%E2%80%99t-use-ai-assets-after-genai-job-listing-appears-online.1301979/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p><span>Today, </span><i><span>Dead by Daylight</span></i><span> fans noticed that developer Behaviour Interactive is </span><a href="https://www.bhvr.com/poste/senior-full-stack-programmer/"><span>hiring for a Senior Full-stack Programmer</span></a><span> at the team’s Montreal and Toronto studios. The person hired would work with the team’s “Generative AI Research Team,” with a directive to work on “researching, developing, and integrating innovative solutions using generative AI.” Fans saw “generative AI” and assumed that this might mean that the online asymmetrical horror game would be filled with generative AI assets in a future update. However, Behaviour has publicly spoken out about these claims, saying that it isn’t the case.</span></p> <p><span>In a post on X, Behaviour responded to a post speculating that the hired programmer would be working on </span><i><span>Dead by Daylight</span></i><span>, clarifying that this position is entirely dedicated to improving the company’s workflow using AI, rather than creating anything that will show up in the game itself.</span></p> <p><span>“We have a very firm policy that prevents the inclusion of anything generated by AI in </span><i><span>Dead by Daylight</span></i><span> or any other game we’re working on, including marketing assets,” the post reads. “Yes, Behaviour is exploring the use of generative AI tools to improve internal workflows – not for anything that ships in our games. But our policy isn’t changing, and this job isn’t for a role on a game team.”</span></p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">We have a very firm policy that prevents the inclusion of anything generated by AI in Dead by Daylight or any other game we're working on, including marketing assets. Yes, Behaviour is exploring the use of generative AI tools to improve internal workflows – not for anything that…</p> <p>— Dead by Daylight (@DeadbyDaylight) <a href="https://twitter.com/DeadbyDaylight/status/1968712705524552064?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 18, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p><span>The actual job listing itself notes this as well, saying “Behaviour is exploring the use of generative AI tools to improve internal workflows – not for anything that ships in our games.” I’m sure people are relieved to know that genAI slop isn’t about to infect </span><i><span>Dead by Daylight </span></i><span>any time soon. However, some people still take issue with the company using generative AI </span><a href="https://x.com/RealDevDaNerd/status/1968714757566841206"><span>in any capacity</span></a><span>, or argue that this is a slippery slope that could lead to </span><a href="https://x.com/KorynsCorner/status/1968717956449202599"><span>implementing it elsewhere in the company</span></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p> <p><i><span>Dead by Daylight</span></i><span> will enter its 37th “Chapter” on September 25, which will introduce The Krasue, a new Killer character </span><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@pvnkster/video/7545926057501773076"><span>with an absolutely gnarly intro animation</span></a><span>.</span></p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dead-by-daylight-behaviour-interactive-ai-art-jobs-2000626902]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Seance of Blake Manor launches October 27]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/the-seance-of-blake-manor-launches-october-27</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-seance-of-blake-manor-launches-october-27.1301970/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Supernatural detective mystery game dated.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Supernatural detective mystery game <em><a title="Games > The Seance of Blake Manor [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-seance-of-blake-manor">The Seance of Blake Manor</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [24,275 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1395520/The_Sance_of_Blake_Manor/" target="_blank">Steam</a> on October 27, publisher <a title="Companies > Raw Fury [106 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/raw-fury">Raw Fury</a> and <em>The Darkside Detective</em> developer <a title="Companies > Spooky Doorway [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/spooky-doorway">Spooky Doorway</a> announced. <span id="more-993726"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1395520/The_Sance_of_Blake_Manor/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><a title="Games > Halloween [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/halloween">Halloween</a>, 1897. A group of mystics from across the globe gather in the west of Ireland to rip open the veil between worlds and speak directly with the dead. 48 hours before the seance, Evelyn Deane goes missing. Detective Ward is summoned to find her and uncover the culprit before someone else disappears.</p><p>But the manor and its residents have more than one secret to hide. Can Ward safely navigate the haunted corridors to save Miss Deane before it is too late</p><p><strong>Enter the Manor</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>As Detective Declan Ward, you’ll interview and interrogate an eclectic group of suspects to learn more about their motivations and unearth any clues they may be hiding.</p><p>Record the details in Declan’s journal, then use your findings to uncover the truth about Blake Manor and the mysterious seance that has brought these unusual guests together.</p><p><strong>Become the Detective</strong></p><p>Arriving at Blake Manor just before Halloween, you’ll soon learn something isn’t quite right as unexplained phenomena torment you at every turn.</p><p>Walking the halls, you’ll learn of the centuries of tragedy that have befallen the manor and the sad stories of spirits suffering because of it.</p><p>And somewhere in the midst of it all lie the mysterious whereabouts of Evelyn Dean.</p><p><strong>Uncover the Secrets</strong></p><p>Study the scenery, solve environmental clues and reach the forbidden areas of the hotel… and beyond.</p><p>But be careful—each <a title="Genres > Action [3,046 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> and every lost minute counts the day down. Be in the right place at the right time to catch critical events pertinent to your investigation. And who knows what hidden secrets lie in wait once you’ve turned in for the night…</p><p><strong>Save Evelyn Deane</strong></p><p>Brought to you by the creators of <em>The Darkside Detective</em> and Raw Fury, <em>The Seance of Blake Manor</em> is depicted by a beautiful comic-book art style. Inspired by Irish Mythology and the spiritualist movements of the Victorian era, players are cast into a first-person narrative <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,563 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a>, blending the supernatural with a classic detective mystery. With its striking cutscenes, compelling narrative and dynamic soundtrack that reacts to the environment around you, Blake Manor and its secrets will leave you on the edge of your seat morning through night.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Embark on an ongoing mystery inspired by Irish Mythology and the spiritualist movements of the Victorian era.</li><li>Explore an ancient manor full of dark secrets and environmental puzzles where time is your most valuable currency.</li><li>Elicit the truth from a host of suspects using immersive detective mechanics</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Release Date Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="The Séance of Blake Manor | Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ATH_4Ea5O6s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/09/the-seance-of-blake-manor-launches-october-27]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Resolution And Frame Rate Targets For PS5, Xbox Series X|S Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-resolution-and-frame-rate-targets-for-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-revealed/1100-6534871/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-resolution-and-frame-rate-targets-for-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-revealed.1301967/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534871">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>EA and Battlefield Studios have revealed the performance targets for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/" data-ref-id="1100-6526583">Battlefield 6</a> on PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S, confirming what console players can expect in terms of graphics and performance.</p><p>The game has Fidelity and Performance modes on Xbox Series X|S, PS5, and PS5 Pro, but not Xbox Series S--that platform has no alternate graphics modes to choose from and instead has a maximum.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1324394106" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466353,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;20%20Minutes%20of%20Battlefield%206%20Operation%20Firestorm%20Gameplay&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:1232,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/20-minutes-of-battlefield-6-operation-firestorm-gameplay\/2300-6466353\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466353\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466353\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466353\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466353&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466353,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6534871&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;battlefield-6&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;battlefield&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;battlefield&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466353},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466353\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4569773-gameplay_bf6_operationfirestorm_v1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/cD5IvkoA.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1758121200,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="cD5IvkoA" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> 20 Minutes of Battlefield 6 Operation Firestorm Gameplay</p>
      </div>
<p><span>The Fidelity mode emphasizes resolution, while Performance targets frame rate. Fidelity mode on Xbox Series X reaches a maximum resolution of 1440p and targets 60fps, while PS5's Fidelity mode cranks up to 1440p and 60fps. Performance mode on Xbox Series X reaches a maximum resolution of 1280p but targets 80fps, and the same values hold for PS5's Performance mode.</span></p><p>The PS5 Pro, meanwhile, ratchets things up to 2160p/60fps for Fidelity mode and 1620p/80fps for Performance mode. You can see the full rundown below. These are all maximum targets, so we don't know the range of resolutions and frame rates players will actually encounter in different scenarios.</p><p>The PC version of Battlefield 6, meanwhile, can <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-pc-specs-revealed-and-you-wont-need-a-military-grade-pc-to-run-it/1100-6533619/" data-ref-id="1100-6533619">reach 2160/4K and 144fps</a> on an official setting or uncapped for people who feel their rig is capable enough. For more, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-pc-specs-revealed-and-you-wont-need-a-military-grade-pc-to-run-it/1100-6533619/" data-ref-id="1100-6533619">see the full PC requirements.</a></p><p>Battlefield 6 launches on October 10 for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. A <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-battle-royale-release-date-trailer-details/1100-6533631/" data-ref-id="1100-6533631">battle royale mode</a> is also in the works.</p><h2><strong>Battlefield 6 console performance targets</strong></h2><ul><li><strong>Xbox Series S:</strong> Maximum resolution of 1080p and targets 60FPS</li><li><strong>Xbox Series X Fidelity Mode:</strong> Maximum resolution of 1440p and targets 60FPS</li><li><strong>Xbox Series X Performance Mode:</strong> Maximum resolution of 1280p and targets 80+FPS</li><li><strong>PlayStation 5 Fidelity Mode:</strong> Maximum resolution of 1440p and targets 60FPS</li><li><strong>PlayStation 5 Performance Mode:</strong> Maximum resolution of 1280p and targets 80+FPS</li><li><strong>PlayStation 5 Pro Fidelity Mode:</strong> Maximum resolution of 2160p and targets 60FPS</li><li><strong>PlayStation 5 Pro Performance Mode:</strong> Maximum resolution of 1620p and targets 80+FPS</li></ul>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-resolution-and-frame-rate-targets-for-ps5-xbox-series-x-s-revealed/1100-6534871/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Adorable 'Lil Gator Game' Is Getting A "Huge" Expansion In 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/the-adorable-lil-gator-game-is-getting-a-huge-expansion-in-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-adorable-lil-gator-game-is-getting-a-huge-expansion-in-2026.1301946/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Update: Promises to be " their biggest yet!"</p>
</section></header><section>
<p><strong>Update [<time datetime="2025-09-18T18:30:00+00:00" data-format="D jS M Y, g:ia">Thu 18th Sep 2025, 7:30pm</time>]:</strong> Get ready for some snappy, child-like adventures in early 2026, as Lil Gator Game's big expansion, In the Dark, arrives next year on Switch.</p>
<p>The release window was just announced as part of today's Six One Indie Showcase, and we got an adorable new trailer to go with the DLC.</p>
<p>Promising the double the size of the original game and bring a little spookiness to Lil Gator's life, you'll be exploring an underground world of cavernous corridors and secret treasure. Oh, and plenty of new friends too. Just have a little peek at these new screenshots:</p>

<p>Lil Gator will get more tools to expand his adorably impressive moveset, too; did you know a gymnastic ribbon can help you double jump? Well, we didn't until now.</p>
<p>This looks like the perfect way to start 2026, so we'll keep an eye out for a release date. And for more details on the expansion, have a look at our story from the start of the year below...</p><hr><p><strong>Original Story:</strong></p>
<p>Playtonic Friends and MegaWobble have announced a surprise expansion to one of the cutest hidden gems of 2022, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/lil_gator_game">Lil Gator Game</a>.</p>
<p><strong>In The Dark</strong> promises to be a "huge" expansion, introducing new characters and doubling the size of the base game. The original was a breezy affair, but we're delighted to have the opportunity to revisit all of our animal friends. You'll be exploring a whole new area tucked under the surface after a new cave opens up. New toys and gadgets will allow you to explore in many different ways.</p>
<p>The DLC doesn't have a release date yet, but we'll be getting more news on it later in the year. And, alongside In The Dark, a new bundle titled <strong>Gator of the Year Edition</strong> will be released, allowing newcomers to grab the base game and the expansion together.</p>

<p>There's no better time to get into Lil Gator Game than this year — and if you want something short, sweet, and meaningful, then <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/switch-eshop/lil-gator-game">we highly recommend it</a>.</p>
<p><em>Will you be getting Lil Gator Game: In The Dark? Let us know in the comments below</em>.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:141934 @ 1758229481 --></section></article><div><p>Alana has been with Nintendo Life since 2022, and while RPGs are her first love, Nintendo is a close second. She enjoys nothing more than overthinking battle strategies, characters, and stories. She also wishes she was a Sega air pirate.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/AlanaHagues"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/alanahagues.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('AlanaHagues');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/the-adorable-lil-gator-game-is-getting-a-huge-expansion-in-2026]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dying Light: The Beast Shows an Aging Engine]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-shows-an-aging-engine/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dying-light-the-beast-shows-an-aging-engine.1301943/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Techland has just released Dying Light: The Beast, the third installment (fourth if you count the original game's expansion pack The Following) in the first-person open world action game zombie series.</p>



<p>You can read our full game review <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dying-light-the-beast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>, written by David Carcasole. Here's an excerpt:</p>



<p><em>Dying Light: The Beast has two core pillars that are fairly strong, and if you are already a fan of the series, then there's sure to be plenty here for you to enjoy, even if it might not knock it out of the park in every element. If you're new to the series and have no prior attachments to it, but love a good zombie-killing game now and then, I'd push you to really consider how much you want to spend your money on this game, when there are so many better games to spend your time with in 2025.</em></p>



<p>In this article, I will concentrate exclusively on the game's technical side. The game utilizes an evolved version of Techland's proprietary C-Engine, last seen in Dying Light 2: Stay Human. As a reminder, Dying Light: The Beast was originally going to be the second DLC for Stay Human, and to be honest, it shows, at least visually.</p>



<p>Even though the development team stressed that there have been a number of significant technical improvements in the game to lighting, weather effects, skyboxes, materials, and foliage, to be honest, the game doesn't look that different. Furthermore, it looks pretty average for a 2025 triple-A game, even with all settings maxed out on PC. The texture work and lighting in particular stand out negatively when compared to top games in the genre. </p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Dying Light: The Beast 4K PC Gameplay - Max Settings, DLAA, DLSS FGx4 with RTX 5090" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ECwhcscNyt0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>Visuals could perhaps slightly improve post-launch. Techland had <a href="https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-pc-requirements-nvidia-dlss-4-amd-fsr-4-intel-xess-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> that Dying Light: The Beast would include ray-traced global illumination and reflections, but these are nowhere to be seen in the graphics options. We reached out to ask about their inclusion, but have not received a response so far. It is possible they might be coming later with a patch.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The flip side is that the game doesn't even perform that well as is, and that is on top-of-the-line hardware. With a Ryzen 7 9800X3D CPU and GeForce RTX 5090, the game averaged 236.2 frames per second with maxed settings at 4K resolution, DLSS Multi Frame Generation (x4), and DLAA. But there is a lot of variance; the 1% Low is at 129 FPS, and the 0.1% Low is at 85 FPS. What's worse, if you check the gameplay video, some stutters go down to 40-45 FPS, and in two instances (toward the end of the footage) even down to 9 or 20 FPS. Needless to say, it feels all the more jarring coming (and quickly returning to) from a very high average frame rate.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Obviously, the side effects of this stuttering can be minimized, as always, by capping your frame rate. But doing so would effectively negate the benefit of having a display with a high refresh rate. It's a trade-off that might be worth it on a case-by-case basis and one that each user will ultimately have to decide for themselves.</p>



<p>One clear improvement over Dying Light 2: Stay Human is that Techland has introduced native support for HDR (High Dynamic Range) displays in this new game. The HDR calibration is well-made, offering detailed sliders for Maximum Luminance, Minimum Luminance, Brightness, Shadows, and UI Brightness. I would definitely recommend turning on HDR if you have the chance, as it can help combat the otherwise bland color palette available in regular SDR.</p>



<p>Overall, though, it is clear to me that Techland will have to significantly step up the technical game with their next title if they want to keep up with the ever-improving visual standard. Part of the reason for the middling visuals can be attributed to having to cater to legacy platforms like PlayStation 4 and Xbox One, at a time when practically every triple-A game save for annual sports titles has dropped those aging consoles. Indeed, Techland should rather look forward. Given the studio's <a href="https://wccftech.com/techland-wants-to-switch-to-a-3-4-year-cycle-starting-with-dying-light-the-beast/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stated goal to create games every three years or so</a>, its next game could very well arrive alongside the next-generation consoles (such as the <a href="https://wccftech.com/ps6-specs-rumor-34-40-tflops-6-12-rt-performance-uplift/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation 6</a>), which will undoubtedly feature some impressive launch titles against which the next Dying Light installment would inevitably be compared.</p>





			
		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/dying-light-the-beast-shows-an-aging-engine/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6 Remaster Maps Are Difficult For A Reason You May Not Expect, Dev Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-remaster-maps-are-difficult-for-a-reason-you-may-not-expect-dev-says/1100-6534869/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6-remaster-maps-are-difficult-for-a-reason-you-may-not-expect-dev-says.1301940/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534869">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/" data-ref-id="1100-6526583">Battlefield 6</a> brings back the fan-favorite Battlefield 3 map Operation Firestorm, but the process of remastering and updating the map--and remastering maps in general--wasn't simple, Battlefield Studios says.</p><p>In an interview with <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/battlefield-6/operation-firestorm-remaster" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">PCGamesN</a>, design director Shashank Uchil said, "You wouldn't believe how difficult it is," and not necessarily for the reason you may expect.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="539875059" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466353,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;20%20Minutes%20of%20Battlefield%206%20Operation%20Firestorm%20Gameplay&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:1232,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/20-minutes-of-battlefield-6-operation-firestorm-gameplay\/2300-6466353\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466353\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466353\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466353\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466353&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466353,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6534869&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;battlefield-6&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;battlefield&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;battlefield&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466353},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466353\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4569773-gameplay_bf6_operationfirestorm_v1.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/cD5IvkoA.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1758121200,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="cD5IvkoA" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> 20 Minutes of Battlefield 6 Operation Firestorm Gameplay</p>
      </div>
<p>Uchil said one part of what makes remaster maps challenging is the expectations players have. Battlefield 3 was released 14 years ago in 2011, and people may be remembering that version and feeling a certain fondness and nostalgia for it.</p><p>"People know the map and people have certain expectations. But also there's rose-tinted glasses, like, 'This is how it used to be,'" he said.</p><p>Battlefield 6 has a different destruction system than Battlefield 3 did and different weapons, and these elements made remastering Operation Firestorm "much more complicated than people think."</p><p>Producer Jeremy Chubb, meanwhile, said remastering maps forces the developer to be wary of a "fine line."</p><p>"Because people have really particular views about what that map was. They want that experience realized. But I think that we would disappoint people little if we weren't able to evolve it and embrace the new ideas and features that we have in this game," Chubb said.</p><p>Battlefield 6 will have <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/battlefield-6-maps/2900-6834/" data-ref-id="2900-6834">nine multiplayer maps at launch</a>, including Operation Firestorm. A <a href="https://thegamepost.com/battlefield-6-maps-leak-all-multiplayer-maps-remasters-revealed/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">datamining effort</a> discovered that there could be at least three more remaster maps coming, including <a href="https://battlefield.fandom.com/wiki/Propaganda" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Propaganda</a> (Battlefield 4), <a href="https://battlefield.fandom.com/wiki/Talah_Market" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Talah Market</a> (Battlefield 3), and <a href="https://battlefield.fandom.com/wiki/Downtown" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Downtown</a> (Battlefield Hardline), but this is not confirmed as of yet. EA has said it will add more maps to Battlefield 6 after launch as part of the game's ongoing seasonal DLC model.</p><p>Battlefield 6 launches on October 10 for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. A <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-battle-royale-release-date-trailer-details/1100-6533631/" data-ref-id="1100-6533631">battle royale mode</a> is also in the works.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-remaster-maps-are-difficult-for-a-reason-you-may-not-expect-dev-says/1100-6534869/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 gets a new PC patch to fix crashes, progression blockers and GPU-related problems]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4-gets-a-new-pc-patch-to-fix-crashes-progression-blockers-and-gpu-related-problems</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-gets-a-new-pc-patch-to-fix-crashes-progression-blockers-and-gpu-related-problems.1301925/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Will hopefully ensure "a more seamless experience"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture data-src-full="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Borderlands-4-review-(3).jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" src="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Borderlands-4-review-(3).jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Borderlands-4-review-(3).jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px) and (min-resolution: 2x)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Borderlands-4-review-(3).jpg?width=690&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 690px)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Borderlands-4-review-(3).jpg?width=414&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-resolution: 2x)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/2K</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Gearbox have released another <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a> update for technical problems on PC, with a particular focus on game stability and crashes, though they've also fixed a progression blocker or two in the process. Unlike <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4-update-aims-to-improve-stability-for-a-wide-range-of-pcs-but-comes-without-proper-patch-notes">that other Borderlands 4 patch</a> from earlier this week, this one has an actual changelog. Gosh, wait till Mark hears of this! Oh nuts, he's already gone on holiday, presumably in sheer consternation over the shortage of bullet points. Look what you did, Randy Pitchford. Look what you did.
</p><!--more-->
<p>"This update improves stability on PC, smooths out progression, and updates the Gilded Glory Pack loot and rewards for a more seamless experience," reads a note on the game's <a href="https://borderlands.2k.com/borderlands-4/update-notes/">official site</a>. "Please restart your game to ensure that the update goes through and to prevent connection errors in matchmaking."
</p>
<p>It follows the publication of our full <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4-review">Borderlands 4 review</a>, in which Jasmine Mannan summarised the new looter-shooter as a good laugh despite <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/i-tried-the-new-recommended-settings-for-borderlands-4-and-oh-no-they-dont-actually-fix-its-stuttering">the lingering stink</a> over choppy frame rates and other technical gremlins. "With improved movement, devastating Action Skills that can be adjusted to suit your playstyle, and very limited Claptrap appearances, Borderlands 4 is easily the best Borderlands game yet," she wrote.
</p>
<p>As of 16th September, at least, Borderlands 4 had <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/psst-borderlands-4-has-a-pretty-broken-infinite-damage-build-and-it-may-soon-go-the-way-of-the-dodo">a build that let you melt bosses</a> by, as far as I can tell, replacing all of your enemy's major arteries with blackholes. I'm quite glad that Borderlands is a stylised, comicbook affair with bouncing damage numerals, because Mark's breakdown of that exploit is absolutely horrendous. I imagine they'll be patching that out pronto. </p><p>Anyway, here's the full changelog for the latest Borderlands 4 update. It is... brief, far too brief for bolded subheadings, really, but I added the first two before I noticed how slight it was, and I'm jiggered if I'm going to change course now.</p>
<blockquote><strong>Stability</strong>
<ul>
<li>Addressed crashes tied to animation states, audio, and collision checks</li>
<li>Addressed various GPU-related crashes</li>
</ul>
<strong>Gameplay &amp; Progression</strong>
<ul>
<li>Resolved an issue where the Reward Center could stop working after claiming the Gilded Glory Pack rewards</li>
<li>Addressed a progression blocker in the mission "Talk to Zadra," where the objective could fail if players exited and relaunched mid-dialogue</li>
<li>Corrected "Doesn't own DLC" warnings incorrectly showing up on non-DLC gear</li>
<li>This will be fixed on consoles in the coming days.</li>
</ul>
<strong>Loot &amp; Items</strong>
<ul>
<li>Updated loot pools so Gilded Glory Pack guns no longer appear in standard chests </li>
</ul></blockquote>
</div>
      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/borderlands-4-gets-a-new-pc-patch-to-fix-crashes-progression-blockers-and-gpu-related-problems]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands 4 September 18 Update Improves Stability on PC and 'Smooths Out' Progression — but According to the Patch Notes Balance Changes Will Have ]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-september-18-update-improves-stability-on-pc-and-smooths-out-progression-but-according-to-the-patch-notes-balance-changes-will-have-to-wait</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-4-september-18-update-improves-stability-on-pc-and-smooths-out-progression-%E2%80%94-but-according-to-the-patch-notes-balance-changes-will-have.1301913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/borderlands-4">Borderlands 4</a> developer Gearbox has released the first meaningful update for the looter shooter that it said improves stability and “smooths out” progression — but there are no balance changes yet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“This update improves stability on PC, smooths out progression, and updates the Gilded Glory Pack loot and rewards for a more seamless experience,” Gearbox said in <a href="https://borderlands.2k.com/borderlands-4/update-notes/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a post on the 2K Borderlands website</a> alongside the patch notes, below. “Please restart your game to ensure that the update goes through and to prevent connection errors in matchmaking.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, Gearbox said Borderlands 4 will see weekly minor updates. These involve changes to which  Weekly Big Encore Boss and Wildcard Mission is live. Maurice’s Black Market Vending Machine is also on the move. The Weekly Big Encore Boss is a tougher variant of an existing boss with an even more rewarding loot pool. Weekly Wildcard Missions add challenging new traits to an existing mission. These missions feature a guaranteed Legendary drop that you can repeatedly earn to get your ideal roll.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">And here’s the official blurb on Maurice’s Black Market Vending Machine:</p><blockquote>Go in search of where the Black Market Vending Machine has moved to and discover what’s available in your game every week. Remember, while the location is the same, your vending machine items are different from other players, so ask around to see if someone has the item you’re looking for!</blockquote><p data-cy="paragraph">Borderlands 4 is currently on a mixed Steam review rating, with most of the negative comments revolving around PC performance. The tech experts at <a href="https://www.patreon.com/digitalfoundry" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Digital Foundry</u></a> have said <a href="https://youtu.be/2v1ST5qMoaY?feature=shared" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>their initial analysis of Borderlands 4 on PC</u></a> shows significant stutter problems, and have advised against running the game on its ‘Badass’ graphics setting, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/tech-experts-say-borderlands-4-on-pc-runs-worse-than-usual-for-an-unreal-engine-5-game-advise-against-badass-setting"><u>which suggests there are indeed problems with the Unreal Engine 5 title</u></a>. From the look of the patch notes, the focus here is on crashes, rather than performance issues. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-patch-due-out-today-pc-performance-our-top-priority-gearbox-says">Gearbox recently said PC performance problems were its "top priority,"</a> so hopefully more to come on that front soon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the meantime, Gearbox has posted a Borderlands 4 Nvidia Optimization guide on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1285190/view/679602429802577921" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Steam</u></a>, advising players how to optimize their graphics settings for “better performance and framerates” on PC with the Nvidia app, although users report mixed results.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Gearbox has also issued a piece of advice to PC gamers that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-dev-gearbox-asks-pc-gamers-to-keep-playing-for-at-least-15-minutes-after-they-tweak-settings-to-see-how-performance-has-changed-as-negative-steam-reviews-pile-up"><u>to me reads like an effort to prevent players from making knee-jerk reactions to the game's performance as soon as they’ve changed their settings</u></a>: “Please note that any time you change any of your graphics settings, your shaders will need to recompile. Please keep playing for at least 15 minutes to see how your PC's performance has changed.”</p><div id="borderlands-4-all-vault-hunter-skill-trees-ranked" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Borderlands 4: All Vault Hunter Skill Trees Ranked</h3><h3>Borderlands 4: All Vault Hunter Skill Trees Ranked</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">While this patch mentions the PC version, there’s no word on improvements to the performance of Borderlands 4 on console. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-performance-gets-worse-the-longer-you-play-on-console-randy-pitchford-suggests-quitting-the-game-and-restarting-as-a-workaround">Console players have reported performance getting worse the longer they play</a>, suggesting Borderlands 4 suffers from a memory leak issue. Gearbox development chief Randy Pitchford has said Gearbox is looking into this one on PS5 Pro specifically, but it doesn’t look like a fix is in place just yet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And there are no balance changes yet, which means <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/abuse-it-while-you-can-borderlands-4-has-an-infinite-damage-build-so-broken-it-kills-bosses-in-seconds">those overpowered builds of yours are safe</a>… for now.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Borderlands 4 September 18, 2025 update patch notes:</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Stability </h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Addressed crashes tied to animation states, audio, and collision checks</li><li>Addressed various GPU-related crashes</li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Gameplay &amp; Progression </h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Resolved an issue where the Reward Center could stop working after claiming the Gilded Glory Pack rewards</li><li>Addressed a progression blocker in the mission “Talk to Zadra,” where the objective could fail if players exited and relaunched mid-dialogue</li><li>Corrected “Doesn’t own DLC” warnings incorrectly showing up on non-DLC gear<ul data-cy="list"><li>This will be fixed on consoles in the coming days.</li></ul></li></ul><h3 data-cy="title3">Loot &amp; Items </h3><ul data-cy="list"><li>Updated loot pools so Gilded Glory Pack guns no longer appear in standard chests</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/borderlands-4-september-18-update-improves-stability-on-pc-and-smooths-out-progression-but-according-to-the-patch-notes-balance-changes-will-have-to-wait]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia, Intel to co-develop “multiple generations” of chips as part of $5 billion deal]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/09/nvidia-will-invest-5-billion-in-intel-co-develop-new-server-and-pc-chips/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nvidia-intel-to-co-develop-%E2%80%9Cmultiple-generations%E2%80%9D-of-chips-as-part-of-5-billion-deal.1301910/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main">
            <article data-id="2117760">
  
  <header>
  <div>
    

    

    <p>
      Intel once considered buying Nvidia outright, but its fortunes have shifted.
    </p>

    

    

    
  </div>
</header>


  

  
      
    
    <div>
                      
                      
          
<p>In a major collaboration that would have been hard to imagine just a few years ago, Nvidia <a href="https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-and-intel-to-develop-ai-infrastructure-and-personal-computing-products">announced today</a> that it was buying a total of $5 billion in Intel stock, giving Intel's competitor ownership of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/18/business/nvidia-intel-stake.html">roughly 4 percent of the company</a>. In addition to the investment, the two companies said that they would be co-developing "multiple generations of custom data center and PC products."</p>
<p>"The companies will focus on seamlessly connecting NVIDIA and Intel architectures using NVIDIA NVLink," reads Nvidia's press release, "integrating the strengths of NVIDIA’s AI and accelerated computing with Intel’s leading CPU technologies and x86 ecosystem to deliver cutting-edge solutions for customers."</p>
<p>Rather than combining the two companies' technologies, the data center chips will apparently be custom x86 chips that Intel builds to Nvidia's specifications. Nvidia will "integrate [the CPUs] into its AI infrastructure platforms and offer [them] to the market."</p>
<p>On the consumer side, Intel plans to build x86 SoCs that integrate both Intel CPUs and Nvidia RTX GPU chiplets—Intel's current products use graphics chiplets based on its own Arc products. More tightly integrated chips could make for smaller gaming laptops and could give Nvidia a way to get into handheld gaming PCs like the Steam Deck or ROG Xbox Ally.</p>
<p>On a conference call with Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang and Intel CEO Lip-Bu Tan this afternoon, the CEOs said that the technical collaboration between teams at Nvidia and Intel had been ongoing for nearly a year, though neither company was ready to announce any products or get specific about launch windows. Chip designs can sometimes take years to come together, so it could still be months or years before the first products to come out of this partnership are actually available to buy.</p>

          
                      
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>Huang estimated that the partnership would be worth between $25 and $50 billion of "annual opportunity," once the products begin shipping, though it wasn't clear how much of that money would show up on Nvidia's balance sheet and how much would show up on Intel's.</p>
<h2>A dramatic reversal</h2>
<p>Back in 2005, Intel <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/24/technology/intel-ai-chips-mistakes.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share&amp;referringSource=articleShare">considered</a> buying Nvidia outright for “as much as $20 billion,” according to The New York Times. At the time, Nvidia was known almost exclusively for its GeForce consumer graphics chips, and Intel was nearing the launch of its Core and Core 2 chips, which would manage to win Apple’s business and set it up for a decade of near-total dominance in consumer PCs and servers.</p>
<p>But in recent years, Nvidia’s income and market capitalization have soared on the strength of its data center chips, which have powered most of the AI features that tech companies have been racing to build into their products for years now. And Intel’s recent struggles are well-documented—it has struggled for years now to improve its chip manufacturing capabilities at the same pace as competitors like TSMC, and a yearslong effort to convince other chip designers to use Intel’s factories to build their chips has yielded <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/12/intel-ceo-pat-gelsinger-steps-down-after-terrible-no-good-very-bad-year/">one ousted CEO</a> and not much else.</p>
<p>The two companies' announcement comes one day after China <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/09/china-blocks-sale-of-nvidia-ai-chips/">banned the sale of Nvidia's AI chips</a>, including products that Nvidia had designed specifically for China to get around US-imposed performance-based export controls. China is pushing domestic chipmakers like Huawei and Cambricon to put out their own AI accelerators to compete with Nvidia's.</p>
<p>Correlation isn't causation, and Intel and Nvidia didn't throw together a $5 billion deal and product collaboration in the space of less than 24 hours. But Nvidia could be looking to prop up US-based chip manufacturing as a counterweight to China's actions.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>There are domestic political considerations for Nvidia, too. The Trump administration <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/intel-agrees-to-sell-the-us-a-10-stake-trump-says-hyping-great-deal/">announced plans to take a 10 percent stake</a> in Intel last month, and Nvidia's Huang has worked to curry favor with the Trump administration by making appearances at $1 million-per-plate dinners at Trump's Mar-a-Lago golf course and <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/07/trump-caving-on-nvidia-h20-export-curbs-may-disrupt-his-bigger-trade-war/">promising to invest billions in US-based data centers</a>.</p>
<p>Although the US government's investment in Intel hasn't gotten it seats on the company's board, the investment <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/intel-details-everything-that-could-go-wrong-with-us-taking-a-10-stake/">comes with possible significant downsides for Intel</a>, including disruptions to the company's business outside the US and limiting its eligibility for future government grants. Trump and his administration could also decide to alter the deal for any or no reason—Trump was calling for Tan's resignation for alleged Chinese Communist Party ties <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/08/president-trump-says-intels-new-ceo-must-resign-immediately/">just days before</a> deciding to invest in the company instead. Investing in a sometime-competitor may be a small price for Nvidia and Huang to pay if it means avoiding the administration's ire.</p>
<p>Huang said on the joint conference call that the Trump administration had been told about the deal but that it wasn't involved in talks between the two companies.</p>
<p>"The Trump administration had no involvement in this partnership at all," said Huang. "They would have been very supportive, of course. Today I had the opportunity to tell Secretary [of Commerce Howard] Lutnick, and he was excited, very supportive of seeing American technology companies working together."</p>

<h2>Outstanding questions abound</h2>
<p>Combining Intel CPUs and Nvidia GPUs makes a lot of sense for certain kinds of products—the two companies' chips already coexist in millions of gaming desktops and laptops. Being able to make custom SoCs that combine Intel's and Nvidia's technology could result in smaller and more power-efficient gaming PCs. It could also provide a counterbalance to AMD, whose willingness to build semi-custom x86-based SoCs has earned the company most of the emerging market for Steam Deck-esque handheld gaming PCs, plus multiple generations of PlayStation and Xbox console hardware.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>
          
          
<p>But there are more than a few places where Intel's and Nvidia's products compete, and at this early date, it's unclear what will happen to the areas of overlap.</p>
<figure>
    
          <figcaption>
        <div>
    
    <p>
      Future Intel CPUs could use an Nvidia-designed graphics chiplet instead of one of Intel's GPUs.

              <span>
          Credit:

          
          Intel

                  </span>
          </p>
  </div>
      </figcaption>
      </figure>

<p>For example, Intel has been developing its own graphics products for decades—historically, these have mostly been lower-performance integrated GPUs whose only job is to connect to a couple of monitors and encode and decode video. But more recent Arc-branded dedicated graphics cards and integrated GPUs have been more of a direct challenge to some of Nvidia's lower-end products.</p>
<p>Intel told Ars that the company "will continue to have GPU product offerings," which means that it will likely continue developing Arc and its underlying Intel Xe GPU architecture. But that could mean that Intel will focus on low-end, low-power GPUs and leave higher-end products to Nvidia. Intel has been <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/07/alive-after-all-intel-is-handing-its-nuc-mini-pc-business-over-to-asus/">happy</a> to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2023/04/intel-introduced-bitcoin-mining-chips-a-year-ago-and-theyre-already-going-away/">discard</a> money-losing side projects in recent years, and dedicated Arc GPUs have struggled to make much of a dent in the GPU market.</p>
<p>On the software side, Intel has been pushing its own <a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/developer/tools/oneapi/overview.html">oneAPI graphics</a> compute stack as an alternative to Nvidia's CUDA and AMD's ROCm&nbsp;and has provided code to help migrate CUDA projects to oneAPI. And there's a whole range of plausible outcomes here: Nvidia allowing Intel GPUs to run CUDA code, either directly or through some kind of translation layer; Nvidia contributing to oneAPI, which is an open source platform; or oneAPI fading away entirely.</p>
<p>On Nvidia's side, we've already mentioned that the company offers some Arm-based CPUs—these are available in the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/01/nvidias-first-desktop-pc-can-run-local-ai-models-for-3000/">Project DIGITS AI computer</a>, <a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/solutions/autonomous-vehicles/">Nvidia's automotive products</a>, or the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/04/nvidia-confirms-the-switch-2-supports-dlss-g-sync-and-ray-tracing/">Nintendo Switch and Switch 2</a>. Nvidia is also said to be working on some Arm products that haven't been announced yet, including <a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/cpus/nvidia-and-mediatek-may-unveil-jointly-developed-n1-arm-chips-for-windows-pcs-at-computex">Arm-based chips for Windows PCs</a> that it's said to be co-developing with MediaTek.</p>

          
                  </div>
                    
        
          
    
    <div>

        
        <div>
          
          
<p>Huang said that the partnership with Intel would have no bearing on its Arm products and that development on those products would continue.</p>
<p>"We're fully committed to the Arm roadmap," Huang said, mentioning a number of upcoming products, including future generations of <a href="https://nvidianews.nvidia.com/news/nvidia-unveils-rubin-cpx-a-new-class-of-gpu-designed-for-massive-context-inference">its Vera CPU architecture</a>.</p>
<p>Finally, there's the question of where these chips will be built. Nvidia's current chips are manufactured mostly at TSMC, though it has used Samsung's factories as recently as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GeForce_RTX_30_series">RTX 3000 series</a>. Intel also uses TSMC to build some chips, including its current top-end laptop and desktop processors, but it uses its own factories to build its server chips and plans to bring its next-generation consumer chips back in-house.</p>
<p>Will Nvidia start to manufacture some of its chips on Intel's 18A manufacturing process or another process on Intel's roadmap? A vote of confidence from Nvidia would be a big shot in the arm for Intel's foundry, which has reportedly struggled to find major customers—but it's hard to see Nvidia doing it if Intel's manufacturing processes can't compete with TSMC's on performance or power consumption, or if Intel can't manufacture chips in the volumes that Nvidia would need.</p>
<p>Huang didn't close the door to working with Intel on manufacturing but responded to multiple questions about it by heaping praise on TSMC, suggesting that the manufacturer was a known quantity that Nvidia was in no rush to stop working with.</p>
<p>"We've always evaluated Intel's foundry technology, and we're going to continue to do that," said Huang. "I think Lip-Bu and I would both say that TSMC is a world-class foundry, and in fact, we're both very successful customers of TSMC's. The capabilities of TSMC, from process technology, their rhythm of execution, the scale of their capacity and infrastructure, the agility of their business operations... just all of the magic that comes together for being a world-class foundry, supporting customers of such diverse needs. I just can't overstate the magic that is TSMC."</p>
<p><em>This article was updated to add details from a conference call with Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang and Intel CEO Lip-Bu Tan.</em></p>


          
                  </div>

                  
          






  <div>
    

    <p>
      Andrew is a Senior Technology Reporter at Ars Technica, with a focus on consumer tech including computer hardware and in-depth reviews of operating systems like Windows and macOS. Andrew lives in Philadelphia and co-hosts a weekly book podcast called <a href="https://overduepodcast.com/">Overdue</a>.
    </p>
  </div>


  <p>
    <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/09/nvidia-will-invest-5-billion-in-intel-co-develop-new-server-and-pc-chips/#comments" title="39 comments">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 80 80"><defs><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__a"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath><clipPath id="bubble-zero_svg__b"><path fill="none" stroke-width="0" d="M0 0h80v80H0z"></path></clipPath></defs><g clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__a)"><g fill="currentColor" clip-path="url(#bubble-zero_svg__b)"><path d="M80 40c0 22.09-17.91 40-40 40S0 62.09 0 40 17.91 0 40 0s40 17.91 40 40"></path><path d="M40 40 .59 76.58C-.67 77.84.22 80 2.01 80H40z"></path></g></g></svg>
    39 Comments
  </a>
      </p>
              </div>
  </article>


  


  


  
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/09/nvidia-will-invest-5-billion-in-intel-co-develop-new-server-and-pc-chips/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battlefield 6's Aim-Assist Is "Very Light"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6s-aim-assist-is-very-light/1100-6534867/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/battlefield-6s-aim-assist-is-very-light.1301907/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6534867">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Like many FPS games on console, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6526583/" data-ref-id="1100-6526583">Battlefield 6</a> will feature aim-assist--and the developer claims it will be "very light." That may make it feel different to Call of Duty, which is known to have a more detectable and significant aim-assist system that players have long complained about.</p><p>Battlefield 6 senior combat designer Matthew Nickerson told <a href="https://www.well-played.com.au/battlefield-6-aims-to-be-a-stable-fair-and-balanced-multiplayer-experience-no-matter-where-you-choose-to-play/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">WellPlayed</a> that the team came up with a new setup they're calling Aim Assist 2.0. "It's an evolution of what we had in Battlefield 2042," Nickerson said, adding that the team is using "real-time" renders in Battlefield 6 to improve aim-assist.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="324077990" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6466351,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;This%20is%20the%20Battlefield%206%20I%E2%80%99ve%20Been%20Waiting%20For&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:628,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/this-is-the-battlefield-6-ive-been-waiting-for\/2300-6466351\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466351\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466351\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6466351\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6466351&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6466351,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6534867&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;battlefield-6,call-of-duty-black-ops-7&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,first-person,shooter,tactical&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;battlefield,call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;battlefield,call-of-duty&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6466351},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6466351\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1862\/18620770\/4569315-handson_bf6_operationfirestorm_v3.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/HgDsBzRv.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1758121200,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="HgDsBzRv" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> This is the Battlefield 6 I’ve Been Waiting For</p>
      </div>
<p>"We've really upped the level of consistency and performance across the board. We're going very light with aim assist. We're not adding rotational aim assist; we actually removed snap zoom, which was in 2042, as we believed it was too mechanically heavy. We want to humanize aim assist, as we call it here internally."</p><p>The goal of aim assist in Battlefield 6 is to simply assist the player, Nickerson said, and not feel like the controls are being taken out of their hands when it switches on.</p><p>"We need player input to even activate the system. We want the player to feel good about what they're doing in-game, achieving those kills, and they feel like <i>they </i>achieved it," Nickerson said. "Not some system or code that achieved it for them.</p><p>Nickerson acknowledged that aim assist is a "hot topic" in the FPS space. "We're really excited about the solution we have, and we're focused on what we feel works best for Battlefield," he said.</p><p>Battlefield 6 launches on October 10 for PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and PC. A <a href="https://x.com/ModernWarzone/status/1968006588784058548" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">battle royale mode</a> is in development as well, and it <a href="https://x.com/ModernWarzone/status/1968006588784058548" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">could launch on October 28.</a></p><p>In other news, EA and Battlefield Studios recently clarified <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6-heres-how-cross-play-works-for-console-and-pc/1100-6534832/" data-ref-id="1100-6534832">how cross-play works</a>, while a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/see-battlefield-6s-biggest-launch-map-in-action/1100-6534835/" data-ref-id="1100-6534835">lot of gameplay footage from the new map, Mirak Valley, has come online. </a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/battlefield-6s-aim-assist-is-very-light/1100-6534867/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>