<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 11:03:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Loss & Acceptance through the lens of Tell Me Why]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/15/loss-acceptance-through-the-lens-of-tell-me-why/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/loss-acceptance-through-the-lens-of-tell-me-why.1218837/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/15/loss-acceptance-through-the-lens-of-tell-me-why/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Life is complicated. No matter how much you do to make your life as easy as possible there will be moments of loss. This can be through so many avenues such as the loss of innocence, the loss of family, the loss of a bond, or the loss of your own self. Dontnod’s 2020 title Tell Me Why explores the themes of loss along with acceptance, including the impact these have on our beliefs and relationships.</p>
<p><em>As is traditional through Pride Month every year, Dontnod and Xbox have made Tell Me Why free to download and keep, available across <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/tell-me-why-chapters-1-3/9NF83PRZK6K3/0010/9MVX2Z790F69">Xbox, Xbox on PC</a> and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1180660/Tell_Me_Why/">Steam</a>.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="Tell Me Why Accolades Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vYrc29kve1U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Tell Me Why tells the story of siblings Alyson and Tyler as they piece together the night of their mother’s death and navigate having been separated for a decade. The game also explores each character’s sense of identity and we come into their journey which has been going of for years for both. Tyler’s is about his self-identity and growing into a life of being a transgender man, while Alyson’s life has been one of avoiding facing the events of the fateful night.</p>
<p>Family means different things to different people. The most common is that family is those who you are related to and have grown up with, but others have a much broader definition where it can be the people you have chosen to be in your life as well. Regardless of who you count as your family, the loss of a family member is devastating. A lot of Tell Me Why’s story is told through replaying memories that Tyler and Alyson have of their mother – it is likely that you would do the same when someone you are close to dies, and it is also my own experience of losing a parent. While life moves on, you will be hit by those moments when you least expect them.</p>

<p>What Tell Me Why also touches on is the fallibility of memory, and how we all remember things in our own way. The way each of us remembers things impacts how we view our relationships. In Tell Me Why, Tyler remembers his mum as being against his trans identity, cold towards him, and angry, but Alyson remembers her as more of tragic character that was falling apart and was softly spoken. The unreliability of memory is a loss in itself, because we lose a true reflection of the experiences that shape us.</p>

<p>Relationship bonds are also a key part of Tell Me Why, with the twins attempting to reestablish their own bond, while Tyler is also looking at his ties with the people that were closest to his mother. One of those characters is Tessa, their mother’s former best friend and a devout Christian. What we learn from events is that she is struggling with accepting the LGBTQ community generally, and her relationship with Tyler who she has loved as a child. We can all-too-easily lose relationships that are important to us because other beliefs come in to override them, but even without dogma coming between us, the majority of people will have had relationships that simply peter out. It can be as simple as losing touch as people move on to new pastures.</p>
<p>Where there is loss, there can be acceptance. That does not necessarily mean what you are accepting is something positive, but that you’re taking the situation for what it is. Alyson and Tyler retread their past, dealing with the beliefs of those around them, learning about the events that have surrounded their childhood and dogged them ever since. Accepting a situation that has does not meet your own expectations or beliefs can be viewed as a loss, but it can be a stepping stone.</p>

<p>The ending of Tell Me Why brings Alyson and Tyler to a place where they can truly start to heal and build their lives. Right now, there are a lot of groups that have been hit by loss as societal views and politics in many countries swing ever rightwards. We have seen the trans community increasingly shunned by the establishment, and this shift being celebrated, we have seen asylum seekers demonised for decades, and we have seen people from ethnic minority groups get attacked and abused due to misinformation. What has to be accepted is that hateful rhetoric and punching down is a form of winning for those that perpetuate it, and that those in charge are largely okay with this. Those of us who belong to groups on the receiving end have to accept that, because once we accept this loss we can regroup and push back. On the flip side, those who back or vote for those who push the hateful rhetoric and punching down have to accept the fact that even if they view themselves as good people, fundamentally they are not. You cannot be okay with alienating, discriminating, and attacking the smallest and most vulnerable groups in society and claim to be good.</p>
<p>Life is complicated. Sometimes you will have to accept a loss in life, take the bruising, to get to a place where you can heal and be stronger. Be like Alyson and Tyler, who suffer loss but in the end, depending on your choice, accept themselves for who they are and in turn help heal the wounds in their community making life better for all.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 4 Is Made with Console-First Approach; 60 FPS on Xbox Series S Will Be ‘Extremely Challenging’ to Achieve, Says CDPR]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-4-is-made-with-console-first-approach-60-fps-on-xbox-series-s-will-be-extremely-challenging-to-achieve-says-cdpr/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-witcher-4-is-made-with-console-first-approach-60-fps-on-xbox-series-s-will-be-%E2%80%98extremely-challenging%E2%80%99-to-achieve-says-cdpr.1218834/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-4-is-made-with-console-first-approach-60-fps-on-xbox-series-s-will-be-extremely-challenging-to-achieve-says-cdpr/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Following the <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-new-trailer-ps5-60-fps-ray-tracing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stunning The Witcher 4 demo</a> shown during the State of Unreal presentation earlier this month, Digital Foundry's Alex Battaglia had the unique opportunity to fly to Poland and meet CD Projekt RED (and Epic) to discuss what went into the demo and what kind of work the studio has ahead of itself for the full game.</p>
<p>During the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OplYN2MMI4Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener">lengthy interview</a>, Charles Tremblay, VP of Technology at CD Projekt RED, revealed that the team switched to a console-first approach to development to achieve its ambitious goal of delivering an open world game with hardware ray tracing running at 60 frames per second on a Sony PlayStation 5 console. This will be easier than scaling down, which the studio had to do with their previous projects.</p>
<p><em>When we started the collaboration, we had super high ambitions for this project. We always do PC and we push and then we try to scale down, but then we had so many problems in the past that we</em><br>
<em>tried to see, okay, this time around we really want to be more of a console first development. Then we worked with Unreal and we saw the challenge to realize the ambition that to make what we want, 60 fps on PS5, there would be work. This is why we started to talk, to figure out what needs to be done with the technology and we also decided, okay, we need to have all those things that need to be developed. Where we go from there, it's hard to say, but right now we really wanted to focus on what does it mean to make this ambition on a console. We&nbsp;really wanted to aim for 60 fps and not go back to 30 fps.</em></p>
<p><em>At this stage, we are perfectly aware that we still have a lot of work ahead of us. This is a tech demo, not the whole gameplay loop is implemented, there's no combat, there's a lot of things that don't work, but still, the ambition is set, so this is where we want to aim for The Witcher 4. It's too early to say if we manage to nail it, but we'll work as hard as we can to make it for sure.</em></p>
<p>The PS5 is not, however, the lowest of current-generation consoles when it comes to hardware performance. There's the Xbox Series S, and Tremblay admitted that the developers haven't begun to optimize The Witcher 4 for it yet, adding that it will be 'extremely challenging' to get it to run at 60 fps.</p>
<p><em>I wish we did a lot of work already on that, but we did not, so this is something that is next on our radar for sure. I will say that 60 FPS will definitely be extremely challenging on Xbox Series S. Let's just say that this is something that we need to figure out.</em></p>
<p>Interestingly, Epic considers software Lumen ray tracing to be a thing of the past due to several limitations, which is why the demo created for The Witcher 4 already implements hardware RT Lumen. CD Projekt RED, on the other hand, mentioned that they'll want to scale up for a high-end PC, although the form that scaling will take remains to be seen at this point.</p>
<p>The Witcher 4 will likely be <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-witcher-iv-wont-launch-until-2027-says-cd-projekt-red/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> in 2027 for PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series S|X. Stay tuned to Wccftech for the latest rumors and reveals.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: Box Art Brawl - Jet Set Radio (Dreamcast)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-box-art-brawl-jet-set-radio-dreamcast</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/poll-box-art-brawl-jet-set-radio-dreamcast.1218831/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-box-art-brawl-jet-set-radio-dreamcast<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The concept of love</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Jet Set Radio - BAB" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/33a1c78fb105b/jet-set-radio-bab.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>Hello folks, and welcome to another edition of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/tags/box-art-brawl">Box Art Brawl</a>.</p>
<p>Before we get cracking, let's see how things panned out last time, hm? We looked at <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/3ds/super_street_fighter_iv_3d_edition">Super Street Fighter IV 3D Edition</a> for the 3DS. North America and Europe joined forces on this one, and together, they managed to bag an impressive 72% of the vote. Well done, indeed.</p>
<p>This week, we're back with the Dreamcast to check out <a href="https://www.timeextension.com/games/dreamcast/jet_set_radio">Jet Set Radio</a> (originally known as <strong>Jet Grind Radio</strong> in the US). Released in 2000, it went on to spawn a sequel and became one of the finest cult classics of the modern age, with an exceptional soundtrack to boot.</p>
<p>It's a full-on three-way brawl this week, so let's get to it!</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:159585,160025 @ 1749984117 -->
<p><em>Be sure to cast your votes in the poll below; but first, let's check out the box art designs themselves.</em></p>
<h2>North America</h2>
<figure><a title="Jet Set Radio - NA" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/717ed2931d893/jet-set-radio-na.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://gamesdb.launchbox-app.com/games/details/30-jet-grind-radio">Sega / Launch Box</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>All three cover designs showcase the main protagonist, Beat, front and centre. North America's approach is a little darker, overall, but the purple, red, and green work really well together.</p>
<h2>Europe</h2>
<figure><a title="Jet Set Radio - EU" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/14eb879dbb811/jet-set-radio-eu.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://gamesdb.launchbox-app.com/games/details/30-jet-grind-radio">Sega / Launch Box</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Europe's design is a little bit lighter and brighter, potentially leaning into the overall theme of the Dreamcast itself. Beat's striking a pretty cool pose in this one, and we like that it makes the roller blade traversal obvious.</p>
<h2>Japan</h2>
<figure><a title="Jet Set Radio - JP" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/cc2e7c9b41465/jet-set-radio-jp.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: <a href="https://gamesdb.launchbox-app.com/games/details/30-jet-grind-radio">Sega / Launch Box</a></em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Good lord, what's going on here? We love it! Very abstract. Beat is completely absent of any colour, and instead, the background is made up of lots of different graffiti images, with the main logo appearing just below Beat's spray can. So cool.</p>
<hr>

<p><em>Thanks for voting! We'll see you next time for another round of Box Art Brawl.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Nintendo Life’s resident horror fanatic, when he’s not knee-deep in Resident Evil and Silent Hill lore, Ollie likes to dive into a good horror book while nursing a lovely cup of tea. He also enjoys long walks and listens to everything from TOOL to Chuck Berry.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Olliemar28"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ollie-nl.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Olliemar28');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Fortnite's Switch 2 Release Will Be Followed By A New Game Mode Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/lego-fortnites-switch-2-release-will-be-followed-by-a-new-game-mode-next-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-fortnites-switch-2-release-will-be-followed-by-a-new-game-mode-next-week.1218813/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/lego-fortnites-switch-2-release-will-be-followed-by-a-new-game-mode-next-week<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Get ready to "power-up" in Expeditions</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>The free-to-play title <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/lego_fortnite">LEGO Fortnite</a> has gone down quite well with LEGO and Fortnite fans, and Epic Games continues to enhance the experience with all sorts of new updates.</p>
<p>The latest reveal is a new teaser for <strong>LEGO Expeditions</strong>. Epic has released a trailer describing how players will suit up, squad up and power up next week on <strong>18th June</strong>, but beyond this, nothing else has been revealed just yet.</p>
<p>Fans are convinced it's going to lead into an "expanded universe" or even a "multiverse" style offering. It will follow on from modes like <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/@epic/lego-fortnite-odyssey?lang=en-US">Lego Fortnite Odyssey</a> and <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/@epic/lego-fortnite-brick-life">Lego Fortnite Brick Life</a>. When we find out more about this new mode, we'll let you know.</p><p><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><a id="yt-3" title="Play" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA"></a><figcaption>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>822k</span></a></figcaption><figcaption><a title="Watch This Video on YouTube" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1rrCdi_XjA">Watch on <strong><span></span> YouTube</strong> <span></span></a></figcaption></figure></p>
<p>LEGO Fortnite originally made its debut on the Switch in 2023 alongside <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/rocket_racing">Rocket Racing</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/fortnite_festival">Fortnite Festival</a>, and is Epic's way of expanding the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fortnite">Fortnite</a> universe. Epic also recently released a free Switch 2 version of Fortnite, and you can find out how LEGO Fortnite and the existing game modes run on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/fortnite">Switch 2 in our Nintendo Life review</a>.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183666 @ 1749983963 -->
<p>Have you tried out LEGO Fortnite yet? What do you think of it? How about Fortnite in genearl? <em>Let us know.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Totaka's Song Appears To Have Been Found In Mario Kart World]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/totakas-song-appears-to-have-been-found-in-mario-kart-world</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/totakas-song-appears-to-have-been-found-in-mario-kart-world.1218804/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/totakas-song-appears-to-have-been-found-in-mario-kart-world<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The famous Nintendo tune returns</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure><a title="Mario Kart World" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/281807c674aa4/mario-kart-world.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Nintendo mentioned how there were all sorts of surprises to discover in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> and a week after the game's launch it looks like Totaka's Song has been discovered.</p>
<p>As highlighted on social media and elsewhere online (via Nintendo Everything), you can hear Yoshi humming this Nintendo tune in the game's character menu. Here's a story and video shared over on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/mariokart/comments/1la5xcm/totakas_song_in_mario_kart_world/">Mario Kart subreddit by the user 'charizardtelephone'</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"I was idling on the character select screen when I noticed Mario began humming after enough time passed. I thought, “Huh, they could totally hide hidden tunes like that.” Wait. Hidden music? In a Nintendo game? With Yoshi? It was too good to be true. But after a few seconds, lo and behold, yoshi begins humming Totaka’s song like the idle yoshis do in Mario Kart 8. Very cool Easter Egg. Not sure if anyone else has noticed it yet."</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>

<p>When we tried this out ourselves, Yoshi started humming the same song just seconds later. It might also be a bit harder to hear depending on the music playing in the background.</p>
<p>This famous song by the Japanese Nintendo composer Kazumi Totaka is often slipped into many of company's games. And if you're wondering why it's specifically Yoshi that hums this tune, it's because Totaka also happens to be Yoshi's voice actor, and once again voices the character in Mario Kart World.</p>
<p>This Easter Egg has also popped up previously in Mario Kart 8 along with series like <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/gamecube/animal_crossing">Animal Crossing</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/legend_of_zelda_links_awakening">Zelda</a>, and was inserted into titles such as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/mario_paint">Mario Paint</a> back in the day.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:183558,91899,183188 @ 1749983303 -->
<p>Have you heard this tune in Mario Kart World yet? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://nintendoeverything.com/mario-kart-world-totakas-song-easter-egg/" rel="noopener" href="https://nintendoeverything.com/mario-kart-world-totakas-song-easter-egg/">nintendoeverything.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/3e5b133501685c0a2330646cb7ca4830 @ 1749984273 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2's Best-Selling eShop Games So Far]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/switch-2s-best-selling-eshop-games-so-far</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/switch-2s-best-selling-eshop-games-so-far.1218798/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/06/switch-2s-best-selling-eshop-games-so-far<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>The first week comes to a close</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="Cyberpunk 2077" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/81f77135db57e/cyberpunk-2077.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: CD Projekt Red</em></figcaption></figure><p>It's now been more than a week since the arrival of the Switch 2, so we've taken another quick look at the US eShop "best sellers" chart to see what users are buying as of 14th July 2025.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> once again takes out the top spot and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk 2077</a> has moved up the ladder to second place, with the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a> upgrade pack in third. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-time-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Fantasy Life</a> is also higher on the list and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/no-mans-sky-nintendo-switch-2-edition">No Man's Sky</a> has entered the top ten after its Switch 2 Edition update (it's also on sale right now).</p>
<h3>Switch 2 eShop Best-Sellers</h3>
<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition">Cyberpunk 2077</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Zelda: The Tears of the Kingdom</a> (Upgrade Pack)</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fantasy-life-i-the-girl-who-steals-time-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Fantasy Life: The Girl Who Steals Time</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/deltarune">Deltarune</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Zelda: Breath of the Wild</a> (Upgrade Pack)</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour">Welcome Tour</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/no-mans-sky-nintendo-switch-2-edition">No Man's Sky</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/bravely-default-flying-fairy-hd-remaster">Bravely Default: Flying Fairy HD Remaster</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/street-fighter-6-years-1-2-fighters-edition">Street Fighter 6</a></strong></li>
</ol>
<p>As for download titles in this same location, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour">Welcome Tour</a> has dropped from first to second, with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/deltarune">Deltarune</a> taking out the top spot. The other games on this list have also been in the top nine over the past week:</p>
<h3>Switch 2 eShop Best-Sellers (Download-Only Games)</h3>
<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/deltarune">Deltarune</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/nintendo-switch-2-welcome-tour">Welcome Tour</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fast-fusion">Fast Fusion</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kunitsu-gami-path-of-the-goddess">Kunitsu-Gami: Path of the Goddess</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/survival-kids">Survival Kids</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/suikoden-iandii-hd-remaster-for-nintendo-switch-2-gate-rune-and-dunan-unification-wars">Suikoden I &amp; II HD Remaster</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/arcade-archives-2-ridge-racer">Ridge Racer</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/nobunagas-ambition-awakening-complete-edition">Nobunaga's Ambition: Awakening Complete Edition</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/wild-hearts-s">Wild Hearts S</a> (pre-order)</strong></li>
</ol>
<p>Keep in mind this is just one region and depending on your location, your Switch 2 eShop's top-selling games might look a bit different. Still, this provides an idea of what people are buying in the launch week of Nintendo's new system.</p>
<p>In the UK, the lists are mostly the same - with Mario Kart in first, Cyberpunk in second, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/fast-fusion">Fast Fusion</a> is in third place overall, No Man's Sky has also entered the top ten, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/puyo-puyo-tetris-2s">Puyo Puyo Tetris 2S</a> is listed as one of the most downloaded eShop titles in this location as well.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:182523,183063,183429 @ 1749981820 -->
<p>Have you bought any games from the Switch 2 eShop yet? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA Online's next update will let you pull off a classic, if slightly dull, type of crime: money laundering]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-onlines-next-update-will-let-you-pull-off-a-classic-if-slightly-dull-type-of-crime-money-laundering</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-onlines-next-update-will-let-you-pull-off-a-classic-if-slightly-dull-type-of-crime-money-laundering.1218717/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-onlines-next-update-will-let-you-pull-off-a-classic-if-slightly-dull-type-of-crime-money-laundering<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Laundry everyone can get behind</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rockstar</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I feel like money laundering is one of those concepts you see in a lot of crime TV shows but it's not really something that seems to come up much in games. I certainly can't think of any games that feature money laundering as an actual mechanic, but I'll be able to add one to the list next week: <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/gta-online">GTA Online</a>. The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-multiplayer-games-on-pc">multiplayer</a> game is getting a new update this coming June 17th called <a href="https://www.rockstargames.com/newswire/article/513kao973a73ko/gta-online-money-fronts-coming-june-17">Money Fronts</a>, and is literally all about buying up small but generally lucrative businesses that you can sneak some money through.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
There's a few businesses you'll be able to pick up but you'll be starting off with a classic: the car wash, specifically Hands On Car Wash. You'll get passive income through this from your criminal network, eventually allowing you to pick up the Smoke on the Water dispensary and Higgins Helitours, all of which will also bring in their own money from actual, legal business operations.
</p>
<p>
However, with the pro of lots of moola, there is a big con too. Operating these businesses this way will generate heat, and if that gets too high, you'll have to actually step in as the local business owner you're pretending to be to manage these companies the way they're legally meant to be.
</p>
<p>
There's a few new rides you can pick up too, like the Karin Everon RS or the Declasse Tampa GT (Muscle). Money Fronts is also bringing in some gameplay tweaks. More than 50 vehicles will have missile lock-on jammer capability, and all sources of arena points are being doubled. A number of cutscenes will be skippable on mission replays too, though which ones that'll be weren't specified.
</p>
<p>
More details will be coming, uh, at some point, Rockstar just said "stay tuned". You only have to wait a few days for it anyway, you'll live.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Cards, Apple AirPods Pro 2, Clair Obscur: Expedition 33, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-june-14-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-deals-today-magic-the-gathering-final-fantasy-cards-apple-airpods-pro-2-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-more.1218684/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-june-14-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Hugely popular items now back in stock.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-fathers-day-gift-ideas-2025">Father's Day</a> is almost here, and now is the time to score some last-minute gifts, as well as catch some popular item restocks. We've rounded up the best deals for Saturday, June 14, below, so don't miss out on these limited-time offers.</p><div catalogid="46793e9b-346e-43ae-a76b-fa815e1d601e" id="222937"><div id="222937" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Wizard of Legend 2</h3></p></div><h2 data-cy="title2">Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Cards Available at Amazon</h2></div><div id="222944" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="3cd545c5-1d5f-4eb7-be84-a6f92ed62e6d"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Starter Kit</h3></p></div><div catalogid="3cd545c5-1d5f-4eb7-be84-a6f92ed62e6d" id="222945"><div id="222945" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Magic: The Gathering - Final Fantasy Play Booster Box</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Magic: The Gathering finally released its Final Fantasy collaboration this week, and this has been a hugely popular set amongst longtime and new fans. If you've never played Magic: The Gathering before, the Final Fantasy collaboration is the perfect time to jump in. The Starter Kit includes everything a beginner needs, and the Play Booster Box is perfect if you're aiming to pull some rare cards.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Dan Da Dan Season 1 Blu-ray for $24.49</h2></div><div catalogid="2878ac8a-c311-4b06-b554-6cab5ef86d9e" id="218215"><div id="218215" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>DAN DA DAN: Season One</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dan-da-dan-episodes-1-3-review">Dan Da Dan</a> was one of my favorite anime series of 2024, and the fact that you can take home all of Season 1 for just $24.49 is an absolute steal. Following Momo Ayase and Ken Takakura, Dan Da Dan is a comedic adventure that throws together aliens, spirits, and so much more. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Donkey Kong Bananza Now Available to Pre-Order at Amazon</h2></div><div catalogid="3cd545c5-1d5f-4eb7-be84-a6f92ed62e6d" id="222943"><div id="222943" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Donkey Kong Bananza - Nintendo Switch 2</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">For quite a while, Nintendo's first-party games have not been available for purchase at Amazon. That changed yesterday, though, as upcoming Nintendo Switch 2 games like Donkey Kong Bananza finally went live for pre-order. If you've been holding out on pre-ordering one of the biggest Switch 2 games revealed so far, now you have yet another option for retailer. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Apple AirPods Pro for $169</h2></div><div catalogid="acabe714-9dd0-4379-8dd1-849381419322" id="207680"><div id="207680" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Apple AirPods Pro 2 with USB-C</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Apple's newest AirPods are all on sale and would make a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-fathers-day-gift-ideas-2025">great gift idea for Father's Day</a>, which lands on June 15. Starting with the highest end model, the second generation <a href="https://zdcs.link/z7b3jy?object_uuid=beb8000e-4614-4330-9401-25a0eefdf93f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0D1XD1ZV3" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Apple AirPods Pro</a> wireless noise-canceling earbuds is $169 shipped (normally $240). The next step down, the <a href="https://zdcs.link/Qx7mlO?object_uuid=beb8000e-4614-4330-9401-25a0eefdf93f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DGJ7HYG1" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Apple AirPods 4 with ANC</a> (active noise cancelation) is down to $148 (normally $179). Finally, the value-packed <a href="https://zdcs.link/QGVXmq?object_uuid=beb8000e-4614-4330-9401-25a0eefdf93f&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" data-aps-asin="B0DGHMNQ5Z" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">AirPods 4 without ANC</a> drops to $99.99 (normally $129).</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Pre-Order Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter</h2></div><div id="218218" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="2878ac8a-c311-4b06-b554-6cab5ef86d9e"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter - Nintendo Switch</h3></p></div><div catalogid="2878ac8a-c311-4b06-b554-6cab5ef86d9e" id="218219"><div id="218219" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Trails in the Sky 1st Chapter has officially opened pre-orders at Amazon, with both PS5 and Nintendo Switch copies available for $59.99. If you're unfamiliar with the Trails series, this is a remake of the very first Trails game, making 2025 the perfect time to jump into the series for the very first time. NIS America is set to bring the latest game in the series, The Legend of Heroes: Trails Beyond the Horizon, to North America and Europe later this year, which is the first time ever the series will be caught up worldwide.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 for PS5 Is In-Stock</h2></div><div catalogid="3cd545c5-1d5f-4eb7-be84-a6f92ed62e6d" id="222942"><div id="222942" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Clair Obscur Expedition 33 - PS5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">As one of the most popular games of the year, Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 has been very hard to find at retailers, especially for PS5 copies. Today, Amazon has put the PS5 copy of the game in-stock, and you can still score a copy at this time. This is the perfect opportunity to pick up a physical copy if you loved the game, and it's also a great time to enter the world of Clair Obscur if you haven't already.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Darkest Dungeon II for $20.75</h2></div><div catalogid="3cd545c5-1d5f-4eb7-be84-a6f92ed62e6d" id="222946"><div id="222946" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Darkest Dungeon II - PS5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Darkest Dungeon II for PlayStation 5 is just $20.75 at Amazon right now. One of the biggest features and upgrades of this game from its predocessor is the token system, which opens up your gameplay in entirely new ways. This game generally retails for $29.99, so this weekend is a great time to pick it up.</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Jun 14, 2025 6:55 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starlight Re:Volver is an upcoming anime as hell Hades-esque, MMO inspired roguelite that already has the vibe]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/starlight-revolver-is-an-upcoming-anime-as-hell-hades-esque-mmo-inspired-roguelite-that-already-has-the-vibe</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starlight-re-volver-is-an-upcoming-anime-as-hell-hades-esque-mmo-inspired-roguelite-that-already-has-the-vibe.1218675/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/starlight-revolver-is-an-upcoming-anime-as-hell-hades-esque-mmo-inspired-roguelite-that-already-has-the-vibe<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>You'll know the vibe when you feel it</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Pahdo Labs</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I'm not much of an MMO person, I've dabbled over the years like with <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/runescape">RuneScape</a> in my youth, and a bit of Final Fantasy 14. These days it's the level of commitment that puts me off, even though I really do love being able to partake in what feels like living, breathing worlds, the hustle and bustle of actual people going to and fro. Luckily, I think I have a lower-key way to get this kind of feeling in the upcoming action <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-roguelike-games-pc">roguelite</a> Starlight Re:Volver.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Right from the first second of Starlight Re:Volver you'll absolutely be thinking to yourself "oh, this is anime as hell." That'll be offputting to some, maybe, but it does so with such a ridiculous degree of finesse and style, I was won over right out the gate. The core gameplay loop is that you set out on runs with up to three of your friends, going through different rooms with waves of enemies across them, picking up abilities and buffs along the way.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Starlight ReVolver - Official Reveal Trailer (ft. Sarah Bonito)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o8WkNXMExSw?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Starlight ReVolver - Official Reveal Trailer (ft. Sarah Bonito)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o8WkNXMExSw?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/o8WkNXMExSw?autoplay=1" title="Starlight ReVolver - Official Reveal Trailer (ft. Sarah Bonito)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o8WkNXMExSw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
It definitely seems like there's a Hades-like approach to the game, though the demo that's currently available for Steam Next Fest is more like an online playtest above all else. Right now I'd say there's a bit of an onboarding issue, as the game doesn't really do much to tell you much about anything, but with multiple characters to choose from all with unique playstyles, I had a fun enough time in the few runs I went through.
</p>
<p>
All of that can be smoothed over of course, I'm not that worried about that, so the real thing that's pulling me in so far is the vibes. The game's Steam page refers to itself as an "anime-inspired MMO universe", and the game's hub area certainly offers a slice of such a pie up.
</p>
<p>
There's an in-world <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/suika-game">Suika Game</a> rip-off to play, a fishing mini-game, clothes to unlock, different areas to just hang out in. You can see different players running around too, and even if there's not much to do right now, it really does capture that specific feeling of being in a virtual place with a whole bunch of strangers.
</p>
<p>
How that may progress whenever the game comes out, I can't tell you, it's certainly something I hope to see expanded upon. In the meantime, you can wishlist the game on Steam <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3201010/Starlight_ReVolver/">here</a>, and you have until June 16th to try out the demo for yourself.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Peak is a small, goofy co-op climbing game from the devs behind Another Crab's Teasure and Content Warning]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/peak-is-a-small-goofy-co-op-climbing-game-from-the-devs-behind-another-crabs-teasure-and-content-warning</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/peak-is-a-small-goofy-co-op-climbing-game-from-the-devs-behind-another-crabs-teasure-and-content-warning.1218633/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/peak-is-a-small-goofy-co-op-climbing-game-from-the-devs-behind-another-crabs-teasure-and-content-warning<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Aggro Crab/ Landfall</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
It's a crossover episode! Like the great team-ups of the past (Scooby-Doo and Batman, the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles and Batman), <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/totally-accurate-battle-simulator">Totally Accurate Battle Simulator</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/content-warning">Content Warning</a> developer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/landfall-games">Landfall</a>, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/another-crabs-treasure">Another Crab's Treasure</a> developer <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/aggro-crab">Aggro Crab</a> have come to make Peak. As in it's literally called Peak, not a qualitative descriptor that's been more widely adopted into Gen-Z slang that you have to Google because you're not a spring chicken anymore.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Peak is an aptly named game too, as it's all about climbing mountains. This being a game made by both Landfall and Aggro Crab, this obviously comes with a certain amount of silliness. Your virtual avatar is one that I can only describe as a "little guy", who you can apparently customise with different outfits and accessories. It's also playable in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-co-op-games">co-op</a>, in fact that kind of seems to be the main selling point, but you can go solo too.
</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>our new game PEAK is a climbing game with friends where the slightest mistake can spell your doom🗻</p><p>reach the top of the mountain as a group of scouts when it drops JUNE 16‼️ <a href="https://t.co/5EADzD6gWd">pic.twitter.com/5EADzD6gWd</a></p></div>— AGGRO CRAB 💥 (@AggroCrabGames) <a href="https://twitter.com/AggroCrabGames/status/1933541312315236620?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 13, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
The whole goal is to get to the top of the mountain (otherwise known as the peak of the mountain, if I need to spell it out for you), in hopes of being rescued after having crash landed on a mysterious island. There's four biomes to wade through, and along the way you'll have to pick up food to keep yourself going. You can get injured too, so unlike the example provided in the trailer above, you probably shouldn't punt your med kit off the side of a cliff.
</p>
<p>
Interestingly, a majority of the game was made within a one month game jam, so you shouldn't necessarily expect infinite content or whatever it is shareholders want these days. It just looks like a silly, goofy way to hang out with some friends for a few hours. It's also out really soon! June 16th to be precise, so you've only got a couple of days to wait. You can wishlist it on Steam <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3527290/PEAK/">here</a>.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nier: Automata creators deny characters "were problematic overseas" and blame mistranslated subtitle for censorship rumours]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nier-automata-creators-deny-characters-were-problematic-overseas-and-blame-mistranslated-subtitle-for-censorship-rumours</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nier-automata-creators-deny-characters-were-problematic-overseas-and-blame-mistranslated-subtitle-for-censorship-rumours.1218594/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nier-automata-creators-deny-characters-were-problematic-overseas-and-blame-mistranslated-subtitle-for-censorship-rumours<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Square Enix</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Nier: Automata producer Yosuke Saito and director <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/yoko-taro">Yoko Taro</a> have denied that any of their character designs were restricted for Western audiences.</p>
<p>As spotted by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/nier-automata-creators-deny-rumors-of-square-enix-imposing-character-design-restrictions-on-them-its-a-huge-mistranslation/">Automaton</a>, the developers were compelled to comment after a mistranslated Japanese-to-English subtitle intimated Nier: Automata had been subjected to censorship from <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> to meet global standards.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="GODDESS OF VICTORY: NIKKE | Producers' Creative Dialogue Special Livestream" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EezDZURfSfk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>GODDESS OF VICTORY: NIKKE | Producers' Creative Dialogue Special Livestream</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EezDZURfSfk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EezDZURfSfk?autoplay=1" title="GODDESS OF VICTORY: NIKKE | Producers' Creative Dialogue Special Livestream">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>GODDESS OF VICTORY: NIKKE | Producers' Creative Dialogue Special Livestream.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EezDZURfSfk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In the interview above (skip to 28:12 for the segment concerned), Sony executive Yoshida Shuhei asked the developers about their design process.</p>
<p>"Our concept is always to do something that's 'not like anything else'. What I mean is, if Nier: Replicant had a boy as the main character, Nier: Automata would have a girl protagonist. If Western sci-fi is filled with Marine-like soldiers, we might go in the opposite direction and use Gothic Lolita outfits, for example," Taro said. "We tend to take the contrarian route."</p>
<p>"There are, of course, certain things that are ethically or morally inappropriate – even if they're just aspects of a character," Saito added, according to the subtitles. "We try to draw a line by establishing rules about what’s acceptable and what’s not.</p>
<p>"While certain things might be acceptable in Japan, they could become problematic in certain overseas regions, and even characters could become problematic as well. These are the kind of situation[s] we usually try to avoid creating. As a result, there are actually countries where we couldn't officially release Nier: Automata."</p>
<p>This immediately caused consternation with fans but as Automaton points out, this "could be a little tricky to translate, even for an advanced Japanese speaker".</p>
<p>When asked directly about the claim, Taro denied it, <a href="https://x.com/yokotaro/status/1933044002095575201">saying on X/Twitter:</a> "I've never heard of such a thing happening". Saito simply said he thought the things he'd mentioned had been mistranslated, and would clarify this in a future livestream.</p>
<p>In the same interview, former PlayStation exec Shuhei Yoshida called <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nier-automata-revived-the-japanese-games-industry-says-former-sony-exec-shuhei-yoshida">Nier: Automata the "game that changed everything", as it was responsible for reviving the Japanese games industry</a> on its release. In a recent interview, Yoshida discussed how during the PS3 era, sales of Japanese games had declined, and increasingly studios there were chasing "overseas tastes".</p>
<p>That changed with NieR: Automata in 2017, released for the PS4. "I think Yoko Taro created it without paying any mind at all to making it sell overseas, but it was a tremendous success," Yoshida said.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2, Spider-Man 2, and more PlayStation titles have been freed from their region lock prison on PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-spider-man-2-and-more-playstation-titles-have-been-freed-from-their-region-lock-prison-on-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-spider-man-2-and-more-playstation-titles-have-been-freed-from-their-region-lock-prison-on-pc.1218591/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-spider-man-2-and-more-playstation-titles-have-been-freed-from-their-region-lock-prison-on-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Your mileage may vary though</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
    

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Arrowhead</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/sony-playstation">Sony</a> have been making a lot of mistakes over the past couple of years, including things like mistakenly thinking they could <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-commits-to-launch-just-six-of-playstations-12-live-service-games-by-march-2026">release 12 live service games by 2026</a>, but the more immediately annoying one is its whole PSN thing. I probably don't need to remind you of that whole <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a> fiasco, where they tried to make logging into a PSN a requirement for those on PC and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/helldivers-2-drops-psn-account-linking-requirement-for-steam-players-after-widespread-backlash">later scrapped this</a> because it went down horrendously. However, there has been one other snag that came with all this PSN nonsense: region locking.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Despite being able to play Helldivers 2 without a PSN account, it was still unavailable in almost 180 countries, all of which you can't make a PSN account in (it's still possible to play the game with an account connected, which will likely have factored into the reasoning behind region locking the game). This has applied to Sony's other PC ports of their PlayStation published games, except now, as shared by deals wizard Wario64, it seems a handful of them are now (mostly) region lock free.
</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreia24z2us5mamqq7fuzivp5cmyswoghpufymdjvsktqboo7fvh62nq" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637/app.bsky.feed.post/3lrj3gsdkr22v"><div lang="en"><p>Sony appears to be removing regional restrictions on their Steam/PC games 

God of War Ragnarok steamdb.info/sub/833972/h...
The Last of Us Part II Remastered steamdb.info/sub/1219787/...
Spider-Man 2 steamdb.info/sub/1219797/...
Helldivers 2 steamdb.info/sub/137730/h...</p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637/post/3lrj3gsdkr22v?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p></div>— Wario64 (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637?ref_src=embed">@wario64.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637/post/3lrj3gsdkr22v?ref_src=embed">June 13, 2025 at 7:38 PM</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>
There are four total, including the aforementioned <a href="https://steamdb.info/sub/137730/history/?changeid=29555004">Helldivers 2</a>, as well as <a href="https://steamdb.info/sub/833972/history/?changeid=29554938">God of War Ragnarok</a>, <a href="https://steamdb.info/sub/1219787/history/?changeid=29555142">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered</a>, and <a href="https://steamdb.info/sub/1219797/history/?changeid=29555257">Spider-Man 2</a>. Worth keeping in mind that these are <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/playstation-finally-drop-the-psn-account-requirement-that-annoyed-every-pc-player">all games that had their PSN requirements lifted earlier this year</a>. From what I can tell there haven't been any changes made to other PlayStation games based on their logs on SteamDB, but I'm also not entirely sure which games were and weren't region locked, so your mileage may vary with their wider portfolio.
</p>
<p>
It's a good move forward at least! Certainly seems like PlayStation are just shooting themselves in the foot by limiting where their games can actually be bought. Now the big question is whether or not their next big game (<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/marathon-players-on-pc-wont-need-a-playstation-account-say-bungie">that isn't Marathon</a>) on PC will have a PSN requirement at all.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout Shelter has been downloaded over 230 million times in 10 years]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-shelter-has-been-downloaded-over-230-million-times-in-10-years</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-shelter-has-been-downloaded-over-230-million-times-in-10-years.1218570/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-shelter-has-been-downloaded-over-230-million-times-in-10-years<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bethesda Softworks</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>On the tenth anniversary of the release of free-to-play <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout-shelter">Fallout Shelter</a>, Bethesda has revealed the management sim game has been downloaded 230 million times across all platforms.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, Bethesda reckons it's time to "celebrate a decade of adventure, excitement, and Vault-building fun with Fallout Shelter" by launching a new in-game event that offers "party favours" for everyone who logs in from 16th–21st June, including bonus lunchboxes, Nuka, and more.</p>
<p>"Tons of content has been added to the game since 2015. You've built Vaults, made lives (or chaos) for your dwellers, and embarked on thrilling quests, all while keeping the spirit of the wasteland alive and well," the developer <a href="https://bethesda.net/en/article/6zT9anWe9yLVqi1F6gGPms/fallout-shelter-10th-anniversary">said</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fallout Season 2 Teaser" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tu5EN8V35JM?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fallout Season 2 Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tu5EN8V35JM?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tu5EN8V35JM?autoplay=1" title="Fallout Season 2 Teaser">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Fallout Season 2 Teaser.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tu5EN8V35JM" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Whether you've been with us all along or you're new to the party, now is a great time to head into the wasteland and start building. To celebrate this huge milestone, we’re offering up to 70 percent off lunchboxes in the in-game store from now through 17th June.</p>
<p>"So, dust off your Pip-Boy, tune in to the celebration, and keep those Vaults thriving. Here's to another 10 years of Fallout Shelter!"</p>
<p>As for those aforementioned party favours?</p>
<ul>
<li>16-17th June: Lunchbox x2, Pet Carrier x1, Nuka x10</li>
<li>18-19th June: Lunchbox x3, Mr. Handy x1, Nuka x15</li>
<li>20-21st June: Lunchbox x5, Pet Carrier x1, Nuka x20</li>
</ul>
<p>ICYMI, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/amazon-renews-fallout-for-third-season-six-months-before-second-arrives">Fallout TV series has already been renewed for a third season on Amazon Prime</a>. That's despite the show's second season still being months away, debuting in December 2025.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBC: Firebreak will keep you busy fending off a bunch of weird stuff right through to 2026 with multiple free updates]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fbc-firebreak-will-keep-you-busy-fending-off-a-bunch-of-weird-stuff-right-through-to-2026-with-multiple-free-updates</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fbc-firebreak-will-keep-you-busy-fending-off-a-bunch-of-weird-stuff-right-through-to-2026-with-multiple-free-updates.1218564/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fbc-firebreak-will-keep-you-busy-fending-off-a-bunch-of-weird-stuff-right-through-to-2026-with-multiple-free-updates<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
There's still a few days to go until <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/remedy-entertainment">Remedy Entertainment's</a> latest entry into their Connected Universe, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fbc-firebreak">FBC: Firebreak</a>, is unleashed onto the world. Whether it's any good or not in its entirety, we probably won't know for a while yet given that online <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooters</a> of its ilk are always guaranteed to receive numerous patches to iron out some kinks. Our own Nic found a good bit to like about the game in his preview, ignoring the at the time rubbish guns, at the very least.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Whether those tweaks come or not, Remedy have guaranteed one thing: some big free updates with new things to do. Ain't that nice! In the 2025 roadmap, there were a couple of updates outlined for the remainder of the year. The first one, coming in the fall/ autumn, is called Codename "Outbreak". This one brings in a new jobsite, the Research Sector, alongside some new gameplay systems and enemies, and earnable rewards. There'll also be a new paid Classified Requisition, which comes with some armour, skins, and character voice packs - the playable stuff in the update will be completely free though.
</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>The launch of FBC: Firebreak is just the beginning. Have a look at what the post-launch roadmap will look like.</p><p>All playable post launch content in the game is free.</p><p>FBC: Firebreak launches June 17. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FBCFirebreak?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FBCFirebreak</a> <a href="https://t.co/bZdliHaOil">pic.twitter.com/bZdliHaOil</a></p></div>— Remedy Entertainment (@remedygames) <a href="https://twitter.com/remedygames/status/1932800170418139480?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 11, 2025</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
Then in the winter there's the Codename "Blackout" update. The jobsite for this one hasn't been named, but there'll be even more enemies and rewards, alongside some new equipment. You'll also be able to pick up another paid Classified Requisition.
</p>
<p>
Remedy's communications director shared in a <a href="https://x.com/RiotRMD/status/1933057792631259491">separate post</a> that there are plans for more updates in 2026 too, but the teams wants to "launch the game first, see what the reception is and what the community wants to see, what you might gravitate to before we make more decisions on what kind of content we'll be releasing, for free, in 2026 for FBC: Firebreak." Lots to come it sounds like then!
</p>
<p>
FBC: Firebreak is due out next week, June 17th. 

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Something for the Weekend – 14/06/25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/14/something-for-the-weekend-14-06-25/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/something-for-the-weekend-%E2%80%93-14-06-25.1218552/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/14/something-for-the-weekend-14-06-25/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It’s one of my favourite weekends of the year, as the roaring engines of dozens of race cars hurtle down the roads of Le Mans. After a busy 10 days, it’s perfect for me to just sit down and watch hour after hour of relentless motor racing.</p>
<p>But let’s just do a quick round up this afternoon, eh?</p>
<h2>In the News This Week</h2>
<p>Our fingers and thumbs have been occupied with other tasks, making our news reporting pretty sparse this week.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/12/silent-hill-remake-announced-by-konami/">Konami announces Silent Hill 1 Remake as it shares more Silent Hill F details</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/11/nintendo-switch-2-sets-new-records-with-over-3-5-million-sales-in-4-days/">Nintendo Switch 2 sets new records with over 3.5 million sales in 4 days</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/12/metal-gear-online-wont-return-for-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater/">Metal Gear Online won’t return for Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a>, but it will have something else</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/10/splatoon-raiders-is-a-fresh-switch-2-exclusive-spinoff-and-theres-a-big-update-for-splatoon-3-too/">Splatoon Raiders is a fresh Switch 2-exclusive spinoff, and there’s a big update for Splatoon 3, too!</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<h2>Games in Review &amp; Featured Articles</h2>
<p>Over in review land, we plugged away at plenty more Nintendo Switch 2 stuff, including the main console review, but that wasn’t the half of it this week’s features! Let’s start with the console itself.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/12/nintendo-switch-2-review-one-week-with-the-new-generation-handheld/"><strong>Nintendo Switch 2</strong></a> – 8/10 (<a href="https://youtu.be/rKWk_eyr9NE">Video Review</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>And in the games:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/12/the-alters-review/"><strong>The Alters</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PC – 9/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/09/rune-factory-guardians-of-azuma-review/"><strong>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma</strong></a> – NSW2, NSW, <strong>PC</strong> – 9/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/12/mario-kart-world-review/"><strong>Mario Kart World</strong></a> – NSW2 – 8/10 (<a href="https://youtu.be/5OOlJ-7svmo">Video Review</a>)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/10/warhammer-40000-space-marine-master-crafted-edition-review/"><strong>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine Master Crafted Edition</strong></a> – <strong>XSX|S</strong>, PC – 7/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/11/to-a-t-review/"><strong>To a T</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PC – 5/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/13/tainted-grail-fall-of-avalon-review/"><strong>Tainted Grail: Fall of Avalon</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PC – 5/10</li>
</ul>
<p>Dom also dug into <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/12/cyberpunk-2077-switch-2-review-ps4-xbox-comparison/"><strong>Cyberpunk 2077: Ultimate Edition for Switch 2</strong></a>, coming away rather impressed with what CDPR has managed to extract from the new handheld. And we combined to explore a whole host of unupgraded, unpatched Switch games to see <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/11/how-the-switch-2-fixed-bad-switch-1-frame-rates-even-without-patches/"><strong>how backward compatibility on Switch 2 powers them to better performance</strong></a>.</p>
<p><iframe title="How Switch 2 Backward Compatibility fixes a lot of bad Switch frame rates" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ds3mP6OMM9w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Miguel was mightily impressed by <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/13/stellar-blade-is-a-stellar-port-for-pc-and-steam-deck/"><strong>Stellar Blade’s PC port</strong></a> this week.</p>
<p>And then from a mix of Steam Next Fest and Summer Game Fest, we had previews of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/07/shinobi-art-of-vengeance-is-another-fantastic-revival-of-a-sega-classic/"><strong>Shinobi: Art of Vengeance</strong></a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/07/hands-on-sonic-racing-crossworlds-now-were-racing-with-portals/"><strong>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds</strong></a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/09/stars-of-icarus-preview-out-with-steampunk-in-with-space/"><strong>Stars of Icarus</strong></a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/09/abyssus-preview-shooting-stuff-underwater-together/"><strong>Abyssus</strong></a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/10/ninja-gaiden-ragebound-is-the-perfect-mix-of-nostalgia-and-modern-game-design/"><strong>Ninja Gaiden Ragebound</strong></a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/10/absolum-preview-a-roguelike-beat-em-up-absolum-lutely/"><strong>Absolum</strong></a></p>
<p>And rounding out the week, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/06/13/what-we-played-the-alters-mario-kart-world-switch-2/"><strong>What We Played</strong></a> featured The Alters, as well as plenty more Switch 2 with Mario Kart World.</p>
<h2>Trailer Park</h2>
<p><strong>Bloober Team drops a new gameplay trailer for Cronos: The New Dawn</strong></p>
<p><iframe title="Cronos: The New Dawn | Gameplay Showcase" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HzBmlQuxB8k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>See the new Metal Gear Solid Delta trailer</strong></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="METAL GEAR SOLID Δ: SNAKE EATER - Gameplay Trailer 【Xbox version】 | KONAMI" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VifvSU5wlY0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>There’s a trailer breakdown for High on Life 2</strong></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="High on Life 2 Trailer Breakdown | Xbox Games Showcase 2025" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6843hNj0nNU?start=187&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Here’s a deep dive into Grounded 2 from Obsidian</strong></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Xbox Games Showcase Deep Dive | Grounded 2" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f_MpCHtM6U0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2>Your Achievements</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Andrewww</strong> didn’t rhyme, but he did alliterate with his gaming this week. He enjoyed all of Dregde’s endings over the past few weeks, continued on with the excellent Disco Elysium, and dipped into the walking sim Death Stranding, which has him still rather befuddled.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s the round up for this week’s round up, but I hope you have a great time, whether you’re watching fast cars or not.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alex Garland’s Elden Ring Movie Should Feel Like Fantasy Warfare]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/alex-garlands-elden-ring-movie-should-feel-like-fantasy-warfare</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alex-garland%E2%80%99s-elden-ring-movie-should-feel-like-fantasy-warfare.1218549/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/alex-garlands-elden-ring-movie-should-feel-like-fantasy-warfare<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">If you could hire any director to make an Elden Ring movie, who would you pick? </p><p data-cy="paragraph">You might settle for fantasy heavyweights like Peter Jackson or Guillermo del Toro, or maybe you’d tap Miguel Sapochnik, the man who brought you many of Game of Thrones’ biggest battles, including Hardhome and Battle of the Bastards. If you’re looking for something a little more avant-garde, you could even pick Robert Eggers (Nosferatu), Yorgos Lanthimos (Poor Things), or Bong Joon Ho (Mickey 17) – filmmakers who, like Elden Ring developer FromSoftware, relish in the surreal, cryptic, and uncanny. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Chances are, you wouldn’t pick Alex Garland. The British writer and director is known for the grounded, slow-burning science fiction dramas Ex Machina and Annihilation, as well as the inventively named war films Civil War and Warfare – none of which resemble FromSoftware’s work in any notable way. However, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/live-action-elden-ring-movie-on-the-way-from-a24-and-director-alex-garland">Garland is precisely who film studio A24 has selected to adapt Hidetaka Miyazaki’s magnum opus</a> for the big screen. Considering Garland – who, in addition to directing, is also set to write the screenplay – isn’t one to take his multi-digit checks and phone it in, you have to wonder how he’ll try to make this work. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/06/11/elden-ring-dragon-1749649681736.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">A24's Elden Ring could focus on the moment-to-moment journey of a single Tarnished, rather than the sprawling saga of the land's lore. | Image credit: FromSoftware</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">At a glance, Garland and Elden Ring do indeed seem like an odd match. Despite his considerable experience with sci-fi, Garland has yet to try his hand at hardcore fantasy – a tricky genre in its own right, and even trickier when dealing with video game adaptations. On top of this, his style doesn’t have a lot in common with FromSoftware’s. The narratives of Ex Machina and Annihilation are rooted in plot, dialogue, and characterization, while games like Dark Souls, Bloodborne, and Elden Ring tell their stories largely indirectly, through item descriptions and environmental design. (Civil War, set in tomorrow’s United States, was widely criticized for its lack of deep backstory). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">But just because Garland has never made a fantasy film, doesn’t mean he can’t. He’s reinvented himself and ventured out into new frontiers before – Civil War and Warfare are radically different from Ex Machina and Annihilation, which are themselves unlike the films he wrote before making his directorial debut – so who’s to say he won’t do so again?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Actually, making an Elden Ring movie wouldn’t entirely constitute uncharted territory for Garland. Many people – including his own fans – don’t know this, but he’s actually an avid gamer. His experience playing the Resident Evil games apparently inspired his script for the 2002 horror 28 Days Later, and the 2000 film The Beach – based on one of his novels – features a game-inspired scene which <a href="https://www.polygon.com/opinion/601104/elden-ring-alex-garland-dredd-video-game-movies" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Polygon’s Matt Patches described as “the closest thing we will ever get” to a Banjo-Kazooie movie</a> starring Leonardo DiCaprio.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Warfare evokes surprisingly similar feelings to those experienced while playing Elden Ring: outnumbered, outmatched, overwhelmed, afraid for your life (or runes). </p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">While many filmmakers seemingly feign interest in the material they’re hired to adapt in order to placate said material’s existing fanbase (to this day I refuse to believe M. Night Shyamalan watched even a single episode of Avatar: The Last Airbender), Garland’s love for The Last of Us, BioShock, and – most importantly – Dark Souls seems to be sincere. He appears to have a decent grasp of what makes the series unique and special compared to other games. <a href="https://youtu.be/TMdasaWiYD8?t=855" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Talking to Gamespot</a> back in 2020, Garland said, “The Dark Souls games seem to have this kind of embedded poetry in them. You’ll have some weird bit of dialogue with some sort of broken soul sat outside some doorway and it feels like you’ve drifted into this existential dream.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sticking to this image of an “existential dream,” Garland could take his Elden Ring adaptation in the direction of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/03/13/annihilation-review">Annihilation</a>, which upon release was praised for its psychedelic visuals. This would work, but it is not the only path forward. Another less obvious but arguably more effective plan of action would be to adapt Elden Ring in the mold of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warfare-review-alex-garland-will-poulter-noah-centineo">Warfare</a>, Garland’s nail-biting thriller about Navy SEALs fighting in Iraq. I say this not because there is something fantastical about this film – on the contrary, it’s been marketed as the one of the most realistic war films ever made – but because watching it evokes surprisingly similar feelings to those you experience while playing Elden Ring: outnumbered, outmatched, overwhelmed, afraid for your life (or runes). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Swap the war-torn Iraqi town of Ramadi for the ruins of Limgrave, alleyways of Leyndell, or badlands of Caelid, and what you’re left with is a film that adapts not the game’s encyclopedic, overarching backstory – the backstabbing saga of Marika, Godrick, Radagon, and the Demigods – but the minute, moment-to-moment experiences of the player’s Tarnished character wading through the Lands Between, so caught up in reaching the nearest Site of Grace in one piece that they have completely lost sight of their larger quest to become Elden Lord, whatever the hell that means. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Given that Garland is <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/elden-ring-movie-director-eyeing-warfares-kit-connor-for-upcoming-adaptation">reportedly looking to cast one of the actors from Warfare</a> – Kit Connor – in the lead, it’s possible that his Elden Ring adaptation will end up adopting a similarly suspenseful tone, not to mention retread those themes of fear, despair, and senseless violence that Connor has already proven himself capable of conveying. Using Warfare as a blueprint for Elden Ring would not only take advantage of Garland’s strengths as a filmmaker who explores psychology through graphic, carefully choreographed action, but also follow the example set by the – fight me – only solid video game adaptation out there, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-1-review">season one of HBO’s The Last of Us</a>, whose quality is in large part derived from the fact that its creators understood what made the original great as a game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Elden Ring, like FromSoftware’s other games, is not a power fantasy where heroes with supernatural abilities beat up giant monsters through flashy cutscenes and epic quick time events. It’s an anti-power fantasy that reduces players to nameless warriors who become well-acquainted with death and bang their head against the fog wall until they finally succeed. For Garland’s adaptation to reach the heights of his previous films, he’d do well to capture that bittersweet sentiment. And through his work on Warfare, we can catch a glimpse of what could be when Elden Ring finally arrives in cinemas. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tim Brinkhof is a freelance writer specializing in art and history. After studying journalism at NYU, he has gone on to write for Vox, Vulture, Slate, Polygon, GQ, Esquire and more.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony quietly removes PC sale restrictions in dozens of countries for four huge PlayStation games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-quietly-removes-pc-sale-restrictions-in-dozens-of-countries-for-four-huge-playstation-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-quietly-removes-pc-sale-restrictions-in-dozens-of-countries-for-four-huge-playstation-games.1218540/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-quietly-removes-pc-sale-restrictions-in-dozens-of-countries-for-four-huge-playstation-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Games returned to sale include God of War Ragnarök, The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered, Marvel's Spider-Man 2, and yes... Helldivers 2.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>PlayStation</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Sony has seemingly loosened regional restrictions on a number of its PC games, including <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/god-of-war-ragnarok">God of War Ragnarök</a>, The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/spider-man-2-walkthrough-9356">Marvel's Spider-Man 2</a>, and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/helldivers-2">Helldivers 2</a>.</p>
<p>As spotted by Wario64, the changelogs for all aforementioned games listed on SteamDB show that a number of sale restrictions were quietly lifted yesterday, 13th June.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered's Roguelike No Return Mode Explained: TLOU2 No Return Gameplay PS5" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n3XuB8ZBHX4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered's Roguelike No Return Mode Explained: TLOU2 No Return Gameplay PS5</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n3XuB8ZBHX4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/n3XuB8ZBHX4?autoplay=1" title="The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered's Roguelike No Return Mode Explained: TLOU2 No Return Gameplay PS5">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n3XuB8ZBHX4">The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered's Roguelike No Return Mode Explained: TLOU2 No Return Gameplay PS5</a>.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n3XuB8ZBHX4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Although Sony made no public comment concerning the furore about sales restrictions invoked in countries where PSN isn't available or shared any plans to address it, check SteamDB and you'll see that the games <a href="https://steamdb.info/sub/833972/history/?changeid=29554938">have indeed trimmed down the number of countries where they're unavailable</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/sony-removes-regional-restrictions-on-four-of-its-biggest-games-on-steam/">PC Gamer</a>). Just one region was added to the restricted sale list: Russian Federation.</p>
<blockquote data-bluesky-cid="bafyreia24z2us5mamqq7fuzivp5cmyswoghpufymdjvsktqboo7fvh62nq" data-bluesky-embed-color-mode="system" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637/app.bsky.feed.post/3lrj3gsdkr22v"><div lang="en"><p>Sony appears to be removing regional restrictions on their Steam/PC games

God of War Ragnarok steamdb.info/sub/833972/h...

The Last of Us Part II Remastered steamdb.info/sub/1219787/...

Spider-Man 2 steamdb.info/sub/1219797/...

Helldivers 2 steamdb.info/sub/137730/h...</p><p><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637/post/3lrj3gsdkr22v?ref_src=embed">[image or embed]</a></p></div>— Wario64 (<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637?ref_src=embed">@wario64.bsky.social</a>) <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:knj5sw5al3sukl6vhkpi7637/post/3lrj3gsdkr22v?ref_src=embed">June 13, 2025 at 7:38 PM</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p><p>This all started, of course, when Helldivers 2 was review-bombed last year following a PSN requirement which led to the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/helldivers-2-has-been-pulled-from-sale-in-177-countries-as-its-psn-linking-requirement-rolls-out">game being pulled from sale in 177 countries</a>. The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-overturns-helldivers-2-psn-requirement-following-backlash">company quickly u-turned its decision</a> following the backlash but not before several Sony-published games were caught up in the controversy. Most recently <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/stellar-blade-pc-release-blocked-on-steam-in-over-120-countries-surprising-even-its-developer">Stellar Blade found itself at the centre of the backlash</a> even though developer Shift Up had stated a PSN account was only optional and not a formal requirement.</p>
<p>On the subject of Sony, president Hideaki Nishino recently stated the company is open to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sony-will-continue-to-add-more-value-to-ps-plus-says-company-president-but-it-may-come-with-price-changes-too">adjusting the price of PlayStation Plus in the future, as the company aims to "maximise profitability</a>".</p>
<p>The comments came as part of a discussion between Sony CEO Hermen Hulst and president Hideaki Nishino on PS Plus and the company's future. Discussing Sony's subscription service, Nishino stated: "We will continue to add more value and adjust our pricing strategy in a dynamic way to maximise profitability."</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kill Team Typhon Review - Purge The Infestation]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/kill-team-typhon-review-purge-infestation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kill-team-typhon-review-purge-the-infestation.1218537/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/kill-team-typhon-review-purge-infestation<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The current season of&nbsp;<em>Kill Team</em>&nbsp;continues with the release of its third expansion set, <em>Kill Team</em> Typhon. Following a slightly different format to previous expansions, we're still treated to 2 brand new kill teams, along with the inclusion of a force of non-player operatives (NPOs) for you to battle solo. In this article, we'll take a look at both kill teams and what Typhon adds to your games.</p>

<p><em>Kill Team</em> is a skirmish wargame set in Games Workshop's larger <em>Warhammer 40,000</em> setting. As a skirmish game, <em>Kill Team</em> features a small number of elite troops, fighting special operations battles, rather than huge battles fought with entire armies. We've covered <em>Kill Team</em> in depth since the first edition, and you can read our review of the current <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/kill-team-starter-set-review" rel="nofollow">Starter Set</a> here.</p>




<h2>A New Infestation</h2>

<p><em>Kill Team</em>&nbsp;Typhon, as with previous expansions, adds 2 brand new kill teams and some scenery that builds on that from the Hivestorm box. It also includes a set of player-versus-player missions, some non-player operative miniatures, and a mission pack for cooperative and solo play. The full box contents is:</p>

<ul><li><em>Kill Team</em>&nbsp;Typhon Dossier</li>
	<li>10x Adeptus Mechanicus Battleclade miniatures</li>
	<li>5x Tyranid Raveners miniatures</li>
	<li>11x Tyranid Hormagaunts and Ripper Swarm NPO miniatures</li>
	<li>Datacards for both kill teams</li>
	<li>Tokens for both kill teams</li>
	<li>15x Tyranid Infestation scenery pieces</li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kill-team-typhon-2.jpg?itok=ndf8BF-j 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kill-team-typhon-2.jpg?itok=veg-jWsh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Suffer Not The Xenos To Live</h2>

<p><em>Kill Team</em> Typhon moves back into the standard <em>Kill Team</em> expansion format with 2 new kill teams, some new scenery, and a mission pack that uses the scenery for you to battle in. It also includes a set of dedicated non-player operatives (NPOs) and a mission pack for cooperative or solo play. The Joint Ops: Typhon Mission Pack sees players battling these AI-controlled Tyranids.</p>

<p>2 types of Tyranid NPOs are included in Typhon, Hormagaunts and Ripper Swarms, but the rules for 6 Tyranid NPOs are included in the Joint Ops pack, should you wish to expand your Joint Ops games with miniatures from the <em>Warhammer 40,000</em> range. The mission pack has 6 missions that can be played individually or as a branching campaign. The missions all use the Tyranid Infestation scenery included in Typhon, and scenery from <em>Kill Team</em> Hivestorm, which is also available separately as Kill Zone Volkus.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kill-team-typhon-3.jpg?itok=EGQvtPnx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kill-team-typhon-3.jpg?itok=j5sitEc6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>The Omnissiah's Will</h2>

<p>Technology under the Imperium's rule is manically controlled by the Adeptus Mechanicus. Part of their remit is to seek out lost technology, to stop it from getting into the wrong hands, which includes Imperial forces, and sometimes other members of the Adeptus Mechanicus. These searches are led by the Technoarcheologists, and their lobotomized, mechanically augmented servitor warriors/slaves in forces known as Battleclades.</p>

<p>The Battleclade kill team is made up of 10 operators, the Technoarcheologist, armed with the powerful Eradication Pistol and Omniscaner ability, which lets you put a token on an enemy within 8 inches, or visible to the Technoarcheologist, and then any friendly attacks against that operative can reroll 1s. The Technoacheologist is supported by another junior Tech-Priest, a Servitor Underseer. The Battleclade has a special rule where, during an operative's activation, they can subtract one from their action points and immediately take a free action (except move) with another servitor after their action ends. The Underseer can do that with a nearby Servitor without ending their turn, and they can spend one of their action points to make a dash move with a nearby Servitor, to position then better for their activation, or to get them into cover (or out of if you need some bait).</p>

<p>The rest of the kill team is made up of 8 servitor operatives, 3 specialists, 2 heavy weapon servitors, and 3 combat servitors with a variety of armaments. You can take additional combat servitors, swapping out specialists and heavy weapons, but they're pretty good, so you're going to want to take them. One of the specialists is the Auto-Proxy Servitor, through whom the Underseer can channel their abilities, and has their own ability to make targeting enemies in cover easier.</p>

<p>The 2 heavy weapon armed servitors come with either a heavy bolter or a heavy arc rifle (you can take 1 of each), and you can take one combat servitor with a melta gun, up to 3 with Incendine Igniters, a short range torrent weapon, or a Phosphor Blaster, which always gets at least 1 crit, even if you don't roll one.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kill-team-typhon-4.jpg?itok=FYPNGEbw 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kill-team-typhon-4.jpg?itok=sQh21mLV 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Thoughts Of A Hive Mind</h2>

<p>The Raveners are a snake-like bioform that the Tyranid Hive Mind uses to burrow beneath the defenses of its targets in its unrelenting quest to devour all biomass. The Raveners are an elite kill team, comprising of 5 operatives, led by a Ravener Prime, who can gain an extra CP each turn if they roll higher than the turn number, and can really hamper your opponent's objective capturing abilities through tier Neuropredatory Crest, which reduces the APL stat for contesting objeives of all enemy operatives when determining control of a marker by 1. It also increases the AP for any nearby enemy operatives using the Pick Up Marker action, and stops them from rerolling attack and defence dice.</p>

<p>All of the Ravener's are fast, with 3 action points and a move of 7. They all also have the Burrow action, which removes them from the Killzone, or if out of the Killzone, allows them to be set up anywhere in your Tunnel, which you develop as the game progresses.</p>

<p>There are 4 types of Ravener specialists, and the basic Ravener Warrior. The Felltalon has the option for a poison attack, the Tremorscythe has a reaction to attack any operative moving near your tunnel network, the Venomspitter has a powerful Venom Bolt attack, and the Wrecker is tougher, and when attacking enemies, can roll off against them for additional damage. As you can only take 4 operatives, you will usually take 1 of each specialist over the basic Warrior, who, while deadly, doesn't have any special abilities other than getting the lethal 5+ against wounded enemy operatives.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kill-team-typhon-5.jpg?itok=uSFB9wZU 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kill-team-typhon-5.jpg?itok=YCsbB4hU 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><h2>Kill Team Typhon Final Thoughts?</h2>

<p><em>Kill Team</em>&nbsp;Typhon means that players finally get a dedicated Tyranid kill team outside of the original compendium, and the Raveners don't disappoint. They're fast and deadly, and their tunnel ability is incredibly thematic, and nerve-wracking for your opponent, who has no idea where they will come out. The Battlclade kill team is, as you would expect, devoid of emotion and entirely goal-oriented. It feels very much like a fantasy Undead kill team, in that you have to protect the Tech Priests, because while the Servitors are tough, they're really boosted by their overseers.</p>

<p>The inclusion of the NPOs and scenery makes Typhon a very exciting pack. Plug this into the <em>Kill Team</em> core rulebook and the&nbsp;Kill Zone Volkus set, and you've got a great experience for players, with player vs player, solo, and cooperative options (which can use either force in the set). The included kill teams are thematic and fun, and it all fits together to feel like more than a box with 2 new kill teams, but a solid gaming set.</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of</em> <strong>Kill Team Typhon</strong>&nbsp;<em>used to produce this review was provided by Games Workshop.</em></p>


</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Answering the Nintendo Switch 2’s lingering accessibility questions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/686591/nintendo-switch-2-accessibility-features-analysis</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/answering-the-nintendo-switch-2%E2%80%99s-lingering-accessibility-questions.1218519/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/686591/nintendo-switch-2-accessibility-features-analysis<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>One of the biggest surprises of the Nintendo Switch 2’s reveal was its proposed accessibility. For years, Nintendo has been known for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tears-of-the-kingdom-shows-that-without-change-accessibility-in-nintendo-games-will-remain-accidental">accidentally stumbling on accessibility solutions</a> while stubbornly refusing to engage with the broader subject. Yet, in the Switch 2, there appeared a more holistic approach to accessibility for which disabled players have been crying out. This was supported by a webpage dedicated to <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nintendo.com%2Fen-gb%2FHardware%2FNintendo-Switch-2%2FNintendo-Switch-2-Accessibility-2785631.html%3Fsrsltid%3DAfmBOoo_dOcl-VTBHzJx3R68LDlmAWIVWPctlJw4BlkSm8BRR32PNCNJ" rel="sponsored">the Switch 2’s hardware accessibility</a>. </p><p>However, specifics were thin and no further information emerged ahead of the Switch 2’s debut. Now, having spent the last week with the Switch 2, I’ve found that this limited information hid, aside from a few missteps, an impressive suite of system-level accessibility considerations and advances that somewhat offset <a href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/682661/nintendo-switch-2-early-hands-on-mario-kart-world">the otherwise gradual update the Switch 2 represents</a>. But as we finally answer lingering accessibility questions over the Switch 2, there’s a nagging sense that this information should have been readily available ahead of launch.</p><div><p id="how-intuitive-is-the-setup-very-but-blind-players-may-need-assistance"><h2>How intuitive is the setup? Very, but blind players may need assistance</h2></p></div><p>I tend to find setup procedures dense and unapproachable thanks to cognitive disability. Yet I was pleasantly surprised at how breezy the Switch 2’s setup was. Aside from a few hiccups trying to decipher <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/659074/nintendo-switch-online-game-sharing-loophole">Virtual Game Cards</a> (a feature I ended up opting out of), the whole process was intuitive and fast.</p><p>Accessibility features, however, are not available during setup. The console’s text-to-speech is not enabled by default, nor can you access text sizing and zoom options. This will represent a significant barrier to entry for some, and blind players may require sighted assistance during setup.</p><div><p id="are-switch-controllers-and-joy-cons-compatible-with-the-switch-2-yes-including-the-hori-flex"><h2>Are Switch controllers and Joy-Cons compatible with the Switch 2? Yes, including the Hori Flex</h2></p></div><p>The increased size of the Joy-Con 2 feels better this time around, as does the Joy-Con 2 grip. But the controller size and the grip’s unergonomic square shape still don’t take long to incite my hand pain. Fortunately, Switch controllers and Joy-Cons are usable on the Switch 2, and the ability to default to the original Pro Controller is welcome.</p><p>It’s encouraging that you can pair other controllers with the Switch 2 using peripherals like the Magic-S Pro 2. Though, given recent trends in third-party peripheral support, I’d be reluctant to suggest that support is here to stay. We’re already seeing some connectivity issues around third-party controllers, especially 8BitDo gamepads, with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/681153/8bitdo-controller-gamepad-nintendo-switch-2-compatible-firmware-update">8BitDo working on updates to get those working with the Switch 2</a>.</p><p>What <em>is </em>supported, however, is Nintendo’s licensed adaptive controller: <a href="https://stores.horiusa.com/flex-controller-for-nintendo-switch/">the Hori Flex</a>. This works docked and in tabletop mode for games that don’t require mouse controls (some other features, like motion controls, may also cause issues). Keep in mind, you will need a USB-A to USB-C adapter to connect in tabletop mode.</p><div><p><cite>Photo: Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge</cite></p></div><div><p id="can-you-connect-a-usb-keyboard-yes"><h2><strong>Can you connect a USB keyboard? Yes</strong></h2></p></div><p>Not everyone finds onscreen keyboards intuitive or accessible. The good news is you can connect a USB keyboard through the console’s USB-C ports and use that instead, including during setup.</p><div><p id="what-is-the-text-to-speech-speed-its-inconsistent-but-us-english-is-120-130-words-per-minute-on-average"><h2><strong>What is the text-to-speech speed? It’s inconsistent, but US English is 120–130 words per minute on average</strong></h2></p></div><p>We have no official number on the speed at which the Switch 2’s text-to-speech reads, but we can estimate. Using the information the system reads when you enable text-to-speech, we’ve found that both voice options averaged around 120–130 words per minute in US English. For UK English, it was 130–140 words per minute. Different languages will see different rates. There was some inconsistency in repeated tests that could not be accounted for simply by considering when timers were started and stopped.</p><p>That’s not the only quirk in the system. Players should be aware there is a noticeable delay between landing on a menu option and the text-to-speech kicking in. Similarly, during testing, toggling text-to-speech off led to a notification with the word “disabled.” Reenabling the function without moving out of the accessibility menu, however, did not lead to anything suggesting text-to-speech was back on.</p><p>All told, however, it’s a good system, controlled by a discrete speed slider that ranges from 50 percent to 300 percent. The slowest rate for US English users reads at around 60–70 words per minute and the max speed, where many blind players operate, is in the region of 400–420 words per minute.</p><div><p id="what-screens-dont-support-text-to-speech-the-eshop"><h2><strong>What screens don’t support text-to-speech? The eShop</strong></h2></p></div><p>When enabling text-to-speech, you’re told the function may not be supported on all screens. As things stand, it looks like text-to-speech works across all system-level menus, but not on the Nintendo eShop. Given this is the first place most players visit after setup, that’s an oversight that needs rectifying <em>soon</em>. Most games also don’t support system-level text-to-speech, including <em>Mario Kart World</em>.</p><div><p id="can-you-adjust-the-switch-2s-audio-balance-no"><h2><strong>Can you adjust the Switch 2’s audio balance? No</strong></h2></p></div><p>Outside the ability to toggle mono audio — an important feature for hard-of-hearing players — greater audio customization is not available on the Switch 2 at a system level.</p><div><p id="does-gamechats-speech-to-text-transcribe-swearing-you-bet-it-fucking-does"><h2><strong>Does GameChat’s speech-to-text transcribe swearing? You bet it fucking does!</strong></h2></p></div><p>You may already know that GameChat’s speech-to-text will transcribe swear words. While this was reported widely as a bit of fun, it’s also an important accessibility feature that allows users — especially deaf players — to engage <em>fully </em>with in-game communication without having to decipher improper transcription and censored text.</p><p>It’s not perfect. You may find speech-to-text swaps in odd words at times, but this is an error rather than censorship of specific terms.</p><div><p id="can-you-remap-controls-at-a-system-level-yes"><h2><strong>Can you remap controls? At a system level, yes</strong></h2></p></div><p>Within the Switch 2’s settings, players can remap all inputs on connected controllers, and do so for each Joy-Con independently. You can also toggle the ability to access this menu at any time from the Switch 2’s quick menu, accessed by holding Home.</p><p>Unfortunately, current evidence suggests this option will not be present in Nintendo’s first-party games. <em>Mario Kart World </em>does not include any remapping options. Some might ask why this is a problem if system-level input rebinding exists, but in-game options for remapping are more instructive and convenient, and they limit rebindings to specific actions in-game rather than having to continuously rebind on a system level for every game. Being able to remap on the fly through the quick menu only mitigates this so much.</p><p>This is something Nintendo appears to understand, allowing remapping in the new GameCube games available to Switch Online subscribers. </p><div><p id="a-quiet-win-overall"><h2>A quiet win overall</h2></p></div><p>It all adds up to an impressive suite of accessibility features and customization that will, hopefully, grow in time. The strange part is that Nintendo is being so quiet about it. <em>The Verge </em>reached out multiple times for clarification on the Switch 2’s accessibility and for more information relating to the questions above, but Nintendo didn’t respond.</p><p>One might expect that points to an internal awareness that features aren’t as robust as they should be. Outside a few missteps, however, this is a significant accessibility win and one would think Nintendo would want it out there. More importantly, and this is a lesson to anyone releasing a device or game: players need clear accessibility information ahead of release to make informed buying decisions and secure any help that might be needed. </p><p>Nintendo’s shift to greater accessibility is welcome. But in restricting the flow of information before release, the win is tempered somewhat by Nintendo’s willingness to keep its players in the dark.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poll: Do You Three-Star-Gold Every Mario World Grand Prix Before Moving On To The Next?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-do-you-three-star-gold-every-mario-world-grand-prix-before-moving-on-to-the-next</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/poll-do-you-three-star-gold-every-mario-world-grand-prix-before-moving-on-to-the-next.1218504/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.nintendolife.com/features/poll-do-you-three-star-gold-every-mario-world-grand-prix-before-moving-on-to-the-next<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Or are you an agent of chaos?</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure><a title="MARIO KART POLL" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/3effd655ac2fb/mario-kart-poll.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>I have been wanting to ask a bunch of people this question for a while now, and it seems this is as good a time as any!</p>
<p>It's a question of gaming habits really, and how you approach doing things within them, that I'm sure holds up a mirror (mode) to our personalities in the 'real world' and all that, but I'm not a certified mind...person...so let's skip getting into anything deep.</p>
<p>No, best not. Anyway. I'm the sort of gamer who needs to stay organised, I'm also the kind of person who checks that doors are locked 50 times every night before bed. It therefore stands to reason that, when playing the likes of a <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/super_mario_kart">Super Mario Kart</a> game, let's say <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a>, since that's popular at the moment for some reason, I 100% <em>must</em> complete a cup to its fullest and shiniest gold-star level before racing the next one.</p>
<p>It is — or at least it feels as though it is — against any religion to skip forward though cups without first making sure I fully rinse the one I'm currently on. I just don't do it. Well, unless something is really frustrating me, then I <em>might</em>. Only might, mind.</p>
<p>The same thing occurs with most games I play. I can't leave a nook or cranny unexplored in open-world games (something that often puts me off them entirely) and I always feel the need to spend extra time milling about and trying to find everything before moving on - hence why Ubisoft-esque maps full of icons have the effect of making me need a 'wee lie down'.</p>
<p>So, I want to know, via the medium of a good old-fashioned poll, how many of you lot need to make sure you've done <em>everything</em> before moving on in Mario Kart's cups, and who is reckless? Who lives their lives like gaming anarchists, blasting through everything without a care in the world? You know. Having <em>fun</em>.</p>
<p>Let's get polling!</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/mario-kart/related-articles:183801,183227,181025 @ 1749985249 --></section></article><div><p>PJ is a staff writer across Pure Xbox and Nintendo Life. He's been playing video games pretty much nonstop since the early 1980s, and enjoys boring people with tedious stories about how long ago that really is.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/PJOReilly"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/pjoreilly.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('PJOReilly');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>