<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:50:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rolling Stone's GOTY List Shows A Whole Lot Of Love For One Nintendo Mascot]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/rolling-stones-goty-list-shows-a-whole-lot-of-love-for-one-nintendo-mascot</link>
            <guid>1371466</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="9723cb0e65e17"><a title="Clair Obscur" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/9723cb0e65e17/clair-obscur.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Sandfall Interactive</em></figcaption></figure><p>How on earth is it that time of year again already? It feels as though we can still sense the tight elastic of our tiny <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-air-riders">Kirby</a> swimming trunks digging into our fresh summer sunburn, and yet <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming-lists/best-video-games-of-2025-1235469710/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-1235469717/">here comes Rolling Stone with its Best of 2025 list</a>, because it's nearly Christmas. Brace for impact!</p>
<p>Yes, Rolling Stone has dropped its 25 favourite gaming experiences of the year and, whilst the number one spot is absolutely no surprise (congratulations to <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/clair_obscur_expedition_33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a>), we've been tickled pink to see that good old <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nes/donkey_kong">Donkey Kong</a> has managed to secure a number three spot via all that wrecking shop he did in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/donkey-kong-bananza-dk-island-and-emerald-rush">Bananza</a>. The big man has smashed his way onto a prestigious podium there, so well done, Mr. Kong. And nice tie!</p><div><figure data-videoid="fMx2XNyAq4E" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytfMx2XNyAq4E" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMx2XNyAq4E?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed5d98e4tmluph&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>840k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Elsewhere on the list, some 10 spaces down in fact, you'll spot another Switch 2-shaped mention in the form of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a>. Honestly, we probably wouldn't have expected that DK would outdo Master Mascot Mario in this way if you'd told us in the summer, but we'd tend to agree on the placement rolling (no pun intended) the great ape's way here.</p>
<p>What else has delighted us in making the cut? Well, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/hundred_line_-_last_defense_academy">The Hundred Line: Last Defense Academy</a> dropping into a very nice 7th place is great, as that really was one of the year's big highlights on Switch, alongside the wonderful <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/absolum">Absolum</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/ball-x-pit-nintendo-switch-2-edition">BALL x PIT</a>, and, of course, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hades-ii-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hades 2</a>, which has pulled off a blinder by snatching the number 2 spot.</p>

<p>Oh, and look at <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hollow-knight-silksong-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Silksong</a>, all the way down (if you can be all the way down on a top 25 list) at number 12. That isn't perhaps where we'd have expected to see such a massively well-reviewed game, but personal taste is a wondrous and mysterious thing, innit!</p>
<p>With a total of 11 of these games available on Switch consoles, it's still a very strong showing for Nintendo gamers - and hopefully we'll see Switch ports of some of these soon!</p>
<p>Here's the full listing for your perusal, but check out <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming-lists/best-video-games-of-2025-1235469710/">the full article</a> for details and reasoning:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</strong></li>
<li><strong>Hades II</strong></li>
<li><strong>Donkey Kong: Bananza</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/dispatch">Dispatch</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/ghost_of_yotei">Ghost of Yōtei</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/blue_prince">Blue Prince</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>The Hundred Line: Last Defense Academy</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/death_stranding_2_on_the_beach">Death Stranding 2: On The Beach</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>BALL x PIT</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/arc_raiders">Arc Raiders</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.purexbox.com/games/xbox-series-x/south_of_midnight">South of Midnight</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong</strong></li>
<li><strong>Mario Kart World</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/shinobi_art_of_vengeance">SHINOBI: Art of Vengeance</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/battlefield_6">Battlefield 6</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/ninja_gaiden_4">Ninja Gaiden 4</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/fatal_fury_city_of_the_wolves">Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>Absolum</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/despelote">despelote</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>The Séance of Blake Manor</strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/split-fiction">Split Fiction</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/citizen_sleeper_2_starward_vector">Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/rematch">Rematch</a></strong></li>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/wVCaeyucLTE?si=hfKDOOCikGYJN5I4" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer ugc"><strong>Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles</strong></a></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps5/silent_hill_f">Silent Hill: F</a></strong></li>
</ol>
<hr>
<p><em>See anything you disagree with making the cut? Think something is too highly/lowly-rated, or even missing entirely? Let us know!</em></p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:194187 @ 1764767703 --></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming-lists/best-video-games-of-2025-1235469710" rel="noopener" href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming-lists/best-video-games-of-2025-1235469710">rollingstone.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/2d372532024192dd9bfbf9d313dd6b3e @ 1764767193 --></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/rolling-stones-goty-list-shows-a-whole-lot-of-love-for-one-nintendo-mascot]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Install Size on PC Shrinks by 85% Thanks to Nixxes]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-install-size-on-pc-shrinks-by-85-percent-thanks-to-nixxes/</link>
            <guid>1371463</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The millions of players who regularly enjoy Helldivers 2 on PC (sales estimates put Steam owners at between 13 and 21 million) can rejoice, as the game's install size on this platform <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/491583942944621371" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">can now be reduced by around 85%</a>. Helldivers 2 previously took roughly 154GB of space from a drive, but Nixxes (the Dutch PC port specialist that <a href="https://wccftech.com/sony-acquires-nixxes-playstation-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was acquired by Sony in July 2021</a>) helped Arrowhead shrink it down to just 23GB, saving you 131GB of space.</p>



<p>The developers have completed several rounds of internal QA and are rolling this out as a public technical beta. Internal testing shows that, in the worst cases, mission loading times have only increased by a few seconds for the small percentage of players still using mechanical hard disk drives.</p>



<p>Before doing this, Arrowhead measured the number of players actively playing Helldivers 2 on a mechanical HDD. As of last week, it was around 11% of the total. The majority of the loading time in the game is due to level-generation rather than asset loading. This level generation occurs in parallel with loading assets from the disk, making it the primary factor in loading time. Critically, testing showed that HDD users are only getting slightly worse mission loading times, in the order of a few seconds in the worst cases. This convinced Arrowhead to go ahead with the public technical beta.</p>



<p>If everything goes well during this testing phase, the developers plan to discontinue the legacy version sometime next year. Those interested in testing the reduced install size can opt in immediately by selecting the game in their Steam library, then navigating to Properties &gt; Beta Participation and selecting prod_slim from the dropdown list.</p>



<p>Helldivers 2 is by far Sony's most significant live service success. In the span of a month since its launch in February 2024, the game <a href="https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-has-reportedly-sold-way-more-than-5-million-units/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">had already sold more than five million units across PC and PlayStation 5</a>, with the former platform accounting for the lion's share. In August 2025, the game launched even on Microsoft's Xbox Series S and X consoles and <a href="https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-xbox-sells-more-gears-of-war-reloaded-ps5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">immediately performed well over there</a>, too.</p>



<p>The most recent large update is September's Into the Unjust, which introduced new enemies, missions, and Hive Worlds.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/helldivers-2-install-size-on-pc-shrinks-by-85-percent-thanks-to-nixxes/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We played Metroid Prime 4, ask us anything]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/836580/metroid-prime-4-ask-me-anything</link>
            <guid>1371460</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTAy"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Ash Parrish</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond </em>is one of those games <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/763698/delayed-games-silksong-metroid-prime-4-2025">that been a long time coming</a>. Fans have been waiting almost a decade for the next entry in Samus’ first-person adventures. Early previews painted an <a href="https://kotaku.com/metroid-prime-4-previews-trailer-ncps-companion-2000644368">alarming picture of overly chatty sidekicks</a> ruining what’s traditionally a lonely and moody experience. Meanwhile formal reviews <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/12/02/nx-s1-5627515/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review">run</a> <a href="https://www.pcmag.com/reviews/metroid-prime-4-beyond">a gamut</a> <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review-1235475679/">of</a> <a href="https://gameinformer.com/review/metroid-prime-4-beyond/worth-the-wait">opinions</a>, leaving the game in the interesting if tiresome discourse-inducing “7 / 10” range — not perfect, not awful, but possessed of a certain<em> something</em> that makes it uniquely more interesting than many higher scoring games.</p><p>So what exactly is that something? Does <em>Metroid Prime 4</em> even have it and if it does, does it make it worth the eight-year wait? My colleague Andrew Webster (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/835325/metroid-prime-4-review-nintendo-switch">who reviewed the game</a>) and I want to answer those questions and more from <em>Verge</em> subscribers right here in the comments. Since the game isn’t out yet, we can’t answer anything too spoilery, particularly as it pertains to the story. But if you wanna know about Samus’ cool new bike, her new friends, new powers, and just what generally makes a <em>Metroid</em> game shine, just ask. We’ll pop on around 1PM ET to answer what we can in the comments.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTAy"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Ash Parrish</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/836580/metroid-prime-4-ask-me-anything]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Switch 2 Compatible Samsung microSDXC Card Is Still at Its Black Friday Pricing, Nintendo Owners Clearing Out Remaining Units]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-compatible-samsung-microsdxc-black-friday-deal-2000650000</link>
            <guid>1371457</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>There is nothing more annoying, frustrating, and heartbreaking than having to delete your old titles just to make room for new ones. We’ve all been in those situations, but there’s a simple way out. Investing in a microSD card can give your storage the boost it needs, and we just spotted a solid option going for a lot less.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5799/">The 512GB Samsung P9 Express microSD card, which is made for Nintendo Switch, is currently going at a 25% discount.</a> This brings its price down to just $75, saving you a nice $15. It’s the lowest we have seen it drop to since its release, but the offer is only around for a short time. Grab it while it’s still live, because once it’s gone, we don’t expect it to be back at this price anytime soon.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5799/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Spacious Capacity, Better Speeds</h2>
<p>Starting off with the storage; the 512GB capacity is more than enough to house all your favorite titles and other downloadable content (DLCs) that you can’t squeeze into the internal storage of your console. It’s not as massive as 1TB, sure, but unless you’re looking to store massive libraries, it’s going to be sufficient. Sequential read speeds of up to 800 MB/s make it easy to access games and get back into action (literally) up to four times faster than most other options in the same range. These speeds translate into quicker load times and much faster updates.</p>
<p>Installation couldn’t be simpler. Just turn your Nintendo Switch off, locate the kickstand on the back, and open it. Look for the dedicated slot and gently insert the card into it. Once it clicks into place, turn your console on and follow any on-screen instructions that pop up. It should be up and running within minutes!</p>



<p>The card plays nicely with Nintendo Switch 2, plus microSD UHS-I devices like computers, tablets, cameras, and select handheld consoles. It’s built to last you for years to come, thanks to its 6 layers of protection. It is waterproof (capable of withstanding up to 72 hours in seawater), temperature-proof with operating temperatures of -13 degrees Fahrenheit to 185 degrees Fahrenheit, X-Ray proof, magnetic-proof, plus drop-proof up to 16.4 feet. Even with all this, Samsung offers a limited warranty of 3 years that covers you if anything goes wrong. The card features a dynamic thermal guard that keeps it cool even during those intense sessions that demand a lot of power. To unlock its full performance, it’s best to use it with the Samsung Magician Software. It lets you verify the product’s authenticity, plus keep an eye on your drive’s health to ensure optimal performance.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5799/">All things considered, if you’ve been looking for a reliable, easy-to-use storage solution, this 512GB Samsung microSD card is an excellent option to consider, especially at this lowest price.</a> It gets you the storage you need, plus faster transfer speeds and exceptional compatibility. If 512GB is more than you need, there’s a 256GB version going for $55, but it’s not discounted. Getting your orders in now will also help you save on the delivery charges, whether you are a Prime member or not. Just be sure to act fast, as drops this massive don’t stick around forever. It’s one of the remaining Black Friday and Cyber Monday deals, and we’re expecting it to wrap within a few hours.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5799/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/switch-2-compatible-samsung-microsdxc-black-friday-deal-2000650000]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Fortnite’s Long-Awaited Ninjago Collab Finally Arrives Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/lego-fortnites-long-awaited-ninjago-collab-finally-arrives-next-week/</link>
            <guid>1371454</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>LEGO Fortnite Odyssey is finally getting the long-awaited, and heavily rumored, Ninjago collab next week, with the official account posting the first teaser.</p>



<p>Fortnite’s LEGO-themed survival mode is now entering its second full year since release, and, after a period of a huge drop in updates to the mode, the biggest collab so far is poised to be introduced.</p>







<h2 id="h-lego-fortnite-ninjago-coming-december-11">LEGO Fortnite Ninjago Coming December 11</h2>



<figure><figcaption>New island? Image via Epic Games</figcaption></figure>



<p>In a teaser post on Twitter, the official LEGO Fortnite account told players to “get ready to master a new adventure in Odyssey,” which will arrive on December 11.</p>



<p>Although it did not mention Ninjago outright, there were big teasers in the emojis that were posted alongside the message, showing an ice cube, a lightning bolt, a cloud, and a Ninja.</p>



<p>The post also confirms when Fortnite’s first major update of Chapter 7 Season 1 will be, which will also see the return of Fortnite OG with a new season, and will set the scene ahead of the Winterfest event later this month.</p>



<p>Rumors of a Ninjago collab coming to LEGO Fortnite have been widespread for a while, and the arrival of the collab will be the biggest update since the Lost Isles update in September 2024.</p>



<p>Since then, the only major update to the mode was the addition of split-screen support, and there had been discontent among the community for the lack of content updates.</p>



<p>However, the Ninjago update on December 11 should appease those concerns with a host of new content, similar to what was introduced in the Lost Isles update and the LEGO Star Wars update.</p>







<hr>



<p>What other collabs would you like to see added to LEGO Fortnite? Share your thoughts in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more Fortnite, read details about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-south-park-leak-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">upcoming South Park collaboration</a>, and check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-dark-voyager-quest-rewards-chapter-7-season-1/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to unlock all Dark Voyager (Reality Redacted) rewards.</a></p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/lego-fortnites-long-awaited-ninjago-collab-finally-arrives-next-week/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MLB The Show Mobile announced for iOS, Android]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/mlb-the-show-mobile-announced-for-ios-android</link>
            <guid>1371451</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile">Mobile</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Available now via limited regional release in the Philippines.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [5,090 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> and developer <a title="Companies > San Diego Studio [46 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment/san-diego-studio">San Diego Studio</a> have <a href="https://theshowmobile.com/" target="_blank">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > MLB The Show Mobile" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/mlb-the-show-mobile">MLB The Show Mobile</a></em>. It is available now via a limited regional release (soft launch) in the Philippines for iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/ph/app/mlb-the-show-mobile-baseball/id6474043167" target="_blank">App Store</a> and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.playstation.mlbtheshowmobile&amp;gl=ph" target="_blank">Google Play</a>. <span id="more-1010845"></span></p><p>The <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [482 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> <em>MLB The Show Mobile</em> is described as “a new standalone experience built from the ground up to deliver realistic baseball gameplay on mobile devices.”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Step up to the plate and swing for the fences in <em>MLB The Show Mobile</em>. Loaded with all-time greats, new fast-paced game modes designed for mobile, and non-stop <a title="Genres > Action [3,248 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>, the most authentic, officially licensed MLB and MLBPI baseball experience is now in the palm of your hand!</p><p>Collect. Build. Dominate. Collect more than a thousand player cards and stack your dream team with today’s superstars and historic legends like Mickey Mantle, Hank Aaron, and Ken Griffey Jr. Put your skills to the test and prove you’ve got what it takes to rule the diamond!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Realistic Batting, Pitching, and Fielding</strong><ul><li>Hit a grand slam, strike out the side, and turn the perfect double play—<em>MLB The Show Mobile</em> gives you full control of the diamond!</li><li>Skill-based controls are easy to learn, but challenging to master—your inputs determine whether you hit a home run or whiff it for a strikeout</li><li>Whether stealing 2nd base or diving for a catch, YOU decide what happens in every play!</li><li>New “Risk It” feature lets you control runners in real-time</li></ul></li><li><strong>The Ultimate <a title="Genres > Sports [683 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/sports">Sports</a> Game <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a></strong><ul><li>Built from the ground up for mobile: the most detailed and realistic way to play on the go</li><li>Compete with true-to-life versions of your favorite MLB heroes!</li><li>Immerse yourself in the action with incredible graphics and more than 16,000 unique animations!</li><li>Play in all 30 real MLB stadiums!</li><li>Feel the depth in every mechanic whether you’re pitching, batting, or fielding</li></ul></li><li><strong>Strategize With the New Momentum System</strong><ul><li>Each player card has a Momentum Cost—start innings with 10 Momentum and spend it strategically to dominate the competition!</li><li>Maintain Momentum through performance—keep the hits coming, or run out of Momentum and risk a power drop</li><li>Player stats are paired with unique abilities, unlocking endless strategic choices!</li><li>Pick your batters and pitchers in real time—don’t just set your lineup, choose the right slugger for the situation and come through in the clutch!</li></ul></li><li><strong>Build the Perfect Squad</strong><ul><li>Collect big-league stars past and present to build your ultimate roster!</li><li>Fill your bullpen with aces, stack your bench and make your lineup explosive with a growing list of more than 1,100 player cards to collect</li><li>Earn XP, upgrade players, and craft attribute bonuses to perfect your collection</li><li>Buy and sell cards directly with other players in the Marketplace!</li></ul></li><li><strong>Play New Game Modes</strong><ul><li>Dominate your rivals in best-of-three player-versus-player matchups featuring an expanding list of quick new modes designed for mobile</li><li>Experience the most iconic MLB Moments and relive baseball history</li><li>Unlock rewards through wins, daily challenges, limited-time events and the Show Pass!</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Preview Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ctcq_G3UclA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/mlb-the-show-mobile-announced-for-ios-android]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia will own 93.4 percent of EA after buyout]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/saudi-arabia-will-own-93-4-percent-of-ea-after-buyout</link>
            <guid>1371445</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">December 3, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>2 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Saudi Arabia's sovereign Public Investment Fund (PIF) is poised to become the majority owner of EA as part of a $55 billon take-private that will see an investor consortium take control of the Battlefield and Apex Legends publisher.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The deal was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/saudi-arabia-is-taking-ea-private-alongside-other-investors">announced earlier this year</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and will result in EA being acquired by a group that includes PIF, Silver Lake, and Affinity Partners, the latter of which is the investment firm established by U.S. president Donald Trump's son-in-law Jared Kushner.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The ownership group will collectively contribute $36 billion to the buyout. JP Morgan Chase Bank will provide an additional $20 billion in debt financing.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Until now, it has been unclear how ownership will be divided between members of the consortium. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.wsj.com/business/deals/saudi-fund-to-own-almost-all-of-electronic-arts-after-buyout-661e92be">As spotted by The Wall Street Journal</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, however, a new filing submitted to regulators in Brazil indicates PIF will own 93.4 percent of EA post-buyout. &nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Silver Lake and Affinity Parters will own 5.5 percent and 1.1 percent, respectively.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA has discussed the potential impact of the deal at length in a series of SEC filings and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-says-55-billion-take-private-won-t-result-in-immediate-layoffs">claims the move won't result in "immediate" layoffs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The company also told employees it will </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-says-it-will-retain-creative-control-under-new-private-owners">retain "creative control" under its new owners</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">PIF made significant inroads into the video game industry before turning its attention to EA, having previously acquired stakes in high-profile companies such as Nintendo, Koei Tecmo, Capcom, Nexon, and Take-Two.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/horses-banned-from-epic-games-store-just-24-hours-before-launch" target="_self" data-discover="true">Horses banned from Epic Games Store just 24 hours before launch</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The investment fund is chaired by Saudi Arabia's de-factor ruler and crown prince, Mohammed bin Salman—who, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-45812399">as noted by The BBC</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, was linked to the murder of Washington Post journalist Jamal Khashoggi.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Advocacy groups such as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.amnesty.org.uk/saudi-arabia-human-rights-raif-badawi-king-salman">Amnesty International</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.hrw.org/world-report/2025/country-chapters/saudi-arabia">Human Rights Watch</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> have strongly criticised Saudi Arabia's human rights record under the leadership of bin Salman, who they claim has suppressed freedom of speech by outlawing protests and demonstrations, criminalising LGBTQ+ relationships and gender expression, and discriminating against women.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Communications Workers of America president </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/cwa-president-implores-u-s-regulators-to-scrutinise-ea-buyout-to-address-national-security-and-labor-concerns">Claude Cummings Jr</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-employees-and-cwa-slam-saudi-led-ea-buyout-call-for-regulatory-scrutiny">unionized workers at EA</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> have called on regulators to scrutinise the buyout to address labor and national security concerns.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Earlier this year, Game Developer&nbsp;columnist Nicole Carpenter </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-gaming-is-the-new-oil-how-the-ea-buyout-diverges-from-the-traditional-playbook-">spoke with a number of analysts</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to better understand how the seismic deal will impact EA and the wider industry.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/saudi-arabia-will-own-93-4-percent-of-ea-after-buyout]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samus' death screams are no longer Jennifer Hale, as Dispatch actress takes over role for Metroid Prime 4: Beyond]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/samus-death-screams-are-no-longer-jennifer-hale-as-dispatch-actress-takes-over-role-for-metroid-prime-4-beyond</link>
            <guid>1371442</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Samus-from-the-Metroid-Prime-4-Beyond-keyart-reaching-out-her-hand-with-a-purple-aura-overlaid-on-an-image-of-Blonde-Blazer-in-Dispatch-wearing-a-blue-mask.-Her-eyes-are-glowing-yellow.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metroid-prime-4">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> has cast a new voice actress for Samus.</p>
<p>If (or should that be when) you succumb to the barrage of enemies that will be heading your way on Metroid Prime 4: Beyond's release tomorrow, it will not be Jennifer Hale that you will hear screaming in pain. </p>
<p>Rather for this release, Hale - who lent her vocal talents to the role of Samus in the original <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metroid-prime">Metroid Prime</a> trilogy - has instead been replaced with American stage and voice actress Erin Yvette.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>You may have already heard Yvette's voice in many of earlier works. Yvette's previous video game roles include Snow White in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/telltale-games">Telltale Games</a>' <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-wolf-among-us">The Wolf Among Us</a> by Telltale Games and Alex in Night School Studio's debut Oxenfree.</p>
<p>More recently, the actress also voiced Blonde Blazer in AdHoc's brilliant (I honestly can't recommend this game enough) superhero workplace comedy, Dispatch.</p>
<p>It is worth noting though, that while Yvette is credited with voicing Samus in Metroid Prime 4: Beyond, the character doesn't exactly talk your ear off in the game. Rather, it is more about those all important effort noises when Samus is making her way through the world, and of course that death scream. To give more context, Yvette's performance in Metroid Prime 4: Beyond is on par with Hale's own performance as Samus in Metroid Prime 3, I am reliably told.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>AdHoc</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>For more on Samus' chatter (or lack thereof), our Alex recently shared his thoughts about Metroid Prime 4: Beyond's almost silent protagonist. You can check it out here: <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-chatty-companions-silent-samus-the-problem">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond's chatty space marine companions aren't so bad - it's Samus who is this game's narrative problem</a>.</p><p>As for the game more generally, well it comes out tomorrow, so there's not too much longer to wait until you can hear Yvette's grunts in action for yourself. "Metroid Prime 4: Beyond is enjoyable enough, and has glimpses of vintage Metroid shining through, but this game could and should have been so much more," reads <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review">Eurogamer's Metroid Prime 4: Beyond review</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/samus-death-screams-are-no-longer-jennifer-hale-as-dispatch-actress-takes-over-role-for-metroid-prime-4-beyond]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resident Evil Requiem Finally Gets First Combat Footage, But Leon is Nowhere to Be Seen]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-finally-gets-first-combat-footage-but-leon-is-nowhere-to-be-seen/</link>
            <guid>1371430</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>The core survival-horror elements of Resident Evil Requiem have been showcased effectively in recent events (<a data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(16, 80, 126, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/gamescom-2025-awards-resident-evil-requiem-capcom/">such as Gamescom 2025</a>), but a crucial part of the experience, combat, has remained unseen until today. Unfortunately, the reveal wasn't accompanied by the confirmation all fans are waiting for: <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-first-trailer-hides-leon-campaign-clues-insider-claims/">the presence of Leon Kennedy in the game. </a></p>



<p>A few hours ago, new Resident Evil Requiem combat footage started making the rounds online. The short clip was shown in a series' special program which aired in Japan earlier today. This clip showcases a brand-new area and Grace fighting multiple zombies using a handgun in some third-person sequences that are highly reminiscent of Resident Evil 4. <a href="https://x.com/AestheticGamer1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">As known insider Dusk Golem</a> stressed, having aired on Japanese television, the footage was captured from a censored version of the game, so blood and gore should be as usual in the international version of the game.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">One thing I'll clarify is since this aired on Japanese television, this is 100% the censored Japanese version. RE games get a "censored" version and a "Z-Rated" version released in Japan, things like headshots/dismemberment are always censored in the Japanese non-Z rated versions</p>— AestheticGamer aka Dusk Golem (@AestheticGamer1) <a href="https://twitter.com/AestheticGamer1/status/1996166803119349812?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2025</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<h2 id="h-the-leon-kennedy-speculation-continues">The Leon Kennedy Speculation Continues</h2>



<p>With the first Resident Evil Requiem combat footage not showing Leon Kennedy in action, the window for such a critical reveal is becoming tighter. </p>



<p>In the previous months, it was speculated that the protagonist of the second and fourth main entries in the series would be the focus of the game's combat elements, and revealing his presence alongside the combat mechanics would have made a lot of sense. Hopes haven't been dashed completely, as <a href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-producer-leon-playable-demo/">game producer Masato Kumazawa recently addressed the rumors without denying them</a>, though, so there's still a chance the beloved character will be the second protagonist of Resident Evil Requiem alongside Grace Ashcroft.</p>



<p>No matter what, there's no denying that Resident Evil Requiem is looking great in the new footage. <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-gamescom-hands-on-preview-turn-on-the-lights/">The new entry in the series felt really promising when I tried it out during this year's Gamescom</a>, and I look forward to delving deeper into the darkness when the game launches on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, and Nintendo Switch on February 27.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/resident-evil-requiem-finally-gets-first-combat-footage-but-leon-is-nowhere-to-be-seen/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring Nightreign's pre-Forsaken Hollows DLC patch is out now, boosting melee attacks and fixing misbehaving churches]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-pre-forsaken-hollows-dlc-patch-is-out-now-boosting-melee-attacks-and-fixing-misbehaving-churches</link>
            <guid>1371427</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>It's also now easier to keep track of your relics and flasks</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elden-ring-nightreign-pre-forsaken-hollows-patch-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>FromSoftware</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a>'s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-the-forsaken-hollows-dlc-drops-next-month-brings-back-a-beloved-dark-souls-bumkicker">Forsaken Hollows expansion</a> arrives tomorrow, December 4th. Ahead of letting folks dive into Limveld's big hole and try out the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreign-dlcs-first-new-class-looks-great-for-book-nerds-and-grubby-old-men-lovers">new nightfarer classes</a>, FromSoft have lobbed out the customary big patch.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>This patch, 1.03, is out now and decently beefy. Looking through the notes, the studio have taken the opportunity to add a a fair amount of new features, with most being minor tweaks which make certain menus easier to parse, allow you to quickly check which relics you're rocking or how many flasks you've got left, and ensure personal objectives don't impede teaming-up. Some shop inventories have also been rearranged or added to.</p>
<p>Arguably the most noteworthy thing about the patch is that FromSoft have opted not to make nightfarer-specific tweaks as part of their latest round of balancing. Instead, stock changes to passive, special and relic effects have been drafted in, with melee attacks made more powerful, while dashing and rolling strikes have also been boosted. Meanwhile, effects that help negate damage when you're already at low health have been made less effective, which is bad news for less tanky builds.</p>
<p>Given the Forsaken Hollows is supposed to be a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-nightreign-forsaken-hollows-dlc-has-reignited-my-interest/1100-6536543/">slightly tougher cookie than the base game</a> anyway, you may want to go back to an old fashioned 'hit everyything with a big stick while cowering behind a tonne of armour plating' type of setup if you're keen to maximise your chances of not being forsakenly hollowed out.</p><p>Rounding out the patch are the usual bug fixes. FromSoft having "mitigated an issue where Sites of Grace or Churches would not activate and leveling up and adding charges to flask could not be performed under some conditions" is a welcome one. As is the rectifying of healing and enhancing effects not applying themselves to allies who happen to be busy dodging or unleashing their ultimate art.</p>
<p>You can check out the full notes rundown for the patch <a href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/elden-ring/news/elden-ring-nightreign-patch-notes-version-103">here</a>. The Forsaken Hollows is set to release on PC at 11PM GMT today, December 3rd. That's 6PM EST and 3PM PST.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/elden-ring-nightreigns-pre-forsaken-hollows-dlc-patch-is-out-now-boosting-melee-attacks-and-fixing-misbehaving-churches]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Girls’ Frontline 2: Exilium’s Anniversary Bash Is All About Huge Rewards and Hot New Features]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/girls-frontline-2-exiliums-anniversary-bash-is-all-about-huge-rewards-and-hot-new-features-2000646724</link>
            <guid>1371418</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p><span>There’s a great 1st anniversary party happening for <em>Girls’ Frontline 2: Exilium</em>, and new players and longtime franchise fans are all invited. Two huge new events, three powerful new dolls—as anniversary celebrations go, this is a big one.</span></p>
<p><span>The fireworks begin on Nov. 27 with a massive overhaul of the Crew Deck, the launch of the <em>Deep Oblivion</em> and <em>Intertwined Assault</em> events, and the debut of new dolls Leva and Lenna. <em>Deep Oblivion</em> is a two-part event, with part 2 dropping on Dec. 18 along with Robella, the third new doll. There are also huge player rewards to be found, including more than 130 pulls and over 13,000 Collapse Pieces. Needless to say, this is an event <em>GFL2</em> fans will not want to miss, and a golden opportunity for new fans to step up and experience this global phenomenon.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_2000646757" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646757"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646757">© Sunborn Games</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Inside the New Crew Deck</h2>
<p><span>The Elmo’s Crew Deck has been upgraded, and the brand-new gameplay is now live. In this updated space, Commanders will find not only fully realized 3D versions of the collectible cabinet and armory, but also a variety of new interactive story moments between Commanders and T-Dolls.</span></p>
<p><span>When the update goes live, Commanders will immediately find Makiatto’s exclusive story <em>Time Capsule: Pulse-Racing Night</em> in their inbox. If you already own Makiatto’s Embroidered Bamboo Blooming Shadows outfit, you can jump right into this free story. Klukai also gets in on the special features, with a Cerulean Breaker outfit (pictured above) that comes with a new Body Maintenance Technician item.</span></p>
<p><span>With more stories, outfits, and furniture for Commanders to invest in, the Crew Deck gets a little more homey and personalized with each addition. And with a brand-new holography function, players can actually embody select Dolls inside the Crew Dec, starting with Klukai, but with more to follow.</span></p>
<p><span>The Crew Deck is a completely new space, no longer just a menu, but an interactive showcase. Among the other anniversary-celebration innovations debuting on Nov. 27:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>3D Ornament Cabinet &amp; Armory</span></li>
<li><span>Memory Corridor for special scene collections</span></li>
<li><span>Crimson Arcade, a minigame zone</span></li>
<li><span>Interior decoration tools</span></li>
<li><span>Tea Break system to unlock extra interactions</span></li>
<li><span>Dreamscape, an atmospheric feature for additional world-building</span></li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_2000649570" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000649570"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000649570">© Sunborn Games</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Loot, Loot, and More Loot</h2>
<p><span>Normally an anniversary party involves gifts being given to the celebrants. But for <em>Girls’ Frontline 2: Exilium</em>‘s big celebration, it’s the players who will be the ones on the receiving end of a staggering amount of free stuff.</span></p>
<p><span>Commanders who participate in the full season of events are in for a serious haul, including over 130 free pulls, over 13,000 Collapse Pieces, 2 free outfits, and a massive array of other upgrade materials, tokens, and Crew Deck bonuses. When the Crew Deck Date Reward arrives on Nov. 27, that’s stacked with </span><span>35 Outfit Access Permissions, </span><span>10 Access Permissions, an Elmo Model Ornament, 300 Collapse Pieces, and multiple other growth materials.</span></p>
<p><span>Other goodies include a free Dragon Chef outfit for Qiuhua available in the Glory Store, and an automatic unlocking of Springfield’s Enjoy the Fragrance. There are more Access Permissions available by completing daily missions, through mail rewards, furniture exchange, gift packs, and the seasonal Battle Pass.</span></p>
<h2>Don’t Miss the Live-Action Trailer</h2>
<p><span>Even with all of these updates, new Dolls, and massive rewards, another exciting part of the <em>GFL2</em> 1st anniversary celebration is a live-action trailer featuring the legendary 404 Squad. The video showcases the characters’ relaxed daily life on the Crew Deck, while also featuring intense combat action.You’ll see the 404 Squad engage in desert firefights and blackout industrial battles, with Humvees, Gatling guns, and a heavily armed helicopter aiding their cause.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_2000646758" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2000646758"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2000646758">© Sunborn Games</figcaption></figure>
<p><span>Even before this giant anniversary party, it’s easy to see how <em>Girls’ Frontline 2: Exilium</em> has become such a worldwide success. Whether you’re a <em>GFL2</em> veteran or you’re just hearing all the rave reviews now and want to see what it’s all about, it’s an awesome experience on PC, or mobile on both Android and iOS devices. Commanders, join in and celebrate the anniversary!</span></p>
      </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/girls-frontline-2-exiliums-anniversary-bash-is-all-about-huge-rewards-and-hot-new-features-2000646724]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horses Is The New Viral Horror Game Banned On Steam & Epic Games Store]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/horses-is-the-new-viral-horror-game-banned-on-steam-epic-games-store/</link>
            <guid>1371412</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Horses was banned at the final hour by Steam and the Epic Games Store due to the game’s unsettling and controversial content, but you can still buy the viral horror title.</p>



<p>The initial premise of Horses seems quite simple: You’re on a two-week break working at a farm. You perform standard tasks, such as feeding the farmer’s dog and tending to the ‘horses.’ It becomes quickly apparent that they aren’t normal horses, and the game quickly descends into a host of horrifying and inhumane themes.</p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-indie-game-deals-holiday-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam</a> and Epic didn’t like this much.</p>







<h2 id="h-you-can-still-buy-horses-elsewhere">You Can Still Buy Horses Elsewhere</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Yes, a carrot. Credit to Santa Ragione Game Studio</figcaption></figure>



<p>Mere hours before its launch, <a href="https://www.horses.wtf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Horses</a> was banned from Steam and the Epic Games Store. If anything, this has furthered the game’s profile with people desperate to understand why.</p>







<p>Take a look at this content warning on the Horses website to get an idea of what to expect:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>“This game contains scenes of physical violence, psychological abuse, gory imagery (mutilation, blood), depictions of slavery, physical and psychological torture, domestic abuse, sexual assault, suicide, and misogyny.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Insider Gaming has seen lots of the game’s footage and the aforementioned content—it’s just as perturbing and disturbing as you can imagine. The Epic Games Store says Horses is still “Coming Soon,” but you don’t have to wait, as the horror game is available to buy on GOG. </p>



<p>The ban decisions could be overturned in the future, especially if Santa Ragione Game Studio fights back, and popularity in the title explodes. Insider Gaming will continue to monitor Horses’ status.</p>



<p>If you’ve played Horses, now’s your chance to share. Is the full game as psychologically damaging as it’s made out to be? Was Steam and the Epic Games Store right to ban it? Share your experience with everyone through the free <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more news and content, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-artist-satisfied/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Artist Who Says Bungie’s Marathon Plagiarism Issue has Been ‘Resolved’</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-resident-evil-requiem-gameplay-shown-exclusively-in-japan-reveals-new-location/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">New Resident Evil Requiem Gameplay Shown Exclusively In Japan, Revealing A New Location</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/horses-is-the-new-viral-horror-game-banned-on-steam-epic-games-store/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Artist Says Bungie’s Marathon Plagiarism Issue has Been ‘Resolved to my Satisfaction’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-artist-satisfied/</link>
            <guid>1371409</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>An artist whose art was stolen by Bungie’s Marathon has now claimed that the issue with Bungie and Sony has been resolved to her satisfaction.</p>



<p>The news came more than six months after the artist took to <a href="https://x.com/4nt1r34l/status/1995907613004018047" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter) to say that Bungie had used the assets she created in 2017 without permission. Back then, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/artist-accuses-bungie-of-plagiarizing-work-for-marathon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">she claimed</a>, “The Marathon alpha released recently, and its environments are covered with assets lifted from poster designs I made in 2017.”</p>



<div><p>The claim was almost immediately picked up by Bungie, who said,</p><p>“We immediately investigated a concern regarding unauthorized use of artist decals in Marathon and confirmed that a former Bungie artist included these in a texture sheet that was ultimately used in-game.</p></div>



<p>This issue was unknown by our existing art team, and we are still reviewing how this oversight occurred. We take matters like this very seriously. We have reached out to @4nt1r34l to discuss this issue and are committed to do right by the artist.</p>



<p>As a matter of policy, we do not use the work of artists without their permission.</p>



<p>To prevent similar issues in the future, we are conducting a thorough review of our in-game assets, specifically those done by the former Bungie artist, and implementing stricter checks to document all artist contributions.</p>



<p>We value the creativity and dedication of all artists who contribute to our games, and we are committed to doing right by them. Thank you for bringing this to our attention.”</p>



<div><p> But now, the issue has been fully resolved, with the artist saying,</p><p>“The Marathon art issue has been resolved with Bungie and Sony Interactive Entertainment to my satisfaction.”</p></div>



<p>As to the extent the issue was resolved, that will likely never be shared, but Sony and Bungie have seemingly gone to great lengths to ensure the artist has been fully compensated and/or reached an agreement. </p>



<p>Bungie’s Marathon is scheduled to release by the end of this fiscal year (by April 1st, 2026).</p>



<p>What do you think the artist got to resolve the issue? Let us know on the&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Official Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>There’s much more news to check out at Insider Gaming, such as&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-south-park-leak-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new Fortnite Leak detailing the upcoming South Park collaboration</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metroid-prime-4-beyond-is-the-lowest-reviewed-game-in-the-series/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond being the lowest-reviewed game in the series</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/marathon-artist-satisfied/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Of Course We're Not Going to Stop Here' — Monster Hunter Developers Talk About the Future of the Series at PlayStation Awards]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/of-course-were-not-going-to-stop-here-monster-hunter-developers-talk-about-the-future-of-the-series-at-playstation-awards</link>
            <guid>1371406</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"We want to let more people play."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">At the PlayStation Partner Awards 2025 Japan Asia held in Tokyo on December 3, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> won the Grand Award and the User's Choice Award. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">In an interview held before the award ceremony, Ryozo Tsujimoto, the producer of this work, and Yuya Tokuda, the director, answered questions from local media. IGN Japan was in attendance. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">When Monster Hunter Wilds was first released on February 28, some players left harsh feedback, but Tokuda said the team worked to improve the game by taking advantage of that feedback.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Immediately after the release, we apologized for the inconvenience caused by the volume of content and the difficulty level. Despite this, we were delighted to receive various awards, including Users' Choice awards. We would like to thank all the players who have given their opinions and spoken warm words even in this situation. The development team was able to turn everyone's feedback into an asset and work on the update with all our strength, and I think the result was also the reason why players voted for us," said Tokuda.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/12/03/img-3587-1764763663206.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Yuya Tokuda (left) and Ryozo Tsujimoto (right) at the PlayStation Partner Awards 2025 Japan Asia held in Tokyo on December 3. Image credit: IGN.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Monster Hunter has the characteristics of a title that gets regular updates, but player opinions were very helpful during the update process, and in order to make Monster Hunter Wilds better, the fans’ voices gave us power. There are still updates left to come, so we will continue to do our best," added Tsujimoto.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Monster Hunter series celebrated its 20th anniversary last year. The franchise was a hit in Japan, and after the release of Monster Hunter: World in 2018, it grew into a literal monster title overseas. According to Tokuda, the Monster Hunter Wilds team were more aware than ever of being accepted by newcomers or those who had trouble beating the games. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"We analyzed what kind of places beginners were stuck in, including Monster Hunter: World. We have worked on these points in turn to make it easier for new users to clear hurdles such as being able to reach certain monsters or to craft certain types of armor. In addition, we have tried to adopt as many new elements as possible that are beneficial for both beginners and existing users, such as Focus Mode. This time, as a result of making the game easy to beat even for new players and players who could not clear it before, I think the difficulty curve was a little lacking for existing users,” said Tokuda. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Tokuda said the team has focused on creating more difficult content with each update. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"If you beat the game immediately after its release and stopped playing, I would appreciate it if you could pick it up again," said Tokuda.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Monster Hunter Wilds still has updates to come, but Tsujimoto also talked a little about the future of the series.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Of course, we don’t intend to stop the series here. We plan to continue, and we want to let more people play. In addition, I would like to think about things beyond the games so that we can further expand the potential of the Monster Hunter IP," said Tsujimoto.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">All Low Rank Armor in Monster Hunter Wilds</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">From Tsujimoto's remarks, it seems we can continue to look forward to new games and more in the Monster Hunter series. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Tsujimoto was also asked where Monster Hunter stands within the overall catalog of Capcom IP, which he answered diplomatically. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Capcom is a company with various IPs, and every IP is very important. I'm in charge of Monster Hunter now, that’s all I can comment on, but as Capcom, we want to expand all our IPs,” he said. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Capcom is scheduled to release Resident Evil Requiem, Onimusha Way of the Sword, and Pragmata in 2026.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is Director, News at IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/of-course-were-not-going-to-stop-here-monster-hunter-developers-talk-about-the-future-of-the-series-at-playstation-awards]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Partner Awards 2025 Japan Asia winners announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/playstation-partner-awards-2025-japan-asia-winners-announced</link>
            <guid>1371403</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO, Monster Hunter Wilds, and more take home the Grand Award.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p><a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [5,090 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> Japan Asia has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2025/12/03/playstation-partner-awards-2025-japan-asia-winners-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> the winners of <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [49,096 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Partner Awards 2025 Japan Asia.</p><p>The winners are as follows:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Grand Award</strong></p><p>Awarded to the top three titles developed in the Japan / Asian regions with highest worldwide sales between October 1, 2024 and September 30, 2025.</p><p>Winners:</p><ul><li><em>eFootball</em> (<a title="Companies > Konami Digital Entertainment [1,154 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/konami">Konami Digital Entertainment</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-ball-sparking-zero">Dragon Ball: Sparking! ZERO</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,800 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco Entertainment</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Marvel Rivals [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/marvel-rivals">Marvel Rivals</a></em> (<a title="Companies > NetEase Games [391 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/netease-games">NetEase Games</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Monster Hunter Wilds [42 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Capcom [2,636 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/capcom">Capcom</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Zenless Zone Zero [29 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/zenless-zone-zero">Zenless Zone Zero</a></em> (<a title="Companies > miHoYo [216 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mihoyo">miHoYo</a>)</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Partner Award</strong></p><p>Awarded to titles developed in the Japan / Asia region with top-ranked worldwide sales between October 1, 2024 and September 30, 2025, with particularly noteworthy activity results.</p><p>Winners:</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Elden Ring Nightreign [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/elden-ring-nightreign">Elden Ring Nightreign</a></em> (<a title="Companies > FromSoftware [408 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kadokawa-corporation/fromsoftware">FromSoftware</a> / Bandai Namco Entertainment)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater">Metal Gear Solid Delta: Snake Eater</a></em>&nbsp;(Konami Digital Entertainment)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Path of Exile II [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/path-of-exile-ii">Path of Exile II</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Grinding Gear Games [11 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/tencent/grinding-gear-games">Grinding Gear Games</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Silent Hill f [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/silent-hill-f">Silent Hill f</a></em> (Konami Digital Entertainment)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Wuthering Waves [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/wuthering-waves">Wuthering Waves</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Kuro Games [21 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kuro-games">Kuro Games</a>)</li></ul><p><strong>Accessibility Award</strong></p><p>Awarded to titles with outstanding accessibility features.</p><p>Winners:</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii">Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii</a></em> (<a title="Companies > SEGA [2,720 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sega">SEGA</a>)</li><li><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> (Capcom)</li></ul><p><strong>PlayStation Indies Award</strong></p><p>Awarded to the top titles chosen by users in the Japan / Asia regions. The title candidates are selected as outstanding independent titles produced in Japan or Asia.</p><p>Winners:</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > ENDER MAGNOLIA: Bloom in the Mist [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ender-magnolia-bloom-in-the-mist">ENDER MAGNOLIA: Bloom in the Mist</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Binary Haze Interactive [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/binary-haze-interactive">Binary Haze Interactive</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Nine Sols [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/nine-sols">Nine Sols</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Red Candle Games [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/red-candle-games">Red Candle Games</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Urban Myth Dissolution Center [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/urban-myth-dissolution-center">Urban Myth Dissolution Center</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Hakaba Bunko [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hakaba-bunko">Hakaba Bunko</a> / <a title="Companies > Shueisha Games [48 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/shueisha-games">Shueisha Games</a>)</li></ul><p><strong>Users’ Choice Award</strong></p><p>Awarded to the top titles chosen by users in the Japan / Asia regions. The title candidates are directly taken from the top 30 titles released between October 1, 2024 and September 30, 2025, ranked by the total number of hours played in the Japan / Asia region.</p><p>Winners:</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Sandfall Interactive [15 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sandfall-interactive">Sandfall Interactive</a> / <a title="Companies > Kepler Interactive [56 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kepler-interactive">Kepler Interactive</a>)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Dynasty Warriors: Origins [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dynasty-warriors-origins">Dynasty Warriors: Origins</a></em> (<a title="Companies > Omega Force [1,254 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games/omega-force">Omega Force</a> / <a title="Companies > Koei Tecmo Games [3,114 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games">Koei Tecmo</a>)</li><li><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> (Capcom)</li><li><em>Silent Hill f</em> (<a title="Companies > NeoBards Entertainment [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/neobards-entertainment">NeoBards Entertainment</a> / Konami)</li><li><em>Wuthering Waves</em> (Kuro Games)</li></ul></blockquote></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/playstation-partner-awards-2025-japan-asia-winners-announced]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starsand Island adds Switch 2 version]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/starsand-island-adds-switch-2-version</link>
            <guid>1371397</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Includes Game Chat and mouse control support.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Platforms > Anime [329 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/anime">Anime</a>-inspired life and farming <a title="Genres > Simulation [888 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Starsand Island [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/starsand-island">Starsand Island</a></em> will launch for Switch 2 alongside its previously announced PlayStation 5, Xbox Series, and PC (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2966320/Starsand_Island/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-us/games/store/starsand-island/9p86lldcl5cc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Microsoft Store</a>) versions in early 2026, developer <a title="Companies > Seed Lab [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/seed-lab">Seed Lab</a>&nbsp; announced. <span id="more-1010804"></span></p><p>The Switch 2 version of Starsand Island will take full advantage of the console’s hardware, offering a “Quality Mode” targeting 45 frames per second in 1080p resolution, and a “Performance Mode” targeting 60 frames per second in 1080p resolution (both docked and handheld), as well as Game Chat during online <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [647 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a>, and mouse control functionality.</p><p>“Bringing <strong>Starsand Island</strong> to <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [737 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Nintendo Switch 2</a> has been a longstanding goal for us; the life-sim genre has a natural home on <a title="Platforms > Nintendo [23,207 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo">Nintendo</a> consoles,” said Seed Lab creative director Richardo Wang in a press release. “Even before it was announced nearly a year ago, we knew—and wanted—our game to be on Nintendo’s next-generation platform. <em>Starsand Island</em> transports players to a simple, pastoral life, and we think that should be available whether they’re at home, commuting to and from work, or taking a break.”</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Seasonal Gameplay and a Cross-Cultural Countryside Journey</span></h2><p><iframe title="Starsand Island | Seasonal Gameplay &amp; A Cross-Cultural Countryside Journey" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dYLKTfy-M-g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/12/starsand-island-adds-switch-2-version]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metroid Prime 4: Beyond Has Been Updated To Ver. 1.1.0, Here Are The Full Patch Notes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/metroid-prime-4-beyond-has-been-updated-to-ver-1-1-0-here-are-the-full-patch-notes</link>
            <guid>1371385</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>A launch day special</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="8f55a0ad19c46"><a title="Metroid Prime 4: Beyond" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/8f55a0ad19c46/metroid-prime-4-beyond.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure><p>Eight years on from its big reveal, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/metroid_prime_4_beyond">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> finally arrives on Switch 1 &amp; 2 tomorrow. To make sure that things are in tip-top condition, Nintendo has today released the launch day update, boosting things up to ver. 1.1.0 and adding a bunch of day-one features to boot.</p>
<p>This update adds in amiibo functionality, some sweet cinematic controller rumble, an easily accessible upgrade path to the Switch 2 Edition in the opening menu, some gallery tweaks, and then the usual adjustments and fixes.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, the patch notes have only been shared on the <a href="https://support.nintendo.com/jp/switch/software_support/bgw5a/110/index.html">Japanese Nintendo Support website</a>. We have included those below (via Google Translate), and we will sub-in the official English translation as soon as it is available.</p>
<h2>Metroid Prime 4: Beyond Ver. 1.1.0 (3rd Dec 2025)</h2>
<ul>
<li>You can now use amiibo on the "amiibo" page in the pause menu.</li>
<li>Controller now vibrates during cinematics.</li>
<li><strong>[Switch 2]</strong>: When you start up Metroid Prime 4 Beyond on Nintendo Switch 2, a "Switch 2 Edition" option will now appear in the menu after the title screen. Selecting this option will take you to the Upgrade Path page on the Nintendo eShop.</li>
<li>The rating information for the rating system "ClassInd (Brazil)" has been updated from "12" to "14".</li>
<li>The condition for unlocking some movies in the "Gallery" has been changed from "achieving 100% item recovery rate" to "clearing the game."</li>
<li>In "Hard Mode," the difficulty of some enemies has been adjusted.</li>
<li>Additionally, we have made some adjustments and fixes to improve your gameplay experience.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>"After 18 years of waiting, Metroid Prime 4: Beyond manages to replicate that magical sense of discovery from the GameCube original while pushing the series in some incredible new directions," we wrote in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">our 9/10 review</a>, describing Samus' latest adventure as "quite possibly the boldest, most well-realised Metroid game to date". Just one more sleep to go!</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-articles:194214,194706 @ 1764768620 -->
<p><em>Are you ready to dive into Prime 4 tomorrow? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://support.nintendo.com/jp/switch/software_support/bgw5a/110/index.html" rel="noopener" href="https://support.nintendo.com/jp/switch/software_support/bgw5a/110/index.html">support.nintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch/related-info/ef57e1d0836b33f196522fde222423a6 @ 1764768585 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/metroid-prime-4-beyond-has-been-updated-to-ver-1-1-0-here-are-the-full-patch-notes]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mario Kart World update 1.4.0 adds custom items, changes course layouts & more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/03/mario-kart-world-update-1-4-0-adds-custom-items-changes-course-layouts-more/</link>
            <guid>1371382</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Nintendo has released <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> update 1.4.0, making a big bunch of changes and bug fixes to the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/nintendo-switch-2">Switch 2’s</a> biggest game.</p>
<p>Amongst the changes are a new custom items rule setting, which lets you pick exactly which items appear in your game – this is really handy for anyone chasing the last few Kamek transformation character!</p>


<p>There’s also an improved way to join up and play multiplayer with friends, as up to four players gathered together in a “Room” can all take part in Race, Knockout Tour and Battle, and you can also join people playing Knockout Tour when in 2P and Online as well.</p>
<p>Nintendo has also changed the course layout for eight of the Intermission style point-to-point races involving Koopa Troopa Beach. All the races heading there will now have two laps of Koopa Troopa Beach once you get there. We hope this is a sign of more changes to come!</p>
<p>Here’s the full patch notes for Mario Kart World update 1.4.0:</p>

<p><strong>General</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added “Custom Items” to the item rules.
<ul>
<li>This is a feature that lets you set which items appear.</li>
<li>This is supported in “VS Race”, “Balloon Battle”, “Coin Runners”, and “Room” in “Online Play” or “Wireless Play”.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Made it so that music track name and source title of the track that is playing will be displayed on the Pause Menu.</li>
<li>Added “Music Volume” to “Settings/Controller”.</li>
<li>Made it so players who gathered in a “Room” of “Online Play” can participate in “Race”, “Knockout Tour”, and “Battle”.
<ul>
<li>Up to 4 players can participate in “Race”, “Knockout Tour”, and “Battle”.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Made it so you can join in with friends who are playing “Knockout Tour” from “Friends” in “2p”, “Online Play” as well.</li>
<li>Added “Restart” and “Next Race” in the Pause Menu for “VS Race” in “Single Player”.</li>
<li>Made it so you can select “Photo Mode” from the Pause Menu in “Race against Ghost” in “Time Trials”.</li>
<li>Changed the course layout of below courses for “VS Race”, or “Race” in “Online Play” or “Wireless Play”.
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li>Race that heads from “Koopa Troopa Beach” to “DK Spaceport”.</li>
<li>Race that heads from “Koopa Troopa Beach” to “Crown City”.</li>
<li>Race that heads from “Koopa Troopa Beach” to “Peach Stadium”.</li>
<li>Race that heads from “Whistlestop Summit” to “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</li>
<li>Race that heads from “Desert Hills” to “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</li>
<li>Race that heads from “DK Spaceport” to “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</li>
<li>Race that heads from “Crown City” to “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</li>
<li>Race that heads from “Peach Stadium” to “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>*Changed it so that, in all races heading toward “Koopa Troopa Beach”, including the above courses, you will cross the finish line after two laps once you arrive at “Koopa Troopa Beach”.</p></li>
<li>You will now dash when riding on Manta Ramp’s back.</li>
<li>Made it so the player will not hit Dragoneel when transformed into Bullet Bill.</li>
<li>Made it so the player cannot use a second Boo while already using a Boo, when holding two Boos.</li>
<li>When Dash Food is taken by someone, shortened the time until that Dash Food reappears.</li>
<li>When a coin placed on water is taken by someone, shortened the time until that coin reappears.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Fixed Issues</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where the dash time was not correct after a Charge Jump.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through a wall when being stomped on from above by a vehicle driving on the road.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a player would be squashed when touching a Thwomp that had landed.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a Bullet Bill would not be displayed after using it.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a character would be blurry even when making “Focus” “Character” when taking a photo in “Photo Mode” on the Pause Menu.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the screen would look distorted if entering a pipe at the same time as joining a Free Roam in “Online Play”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where player could not get in a UFO when multiple players tried to get in a UFO at the same time in Free Roam in “Online Play”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a friend’s information would not be updated when looking at the list of friends in “Friends” in “Online Play”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where there would be a communication error when looking at a group ID in “View Room Info” when participating in a group in “Friends” in “Online Play”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a player’s place would go down if retiring during “Knockout Tour” in “Online Play”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a player that is seen when spectating looks like they are going off the course over and over during “Knockout Tour” in “Online Play” or “Wireless Play”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player’s own character or vehicle would change when starting “Online Play” or “Wireless Play” again after quitting a game after “Knockout Tour” in “Online Play” or “Wireless Play”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a player would get stuck on a wall when using a Bullet Bill while falling off the course in “Sky-High Sundae”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a Bullet Bill would go outside the course when using it on the final curve in “Boo Cinema”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through a bulldozer in “Toad’s Factory”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on a spotlight in the race that heads from “Toad’s Factory” to “Bowser’s Castle” when transformed into Bullet Bill.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where if the player used a Bullet Bill or Spiny Shell in the first curve of “Desert Hills”, it would get stuck on a rock.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on a tree when using a Bullet Bill on “DK Pass”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, when the player was small because of Lightning, they would slip through the wall on the final curve of “DK Pass.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on a billboard when transforming into Bullet Bill in the race that heads from “Crown City” to “Desert Hills”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through the ring of stone when using a Bullet Bill or Mega Mushroom while falling in “Great ? Block Ruins” right before the final curve.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on the ground on the meadows near “Big Donut”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through the wall if rewinding after wall riding in the special room you can go to from a pipe in “Shy Guy Bazaar”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would still fall into the lava even though they have “Smart Steering” ON in “Dry Bones Burnout”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course when using a Bullet Bill while rail riding in “Wario Stadium”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would not be able to glide if getting on a glide panel while gliding in the race that heads from “Wario Stadium” to “Airship Fortress”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on the ground while heading from “Wario Stadium” to “Airship Fortress”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the vehicle would float up from the rail when the player did a rail ride after a wall ride in a bike-type vehicle in “Wario Stadium”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course when using a Bullet Bill on the shortcut while heading from “Dandelion Depths” to “Cheep Cheep Falls” in the “Ice Rally” of “Knockout Tour”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course while gliding, while heading from “Dandelion Depths” to “Cheep Cheep Falls” in the “Moon Rally” of “Knockout Tour”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a green shell would get stuck on the ground while heading from “Airship Fortress” to “Dry Bones Burnout” in the “Heart Rally” of “Knockout Tour”.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course when they transformed into Bullet Bill on top of a building in “Crown City” in the below races:
<ul>
<li>Race that heads from “DK Spaceport” to “Crown City”.</li>
<li>Race that heads from “Koopa Troopa Beach” to “Crown City”.</li>
<li>Race that heads from “Faraway Oasis” to “Crown City”.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Several other issues have been addressed to improve the gameplay experience.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://en-americas-support.nintendo.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/68580/~/how-to-update-mario-kart-world">Nintendo</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/03/mario-kart-world-update-1-4-0-adds-custom-items-changes-course-layouts-more/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't expect a SteamOS phone after the Steam Machine, Valve engineer says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-expect-a-steamos-phone-after-the-steam-machine-valve-engineer-says</link>
            <guid>1371379</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Though the Steam Frame's compatibility tech is helping smooth out Windows-to-Android emulation</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gamehub-Silksong.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gamehub-Silksong.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gamehub-Silksong.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gamehub-Silksong.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gamehub-Silksong.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gamehub-Silksong.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gamehub-Silksong.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gamehub-Silksong.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Gamehub-Silksong.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Valve’s quiet bankrolling of open-source emulation tools could make it heaps easier to play your PC games library on a humble smartphone, though it sounds like Gabe-made SteamOS phones are unlikely to be joining the company’s <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/valve-announce-a-new-steam-machine-steam-controller-and-the-steam-frame-vr-headset-and-ive-played-them">growing hardware catalogue</a>. In an interview with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/report/820656/valve-interview-arm-gaming-steamos-pierre-loup-griffais">The Verge</a>, Valve engineer Pierre-Loup Griffais confirmed that they’ve been funding the development of Fex – a free compatibility tool that gets Windows apps functioning on mobile ARM processors – since well before revealing the ARM-based <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-steam-frame-is-real-and-valve-want-it-to-be-the-last-vr-headset-youll-ever-buy">Steam Frame</a> standalone VR headset.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Valve's bundling Fex into SteamOS so the Frame, due in 2026, can run Steam games straight off the headset’s internal chip. But it is already out in the wild right now – i.e. <a href="https://github.com/FEX-Emu/FEX">GitHub</a> –, and has a promising future in bringing those very same games to Android phones. Just not, Griffais says, phones with a Steam logo on them.</p>
<p>"I don’t know if that’s going to be a big focus for us to develop local content or try to develop SteamOS for devices like that" he explains. "I mean, I’m not discounting any possibility, but I think with just living room, handheld, and desktop, trying to have a good outcome for gaming applications and everything else you’d want to do in a desktop, we have a ton of work to do."</p>
<p>The living room and handheld formats clearly refer to, respectively, the upcoming <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hands-on-with-the-new-steam-machine-valves-square-shot-at-steamos-pc-redemption">Steam Machine</a> and the existing <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-steam-deck-games">Steam Deck</a>. But these are both based on x86 processors, much like a regular Windows PC or laptop. It’s ARM hardware, the diesel to x86’s unleaded, that Fex and the Frame are trying to crack – <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/it-just-works-valve-talk-the-steam-frame-android-games-on-steamos-and-putting-a-pc-on-your-face">with at least some success</a>, judging by the slickness with which <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hades-2">Hades 2</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/hollow-knight-silksong-walkthrough">Hollow Knight: Silksong</a> ran on the Frame when I tried it at Valve’s offices last month.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Steam phone or no, Fex may fulfil that promise of Steam games on mobile. It is, for instance, one of multiple x86 emulation layers employed by <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.xiaoji.egggame&amp;hl=en_GB">Gamehub</a>, an Android game launcher app produced by Chinese peripheral makers GameSir. I’ve tried this on my Pixel 9 and admittedly haven’t had much luck, even with the games I know work well on the Steam Frame: Hades 2 crashes immediately and Silksong gets stuck on an endless launching screen. Also, there’s a non-zero possibility that I’ve handed over my Gmail and Steam account details to the Chinese Communist Party. C'est la vie. You <a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=gamehub">don’t have to look far</a>, mind, for folks who’ve used Gamehub to get Androidified Steam games up and running, including the author of that Verge piece.</p><p>Hopefully this cross-device compatibility push continues apace; Valve obviously have a business interest in getting Steam games (uhhhh, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/saturnalia-creators-santa-ragione-will-wind-down-operations-after-valve-ban-horror-game-horses-from-steam">sorry Horses</a>) playable on as many computery doohickeys as possible, but kicking down compatibility barriers and spreading software across devices of the user’s choosing is good for the common gamesplayer as well.</p>
</div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-expect-a-steamos-phone-after-the-steam-machine-valve-engineer-says]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Galaxy Watch 8 Classic Stays at Its Cyber Monday Low as Samsung Quietly Clears Leftover Black Friday Stock]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/galaxy-watch-8-classic-stays-at-its-cyber-monday-low-as-samsung-quietly-clears-leftover-black-friday-stock-2000649660</link>
            <guid>1371376</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p data-start="96" data-end="911">Making progress in any sport really comes down to knowing your numbers. If you want to improve, you need a solid idea of what you’re working toward and a convenient way to keep an eye on it. Whether you’re just getting into running and hitting your favorite trails, jumping in open water for triathlon training, or biking some hills, a reliable GPS watch can make all the difference. It helps you stay motivated, stay on track, and avoid losing steam. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6183/">Conveniently, Samsung’s newly released 2025 version of its smartwatch—the Galaxy Watch 8 Classic—is still on sale post Black Friday and Cyber Monday</a>. This watch normally goes for $500, but right now you can grab it for 20% off, bringing it down to $400. You end up saving yourself a whole $100.</p>
<p data-start="96" data-end="911">Now this is the Classic model of the Watch 8. What’s different about it? First up, it’s much bigger. The standard models come in either 40mm or 44mm. This watch face measures across at 46mm. But more noticeable that that, the watch has a metal casing. The new lug system allows for easy band detachment and replacement. So when you’re not working out, this watch maintains a professional work you could even pair nicely with a suit. Then when it’s time to hit the pavement in your running attire, swap out the band for a silicone one, easily.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6183/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2 data-start="913" data-end="946">A Fitness Coach on Your Wrist</h2>
<p data-start="948" data-end="1552">The Galaxy Watch 8 runs on Samsung’s Galaxy AI platform, which helps it deliver smarter health and fitness tracking. Whenever you head out for a ride, run, hike, or any sort of outdoor workout, the watch can keep tabs on how you’re performing in real time and compare it to your past sessions. Throughout the day, it can nudge you with personalized wellness suggestions to help you steadily move toward your fitness and health goals. The improved heart-rate tracking is also a big upgrade. It filters out the noise from natural body motion, giving you a more accurate reading than previous Samsung watches.</p>
<p data-start="1554" data-end="1991">Your sleep gets just as much attention. The Watch 8 tracks your patterns closely enough to flag possible signs of sleep apnea and gives you a much clearer look at how well you’re actually resting each night. When you wake up, you get a quick snapshot of your energy level and readiness for the day. It combines details like your sleep score, steps, heart-rate behavior, and more to give you a realistic picture of where your body stands.</p>


<p data-start="1993" data-end="2450">Of course, it’s not just about fitness. The Galaxy Watch 8 works great as a full-blown smartwatch for everyday life. You can read and respond to messages straight from your wrist without fishing your phone out of your pocket. And if it’s paired with your phone, the watch becomes a remote camera controller—perfect for group shots or selfies at a distance. You can change settings, hit the timer, and take the picture all from the watch.</p>
<p data-start="2485" data-end="2997">The new Watch 8 can hit up to 3,000 nits, while the Watch 7 maxes out at 2,000 nits. That extra brightness makes a big difference when you’re checking stats under direct sunlight. Both models are still tough enough for all-weather training, whether you’re out in the cold, the rain, or the heat.</p>
<p data-start="3279" data-end="3522"><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6183/">The Galaxy Watch 8 is also designed from the ground up to work with Gemini, the AI assistant built by Samsung and Google</a>. You can use it to check your schedule, reply to texts, set reminders, and handle a bunch of everyday tasks with ease.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6183/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/galaxy-watch-8-classic-stays-at-its-cyber-monday-low-as-samsung-quietly-clears-leftover-black-friday-stock-2000649660]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest creator "can't talk about" future Chrono Trigger plans, sparking more remake speculation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-quest-creator-future-chrono-trigger-plans-remake-speculation</link>
            <guid>1371373</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/CHRONO-TRIGGER-%E2%80%93-Launch-Trailer-0-38-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/CHRONO-TRIGGER-%E2%80%93-Launch-Trailer-0-38-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/CHRONO-TRIGGER-%E2%80%93-Launch-Trailer-0-38-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/CHRONO-TRIGGER-%E2%80%93-Launch-Trailer-0-38-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/CHRONO-TRIGGER-%E2%80%93-Launch-Trailer-0-38-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/CHRONO-TRIGGER-%E2%80%93-Launch-Trailer-0-38-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/CHRONO-TRIGGER-%E2%80%93-Launch-Trailer-0-38-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/CHRONO-TRIGGER-%E2%80%93-Launch-Trailer-0-38-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/CHRONO-TRIGGER-%E2%80%93-Launch-Trailer-0-38-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Square Enix</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Dragon Quest creator Yuji Horii has said he "can't talk about" future plans for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/chrono-trigger">Chrono Trigger</a>, suggesting something is indeed in the works.</p>
<p>Though best known for Dragon Quest, Horii was a supervisor on the celebrated Chrono Trigger, which is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-celebrating-chrono-trigger-anniversary-with-new-projects-sparking-re-release-hopes">celebrating its 30th anniversary this year</a>.</p>
<p>During Horii's latest talk show livestream KosoKoso Hōsō Kyoku, he was asked about current buzz surrounding Chrono Trigger and whether this was "foreshadowing" a bigger announcement (thanks <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/chrono-triggers-original-supervisor-yuji-horii-says-i-cant-talk-about-it-dont-ask-and-ill-get-in-trouble-when-asked-about-new-developments/">Automaton</a>).</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="CHRONO TRIGGER – Launch Trailer" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2fl-AylaHY8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>CHRONO TRIGGER – Launch Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2fl-AylaHY8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2fl-AylaHY8?autoplay=1" title="CHRONO TRIGGER – Launch Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>CHRONO TRIGGER – Launch Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2fl-AylaHY8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p>Horii was also joined by former editor of Shonen Jump Kazuhiko Torishima, who noted a number of Chrono Trigger-related projects that were previously announced, including a concert series planned for next year. Torishima asked Horii if there would be any developments in the franchise.</p><p>"I can't talk about that," said Horii, becoming flustered. He added: "Wait, if I say that, you'll figure it out!", "Don't ask!", "Asking is off-limits!", and "I'll get in trouble!", to which the panel collectively laughed. Torishima cheekily replied: "There's something".</p>
<p>It would seem, then, there's at least something in the works, even if Horii remains tight-lipped on any details.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="【11/30(日)生配信】㊗️堀井雄二「旭日小綬章」受章！｜マクロン大統領の写真が！？｜「DRAGON BALL STORE」に行ってみた！｜「ドラクエ1&amp;2 リメイク」やってみた！" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nq1II1jaiuA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>【11/30(日)生配信】㊗️堀井雄二「旭日小綬章」受章！｜マクロン大統領の写真が！？｜「DRAGON BALL STORE」に行ってみた！｜「ドラクエ1&amp;2 リメイク」やってみた！</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nq1II1jaiuA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/nq1II1jaiuA?autoplay=1" title="【11/30(日)生配信】㊗️堀井雄二「旭日小綬章」受章！｜マクロン大統領の写真が！？｜「DRAGON BALL STORE」に行ってみた！｜「ドラクエ1&amp;2 リメイク」やってみた！">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>【11/30(日)生配信】㊗️堀井雄二「旭日小綬章」受章！<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nq1II1jaiuA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>


<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> acknowledged the 30th anniversary of Chrono Trigger earlier this year, stating it would launch "various projects that go beyond the world of the game over the next year to express our gratitude to everyone who has played Chrono Trigger so far."</p>
<p>Of course, fans speculated a remake or re-release could be in the works, though there's been nothing official on this. Horii's latest comments are certainly fueling the fire, however.</p>
<p>Still, there are plenty of other projects inspired by Chrono Trigger you can check out: <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sea-of-stars-clockwork-dlc-will-release-later-this-month">Sea of Stars received DLC</a> earlier this year, while future games like <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/want-a-french-made-rpg-that-takes-inspiration-from-japanese-rpgs-and-was-actually-made-by-a-team-of-30-edge-of-memories-should-scratch-that-itch">Edge of Memories</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/as-chrono-trigger-celebrates-30th-anniversary-spiritual-successor-threads-of-time-gets-fresh-gameplay-trailer">Threads of Time</a> are heavily inspired by Square Enix's classic.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-quest-creator-future-chrono-trigger-plans-remake-speculation]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["It's crazy to me that someone can just take down our game" - well-received horror No Players Online returns to Steam following "unfounded" DMCA]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/well-received-horror-no-players-online-returns-to-steam-following-unfounded-dmca</link>
            <guid>1371370</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>But studio's future now uncertain.</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/no-players-online.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/no-players-online.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/no-players-online.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/no-players-online.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/no-players-online.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/no-players-online.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/no-players-online.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/no-players-online.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/no-players-online.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Beeswax Games</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Well-received horror game No Players Online has returned to Steam after nearly three weeks of unavailability, which its developer Beeswax Games has blamed on an "unfounded" DMCA takedown notice filed by a "former friend".
</p>
<p>
No Players Online is a narrative adventure in which players explore the files of a '90s desktop PC in order to uncover the secrets of a long-abandoned shooter. It started life as a short Game Jam title in 2019, garnering positive critical attention and something of a cult following - and an expanded reimagining was launched for Steam at the start of November. Not long after, keen-eyed horror fans began noticing it had disappeared, with Beeswax Games initially appearing unsure why, and promising to "figure out what's going on".
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="No Players Online - Release Trailer (2025)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Kv8dNNkekC8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>No Players Online - Release Trailer (2025)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Kv8dNNkekC8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Kv8dNNkekC8?autoplay=1" title="No Players Online - Release Trailer (2025)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>No Players Online launch trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kv8dNNkekC8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Three weeks on, Beeswax Games has announced No Players Online's <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2701800/No_Players_Online/">return to Steam</a>, shedding some light on the reason for its initial disappearance. "[The game] was removed from steam for nearly three weeks right after launch, following a DMCA (Digital Millennium Copyright Act) claim made by a former friend," the studio explained in a <a href="https://noplayersonline.net/statement">message shared on its website</a>. "They claimed to be a co-author of the game despite not having done anything for it. No Players Online was made completely from scratch by our team."
</p><p>
Beeswax, which counts the 2019 game's trio of creators - Adam Pype, Tibau Van den Broeck, and Viktor Kraussays - among its number, say the unnamed individual "recklessly filed the DMCA to Steam without any notice", resulting in the game's removal a little over a week after launch. "We immediately filed a counter-notice," it continued, "and today the game has been reinstated after the time for them to respond has passed."
</p>
<p>
"It's crazy to me that someone can just take down our game by filling out a simple form," it added. "It's been tough trying to reconcile with this betrayal from someone I considered a dear friend." Beeswax doesn't detail the specifics of the disagreement, only saying it attempted to offer clarity to the claimant prior to the filing that "their allegations were completely unfounded".
</p>
<p>
"This situation has had a significant impact on us," it continued, "especially given how crucial the first months after release are for small indies like us." The studio says it spent a "ton of money" over the two and a half years it took to complete No Players Online, and that its temporary removal from Steam means it "lost out on much needed momentum and revenue". As a result, Beeswax is "unsure if [it] will be able to recover financially" given its "already thin margins", and says the future of the studio is uncertain. However, it remains "committed to doing all that we have planned still for No Players Online".
</p>
<p>
DMCA copyright claims have proven highly controversial over the years, given the ease with which they can be abused. In 2023, for instance, Soviet city-builder game Workers &amp; Resources was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/soviet-city-builder-game-taken-off-steam-due-to-nonsense-dmca-strike-from-rogue-fan">temporarily pulled from Steam</a> following a "nonsense" DMCA notice from an angry fan, while <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/destiny-2">Destiny 2</a> studio Bungie <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bungie-files-lawsuit-against-individuals-behind-false-destiny-copyright-takedowns">launched legal action against a disgruntled YouTuber in 2022</a>, accusing them of maliciously filing fraudulent takedown notices against other content creators in retaliation for a DMCA filing by Bungie's own team.
</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/well-received-horror-no-players-online-returns-to-steam-following-unfounded-dmca]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Senior Baldur's Gate 3 developer rolls dice and joins The Witcher 4 studio CD Projekt Red]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/senior-baldurs-gate-3-developer-rolls-dice-and-joins-the-witcher-4-studio-cd-projekt-red</link>
            <guid>1371367</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Astarian-from-BG3-and-Ciri-from-The-Witcher-4.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Astarian-from-BG3-and-Ciri-from-The-Witcher-4.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Astarian-from-BG3-and-Ciri-from-The-Witcher-4.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Astarian-from-BG3-and-Ciri-from-The-Witcher-4.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Astarian-from-BG3-and-Ciri-from-The-Witcher-4.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Astarian-from-BG3-and-Ciri-from-The-Witcher-4.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Astarian-from-BG3-and-Ciri-from-The-Witcher-4.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Astarian-from-BG3-and-Ciri-from-The-Witcher-4.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Astarian-from-BG3-and-Ciri-from-The-Witcher-4.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A senior developer who worked on Larian's much loved and critically acclaimed <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-a-critical-success-with-critical-failures">Baldur's Gate 3</a> has moved studios, and is now working with Witcher 4 and Cyberpunk studio CD Projekt Red.</p>
<p>Senior developer Felix Pedulla worked at Larian for six years on the cinematic side of the team, before announcing his departure this week. He called his time at the Baldur's Gate 3 studio an "incredible" and "frankly wild" ride.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>"I'm so grateful for every chaotic, creative, and unforgettable moment we shared. We made some serious magic together, and I'll forever cherish the lessons and memories," Pedulla wrote on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/fedulla_newjob-careergrowth-gamingindustry-activity-7401304661347172352-uP_M/">LinkedIn</a>. "A huge thank you to all my incredible colleagues and friends I made."</p>
<p>The developer has now moved to CD Projekt Red, where he will "trade in [his] <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/baldurs-gate">Baldur's Gate</a> dice for some Polish steel" as the company's new senior cinematic designer. It's time to "get to work crafting some epic cutscenes," Pedulla closed.</p><p>While the cinematic designer did not say which of CDPR's games he would be working on, it is fair to assume that he will be lending his talents to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-witcher-4">The Witcher 4</a>. Just last month, it was confirmed some <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cd-projekt-bolsters-the-witcher-4-team-with-key-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-talent">key Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 development talent had also made the jump to CD Projekt and Ciri's new adventure</a>.</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>CDPR</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for The Witcher 4, its<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-gets-its-a-first-trailer-and-yes-ciri-is-the-star"> first trailer was revealed at last year's The Game Awards</a>, though <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-not-at-the-game-awards-this-year">don't expect it to show up again this year</a>.</p>
<p>We got another look at the next Witcher game in-action back in June. The team did caveat though, that though that particular demo may have looked like gameplay, it was actually a representation of what the tech could do, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4-unreal-tech-demo-was-running-on-a-standard-ps5-at-60fps-with-ray-tracing">wasn't actually representative of the final game</a>. The performance seen during said tech demo is what the game is aiming for, however. At this time, the studio also <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-witcher-4s-northern-setting-revealed-in-new-unreal-livestream">showed off the northern setting for The Witcher 4</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/senior-baldurs-gate-3-developer-rolls-dice-and-joins-the-witcher-4-studio-cd-projekt-red]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["I'll Get In Trouble" - Yuji Horii "Can't Talk About" Future Chrono Trigger Developments]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/ill-get-in-trouble-yuji-horii-cant-talk-about-future-chrono-trigger-developments</link>
            <guid>1371358</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Well that's not suspicious at all!</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="8cd734bd57d33"><a title="Chrono Trigger" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/8cd734bd57d33/chrono-trigger.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Square Enix</em></figcaption></figure><p>11th March 2025 marked the 30th anniversary of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/snes/chrono_trigger">Chrono Trigger</a>. Square Enix marked the occasion by announcing that "<a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/03/chrono-trigger-to-celebrate-30th-anniversary-with-various-projects">various projects</a>" would be coming our way over the next year, but so far, those projects have been limited to character popularity polls and planned orchestral concerts. Importantly, that's <em>not</em> the remake that we all want to see and have been chatting about for years. But we're still not ready to completely throw out all hope just yet.</p>
<p>You see, in the latest episode of the '<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nq1II1jaiuA&amp;t=6628s">KosoKoso Hōsō Kyoku</a>' talk show livestream (translated by <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/chrono-triggers-original-supervisor-yuji-horii-says-i-cant-talk-about-it-dont-ask-and-ill-get-in-trouble-when-asked-about-new-developments/">Automaton</a>), <strong>Dragon Quest</strong> creator and Chrono Trigger supervisor Yuji Horii attempted to keep his lips sealed about where the series is heading — but in saying nothing, has he actually said <em>everything</em>?</p>
<p>"I can't talk about that," Horii-san told the interviewer when asked whether the smaller anniversary events might be "foreshadowing" bigger developments down the line. He jokingly added clarifying statements like, "Wait, if I say that, you'll figure it out!," "Don't ask!," and "I'll get in trouble!" before the panel decided to move on with the show.</p>
<p>Hmmm. It's far from anything concrete, and there's every chance that Horii-san was genuinely just trying to get himself out of a sticky situation, but we can't help feeling that the whole thing is a <em>little</em> suspicious. Hey, perhaps it's just wishful thinking on our end.</p>
<p>Back in May, it seemed like Horii-san might have <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/05/oops-yuji-horii-may-not-have-leaked-massive-remake-news-after-all">let the news of an upcoming remake slip</a> during a panel at Napoli Comicon. However, it later turned out that it was just the translator bringing up the series, not Yuji Horii himself. <em>D'oh</em>.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, the best way to officially play Chrono Trigger remains the wonderful 2008 <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/ds/chrono_trigger">DS port</a>, which'll set you back a pretty penny if you try to pick it up on the resale market today. It has arrived on mobile and Windows in the years since, but come on, we all want to see it on Switch (2), right?</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-articles:193538,177779,188142 @ 1764768445 -->
<p><em>What do you make of Horii's comments? Might a remake be on the cards? Let us know your thoughts in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nq1II1jaiuA&amp;amp;t=6628s" rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nq1II1jaiuA&amp;t=6628s">youtube.com</a>, via <a title="External Link: https://automaton-media.com/en/news/chrono-triggers-original-supervisor-yuji-horii-says-i-cant-talk-about-it-dont-ask-and-ill-get-in-trouble-when-asked-about-new-developments/" rel="noopener" href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/chrono-triggers-original-supervisor-yuji-horii-says-i-cant-talk-about-it-dont-ask-and-ill-get-in-trouble-when-asked-about-new-developments/">automaton-media.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/related-info/27eb34afa0f9a6e145926748041ba916 @ 1764769303 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/ill-get-in-trouble-yuji-horii-cant-talk-about-future-chrono-trigger-developments]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Haunted videogame No Players Online resurrected on Steam after a disgruntled "former friend" had it exorcised via DMCA]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haunted-videogame-no-players-online-resurrected-on-steam-after-a-disgruntled-former-friend-had-it-exorcised-via-dmca</link>
            <guid>1371355</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"Spiritual successor" at large again after being taken down a week after launch</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/noplayersonline2025.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/noplayersonline2025.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/noplayersonline2025.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/noplayersonline2025.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/noplayersonline2025.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/noplayersonline2025.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/noplayersonline2025.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/noplayersonline2025.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/noplayersonline2025.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Black Lantern Collective</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
A few weeks ago, developers Beeswax Games released a "spiritual successor" to 2019 freeware game <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/no-players-online">No Players Online</a> on Steam. If you've not played the old freeware project - <a href="https://papercookies.itch.io/no-players-online-classic">still available on Itch</a> - it's one of those haunted software jobbies that accentuate the eerieness of elderly 3D simulation tech, and in this case, abandoned FPS multiplayer maps. I was looking forward to playing the successor. But then, spookily, the Steam page vanished. And now, spookily, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2701800/No_Players_Online/">it's back</a>. 
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
According to Beeswax, the game was hit by a Digital Millennium Copyright Act claim filed by a "former friend" who "claimed to be co-author of the game despite not having done anything for it". Valve then took the game down on 13th November, a week after release. The developers filed a counter-notice, and Valve have now reinstated the Steam release after the complainant neglected to respond to that counter-notice in time.
</p>
<p>
You can read developer Adam Pype's full account of events <a href="https://noplayersonline.net/statement">here</a>. It doesn't name the "former friend", and I'm not going to speculate about their identity. Pype says the upheaval has cost the project dearly, writing that "we spent 2 and a half years of our lives and a ton of money making this game. we also have a lot of people who believed in us and wanted us to succeed. it's crazy to me that someone can just take down our game by filling out a simple form, and it's been tough trying to reconcile with this betrayal from someone i considered a dear friend."
</p>
<p>
Pype continues that "this situation has had a significant impact on us, especially given how crucial the first months after release are for small indies like us. we lost out on much needed momentum and revenue right after the release of our game and we're unsure if we will be able to recover financially from this given our already thin margins."
</p><p>
I haven't been keeping up with latest happenings in DMCA-land, but this particular legal institution has attracted much criticism for being easy to abuse. Back in 2017, Alice O (RPS in peace) <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/river-city-ransom-underground-pulled-from-sale-following-copyright-claims">reported</a> on the yoinking from sale of River City Ransom Underground, commenting that DMCA filings "don't require that the accuser offer proof that they hold the rights, putting the burden of time and effort (and sometimes money) on the accused". More recently in 2023, a community guide writer had ace city-builder <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/workers-resources-soviet-republic">Workers &amp; Resources: Soviet Republic</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/workers-resources-soviet-republic-is-back-on-steam-after-a-dmca-strike-from-disgruntled-player">removed from Steam for a month or so</a>, after developers 3Division added a mode that seemingly took a little inspiration from the writer's work.
</p>
<p>
Natalie Clayton <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/no-players-online-offers-free-spooks-on-the-empty-servers-of-a-dead-multiplayer-game">had a rare old time</a> with No Players Online back in 2019. "No Players Online sees me, booting up old games, looking for that sweet nostalgia kick, and suggests that maybe I let dead things stay buried," she wrote. These cautionary sentiments notwithstanding, I'm thankful that the spiritual successor has escaped the grave of DMCAing. It expands on the freeware game's premise with a faux-90s desktop interface and a bunch of different, presumably cursed games to download from various not-forums.
</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/haunted-videogame-no-players-online-resurrected-on-steam-after-a-disgruntled-former-friend-had-it-exorcised-via-dmca]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Avowed's new game plus, fresh kind of weapon and photo mode are now coming in a beefy anniversary update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/avoweds-new-game-plus-fresh-kind-of-weapon-and-photo-mode-are-now-coming-in-a-beefy-anniversary-update</link>
            <guid>1371352</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Obsidian have pushed their autumn plans into a bigger bag of tricks set to be opened next year</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/avowed-new-game-plus-coming-next-year-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/avowed-new-game-plus-coming-next-year-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/avowed-new-game-plus-coming-next-year-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/avowed-new-game-plus-coming-next-year-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/avowed-new-game-plus-coming-next-year-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/avowed-new-game-plus-coming-next-year-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/avowed-new-game-plus-coming-next-year-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/avowed-new-game-plus-coming-next-year-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/avowed-new-game-plus-coming-next-year-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Obsidian</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/avowed">Avowed</a> won't be getting the final update devs Obsidian had planned for this year. Instead the studio have opted to save putting out the new game plus mode they'd planned for this autumn for a big update to make the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a>'s first birthday in February. To make up the extra wait, the anniversary update'll be adding some mystery extra bits alongside the already announced features.</p>
<p>The autumn patch was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/avoweds-latest-update-comes-with-community-requested-features-lots-of-tweaks-and-a-promise-of-a-roadmap">originally set</a> to be the third update delivered to the nature-rific blunderbuss adventure this year. The last one to arrive was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/avoweds-summer-update-revamps-fighter-and-ranger-skills-so-those-pesky-wizards-arent-having-all-the-fun">the summer update</a>, which aimed to round out the fighting skills of non-magic users so that wizards weren't having all of the fun.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Now, though, the roadmap has been remapped. No autumn update shall exist, with Obsidian having <a href="https://x.com/AvowedtheGame/status/1995917924708876634">announced</a> that they're shifting efforts to "a larger update coming next February, timed with the anniversary of the game’s release". As such, stuff like new game plus, a photo mode, and a new type of weapon will now be arriving around February 18th, having been delayed from their original slot.</p>
<p>As someone who really should get around to replaying Avowed now some time's passed, I'm pretty happy to be able to leave thinking about doing so via new game plus next year, given how packed December always is. The photo mode'll also be a cool addition, given Avowed's vibrant natural scapes are <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rps-verdict-avowed">one of the areas</a> in which it really sung. They'll have to pry my arquebus out of my cold, dead mushroom hands to get me to try the new kind of weapon, though.</p><p>Some character customisation additions have also been pushed from this year to the anniversary update. These include the ability to switch up your appearance within the world, as well as more presets for characters and their Godlike features. The Godlike features for the uninitiated, are the mushrooms and bits of wood you can slap across your envoy's face to show that they are the mystical nature-person of legend.</p>
<p>Alongside those announced bits, Obsidian added that you can expect some surprise "additional features" that'll fleash out the anniversary update to make it the game's biggest yet. My money's on a giant mushroom you can peel off your face, then mount to fly around Eora. Or throw at enemies like a pizza-shaped fungi boomerang. Either that or some sort of Outer Worlds 2 crossover which sees the citizens of fantasyland have to fight off an invasion of corporate types whose leader <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-outer-worlds-2s-faction-writing-falls-short-of-fallout-new-vegas-and-how-it-handles-the-powerful-is-key">the writers feel a bit sorry for</a>.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/avoweds-new-game-plus-fresh-kind-of-weapon-and-photo-mode-are-now-coming-in-a-beefy-anniversary-update]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Resident Evil Requiem Gameplay Shown Exclusively In Japan Reveals New Location]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-resident-evil-requiem-gameplay-shown-exclusively-in-japan-reveals-new-location/</link>
            <guid>1371349</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Every bit of new Resident Evil Requiem gameplay is welcome. So, while it’s a bummer that exclusive Resident Evil Requiem gameplay was shown off in Japan, a video has been shared, showcasing the intriguing footage.</p>



<p>Resident Evil Requiem adds to what is already a ridiculous 2026 for gaming. Capcom’s newest survival horror entry in the genre-defining franchise puts Grace Ashcroft in the hot seat. It’s already been revealed how <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-requiem-devs-reveal-how-grace-differs-from-previous-protagonists/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Grace differs from previous protagonists</a>, but seeing her in action is a treat—as shown in a new gameplay clip.</p>







<h2 id="h-exclusive-resident-evil-requiem-gameplay-revealed">Exclusive Resident Evil Requiem Gameplay Revealed</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Shocking. Credit to Capcom</figcaption></figure>



<p>The ever-reliable <a href="https://x.com/AestheticGamer1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Dusk Golem</a> shared a video showing “new Resident Evil Requiem gameplay of a new area with Grace fighting a zombie in the Resident Evil special program that aired on Japanese television.”</p>







<p>A 34-second video shows the new ability to flick between first-person and third-person, and shows Grace battling off zombie threats with a pistol. The gameplay looks infinitely more horrible, claustrophobic, and terrifying in first-person, which would explain why <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/resident-evil-9-has-a-third-person-camera-because-resident-evil-7-was-too-scary/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Resident Evil 9 has a third-person camera</a>.</p>



<p>The indoor environment certainly looks new, and nothing we’ve seen already in any previous gameplay footage or teaser trailers.</p>



<p>Dusk Golem clarifies that because it’s a Japan-only advert, meaning it’s “100% the censored Japanese version.” It still features blood and gory effects, but presumably to a far lesser extent than we’ll see in the full release.</p>



<figure><div><blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">There was some new Resident Evil Requiem gameplay of a new area with Grace fighting a zombie in the Resident Evil special program that aired on Japanese television. <a href="https://t.co/FToPeqi4HW">pic.twitter.com/FToPeqi4HW</a></p>— AestheticGamer aka Dusk Golem (@AestheticGamer1) <a href="https://twitter.com/AestheticGamer1/status/1996158141793489389?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 3, 2025</a></blockquote></div></figure>



<p>It definitely gives off more of a Resident Evil 2 Remake and Resident Evil 7 vibe—which will be music to the ears of those who lambasted Resident Evil 8’s somewhat familiar return to action and open areas.</p>



<p>What do you think of this short gameplay extra? Is Resident Evil Requiem looking better by the day? Will this be a return to the classic vibe of vintage Resident Evil games? You can let everyone know in the usual place: The free-to-join <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Official Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>There’s much more news to check out at Insider Gaming, such as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-south-park-leak-details/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new Fortnite Leak detailing the upcoming South Park collaboration</a>, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/metroid-prime-4-beyond-is-the-lowest-reviewed-game-in-the-series/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond being the lowest-reviewed game in the series</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <!--<div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on iOS & Android</div>-->
        <p><i></i> Available on Android</p>

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/new-resident-evil-requiem-gameplay-shown-exclusively-in-japan-reveals-new-location/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Has Replaced Samus' Voice Actor For Metroid Prime 4, So It's No Longer Mass Effect's Jennifer Hale Doing the Grunts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-has-replaced-samus-voice-actor-for-metroid-prime-4-so-its-no-longer-mass-effects-jennifer-hale-doing-the-grunts</link>
            <guid>1371346</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"I have no recollection of recording it or signing a contract."</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Legendary voice actress Jennifer Hale has been replaced as the voice of Samus in Metroid Prime 4, the new game's credits have revealed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Numerous actors have voiced Samus over the years, though Hale had been the artist behind most of the bounty hunter's grunts and cries in Metroid Prime 1, 2 and 3 (with some additional work from a second artist, Vanessa Marshall). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Many fans had assumed Hale would return as Samus in Nintendo's long-awaited new Prime game, but <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/12/metroid-prime-4-beyond-credits-reveal-a-plethora-of-assist-devs-including-next-level-games" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nintendo Life</a> has now reported on Metroid Prime 4's credits, which list that Erin Yvette has taken on the role of Samus. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're playing Metroid Prime 4 and think Samus' grunts sound familiar, Yvette previously voiced Snow White in The Wolf Among Us, Alex in Oxenfree, and can currently be heard as Blonde Blazer in Dispatch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The past few years have seen Nintendo replace many of its previous regular voice actors,<a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-confirms-charles-martinet-is-not-involved-in-super-mario-bros-wonder"> including the veteran voice of Mario and Luigi, Charles Martinet</a>. Princess Peach and Toad voice actress Samantha Kelly, meanwhile, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/princess-peach-and-toads-veteran-voice-actor-says-nintendo-told-her-shed-been-replaced-on-switch-2-launch-day-as-mario-kart-world-released-without-her-in-it">discovered her 18-year tenure as the Super Mario characters was over on Nintendo Switch 2 launch day</a> — when <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> released without her in it. Takashi Nagasako, who previously voiced Donkey Kong for 21 years, has also been replaced as of the Switch 2's launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">IGN recently caught up with Hale and discussed her past work as Samus, and questioned whether she had recorded any new material for Metroid Prime 4 over the course of its lengthy development. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I don't know," Hale told IGN. "I have no recollection of recording it or signing a contract, so it could be no. When we work, this is the thing, everything's under a code name, so they would've called it Sasquatch or Pineapple or Cookie Jar. And 'okay, I'm going to do Cookie Jar.' And then when you get to the session they'll tell you, but it stays in your brain for so much shorter a time. It doesn't stick as much."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Metroid Prime 4 Beyond Switch 2 Edition Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">While Hale's work as Samus is limited to the famously silent bounty hunter's range of grunts, she said she still had a full voice for the character in her mind while performing the role.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I like to have identified a character's way of speaking before I do grunting for them, because how you grunt is different to how I grunt, to how anyone else grunts," Hale explained. "It's very specific. If you are a civilian and you're grunting, you're like... [makes surprised grunt noise] because it's all surprising and it's all new. If you've done it a million times, you're like [makes short grunt noise], because you've gone under fire 1,800 times and you're used to it."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Hale has voiced a string of famous video game characters over the years, including Ratchet and Clank's Rivet, Metal Gear Solid's Naomi Hunter, and BioShock Infinite's Rosalind Lutece. But it's for her role in Mass Effect that she remains perhaps known. Speaking to IGN, Hale said <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/i-love-that-universe-im-ready-anytime-jennifer-hale-calls-on-fans-to-tell-bioware-theyd-love-to-see-commander-shepard-return-for-mass-effect-5">she hadn't been asked to return for Mass Effect 5 yet</a>, but "would be there before they finish the sentence" if BioWare got in touch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Not all of Prime 4’s additions work, but this is still an excellent comeback," IGN wrote in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review">Metroid Prime 4 review</a>, scoring the game an 8/10.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-has-replaced-samus-voice-actor-for-metroid-prime-4-so-its-no-longer-mass-effects-jennifer-hale-doing-the-grunts]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Octopath Traveler 0 Review in Progress]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/octopath-traveler-0-review</link>
            <guid>1371343</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Lengthy RPGs are one of the great joys in my life, but it can sometimes feel a bit daunting to pack one into just a few weeks for the review process. As of writing this, I have played just over 70 hours of Octopath Traveler 0 and am nearing the final few chapters in its main questline – and having played these kinds of RPGs most of my life, I already know those "final few chapters" will be anything but short. However, I'm eager to wrap them up in the coming days because it's been a worthwhile journey so far. Between the new wrinkles in its dynamic combat system and some fantastic music that uplift its big battles, Octopath Traveler 0 is hitting the right notes and delivering the things I seek from RPGs. The tales told within its various quest branches have been hit and miss, though, and I'm still waiting to see if the story will come together and hit its stride in this last stretch before I settle with a final, scored review.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With Octopath Traveler 0, Square Enix has adapted the 2022 mobile game Octopath Traveler: Champions of the Continent into a more traditional package, serving as both a prequel to the original and a reconfiguration of what's already available on phones. Regardless of where I land in my final review, I'm glad it exists in this form at all since it ditches the gacha/microtransaction elements that were used to build your party and instead has you recruiting team members through sidequests. Thus, the better parts of the mobile game come to the forefront and highlight that the foundation of the series held up then and still holds up now.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Octopath Traveler 0 Review - Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Story is where most of my reservations are since it hits some pretty high highs and fairly low lows. While I'm not expecting it to be the most beautifully written script or deepest character study, I've found several plot beats to fall quite flat due to some shallow storytelling, rudimentary dialogue, or things that happen <em>just because</em>. Comically evil villains make for bosses I get fired up to absolutely destroy, but it's hard to take them seriously at times when their foolish cruelty and thirst for power is the main hook, so I'm not coming away with a sense of satisfaction I've felt elsewhere (namely, Octopath Traveler 2). Like the rest of the series, godly powers linger in the background and slowly reveal themselves as you uncover the real purpose behind the eight divine rings, one of which is assigned to "the chosen one" who is your created protagonist. Despite the inconsistent quality of its storytelling across this long runtime, Octopath Traveler 0 runs at a decent pace and propels you forward without sitting on any one story thread for too long.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">A big part of this is in how the main questline is structured; after a tragic prologue where your hometown is burned to the ground, you're given three story branches to pursue the trio of villains responsible. Themed around power, fame, and wealth, respectively, those three paths then converge into a conclusion for what is roughly the first half of the overall story (at about 40 hours). It then splits into three <em>new </em>questlines that pick up those themes once again, and although they retread similar territory, the stakes get higher as more of Octopath's world gets involved. That's a lot to chew on, but it's able to keep momentum rather than trying to build eight separate stories that have to run in parallel. Octopath Traveler 2 was very successful with regard to its cast of eight and made for some of the most memorable RPG stories in recent memory, but this is a smart direction considering that this (and the mobile game) centers around recruiting <em>a lot </em>of characters to swap in and out of your party. Unfortunately this means most party members feel rather disposable, so the disonance it creates is just the trade-off that gets made.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>So far the story has hit some pretty high highs and fairly low lows.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">While I haven't experienced the same compelling, emotionally resonant character arcs I saw in the second game, specific moments remind me that there's still some heartfelt stuff tucked within. Whether it's a character wielding their pain from tragedy to summon a new power mid-battle or a quiet, reflective cutscene back at town to remind you what "home" really means, Octopath Traveler 0 has brief moments of greatness. The big picture is solid, too – the alliances and betrayals of various kingdoms don't get bogged down in exposition and deliver good old fashioned drama. The stories around Octopath's world religion get a bit unwieldy when it comes to the greater lore, but it's not incomprehensible and makes the mechanism of the church quite clear. Like the previous game, class warfare and going from nothing to something remains a prominent motif, and even though it sometimes fumbles the messaging here, it's willing to talk about those topics with enough clarity. Whether or not all these threads pay off, well, that's what's left for me to determine as I finish the main story.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, that's the A-plot. There's a B-plot that revolves around rebuilding your hometown through an independent but related questline that's tied to the town-building system. In the process of bringing your hometown back to life narratively, you actually <em>rebuild </em>it in a similar vein to Fallout 4 or even Ni no Kuni 2. You collect crafting materials naturally throughout which then allow you to build housing, shops, and decor wherever you like within certain parameters. It’s an enjoyable side activity, with tangible benefits that come from constructing new buildings and recruiting new residents you invite from across the map. You get perks such as discounted shop prices, a self-sufficient flow of materials, and a training ground for inactive party members to continue leveling up, among other things. Town building may seem optional at first, but it becomes almost essential the deeper you get, especially when you consider the story's broader message about what home means to you and the people you care for. It's a bit cheesy at times, but its heart is in the right place as it gets sentimental about what it takes to rebuild after losing everything. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">You get a ton of sidequests thrown at you as you progress in the main game, many of which are a short series' of objectives to unlock new party members – some of which are cast members from the original game. It's super cool to see, but don't expect them to have any particular depth as the main story is largely focused on specific, non-optional characters. One thing I do enjoy about Octopath games and RPGs like them is the sense of discovery and stumbling upon secrets or locations you wouldn't visit otherwise, and the sidequests, if anything, have been a good way to pull you in those directions.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I've been <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/gamespots-10-best-games-of-2023/2900-4972/#8" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on record saying Octopath Traveler 2</a> has one of my favorite turn-based combat systems ever; it shines here as well and for slightly different reasons. The Boost and Break systems give the typical dynamic of hitting elemental affinities extra depth. Playing the guessing game of discovering what enemies are weak against gets a little tiresome, but once that part is solved, scheming for your plan of attack based on turn order to Break enemies and tee up the big hits is oh so satisfying. Building each party members' Boost points to add extra hits or increase spell potency gives you something to plan around for turns well in advance. And lining up all these variables while juggling the threat of hard-hitting bosses who impose some impactful status ailments have me feeling like a genius tactician. Octopath might be playing on our nostalgia with its HD-2D retro-style visuals, but I honestly believe it has continually set a higher bar for turn-based combat systems in modern gaming.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>This series has continually set a higher bar for turn-based combat systems.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Party composition is quite different this time around since you have eight active party members at all times – four in the front row and four in the back who you can swap between mid-turn. With 30-something characters in my current roster, it's an overwhelming amount to process and manage. But while the fundamentals of Octopath's combat system are familiar, pairing characters as duos for the column they occupy is a unique strategic layer that allows for a lot of flexibility in combat. And because they build Boost points individually, you can dole out the big hits more frequently and keep up a brisk pace in battle. You sacrifice individual character depth, however, as each party member has just one Job to progress through (aside from your protagonist), but you can at least master specific Job skills to then equip on other characters to diversify their moveset. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I'm not quite ready to say whether I like this combat more or less than Octopath Traveler 2 since I found its character growth more meaningful, but it’s still been a welcome change of pace that hits the turn-based highs that've made the series special. The slow-motion cinematic camera cuts for Max Boost attacks and tide-turning limit breaks still get me hyped up, giving combat the visual flair that truly makes the HD-2D style stand out when the action picks up. The confluence of thoughtful gameplay, fantastic graphics, and a banging soundtrack that contends with some of the RPG greats, showcases why the genre is still in good hands.</p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Michael Higham's Top 10 Favorite RPGs of All Time</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Octopath Traveler 0 has so much firing off in parallel with its separate story branches, overarching themes, and complex-but-satisfying RPG combat system, and I'm excited to see how it all concludes as I inch closer to the end. Great RPGs live or die by how their final acts play out – with the expectation of wild boss battles, story revelations, and resolution to an 80-hour-plus journey, a lot is riding on it. And I'm just as eager to finalize my thoughts and feelings on Octopath Traveler 0 soon after.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/octopath-traveler-0-review]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Horses banned from Epic Games Store just 24 hours before launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/horses-banned-from-epic-games-store-just-24-hours-before-launch</link>
            <guid>1371328</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-testid="article-base-contributors"><div data-component="contributors"><p><a data-testid="contributor-name" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/author/chris-kerr" data-discover="true">Chris Kerr</a><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->Senior Editor, News</span><span data-testid="contributor-title">, <!-- -->GameDeveloper.com</span></p><p data-testid="contributors-date">December 3, 2025</p></div><p><span data-component="icon" data-name="Clock"></span><span>4 Min<!-- --> <!-- -->Read</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Horses</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the indie horror title from Santa Ragione, is out now. Yet, if you only shop on the more popular digital storefronts, you probably wouldn't know.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The title was barred from Steam by Valve mid-development, leaving Santa Ragione unable to access a massive portion of the market and casting the future of the studio in doubt.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's a situation that studio co-founder Pietro Righi Riva described as "scary, humiliating, and patronizing" duri</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-it-is-scary-humiliating-and-patronising-santa-ragione-facing-closure-after-horses-barred-from-steam">ng a recent conversation with Game Developer</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and one he claimed should raise alarm bells about the censorship of art on major storefronts.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Then, on December 1 at 5pm CET (roughly 24 hours before launch) Horses was banned from the Epic Games Store.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.horses.wtf/BannedFromSteam/index.html#Q17">In an extensive FAQ published online</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Santa Ragione said it received an email from Epic Games in which the company explained it was unable to distribute the surreal horror experience because it violates the Epic Game Store Content Guidelines—specifically, the "Inappropriate Content" and Hateful or Abusive Content" policies.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Here is the full email sent to Santa Ragione by Epic Games:</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>"We are unable to distribute Horses on the Epic Games Store because our review found violations of the Epic Games Store Content Guidelines, specifically the 'Inappropriate Content' and 'Hateful or Abusive Content' policies. The 'Inappropriate Content' policy prohibits content which 'contains explicit or frequent depictions of sexual behavior or not appropriately labeled, rated, or age-gated.' The 'Hateful or Abusive Content' policy prohibits content that promotes abuse and animal abuse. This content is prohibited by our Guidelines and cannot be distributed on the Epic Games Store. Additionally, when we [Epic] filled out the IARC Questionnaire based on the content that we reviewed, it received an Adult Only (AO) rating. Products with AO ratings cannot be distributed on the Epic Games Store (the only exception is for products in cases where an AO rating was applied solely due to the usage of blockchain or NFT technology). You have some options on how to move forward: 1. You can make updates to your product to ensure compliance and resubmit it for review. 2. If you believe we made a mistake, you also have the ability to appeal this decision. You can appeal by replying to this email or creating a private discussion on our Developer Support site. Select 'Epic Games Store' as the topic. 3. You cannot change the title or content to repurpose it for another game. If you choose not to move forward, we'll refund your submission fee for this product."</span></span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/american-company-is-overcharging-japanese-devs-for-japanese-language-fonts" target="_self" data-discover="true">Monotype accused of overcharging Japanese devs for Japanese language fonts</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Santa Ragione explained it immediately appealed the decision through the suggested channels.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/uk-publisher-outright-games-confirms-layoffs" target="_self" data-discover="true">UK publisher Outright Games confirms layoffs</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It said the title does not contain explicit or frequent depictions of sexual behaviour. "All nudity in the game is completely censored via pixelation. There is never any visible sexual act involving genitalia and all animations are stylized and unrealistic. Additionally, in the three hours of gameplay contained in the game, there are only four brief and censored sexual sequences, with two of them happening mainly off camera," wrote the studio.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Notably, Santa Ragione clarified that </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Horses</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> does not in any way promote abuse—including animal abuse—and is in its view a "strong critique of violence and abuse in general."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The studio said it then reminded Epic it had already secured an International Age Rating Coalition (IARC) rating as part of its submission process over five weeks before release. Santa Ragione said </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Horses</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> received a PEGI 18 and ESRB M rating, as was displayed on its 'Coming Soon' page on the Epic Games Store.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It did not, emphasized the studio, receive an AO rating.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"After the appeal, we reached out to our contact at Epic Games to beg them to reconsider this last-minute decision and to stress how </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Horses</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> builds had been submitted and reviewed by their team for the last two months, with the final achievements-ready build being approved for release 18 days prior to launch," continues the FAQ published by Santa Ragione.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/arc-games-becomes-independent-publisher-after-splitting-from-embracer" target="_self" data-discover="true">Arc Games becomes independent publisher after splitting from Embracer</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The studio received the following automated message in response:&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We are writing to provide an update regarding your appeal. We conducted an extensive review before our initial notice, and found your content is prohibited by our Content Guidelines and cannot be distributed on the Epic Games Store. We reviewed your appeal and found the original decision was appropriately applied and will remain in place."&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Santa Ragione said it has once again been hung out to dry by a major platform holder who has banned their product without a clear explanation that would have allowed them to address specific issues.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Once again, no specific indication of problematic content in the game was given. Even if Epic's initial ban communication specified that we could 'make updates to [our] product to ensure compliance,' the email did not include any information on what would need to be changed, and it would have been impossible to make significant changes one day from launch anyway," continued the studio.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">When approached for comment by Game Developer, Epic Games communications director Jake Jones said the company made it clear what can and cannot be distributed on its platform.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"We set clear guidelines for the content that can be distributed on the Epic Games Store and found violations of those guidelines during our extensive review," said Jones.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Horses</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is available now on Itch.io, GOG, and the Humble Store.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, News, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;PocketGamer.biz. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton.&nbsp;</span></p></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/horses-banned-from-epic-games-store-just-24-hours-before-launch]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Huge Mario Kart World update changes course layouts, Dash food reappearances and so much more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/huge-mario-kart-world-update-changes-course-layouts-dash-food-reappearances-and-so-much-more</link>
            <guid>1371325</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-lot-of-Yoshis-racing-in-Mario-Kart-World.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-lot-of-Yoshis-racing-in-Mario-Kart-World.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-lot-of-Yoshis-racing-in-Mario-Kart-World.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-lot-of-Yoshis-racing-in-Mario-Kart-World.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-lot-of-Yoshis-racing-in-Mario-Kart-World.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-lot-of-Yoshis-racing-in-Mario-Kart-World.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-lot-of-Yoshis-racing-in-Mario-Kart-World.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-lot-of-Yoshis-racing-in-Mario-Kart-World.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/A-lot-of-Yoshis-racing-in-Mario-Kart-World.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Nintendo has released a new update for <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a>, and it's another big one.</p>
<p>Version 1.4.0, to give it its proper name, has made swathes of changes to Nintendo's latest Mario Kart installment, ranging from the way music tracks are displayed all the way to UFO entries.</p>
<p>There are tweaks to the smart steering, some course changes for those taking part in "VS Race", "Race" in "Online Play" or "Wireless Play", and adjustments to the speed at which Dash food reappears. You will also now dash when riding on Manta Ramp's back, and there also <em>so much</em> more on the list. Nintendo has really gone to town with this one.</p>
<p>Alas, there's still no mention of racing on individual tracks in multiplayer, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mario-kart-world-fine-tunes-race-selection-in-vs-race-pool-responding-to-player-criticism">but we all know that's something everyone wants</a>. Maybe next time...</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>You can check out the full patch notes for Mario Kart World Version 1.4.0 below:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>General</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added "Custom Items" to the item rules.</li>
<li>This is a feature that lets you set which items appear.</li>
<li>This is supported in "VS Race", "Balloon Battle", "Coin Runners", and "Room" in "Online Play" or "Wireless Play".</li>
<li>Made it so that music track name and source title of the track that is playing will be displayed on the Pause Menu.</li>
<li>Added "Music Volume" to "Settings/Controller".</li>
<li>Made it so players who gathered in a "Room" of "Online Play" can participate in "Race", "Knockout Tour", and "Battle".</li>
<li>Up to 4 players can participate in "Race", "Knockout Tour", and "Battle".</li>
<li>Made it so you can join in with friends who are playing "Knockout Tour" from "Friends" in "2p", "Online Play" as well.</li>
<li>Added "Restart" and "Next Race" in the Pause Menu for "VS Race" in "Single Player".</li>
<li>Made it so you can select "Photo Mode" from the Pause Menu in "Race against Ghost" in "Time Trials".</li>
<li>Changed the course layout of below courses for "VS Race", or "Race" in "Online Play" or "Wireless Play".</li>
<li>Race that heads from "Koopa Troopa Beach" to "DK Spaceport".</li>
<li>Race that heads from "Koopa Troopa Beach" to "Crown City".</li>
<li>Race that heads from "Koopa Troopa Beach" to "Peach Stadium".</li>
<li>Race that heads from "Whistlestop Summit" to "Koopa Troopa Beach".</li>
<li>Race that heads from "Desert Hills" to "Koopa Troopa Beach".</li>
<li>Race that heads from "DK Spaceport" to "Koopa Troopa Beach".</li>
<li>Race that heads from "Crown City" to "Koopa Troopa Beach".</li>
<li>Race that heads from "Peach Stadium" to "Koopa Troopa Beach".</li>
<li>*Changed it so that, in all races heading toward "Koopa Troopa Beach", including the above courses, you will cross the finish line after two laps once you arrive at "Koopa Troopa Beach".</li>
<li>You will now dash when riding on Manta Ramp's back.</li>
<li>Made it so the player will not hit Dragoneel when transformed into Bullet Bill.</li>
<li>Made it so the player cannot use a second Boo while already using a Boo, when holding two Boos.</li>
<li>When Dash Food is taken by someone, shortened the time until that Dash Food reappears.</li>
<li>When a coin placed on water is taken by someone, shortened the time until that coin reappears.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Fixed Issues</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where the dash time was not correct after a Charge Jump.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through a wall when being stomped on from above by a vehicle driving on the road.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a player would be squashed when touching a Thwomp that had landed.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a Bullet Bill would not be displayed after using it.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a character would be blurry even when making "Focus" "Character" when taking a photo in "Photo Mode" on the Pause Menu.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the screen would look distorted if entering a pipe at the same time as joining a Free Roam in "Online Play".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where player could not get in a UFO when multiple players tried to get in a UFO at the same time in Free Roam in "Online Play".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a friend's information would not be updated when looking at the list of friends in "Friends" in "Online Play".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where there would be a communication error when looking at a group ID in "View Room Info" when participating in a group in "Friends" in "Online Play".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a player's place would go down if retiring during "Knockout Tour" in "Online Play".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a player that is seen when spectating looks like they are going off the course over and over during "Knockout Tour" in "Online Play" or "Wireless Play".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player's own character or vehicle would change when starting "Online Play" or "Wireless Play" again after quitting a game after "Knockout Tour" in "Online Play" or "Wireless Play".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a player would get stuck on a wall when using a Bullet Bill while falling off the course in "Sky-High Sundae".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a Bullet Bill would go outside the course when using it on the final curve in "Boo Cinema".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through a bulldozer in "Toad's Factory".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on a spotlight in the race that heads from "Toad's Factory" to "Bowser's Castle" when transformed into Bullet Bill.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where if the player used a Bullet Bill or Spiny Shell in the first curve of "Desert Hills", it would get stuck on a rock.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on a tree when using a Bullet Bill on "DK Pass".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where, when the player was small because of Lightning, they would slip through the wall on the final curve of "DK Pass.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on a billboard when transforming into Bullet Bill in the race that heads from "Crown City" to "Desert Hills".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through the ring of stone when using a Bullet Bill or Mega Mushroom while falling in "Great ? Block Ruins" right before the final curve.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on the ground on the meadows near "Big Donut".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would slip through the wall if rewinding after wall riding in the special room you can go to from a pipe in "Shy Guy Bazaar".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would still fall into the lava even though they have "Smart Steering" ON in "Dry Bones Burnout".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course when using a Bullet Bill while rail riding in "Wario Stadium".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would not be able to glide if getting on a glide panel while gliding in the race that heads from "Wario Stadium" to "Airship Fortress".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would get stuck on the ground while heading from "Wario Stadium" to "Airship Fortress".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the vehicle would float up from the rail when the player did a rail ride after a wall ride in a bike-type vehicle in "Wario Stadium".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course when using a Bullet Bill on the shortcut while heading from "Dandelion Depths" to "Cheep Cheep Falls" in the "Ice Rally" of "Knockout Tour".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course while gliding, while heading from "Dandelion Depths" to "Cheep Cheep Falls" in the "Moon Rally" of "Knockout Tour".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a green shell would get stuck on the ground while heading from "Airship Fortress" to "Dry Bones Burnout" in the "Heart Rally" of "Knockout Tour".</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the player would go off the course when they transformed into Bullet Bill on top of a building in "Crown City" in the below races:</li>
<li>Race that heads from "DK Spaceport" to "Crown City".</li>
<li>Race that heads from "Koopa Troopa Beach" to "Crown City".</li>
<li>Race that heads from "Faraway Oasis" to "Crown City".</li>
<li>Several other issues have been addressed to improve the gameplay experience.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<figure data-count="2" role="group">
<figure>
 


</figure>
<figure>
 


</figure>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Nintendo</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>If you are still on the fence about giving Mario Kart World a spin, be <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mario-kart-world-review">sure to check out Eurogamer's review</a>, where our Tom remarked how the game "offers neat twists on the classic Mario Kart formula", calling it all "entertaining, snackable, fun".</p><p>Elsewhere in Nintendo news, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/metroid-prime-4">Metroid Prime 4: Beyond</a> finally releases tomorrow, after what has felt like eons of waiting. "Metroid Prime 4: Beyond is enjoyable enough, and has glimpses of vintage Metroid shining through, but this game could and should have been so much more," reads <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/metroid-prime-4-beyond-review">Eurogamer's Metroid Prime 4: Beyond review</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/huge-mario-kart-world-update-changes-course-layouts-dash-food-reappearances-and-so-much-more]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>