<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 16:37:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Max Payne 1 & 2 remake enters full production, Control 2 features in "playable form"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/max-payne-1-2-remake-enters-full-production-control-2-features-in-playable-form</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/max-payne-1-2-remake-enters-full-production-control-2-features-in-playable-form.949359/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/max-payne-1-2-remake-enters-full-production-control-2-features-in-playable-form<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Alan Wake 2 still not generating royalties.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/control-1_f1wBd5A.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Remedy Entertainment</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Remedy Entertainment has released its latest <a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/announcements/remedy-entertainment-plc-half-year-financial-report-january-june-2024-codename-condor-and-max-payne-12-remake-in-full-production-and-alan-wake-2-night-springs-expansion-launched/">half-year financial report</a>, detailing progress on some of its most anticipated titles - with its Max Payne 1 &amp; 2 remake confirmed to have entered full production, while "important" Control 2 features are now in "playable form".
</p>
<p>
Remedy <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/max-payne-1-and-2-remake-in-the-works-remedy-confirms">confirmed it was remaking cult-classic slo-mo shooters Max Payne 1 &amp; 2</a> back in 2022 as part of a collaboration with Rockstar, and the studio has sporadically offered updates since then. Last October brought the news the project had <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/remedys-control-2-still-in-proof-of-concept-stage-as-max-payne-remake-enters-production-readiness">entered "production readiness"</a>, and things are now a further step closer to release as the game moves to "full production".
</p>
<p>
More specifically, Remedy says the development team "has been working towards developing the game to an early functional state from beginning to end."
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Alan Wake 2's Night Springs expansion arrived in June.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EgRKLZtNSag" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Live-service <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/remedy-details-control-live-service-multiplayer-spin-off">Control spin-off</a> Condor, now the only multiplayer game in the works at Remedy following the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/alan-wake-developer-cancels-premium-co-op-multiplayer-codename-kestrel-despite-early-promise">cancellation of Codename Kestrel</a> earlier this year, has also reached full production, with "multiple maps and different mission types" in development. Remedy adds it's been stepping up its internal and limited external testing "for feature validation and feedback."
</p>
<p>
As for Control 2, the sequel to 2019's acclaimed weird office shooter, that's not at quite such an advanced stage. Right now, it's in "production readiness", and the team is said to have reached an key milestone in "delivering a build of the game showcasing several important features in playable form". Remedy is working towards scaling up production on the project, with "business negotiations" continuing.
</p>
<p>
Elsewhere in Remedy world, Alan Wake 2 still hasn't sold enough copies to begin generating royalties for Remedy despite launching to significant critical acclaim, but the studio notes it's now "recouped most of its development and marketing expenses". It also highlights "excellent" press reviews and fan feedback for this year's Night Springs expansion, and points toward the physical edition of Alan Wake 2 arriving this October.
</p>
<p>
That coincides with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/alan-wake-2-expansions-detailed-include-trip-inside-fictional-tv-show">Alan Wake 2's second DLC</a>, The Lake House, which sees players exploring a "mysterious facility situated on the shores of Cauldron Lake set up by an independent government organisation to conduct secret research... until something goes wrong".
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Doom Console Port Flooded With Old Mario Mods And More]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/doom-new-mods-super-mario-xbox-simpsons-bethesda-ps5-1851618087</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-doom-console-port-flooded-with-old-mario-mods-and-more.949353/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/doom-new-mods-super-mario-xbox-simpsons-bethesda-ps5-1851618087<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The newest official port of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/lets-rank-all-the-doom-games-from-worst-to-best-1846753672&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/lets-rank-all-the-doom-games-from-worst-to-best-1846753672"><em>Doom </em>and <em>Doom 2</em></a></span>—classic ‘90s shooters from id Software—fully supports player-created mods and maps. And in less than 48 hours, you can now shoot <em>Mario </em>characters in <em>Doom </em>on your Xbox thanks to modders.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196049" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="134" data-playlist="196049,196163,196653" data-current="196049"><div><p>This Modern Warfare 3 Gameplay Feature Spices Up A Weak Campaign</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196049/196049_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21580.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Yesterday at QuakeCon, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-new-port-free-quakecon-snes-mod-tools-eternal-pc-1851617354&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-new-port-free-quakecon-snes-mod-tools-eternal-pc-1851617354">id Software announced <em>Doom + Doom II</em></a></span>, a new enhanced port of the classic FPS games that include some new features and content, like a new official episode of <em>Doom</em>. But more interestingly, this recently released port adds full mod support to all platforms, letting anyone upload custom maps and mods to be played on Xbox and PlayStation. And uh, people are going wild with this feature, adding famous maps like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/b2Hx8RGxiPI&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/b2Hx8RGxiPI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">nuts.wad,</a></span> and a ton of IP-infringing mods that might not stick around long. </p><p>On Thursday, after work, I booted up the new<em> Doom + Doom II </em>port on my Xbox Series X and started checking out the mods that people had uploaded. At first, it was just a few things like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/sigil-ii&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/sigil-ii">Romero’s <em>SIGIL 2</em></a></span> and <em>Harmony</em>. Cool stuff, for sure, but nothing <em>too </em>weird. </p><p>But by the end of the night, I found a <em>Super Mario Bros </em>mod, multiple uploads of <em>Hexen</em>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/doom-2-free-mods-myhouse-download-gzdoom-goty-1850616515&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/doom-2-free-mods-myhouse-download-gzdoom-goty-1850616515">the creepy (and recently created) myhouse.wad</a></span>, a few versions of nuts.wad, and even <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://archive.org/details/harrisdoom&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://archive.org/details/harrisdoom" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a controversial map pack created</a></span> by one of the Columbine shooters. Someone has also uploaded a working version of “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://youtu.be/NysJBmCVNJw&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://youtu.be/NysJBmCVNJw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Imp Encounter</a></span>,” aka the <em>Doom </em>map that infamously ends with the Doomguy having sex with an Imp enemy. So that’s now playable on Xbox, which is something I never expected.</p><p>As of Friday morning, all of these mods are still available to play on my Xbox. Just a few minutes ago, I booted up the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.doomworld.com/forum/topic/116454-mariodoompk3-vanilla-edition-unofficial-patch/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.doomworld.com/forum/topic/116454-mariodoompk3-vanilla-edition-unofficial-patch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Super Mario Bros </em>mod</a></span>, which swaps out enemies, weapons, and sound effects from <em>Doom </em>with stuff from the Nintendo franchise. It’s pretty well-made and has been floating around the web since the early 2000s. </p><p>Another I checked out isn’t as well made and features <em>Simpsons </em>characters replacing demons. I’m not sure Nintendo or Disney will be happy to see either of these mods playable on Xbox or PlayStation. I have to assume that Bethesda is going to sweep through these mods soon and start removing some of this stuff. </p><p>To be clear, I don’t want that to happen. <em>Doom </em>modding has a long history of taking other franchises and characters and cramming them into the classic FPS. Some of the best and most-played mods in history mix and match different IPs in silly ways. It’s a core part of <em>Doom </em>modding. </p><p>But, I also expect Bethesda doesn’t want to upset any other companies or risk a lawsuit, so I doubt these mods survive for long. But hey, if you are quick enough, you can download some and check them out on Xbox or PlayStation and have some fun before the lawyers ruin everything. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When To Expect The Next College Football 25 Title Updates]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/when-to-expect-the-next-college-football-25-title-updates/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-to-expect-the-next-college-football-25-title-updates.949347/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/when-to-expect-the-next-college-football-25-title-updates/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>College Football 25 just received its second title update of the year — the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/college-football-25-gets-first-major-title-update/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first major one</a>, however — on Thursday, August 8. Of course, that won’t be the last major update to come to the first college football game in 11 years.</p>



<p>While EA Sports hasn’t confirmed when future title updates are coming, we do have an idea thanks to a <a href="https://x.com/trayj08/status/1821684374435217857" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">twitter post</a> from the Virginia Cavaliers deputy athletics director Tyler Jones.</p>







<p>According to Jones, who spoke with EA about updates to Virginia’s stadium in the game, College Football 25’s third title update is “scheduled 45 days after the original launch”. That would put the release around August 29, just before the start of the real college football season.</p>



<p>He then mentioned the fifth title update, which is scheduled for 90 days after launch. That would put it around October 17 if it remains on schedule.</p>



<p>Based on the timeline Jones gave in his post, College Football 25 should receive five title updates within the first three months. It’s unlikely that any future updates will be as large in scale as August 8th’s, but it’s still nice to know what a tentative schedule is like. Also, there will continue to be various small patches in between the larger title updates as issues arise that need urgent addressing.</p>



<p>College Football 25 is available now for PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S.</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the timeline for future College Football 25 title updates? For more Insider Gaming, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dungeons-and-degenerate-gamblers-review/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our review for Dungeons and Degenerate Gamblers</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bandai Namco Announce First-Ever Dragon Ball MOBA Game, Dragon Ball Project: Multi]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/bandai-namco-announce-first-ever-dragon-ball-moba-game-dragon-ball-project-multi</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bandai-namco-announce-first-ever-dragon-ball-moba-game-dragon-ball-project-multi.949344/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/bandai-namco-announce-first-ever-dragon-ball-moba-game-dragon-ball-project-multi<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Putting the Z-fighters in a MOBA just makes sense. </h2></div><section><p>Bandai Namco announced the first-ever team-oriented free-to-play Dragon Ball Z MOBA game called Dragon Ball Project: Multi.</p><p>Dragon Ball Project: Multi, developed by <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/03/13/one-piece-world-seeker-review">One Piece World Seeker</a> developer Ganbarion, is a top-down action RTS game that features 4v4 battles where players must utilize heroes' abilities to turn the tide in battle. Such heroes include Goku, Vegeta, Future Trunks, Piccolo, Krillin, Android 18, and Majin Buu. The will also feature series villains spanning Dragon Ball’s mythos like Cooler from Dragon Ball Z, and Dragon Ball Super’s Zamasu and Vermoud. </p><blockquote data-theme="light">— DRAGON BALL PROJECT : Multi (@db_prjmulti) <a href="https://twitter.com/db_prjmulti/status/1821458190728626634?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 8, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>According to its <a href="https://dbpm.bn-ent.net/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>official website</u></a>, the game will be playable on Google Play, The App Store, and Steam. Along with Dragon Ball Project: Multi’s reveal, the company also announced its regional beta test, which will last from August 20 to September 3. </p><p>Like any MOBA, Dragon Ball Project: Multi will require players to conquer enemy objectives by organizing a well-rounded team comprised of tanks, support, and damage characters. The game will also offer customization options, allowing players to swap skins, entrance, and finisher animations. Because Dragon Ball Project: Ulti is mainly geared toward online matches, players will be required to have an internet connection to play. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>DRAGON BALL PROJECT: Multi - Official Reveal Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Dragon Ball fans appear to be in a bit of a renaissance with the imminent return of the Budokai series in Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero. In <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-is-like-controlling-a-battle-from-the-anime">our preview</a>, we lauded the game for its battles feeling like they were lifted right out of the anime, saying, “Even after just a dozen or so matches against the CPU, it became clear to me that Dragon Ball superfans who are exceptionally good at fighting games – or those who intend to practice a lot with Sparking Zero – are going to find themselves having a great time crushing their competition.” </p><p>Seeing as how we’re roughly nine weeks away from Sparking! Zero’s release on October 11, Dragon Ball Project: Multi has the latent potential to be a refreshing new game for players to test their Z-fighter battle senses.   </p><p>Isaiah Colbert is a freelance writer for IGN. You can follow them on Twitter @ShinEyeZehUhh.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Under Defeat coming west for PS5, PS4, and Switch this fall, Xbox and PC later]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/under-defeat-coming-west-for-ps5-ps4-and-switch-this-fall-xbox-and-pc-later</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/under-defeat-coming-west-for-ps5-ps4-and-switch-this-fall-xbox-and-pc-later.949341/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/under-defeat-coming-west-for-ps5-ps4-and-switch-this-fall-xbox-and-pc-later<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Published by Clear River Games.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Clear River Games [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/clear-river-games">Clear River Games</a>, in cooperation with <a title="Companies > City Connection [173 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/city-connection">City Connection</a>, will release <a title="Genres > Shoot 'Em Up [723 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up">shoot ’em up</a> <em><a title="Games > Under Defeat (2024) [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/under-defeat-2024">Under Defeat</a></em> both physically and digitally for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,628 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,039 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,769 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> this fall in the west, followed by a digital-only release for <a title="Platforms > Xbox [24,519 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox">Xbox</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,849 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam at a later date, the companies announced. <span id="more-904977"></span></p><p>In Japan, <em>Under Defeat</em> <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/under-defeat-for-ps5-ps4-and-switch-launches-december-5-in-japan">is due out</a> for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and Switch on December 5.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Clear River Games:</p><blockquote><p><em>Under Defeat</em> plunges the gamer into an alternative history where all-out war has erupted across the fictional “continent” and players battle against their mortal enemies “The Union” in a nail-biting fight for <a title="Genres > Survival [301 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a>.</p><p>The development of this new release is being handled by City Connection, valued partner of Clear River Games, under supervision by Takehiro Eda and <a title="Companies > Zerodiv [55 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/city-connection/zerodiv">Zerodiv</a> Fukushima Factory, renowned in the <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,837 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a> community for their high-quality ports of classic games.</p><p>Originally released in Japanese <a title="Platforms > Arcade [372 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/arcade">arcades</a> in 2005 via <a title="Companies > G.rev [44 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/g-rev">G.rev</a>‘s arcade release, <em>Under Defeat</em> has the player assume control of a weapon laden helicopter as they maneuver across a semi-isometric playfield taking on a non-stop barrage of enemy airborne and ground-based combat vehicles. Renowned for its impressive 3D graphics and high intensity gameplay, <em>Under Defeat</em> now arrives on modern console platforms with no less than three game modes designed to suit the gamers’ preference and supervised by G.rev.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><a title="Genres > Arcade [57 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">Arcade</a> Mode faithfully replicates the original arcade experience, presenting the game in a 4:3 ratio and a pseudo vertical screen, for the purest possible representation of the game. New Order Mode adapts the game for modern displays, transforming the adrenaline packed shooting <a title="Genres > Action [2,072 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> to widescreen 16:9 ratio, and New Order Mode+ brings a host of additional elements to the game, not least being a “WARNING GAUGE,” which adds a risk/reward mechanic to assist the player as they shoot, bomb and swerve through the hordes of enemy invaders. All modes have access to a choice of four unique helicopters to pilot into battle, each with different attributes and weapon systems. In addition, this new release also features newly added practice features for each mode, along with a choice of all three existing soundtracks, and a new Boosted soundtrack by video game music veteran, Shinji Hosoe (<em>Ridge Racer</em> series, <em>Tekken</em> series, etc.) and his company, Super Sweep.</p></blockquote><p>View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/under-defeat-2024/august-9-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_904980"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[14-Game Star Wars Collection Is Only $13 For The Next 24 Hours]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/14-game-star-wars-collection-is-only-13-for-the-next-24-hours/1100-6504813/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/14-game-star-wars-collection-is-only-13-for-the-next-24-hours.949338/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/14-game-star-wars-collection-is-only-13-for-the-next-24-hours/1100-6504813/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6504813">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The <span data-embed-type="buylink" data-size="buylink__embed" data-collection="%7B%22text%22:%22Star%20Wars%20Collection%20is%20on%20sale%20for%20only%20$13%22,%22monetizedUrl%22:%22https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-100770772-13797872?sid=subid_value&amp;url=https://www.fanatical.com/en/bundle/star-wars-collection?v=4042%22,%22rawUrl%22:%22https://www.fanatical.com/en/bundle/star-wars-collection?v=4042%22%7D">           <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.anrdoezrs.net%2Fclick-100770772-13797872%3Fsid%3Dsubid_value%26url%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.fanatical.com%252Fen%252Fbundle%252Fstar-wars-collection%253Fv%253D4042&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2F14-game-star-wars-collection-is-only-13-for-the-next-24-hours%2F1100-6504813%2F&amp;event_type=click" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.fanatical.com\/en\/bundle\/star-wars-collection?v=4042&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;buylink|embedded-link&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;buylink|embedded-link&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.fanatical.com/en/bundle/star-wars-collection?v=4042">Star Wars Collection is on sale for only $13</a> </span> at Fanatical until tomorrow, August 10 at 8 AM PT / 11 AM ET. This bundle contains 14 games from the Star Wars franchise, all of which will unlock immediately after purchase as Steam keys. You're paying less than a buck for each game--and the Star Wars Collection features a few of the very <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/best-star-wars-games-of-all-time/2900-4064/" data-ref-id="2900-4064">best Star Wars games</a>. This offer is one of the latest flash deals in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fanatical-summer-sale-includes-hundreds-of-steam-games-for-big-discounts/1100-6525417/" data-ref-id="1100-6525417">Fanatical's massive Summer Sale</a>. As an added bonus, you'll get a free bonus game or coupon for spending over $12 during the sale.</p><p>Three of our favorite Star Wars games our featured in the bundle: Knights of the Old Republic, Star Wars: Republic Commando, and Star Wars Jedi Knight II: Jedi Outcast.</p><p>KOTOR is arguably the most beloved Star Wars game. Once you roll credits on the classic RPG, you can jump into Star Wars Knights of the Old Republic II: The Sith Lords, which is also included in the collection. And if you're looking for a more action-focused Star Wars game, both Force Unleashed games are in the Star Wars Collection.</p><p>While Jedi Knight II is probably the best in the sub-series, three other titles from that era are up for grabs here: Jedi Academy, Dark Forces II, and Mysteries of the Sith.</p><p>Only one aerial combat Star Wars game is included: Star Wars: Starfighter. But hey, you can also check out the original Star Wars: Battlefront II and the great 2006 RTS Star Wars: Empire at War.</p><h2>Star Wars Collection</h2><ul><li>Star Wars: Knights of the Old Republic</li><li>Star Wars Knights of the Old Republic II: The Sith Lords</li><li>Star Wars: Republic Commando</li><li>Star Wars: The Force Unleashed</li><li>Star Wars: The Force Unleashed II</li><li>Star Wars Jedi Knight: Jedi Academy</li><li>Star Wars Jedi Knight II: Jedi Outcast</li><li>Star Wars Jedi Knight: Dark Forces II</li><li>Star Wars Jedi Knight: Mysteries of the Sith</li><li>Star Wars: Dark Forces</li><li>Star Wars: Empire at War</li><li>Star Wars: Battlefront II (2005)</li><li>Star Wars: Starfighter</li><li>Star Wars: The Clone Wars - Republic Heroes</li></ul><p><em>Disclosure: GameSpot and Fanatical are both owned by Fandom.</em></p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/lego-new-releases-august-2024-mario-star-wars-marvel-minecraft-batman/2900-5655/">Over 100 Lego Sets Released This Month - Here Are The Biggest Ones</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-18-lego-video-games-for-only-15-marvel-batman-lotr-star-wars-and-more/1100-6525462/">Get 18 Lego Video Games For Only $15 - Marvel, Batman, LOTR, Star Wars, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/super-mario-world-lego-set-preorder-mario-and-yoshi/1100-6525283/">Super Mario World Lego Set Is Up For Preorder At Target</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (4)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/7-new-lego-minecraft-sets-are-available-now-including-the-iconic-crafting-table/1100-6523896/">7 New Lego Minecraft Sets Are Available Now, Including The Iconic Crafting Table</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-lite-bundle-with-animal-crossing-new-horizons-is-only-159-at-walmart/1100-6522718/">Nintendo Switch Lite Bundle With Animal Crossing: New Horizons Is Only $159 At Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/playstation-back-to-school-sale-2024-ps5-games-playstation-vr-ps5-slim-deals/2900-5638/">PlayStation Back To School Sale: Save Over 50% On PS5 Exclusives, $200 On PSVR 2, And $50 On Consoles</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvels-spider-man-2-drops-to-best-price-yet-alongside-more-great-ps5-game-deals/1100-6525363/">Marvel's Spider-Man 2 Drops To Best Price Yet Alongside More Great PS5 Game Deals</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525536&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/star-wars-outlaws-will-let-you-meet-the-coolest-gambler-in-the-galaxy-if-you-pay\/1100-6525536\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525540&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/why-lego-star-wars-is-bringing-darth-jar-jar-to-life-in-rebuild-the-galaxy\/1100-6525540\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525525&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-season-2-gets-first-teaser-trailer\/1100-6525525\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525548&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-first-dark-souls-manga-releases-this-month-preorder-for-15-at-amazon\/1100-6525548\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525533&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-hamish-linklater-tried-to-find-his-batman-voice-for-caped-crusader\/1100-6525533\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525538&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/star-trek-prodigy-creators-want-to-continue-show-in-live-action-or-as-a-movie\/1100-6525538\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525498&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-advent-calendars-2024-star-wars-spider-man-harry-potter-disney\/1100-6525498\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525451&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/jeff-vandermeer-absolution-southern-reach-annihilation-preorder-guide\/1100-6525451\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525545&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fall-guys-invades-fortnites-battle-royale-modes\/1100-6525545\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525542&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/m-night-shayamalan-trap-4k-blu-ray-preorder-amazon\/1100-6525542\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525567&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/metal-gear-solid-nendoroid-preorders-restocked-at-amazon-low-poly-snake-and-naked-raiden\/1100-6525567\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525571&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/jenna-ortega-revisits-her-controversial-wednesday-comments\/1100-6525571\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525559&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/james-sa-corey-the-expanse-writer-new-series-captives-war-the-mercy-of-gods-book-one\/1100-6525559\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525581&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fallout-power-armor-collection-mega-bloks-set-is-up-for-preorder-and-its-super-affordable\/1100-6525581\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525584&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-explains-why-it-invested-1-5-billion-into-fortnite-and-what-it-hopes-to-achieve\/1100-6525584\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6516023&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-solstice-guide-how-to-get-silver-leaves-upgrade-armor-and-more\/1100-6516023\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525580&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/destiny-2-fortunate-star-god-roll-guide\/1100-6525580\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525582&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/david-fincher-movie-zodiac-4k-blu-ray-preorder\/1100-6525582\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525610&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-batman-coming-back-to-theaters-with-sneak-peak-of-the-penguin\/1100-6525610\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525628&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ea-sports-college-football-25-patch-adds-new-on-field-fits-formations-and-bug-fixes\/1100-6525628\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Is Getting Its Own In-Game Disney Store, According To Leak]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-is-getting-its-own-in-game-disney-store-according-to-leak/1100-6525674/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-is-getting-its-own-in-game-disney-store-according-to-leak.949335/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-is-getting-its-own-in-game-disney-store-according-to-leak/1100-6525674/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525674">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Disney might be getting its own dedicated store within Fortnite, and it could be announced very soon.</p><p>A leaked image has surfaced online showing what appears to be a separate store section for Disney and Marvel skins that Fortnite has had thus far. The reason for Disney and Epic for going down this route is unclear, but it's possible that due to the many collaborations between them, perhaps they wanted to make their skins more readily available.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/ShiinaBR/status/1821930442758733912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1821930442758733912%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">RUMOR: FIRST LOOK AT AN UPCOMING DISNEY ITEM SHOP 🔥<br>This image was sent to <a href="https://twitter.com/HYPEX?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@HYPEX</a> &amp; me earlier today. The person who sent this to us explained that Epic Games is "developing a Disney IP store in Fortnite" 👀<br>If accurate, this update might be announced at D23 tomorrow! <a href="https://t.co/7HPxUGiaUr" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/7HPxUGiaUr</a></p>  — Shiina (@ShiinaBR) <a href="https://twitter.com/ShiinaBR/status/1821930442758733912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 9, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Many Disney skins, such as Darth Vader and the original Spider-Man, can't be obtained anymore either because they were limited-time items or locked away behind previous battle passes.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/watch-a-d23-presentation-about-fortnite-x-disney-get-a-free-wolverine-themed-back-bling/1100-6525630/" data-ref-id="1100-6525630">D23 takes place from August 9-11</a> so it's possible that this announcement could be revealed there. Coincidentally, Fortnite is making a big change to its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-ends-exclusivity-for-future-battle-passes/1100-6525606/" data-ref-id="1100-6525606">battle-pass structure</a>. Starting with the upcoming Chapter 5 Season 4 battle pass, items will not be exclusive to the season they belong to.</p><p>Additionally, Disney pumped <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/disney-explains-why-it-invested-1-5-billion-into-fortnite-and-what-it-hopes-to-achieve/1100-6525584/" data-ref-id="1100-6525584">$1.5 billion into Fortnite back in February</a>, which makes the revelation of a apparently separate store for Disney IP much more interesting.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Lite-Brite Gets Nice Discount At Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-lite-brite-gets-nice-discount-at-amazon/1100-6519149/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-lite-brite-gets-nice-discount-at-amazon.949332/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-lite-brite-gets-nice-discount-at-amazon/1100-6519149/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6519149">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Only cool kids play with Lite-Brite toys which allow their imagination to shine with the unbridled power of neatly arranged LEDs, but <em>really cool </em>kids play with Pokemon Lite-Brites. Released over the holidays last year, the <strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CBQLPWJF?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Pokemon Lite-Brite featuring Pikachu is on sale for 20% off at Amazon</a></strong>, dropping the price from $25 to $20.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4220398-pokemon-brite.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4220398" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4220398-pokemon-brite.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4220398"></a><figcaption>Pokemon Lite-Brite</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1601/16018044/4220398-pokemon-brite.jpg"></figure><p>The classic creative toy has been updated with a high-definition light grid that is brighter and better than ever with double the LEDs. You'll get six high-definition Pokemon templates with this special-edition Lite-Brite, allowing you to create charming designs featuring Piakchu and several Poke Balls.</p><p>Simply place your favorite template under the grid, start inserting the right pegs, and congratulations! You've created some adorable art. This set comes with 1,000 mini-pegs, four light modes, and a USB port so that you brighten up the home with your designs.</p><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/lego-new-releases-august-2024-mario-star-wars-marvel-minecraft-batman/2900-5655/">Over 100 Lego Sets Released This Month - Here Are The Biggest Ones</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/get-18-lego-video-games-for-only-15-marvel-batman-lotr-star-wars-and-more/1100-6525462/">Get 18 Lego Video Games For Only $15 - Marvel, Batman, LOTR, Star Wars, And More</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/super-mario-world-lego-set-preorder-mario-and-yoshi/1100-6525283/">Super Mario World Lego Set Is Up For Preorder At Target</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (4)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/7-new-lego-minecraft-sets-are-available-now-including-the-iconic-crafting-table/1100-6523896/">7 New Lego Minecraft Sets Are Available Now, Including The Iconic Crafting Table</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-lite-bundle-with-animal-crossing-new-horizons-is-only-159-at-walmart/1100-6522718/">Nintendo Switch Lite Bundle With Animal Crossing: New Horizons Is Only $159 At Walmart</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/playstation-back-to-school-sale-2024-ps5-games-playstation-vr-ps5-slim-deals/2900-5638/">PlayStation Back To School Sale: Save Over 50% On PS5 Exclusives, $200 On PSVR 2, And $50 On Consoles</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/marvels-spider-man-2-drops-to-best-price-yet-alongside-more-great-ps5-game-deals/1100-6525363/">Marvel's Spider-Man 2 Drops To Best Price Yet Alongside More Great PS5 Game Deals</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525525&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-last-of-us-season-2-gets-first-teaser-trailer\/1100-6525525\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525519&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/avowed-delayed-to-february-2025-graciously-making-2024-a-little-less-crowded\/1100-6525519\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525521&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/alien-romulus-clip-channels-director-fede-alvarezs-past-work\/1100-6525521\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525522&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/apex-legends-devs-on-season-22s-new-map-dual-wielding-pistols-and-controversial-new-battle-pass\/1100-6525522\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525529&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-features-familiar-locations-scrumptious-slushies\/1100-6525529\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525526&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/monster-hunter-wilds-introduces-new-gameplay-systems-to-make-you-deadly-and-precise\/1100-6525526\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525527&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dataminer-thinks-half-life-3-is-in-development-after-resume-leak\/1100-6525527\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525535&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-3-will-include-queens-blood\/1100-6525535\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525533&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-hamish-linklater-tried-to-find-his-batman-voice-for-caped-crusader\/1100-6525533\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525537&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/diablo-4-has-terrible-secret-item-nobody-wants-to-use\/1100-6525537\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525536&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/star-wars-outlaws-will-let-you-meet-the-coolest-gambler-in-the-galaxy-if-you-pay\/1100-6525536\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525538&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/star-trek-prodigy-creators-want-to-continue-show-in-live-action-or-as-a-movie\/1100-6525538\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525532&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/former-game-informer-staffer-offers-an-actual-farewell-be-well-play-well\/1100-6525532\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525540&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/why-lego-star-wars-is-bringing-darth-jar-jar-to-life-in-rebuild-the-galaxy\/1100-6525540\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525547&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-leaks-continue-this-time-with-a-graphic-new-ability\/1100-6525547\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525543&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/a-john-wick-sequel-series-is-in-development\/1100-6525543\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525541&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/house-of-the-dragon-co-creator-says-season-4-will-end-the-series\/1100-6525541\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525498&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/lego-advent-calendars-2024-star-wars-spider-man-harry-potter-disney\/1100-6525498\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525539&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/house-of-the-dragon-season-two-blu-ray-preorders-game-of-thrones\/1100-6525539\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525128&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/how-to-make-a-fence-in-minecraft\/1100-6525128\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Control 2 Hits "Important Milestone," As Max Payne 1 And 2 Remakes Go Into Full Production]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/control-2-hits-important-milestone-as-max-payne-1-and-2-remakes-go-into-full-production/1100-6525672/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/control-2-hits-important-milestone-as-max-payne-1-and-2-remakes-go-into-full-production.949329/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/control-2-hits-important-milestone-as-max-payne-1-and-2-remakes-go-into-full-production/1100-6525672/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525672">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">There is now a playable build of Control 2, meaning the sequel has entered the "production readiness stage." That's not the only notable development at Remedy, either. The company announced that the Max Payne 1 and 2 remakes have gone into "full production."</p><p dir="ltr">Remedy detailed these upcoming projects as part of its <a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/announcements/remedy-entertainment-plc-half-year-financial-report-january-june-2024-codename-condor-and-max-payne-12-remake-in-full-production-and-alan-wake-2-night-springs-expansion-launched/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">half-year financial report for 2024</a>. For Control 2, this stage is an "important milestone" because not only is it playable, but the build highlights some features for the sequel, too. The developer adds this will help "ongoing business negotiations." <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/control-2-officially-in-development-for-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s/1100-6509106/" data-ref-id="1100-6509106">Control 2 was officially confirmed</a> in 2022, though earlier this year, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/control-2-is-still-a-ways-off-but-spin-off-codename-condor-is-getting-closer/1100-6523034/" data-ref-id="1100-6523034">Remedy said it was still a ways off.</a></p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1828536427" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6462721,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Alan%20Wake%202%20Review&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:0,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/alan-wake-2-review\/2300-6462721\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6462721\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6462721\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6462721\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6462721&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1568\/15687785\/4211703-review_aw2_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:[],&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1698325200,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="k4EFSth5" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Alan Wake 2 Review</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, it's full steam ahead for the Max Payne 1 and 2 remakes. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/remedy-is-remaking-max-payne-1-and-2-for-pc-ps5-and-xbox-series-x-s/1100-6502260/" data-ref-id="1100-6502260">Originally revealed in 2022</a>, the remakes will combine Max Payne and Max Payne 2: The Fall of Max Payne into a single package for PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X|S. Remedy is working with Rockstar and utilizing the Northlight game engine for the title, which was previously used for Control.</p><p dir="ltr">Last but not least, the Control multiplayer spin-off game called Codename Condor is now seeing "external playtesting for feature validation and feedback." Remedy also points out "multiple maps" and various missions for the title.</p><p dir="ltr">Another multiplayer game that was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/alan-wake-dev-cancels-multiplayer-game-before-it-was-even-announced/1100-6523223/" data-ref-id="1100-6523223">in the works at Remedy codenamed Kestrel was canceled earlier this year</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Garden Path's savviest design decision: connecting to the cosmos]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/the-garden-path-s-savviest-design-decision-connecting-to-the-cosmos</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-garden-paths-savviest-design-decision-connecting-to-the-cosmos.949308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/the-garden-path-s-savviest-design-decision-connecting-to-the-cosmos<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via carrotcake and MoonCat Games</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I'm only a few hours into Carrotcake's cozy forest exploration/gardening sim, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Garden Path</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but I'm already impressed. I have whatever gene it is that makes games of this nature connect on a deep synaptic level: on my Switch alone I've played well over 2500 hours of the original </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cozy Grove</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> (itself a sort of "Animal Crossing with crafting and more story"), and close to that in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Animal Crossing: New Horizons</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. There's something deeply appealing about this style of game for me as a sort of warm-up to my day (and nice place to check in on and chill out with during the work day), and thus far, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Garden Path</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is scratching that itch well.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It's much more </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cozy Grove</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> than anything else in cozy sim territory, but with a fairly different tone and much more emphasis on gardening vs. other kinds of crafting. We have the requisite chill questing on behalf of cute characters, lots of checking up on plant life, foraging, fishing (though there is a different minigame afoot for actually catching them) and here, the gardening. But there's one particularly wonderful design decision that caught my eye the second I encountered it: the way the game rewards your progress. Instead of a cute journal or notebook like the aforementioned games, your achievements are marked by stars in the sky.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="The Garden Path to the stars">The Garden Path to the stars</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The first time I brewed a cup of tea at a forest firepit (itself an adorable system that has gameplay value), the camera turned up towards the sky and showed me my first star, awarded for making that first cuppa. Stars are linked in constellations, lending cottagecore vibes that fit well with the game's aesthetic and evoking the best part of camping or spending time outdoors on a summer night: looking up at the cosmos. Other games of its ilk have hinted at the universe above: sky reflections and star fragments, objects with astronomical flair, and so on. But I do very much want to look up and star gaze when I'm in these peaceful worlds, and this gives me the chance to do just that.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">It also evokes a certain brilliant and perhaps forgotten aspect of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Super Mario 64</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, where earning a star (in a less literal sense) came with a sometimes-vague hint about how to grab another one (or a few others, depending on how you go about the game). </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Garden Path</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> uses the system to hint at other star achievements, in a way that feels satisfying and even a tiny bit mysterious, like a lightly signposted adventure game puzzle. It's charming, it's effective, and it keeps me invested in this game's beautiful world.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Time will tell if </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Garden Path</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will worm its way into my heart with quite the same intensity as </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Cozy Grove</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. But as I write this, I feel the itch to go check in on my garden—and on the stars above it.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Editor-in-Chief, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Danielle is the editor-in-chief of Game Developer, with previous editorial posts at Fanbyte, VICE, and Polygon. She’s also a lecturer in game design at the Berklee College of Music, and a hobbyist game developer in her spare time.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Looks like Valve is introducing a new review system to filter out "unhelpful" reviews]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/looks-like-valve-is-introducing-a-new-review-system-to-filter-out-unhelpful-reviews</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/looks-like-valve-is-introducing-a-new-review-system-to-filter-out-unhelpful-reviews.949305/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/looks-like-valve-is-introducing-a-new-review-system-to-filter-out-unhelpful-reviews<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>Valve looks to be introducing a new filter system to help players sift out user reviews not deemed "helpful."</p>
<p>As spotted by a member of the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Steam/comments/1emb4ch/valve_is_finally_addressing_bad_reviews_issue/">Steam subreddit</a>, Valve appears to have briefly activated a "helpfulness system" that essentially hid joke or silly reviews from view.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PlayStation live-service Concord won't sell you a battle pass - would it be better if it did?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PlayStation live-service Concord won't sell you a battle pass - would it be better if it did?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>PlayStation live-service Concord won't sell you a battle pass - but would it be more successful if it did?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1LcpqnUgV5E" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The system has already been deactivated again, so it looks as though the feature is still under review, but a user was able to snap a screenshot whilst the trial (or premature launch) was live.</p>
<blockquote data-embed-height="316"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Steam/comments/1emb4ch/valve_is_finally_addressing_bad_reviews_issue/">Valve is finally addressing bad reviews issue</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/fuckingshitverybitch/">u/fuckingshitverybitch</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Steam/">Steam</a></blockquote><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p>
<p>Interestingly, the "learn more" link apparently took players to a non-existent blog post, adding credence to speculation that this feature is still in development.</p>
<p>It'll be interesting to know who will be the arbiter of "helpful", though, as this is currently one of Elden's <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/rinjvonscoot/recommended/1245620/">highest-rated reviews</a> with over 400 helpful votes: "Nothing in this game was as brutal as the moment when my son saw me fighting [a boss] and started cheering for [the boss]. 10/10."</p>
<p>In case you missed it, Steam has updated how <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/steam-improves-how-demos-appear-and-behave-in-your-library-and-the-steam-store">demos "appear and behave" within the Steam library</a>.</p>
<p>Valve said last month that with "thousands of playable demos launching on Steam every year, and millions of players trying them out, we've noticed some trends in feedback from both developers and players about the process and functionality. We've put together an update based on that feedback".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Japanese Esports Tournament Will Penalise Players For Not Sleeping Enough]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/japanese-tournament-sleep-fighter/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/japanese-esports-tournament-will-penalise-players-for-not-sleeping-enough.949293/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/japanese-tournament-sleep-fighter/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In Japan, an esports tournament called ‘Sleep Fighter’ has surfaced. It has a bizarre concept attached to it that sees players strap on a sleep monitoring device when they go to bed, and if they don’t get enough sleep, they’re penalised in the tournament. It’s a competition being played on the Street Fighter platform (hence the pun), and it’s being sponsored by SS Pharmaceuticals, which is linking the event with an initiative called the ‘Active Sleep Project’.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-it-s-not-a-bad-thing">It’s Not A Bad Thing</h2>



<p>Gamers are notorious for not taking the best care of themselves – which is why his tournament isn’t the worst idea in the world.</p>



<p>In a statement, representatives of SS Pharmaceuticals explained why the Active Sleep Project is so important to everyone – not just gamers:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>By actively sleeping, you can make the most of each day and live your life to the fullest. In order to bring this ‘active sleep’ to as many people as possible, we are starting the Active Sleep Project to do our best to support those who are taking on the challenge of sleeping.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In the week leading up to Sleep Fighter, players will be monitored when they head to bed, and they’ll need to get at least six hours of sleep a night. If they underdeliver, they’ll be docked points when the tournament goes live. It’s a team-based effort, so one poor sleeper could negatively impact their teammates.</p>



<p>The tournament goes live on August 31. In another twist, it was revealed that attendees to the event will need to win a lottery to qualify for a limited spot in the crowd at the Ryogoku KFC Hall in Tokyo.</p>



<p>Would you be able to succeed at this challenge, or do you hate sleeping?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming Esports, check out the news that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/riot-games-valorant-night-market/">VALORANT Night Market is about to make a return</a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonic x Shadow Generations New Images Tease Black Doom & More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-x-shadow-generations-new-images-tease-black-doom-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sonic-x-shadow-generations-new-images-tease-black-doom-more.949290/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-x-shadow-generations-new-images-tease-black-doom-more/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In a new report <a href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/771/G077171/20240809033/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">by 4gamer</a>, new images of Sonic x Shadow Generations tease a modern render of popular antagonist Black Doom and the Sky Sanctuary stage.</p>



<p>The villainous Black Doom first appeared in Shadow the Hedgehog, which released nearly 20 years ago. Fans largely praised the first image of Black Doom’s updated iteration and polished details. </p>



<p>The other two fresh images of Sonic x Shadow Generations include a wide shot of Sonic cruising down a rail in Sky Sanctuary, and speeding across some interior platforms. Longtime Sonic community contributor TailsChannel also posted the new screenshots on X.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Black Doom was leader of the Black Arms, bent on invading Earth and using humanity as livestock. Sonic fans may best recognize Sky Sanctuary as the popular zone from Sonic &amp; Knuckles, an ancient temple floating in the clouds.</p>



<p>Last week, Sega confirmed the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-x-shadow-generations-price-and-game-size-disclosed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">price and game size</a> for Sonic x Shadow Generations after the store page went live. The Standard Edition will cost $49.99, and its file size will be 13.1 GB. </p>



<p>Sega <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-shadow-generations-revealed-playstation-state-of-play/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first announced</a> Sonic x Shadow Generations during PlayStation’s State of Play from January 2024. It later got a new trailer during Summer Game Fest this year, confirming the release date. </p>



<p>Sonic x Shadow Generations launches on October 25, 2024. It will be available on PC, Nintendo Switch, PlayStation, and Xbox, including last-gen consoles.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, you can read about Take-Two CEO CEO Strauss Zelnick <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/take-two-addresses-call-of-duty-on-game-pass-pipeline-plans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">offering new comments</a> about Call of Duty on game pass, and sign up to receive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Losses in Unity's app marketing division drive 16 percent revenue dip]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/losses-in-mobile-marketing-division-drive-16-percent-revenue-dip-at-unity</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/losses-in-unitys-app-marketing-division-drive-16-percent-revenue-dip.949242/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/losses-in-mobile-marketing-division-drive-16-percent-revenue-dip-at-unity<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Even after </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/unity-is-cutting-1-800-jobs-in-the-name-of-profitable-growth-">laying off over a thousand employees</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> at the start of the year, game engine and monetization solutions developer Unity has yet to see the 'profitable growth' it sought. Today the company reported a 16 percent decline in revenue year-over-year (down from $533 million to $426 million), contributing to a net loss of $126 million for the time period ending July 31, 2024.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Unity's losses are nothing new, but their persistent presence was what drove an ill-advised "Runtime Fee" policy introduced in late 2023 that was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/unity-apologizes-to-devs-reveals-updated-runtime-fee-policy">altered</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for Unity 6 users after a mass uproar from developers. The good news is it is losing </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>less</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> money; net losses declined about 35 percent, decreasing from $193 million in 2023 to $126 million.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Unity's Grow Solutions did not in fact, grow">Unity's Grow Solutions did not in fact, grow</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Some of Unity's revenue dip was expected given the company announced it would be winding down strategic partnerships and professional services that proven vestigial to its operations. What's surprising is that revenue from Grow Solutions (Unity's app monetization division, which houses what used to be IronSource and TapJoy) declined 9 percent year over year to $296 million. In a letter to shareholders, newly-installed CEO Matthew Bromberg cast a positive light on the news, saying the division had seen steady quarter-over-quarter growth, meaning it could make up that gap in the months ahead.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Create Solutions, the main hub for the Unity game engine, did see revenue growth despite the Runtime Fee fracas. Revenue from that division rose 4 percent year-over-year to $126 million.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If developers don't jump ship en masse and can swallow the new Unity 6 fees, that revenue could continue to grow.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The losses in Grow Solutions were enough for Unity to adjust its revenue guidance to $1.68 billion to $1.69 billion, down 2-3 percent from its previous forecast. Bromberg informed shareholders that this guidance reflects the company's "cautious approach" to the division's "recovery."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Investments in fundamental product enhancements will take some time to manifest in sustainable increased performance," he penned.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Unity's path forward">Unity's path forward</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On a post-report earnings call with investors he elaborated on that recovery, saying the company needs to focus on its machine learning and data infrastructure stack to better improve performance in ads and monetization. He implied that the company hopes to make fundamental improvements to its offerings, and not just pursue incremental upgrades.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The contrast between Grow Solution and Create Solutions this corner is something of an indictment of Unity's growth-focused business strategy under CEO Riccitiello, whose understanding of the video game market seemed to so hyperfixate on mobile monetization that he at one point called developers who didn't think ahead on monetization "</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/unity-ceo-john-riccitiello-is-sorry-for-calling-devs-fucking-idiots-regrets-using-crude-language">fucking idiots</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">While investors will continue to scrutinize Grow Solutions (which, for better or worse, will continue to earn more in revenue than its game engine division), developers will likely watch out for improvements in Unity 6 that justify keeping with the platform.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bromberg stressed to analysts on the earnings call that Unity plays an important role in the video game ecosystem...but if faith in the company slips away, that role could diminish.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take-Two boss asks you to give the Borderlands movie "a chance", as "a lot of people worked really hard on it"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/take-two-boss-asks-you-to-give-the-borderlands-movie-a-chance-as-a-lot-of-people-worked-really-hard-on-it</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/take-two-boss-asks-you-to-give-the-borderlands-movie-a-chance-as-a-lot-of-people-worked-really-hard-on-it.949239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/take-two-boss-asks-you-to-give-the-borderlands-movie-a-chance-as-a-lot-of-people-worked-really-hard-on-it<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"Let's see what audiences have to say."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/borderlands-movie-still.jpeg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Lionsgate Films</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Take-Two boss Strauss Zelnick would like you to give the new Borderlands movie "a chance" because "a lot of people worked really hard on it".</p>
<p>Zelnick was asked about the film's less-than-stellar early reviews during yesterday's Q1 earnings call, and whilst he called the "look and the feel" of the movie "terrific", Zelnick told <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-ceo-responds-to-borderlands-movies-poor-reviews-give-the-film-a-chance">IGN</a> its performance "wouldn't have a financial impact" on Take-Two or, indeed, the Borderlands franchise itself.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Borderlands (2024) Official Trailer - Cate Blanchett, Kevin Hart, Jack Black" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lU_NKNZljoQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Borderlands (2024) Official Trailer - Cate Blanchett, Kevin Hart, Jack Black</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lU_NKNZljoQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/lU_NKNZljoQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Borderlands movie trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lU_NKNZljoQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Let's give the film a chance. A lot of people worked really hard on it," Zelnick said.</p>
<p>"The underlying intellectual property is phenomenal, the cast is amazing, I think the look and feel is really terrific. So let's see what audiences have to say.</p>
<p>"But to answer your question, no, the performance of the film wouldn't have a financial impact on us or on the franchise one way or another."</p>
<p>The Borderlands movie has, of course, been in the works for some time now. It was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/borderlands-movie-in-the-works">initially announced</a> back in 2015 before utterly vanishing. Just as it looked like the project was dead and buried, Gearbox <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hostel-director-eli-roth-is-helming-the-borderlands-movie">re-announced it</a> in February 2020, this time with Hostel director Eli Roth at the helm.</p>
<p>Since then, the high-profile likes of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/cate-blanchett-cast-in-eli-roths-borderlands-movie-adaptation">Cate Blanchett</a>, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/borderlands-movie-signs-up-jamie-lee-curtis">Jamie Lee Curtis</a>, Gina Gershiwn, Kevin Hart, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/jack-black-joins-borderlands-movie-cast-as-claptrap">Jack Black</a> all signed onto the project, giving fans at least some hope it wouldn't entirely suck.</p>
<p>But then came the reviews and… well, as Matt summarised for us yesterday, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/early-borderlands-movie-impressions-brand-it-a-disaster-and-a-huge-misfire">early impressions are not great</a>, with critics lamblasting the live-action film adaptation of Gearbox's looter-shooter as everything from a "huge misfire" to a "disaster".</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Optimized Path Tracing Mod v5.0 Brings up to 40% Performance Improvement]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-optimized-path-tracing-mod-40-performance-improvement/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-optimized-path-tracing-mod-v5-0-brings-up-to-40-performance-improvement.949233/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-2077-optimized-path-tracing-mod-40-performance-improvement/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The latest version of a popular Cyberpunk 2077 brings significant performance improvements with path tracing at all resolutions, as showcased by a comparison video shared today.</p>
<p>The new video put together by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MxBenchmarkPC">MxBenchmarkPC</a> highlights how the 5.0 version of the <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/cyberpunk2077/mods/10490?tab=description" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ultra Plus Engine Control Panel mod</a>, which optimizes path tracing so that the game can run more smoothly with little impact on visual quality, brings up to 40% performance improvement. It delivers framerates close to 60 FPS at 4K resolution and ultra settings with NVIDIA DLSS 3.7 in Balanced mode. Smoothness is further improved with NVIDIA DLSS 3 Frame Generation, delivering an even better experience.</p>
<p><iframe title="Cyberpunk 2077 Optimized Path Tracing Mod v5.0 - Up to 40% More FPS | RTX 4080 4K, 1440p DLSS 3.7 FG" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5oOqt0PCSJg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Path tracing support is only one of the many things that set Cyberpunk 2077 apart from the vast majority of open-world RPGs available on the market. Thanks to the 2.0 update, which overhauled some of the game's core systems and added more content, and the Phantom Liberty expansion, the game developed by CD Projekt Red has become a game worthy of the time of role-playing game fans. You can learn more about both by checking out Alessio's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/cyberpunk-2077-phantom-liberty-shiny-firmware-update/">review.</a></p>
<p><em>Cyberpunk 2077: Phantom Liberty builds upon what was an already great game to deliver more fantastic storytelling (with a spy thriller theme, this time around), exciting combat, and very high-quality side content. The perk tree overhaul is a major improvement to progression, and additions like vehicle combat and the overhauled police system are very welcome, albeit not game-changing. If you've been holding out on Cyberpunk 2077 until now, you'll find a huge game with over 120 hours of quality content and an incredibly immersive game world to literally lose yourself in. On top of that, it's by far the most beautiful and technically advanced game available if you have the hardware for it (PC and RTX 40 GPU).</em></p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring’s Latest Patch Fixes A Bunch Of Spirit Ashes]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-patch-spirit-ash-1851618008</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-ring%E2%80%99s-latest-patch-fixes-a-bunch-of-spirit-ashes.949224/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-patch-spirit-ash-1851618008<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="87e6e72fe36178b86b61a4646b25ddf3" data-recommend-id="image://87e6e72fe36178b86b61a4646b25ddf3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A knight with a blue cloak holds their sword out as an enemy approaches on horseback" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A knight with a blue cloak holds their sword out as an enemy approaches on horseback" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bandai Namco</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="87e6e72fe36178b86b61a4646b25ddf3" data-recommend-id="image://87e6e72fe36178b86b61a4646b25ddf3" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A knight with a blue cloak holds their sword out as an enemy approaches on horseback" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>FromSoftware, the developer behind 2022’s Game of the Year <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-fromsoftware-review-hidetaka-miyazaki-dark-s-1848694257&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-fromsoftware-review-hidetaka-miyazaki-dark-s-1848694257"><em>Elden Ring</em></a></span> and this year’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-expansion-review-1851545505&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-expansion-review-1851545505"><em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em></a></span> expansion, has released a new hotfix for the game. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/elden-ring/news/elden-ring-patch-notes-version-1132&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/elden-ring/news/elden-ring-patch-notes-version-1132" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Version 1.13.2</a></span> is now live for all platforms and, while less substantial than many of the game’s previous patches, it addresses a number of bugs that have been plaguing players.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195502" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="307" data-playlist="195502,195624,196773" data-current="195502"><div><p>The Most Sought After Elden Ring Sword Has A Storied History</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195502/195502_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20979.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Perhaps most significant are the fixes to how <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-lone-wolf-spirit-ashes-how-to-get-church-ell-1848703303&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/elden-ring-lone-wolf-spirit-ashes-how-to-get-church-ell-1848703303">Spirit Ashes</a></span> work. Prior to this patch it seems that using the DLC’s Revered Spirit Ash upgrade material resulted in a number of Spirit Ashes (summonable NPC allies) being spawned without the proper attack and defense stats. Especially in the challenging DLC, Spirit Ashes can be the key to success, so this fix is a welcome one. A full list of the affected spirits is listed in the patch notes. </p><p>For you co-op players, meanwhile, you won’t be able to summon your friends in certain areas of Scadu Atlus anymore, as the new hotfix removes a bug that allowed unintended multiplayer in that area. And if you’ve had any issues with the Red Bear fight and felt it was a little too hard, it turns out you may have been right. The hotfix notes that some of the NPC’s attacks were more powerful than intended, so the optional boss is getting a slight nerf.</p><figure id="" data-id="e6633ae406c1af9070b4fecef8e7603f" data-recommend-id="image://e6633ae406c1af9070b4fecef8e7603f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A samurai surrounded by ghost wolves stands in a dark field" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A samurai surrounded by ghost wolves stands in a dark field" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bandai Namco</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e6633ae406c1af9070b4fecef8e7603f" data-recommend-id="image://e6633ae406c1af9070b4fecef8e7603f" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A samurai surrounded by ghost wolves stands in a dark field" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Here is the full list of patch notes: </p><p><strong>Bug fixes</strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Fixed a bug which caused the Death status ailment from the Skill “Death Flare” to be applied to the Skill “Deadly Poison Spray”.</li><li>Fixed a bug that caused the power of some attacks used by the NPC “Red Bear” to be higher than intended.</li><li>Fixed a bug that prevented players from invading other players’ worlds in some areas of Scadu Altus under certain circumstances.</li><li>Fixed a bug that allowed Cooperative multiplayer in some areas of Scadu Altus with no area bosses present.</li><li>Fixes to adjustments regarding Revered Spirit Ash Blessing and some spirits introduced in App Ver. 1.13 App Ver. 1.13/Regulation Ver. 1.13.1</li><li>Fixed a bug where summoned spirits were not correctly receiving the attack power and damage negation increase effect from Revered Spirit Ash Blessing.</li><li>Fixed a bug in which the amount of status increase in the following spirits was different than expected.</li><li>Warhawk／Spider Scorpion／Bigmouth Imp／Gravebird／Stormhawk Deenh／Banished Knight Engval／Fire Knight, Hilde／Battlemage Hugues／Depraved Perfumer Carmaan／Blackflame Monk Amon／Demi-Human Swordsman Yosh／Cleanrot Knight Finlay／Nightmaiden &amp; Swordstress</li></ul><p>If you are still having trouble exploring the <em>Shadow of the Erdtree</em> DLC, then go check out <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/elden-ring&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/elden-ring">our guides</a></span> to make your adventure through the Land of Shadow easier.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix Faces Major Anime Crisis As Fans Freak Out Over Leaks]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/netflix-anime-leak-arcane-s2-dandadan-ranma-full-eps-1851617923</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflix-faces-major-anime-crisis-as-fans-freak-out-over-leaks.949221/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/netflix-anime-leak-arcane-s2-dandadan-ranma-full-eps-1851617923<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>There’s a ton of cool Netflix anime coming out this fall, and a bunch of it just leaked early. Screenshots, blurry clips, and in some cases entire episodes appeared online early, leading fans to worry about spoilers and call on the streaming platform to release shows early. Days later, Netflix has finally acknowledged the breach but doesn’t sound like it’s changing its anime fall release plans at all.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="191783" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Anime Dream Team Behind Chainsaw Man" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="154" data-playlist="191783,192615,194547" data-current="191783"><div><p>The Anime Dream Team Behind Chainsaw Man</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/191783/191783_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/191783/191783_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/191783/191783_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/191783/191783_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/17503.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>“One of our post-production partners has been compromised and footage from several of our titles has unfortunately leaked online,” a Netflix spokesperson <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/netflix-aggressively-taking-action-against-anime-leaks-crunchyroll-also-affected&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/netflix-aggressively-taking-action-against-anime-leaks-crunchyroll-also-affected" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told <em>IGN</em></a></span> only several days after the leaks began. “Our team is aggressively taking action to have it taken down.” </p><p>While removing leaked content is one thing, the fight against online spoilers in YouTube thumbnails or TikTok videos pelting fans from social media algorithms is another thing entirely. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/netflix-aggressively-taking-action-against-anime-leaks-crunchyroll-also-affected&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/netflix-aggressively-taking-action-against-anime-leaks-crunchyroll-also-affected" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">According to<em> IGN</em></a></span>, the list of impacted shows is quite long and includes <em>Terminator Zero</em>, <em>Heartstopper </em>season 3, <em>Ranma ½</em>, <em>Re: Zero</em> season 3, <em>Dandadan</em>, <em>Spellbound</em>, <em>Arcane</em> season 2, and <em>Plankton: The Movie</em>, a <em>SpongeBob SquarePants </em>spin-off. </p><p><em>Arcane</em>, the <em>League of Legends</em> adaptation about techno-infused class-warfare between the utopian city of Piltover and its fringes, was especially hard hit. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/arcane-final-season-first-of-many-league-of-legends-1851535061&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/arcane-final-season-first-of-many-league-of-legends-1851535061">Its next season will be its last</a></span> but it doesn’t begin airing until November.  In the meantime, five whole episodes of the steampunk action series have leaked online, with some fans taking the plunge and watching them despite the low quality and internal production watermarks. </p><p>Places like the <em>Arcane</em> subreddit have had to go on high alert banning posts and comments discussing spoilers for the upcoming season, but it hasn’t been enough. “This subreddit isn’t safe either,” one fan <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/arcane/comments/1envcxv/no_spoilers_this_subreddit_isnt_safe_either/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/arcane/comments/1envcxv/no_spoilers_this_subreddit_isnt_safe_either/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote</a></span> today. “Be careful with comments. I hope to god that wasn’t a spoiler and just some lame ass troll but be extremely careful. I suggest not to scroll until the end of comments and do not tap to see comments with negative votes.”</p><p>Fans of other shows like <em>Ranma ½ </em>and <em>Heartstopper </em>have also been frustrated by the leaks, calling on others to stop spreading links to clips or full episodes, both out of respect for one another but also the creators of the shows. “It took so many hours just to animate 1-3 seconds cut,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/firaflakes/status/1821406792506851715&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/firaflakes/status/1821406792506851715" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeted</a></span> one person. “If animators can stand hours to make one episode, I hope anime fans can also wait patiently for it to be release in the best of quality.”</p><p>But others are engaging with the leaks anyway. <em>Dandadan</em>, the upcoming anime adaptation of a Shōnen manga about high school kids who use occult powers to fight aliens and fall in love, has already undergone a full cycle of discourse over its polarizing intro that won’t actually air until October. “Hating the <em>Dandadan</em> opening before it’s even airing is insane,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/CozyMane/status/1821323666287632593&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/CozyMane/status/1821323666287632593" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote</a></span> one fan. “Stay off.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dungeons and Degenerate Gamblers Review]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dungeons-and-degenerate-gamblers-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dungeons-and-degenerate-gamblers-review.949218/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dungeons-and-degenerate-gamblers-review/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Blackjack is a game that has been played for hundreds of years, but it’s safe to say it’s never been played or crafted in the way that Purple Moss Collectors has done with Dungeons and Degenerate Gamblers.</p>



<p>Dungeons and Degenerate Gamblers is a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/?s=roguelike" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">roguelike</a> that takes the simple game of Blackjack, and turns it into a battle between players.</p>



<p>The premise is pretty simple, take a deck of cards and go on a run against a variety of opponents in the classic card game. This game, however, takes that premise and turns it upside down through power ups, special cards, and a battle mechanic that attacks your opponent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But just how well executed is the idea, and is Dungeons and Degenerate Gamblers worth your time?</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-dungeons-and-degenerate-gamblers-review">Dungeons and Degenerate Gamblers Review</h2>



<p>Things start pretty straightforward. You’ll start a run by choosing your suit, each having different base abilities. For example, choosing hearts will help heal you while clubs deal extra damage. There are a number of decks in this game, – 18 in total at launch – many to be unlocked that have different abilities to help you control the game and beat your opponents one by one.</p>



<p>Now, once you figure out your base deck, it’s time to begin your run. You start by playing a&nbsp; short starter match where you’ll then get to pick your advantage chip that could help you on your run.</p>



<p>After each match, you’ll be able to add a card to your deck. Three are usually visible while a fourth requires you to spend chips you’ve earned on your run to view.</p>



<h6>READ MORE: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-london-review-first-impressions/">Fallout London Review: Early Impressions of the Mod</a></h6>



<p>Throughout your run, you’ll also be able to make choices like staying a night in a hotel to heal or even paying a counterfeiter to secretly adjust your cards. All of these cost the aforementioned chips.</p>



<p>Each opponent plays a bit differently, some have decks built around stealing the card you’re currently playing. Others are built around forcing you to bust. But the more you play, the more you get the hang of what they’re going to do. There’s nothing that really changes things up from an opponent standpoint during a match. The biggest risk comes down to the fact that Blackjack is a game of chance. You could think you have the best deck in the world, but if your opponent just keeps hitting 21 after 21 after 21, it won’t matter.</p>



<figure><figcaption>Exploits can give you different advantages on your run.</figcaption></figure>



<p>At the end of your run, there are boss fights that allow you to get to the next difficulty. Like the regular opponents, the bosses don’t change as you play them over and over. It’s main about building a deck to beat their consistent strategy and getting lucky on the draw.</p>



<p>Of course, it’s not a deck builder without being able to add special cards that change things up entirely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dungeons and Degenerate Gamblers has a number of cards that vary in their abilities. You have cards like The Chariot that force an opponent to stand no matter what they have. Then there’s the Blank card that allows you to set its value anywhere between 1 and 11 when played. Some, like the Jackhammer of Clubs that can deal five damage when using your advantage chip to exploit, are one-time-use cards for your run.</p>



<p>There are cards that pay homage to games like The Witcher and even make fun of NFTs in a not-so-subtle way. It’s all just good fun seeing what each card does and figuring out its inspiration.</p>



<p>There are 307 cards to collect at launch and even after nearly 10 hours of playtime, I’ve yet to collect all of them on my runs. Right now, I stand at 197 of the 307 cards collected. There’s also card and deck stickers to collect for the completionists out there that should keep you coming back.</p>



<figure></figure>



<h2 id="h-dungeons-and-degenerate-gamblers-review-verdict">Dungeons and Degenerate Gamblers Review Verdict</h2>



<p>When looking at Dungeons and Degenerate Gamblers, it’s almost a guarantee that people will compare it to the 2024 breakout hit Balatro. While the comparison can be made, in a way, it’s not a completely fair one to make.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dungeons and Degenerate Gamblers is a more traditional deck building roguelike that features battles and power ups. It just so happens to be a casino card game at its base. It’s a fun time that has this “one more run” feeling with it. I would’ve liked to see more variety in the opponents you face because it can get quite repetitive and bland after a little while. That said, it seems to subside a bit when you come across a new card that changes up your strategy entirely. It really makes the deck building aspect of the game one of the more fun ones on the market.</p>



<p>Will that remain the case? I don’t know. I haven’t unlocked every single card yet. But no matter what, this is still a game that’s hard to not recommend for those who love gambling, roguelikes, and everything in between.</p>





<hr>



<p><em>A copy of Dungeons and Degenerate Gamblers was provided to Insider Gaming for the purposes of this review</em>. The game is available on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2400510/Dungeons__Degenerate_Gamblers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PC via Steam</a>. </p>



<p>For more on Insider Gaming reviews, check out our full <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/review-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">review policy</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astro Bot Controller Pre-Orders Live Now, But They’re Selling Fast]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-controller-pre-orders/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/astro-bot-controller-pre-orders-live-now-but-they%E2%80%99re-selling-fast.949215/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/astro-bot-controller-pre-orders/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>The Astro Bot controller for PS5 is available to pre-order at Amazon, Walmart, PlayStation, and Best Buy, but they’re almost sold out universally. This adorable, on-theme peripheral was revealed a couple of weeks ago. On September 6, it’ll be released alongside Astro Bot, the full-fledged, semi-open-world game featuring PlayStation’s cute robot mascot with a price tag of just $79.99.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-already-gone">Already Gone</h2>



<p>As one of the most innovative and limited edition PS5 controllers ever made, the Astro Bot controller is understandably selling out worldwide despite not being available for almost a month. On the trackpad of this controller, PlayStation has integrated a set of animated eyes that blink and emote as you play games.</p>



<p>It’s a charming white and blue model with stunning colours, laser-etched markings, and all the bells and whistles of a typical Dualsense controller. Even at just face value, it’s one of the nicest special edition controllers I’ve ever seen, and I’m disappointed they’re proving to be so hard to come by – but that’s <strong>limited edition </strong>for you. </p>



<p>If you want to get your hands on one, you might have to wait until it’s on the market and hopefully snag one at retail <strong>or </strong>pick one up from a scalper. It’s the way of the world.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/unity-6-is-on-track-for-a-fall-2024-release/">Unity 6 is on track to release in a month or two</a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>