<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 20:51:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[James Cameron Thinks AI Could Be Necessary To Keep Making Movies Like Dune]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/james-cameron-ai-terminator-dune-avatar-1851775691</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/james-cameron-thinks-ai-could-be-necessary-to-keep-making-movies-like-dune.1161183/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/james-cameron-ai-terminator-dune-avatar-1851775691<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In some fictional world probably created by AI, John Connor is rolling over in his grave. On the the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qOdjM14QW0s&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qOdjM14QW0s" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Boz to the Future</em></a></span> podcast, <em>Terminator </em>director and former staunch AI detractor James Cameron not only explains his new support of AI but says it could be an essential tool if filmmakers want to keep making visually daring films like the <em>Dune</em> movies in the future. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="194547" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Oshi No Ko Is An Early Anime Of The Year Contender" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="193" data-playlist="194547,197298,197284" data-current="194547"><div><p>Oshi No Ko Is An Early Anime Of The Year Contender</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194547/194547_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194547/194547_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194547/194547_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/194547/194547_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20009.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>On the podcast, the three-time Oscar winner explains he changed his stance on AI being part of the filmmaking process for the same reason that can make almost anyone change their opinion on anything: money. No, he wasn’t paid to change his opinion (as far as we know), but he harped on the financial burden incurred when crafting elaborate VFX-heavy films like his <em>Avatar</em> series and Denis Villeneuve’s <em>Dune </em>movies<em>. </em>According to him, if we want to keep making such films, production costs have to come down, and AI might be the way to do that.</p><p>“If we want to continue to see the kinds of movies that I’ve always loved and that I like to make and that I will go to see—<em>Dune</em>, <em>Dune: Part Two</em>, or one of my films or big effects-heavy, CG-heavy films—we’ve got to figure out how to cut the cost of that in half.” </p><p>He made sure to clarify that in his view, AI shouldn’t replace humans’ jobs, but accelerate them. AI should be “doubling their speed to completion on a given shot, so your cadence is faster and your throughput cycle is faster, and artists get to move on and do other cool things and then other cool things.” It appears he views AI in movies as akin to the computer replacing the typewriter, rather than sentient killing machines replacing the human species.<br></p><p>As practical as that may be, it still sounds like it came from bizzarro world when you remember that Cameron gave an ominous warning about AI <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://deadline.com/2023/07/terminator-director-james-cameron-on-rise-of-ai-1235441905/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://deadline.com/2023/07/terminator-director-james-cameron-on-rise-of-ai-1235441905/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">back in 2023</a></span> when he told CTV News, “I warned you guys in 1984, and you didn’t listen.” Finding AI so horrifying that he references his 1984 film <em>The</em>&nbsp;<em>Terminator</em>, whose plot is set in motion by an AI that seeks to wipe out humanity, when warning about its dangers doesn’t sound like a stance one can just pivot from in less than two years. <br></p><p>Still, he’s spent time since then studying the workings of AI, which may have contributed to the shift in his views. On the <em>Boz to the Future</em> podcast he discussed taking time to learn the nuances of the AI space in order to find a way to leverage its redeemable aspects to push filmmaking further. “The goal was to understand the space, to understand what’s on the minds of the developers,” he explained. “What are they targeting? What’s their development cycle? How much resources you have to throw at it to create a new model that does a purpose-built thing, and my goal was to try to integrate it into a VFX workflow.”<br></p><p>To his credit, he never said AI should be writing movies, having said in 2023, “ “I just don’t personally believe that a disembodied mind that’s just regurgitating what other embodied minds have said—about the life that they’ve had, about love, about lying, about fear, about mortality—and just put it all together into a word salad and then regurgitate it...I don’t believe that have something that’s going to move an audience.” So he’s not fully on the AI bandwagon. But he did join the Stability AI <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://deadline.com/2024/09/james-cameron-joins-stability-ai-board-of-directors-1236097835/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://deadline.com/2024/09/james-cameron-joins-stability-ai-board-of-directors-1236097835/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Board of Directors</a></span> last September to help bring AI capabilities to future filmmakers. With Cameron on board, it could only be a matter of time before Hollywood begins finding ways to incorporate AI without killing us all.<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slot machine roguelite horror game CloverPit announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/slot-machine-roguelite-horror-game-cloverpit-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/slot-machine-roguelite-horror-game-cloverpit-announced-for-pc.1161180/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/slot-machine-roguelite-horror-game-cloverpit-announced-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Future Friends Games [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/future-friends-games">Future Friends Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Panik Arcade [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/panik-arcade">Panik Arcade</a> have announced slot machine roguelite <a title="Genres > Horror [589 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror game</a> <em><a title="Games > CloverPit" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/cloverpit">CloverPit</a></em>, described as “the demonic lovechild of <em><a title="Games > Balatro [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/balatro">Balatro</a></em> and <em><a title="Games > Buckshot Roulette [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/buckshot-roulette">Buckshot Roulette</a></em>, for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,854 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3314790/CloverPit/" target="_blank">Steam</a>). It will launch in 2025. A demo is available now.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3314790/CloverPit/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>CloverPit</em> is the demonic lovechild of <em>Balatro</em> and <em>Buckshot Roulette</em>, a roguelite that traps players in a hell of their own creation. Locked in a rusty cell with a slot machine and an ATM, you must pay off your debt at the end of each round, or fall to ruin—literally!</p><p>Manipulate the slot machine to earn extra coins. Turn the odds in your favor with various prizes and charms that trigger big big combos, snowballing into a dazzling lucky run. Bend the rules, break the game, and pay off your captor long enough to earn a shot at freedom.</p><p><strong>Features:</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>A gripping <a title="Genres > Roguelite [235 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">rogue-lite</a> where every round could be your last!</li><li><a title="Platforms > Meta [138 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/meta">Meta</a>-progression, multiple endings and unlockable power-ups!</li><li>Push your score to new heights in Endless Mode!</li><li>A hellish escape room atmosphere!</li><li>150 + items and synergies to boost your luck!</li><li>A sinister tale of addiction and escape!</li></ul><p><strong>P.S. Is This Gambling?</strong></p><p>Hell no! <em>CloverPit</em> is a roguelite horror game, and not a slot machine simulator. Our slot machine is designed to be broken and ultimately overcome, and will never ask you for real money!</p></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Cloverpit Official Game Announcement | Triple-i Showcase 2025" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8Ir6ZnqerQ0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Five standout games revealed at today’s Triple-i Showcase]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/04/five-stand-out-games-revealed-at-todays-triple-i-showcase/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/five-standout-games-revealed-at-today%E2%80%99s-triple-i-showcase.1161177/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/04/five-stand-out-games-revealed-at-todays-triple-i-showcase/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                      
                      
          <p>"No ads, no hosts, no sponsors, just games." <a href="https://iii-initiative.com/">The Triple-i Initiative</a>'s pitch for its now-annual showcase of games, crafted by studios working somewhere between "Solo dev or very small team" and "Investor-minded conglomerate with international offices," promises a lot of peeks at games without a lot of chatter, and once again it delivered.</p>
<p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/04/slay-the-spire-2-vampire-survivors-meets-contra-and-other-triple-i-games/">Last year's showcase</a> debuted titles like <em>Norland</em>, <em>Slay the Spire 2</em>, and <em>The Rogue Prince of Persia</em>, along with updates from&nbsp;<em>Darkest Dungeon 2</em>,&nbsp;<em>Palworld</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Vampire Survivors</em>. This year featured looks at titles from the&nbsp;Deep Rock universe, the cloning-yourself-to-survive curiosity&nbsp;<a href="https://altersthegame.com/"><em>The Alters</em></a>, an <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3407390/ENDLESS_Legend_2/"><em>Endless Legend 2</em></a> that continues tweaking the 4X formula, and more.</p>
<p>Below are five selected highlights for the Ars crowd, along with some notable other announcements. The full list is not yet up on <a href="https://iii-initiative.com/">the Triple-i site</a>, but you can see what jumped out from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qMyziPJY_aw">the full showcase</a>.</p>
<h3><em>Deep Rock Galactic: Rogue Core</em></h3>
<figure><p><iframe allow="fullscreen" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eq303OLkBkY?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent"></iframe></p><div>
    
    <p><em>Deep Rock Galactic: Rogue Core</em> gameplay reveal.

          </p>
  </div>
</figure>
<p>Ghost Ship Games and its publishing arm advanced two of its <em><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2021/08/how-deep-rock-galactics-dwarf-miners-have-helped-me-survive-the-pandemic/">Deep Rock Galactic</a> (DRG) </em>spinoffs at the showcase, one of them with real gameplay. <em>DRG: Rogue Core</em>, the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2023/10/deep-rock-galactic-is-getting-a-roguelite-spin-off-but-core-game-remains/">run-based, shoot-ier game</a> set in the same dwarven universe as&nbsp;<em>DRG,&nbsp;</em>showed off <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-EfBOHWeaSo&amp;feature=youtu.be">a new trailer with actual play</a> and announced a closed alpha test, accessible on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2605790/Deep_Rock_Galactic_Rogue_Core/">the game's Steam page</a>.&nbsp;<em>DRG: Survivor</em>, a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/02/deep-rock-galactic-survivor-is-a-fine-entry-point-into-the-auto-shooting-depths/">fine entry</a> into the burgeoning "Survivor-like" genre (it <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/so-so-many-vampire-survivors-clones-came-out-this-year/">still needs a name</a>), now has a 1.0 date set for September 17. The <a href="https://youtu.be/EDnQNFn6vIk">trailer</a> shows off some of the new content updates, biomes, systems, and quirky little "overclocks" and artifacts that make the number of run variations nearly incalculable.</p>
<h3><em>Endless Legend 2</em></h3>
<figure><p><iframe allow="fullscreen" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EzXjjWHwSRM?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent"></iframe></p><div>
    
    <p><em>Endless Legend 2</em> early access announcement trailer.

          </p>
  </div>
</figure>
<p>The sequel to the game that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2016/05/stellaris-and-strategy-gamings-bad-luck-problem/">expertly incorporated randomness into a 4X strategy framework</a> is getting a sequel, and it hits early access this summer. The game will add more factions as the summer approaches, and the sequel promises more disasters and strategy options to come. You can sign up for early access through Amplitude Studios' <a href="https://ampli.click/insidersprogramsurvey">Insider Program</a>.</p>
<h3><em>Heroes of Might &amp; Magic: Olden Era</em></h3>
<figure><p><iframe allow="fullscreen" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FezxEnr8QI8?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent"></iframe></p><div>
    
    <p><em>Heroes of Might &amp; Magic: Olden Era </em>trailer.

          </p>
  </div>
</figure>
<p>It's been a minute since a turn-based game set in the&nbsp;Might &amp; Magic world of Enroth came around—about 10 years, actually, not counting <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/05/songs-of-conquest-is-the-heroes-of-might-magic-rebirth-we-all-deserve/">spiritual successors</a>.&nbsp;<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3105440/Heroes_of_Might_and_Magic_Olden_Era/"><em>Olden Era</em></a> takes players to the continent of Jadame, never before explored in the game universe. Woodland spirits fight medieval armies, zombies spawn from the battlefield, demons get into the mix—there's a lot going on. You can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3105440/Heroes_of_Might_and_Magic_Olden_Era/">sign up for a playtest at the game's Steam page</a>, and it's due out in early access in Q2 2025.</p>

          
                      
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last of Us is being released again, but this time as a Complete edition]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-is-being-released-again-but-this-time-as-a-complete-edition</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-is-being-released-again-but-this-time-as-a-complete-edition.1161171/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-is-being-released-again-but-this-time-as-a-complete-edition<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>There's a physical version coming too.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/last-of-us-complete-artwork.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sony</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
If you thought Nintendo was the master of re-releases, then <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/naughty-dog">Naughty Dog</a> might just be gunning for its title. The studio has announced yet another release for The Last of Us - but this time it's returning in the form of a two-game Complete edition.
</p>
<p>
Hints that Sony and Naughty Dog might be preparing another The Last of Us release first surfaced back in March, when it was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-reportedly-getting-mysterious-new-physical-ps5-special-edition">reported a mysterious new PlayStation 5 special edition was on the way</a>. Little was known about it at the time, beyond the fact it was supposedly getting a physical edition, but all has now been revealed.
</p>
<p>
The Last of Us Complete, as its name suggests, bundles together the PS5 versions of The Last of Us Part 1 and The Last of Us Part 2 Remastered, which initially released in 2022 and 2024 respectively. It'll be available in two forms; a digital edition, which is live on the PlayStation Store right now, and a special physical Collector's Edition, which arrives on 10th July.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Last of Us Complete - Launch Trailer | PS5 Games" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8b8pnfHd2cs?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Last of Us Complete - Launch Trailer | PS5 Games</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8b8pnfHd2cs?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8b8pnfHd2cs?autoplay=1" title="The Last of Us Complete - Launch Trailer | PS5 Games">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>The Last of Us Complete launch trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8b8pnfHd2cs" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
The Last of Us Complete's digital release features exactly the same content as you'd get if you brought both games separately, but it does provide a bit of saving. It's <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-gb/product/EP9000-PPSA29488_00-0000000000000000">priced at £94.99 on the PlayStation Store</a>, making a purchase £19.99 cheaper than buying Part 1 and Part 2 individually.
</p>
<p>
As for the Collector's Edition, it's exclusive to PlayStation's online store. It comes in a steelbook case with separate discs for Part 1 and Part 2, and also includes the Left Behind prequel chapter, The Last of Us: American Dreams Comics #1-4 with new cover art, a set of four lithographic art prints, and a Thank You letter from Naughty Dog boss Neil Druckmann - which I'm assuming isn't going to be handwritten. It costs £109.99/$109.99 USD, and <a href="https://direct.playstation.com/en-gb/buy-games/the-last-of-us-complete-collectors-edition-ps5">pre-orders are open now</a>.
</p>
<p>
But will Naughty Dog's latest The Last of Us release <em>actually</em> end up being the "complete" edition. Druckmann has sent mixed messages about the likelihood of a third series instalment over the last few years, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-part-3-could-be-one-more-chapter-to-this-story-says-co-creator-druckmann">telling fans "there's probably one more chapter to this story" back in 2024</a>, before <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/naughty-dog-boss-says-dont-bet-on-there-being-a-the-last-of-us-part-3">reversing course this March</a> and warning, "Don't bet on there being more."
</p>
<p>
There is, though, <em>sort of</em> new The Last of Us on the way, courtesy of HBO's live-action TV adaptation. Season 2 <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-long-awaited-season-2-finally-gets-a-start-date">begins airing</a> this Sunday, 13th April (14th April in the UK), and looks like it'll be substantially expanding on the events of the second game. We already know some new characters are being introduced for Season 2 - including <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/heres-who-catherine-ohara-will-play-in-the-last-of-us-marking-a-significant-change-from-the-games">Catherine O'Hara's Gale</a> - and given showrunner Craig Mazin is predicting the series will run to four season, there's plenty of space to chart routes previously unseen. Especially as <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-last-of-us-tv-show-renewed-for-season-three-and-the-second-hasnt-even-aired-yet">Season 3 is already confirmed</a>.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elder Scrolls Online Subclassing Q&A – ‘Power Level Will Go Up Some, But We’re Fine Where It Is’]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/elder-scrolls-online-subclassing-qa-power-level-will-go-up-some-but-were-fine-where-it-is/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elder-scrolls-online-subclassing-q-a-%E2%80%93-%E2%80%98power-level-will-go-up-some-but-we%E2%80%99re-fine-where-it-is%E2%80%99.1161147/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/elder-scrolls-online-subclassing-qa-power-level-will-go-up-some-but-were-fine-where-it-is/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>During the ESO Direct, ZeniMax Online Studios unveiled what's coming this year to the popular MMORPG Elder Scrolls Online. You can read about all of it <a href="https://wccftech.com/elder-scrolls-online-to-add-subclassing-and-seasons-of-the-worm-cult-this-year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>, from the new subclassing feature to the Season of the Worm Cult (which continues the original game's storyline) and more.</p>
<p>Wccftech was among select outlets that accessed the presentation beforehand. Afterward, key developers from ZeniMax Online Studios (Studio Head Matt Firor, Game Director Rich Lambert, and Executive Producer Susan Kath) answered several questions from the assembled press. You can find the full transcript below.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'I personally love the interesting mix of architecture that we have. It's Argonian and High Elf kind of put together. I love the wall that we've got in there; it's splitting the zone in two. And then, this isn't specific to Solstice, but I freaking love subclassing. It opens up so many opportunities for builds.' - Rich Lambert</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Why did you decide to change from an annual Chapter model to the content pass?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor:</strong> With the chapter mode, we did a lot of great content over the years, but most of it hit in June. It was a big moment and it didn't leave a lot of time for the team to make content over the rest of the year. What it really did is it locked us into this cadence that made it so we couldn't experiment as much as we wanted. This will free us up so that we can put time into doing<br>
things like the Cyrodiil Champions test, for example. Take some time out of the content pipeline and move it into how we can make the game better, how we can make systems that are already in the game better, and what we can do to shake things up.</p>
<p><strong>Will subclassing work with my current character build?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert:</strong> Yes. That's the most important part of subclassing: you don't have to reroll a new character in order to do it. You can just take the class that you already have or a character that you've already spent all this time and effort with and roll out new abilities and new skill lines to it.</p>
<p><strong>How will this seasonal pass affect ESO Plus?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Susan Kath:</strong> Not significantly, because you're still getting access to the things that traditionally you got access to as part of ESO Plus. It is just a way to group the content over the entire year kind of into one package that you can pre-purchase, so you have access to it all the moment that we release it.</p>
<p><strong>What is your favorite thing about the new Solstice zone?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>There's so much. I personally love the interesting mix of architecture that we have. It's Argonian and High Elf kind of put together. I love the wall that we've got in there; it's splitting the zone in two. And then, this isn't specific to Solstice, but I freaking love subclassing. It opens up so many opportunities for builds.</p>
<p><strong>Is subclassing a part of the base game update?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>It is, yes.</p>
<p><strong>Will subclass abilities be weaker versions of the original ones or the same?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>They are the same. The only penalty that you have is that those abilities cost twice as many skill points to use. That was the trade-off. In order to give you more flexibility, you have to be even more invested in the character.</p>
<p><strong>How will you balance the FOMO (flavor of the month) with these seasons?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>That's a really good question. I think what we have shown in the past is with new things that we do, there's always a little bit of that FOMO, but we will sometimes bring things back. We will also make sure that super exclusive things are generally easy to get so that you don't feel like you have to grind every single day of the season in order to get it. Those are the pillars that we're leaning on for the seasonal stuff.&nbsp; Some of it is FOMO, though. It's a season, it's active; go and play and do the things and experience it while it's there.</p>
<p><strong>Will subscribers of ESO Plus have access to the content pass with their active subscription?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Susan Kath: </strong>Well, there's the content pass, and then there's ESO Plus. No, it is not included in ESO Plus.</p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor: </strong>Just like the Chapters before weren't included in ESO Plus. There will be content throughout the year that is included in ESO Plus, but what is in the content pass for Seasons of the Worm Cult is not included in ESO Plus, just like last year's Chapter was not included in ESO Plus.</p>
<p><strong>How do you plan on balancing subclassing? For example, taking the Arcanist and using a Templar beam, will that be way overpowered?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>That was the biggest concern when we first started pitching this. In particular, the dungeon team were like, don't break our Trials. We've done a lot of testing on that and yes, power level will go up some, but we're fine with where it is. We haven't done anything to dramatically nerf things or reduce a lot of power from the abilities. We want this to be fun and we want players to experiment and make cool things.</p>
<p><strong>How are we going to access the subclassing feature?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>There's a little bit of friction in terms of how you unlock it. If you are someone like me or Matt who's played Elder Scrolls Online forever and have multiple level 50 characters, then all those skill lines are unlocked and the only thing you have to worry about is leveling the actual abilities on your character. If you are a player that only has one character, then you can go through a number of quests and train those skill lines in order to be able to use them. We thought about a bunch of different ways to make this as widely available as possible.</p>
<p><strong>Can you further explain the new content pass?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Susan Kath: </strong>By purchasing the content pass this year, you will have access to the <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-elder-scrolls-online-gets-fallen-banners-dungeon-dlc-overhauled-starting-zones/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fallen Banners dungeons</a>. You have Seasons of the Worm Cult part one and part two and you have the Soul Wall event. The Soul Wall event, however, is unique in that everyone will be able to participate, but the experience if you have purchased the content pass is going to be different.</p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>Yeah, there's more stuff. I think the best way to explain it is with the Chapter model. The content pass encapsulates everything for the entire year. If you have ESO Plus, you still get the dungeons, the way it's always been.</p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor: </strong>If people are a little confused about it, this year is a transition between last year's Chapter model and next year. This year, we already had content in the pipeline, and so we're doing this bridge year where we have some items that feel a little bit like the Chapter did, but we're calling it a content pass just so we can put some extra things in it and get people ready for what's coming next.</p>
<p><strong>How much will the content pass cost and what will it include?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Susan Kath: </strong>I cannot tell you that right now as I don't remember it.</p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor: </strong>The basic idea is that if you want to go to the zone of Solstice, you have to buy the content pass. Then there are some things around the edges, but that's the big thing.</p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>You get to participate in the Soul Wall event even if you don't have Solstice. There's some things you can't do in there, but you can help the server work towards unlocking things.</p>
<p><strong>Susan Kath: </strong>Matt spoke to it very succinctly. It is a transition year for us. It is spreading things out a bit. You could think of it very much akin to what you have seen in the past, but it's spread out, it's changed up a little bit and it'll change more as we go into the next year. But the base game of Elder Scrolls Online is still getting updates throughout the year. That doesn't change.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'The entire server is working towards the goals of the event, and there's a number of stages. I'm not going to go too deep into things, but there's a number of stages that you work towards. You help set the camps, you help fend off attacks on those camps, and then the last stage is actually going into the wall area and bringing it down for the entire city. This is something we've never done before and I'm super excited for this.' - Rich Lambert</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Will the Writhing Wall event be a real-time experience shared among all players, similar to how Fortnite events are usually conducted?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>Sort of. The entire server is working towards the goals of the event, and there's a number of stages. I'm not going to go too deep into things, but there's a number of stages that you work towards. You help set the camps, you help fend off attacks on those camps, and then the last stage is actually going into the wall area and bringing it down for the entire city. This is something we've never done before and I'm super excited for this.</p>
<p><strong>How does subclassing maintain class exclusivity?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>I knew that question was going to come up. One of the core tenets of subclassing is that you can't change your original Elder Scrolls Online class. You have to have at least one skill line from your original class in there. If I'm a Templar, I can drop two of the skill lines, but I have to keep one of them. That allows us to retain some of that class identity. It still makes your class choice important, but you have this flexibility to really turn it into a hybrid of whatever you want.</p>
<p><strong>How will you reintroduce the existing systems for Elder Scrolls Online players who come back after a while?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Susan Kath: </strong>The returning player stuff, the welcome-back stuff, is very near and dear to my heart because when joining the team here at ZOS, that is exactly what I was. I have played the game numerous times since launch. Coming in as a returning player, these two got earfuls from me in my first few months back where I was pinging them and going "Oh my God, I don't know how to do this and this is really frustrating to me." I'm really excited about this system. As a longtime MMO player, not just of Elder Scrolls Online, I've fallen in love with the games that I've played over the years and they all feel like home to me in some way or another. Coming back to a game, it's like slipping into a book that I'm familiar with. It is comforting and I would like to make it as easy as possible for people to come in. The answer to the actual question is that is part of what the whole welcome back experience is all about.</p>
<p>We've found numerous things, like Golden Pursuits, that have been a great way to bring people to content that they may not have experienced before that's happened since they've left and returned. That is just one of the ways that plays into that system. I think it's going to be really cool, and it's all based on the player as well.</p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor: </strong>That's actually a good point. All you have just seen was about all the new content that's coming up and some new systems, but we're still doing all the other stuff that we talked about over the course of the last 6 months, which is making the new user experience better, making the returning user experience better, etc. We redid the graphical look and feel of the starting islands in the last update, and we're continuing to do main game tutorial work.</p>
<p><strong>Are there any planned social features or improvements for guilds, such as exclusive cooperative content, internal events, or more robust management tools?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>How about I just say we have some things planned for guilds that we're not quite ready to talk about yet? But we understand this is a big thing for players.</p>
<p><strong>What was the primary objective of the UI rework?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor: </strong>To make the game feel more modern. In 2014, on PC, it was a different world than it is now. We made our console UI in 2015 to be a little more forward-looking and less old-school MMO, so the work we're doing now is making the PC version and bringing that up to the same level. It's about making it cleaner, more intuitive, and just making it look and feel better.</p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>And also make it easier to maintain. It's a combination of things.</p>
<p><strong>The starter zones just got a facelift, like you mentioned. Are there any plans to enhance other visual aspects of Elder Scrolls Online, such as character hair?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor: </strong>We have a list of things that we're enhancing. Everything that you're thinking about is on a list somewhere, but obviously, we can't do everything all at once. We have a cadence that we're trying to hit to make other zones in the game look better. We've already talked publicly about making combat look and feel more modern and better, which includes everything you're just talking about, except for possibly hair.</p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>We actually just introduced hair, too!</p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor: </strong>All of these things are on a list, and by going to a cadence that isn't locked into the calendar year, we get to do these things. That's the big message from us.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'We have a list of things that we're enhancing. Everything that you're thinking about is on a list somewhere, but obviously, we can't do everything all at once. We have a cadence that we're trying to hit to make other zones in the game look better. We've already talked publicly about making combat look and feel more modern and better, which includes everything you're just talking about.' - Matt Firor</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>What more can you tell us about the recent Cyrodiil Champions experiment and possible new PVP content?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>It was a phenomenal test for us, orders of magnitude better than I think a lot of us thought was going to happen. It really showed that that original vision that we wanted for this massive scale PVP, we can do it. Now, what we are doing is digging through the mountains of data, because there were some spikes, it wasn't all perfect. We are digging through the mountains of data and seeing where those problems were and what we can do to solve them, and then we're going to continue to roll out more tests.</p>
<p>The next one is probably going to happen sometime after Update 46. But the goal is to make incremental progress on this and continue to reintroduce more things, because what we did in the Cyrodiil Champions test was as bare bones as we could make it so we could really prove whether it was the ability system.</p>
<p><strong>Going to the Solstice zone, how does the size of Solstice compare to regions added in previous Chapters? Does the change in cadence mean there may be years with no region added at all?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>Maybe. It's comparable in size to your previous chapters; it's just split in half.</p>
<p><strong>What do you think really sets this season's new environments apart from what we've already seen?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>It's partly the mix. It's Argonian and High Elf, which just sounds weird but makes sense. It's also this tropical feel. Solstice is a tropical island mixed with some Cold Harbour and other fun stuff. It's just a different vibe and feel.</p>
<p><strong> Any further details about the new Trial?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>I always say this and people think I'm full of it, but the team always finds new ways to impress and push the boundaries of our technology. They've done some things. In particular, there is a fight where you have multiple bosses and you're moving around between platforms and just doing crazy cool things. Again, they one-upped themselves with this Trial, and I can't wait for people to jump in there and start playing with it.</p>
<figure><figcaption>'I always say this and people think I'm full of it, but the team always finds new ways to impress and push the boundaries of our technology. They've done some things. In particular, there is a fight where you have multiple bosses and you're moving around between platforms and just doing crazy cool things. Again, they one-upped themselves with this Trial, and I can't wait for people to jump in there and start playing with it.' - Rich Lambert</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Are there plans to introduce new dungeons for four players?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>Quarter one and quarter three are the dungeon updates. It's four dungeons in total. We've already launched two this year with Fallen Banners, and the other pack is in the third quarter. I can't remember the name of what we called it, but there's two more dungeons on the way.</p>
<p><strong>Will subclassing be usable everywhere, such as Trials? How do you expect it to impact the build diversity?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>Yes, it's everywhere. It's part of the base Elder Scrolls Online game. The hope is that this opens the door for even more cool builds and definitely spreads out some of the current meta. I mean, it's going to break the current meta. It'll be really interesting to see what players come up with. The meta is something that we talk about a lot. It's really pushed by a certain number of players that this is the only way to do a thing, and that's not entirely true, but I think this is going to open up a lot more flexibility.</p>
<p><strong>Will subclassing allow you to select skill lines or pick skill by skill?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>It is skill line wise, and then you can pick the skills within that skill line. You can't cherry-pick the best skills from each line.</p>
<p><strong>Will subclassing worsen the issue of hybrid changes and Scribing, undermining the distinct identities of the classes?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>There's going to be some of that naturally, just because you're going to be able to have multiple skill lines that aren't from your class. But that also very much fits the mold of what our game is, which is play whatever you want.</p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor: </strong>It is what Elder Scrolls is all about: player freedom. We have to put some box around it; we're just making the box a little bigger with this.</p>
<p><strong>How will subclassing avoid the problem where everyone equips certain powerful abilities, such as Radiant Oppression? Players will be concerned about this.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>We're concerned about it as well. That goes back to the meta and shaping up the meta. In our internal and external tests, we have found that there's a huge amount of diversity in terms of builds and skills and whatnot. What some players think works and is the only way to do it isn't necessarily the right way.</p>
<p><strong>You mentioned plans for new Elder Scrolls Online players who want to start their journey in a game that has been there for more than 10 years. Can you please explain this a bit more?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Susan Kath: </strong>We've already begun rolling out the first of the new player improvements since November. We did some more in this most recent update, refreshing the new player zones and really looking closely at the&nbsp;new player experience. We've put a lot of research into that, seeing where people were struggling to get into the game. Our plan is to continue to support that.</p>
<p>Again, as Matt said, this decision to move away from the Chapter model is so that we can return to things like this. We can make some changes and see if this makes the new player experience even better. We'll watch it for a while, come back, and make some more changes. That's not something&nbsp;that we've had the luxury of being able to do for a while.</p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor: </strong>It's a ten-year-old game but still, millions of people play Elder Scrolls Online for the first time every year. We have so many new players that come in all the time. During the pandemic, we had so many people playing the game that we had to focus on server stability and making sure that the game was going to hold together. Now that we're getting into the back end of the swing of things, it's 'let's make this game as good as possible for new players and returning players.'</p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>The ultimate goal with the new player stuff is to make sure that players understand all the things that are in the game because there's a ton of stuff, and we don't do a particularly good job of surfacing all of those things.</p>
<p><strong>What's the future for companions and crafting? Will we see new recipes and companions each season or similar?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>I don't know about each season, but companions are pretty popular with our player base and so we will find ways to continue to build on that system.</p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor: </strong>If you think about companions, we've added new systems to the game since launch, at least one a year. Companions, the card game, the housing. These are all things that we can pull from when we're putting a new season together to make a really compelling season. That gives us a lot of flexibility.</p>
<p><strong>Why is now the right time to continue the base game story?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Matt Firor: </strong>I was waiting for that question. Most of the questions here so far have been about systems, which is great because a lot of people play these games for character development, but Elder Scrolls Online is centered around storytelling and our storytelling is probably the best in the industry. We&nbsp;love what we do here and the main story of the game when it launched had unbelievable voice talent and really cool characters. We brought many of these characters back in different Chapters and in different situations, but we haven't actually told the next version of the story of what happened after the Planemeld didn't happen.</p>
<p>This is cool for us because we get to bring these characters back in the same way that they were in 2014 when the game launched. You're going to see a lot of familiar names and voice talent. It's just super fun and nostalgic for us to be able to go back and extend the story going forward. Just seeing Raz and Gabrielle, these people were part of our lives early on, because we tested this game internally for many, many years and we know these characters very well.</p>
<p><strong>Could you provide more information about the returning characters, especially about a specific necromancer?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>No, that's a story spoiler! But hey, the Worm Cult's coming back. That should be a big enough thing.</p>
<p><strong>Will we have the opportunity to test everything that was mentioned on the Elder Scrolls Online PTS server? If so, is there any information on when that might be?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Rich Lambert: </strong>Next Monday.</p>
<p><strong>Thank you for your time.</strong></p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vampire Survivors will let you share saves across platforms — but not on PlayStation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/646760/vampire-survivors-cross-saves-playstation-emerald-diorama</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/vampire-survivors-will-let-you-share-saves-across-platforms-%E2%80%94-but-not-on-playstation.1161144/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/646760/vampire-survivors-cross-saves-playstation-emerald-diorama<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/jay-peters">Jay Peters</a> <span>is a news editor covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Vampire Survivors</em> is finally launching cross-saves today, but they won’t be available on PlayStation to start and have a “very slim” chance of coming to the platform because of a “legal issue.” </p><p>“Last month, we told everyone that cross-save would be available on PlayStation 4 / 5, PC, Xbox, Android and iOS alongside our next free <em>VS</em> update in April,” according to <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fnews%2Fapp%2F1794680%2Fview%2F529842339955345357" rel="sponsored">a Steam post from Poncle</a>, the game’s developer. “But at last [sic] minute, we’ve run into a legal issue on PlayStation we weren’t aware of that requires us to share info on our partners that we’re unable to. The chances of Cross-Save coming to PlayStation consoles are now very slim, but not impossible, so we’re going to keep working alongside PlayStation to resolve these problems.”</p><p>Poncle and PlayStation didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment.</p><p>Cross-saves are now available on Android, iOS, PC, and Xbox, Poncle says. <em>Vampire Survivors</em> on Nintendo Switch will also get cross-saves, but “at a later date.” Poncle wants to bring them to the Apple Arcade version of the game, but only “if we can do so without breaching any privacy commitments.” </p><p>If you want to turn on cross-saves, <a href="https://poncle.games/accounts">check out Poncle’s guide</a>. Note that cross-saves aren’t automatically synced, meaning you’ll have to manually save and load your save data across platforms as needed.</p><p>Alongside the cross-saves news, Poncle also released a free <em>Vampire Survivors</em> DLC expansion based on the Square Enix’s <em>SaGa</em> franchise titled <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F3451100%2FVampire_Survivors_Emerald_Diorama%2F" rel="sponsored"><em>Emerald Diorama</em></a> and a chicken-themed update to the main game that Poncle calls “The Coop.”</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Savagely Styled First Berserker Armor Set Lets You Deal Tougher Blows]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/first-berserker-khazan-crimson-fiend-armor-mortal-blow-1851775695</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-savagely-styled-first-berserker-armor-set-lets-you-deal-tougher-blows.1161138/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/first-berserker-khazan-crimson-fiend-armor-mortal-blow-1851775695<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="df5a5992003fd99501e26ad3430791b1" data-recommend-id="image://df5a5992003fd99501e26ad3430791b1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The protagonist of the First Berserker stands tall while wearing the Crimson Fiend's armor." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The protagonist of the First Berserker stands tall while wearing the Crimson Fiend's armor." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nexon / Billy Givens / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="df5a5992003fd99501e26ad3430791b1" data-recommend-id="image://df5a5992003fd99501e26ad3430791b1" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The protagonist of the First Berserker stands tall while wearing the Crimson Fiend's armor." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>A lot of the armor in<em> The First Berserker: Khazan</em> looks pretty damn cool, but the Crimson Fiend Set has one of the most barbaric styles. And if you’re a Greatsword user who has spec’d into Mortal Blow, this is a set you do not want to overlook. Here’s what to know about the Crimson Fiend Set and where to find the Crimson Fiend’s Scroll so the blacksmith can craft it for you.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h241255"><a id=""></a>Crimson Fiend Set stats</h2><p><strong>The Crimson Fiend Set offers a generous 20-percent boost to the damage dealt by Mortal Blow</strong>. You also get bonuses for charge attacks, which should be a fairly common part of the combos you unleash with your big ‘ol sword. The extra stamina recovery when using Mortal Blow or charged attacks is quite nice, too.</p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li><strong>2 pieces</strong> - Enraged: 15% DMG Increase</li><li><strong>3 pieces</strong> - Charged Attack: 10% DMG Increase</li><li><strong>4 pieces</strong> - Mortal Blow and Charged Attack: 100 Stamina Recovery</li><li><strong>5 pieces</strong> - Enraged: 30% Received DMG Decrease</li><li><strong>6 pieces</strong> - Mortal Blow: 20% DMG Increase</li></ul><h2 id="h241256"><a id=""></a>Where to find the Crimson Fiend’s Scroll</h2><p>The Crimson Fiend’s Scroll is found in the “Hermit Mountains” main mission, which can be started at the Heart of Pell Los portal.</p><p>From the Hermit’s Cave Blade Nexus, which is encountered fairly early on in the mission, head forward up the stairs, then take the next set of stairs on your right to enter an area with trees that can infect you with Plague. You’ll want to proceed through here carefully to avoid having your health chunked off by this annoying status effect.</p><figure id="" data-id="d9138d08d3d0abed4167f6dc8ed7c14b" data-recommend-id="image://d9138d08d3d0abed4167f6dc8ed7c14b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The protagonist stands in a dark valley while wielding a massive spear." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The protagonist stands in a dark valley while wielding a massive spear." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nexon / Billy Givens / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d9138d08d3d0abed4167f6dc8ed7c14b" data-recommend-id="image://d9138d08d3d0abed4167f6dc8ed7c14b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The protagonist stands in a dark valley while wielding a massive spear." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Move through the linear path until you enter an open section with a large skeleton archer and various other enemies. Dispatch them, then check the leftmost corner of the area to find the Crimson Fiend’s Scroll on the ground. Remember to take it back to the blacksmith and have him craft you a set of this bloody armor.</p><hr><p><br><em>The First Berserker: Khazan</em> is available now on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and Windows PCs.  </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Devs React to Speedruns Returns This Weekend]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/devs-react-to-speedruns-returns-this-weekend</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/devs-react-to-speedruns-returns-this-weekend.1161135/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/devs-react-to-speedruns-returns-this-weekend<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">I feel the need, the need for speed(runs)</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Buckle up because one of IGN’s biggest original shows returns this Saturday!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re not familiar with <em>Devs React to Speedruns</em>, let me fill you in! <em>Devs React to Speedruns</em> is an IGN show that celebrates speedruns in the best way we know how—by showcasing the incredible playthroughs completed by the speedrun community and presenting them to the developers of those games. There’s nothing quite like watching developers who have spent years working on a game witness it being completed in mere minutes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the upcoming season of <em>Devs React to Speedruns</em>, we’ve partnered with some of the biggest games and developers in the world to bring you a series of exciting episodes. It all kicks off this Saturday, April 12, at 8:30 AM PT with Larian Studios, where we’ll show them a sub-20-minute speedrun of <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>. Will it sadden them to learn that their game can be finished in just 20 minutes? You’ll have to watch to find out!</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/10/bg3-yt-1744305209369.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Developers React to Baldur's Gate 3 will air on April 12, 2025 at 8:30am PT on IGN and YouTube!</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Following <em>Baldur’s Gate 3</em>, we’ll be releasing a brand-new episode every Saturday for the next couple of months—all at 8:30 AM PT. These new episodes will feature some of the most popular games from world-renowned studios, including Team ASOBI, MachineGames, Bloober Team, Shared Memory, Surgent Studios, and Megagon Industries.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">If you’re not already familiar with <em>Devs React to Speedruns</em>, I highly encourage you to check out our extensive 100-episode library! Some highlights include <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/doom-eternal-developers-react-to-27-minute-speedrun"><u><em>Doom Eternal</em></u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/half-life-2-developers-react-to-50-minute-speedrun"><u><em>Half-Life 2</em></u></a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/video-embed?url=/videos/2019/11/23/the-outer-worlds-developers-react-to-12-minute-speedrun"><u><em>The Outer Worlds</em></u></a> (the very first episode of Devs React), and much, much more!<br>
</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anxiety horror thriller No, I’m not a Human launches this fall for PC, later for PS5 and Xbox Series]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/anxiety-horror-thriller-no-im-not-a-human-launches-this-fall-for-pc-later-for-ps5-and-xbox-series</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anxiety-horror-thriller-no-i%E2%80%99m-not-a-human-launches-this-fall-for-pc-later-for-ps5-and-xbox-series.1161132/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/anxiety-horror-thriller-no-im-not-a-human-launches-this-fall-for-pc-later-for-ps5-and-xbox-series<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Updated demo coming this summer.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > No, I'm not a Human [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/no-im-not-a-human">No, I’m not a Human</a></em>, an anxiety <a title="Genres > Horror [589 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror</a> thriller about paranoia in the End of Times, will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,854 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3180070/No_Im_not_a_Human/" target="_blank">Steam</a> this fall, followed later by <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,241 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,023 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, publisher <a title="Companies > Critical Reflex [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/critical-reflex">Critical Reflex</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Trioskaz" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/trioskaz">Trioskaz</a> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/3180070/view/543354486002811409" target="_blank">announced</a>. An updated demo will be available this summer. <span id="more-957477"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3180070/No_Im_not_a_Human/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>WARNING. Stay inside. Lock your doors. Close the blinds. Only let humans in. Eliminate all Visitors. An anxiety horror about paranoia in the End of Times.</p><p><strong>Don’t <a title="Companies > Panic [28 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/panic">Panic</a></strong></p><p>Sunrise. Twilight of earth. The world is ending. Acrid auromas of sun-scorched streets fill the air. Blackened corpses gnarled into shapes of agony line streets. Peering outside is enough to scorch eyes from socket. The only refuge is in the night.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>But the night belongs to the Visitors.</p><p><strong>Let the Right Ones In</strong></p><p>A knock on the door. A solitary voice, begging for refuge. They look like us. Talk like us. Smell like us. Are they us? Look for the signs.</p><p><strong>Your Guests, Your Death</strong></p><p>Isolation is not an option. The Visitors will overwhelm us. Let some in. Hear their stories. Some will help. Some will need help.</p><p>Some are Visitors.</p><p><strong>Do What You Must</strong></p><p>The Visitors kill. Kill them first. Interrogate the guests. Do what must be done.</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Coming Soon Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="No, I'm not a Human — Coming Soon" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7bFciBjEuOk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elder Scrolls Online Will Soon Let You Mix And Match Class Abilities]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elder-scrolls-online-will-soon-let-you-mix-and-match-class-abilities/1100-6530747/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elder-scrolls-online-will-soon-let-you-mix-and-match-class-abilities.1161129/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elder-scrolls-online-will-soon-let-you-mix-and-match-class-abilities/1100-6530747/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530747">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/the-elder-scrolls-online/">The Elder Scrolls Online</a> is looking to experiment in 2025, ranging from its new seasonal content model, a major server-wide event unlike anything in the game's history, and even the ability to mix and match abilities from different classes to create something entirely new.</p><p dir="ltr">Developer ZeniMax Online revealed what's coming in the year ahead for its long-running MMORPG at a recent ESO Direct. In it, studio director Matt Firor reiterated much of what he said in an <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elder-scrolls-online-is-ditching-chapters-in-favor-of-more-frequent-bite-sized-updates/1100-6528526/">end-of-year blog post</a> from December. Unlike every year since 2017's Morrowind chapter, 2025 will not see the release of a new expansion, but will instead see the game shift to a seasonal content model that Firor said will allow it more freedom to experiment when it comes to releasing new content and addressing the needs of the game.</p><p dir="ltr">"We want to keep telling great stories, but also mix in new ideas and gameplay systems, and that's exactly what we're going to do," Firor said. "But we'll do this in a different cadence, one that allows us, the developers, to broaden our focus and increase variety."</p><h2 dir="ltr">Seasons Of The Worm Cult</h2><p dir="ltr">ESO game director Rich Lambert and executive producer Susan Kath then dove into what all will be coming in place of a new chapter. The game's first season under this new format will be Seasons of the Worm Cult, one that will actually serve as a decade-later sequel to the game's original Molag Bal storyline and will kick off in June. It will introduce a new zone, the isle of Solstice, where players will investigate the resurgence of Bal's Worm Cult and meet familiar faces from the game's first main quest along the way. The zone is home to outcast elves and Argonians, with Carribean-esque beaches and tropical forests for players to explore.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4473776-esosolsticebeach.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4473776" data-ratio="0.56253443526171" data-width="1815" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4473776-esosolsticebeach.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4473776"></a><figcaption>The new Solstice zone sits off Tamriel's southern coast.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4473776-esosolsticebeach.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Though Seasons of the Worm Cult will last most of the year, Kath made clear that might not be the case for future seasons. In the years ahead, seasons could be shorter, ranging from three to six months. Those may take the form of "remix" seasons where ZeniMax Online revisits old storylines, with the developer teasing a Dark Brotherhood-themed season.</p><p dir="ltr">Instead of purchasing a new chapter, players will instead be able to purchase a $50 content pass that will include all of the year's upcoming seasonal updates, including new dungeons. The content pass will be separate from ESO's existing ESO Plus subscription, though all of Season of the Worm Cult's new dungeons will be included as part of ESO Plus. During a post-ESO Direct press Q&amp;A attended by GameSpot, Kath said the team was looking at ways to further add to and incentivize ESO Plus but did not announce any specifics.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Subclasses</h2><p dir="ltr">News that subclassing will be coming to ESO for all players in June is likely the biggest announcement. Regardless of which of the game's seven classes a player originally picked, they'll be able to select abilities from up to two skill lines from other classes to experiment with, with over 3,000 unique skill line combinations.</p><p dir="ltr">The ESO Direct and subsequent Q&amp;A didn't dive into many details, but ZeniMax Online did confirm players will need to keep at least one skill line from their original class. While one character can learn all the available non-main class skill lines, they'll only be able to actively use abilities from two other class skill lines at a time. The feature will unlock at the game's max level of 50, and unlocking subclass skill lines will be account-wide across all characters. Some class skill lines will cost double the amount of skill points, though Lambert said he doesn't think that will be a problem for the game's dedicated players.</p><h2 dir="ltr">New Experiments</h2><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4473777-esosolsticewrithingwall.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4473777" data-ratio="0.56262626262626" data-width="1980" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4473777-esosolsticewrithingwall.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4473777"></a><figcaption>A massive magical barrier, the Writhing Wall, divides the new Solstice zone in half.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1647/16470614/4473777-esosolsticewrithingwall.jpg"></figure><p>Aside from subclassing, ZeniMax Online is experimenting in other ways as well. The new Solstice zone will be divided in half by a massive magical barrier called the Writhing Wall, an obstacle that will see players later in the summer participate in a server-wide event that will be the first of its kind in ESO. Players on each server will need to come together to gather resources, defend the island from the Worm Cult, and eventually breach the wall, in the process unlocking the second half of the zone. From how it was described, it sounds similar to something like vanilla World of Warcraft's iconic Gates of Ahn'Qiraj event, where players contributed to a war effort in order to unlock the gates and access two new raids. Lambert said breaching the wall will be a one-time event per server but that there will be ways to experience most of the event for those who miss out.</p><p dir="ltr">"The goal will be to work together with fellow players to breach the wall from the West and gain access to the Eastern half of Solstice," Lambert said. "Your mega-server's collective effort and activity is really going to dictate how fast that server will progress through the phases, which ultimately means players are going to experience the epic final encounter and outcome of the event at different times."</p><p dir="ltr">One major experiment ZeniMax Online has already conducted is the recent <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elder-scrolls-onlines-longest-running-issue-is-the-target-of-a-new-play-test-but-its-just-a-first-step/1100-6530226/">Cyrodiil Champions test</a>, which was briefly mentioned during the ESO Direct. It's the studio's answer to performance problems that have long plagued the game's large-scale PvP mode and something that Firor specifically called out as needing to be addressed in his end-of-year blog post. The test, which ran March 24-31, vastly simplified abilities and stats for all players in Cyrodiil in the name of significantly improving performance. In the Q&amp;A, Firor said the test was a huge success and surpassed its goal of being able to support the number of players in Cyrodiil seen shortly after the game's launch in 2014.</p><p dir="ltr">"It couldn't have gone much better," Firor said. "It was beyond-our-wildest-dreams successful."</p><p dir="ltr">Lambert said the next step is to dig through the "mountains of data" from the test. Then, the team will begin to add more changes like additional skill lines and stats before running more tests, slowly working towards turning Cyrodiil Champions into a full-fledged feature.</p><p dir="ltr">ZeniMax Online is also putting an emphasis on catering to new and returning players. As spotlighted in the ESO Direct, updates have already been made to the game's tutorial and starter zones, and the team will continue to look at making the returning player experience better with a "Welcome Back" system set to debut this summer. Kath declined to go into detail on what such a system would entail during the Q&amp;A but said it wasn't a "one-size-fits-all" approach and that it would be a "quest-based, reward-driven experience."</p><p dir="ltr">ESO celebrated its 10-year anniversary last year, and Firor said the game will continue to evolve in the years to come, now with a new format that will allow the team to improve aspects of the game it couldn't find time for on its old yearly chapter schedule.</p><p dir="ltr">"We just didn't have time to do all those little things," Firor said. "This lets us open the development schedule and do lots of cool little things as well as continue to work on content."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open-World Camper Simulator Outbound Is Getting A Closed-Alpha Very Soon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/open-world-camper-simulator-outbound-is-getting-a-closed-alpha-very-soon/1100-6530793/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/open-world-camper-simulator-outbound-is-getting-a-closed-alpha-very-soon.1161123/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/open-world-camper-simulator-outbound-is-getting-a-closed-alpha-very-soon/1100-6530793/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530793">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Outbound, an indie open-world camper simulator where players live off the grid in their van, is getting a closed alpha on April 14.</p><p>A new trailer for the cozy survival-crafting game was shown as part of the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/triple-i-initiative-2025-everything-announced-at-the-showcase/2900-6460/" data-ref-id="2900-6460">2025 Triple-I Initiative showcase</a>. In the closed alpha, players will be able to explore the plains and forests of the game's first biome, participate in four player co-op, try out the game's building system, and more.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tvTyMmd7ouM" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tvTyMmd7ouM" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>To access the closed alpha, players will need to sign-up for the game's newsletter through the Outbound <a href="https://www.squareglade.games/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">website</a>. Starting on April 14, random subscribers will be selected to join the playtest.</p><p dir="ltr">"The closed alpha is an early build of the game and we want to test mechanics and overall stability with a limited number of players," the developer, Square Glade Games, stated in a post on Steam. "With a little bit of luck, you can also join!"</p><p dir="ltr">While Square Glade Games says most of the game's features--including cooking, vehicle and player upgrades, environmental puzzles, collectables, and more--are part of the alpha, there are still more features currently in the works. Those features, which are slated to ship as part of the game's launch, including fishing, bee-keeping, more biomes, additional character customization options, a dog companion, and full controller support.</p><p dir="ltr">Outbound players start with an empty camper van powered by renewable energy and a dream. Over time, players can scavenge materials to craft upgrades and make the camper self-sufficient with more advanced technology and the ability to create gardens of plants that can be used for food.</p><p dir="ltr">The game raised nearly $300,000 in September 2024 on <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/squareglade/outbound" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Kickstarter</a>, after which Square Glade Games promised to add additional features like fishing and the game's dog companion. Though Outbound doesn't have an official release date, its "estimated delivery" date on Kickstarter is January 2026. It is planned to release on PC as well as PlayStation, Xbox, and Nintendo Switch, with the caveat that its console release date may differ from its PC release.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Katana Zero DLC Still Coming, It’ll Still Be Free, And It’ll Be Almost As Big As The Original Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/katana-zero-dlc-still-coming-itll-still-be-free-and-itll-be-almost-as-big-as-the-original-game/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/katana-zero-dlc-still-coming-it%E2%80%99ll-still-be-free-and-it%E2%80%99ll-be-almost-as-big-as-the-original-game.1161102/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/katana-zero-dlc-still-coming-itll-still-be-free-and-itll-be-almost-as-big-as-the-original-game/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Six years after its original release, Katana Zero remains one of the best 2D hack-and-slash one-hit-kill games on any platform. Its tightly executed gameplay and mysterious story make it extremely repayable, along with the speedrunning mode that was added to the game post-launch.</p>
<p>The DLC that developer Askiisoft announced shortly after the game's launch in 2019 has yet to come. However, during today's Triple-I Initiative Showcase, we finally got a glimpse at the DLC, along with the announcement that it'll be "<em>coming soon</em>."</p>
<p>Askiisoft also confirmed that the DLC will still be free for players who already own Katana Zero. Just as exciting is the confirmation that every new addition the DLC brings will add up to this expansion being about "<em>the size of the original game</em>."</p>
<p>The DLC will feature new characters, levels, and gameplay mechanics, and developer Askiisoft assures players in a press release that when it does arrive, this DLC will have been "<em>worth the wait.</em>"</p>
<p><iframe title="Katana ZERO - Free DLC Trailer | The Triple-i Initiative" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qMyziPJY_aw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Fans of Katana Zero have been waiting for answers about the base game's story, which this DLC promises to include. Understandably, Askiisoft is hesitant to provide any story insights ahead of the DLC's release. What we do know is that this DLC will pick up right where Zero's story left off in the base game, and as we see in the trailer, we'll also get a better glimpse into his past.</p>
<p>This DLC reveal was the 'one more thing' at the end of the Triple-I Initiative Showcase, which shows just how much pent-up excitement exists for the next chapter of Katana Zero's story. It's definitely still upsetting that we don't even have a release window yet, but the fact that we have an update after years of silence has definitely rekindled fans excitement, and removed any doubt that the DLC had died somewhere along the way in the last six years.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[X4: Foundations, the space sim that lets you take an empire to war, will let you just talk things out in its next update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/x4-foundations-the-space-sim-that-lets-you-take-an-empire-to-war-will-let-you-just-talk-things-out-in-its-next-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/x4-foundations-the-space-sim-that-lets-you-take-an-empire-to-war-will-let-you-just-talk-things-out-in-its-next-update.1161099/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/x4-foundations-the-space-sim-that-lets-you-take-an-empire-to-war-will-let-you-just-talk-things-out-in-its-next-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article">
        <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/x4-foundations-diplomacy.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Egosoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
There's a whole bunch of games set in space that let you duke it out in dogfights, form strategies around entire fleets, terraform planets, all often pretty violent acts. So, I found it very funny to see <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/x4-foundations">X4: Foundations</a> at the Triple-I showcase today, which received a trailer for its upcoming Diplomacy update which is literally about just talking things out. Seriously, when it says that it's introducing diplomacy it means it, as when it arrives you'll be able to send diplomats to negotiate and forge alliances so that you don't have to jump to war right off the bat.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
There's a new facility, the Embassy, that you'll be able to send said diplomats to chat with other factions. On top of that there's Agents, who can "be deployed on independent assignments to achieve diplomatic objectives within the X universe." Details about the update are pretty slim outside of that, the trailer didn't give all that much away, not even a release date outside of the fact it's coming in 2025. The update will be free at the very least! Not bad for a game that'll be seven years old this November.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="X4: Foundations - Diplomacy Update Trailer | The Triple-i Initiative" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O2xlyJXgCGQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>X4: Foundations - Diplomacy Update Trailer | The Triple-i Initiative</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O2xlyJXgCGQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/O2xlyJXgCGQ?autoplay=1" title="X4: Foundations - Diplomacy Update Trailer | The Triple-i Initiative">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O2xlyJXgCGQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
From an outsider's POV, it does also tickle me that this game is so old yet in a game about building a space empire, trading, fighting, all that jazz you'd expect from a sci-fi game of its ilk, the game's inhabitants never thought to just talk to each other. Oh well! Better late than never.
</p>
<p>
It's probably worth pointing out that X4: Foundations is actually on sale right now, as it's only £12/ $15 down from £40/ $50. You've got until April 16th to get it at that price, no need to rush, but it might be good to get it now ahead of this upcoming update if it takes your fancy.

</p></div>

        </article>

  
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[All 36 Games We Saw At The Triple-i Spring Indie Showcase Extravaganza]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/triple-i-initiate-indie-showcase-roguelike-survival-rpg-1851775569</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/all-36-games-we-saw-at-the-triple-i-spring-indie-showcase-extravaganza.1161093/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/triple-i-initiate-indie-showcase-roguelike-survival-rpg-1851775569<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="feec6616b663417b0372aee2d4af38b7" data-recommend-id="image://feec6616b663417b0372aee2d4af38b7" data-format="png" data-width="1897" data-height="1059" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Images show screenshots of gameplay from the Triple-i initiative showcase." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Images show screenshots of gameplay from the Triple-i initiative showcase." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Evil Empire / Triple-i Initiative / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="feec6616b663417b0372aee2d4af38b7" data-recommend-id="image://feec6616b663417b0372aee2d4af38b7" data-format="png" data-width="1897" data-height="1059" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Images show screenshots of gameplay from the Triple-i initiative showcase." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Big gaming showcases shouldn’t just be for major console makers and Geoff Keighley, which is why the team behind <em>Dead Cells</em>’ ongoing support, Evil Empire, launched the Triple-i Initiative last year. The event puts the spotlight on smaller projects ahead of Summer Game Fest season and returned this year with updates on a whopping 36 games, including world premieres for a few that look really cool. </p><p>There was news about 2019 action platforming hit <em>Katana Zero</em> and its long-promised DLC, as well as brand new reveals for upcoming releases. There was <em>Void/Breaker</em>, a frenetic roguelike cyberpunk FPS from Stubby Games that looks like it builds off of some of the ideas in the team’s 2022 FPS puzzle adventure<em> The Entropy Centre</em>. There was also <em>Frostrail</em>, a post-apocalyptic survival crafting shooter from Shiro Unlimited and FakeFish. Another one of those? Yes, but this one revolves around a train that serves as your home base, transportation, and salvation from the cold and the “horrifying abominations” hiding in it.</p><p>The most surprising announcement for me personally was the latest free DLC for <em>Vampire Survivors</em>. While the bullet hell roguelite getting more content is nothing new, this update is a crossover with Square Enix’s lesser known<em> SaGa</em> franchise. Out now, the DLC drops<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/games/saga-emerald-beyond&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/games/saga-emerald-beyond"> <em>SaGa Emerald Beyond</em></a></span>’s characters into the game’s chaotic arcade adventure. What franchise collab should be next? I’m still holding out for <em>Mega Man</em>. You can watch the full showcase below or scroll through for a look at everything else announced during the 2025 Triple-i Initiative showcase. </p></div></div><div><p>Real ones know and have been waiting almost five years for a glimpse of what was once likened to <em>Katana Zero 1.5</em>. With “all new characters, levels, gameplay and story,” this “massive” DLC still doesn’t have a release date but sounds oh so close. </p></div><div><p>The high-speed shooter is coming later this year and offers weapon crafting, gun modding, and environmental destruction. An open playtest is currently running on Steam through April 24. </p></div><div><p>The first-person shooter is all about open-world survival crafting to upgrade the train that’s keeping you and your friends alive. It hits Early Access for PC in 2026.</p></div><div><p>11 Bit Studios’ latest project is about a space mission worker named Jan Dolski who must create alternate versions of himself with unique skills but shared memories in order to survive. It now has a release date of June 13, 2025.</p></div><div><p>A nightmarish life sim, <em>Neverway</em> features the work of <em>Celeste </em>and<em> TowerFall</em>’s pixel artist and the music of Disasterpeace who composed the mesmerizing soundscapes for both <em>Fez </em>and <em>Hyper Light Drifter</em>.  That’s it. That’s all I needed to know. </p></div><div><p> If you guessed that <em>Deep Rock Galactic: Rogue Core</em> would feature the mining horde mode shooter’s mechanics with new run-based roguelike elements, you’d be correct. Players can sign up for a Closed Alpha happening now. </p></div><div><p>One of the better <em>Vampire Survivors</em> copycats now has a 1.0 launch date. After winning fans over in Early Access, the full version is coming out September 17, 2025. </p></div><div><p>The twee van-life sim about crafting and sustainability will feature a closed alpha on April 14. Upgrade your vehicle, grow crops, and explore a beautiful alternate world where hope still abounds. </p></div><div><p><em>SpeedRunners 2: King of Speed</em> was announced with a release window of 2025 for PC and 2026 for console. The <em>Nickelodeon All-Stars Brawl</em> team is making it, and for anyone unfamiliar with the original, the hook is the game’s 8-player platforming races with a battle royale-like “ever-shrinking ring of fire.”</p></div><div><p> A workshop apprentice goes on an adventure. Many 3D action-platformer hijinks ensue. Will there be collectibles in this modern re-imagining of a retro throwback? Players can find out when it hits PC and console in 2026. <br></p></div><div><p> Control cabin boy Sam and loyal husky Ellie in solo or co-op to explore an uncharted island and uncover a bleak mystery. Who’s ready to cry?!</p></div><div><p> But what is it exactly? I’ll let the devs explain. According to them, <em>Into the Fire</em> is “a disaster extraction survival with arcade elements.” Neat! Players can face volcanic demons in Dante’s Archipelago in Early Access later this year. </p></div><div><p>Arcade medieval army brawler<em> Tears of Metal </em>has a great art style and some really rad-looking combat. You can try the hack-and-slash roguelike online with friends in the current Steam beta running until April 17. </p></div><div><p><em> Vampire Survivors: Emerald Diorama</em> is the hit arcade roguelite’s latest free update featuring a cross over with Square Enix. It’s out on every platform right now. </p></div><div><p> The long-awaited strategy follow-up now has an Early Access launch window of summer 2025. I can’t wait. </p></div><div><p> Interstellar politics is about to get more complicated. A free summer update for<em> X4: Foundations </em>will add new strategic elements for alliance building, including sending agents out on missions to influence partners and rivals.</p></div><div><p> The escape room game lets you solve puzzles in Dracula’s castle or deep space starships. Players can go hands-on with the sequel now on Steam. </p></div><div><p> You’re stuck in a gross prison cell. Pay off your debt with nothing but an ATM and a slot machine. It’s coming to Steam later this year and also has a free demo available to try now. </p></div><div><p> The action-roguelike spin-off is getting a couch co-op mode for two players and content from <em>Dead Cells</em> sometime this summer. </p></div><div><p> The survival crafting Soulslike is getting a new Thralls of Twilight update in May as it continues its Early Access journey. </p></div><div><p><em> Olden Era</em> is a new entry in the beloved  turn-based strategy series. It’s being developed by<em> Iratus </em>makers Unfrozen and published by Ubisoft and takes players to the previously unexplored continent of Jadame. </p></div><div><p><em> Moonlighter 2: The Endless Vault</em> takes the shopkeeper roguelite into 3D in just a few months. The dungeon crawler will be starting out in Early Access. </p></div><div><p> The character action roguelite in which you transform into different characters to unleash powerful attacks hits Early Access this summer. </p></div><div><p>The next game from the maker of <em>Art of Rally</em> lets you drive classic off-roading vehicles through trails and scenic landscapes for the colorful, lo-fi escape we all need right now. </p></div><div><p> But horror fans may be enthused. Navigate a  post-catastrophic world where creatures disguise themselves as humans in a very <em>Night Trap</em> meets <em>Maniac Mansion </em>meets Aphex Twin kind of way. </p></div><div><p><em>The Forgotten Depths </em>is a free content drop out today that adds a new biome to the pixel art-looking combat crafting sim. <em>Necesse</em> is slated to leave Early Access this summer. </p></div><div><p> The top-down survival game is getting Invaders of Oakveil on April 28. Players will explore a new venomous area, collect poisonous weapons, and fight the  Serpent Queen Megara. </p></div><div><p> The narrative-driven adventure game has you use old cameras to explore a place outside of reality uncovering secrets, and probably dealing with past traumas, to make your way home. The music and art looks excellent. </p></div><div><p>“Embark on an epic quest as Ezekiel, a devoted young bishop of the god Sheol, who must recover the sacred Malkora and cleanse Antioch from heretics,” reads the plot summary. If the whole game looks and sounds as good as the trailer, sure!</p></div><div><p>The Dimension Update arrives June 2 for the construction management game. It adds a bunch of new features including a refined placement system, multi-floor platforms, and various quality-of-life improvements. </p></div><div><p>The next project from the makers of <em>Dorfromantik</em> is <em>Star Birds</em>. You lead spacefaring birds across the galaxy by automating systems on an asteroid. Its first demo is just a few months away. </p></div><div><p>It’s a roguelite city builder in which you harvest, build, mine, cook, brew, and grow in order to defend against invasions. You can lead the human or undead kingdoms, each rendered with an old-school 8-bit look. </p></div><div><p>In <em>Timberborn </em>Update 7 the post-apocalyptic beaver masses are taking to the skies and water-sealed tubeways. “By putting up the dirt in layers, they now can build hanging gardens, grow plants on their roofs, and even create tunnels and artificial caves.” It hits May 8.</p></div><div><p>The blacksmithing sim lands in Early Access on May 25. Run a medieval smithy from top to bottom, supervising ore shipments and selling the finished products. </p></div><div><p>  <em>The Eternal Life of Goldman</em> will land sometime in 2025 and is boasting an all-star cast of composers when it does, with contributions from Kevin Penkin (<em>Star Wars: Visions</em>, <em>Made in Abyss</em>, <em>Florence</em>), Mason Lieberman (<em>Overwatch 2</em>, <em>Stray Gods: The Roleplaying Musical</em>,<em> League of Legends: Wild Rift</em>), Pete Lepley (<em>Wargroove</em>, <em>Sky Rogue</em>), and Yasunori Nishiki (<em>Octopath Traveler</em>, <em>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</em>).<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Time Does Indiana Jones and the Great Circle PS5 Release? Release Date & Times Confirmed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/what-time-does-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-release-date-times-confirmed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-time-does-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-release-date-times-confirmed.1161090/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/what-time-does-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-release-date-times-confirmed/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>PlayStation players are a little late to the party, but Indiana Jones and the Great Circle launches soon. Here is everything you need to know about the release date and start times. </p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> follows the iconic professor by day and action hero by night as he attempts to stop enemy parties from acquiring an artifact connected to the Great Circle. </p>



<p>MachineGames’ latest project received glowing reviews, leading to reports that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/more-indiana-jones-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">more Indiana Jones games</a> are in development. Reviewers weren’t the only ones who praised the game, as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/harrison-ford-troy-baker-indy-brilliant-job/">Harison Ford</a> said that Troy Baker ‘did a brilliant job’ portraying his character. Let’s jump right into how PlayStation users can see that performance. </p>



<h2 id="h-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-release-date">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Release Date</h2>



<p><strong>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</strong> <strong>officially launches for PS5 on April 17</strong>. </p>



<p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle initially launched in December 2024 as an Xbox Series X/S and Windows exclusive.&nbsp;PlayStation fans didn’t think they would ever have a chance to play this game, but Microsoft shocked fans at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=76VpUciztBs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Gamescom 2024</a> by announcing that it would no longer be an Xbox and Windows exclusive title.  </p>



<h2 id="h-does-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-have-early-access">Does Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Have Early Access?</h2>



<p><strong>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle early access behind on April 15. </strong></p>



<p>Early access is only available if you <strong>pre-order the Premium Edition, which costs $99.99</strong>. Here is everything else included in the Premium Edition. </p>



<ul>
<li>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</li>



<li>Up to 2-Day Early Access</li>



<li>The Order of Giants Story DLC</li>



<li>Digital Artbook</li>



<li>Temple of Doom Outfit</li>



<li>The Last Crusade Pack</li>
</ul>



<p>Check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-the-great-circle-ps5-preload-guide-how-big-it-is-file-size-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">preload and file size guide</a> for more information about downloading the game and getting in as soon as possible. </p>



<h2 id="h-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-start-times">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Start Times</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Once Indiana Jones pulls out the whip, enemies have no chance. Image via Bethesda</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Standard Edition releases at 5:00 AM PDT on April 16, and the Premium Edition launches at 5 PM PDT on April 14—with other regions also following soon after.</strong></p>



<p>Below are release times and dates for key time zones worldwide, including the United States, Australia, and more.</p>



<p><strong>Standard Edition </strong></p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Release Times &amp; Dates</th></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Daylight Time (PDT)</td><td data-align="center">5:00 PM—April 16</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Daylight Time (CDT)</td><td data-align="center">7:00 PM—April 16</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Daylight Time (EDT)</td><td data-align="center">8:00 PM—April 16</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)</td><td data-align="center">11:00 PM—April 16</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Daylight Time (AEDT)</td><td data-align="center">9:00 AM—April 17</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p><strong>Premium Edition </strong></p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><th data-align="center">Time Zone</th><th data-align="center">Release Times &amp; Dates</th></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Pacific Daylight Time (PDT)</td><td data-align="center">5:00 PM—April 16</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Central Daylight Time (CDT)</td><td data-align="center">7:00 PM—April 16</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Eastern Daylight Time (EDT)</td><td data-align="center">8:00 PM—April 16</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)</td><td data-align="center">11:00 PM—April 16</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Australian Eastern Daylight Time (AEDT)</td><td data-align="center">9:00 AM—April 17</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr>



<p>While it’s an exciting time to be a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-playstation-plus-game-catalog-games-announced-for-april-2025/">PlayStation</a> user, that doesn’t necessarily translate to success for console gaming. According to the latest global data, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pc-gaming-gained-more-players-than-console-in-2024/">PC gaming gained more players than console</a> in 2024, and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/console-gaming-revenue-fell-in-2024-thanks-to-premium-game-revenue-dropping/">console gaming revenue</a> also fell this past year.  </p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roguelike character action game Morbid Metal launches in Early Access this summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/roguelike-character-action-game-morbid-metal-launches-in-early-access-this-summer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roguelike-character-action-game-morbid-metal-launches-in-early-access-this-summer.1161087/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/roguelike-character-action-game-morbid-metal-launches-in-early-access-this-summer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>New gameplay trailer released.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Roguelike [315 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelike">Roguelike</a> character <a title="Genres > Action [2,656 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Morbid Metal" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/morbid-metal">Morbid Metal</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,854 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1866130/Morbid_Metal/" target="_blank">Steam</a> this summer, developer <a title="Companies > SCREEN JUICE" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/screen-juice">SCREEN JUICE</a> <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1866130/view/537724907214077955" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-957461"></span></p><p>“It’s been many years since the development of <em>Morbid Metal</em> started and I posted the first bits and pieces online&lt;" SCREEN JUICE said in the announcement. "Now we are a small team of passionate developers working on it and we are so proud to finally be able to say it is coming this summer! All of you have been eagerly waiting to finally get your hands on <em>Morbid Metal</em> to unleash your stylish combos onto deadly enemies. Your continued support means so much to us and the project would not have been possible without it. Thank you!”</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1866130/Morbid_Metal/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Morbid Metal</em> is an action-packed roguelite, in which players can shapeshift between four different characters in real-time, all with unique active abilities and stylish attacks. Rapidly switch characters and combine abilities to slaughter enemies in stylish fashion.</p><p>Progress through stunning, semi-procedurally generated levels, fighting through hordes of enemies and powerful bosses in various environmental biomes, ranging from desolate wastelands of the far future, to the overgrown ruins of mankind.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Upgrade your characters and progressively grow stronger to annihilate your enemies. But beware: death is closer than you think, and if he gets you, you start all over again.</p><p><strong>Action-Packed Combat</strong></p><p>In <em>Morbid Metal</em>, you can expect high octane, fast paced action, with dozens of stylish moves to wreak havoc upon your enemies. With a single press of a button, rapidly shapeshift into deadly characters, each with their own unique move sets, active abilities and of course a signature special skill. Use attacks and active abilities of multiple characters to unleash powerful combos upon hordes of deadly machines and fight your way through beautiful and challenging levels.</p><p><strong>Fight, Upgrade, Die, Repeat</strong></p><p>Pick your team of up to four characters and jump right into the action! With each enemy slaughtered, each level cleared, become stronger by unlocking impactful upgrades and engaging new ways to battle. But if you die, it’s all gone. Permanently unlock and upgrade characters to grow more powerful each time you fight your way through the semi-procedurally generated levels of a far future to ultimately uncover the mystery of this deadly new world.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Action-packed combat.</li><li>Realtime shapeshifting.</li><li>Stylish combos.</li><li>Next-generation graphics.</li><li>Diverse environments.</li><li>Semi-procedurally generated levels.</li><li>Run-based <a title="Genres > Roguelite [235 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/roguelite">rogue-lite game</a>play.</li><li>Unique and satisfying upgrades.</li><li>Permanent upgrades and character unlocks.</li><li>Rich lore and compelling world of the distant future.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Early Access Release Window Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="MORBID METAL Early Access Release Window Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UKiW3UmlcG8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ENDLESS Legend II launches in Early Access this summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/endless-legend-ii-launches-in-early-access-this-summer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/endless-legend-ii-launches-in-early-access-this-summer.1161081/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/endless-legend-ii-launches-in-early-access-this-summer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Build your Empire across the evolving world of Saiadha.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > ENDLESS Legend II [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/endless-legend-ii">ENDLESS Legend II</a></em> will launch in Early Access for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,854 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3407390/ENDLESS_Legend_2/" target="_blank">Steam</a> this summer, publisher <a title="Companies > Hooded Horse [8 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/hooded-horse">Hooded Horse</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Amplitude Studios [14 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/amplitude-studios">Amplitude Studios</a> announced. <span id="more-957466"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3407390/ENDLESS_Legend_2/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>ENDLESS Legend II</em> is a fantasy <a title="Genres > Strategy [233 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">strategy game</a> where you lead wildly varied factions as they build grand empires and wage planet-spanning wars on an ever-evolving ocean world at the brink of extinction. Cataclysmic events have wrought havoc on the natural order, and the very world will change as time goes on revealing new opportunities for exploration and conquest to the bold and daring. Establish expansive cities to spread your influence and strengthen your economy, raise armies and command troops in turn-based tactical battles to overcome your enemies by force, and push forth into the unknown to uncover the dark secrets that lie at the planet’s core.</p><p><strong>Lead Disparate Factions</strong></p><p>Whether you command righteous warriors descended from the stars or hive-minded aliens that know only how to fight, feed, and propagate, <em>ENDLESS Legend II</em> features vastly different factions each driven by their own philosophies, histories, capabilities, and narratives. Each of the factions have unique traits that set them apart from one another whether on the battlefield, in matters of commerce, with regards to empire-building, or in diplomatic affairs—it is up to you to adapt to their strengths and weaknesses and build strategies and distinct playstyles.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>The choice of faction will influence every aspect of the game. Will you prefer to benefit from a constant state of fighting, untethered by the need to justify your wars, spawning additional warriors with each victorious battle to grow endlessly in strength? Or will you choose to benefit from cohabitation and cooperation, spreading tendrils of influence throughout the world to build a network of allies, leveraging relationships with the minor factions of the planet to further enrich your empire? Learn what makes each faction distinct and use it to your advantage whether you’re leading them, or looking to destroy them.</li><li>Military doctrine varies greatly between the factions, providing unique opportunities for a capable commander to gain an advantage over their foe, even when out of combat. Whether you’re building massive fortifications as the Kin of Sheredyn to defend your cities, establishing connections to powerful weapons and support systems waiting in orbit, or you’re investing in the spread of coral that allows the units of spiritualist Aspects to support themselves outside of friendly territory, know your enemy and know yourself to gain the upper hand in any conflict.</li><li>Either auto-resolve combat or take direct control of individual units within your armies when battle begins, using the surrounding terrain to your advantage as you seek out chokepoints, cover, and the high ground. Apart from having faction-specific units, traits, weapons, and attributes, each faction also features special battlefield abilities that can turn the tide of battle if properly utilized. Where one faction might work best with a patient commander, able to meticulously maneuver troops to secure powerful adjacency bonuses, another might rely on force of numbers and overwhelming strength.</li><li>Recruit heroes and watch them grow over time as they gain new traits to bolster their abilities, build relationships that provide them with various boons, and acquire equipment useful both in and out of battle. Powerful commanders, properly trained and armed, can turn the tide of entire wars when wisely utilized.</li></ul><p><strong>Reign in an Evolving World</strong></p><p>Empires will rise and fall based on their ability to adapt to a changing world. Starting from a single humble city, expand according to your faction’s unique strengths and limitations while adapting to the periodic monsoons and tidefalls. Build districts around your cities’ central structures, exploit strategic and luxury resources littered around the world, and develop your technological capabilities and industrial might.</p><ul><li>Cataclysmic tidefalls will expose new opportunities and threats as the oceans recede to unveil new land ripe for expansion. While your existing territory will remain unscathed, the newly revealed terrain from the retreating oceans will open up new avenues of approach for you and your enemies, alongside new resources to exploit and new anomalies to explore. While this can fundamentally change the strategic value of various locations as time goes on, a wise leader will plan for the inevitable—will you prepare to expand into new lands as soon as a tidefall occurs, or focus on shoring up your defenses where you anticipate new landbridges to appear?</li><li>Plan the development of your cities to focus on population growth, industrialization, and commerce, or prioritize their contribution to the sciences, your empire’s influence, and your military might— the choice is yours based on the needs of your burgeoning empire. Establish districts that provide fortifications or further the production of various resources, take advantage of adjacency and terrain bonuses, and pursue technological advancements that allow you to upgrade established districts or unlock entirely new options. Will you patiently seek out ideal locations to establish long-term economic hubs and military strongholds, or will you spread rapidly to secure new lands and increased productivity ahead of your enemies?</li><li>The lands around you are teeming with both opportunity and danger alike. Crush the weaker minor factions littered around the world to pillage their resources, or instead cultivate friendly relations and have them join your growing empire, incorporating their distinctive units and heroes to further strengthen your people. Explore ancient ruins and strange anomalies, braving the dangers of the unknown to enrich your lands and gain powerful artifacts to wield against your enemies.</li></ul><p><strong>Write Your Own Legend</strong></p><p>A deep mystery lies buried beneath the surface of this once-tranquil ocean world, where an ancient power stirs in the darkness. Gain dominion over the planet through violent conquest, seek victory through diplomatic and technological advancements, pursue quests and tackle events that can alter the course of a campaign, or empower your sworn heroes to unveil the story of your people—the choice is yours.</p><p>Will you be a ruthless conqueror or a cunning builder? A cultivated diplomat or a flesh-eating beast? Will you bring harmony back to the planet, seeking out lost legends and heroes, or will you defy the fate that drives your faction and carve a legend of your own?</p></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="ENDLESS™ Legend 2 - Gameplay Trailer | Triple I" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6ZbcbtTLsxI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SacriFire launches in Q1 2026 for PC, later in 2026 for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, and Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/sacrifire-launches-in-q1-2026-for-pc-later-in-2026-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sacrifire-launches-in-q1-2026-for-pc-later-in-2026-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch.1161078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/sacrifire-launches-in-q1-2026-for-pc-later-in-2026-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-and-switch<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Latest trailer features new track by Motoi Sakuraba.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Pixel art <a title="Genres > RPG [17,142 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > SacriFire [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sacrifire">SacriFire</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [22,854 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1661330/SacriFire/" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://www.gog.com/game/sacrifire" target="_blank">GOG</a> in Q1 2026, followed by <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,241 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,023 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,895 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,904 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,930 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> later in 2026, developer <a title="Companies > Pixelated Milk [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/pixelated-milk">Pixelated Milk</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/pixelated_milk/status/1910377683130646673" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-957451"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its store pages:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>SacriFire</em> is an upcoming RPG, inspired by the 90s titles that began our love affair with gaming.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Dynamic Battles</strong> – Our combat engine merges real-time and turn-based styles to provide a fluid experience that is both challenging and satisfying. Fight alongside companions, choose from multiple weapons, target individual enemy body parts, and string attacks together to create elaborate combos.</li><li><strong>High-Quality Presentation</strong> – Employing both pixel art and 3D graphics allows us to combine retro-style graphics with innovative digital effects wizardry. Hand-drawn and animated characters blend seamlessly with 3D-modeled environments.</li><li><strong>Moral Complexity</strong> – <em>SacriFire</em>‘s original story aims to both respect and subvert the standard RPG tropes, so although you’ll feel right at home with our cast of lovable characters, you’ll never know what to expect next!</li><li><strong>A Tale of Two Worlds</strong> – Travel between the sprawling subterranean city of Antioch and the idyllic spirit paradise of Erebus in a well-developed game universe which includes elements of both fantasy and science-fiction.</li><li><strong>Elaborate Gameplay Systems</strong> – Adopt diverse combat disciplines, craft weapons, solve puzzles and tackle imaginative dungeons.</li><li><strong>Original Music and Professional Voice Acting</strong> – A brand new soundtrack composed by G4F and the legendary Motoi Sakuraba. The talented Sound Cadence Studios bring <em>SacriFire</em>‘s memorable cast to life!</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below, featuring a new track by Motoi Sakuraba.</p><h2><span>Release Window Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="SacriFire - Launch Window Reveal" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UT-RBwfI8Qs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PC Gaming Gained More Players Than Console In 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pc-gaming-gained-more-players-than-console-in-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pc-gaming-gained-more-players-than-console-in-2024.1161051/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/pc-gaming-gained-more-players-than-console-in-2024/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>PC gaming is outgrowing console gaming when it comes to total number of players.</p>



<p>In the 2025 PC and Console Gaming Report from <a href="https://newzoo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Newzoo</a>, global data indicates that more players started playing games on PC than they did on console. According to the report, PC player numbers rose 3.9% year-over-year (YoY) from 873.5 million to 907.5 million in 2024. Console players growth, on the other hand, while still up, only grew 2.3% from 615.6 million to 629.5 million.</p>



<p>Looking to the future, Newzoo projects that player growth will steadily continue to rise for 2025 and through 2027. It projects that PC numbers will increase to around 930.1 million this year while console players will jump to 653.1 million. By the end of 2027, Newzoo suggests that PC and console player numbers will be around 971.7 million and 698 million, respectively.</p>



<h6 id="h-read-more-triple-i-initiative-showcase-2025-everything-announced">READ MORE: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/triple-i-initiative-showcase-2025-everything-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Triple-i Initiative Showcase 2025—Everything Announced</a></h6>



<p>Despite PC players growing at a higher rate and there being more of them, console revenue was slightly ahead of PC. In 2024, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/console-gaming-revenue-fell-in-2024-thanks-to-premium-game-revenue-dropping/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">console gaming made $42.8 billion</a> in revenue while <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/58-of-pc-gaming-revenue-came-from-microtransactions-in-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PC gaming came</a> in at $37.3 billion. With a total of $80.2 billion for the year, that was a bit less than the $81.9 billion in revenue in 2023. Still, it’s expected that gaming revenue in general will grow in 2025 to $85.2 billion. By 2027, Newzoo expects revenue to surpass $92 billion for the year.</p>



<p>A reason for the increase in overall gaming revenue projections? New hardware. The Nintendo Switch 2 in 2025 and the expected new hardware around 2027 will lead to more gaming purchases for players.</p>



<p>What do you think of PC players outgrowing console players in 2024? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1855/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the latest rumors surrounding&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/latest-titanfall-3-rumors-not-real-according-to-jeff-grubb/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Titanfall 3 not being real</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Free-to-Play Mythic Sci-Fi Action RPG Black Beacon Is Out Now on iOS and Android]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/free-to-play-mythic-sci-fi-action-rpg-black-beacon-is-out-now-on-ios-and-android</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/free-to-play-mythic-sci-fi-action-rpg-black-beacon-is-out-now-on-ios-and-android.1161048/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/free-to-play-mythic-sci-fi-action-rpg-black-beacon-is-out-now-on-ios-and-android<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Lead a squad of heroes on a journey through time.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Beacon is the newest title from publisher Glohow that recently launched on mobile devices. It’s a mythic sci-fi action RPG with a story that sees you travel through time and visit different eras of history to try to prevent catastrophe.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In this world, there are mysterious substances known as beacons that seemingly defy logic — they change size, shape, and texture depending on who’s observing them and how they’re observed. What stays consistent is their abyssal black color (which gives the game its name) and the fact that anomalies accompany them wherever they’re found.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/03/black-beacon-gameplay-1-1743705548457.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Throughout human history, the phenomena these beacons created have been considered miracles or revelations, causing them to be worshipped as sacred objects. Ancient humans embedded them in obelisks, sealed them under temples, or cast them into stained glass frames.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s the background lore, but the story of Black Beacon picks up with you playing the Seer. You’ve been entrusted with the key to the Library of Babel, which is essentially an endless labyrinth that contains all possible permutations of the past, present, and future. You get a vision of a disastrous future, setting you on your time-traveling path to prevent it.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/03/black-beacon-gameplay-3-1743713753488.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">To accomplish that, you’ll need to gather a team of heroes. That starts with Zero and Ereshan, who will join up with you at the beginning of the story. Zero is a mysterious guardian of the Library of Babel who shows little emotion and doesn’t seem to care about worldly events. Ereshan is the granddaughter of the former director of the Library of Babel who was stripped of her inheritance when Zero showed up, leading to loathing that has since cooled.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You’ll have the opportunity to add plenty of other characters to your crew, from the affable Nanna to the intimidating Shamash to the elegant Viola. There’s more than 10 characters available at launch, with more to be added in the future.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">You’re able to take three characters into each combat encounter; you only control one at a time, but can switch between them on the fly. Each character’s abilities are on individual cooldowns, so you need to swap them in and out quickly and efficiently to chain their attacks and abilities together in fluid combat.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/03/black-beacon-gameplay-2-1743705859398.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The main story progresses in chapters that are further broken down into several stages, some of which are purely cutscenes while others are combat stages. Both advance the story forward and include full voice acting.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As you complete stages, you’ll earn rewards that can be used to improve characters or their weapons. Skill books are used to level up characters, and they each have unique abilities you can also level up. Once characters reach a certain level threshold, you’ll need certain items to let them “breakthrough” that threshold and continue gaining levels.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Weapons have a similar system. Each weapon starts with an innate rarity measured in a star level, up to 5 stars. You can level up weapons to a certain threshold, then use items to “breakthrough” that threshold and both power up the weapon and increase its star rating.</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/04/03/black-beacon-gameplay-4-1743713807419.png" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">You can earn more of the items necessary for character and weapon progression outside of the main story in the Resources mode, which you can select from the main menu. You can choose to focus on items to level up, increase skills, or break through thresholds. Whichever version you choose, you’ll get new combat encounters that provide rewards for completion as well as goals specific to that stage, like completing it within a certain amount of time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">There’s also an EX mode, which basically acts as a tutorial to teach you how to use particular characters and a practice space to get better with them. And if you want to take a break and just hang out with some of the characters in your squad, you can do that too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Black Beacon is available now for free through the App Store on iOS, Google Play on Android, and through Google Play Games if you prefer to play on a PC client. For more info, you can check out the <a href="https://blackbeacon.astaplay.com/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>game’s official website</u></a> or follow along with the community on <a href="https://x.com/BB_BlackBeacon" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Twitter</u></a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/BB.BlackBeacon" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Facebook</u></a>, <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@bb_blackbeacon" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>TikTok</u></a>, or <a href="https://discord.com/invite/pHgnz5C5Uc" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer sponsored"><u>Discord</u></a>.</p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 Bundles Are On Auction Sites for $300+ Above Recommended Retail Prices, But Fans Are Fighting Back]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-bundles-are-on-auction-sites-for-300-above-recommended-retail-prices-but-fans-are-fighting-back</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-bundles-are-on-auction-sites-for-300-above-recommended-retail-prices-but-fans-are-fighting-back.1161042/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-bundles-are-on-auction-sites-for-300-above-recommended-retail-prices-but-fans-are-fighting-back<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">"If anyone wants to do their bit for society…"</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Nintendo fans in the U.S. may be feeling pretty hard done by now as the rest of the world fights for a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-2"><u>Nintendo Switch 2</u></a> pre-order, but some are fighting back by challenging and reporting every Nintendo Switch 2 auction listing they can find.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On eBay.com, Nintendo Switch 2 consoles are, at the time of writing, listed from anywhere between $468 to $855, with a lot listing Buy It Now prices of around $700-$750 — that's $300 over the recommended retail price.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">United in their frustrations both about the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-delays-switch-2-pre-order-date-in-the-us-to-assess-impact-of-trumps-tariffs"><u>pre-order delay</u></a> and the preponderance of over-priced pre-orders on eBay, however, players are working to take scalpers down together. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"If anyone wants to do their bit for society, go on eBay and report the scalpers," said one <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/comments/1jv4gp0/scalpers_ebay/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Redditor</u></a>. "I've had about 15 listings removed, spent literally minutes reporting them."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"Reminder that preselling an eBay item is not allowed unless it will be shipping within 40 days of purchasing off eBay, (impossible for the Switch!), at least in the UK anyways," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/comments/1jv3bvu/bye_bye_ebay_scalpers/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>said another</u></a>, racking up almost 6,000 upvotes. The image attached showed a long list of confirmation emails from eBay stating that the content they had reported was removed.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another jumped on Reddit to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/comments/1jvqces/just_got_15_more_scalpers_removed_from_ebay/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>confirm</u></a> they'd had "15 more scalpers removed from eBay," while another player <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/comments/1jvi4fa/i_have_gotten_over_20_switch_2_preorder_listings/?" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>posted to say</u></a> their actions saw 20 Switch pre-order listings scrubbed from the site.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, just why are players having so much luck combating scalpers this time around? Well, that has to do with eBay's very own <a href="https://www.ebay.com/help/policies/listing-policies/presale-listings-policy?id=4252" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>terms and conditions concerning pre-sale items</u></a>, which say "pre-sale listings must clearly state that they are 'presale' in the title and description, and guarantee shipment within 40 business days of purchase."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"You’re not allowed to sell pre-orders on eBay because the seller doesn’t have, and it’s possible they will never actually get, the item they’re selling," explained<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/comments/1jucti7/hate_scalpers_on_ebay_report_them_ebay_will/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u> rmajor86</u></a> on a post that's also been upvoted hundreds of time. "Just report the listing, and eBay will remove it."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That said, things may change soon. As <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NintendoSwitch2/comments/1jucti7/comment/mm4biwh/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>formerlyDylan</u></a> pointed out, June 5 is 40 business days from today, April 10 (excluding Easter), and eBay's terms and conditions state pre-sale items must "guarantee shipment within 40 business days of purchase."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">While this means scalpers may soon be able to legitimately list their pre-orders for sale across parts of the world where the console <em>will</em> release on June 5, fans may be able to continue to fight scalpers across the U.S. and Canada right up until those countries have a shipping date.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/switch-2-release-date-confirmed-during-nintendo-direct"><u>Nintendo Switch 2 arrives on June 5, 2025</u></a>, with prices starting at $449.99, but the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-delays-switch-2-pre-order-date-in-the-us-to-assess-impact-of-trumps-tariffs"><u>Nintendo Switch 2 pre-order</u></a> was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-delays-switch-2-pre-order-date-in-the-us-to-assess-impact-of-trumps-tariffs"><u>delayed in the United States after import tariffs enacted by President Trump sent financial markets spiraling</u></a>. Just a few days later, the issue spread across the border, with <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-tariff-pre-order-delay-hits-canada-too"><u>Nintendo Canada also confirming pre-orders would now be delayed there</u></a>, too.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The tariff uncertainty and greedy scalpers have left <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-fans-fear-impact-of-tariffs-on-switch-2-price-i-shouldnt-as-an-average-person-be-priced-out-of-this"><u>some Nintendo fans concerned they may be priced out of the next-generation</u></a> if the company goes even higher than the already controversial prices for the Switch 2 and its games, such as the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-world-costs-80-30-cheaper-if-you-buy-it-bundled-with-the-nintendo-switch-2"><u>$79.99</u></a> Mario Kart World.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Missed the Nintendo Direct presentation? Worry not — you can catch up on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-direct-everything-announced"><u>everything shown at the Nintendo Direct</u></a> right here, and here's a handy list for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/nintendo-switch-2/Switch_2_Games_List_-_Release_Date,_Price,_and_Exclusives"><u>every game confirmed for Nintendo Switch 2</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter, critic, columnist, and consultant. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>