<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:14:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hero to Net Zero – What is Phil Spencer’s legacy at Xbox?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/24/hero-to-net-zero-what-is-phil-spencers-legacy-at-xbox/</link>
            <guid>1444606</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>A little over five years ago, on the eve of the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-series-x">Xbox Series X|S</a> launch, Phil Spencer might have been heralded as the console brand’s saviour, but as <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/20/phil-spencer-retires-from-xbox-with-coreai-exec-asha-sharma-taking-over-as-microsoft-gaming-ceo/">he retires from the head of Microsoft’s gaming with almost immediate effect</a>, the picture of his time is distinctly less rosy.</p>
<p>The Xbox brand was in complete disarray in 2014. After gaining a foothold with the original Xbox and then stealing the early lead with the Xbox 360 (and paying the price with the Red Ring of Death debacle), Xbox began to shift its focus under Don Mattrick’s leadership. The Xbox 360 lineup felt played out by the end of the generation – each year inevitably leaned on a Halo or Gears of War game alongside a Forza – and a lot of emphasis was being placed on <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/kinect">Kinect,</a> to challenge the Wii for family gaming. And when the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2013/05/22/xbox-one-reveal-how-microsoft-is-getting-its-message-wrong/">Kinect was then bundled in with the Xbox One</a>, making it both more expensive and less powerful than the PS4? And announced with so much emphasis being put on TV connectivity and with a tone-deaf message about always online DRM? It practically <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kWSIFh8ICaA">handed the upcoming generation to PlayStation</a>.</p>
<p>Having already filled in after Mattrick’s sudden departure, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2014/03/31/phil-spencer-fills-the-spot-of-head-of-xbox-at-microsoft/">Phil Spencer was promoted to lead all things Xbox in March 2014</a>, and his immediate actions were decisive. Kinect was cut out of the Xbox One box, the price was cut by $100, and being able to point to being a keen gamer himself, and not just another Microsoft suit, helped to build a little confidence in the platform’s future once more.</p>
<div id="attachment_469179"><p id="caption-attachment-469179">Phil Spencer at Gamescom 2015 –&nbsp;Image credit: Microsoft</p></div>
<p>Through the rest of the Xbox One generation, Phil Spencer’s appearances at E3 were a mixture of pondering what game dev-branded tee he would be wearing under his jacket, expected sequels and ports, and some truly transformational announcements. In 2015 it was backward compatibility for select Xbox 360 and (eventually) Xbox games, which helped to preserve ties to gaming history, when the only similar option on PS4 was for a full-blown port and remaster. 2016 saw Xbox games coming to Windows at the same time, first with Quantum Break and Forza Horizon 3, and eventually broadening to day-and-date launches on Steam. The Xbox One X in 2017 was Microsoft setting the story straight on hardware design, delivering the undisputed most-powerful console of the generation, shifting back to a more optimal architecture and paving the way for the future. But it was Xbox Game Pass and flurries of game studio acquisitions that started to herald the future of Microsoft’s gaming business.</p>

<p>Xbox Game Pass also launched in 2017, right at the point that it felt like a Netflix-like model would be relatively positive for the all the media we consume. The deal got even better a year later, as first party games would now come to Game Pass day and date, it came to PC in 2019, and then Project xCloud meant that you could play many of these games wherever you were, and take your progress between platforms. It sounded like a gaming utopia, even if it maybe wasn’t quite as smooth as you’d hope.</p>

<p>Having relied far too heavily on their tried and true franchises (and with some notable game cancellations and studio closures) the Xbox exclusives cupboard was feeling pretty bare. 2018 was the swing back in the other direction, Microsoft acquiring Compulsion Games, Ninja Theory, Obsidian, Playground Games, Undead Labs and inXile, and founding The Initiative. Some were long-time partners, other were still working on cross-platform games when they were acquired, and with a new generation on the horizon, it bode well for what was to come, even if a lot of PlayStation gamers felt put out by the prospect of their games now being exclusives… but let’s come back to that.</p>
<p>With the reveal of the Xbox Series X, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2019/12/13/xbox-series-x-reveal-project-scarlett-design-horizontal-tower-next-gen-ps5-rival/">a black obelisk of a design</a> coming alongside the first embers of the broadened Xbox Game Studios promising stunning visuals in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/hellblade-senuas-saga">Hellblade: Senua’s Saga</a>, not to mention the long-awaited <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/halo-infinite">Halo Infinite</a>, all backed by backward compatibility and Xbox Game Pass as a still tempting price point, there was cause to believe that Xbox could truly compete with Sony once again. OK, so the name wasn’t particularly great, following on from the Xbox One X, but on paper it looked good.</p>

<p>But the console name wasn’t the last befuddling thing for the Xbox Series X. For one thing, there was eventually the Xbox Series S, which <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/09/09/xbox-series-s-4-tflops-series-x-specs-more-powerful/">mystifyingly features less RAM than the Xbox One X</a>, meaning it couldn’t match the outgoing hardware and would soon become the butt of every game performance comparison video. Then there was the chopping and changing of the Optimized for Series X logo, Smart Delivery as a concept, and the commitment to cross-gen games from Microsoft studios that went out the window soon. Cross-gen support was pretty opaque over on PlayStation too, but this could have been a win for Microsoft, and it was fumbled.</p>
<p>That’s far from the only thing that now feels like a fumble. With <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2020/08/11/halo-infinite-delayed-to-2021-xbox-series-x-release-date/">Halo Infinite’s much-hated reveal seeing it delayed</a>, leaving just <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/01/27/the-medium-review-xbox-series-x-pc/">The Medium’s</a> split-screen horror and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/04/14/gears-5-hivebusters-dlc-you-should-play-it-needs-a-standalone-release/">Gears 5 Hivebusters DLC</a> to really act as launch window exclusives, it layered significance to the acquisition of Bethesda. Xbox needed something big to tip the tables, and Bethesda had seemingly been keen for a buyer. Oh sure, they still had to deliver timed exclusive games <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/09/13/deathloop-review-ps5-pc/">Deathloop</a> and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/03/21/ghostwire-tokyo-review-ps5/">Ghostwire: Tokyo</a> to PlayStation, but <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/starfield">Starfield</a> as an Xbox exclusive felt fairly natural given previous closeness.</p>

<p>But that didn’t help fill Xbox’s release schedule or make for huge hits. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/08/20/halo-infinite-campaign-co-op-delayed-forge-mode-release-date-announcement-soon/">Halo Infinite had a troubled launch</a>, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/01/25/forza-motorsport-is-now-only-coming-2023-seemingly-delayed-from-spring-release-window/">Forza Motorsport taking an age</a>, Redfall was a straight-up flop, Starfield drew a collective shrug. The main highlights (outside of the ever-reliable Forza Horizon 5) were the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/02/05/hi-fi-rush-review/">shadow-dropped Hi-Fi Rush</a> and the clutch of smaller projects that Obsidian was able to release.</p>
<p>Was it desperation that led Microsoft down the path to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/01/18/microsoft-activision-what-does-acquisition-mean-for-gamers-playstation-xbox-game-pass-call-of-duty-exclusive/">acquire Activision Blizzard</a>? This eye-watering purchase is the real tipping point. Since closing the deal in 2023, the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/06/22/microsoft-announces-xbox-series-x-xbox-game-pass-price-hikes-for-july-august/">Xbox Series X|S has rapidly increased in price faster</a> than PlayStation 5, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/01/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-2025-price-increase-ubisoft-fortnite-crew/">Xbox Game Pass has ballooned both in cost and the bundled subscriptions</a> to justify this, and <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/10/xbox-game-pass-gets-price-increases-drops-day-one-games-on-standard-tier/">the rules on ‘day one’ games changed</a> since <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/28/the-game-pass-app-has-confirmed-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-for-day-one/">Call of Duty’s addition to the service</a>. Not only that, but the whole reason for Xbox as a console manufacturer has been called into question as Microsoft has chosen to bring its games to PlayStation. It’s done so in the most consistently inconsistent fashion, as well. Some games are simultaneous launches, others are clearly defined timed exclusives, and others more nebulous.</p>
<div id="attachment_469180"><p id="caption-attachment-469180">The ‘This is an Xbox’ marketing campaign</p></div>
<p>But if you want to play all these games on day one? Well, you can always find them on Xbox. But what even is an Xbox anymore? The marketing over the last couple of years would want you to know that everything’s an Xbox. There’s your consoles, of course, but there’s also Windows PCs, that ROG Xbox Ally handheld now (which is a handheld PC more than an Xbox console), or just streaming to your TV or phone. So… you don’t need to buy an Xbox anymore. Is that the message? Given how dominant PlayStation 5 has been and the massively strong start for the Switch 2, that’s seemingly what the gaming populace has taken away from this all.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for Phil Spencer, that now feels like his true legacy for Xbox, the brand being continually diluted. He was once its saviour, convincing Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella to stay the course through the Xbox One era, but when six years of rebuilding didn’t lead to early success in the following generation, cheques were signed to buy huge third-party publishers, shifting the expectations for what Xbox could deliver to Microsoft’s bottom line. It’s hard to say that Xbox is in a worse position now than when Spencer took over, when there’s more invested in it than ever and Microsoft’s studios have started to release great and varied games again, but the tone and what people expect from Xbox has changed. It now feels like less of a rival to PlayStation, and more like a publisher with consoles on the side.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/24/hero-to-net-zero-what-is-phil-spencers-legacy-at-xbox/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cicadamata" is the most exciting FPS I've played in years - come try the demo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cicadamata-is-the-most-exciting-fps-ive-played-in-years-come-try-the-demo</link>
            <guid>1444603</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>become one with joyeuse, until you are no longer you</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_g6CkVyg.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_g6CkVyg.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_g6CkVyg.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_g6CkVyg.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_g6CkVyg.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_g6CkVyg.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_g6CkVyg.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_g6CkVyg.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_g6CkVyg.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>✿ flowergarden</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Let me slash the tendons of that strutting headline with some immediate caveats. Most obviously, you will not like Cicamadata” if you have an overpowering hatred of feisty punctuation in game titles. You will not like it if you're averse to abstract and ostentatiously computerised, 'product design' art direction that is somehow both bright and foggy, crisp and distorted.</p>
<p>You won’t like it if you really dislike artisanal glitches and general HUD palaver – cockroach text scuttling across the view; boxy white velocity lines; an oversized Doomguy-style character model to indicate health; damage and state changes that cause the screen to blink and reset, as though you’d jolted a cable.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
You may be especially unkeen on Cicamadata” if you try to play the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4257090/CICADAMATA_Demo_Disc/?curator_clanid=45851876">Steam demo</a> on a Latitude 5320 Dell i5-1145G7 with 16 GB of RAM and integrated graphics, like my work laptop. The demo crashed my laptop three times before I grudgingly shuffled over to my review PC, though it ran comfortably enough during the tutorials.
</p>
<p>
Now that the rhetorical ankle-slicing is over, let us bask in the glow of what is not only my favourite FPS demo of recent times but also, one of the few demos I’ve played that conjures the same urge to replay and squeeze out every last drop of blood that I once felt for magazine cover disc demos in the 1990s. 
</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="CICADAMATA&quot; Demo Disc + february 23rd" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QjQdp4Gwix8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>CICADAMATA" Demo Disc + february 23rd</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QjQdp4Gwix8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QjQdp4Gwix8?autoplay=1" title="CICADAMATA&quot; Demo Disc + february 23rd">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QjQdp4Gwix8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>
Inasmuch as the writing spells anything out for sure, Cicamadata” casts you as a wayward soul stuffed into the carapace of a super-mobile bunny bot, equipped with what may be either a three-pellet, flip-to-reload shotgun or some kind of grieving, triumphant demigod – as the Steam page puts it, “i am joyeuse. i am not the weapon that failed. i have given everything to masters who forgot my name." 
</p><p>
You’re dropshipped into a bunch of maps that look like enormous, ethereal circuit boards, some floating in the sky, others half-underwater, some encased in ice, others covered in plastic vegetation. Your job is to gather a bunch of CORES and get to the EXIT. Red things are bad things that need to be shot, jumped on, or slammed into. You’ve got a triple-jump and a forward dash you can perform in the air - a dash that will carry you clean past the platform you’re aiming at, until you develop your rhythm. 
</p>
<p>
Save for one corridor affair that teaches you to attack certain foes in certain ways, the demo levels are airy, open-ended creations with secrets above and below. But when you are in full flight, picking off enemy crabs and gun turrets in a jumble of cybernetic squeals and chirping cooldowns, even the largest of these volumes shrinks to a snowglobe, yours to roll about as you please.</p>
<p>It’s good to be fast: Cicamadata” is a speedrunner’s game with omnipresent leaderboards, though you’re free to bounce and roar around the demo levels for as long as you wish. I had great fun discovering each demo map’s terrain conditions – the ice level is slippy, as you’d expect, and the underwater areas slow your shotgun blasts to shoals, obliging you to lead targets.
</p>
<p>
When I first covered Cicamadata” I compared it to the PS1’s Jumping Flash!, another game with exasperating title punctuation that represents a road not entirely taken for first-person platformers, made up of stratospheric playgrounds navigated by means of a big-footed robot shadow. I’m shocked to discover how much Cicamadata” pays homage to that game, even more so than <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1187870/FORZA_POLPO/">Forza Polpo</a> (which I also love). 
</p><p>
There’s the same basic language of waypoints, the same sense that each level is a compact paradise of things to find and jump on and burst into flecks. But Cicamadata” blends the PS1 game’s rabbity whimsy with a queer and insectile savagery. “Obligations no longer bind you,” promises your handler. “Tear flesh from bone.”
</p>
<p>
The demo is live on Steam from now until March 5th. Go on, hop in. See if you can beat my seventh place leaderboard finish in the ice level. The full game is <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3817250/CICADAMATA/">out later this year</a>.
</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/cicadamata-is-the-most-exciting-fps-ive-played-in-years-come-try-the-demo]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 Director Now Focusing On Movie Adaptation]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-director-now-focusing-on-movie-adaptation/</link>
            <guid>1444597</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new development reveals that the Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Creative Director has been tasked with working on the live-action movie adaptation. </p>



<p>The last details we heard about the Kingdom Come: Deliverance franchise were KCD 2 coming to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/xbox-game-pass-games-for-february-wave-2-features-witcher-3-kingdom-come-deliverance-2-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Xbox Game Pass</a> in February 2026 and the previous title receiving an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-enhanced-update-now-available/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Enhanced Update</a> for current-gen consoles. Now, we have been informed of a live-action movie that will be supervised by the game’s creative director. </p>







<h2 id="h-kcd2-director-daniel-vavra-moving-to-live-action-movie-won-t-work-on-new-warhorse-game">KCD2 Director Daniel Vávra Moving to Live-Action Movie Won’t Work on New Warhorse Game</h2>



<p>The latest update on the shift in focus for Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2’s creative director comes from a new interview with the studio head on <a href="https://cc.cz/daniel-vavra-uz-nepracuje-pro-warhorse-studios-na-nove-hre-misto-toho-pripravuje-hrany-film-kingdom-come/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Czech Crunch</a>. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/warhorse-studios/" id="1409">Warhorse Studios</a> head Martin Frývaldský has stated that creative director Daniel Vávra has a “new role” in the “creation of the Kingdom Come movie”. Frývaldský added that the franchise has already expanded into other media, such as comics, concerts, and tourism; however, a movie has attracted them the most, and there is already a “draft script”. </p>



<p>Frývaldský added that Warhorse can already feel “interest from the film world” in the Kingdom Come: Deliverance movie, with “negotiations already underway”. The studio head added that they aren’t looking to sell the rights and want the film to be what the studio imagines it to be. </p>



<p>Martin Frývaldský added that Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 creative director’s decision to move to the movie was his own. Vávra had already made three games that achieved global success, and he has been “wanting to try something different for a long time.” Getting Kingdom Come to the screen in the “next few years” is a milestone the studio wants to achieve, and that’s Daniel Vávra’s new responsibility. </p>



<p>Warhorse Studio’s head also explained that Daniel Vávra won’t be part of the daily work in the office, but he will still be part of the studio in a “broader sense”. Frývaldský elaborated that Vávra’s new position can be called “transmedia director.” Vávra is no longer involved in a new game from Warhorse Studios. </p>







<p>In other news, Kingdom Come: Deliverance’s director previously stated AI is “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/ai-is-here-and-not-going-kingdom-come-director-admits/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here and it’s not going anywhere</a>“. What are your thoughts on Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Creative Director shifting focus to movie adaptation? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/complete-arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-patch-notes-new-map-condition-buffs-and-nerfs-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders Shrouded Sky update 1.17.0 patch notes</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-director-now-focusing-on-movie-adaptation/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["It's a challenge" - Roblox head of parental advocacy speaks on protecting children amidst increasing safety concerns]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/its-a-challenge-roblox-head-of-parental-advocacy-protecting-children-amidst-increasing-safety-concerns</link>
            <guid>1444594</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/roblox-characters_LHW6U2o.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/roblox-characters_LHW6U2o.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/roblox-characters_LHW6U2o.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/roblox-characters_LHW6U2o.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/roblox-characters_LHW6U2o.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/roblox-characters_LHW6U2o.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/roblox-characters_LHW6U2o.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/roblox-characters_LHW6U2o.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/roblox-characters_LHW6U2o.png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Roblox</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>A new interview with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/roblox">Roblox</a>'s head of parental advocacy Dr. Elizabeth Milovidov has touched on the subject of children's safety on the platform, as well how easy it is for children to be exposed to unregulated content. This, according to Milovidov, is a "challenge".</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/roblox-kids-safety-head-of-parental-advocacy-interview.html?utm_medium=s1&amp;utm_campaign=vulture&amp;utm_source=bluesky">Speaking to Vulture</a>, Milovidov addressed previous reports of children being exposed to content or people that they shouldn't have access to, and stated that they've heard mixed reports from parents on the dangers of Roblox.</p>
<p>"That's kind of the interesting spot right now is that no matter how good my intentions are, sometimes it's hard to beat back against something negative that goes viral," Milovidov said. "A lot of the reports that have come out have been based on things that happened a few years ago, or where moderation teams caught it but, unfortunately, someone took a screenshot; it went out on Instagram and it's game over for us."</p>
<p>When Vulture asked if Milovidov was saying the problem wasn't real, she responded: "I would say that, in general, Roblox is a platform online. The internet is the internet, right? We have to realize that once we give a child any sort of Wi-Fi access, the world is an open place, right? I remember doing digital parenting sessions and telling parents, 'Look, I'm wearing my Apple Watch. Can you believe I can be bullied on my Apple Watch?' You can be bullied in Google Documents. It's not about banning these things. It's about balance and boundaries. Now that we've introduced them, they've seen the water; we can't just say, 'You're never going to go there.'</p><p>When asked if parents and Roblox and the parents of Roblox players had equal responsibility in protecting these children, Milovidov responded with: "Oh, 1,000 percent. Would I say equal? Oh, Nicole, I think you're going to get me in trouble. I would say the company has even more responsibility. But yes, parents are right in there. I think all the tech companies have a responsibility to ensure that they are doing their utmost to make sure the platform is safe. Do I think Roblox is doing that? Yes, I do. I wouldn't be here if I didn't. Do I think there's more to be done? Yes, I do."</p>
<p>Vulture also raised the issue of ease of access, specifically with how easy it was for children to make new accounts and access unregulated, potentially problematic content. To this, Milovidov said: "We're trying to balance the privacy concerns of users and families with trying to wall things down a little bit more. It's a challenge. When I was writing the parent's guide for Instagram, I was also telling parents about finsta -- fake Instagram accounts. I mean, these things exist in almost every setting. The idea, again, is to talk with your children and say, 'Listen, this is our family. These are our expectations on this. This is why I don't want you to do this.'</p>
<p>"I know parents are busy, and I don't want to put the onus on them, which is why I'm trying to make it as simple as possible. Let your child guide you. Ask them what they're doing on Roblox. Ask them, 'Has anything ever happened that made them feel a little icky?'"</p>
<p>In a 2022 UK report - the <a href="https://assets.childrenscommissioner.gov.uk/wpuploads/2022/09/cc-digital-childhoods-a-survey-of-children-and-parents.pdf">UK's Digital childhoods: a survey of children and parents report</a> -  the Children's commissioner for England found among other things that "50 percent of children who saw harmful content reported it, older children and girls are less likely to report harmful content. 40 percent of children who didn't report harmful content told us they didn't report because they felt there was no point in doing so, while only 15 percent felt that the content didn't need to be reported."</p><p>Roblox is currently being sued by a variety of entities on the grounds of children's safety. Only last week, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/business-news/los-angeles-county-sues-roblox-rcna259891">Los Angeles county sued Roblox</a>, alleging it made it easy for adults to target children. <a href="https://www.lawsuit-information-center.com/roblox-sex-abuse-lawsuit.html">Many families are also suing Roblox over similar grounds</a>, these include <a href="https://topclassactions.com/lawsuit-settlements/lawsuit-news/roblox-class-action-lawsuit-sent-to-arbitration-in-kids-data-privacy-case/">class action lawsuits</a>, <a href="https://newschannel9.com/news/local/georgia-attorney-general-investigates-roblox-over-child-exploitation-concerns">a grooming lawsuit in Georgia</a>, and <a href="https://www.uppermichiganssource.com/2025/09/03/accused-assault-dickinson-county-girl-brings-lawsuit-towards-roblox/">one from Dickinson Country, Michigan</a> in which its alleged that an 11-year-old girl was sexually assaulted on the platform.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/its-a-challenge-roblox-head-of-parental-advocacy-protecting-children-amidst-increasing-safety-concerns]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Party Platformer 'King Of Meat' Bites The Dust Before It Could Make It To Switch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/party-platformer-king-of-meat-bites-the-dust-before-it-could-make-it-to-switch</link>
            <guid>1444582</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Ends Meat</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="090485f191f46"><a title="King of Meat" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/090485f191f46/king-of-meat.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Amazon Game Studios</em></figcaption></figure><p>Despite being announced for Switch back in 2024 and even being given an <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/08/co-op-party-platformer-king-of-meat-will-make-the-jump-to-switch-early-next-year">"early 2026" release window</a> last year, Amazon Games and Glowmade have today announced that the party platformer <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/king_of_meat">King of Meat</a> will be shutting up shop before it could make the jump to Nintendo systems.</p>
<p>While the game has now been removed from all storefronts to prevent any new purchases, the King of Meat servers will be sticking around on all currently available platforms (Steam, Xbox Series and PS5) until <strong>9th April</strong>, so those with the game already downloaded still have a few weeks to make the most.</p><div><figure data-videoid="8i2vvu-qeBQ" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8i2vvu-qeBQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt8i2vvu-qeBQ" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8i2vvu-qeBQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8i2vvu-qeBQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed4c3af8ghntmo&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Between now and the server's close date, all those who purchased the game are entitled to a full refund.</p>
<p>"Despite the creativity and innovation Glowmade brought to King of Meat, the game has unfortunately not found the audience we hoped for," a new message on the <a href="https://www.kingofmeat.com/en-us">King of Meat website</a> reads. "As a result, we have made the difficult decision to conclude our investment in the game, and King of Meat's servers will close on April 9, 2026. Players will be able to access and play all existing content until then, so we encourage you to enjoy your remaining time in the game with your fellow Contenders."</p>
<p>After clarifying refund availability, the message concludes with the following thank-you note:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We want to sincerely thank every player who supported King of Meat and the wonderful community that formed around it. Your enthusiasm, imagination, and feedback have meant the world to us and to the team at Glowmade. We're grateful for Glowmade’ s partnership and passion throughout this journey and wish them continued success in the future.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Live service closures have come thick and fast in recent years, but it's still a shame that we never got to see this one materialise on Switch, especially after it cropped up in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/nintendo-direct-march-2025-every-announcement-game-reveal-trailer">March 2025 Nintendo Direct</a>. Here's hoping that Glowmade's next project has the legs to last a little longer.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:169643 @ 1771934637 -->
<p><em>Did you ever check out KoM on other platforms? Were you hoping to see it materialise on Switch? Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://www.kingofmeat.com/en-us" rel="noopener" href="https://www.kingofmeat.com/en-us">kingofmeat.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-info/79fbe1bb2da6e687d36ba79a2e8a6259 @ 1771931705 --></div></article><div><p>Jim came to Nintendo Life in 2022 and, despite his insistence that The Minish Cap is the best Zelda game and his unwavering love for the Star Wars prequels (yes, really), he has continued to write news and features on the site ever since.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/JimNorman"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jimnormann.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('JimNorman');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/party-platformer-king-of-meat-bites-the-dust-before-it-could-make-it-to-switch]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance Creator Will Now Focus on Bringing the IP to the Big (or Small) Screen Rather Than Making a Third Game]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-creator-focus-movie-tv-live-action/</link>
            <guid>1444579</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Website CzechCrunch has <a href="https://cc.cz/daniel-vavra-uz-nepracuje-pro-warhorse-studios-na-nove-hre-misto-toho-pripravuje-hrany-film-kingdom-come/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">revealed</a> that <strong>Kingdom Come: Deliverance</strong> creator <strong>Daniel Vávra</strong>, who co-founded <strong>Warhorse Studios</strong> and served as the Game Director and Lead Writer for the franchise's two <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">released installments</a>, will focus on bringing the IP to cinema or television rather than working on a third entry.</p>



<p>The news was shared by Warhorse CEO <strong>Martin Frývaldský</strong>, who explained:</p>



<p><em>Dan has a new role. That's the creation of the Kingdom Come movie. We have been moving the Kingdom Come brand away from video games for some time now. So far, we have been in comics, concerts, and tourism, but the film has attracted us the most. That is why Dan and I are working on getting it onto the screen or the big screen. There is also a draft script. We feel the interest from the film world, negotiations are already underway. We don't just want to sell the rights, we want the film to be what we imagine it to be. </em></p>



<p>However, Frývaldský also clarified that this isn't a breakup with Warhorse for Vávra:</p>



<p><em>I'm sure people will wonder if this is some kind of breakup with Warhorse. No, on the contrary, Dan himself wanted to move on. He made three games that were a global success, he has been wanting to try something different for a long time. Getting Kingdom Come to the screen or the screen in the next few years is another milestone that we want to achieve, and that is Dan's new role. You won't see him in the office every day anymore, but in a broader sense, he is still part of Warhorse.</em></p>



<p><em>We would have to be blind if we didn't realize how much our brand has grown. In fact, Dan Vávra's new position could be called transmedia director. In any case, we see the film as a complement to our game creation, which can be extremely successful in its own right.</em></p>



<p>In the interview, Frývaldský even revealed that Warhorse <strong>had already been approached about adapting Kingdom Come: Deliverance after the first game</strong>. However, the arrival of COVID meant discussions died down for a few years. Now, following the amazing success of the new game (<strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii-5-million-units-sold/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">over five million units sold</a></strong>), the studio is more interested than ever in pursuing this venue.</p>



<p>It would be just the latest in an ever-growing list of game adaptations for cinema or TV. Historically, they haven't fared well, but that is slowly changing with the likes of <strong>The Last of Us</strong>, <strong>Super Mario</strong>, <strong>Fallout</strong>, and <strong>Sonic</strong>, to name a few.</p>



<p>As for Daniel Vávra, we're sure that even in his new position, he'll continue to make controversial comments on social media, like <a href="https://wccftech.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-director-criticized-the-outer-worlds-2-obsidian-hasnt-innovated-since-fallout-new-vegas/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">when he criticized <strong>Obsidian</strong> for not making an innovative game since <strong>Fallout: New Vegas</strong></a>. </p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-creator-focus-movie-tv-live-action/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders Surgeon Deck—How To Claim & All Rewards, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-surgeon-deck-how-to-claim-all-rewards-explained/</link>
            <guid>1444573</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>ARC Raiders neglects the ever-popular battle passes in favor of Raider Decks, which offer pages of rewards for you to claim, all in exchange for Cred. From usable items to cosmetics and currency, they’re quite popular amongst the player base, and Shrouded Sky has finally added a new one—the Surgeon Deck.</p>







<p>However, you’ll need to claim it before you can start unlocking the brand new rewards, but thankfully, it’s easier than ever. If you’re interested in the new Surgeon Raider Deck in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/arc-raiders/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/games/arc-raiders/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders</a>, here’s how to claim it, as well as every reward it has on offer.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-claim-the-surgeon-deck-in-arc-raiders">How To Claim The Surgeon Deck In ARC Raiders</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Free as a bird. Image by Insider Gaming.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>To claim the Surgeon Deck in ARC Raiders, all you have to do is head on over to the Decks tab and purchase it for free. </strong></p>



<p>Despite the Decks showcasing Raider Tokens as the pricing, not a single one has released that isn’t free yet, with all three of them being readily available for all to claim. It’s a consumer-friendly approach by Embark Studios, and long may it continue. </p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming:</strong> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-weather-monitor-system-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-weather-monitor-system-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/">Weather Monitor System Project Guide</a></li>
</ul>



<p>That being said, you’ll need Cred to unlock these rewards, but luckily for you, they’re easy to earn. The fastest way to earn them is by completing Feats, which are simple in-game tasks to complete during raids. </p>



<h2 id="h-all-rewards-from-the-surgeon-deck-in-arc-raiders">All Rewards From The Surgeon Deck In ARC Raiders</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Solid Outfit. Image by Insider Gaming.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Overall, there are 25 rewards to claim from the Surgeon Deck in ARC Raiders, totalling 1,070 Cred. </strong></p>



<p>Based on the theme, you can expect a lot of medical supplies in the Surgeon Deck, although there is a healthy amount of Raider Tokens to claim, too. The star of the show, however, is easily the suite of cosmetics on offer, with the new Surgeon outfit getting a variety of colours.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming:</strong> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hurricane-map-condition-in-arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-explained/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/hurricane-map-condition-in-arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hurricane Map Condition, Explained</a></li>
</ul>



<p>For all rewards, check out the table below:</p>







<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Surgeon Deck Reward</th><th data-align="center">Surgeon Deck Reward Cred Cost</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Surgeon Outfit (Red)</td><td data-align="center">30</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">First Aid Kit Backpack Attachment</td><td data-align="center">10</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bone Saw Backpack Charm</td><td data-align="center">10</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x5 Seeker Grenade</td><td data-align="center">20</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x5 Sterilized Bandage</td><td data-align="center">20</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x50 Raider Tokens</td><td data-align="center">20</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Paramedic Backpack</td><td data-align="center">50</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Face 18</td><td data-align="center">50</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Surgeon Outfit Variant</td><td data-align="center">50</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x5 Surge Shield Recharger</td><td data-align="center">30</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x50 Raider Tokens</td><td data-align="center">30</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Surgeon Outfit Variant</td><td data-align="center">40</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Tactical MK. 2 Augment</td><td data-align="center">30</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Surgeon Outfit Colour (Cyan)</td><td data-align="center">50</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Surgeon Outfit Variant Colour (Red)</td><td data-align="center">70</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x5 Smoke Grenade</td><td data-align="center">30</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x3 Defibrillator</td><td data-align="center">30</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x50 Raider Tokens</td><td data-align="center">30</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Surgeon Hat Scrappy Outfit</td><td data-align="center">90</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Raider Hatch Key</td><td data-align="center">50</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x3 Vita Shot</td><td data-align="center">50</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x50 Raider Tokens</td><td data-align="center">40</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Tactical MK. 3 (Revival) Augment</td><td data-align="center">50</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">x50 Raider Tokens</td><td data-align="center">40</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Full Beard Facial Hair</td><td data-align="center">150</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr>



<p>What are your thoughts on the Shrouded Sky update? Share your thoughts in the official <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" id="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<p>For more ARC Raiders, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/7-secret-loot-spots-you-need-to-know-in-arc-raiders/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/7-secret-loot-spots-you-need-to-know-in-arc-raiders/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the 7 secret loot spots you need to know about</a>, as well as the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-event-tracker-every-map-condition-schedule/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-event-tracker-every-map-condition-schedule/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Map Condition tracker</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-surgeon-deck-how-to-claim-all-rewards-explained/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Simpsons: Hit & Run and Prototype Developer Radical Entertainment Appears to Have Returned, and Fans Are Hyped for Fresh Remakes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-simpsons-hit-run-and-prototype-developer-radical-entertainment-appears-to-have-returned-and-fans-are-hyped-for-fresh-remakes</link>
            <guid>1444570</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">You only get what you give.&nbsp;</h2></div><div><section data-cy="article-content" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">The studio responsible for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-simpsons-hit-run">The Simpsons: Hit &amp; Run</a> and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/prototype"><u>Prototype</u></a>, Radical Entertainment, appears to be back under a new name: New Radical Games.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">An amalgamation of "Radical Entertainment plus Hothead Games," the studio's new <a href="https://www.newradical.ca/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>website</u></a> says, "it all started with Radical Entertainment back in 1991. Fast forward to 2025 and we have amassed invaluable experience along the way. We know how to capture the essence of world-class intellectual properties, and deliver licensed games that delight fans everywhere."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Vancouver-based Radical was bought by Activision in 2008, and was shuttered little more than five years later after living out its final years as a Destiny support studio. Hothead — also based in Vancouver — went bankrupt in 2024. The new studio is led by CEO Ian Wilkinson, who co-founded Radical, and COO Tim Bennison, who served as chief operating officer at Capcom's Vancouver studio and had previously worked at Radical, too, as executive producer and VP technology.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">News of the new studio from the people who brought us games like Prototype, Scarface: The World Is Yours, and The Simpsons: Hit &amp; Run has clearly excited fans, with many now crossing their fingers that the new outfit could be set on bringing those dormant IPs back to life.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"I LITERALLY JUST TALKED ABOUT THIS IN A THREAD ABOUT WHAT DEV STUDIOS WE WOULD REVIVE IF WE WERE RICH A COUPLE OF DAYS AGO!! HOLY S***!! I WILLED THIS INTO EXISTENCE!! I'M A GOD!!" <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TwoBestFriendsPlay/comments/1rcru49/comment/o70k5fc/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>exclaimed</u></a> one very excitable fan.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"A few months ago, rumors started going around about a Prototype remaster. Today, Radical games has seemingly relaunched and their website prominently displays their older titles including Prototype and Simpsons Hit &amp; Run," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1rcqler/radical_entertainment_just_relaunched_their/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>teased</u></a> another.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Late last year, IGN reported that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/prototype-remaster-may-be-on-the-way-after-new-credits-were-quietly-added-to-the-steam-version"><u>fans thought they'd uncovered proof that 2009 action game Prototype could be getting a new lease of life</u></a>. While the game has mostly remained dormant on Steam since its release 16 years ago, eagle-eyed fans spotted a flurry of updates behind the scenes via SteamDB, as well as a revealing datamine effort that has discovered a mysterious change to the game's credits that adds in remaster studio, Iron Galaxy, and a curious reference to Ubisoft Connect.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That's not all, though. "So one of the OG modders for the game data mined the recent update and has found a lot of interesting things," a fan explained on the game's subreddit. "For Prototype 1, they have added some test maps and quite a few new names in the credits. There might be some hope for a remaster after all."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This isn't, of course, evidence that a remaster is <em>actually</em> happening — right now, we're purely going on vibes and crossed fingers — but New Radical must have been established to work on <em>something</em>, so keep those fingers crossed!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Calls for an official Simpsons: Hit and Run remake have similarly cropped up from time to time in the 20+ years since the original’s release, but it seems an unlikely project. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/matt-selman-simpsons-hit-and-run-remake"><u>In 2021 we spoke to Simpsons writer Matt Selman</u></a> who said that while he "would love to see a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/11/12/best-games-that-deserve-sequels"><u>remastered version of [Simpsons Hit &amp; Run]</u></a>", it would be "a complicated corporate octopus to try to make that happen."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For more, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-best-worst-and-weirdest-simpsons-games"><u>find out exactly where we placed The Simpsons: Hit &amp; Run in our rundown of the best, worst, and weirdest Simpsons games</u></a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Vikki Blake is a reporter for IGN, as well as a critic, columnist, and consultant with 15+ years experience working with some of the world's biggest gaming sites and publications. She's also a Guardian, Spartan, Silent Hillian, Legend, and perpetually High Chaos. Find her at </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/vixx.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>BlueSky</em></a><em>.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="title3"><svg data-cy="icon-logo" viewBox="0 0 76 24" title="IGN"><title>IGN Logo</title><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M5.38 7.65a7.85 7.85 0 0 1 2.26-2.26c.13-1.18.31-2.26.52-3.21a10.605 10.605 0 0 0-6 6c.95-.22 2.03-.39 3.21-.52M16.34 5.36v.02c.9.59 1.67 1.37 2.27 2.27 1.18.13 2.26.31 3.21.52a10.627 10.627 0 0 0-6.02-6.01c.22.95.4 2.02.54 3.2M7.64 18.62c-.9-.59-1.67-1.37-2.27-2.27h-.03c-1.19-.14-2.26-.32-3.19-.54 1.07 2.75 3.26 4.95 6.01 6.02-.22-.95-.39-2.03-.52-3.21M18.64 16.35h-.03c-.59.9-1.37 1.67-2.27 2.27v.03c-.14 1.17-.32 2.25-.54 3.19a10.59 10.59 0 0 0 6.03-6.03c-.94.22-2 .4-3.19.54M10.04 0h3.9c.85 1.85 1.2 4.59 1.3 5.52.04.22.06.43.06.63L12 9.11 8.7 6.15c0-.17.02-.35.05-.55.1-.95.43-3.75 1.29-5.61M8.7 17.83c0 .17.02.35.05.55.1.95.43 3.75 1.29 5.61h3.9c.85-1.84 1.2-4.59 1.3-5.52.04-.22.06-.43.06-.64L12 14.87l-3.3 2.96ZM6.16 8.68c-.17 0-.35.02-.55.05-.95.12-3.75.45-5.61 1.31v3.9c1.84.85 4.59 1.19 5.52 1.3.22.04.43.06.64.06L9.11 12 6.16 8.7ZM24 10.02c-1.86-.86-4.66-1.19-5.61-1.29-.2-.03-.38-.05-.55-.05l-2.96 3.3 2.96 3.3c.2 0 .41-.02.64-.06.93-.11 3.68-.45 5.52-1.3v-3.9Z"></path><path fill="currentColor" stroke="none" d="M42.83 13.9V10h10.45c1.06 0 1.93.86 1.93 1.92v4.63c0 2.38-1.91 4.36-4.33 4.36h-6.69c-4.96 0-8.97-4-8.97-8.94s4.04-8.95 8.98-8.95h10.36v4.11H44.2c-2.67 0-4.86 2.17-4.86 4.84s2.16 4.83 4.86 4.83h6.91v-2.91h-8.27ZM33.86 3h-4.07v16.02c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.15V3M74.37 3.01h-2.18v13.81s0 .08-.03.11a.29.29 0 0 1-.24.14c-.09 0-.16-.04-.25-.15L64.83 4.93a4.347 4.347 0 0 0-3.72-2.11h-.07c-2.39 0-4.32 1.93-4.32 4.32v11.88c0 1.05.86 1.91 1.91 1.91h2.17V7.14s.02-.09.04-.13a.29.29 0 0 1 .24-.14c.09 0 .18.03.24.14l6.88 12.07c.76 1.27 2.12 2.05 3.69 2.05h.07c2.39 0 4.32-1.93 4.32-4.32V4.92c0-1.05-.85-1.91-1.91-1.91"></path></svg>Recommends</h3></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-simpsons-hit-run-and-prototype-developer-radical-entertainment-appears-to-have-returned-and-fans-are-hyped-for-fresh-remakes]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['This Ain't It': Activision Issues Rare Denial of Standalone Call of Duty Zombies Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/this-aint-it-activision-issues-rare-denial-of-standalone-call-of-duty-zombies-report</link>
            <guid>1444567</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Call of Duty publisher Activision has issued a rare, if brief, comment to seemingly deny a claim it planned to launch a standalone Zombies game. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Earlier this week, Call of Duty leaker <a href="https://x.com/TheGhostOfHope/status/2025670143184101532" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TheGhostofHope</a> stated on social media that Activision was prepping two separate Call of Duty games for the launch of Microsoft's next-gen Xbox console (currently <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/next-generation-xbox-could-launch-in-2027-hints-amd">expected to launch in 2027 at the earliest</a>). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The claim described these two launches as "a traditional Call of Duty multiplayer and a standalone Zombies title presumably developed by Treyarch," and likened their release to when "Infinite Warfare and Modern Warfare Remastered where [sic] both released together."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">That leak was then picked up by gaming blog Dexerto, to which Activision has now responded using its official Call of Duty social media account: "The rumor factory working overtime," Activision <a href="https://x.com/CallofDuty/status/2026038116364992596" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wrote</a>. "This ain't it."</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Activision typically does not respond to rumors or speculation, making this intervention notable. That said, the vague nature of the denial makes it unclear exactly which parts of the original claim Activision is now saying are untrue, or whether some element of this claim was true until plans ultimately changed. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">On social media, Call of Duty's response comes specifically in reply to a thread of tweets discussing the standalone Zombies title, and the claim it was being prepped as a launch title for Microsoft's next console.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The original rumor suggested that Microsoft's shifting release plans for its next Xbox hardware had meant that Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 4, the franchise's most anticipated upcoming release, would no longer be a launch title for the next-gen Xbox, as apparently had been planned. While not yet officially confirmed, Modern Warfare 4 is expected by fans to be this year's Call of Duty entry — but there's absolutely no suggestion that Microsoft is planning to launch new consoles this year. </p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><span data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><div data-cy="slideshow-preview"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The Best Call of Duty Campaigns</h3></div></span></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Still, some kind of shakeup to Call of Duty's forthcoming release schedule is expected, following Activision's recent pledge to make <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-will-no-longer-do-back-to-back-releases-of-modern-warfare-or-black-ops-games"><u>significant changes</u></a> to the franchise following the underperformance of Black Ops 7. The publisher has said it will never release back to back games in the same sub-brand (Modern Warfare, Black Ops) again, meaning it will likely need to come up with other options if it continues with an annual release schedule.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As for Microsoft's plans for new consoles, the company has confirmed it has fresh hardware in the works on several occaisons. In 2024, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xbox-moving-full-speed-ahead-on-next-gen-console">former Xbox president Sarah Bond said</a> Microsoft was "moving full speed ahead on our next generation hardware, focused on delivering the biggest technological leap ever in a generation." A year later, the company publicly <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/microsoft-confirms-first-party-next-generation-xbox-consoles-announces-deal-with-amd-and-promises-full-backwards-compatibility-with-your-existing-xbox-library"><u>confirmed its partnership with AMD on its next-generation Xbox project</u></a>. But a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/next-gen-xbox-2027-launch-reportedly-best-case-scenario-following-amd-hint-that-microsoft-may-ship-new-hardware-next-year">recent report suggested that 2027 was now a conservative estimate for the company's new hardware</a> — which instead could now arrive later. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sony-reportedly-considering-pushing-back-ps6-release-to-2028-or-even-2029-amid-ai-fueled-chip-crisis">Sony is also reportedly considering delaying the launch of PlayStation 6 to 2028, or potentially even later</a>, due to the ongoing AI-fueled chip crisis.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/this-aint-it-activision-issues-rare-denial-of-standalone-call-of-duty-zombies-report]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Reveals 1025 Logos for 30th Anniversary Featuring Every Single Species — and Here's How You Can 'Catch' One]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-reveals-1025-logos-for-30th-anniversary-featuring-every-single-species-and-heres-how-you-can-catch-one</link>
            <guid>1444561</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle" data-autopogo="true"><p data-cy="paragraph">Pokémon celebrates its 30th birthday this week and, as part of the celebrations, the brand has just revealed an astonishing 1025 variations of its 30th anniversary logo. Each design features a different creature peeking out of a Pokéball — and every single Pokémon species gets its moment to shine.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The official Japanese Pokémon account on X/Twitter is currently running a social media campaign. If you click the image in the post below and retweet it, you will receive one of the logos. Pokémon hunting Twitter users have until March 9 to 'catch' their Pokémon logo. </p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p data-cy="paragraph" lang="ja" dir="ltr">大阪なんば駅 <a href="https://t.co/2ghHZc4192" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/2ghHZc4192</a></p>— adi (@redlaysdedo) <a href="https://twitter.com/redlaysdedo/status/2025828518828155347?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">February 23, 2026</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The logos can also be hunted down in five major cities across Japan. Large digital signboards that cycle through all the logos can be found in prominent locations, including Tokyo’s Shinjuku Station and Osaka’s Namba Station. The signboards feature all of the different logos arranged in a color spectrum on a white background.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The colors of each logo match the colors and elements of their respective Pokémon. Of course, well-known Pokémon like Pikachu, Charizard and Bulbasaur have their own logos, but newer and more obscure Pokémon are also being shown love, such as Paradox Pokémon Iron Bundle and the matcha-themed Poltchageist. Pokemon fansite Serebii.net has been <a href="https://www.serebii.net/pokemon30/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>cataloging the logo variations</u></a> with help from the community. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Various releases to mark three decades of the game, anime and TCG franchise are also on the way. The original FireRed and LeafGreen are <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-fans-are-worried-firered-and-leafgreen-wont-be-compatible-with-pokemon-home-making-the-pokedex-impossible-to-finish"><u>getting rereleased </u></a>on Nintendo Switch on February 27th (the date on which the games were first launched in Japan back in 1996) — though there has been <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/we-thought-it-would-be-fun-nintendo-has-a-whole-faq-on-why-its-selling-pokmon-firered-and-leafgreen-separately-for-20-each">some controversy over their launch method</a> and pricing, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-fans-are-worried-firered-and-leafgreen-wont-be-compatible-with-pokemon-home-making-the-pokedex-impossible-to-finish">plus Pokémon Home compatibility</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Stateside, this month’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/time-magazine-is-celebrating-pokmons-30th-anniversary-with-three-exclusive-covers"><u>TIME Magazine has a special feature </u></a>on Pokémon, complete with different cover variations. The Pokémon Trading Card Game is getting the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-first-partner-illustration-collection-explainer"><u>First Partner Illustration Collection - Series 1</u></a>, out on March 20th. These nostalgic cards celebrate the bond between the Trainer and their starter Pokémon. TCG will also be getting Perfect Order on March 27, a new expansion focusing on Pokémon from the Legends: Z-A game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Over in Japan, the first permanent Pokémon theme park opened on February 5th — PokéPark Kanto (more about that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-to-get-first-permanent-theme-park-in-tokyo-february-2026"><u>here</u></a>). As for new games, Pokémon Pokopia, the franchise’s first ever cozy farming/life sim, is coming to Switch 2 on March 5 — check out our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/videos/we-played-pokmon-pokopia-nvc-clips"><u>video report on playing the preview version</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Expect to hear much more about the future of Pokémon later this week with the company's annual announcement broadcast Pokémon Presents, which is set to air this Friday, February 27 at 6am Pacific / 9am Eastern / 2pm UK.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Verity Townsend is a Japan-based freelance writer who previously served as editor, contributor and translator for the game news site Automaton West. She has also written about Japanese culture and movies for various publications.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-reveals-1025-logos-for-30th-anniversary-featuring-every-single-species-and-heres-how-you-can-catch-one]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Microsoft wants a turnaround and is worried about losing Xbox" - Insider report paints a different picture of Phil Spencer's retirement and Sarah Bon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-insider-report-paints-different-picture-of-spencer-retirement-and-bond-departure</link>
            <guid>1444558</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Could this be a genuine reset moment?</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/phil-spencer-sarah-bond-xbox.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/phil-spencer-sarah-bond-xbox.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/phil-spencer-sarah-bond-xbox.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/phil-spencer-sarah-bond-xbox.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/phil-spencer-sarah-bond-xbox.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/phil-spencer-sarah-bond-xbox.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/phil-spencer-sarah-bond-xbox.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/phil-spencer-sarah-bond-xbox.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/phil-spencer-sarah-bond-xbox.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Xbox</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The surprising appointment of Microsoft's CoreAI president Asha Sharma as head of Microsoft Gaming at the weekend - in conjunction with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/today-marks-an-exciting-new-chapter-xbox-boss-phil-spencer-retiring-amid-major-leadership-shakeup-that-sees-microsofts-coreai-president-taking-over-roll">Microsoft Gaming boss Phil Spencer retiring and former Xbox president Sarah Bond suddenly departing</a> - may actually be a genuine attempt by the company to turn Xbox's fortunes around. This slightly different read on the events of the past few days comes from The Verge, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/883015/microsoft-xbox-new-ceo-shakeup-notepad">a report compiled by long-time Microsoft reporter Tom Warren</a> who spoke to "multiple" sources it sounds like were inside the company itself.</p>
<p>The Verge heard that Spencer's retirement had been a long time coming and was largely expected by staff. But Bond's more surprising departure - for she had been the obvious replacement-in-waiting for Spencer - came about as the result of her big 'Xbox Anywhere' push not working out. Her idea was to move Xbox away from a single console and spread the brand across multiple devices including mobile. This divided focus led to continued drops in hardware revenue, and things like an Xbox mobile gaming store, a crucial component of the vision, still hasn't launched a year-and-a-half after it was supposed to.</p>
<p>Internally this Xbox Anywhere plan apparently "offended many Xbox employees", The Verge reported, and Bond herself is described as "tough to work with". She's praised by employees for striking deals with companies - apparently she was "crucial" in completing the $68.7bn Activision Blizzard deal - but she was also allegedly ruthless if you didn't stick to her vision. "You were out," The Verge wrote. "Most of the current and former Xbox employees I've spoken to in recent days are relieved that Bond is leaving Microsoft."</p>
<p>It's against that backdrop Asha Sharma was brought in, someone who seems ill-fitted to the role of CEO of Microsoft Gaming because she doesn't have gaming experience, either professionally or personally, and because of her worrying <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xboxs-new-head-of-gaming-has-no-tolerance-for-bad-ai-following-concerns-about-the-proliferation-of-ai-slop-and-sharmas-tech-background">background in AI - a background she's already had to answer for</a>. But there might actually be a legitimate push here to reboot and refresh the Xbox division.</p><p>If Microsoft were only interested in making Xbox a game publisher going forwards, why not promote Xbox game overseer Matt Booty? And why would Sharma promise a "return of Xbox" and say things like "I want to return to the renegade spirit that built Xbox" if looking only for empty platitudes while Xbox was sunsetted? Those are the kind of claims that will embarrass a person should they be proven insincere. "I get the impression from sources that Microsoft wants a turnaround and is worried about losing Xbox," The Verge wrote, "as it's one of its only remaining successful consumer brands."</p>
<p>Those who know Sharma reportedly say she's "enthusiastic" and "willing to learn" and "very capable of getting teams to execute on a clear vision", and that she's had good success with user acquisition at previous companies - something Xbox could sorely do with. Is this the start of a comeback fight for the Xbox console - a return to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-was-afraid-sony-was-going-to-own-the-living-room-the-big-xbox-360-interview">the "challenger brand" mindset Peter Moore instilled so aggressively for Xbox 360</a>? And if it is, what happens to that Xbox Anywhere vision?</p>
<p>Questions abound. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/personas/phil-spencer">Phil Spencer</a> has been the vision holder for Xbox for a long time. He became president of Xbox in 2014 and then CEO of Microsoft Gaming in 2022, and helped drastically revitalise Xbox's image after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-one-developers-have-their-say-on-specs-self-publishing-and-tvtvtv">the disastrous Xbox One reveal</a> and launch. He was the face and figurehead of Xbox, even with Sarah Bond as president, and he instigated things like Xbox Game Pass, which Sharma will have to deal with now.</p>
<p>But there is an opportunity for Sharma to re-establish Xbox when launching new hardware, which <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/next-gen-xbox-confirmed-in-development-following-rumours-microsoft-would-stop-making-consoles">Microsoft has said it's working on</a>, although we have no idea when it intends to release it. There are, however, strong economical challenges faced by hardware manufacturers today, notably those caused by a rush to gen-AI, which is pushing component prices sky high, as well as unpredictable tariffs and a general rise in living costs. As we've been told before, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-role-of-the-console-is-shifting-are-rising-prices-the-end-for-games-consoles-as-we-know-them">the role of the console is changing</a>.</p>
</div>

  
      </article>



  




  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/xbox-insider-report-paints-different-picture-of-spencer-retirement-and-bond-departure]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Complete ARC Raiders Shrouded Sky Patch Notes—New Map Condition, Buffs and Nerfs & More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/complete-arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-patch-notes-new-map-condition-buffs-and-nerfs-more/</link>
            <guid>1444546</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>ARC Raiders Shrouded Sky update 1.17.0 is now live, and it introduces the new map condition, new ARC enemies, weapon buffs &amp; nerfs, and much more. </p>



<p>Some details of this update have been revealed ahead of its release, including the new map condition that introduces <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hurricane-map-condition-in-arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hurricanes</a>. However, the update is much more comprehensive than that, adding new balancing changes for popular weapons, items, and crafting, bug fixes, and much more. Learn everything new in update 1.17.0 below.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-s-new-in-arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-update-1-17-0">What’s New in ARC Raiders Shrouded Sky Update 1.17.0</h2>



<p>Starting with the highlights, the ARC Raiders Shrouded Sky Update 1.17.0 adds a new Hurricane Map condition, which was mentioned above. There’s a new ARC threat to look out for, with two new unique machines that players can face: the Firefly and the Comet. Additionally, there’s a new project to build a Weather Monitoring System, a Free Raider Deck: Surgeon, and a new area has been uncovered in Dam Battlegroud, the Controlled Access Zone. Lastly, the game has also added <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/embark-studios-giving-arc-raiders-players-what-they-want/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">facial hair</a> with this update. </p>



<h2 id="h-weapon-and-item-balancing-changes-in-arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-update-1-17-0">Weapon and Item Balancing Changes in ARC Raiders Shrouded Sky Update 1.17.0</h2>



<p>Regarding balancing, the developers have revealed that many players reported a “shadow buff” in update 1.13. The developers fixed it in 1.13.1, but it inadvertently impacted the game’s weapon input buffers. The developers want to fix that now while maintaining some middle ground between what already exists. The developers are also looking to balance between low-tier and high-tier weapons. The balancing changes have been made to the following weapons: Stitcher, Kettle, Venator, Jupiter, and Aphelion.</p>



<p>Additionally, there are changes to Item &amp; Crafting, tons of content &amp; bug fixes, and an update to Anti-Cheat that players can check out in the patch notes below: </p>



<h2 id="h-all-arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-update-1-17-0-patch-notes">All ARC Raiders Shrouded Sky Update 1.17.0 Patch Notes</h2>



<h3>What’s New?</h3>



<ul>
<li>Hurricane Map Condition</li>



<li>Two New ARC Enemies</li>



<li>The Weather Monitoring System – Seasonal Player Project</li>



<li>Free Raider Deck</li>



<li>Dam Battlegrounds Map Update</li>



<li>Expedition Window</li>



<li>Facial Hair Customization</li>
</ul>



<h3>Patch Highlights</h3>



<ul>
<li>Weapon balancing for Stitcher, Kettle, Venator, Jupiter and Aphelion.</li>



<li>Added a piano as an interactable object in the world.</li>



<li>Prevented enabling all NVIDIA Freestyle filters simultaneously to remove an unfair visual advantage.</li>



<li>Feats can now be rerolled three times per day for free.</li>



<li>Removed PvP Feats, updated a few existing Feats and added a few new ones.</li>



<li>Ziplines can no longer be placed on carryable objects.</li>



<li>Mines, traps, or remote flares can no longer be placed on other deployables.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-balance-changes">Balance Changes</h3>



<h4 id="h-weapons">Weapons</h4>



<p><strong>Stitcher</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Reduced Headshot Multiplier from 2.5 to 1.75</li>



<li>Reduced Base Damage from 7 to 6.5</li>



<li>Increased Per Shot Dispersion by around 50% (Making it bloom faster)</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Kettle</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Reduced Base Damage from 10 to 8.5</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Venator</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Reduced Headshot Multiplier from 2.5 to 2</li>



<li>Reduced Base Damage from 9 to 8</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Jupiter</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Improved ADS Magnification from ~1.9x to ~2.2x</li>



<li>Improved Equip Time from 1.2s to 1.05s</li>



<li>Improved Unequip Time from 0.9s to 0.75s</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Aphelion</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Reduced Base Reload Time from 4.5s to 3.5s</li>



<li>Reduced Time Between Shots from 0.9s to 0.7s</li>



<li>Reduced Vertical Recoil by ca 50%</li>



<li>Improved ADS Settle Speed by ca 35%</li>
</ul>



<h4 id="h-item-and-crafting">Item and Crafting</h4>



<h4>Energy clip</h4>



<ul>
<li>Now available by default in the Workbench.</li>
</ul>



<h4>Item Value and Cost Changes</h4>



<p>Following item values and costs have been adjusted with appropriate recycle and salvaging adjustments:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Deadline</strong>
<ul>
<li>Value increased from 5,000 to 6,000.</li>



<li>Trader price increased from 15,000 to 18,000.</li>



<li>Added a new ARC part as a crafting cost.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Trailblazer</strong>
<ul>
<li>Value increased from 1,600 to 2,200.</li>



<li>Trader price increased from 4,800 to 6,600.</li>



<li>Added a new ARC part as a crafting cost.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Wolfpack</strong>
<ul>
<li>Value increased from 5,000 to 6,000.</li>



<li>Added Rocketeer Driver as a crafting cost.</li>



<li>Reduced Refined Explosive cost.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Vita Spray</strong>
<ul>
<li>Value increased from 3,000 to 3,400.</li>



<li>Added Tick Pod as a crafting cost.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Showstopper</strong>
<ul>
<li>Value decreased from 2,200 to 2,100.</li>



<li>Added Hornet Driver as a crafting cost.</li>



<li>Changed crafting component from Advanced Electrical Components to Electrical Components.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>ARC Parts sell value has been reduced to better reflect their crafting and progression uses.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Content and Bug Fixes&nbsp;</h3>



<h3>Achievements</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where the “Blindsided” achievement sometimes did not trigger as intended on the first attempt.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Animation</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed various animation issues while vaulting.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where some weapons didn’t drop magazines during reloads.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where reattaching to a ladder after jumping could distort the climbing animation.</li>



<li>Polished equip animations for pistols and hand cannon to better match timing and reduce visual popping when switching from unarmed.</li>



<li>Improved arm and weapon positioning when swapping shoulders to prevent visual popping during the transition.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where fall damage wouldn’t get applied if the player was in a knockback animation.</li>



<li>Polished low-health reaction animations for improved clarity.</li>



<li>Fixed weapon-shake animation incorrectly triggering indoors during freezing weather; it now only occurs outdoors.</li>
</ul>



<h3>ARC</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where Surveyors and Fireballs could open prematurely before stabilizing.</li>



<li>Reduced erratic movement of ARC parts when they are stuck to a looted item.</li>



<li>Hornets now keep their upper armor after being destroyed, making the lootable piece easier to distinguish from Wasps.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the Rocketeer sometimes would not shoot despite having a clear view of its target.</li>



<li>Reduced cases where the Sentinel’s shots could pass through geometry when its weapon clips into walls at very close range.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Audio</h3>



<ul>
<li>Limited bullet sound effects per trigger pull on burst weapons to the burst size to prevent extra shots from playing.</li>



<li>Reduced audio stuttering on lower-spec PCs for smoother, more consistent sound during gameplay.</li>



<li>Lowered non-radio voice volumes: in-game dialogue.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where sliding on stairs or debris could cause audio stutters.</li>



<li>Scrappy has received your feedback about being too noisy, he will now try to cluck less frequently.</li>



<li>Reduced overall volume and rebalanced the menu SFX and music mix for a more comfortable Speranza experience.</li>



<li>Shortened one tube deployment music track that lingered for too long in session.</li>



<li>Birds perched on ziplines now screech with correct positional audio when startled.</li>



<li>Decreased&nbsp; audio occlusion / obstruction slightly across the board and especially for players .</li>



<li>Updated acoustic guitar music tracks.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Cosmetics</h3>



<ul>
<li>The Volare Set&nbsp;</li>



<li>The Surgeon Set</li>



<li>The Devotee Set coming soon.</li>



<li>Added a new facial hair customization option.</li>



<li>Fixed incorrect visor glass material on the Marco outfit’s green color variant.</li>



<li>Fixed various instances of clipping on certain outfits.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Gameplay</h3>



<ul>
<li>Added a piano as an interactable object in the world.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where interactions could be triggered from too far away, allowing players to open doors, start hatches, or loot items without being nearby.</li>



<li>Hold and continuous interactions now cancel when equipping another item or weapon.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where players could become unable to move after being revived with a defib.</li>



<li>Prevented players from standing on or being carried by thrown grenades and other non-walkable items.</li>



<li>Added missing gamepad aim assist for Sentinels, Turrets, Shredders and Surveyors.</li>



<li>Disabled queuing for Practice Range while in a party to prevent matchmaking errors.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where a downed raider’s body could block hatch extraction by triggering a search prompt.</li>



<li>Prevented enabling all NVIDIA Freestyle filters simultaneously to remove an unfair visual advantage.</li>



<li>You can now make purchases with seeds and free loadout augments even if your stash is overflowing.</li>
</ul>



<h3>General</h3>



<ul>
<li>General performance improvements.</li>



<li>Fixed some popping issues.</li>



<li>Fixed a crash when launching the game with DirectX 11.</li>



<li>Fixed a crash that could happen when traversing ziplines.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Maps</h3>



<h4>General</h4>



<ul>
<li>Fixed broken interactions near the top of certain ladders.</li>



<li>Fixed missing collision on several environment props to reduce clipping and unintended traversal.</li>



<li>General lighting fixes across different maps.</li>
</ul>



<h4>Buried City</h4>



<ul>
<li>The chance of finding rare loot in chimneys has been lowered slightly during Bird City map condition.</li>
</ul>



<h4>Stella Montis</h4>



<ul>
<li>Fixed multiple collision issues on Stella Montis (Lobby, Atrium, Loading Bay, Train Station tunnels, Seed Vault) to prevent players from reaching out-of-bounds areas using the ‘Unstuck’ function and to address shots coming from the Lobby ceiling.</li>



<li>Adjusted night lighting on Stella Montis to improve visibility in darker areas.</li>



<li>Improved night-time visibility at the Seed Vault extraction by adding local lighting.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where lowered Spillway bridges still displayed an interaction prompt, interaction is now correctly disabled when the bridge is down.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue that allowed players to get on top of metro trains.</li>
</ul>



<h4>Blue Gate</h4>



<ul>
<li>Improved thunderstorm lighting for better visual clarity.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where players could go out of bounds in the Blue Gate tunnels.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Movement</h3>



<ul>
<li>Adjusted ladder jump-off to match vault jump-off behavior, smoothing movement and preventing unintended momentum from rapid inputs.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where sliding could clip through stairs and escalators.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Progression</h3>



<ul>
<li>You can now reroll Feats three times per day for free.</li>



<li>Removed PvP Feats, updated a few existing Feats and added a few new ones.</li>



<li>Added an Expedition catch-up system to earn missed Skill Points from previous runs, with an updated UI to track your progress.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where players occasionally did not receive a skill point as indicated in the result screen.</li>



<li>Candleberries in Blue Gate now count toward the Harvest Plants trial.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Quests</h3>



<ul>
<li>Added clearer ping labels for quest-related world objects to improve readability.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where the next objective pop-up in multi-step quests could be missing or show a completed step. It now consistently displays the correct upcoming objective.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where a quest item could appear as world loot without the related quest being active.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Social</h3>



<ul>
<li>When playing in a party, map selection now shows all locations unlocked by the member with the most rounds played.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where previous teammates could appear in the Social tab’s In Proximity list after starting a new session.</li>



<li>Added clearer error messages when friend requests fail due to too many outgoing requests or rate limiting.</li>



<li>Fixed friends appearing offline when they have more than one platform linked.</li>



<li>Added the ability to hide friend requests.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h3>UI</h3>



<ul>
<li>Item pings for items in containers now appear above the container’s interaction point and no longer appear at the wrong location in certain containers.</li>



<li>Added a ready-up warning when deploying with Raider Hatch keys into a map with no active hatches.</li>



<li>Added icons to inventory tooltips to show recycle/salvage outputs.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where squad colors could display incorrectly after squad changes.</li>



<li>Fixed a bug where adding a secondary keybind would overwrite the primary keybind in the next round.</li>



<li>Updated localization for unique loot from new enemy variants to improve in-game naming and clarity.</li>



<li>Improved matchmaking messaging when some party members are still topside.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where end-of-round health was not correctly shown for all players.</li>



<li>It is now clearer when you join a party which party member is topside while you’re in Speranza.</li>



<li>You can now use the mouse scroll wheel to switch between pages in the Raider Deck.</li>



<li>Polished UI text and updated translations across supported languages.</li>



<li>Added additional ping labels for various quest objects to improve clarity.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where mouse smoothing could remain enabled despite being turned off, ensuring the setting is correctly applied at round start.</li>



<li>Improved the red zipline preview when the zipline cannot be placed.</li>



<li>Updated login message to clearly explain when access is restricted because the shared account owner has been banned.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue in Expeditions where the timer could go negative after the departure countdown and the Sign Up button stayed active; the screen now updates correctly and the button is disabled.</li>



<li>Fix an issue where the repair preview wasn’t displayed correctly when repairing items.</li>



<li>Crafting and recycling screens now display item costs and rewards in a consistent order for easier reading.</li>



<li>The VoIP icon in the HUD will now better visually represent if the microphone is going to transmit or not if you’re using Push To Talk or Toggle To Talk.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Utility</h3>



<ul>
<li>Pop Triggers and Spotter Relays can now be used in quick slots.
<ul>
<li>The Spotter Relay can now be deployed as a trap that lures nearby ARC.</li>



<li>The Pop Trigger can now be deployed to roll forward briefly before exploding.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Added a new Field craft item: Shaker instrument.</li>



<li>Adjusted Vita Spray so healing applies continuously while in use to prevent exploit cases.</li>



<li>Fixed an unintended behaviour with the Snaphook causing it to pull players after it had been cancelled.</li>



<li>Ziplines can no longer be placed on carryable objects.</li>



<li>Fixed Zipline placement on ARC remnants that could consume the item or leave it partially placed.</li>



<li>Mines, traps, and remote flares can no longer be placed on ziplines, or on other small deployables.</li>



<li>The T3 Tactical (Healing) Augment now correctly states that healing is applied instantly.</li>
</ul>



<h3>VFX</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where Jupiter’s windup visual could face sideways, making the beam appear misaligned.</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where Trailblazer’s gas effect could persist indefinitely if interrupted by the Matriarch’s shield.</li>
</ul>



<h2>Anti-Cheat</h2>



<blockquote>
<p>When we shared our last update about tackling unfair play, we didn’t fully convey the complexity and scale of what goes into cheat detection. Our defenses operate on multiple levels: some checks are simple and definitive, while others are behavioral and data-driven and evolve over time. We also leverage broad gameplay telemetry and machine learning techniques to spot patterns that aren’t obvious at first glance. These methods take longer to develop, must adapt as game systems change, and don’t always offer instant certainty the way blunt software detections can.</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote>
<p>We’ve recently taken action against different exploits and we are further tightening our rules and stepping up enforcement. Serious infractions now carry stricter consequences. Strong detections will receive permanent bans right off the bat, while others will receive a temporary suspension and a single chance to correct the behavior. Recent updates to Family Sharing have strengthened our ability to curb misconduct and streamlined the removal of bad actors from the game. We are preparing to launch a systematic manual review of ban appeals. The game is young and the volume of telemetry is enormous, but this process ensures every case is handled with care as we continue to learn quickly and invest heavily in the precision of our enforcement tools.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The patch notes were found through ARC Raiders <a href="https://arcraiders.com/news/shrouded-sky-patch-notes-1-17-0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">website</a>. </p>



<p>In other news, Embark has confirmed that ARC Raiders does not use any kind of <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/embark-confirms-arc-raiders-no-aggression-matchmaking/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Aggression-Based Matchmaking</a> mechanics. What are your thoughts on ARC Raiders Shrouded Sky Update 1.17.0? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mouse-p-i-for-hire-release-delayed-until-april/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mouse: PI for Hire being delayed until April 2026</a>.&nbsp;Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>






        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/complete-arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-patch-notes-new-map-condition-buffs-and-nerfs-more/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ARC Raiders Weather Monitor System Project Guide—All Requirements & Rewards, Explained]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-weather-monitor-system-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/</link>
            <guid>1444540</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Shrouded Sky update for ARC Raiders is here, and there’s a lot to unpack. From the new Hurricane Map Condition to the two new ARC threats, there’s a heap of content to explore. However, one of the highlights is the brand new Project, the Weather Monitor System.</p>



<p>Shani needs you to help her build the system so Speranza isn’t caught off guard by weather anomalies like the Hurricanes in the future. Don’t worry, it’s not all done out of the kindness of your heart, as there are plenty of rewards on offer too. </p>







<p>If you want to know what items to look out for on your next raid, then you’re in the right place. Follow this guide to see every requirement and reward tied to the Weather Monitor System Project in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/games/arc-raiders/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/games/arc-raiders/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders</a>, along with how long you have to complete it.</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-complete-the-arc-raiders-weather-monitor-system-project">How To Complete The ARC Raiders Weather Monitor System Project</h2>



<figure><figcaption>The first stage. Image by Insider Gaming.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>There are five stages to the Weather Monitor System Project in ARC Raiders, with each one having four requirements to fulfil.</strong></p>



<p>Frustratingly, you cannot cycle through the stages to see what you’ll need down the line, and since the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-release-date-start-times-all-content-explained/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-release-date-start-times-all-content-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shrouded Sky update</a> is so fresh, only the first stage will be viewable for many. However, some raiders are already making swift work of the Project, and they’ve shared the requirements for each stage—as well as the rewards.</p>



<p>As more stages are unveiled by the fanbase, Insider Gaming will be quick on the trigger to update the article.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming:</strong> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hurricane-map-condition-in-arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-explained/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/hurricane-map-condition-in-arc-raiders-shrouded-sky-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hurricane Map Condition, Explained</a></li>
</ul>



<p>With that said, here’s every stage of the Weather Monitor System Project, including the requirements as well as the rewards:</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Project Stage</th><th data-align="center">Project Requirements</th><th data-align="center">Project Rewards</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 1: Atmospheric Pressure</td><td data-align="center">– 25x Plastic Parts<br>– 15x Metal Parts<br>– 5x ARC Alloy<br>– 3x Oil</td><td data-align="center">– 5x Durable Cloth<br>– 5x Great Mullein<br>– 5x Antiseptic<br>– 3x Vita Shot</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 2: Sunlight</td><td data-align="center">– 1x Snitch Scanner<br>– 3x Wires<br>– 3x Sensors<br>– 1x Comet Igniter</td><td data-align="center">– 10x Processor<br>– 5x Advanced Electrical Components<br>– 3x Zipline<br>– 1x Raider Hatch Key</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 3: Precipitation</td><td data-align="center">– 5x ARC Powercell<br>– 5x Canister<br>– 5x Steel Spring<br>– 1x Fine Wristwatch</td><td data-align="center">– 3x Medium Gun Parts<br>– 2x Complex Gun Parts<br>– 3x Advanced Mechanical Components<br>– 1x Renegade Level 3</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 4: Humidity</td><td data-align="center">– 10x Duct Tape<br>– 3x Rusted Bolts<br>– 1x Water Pump<br>– 3x Wasp Driver</td><td data-align="center">—</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Stage 5:</td><td data-align="center">—</td><td data-align="center">—</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Project Completion</td><td data-align="center">Complete all 5 Stages</td><td data-align="center">– Anemometer Backpack Charm<br>– 250x Raider Tokens</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-when-does-the-arc-raiders-weather-monitor-system-project-end">When Does The ARC Raiders Weather Monitor System Project End?</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Is it worth it? Image by Insider Gaming.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>As things stand, there is no expiry date on the Weather Monitor Display Project in ARC Raiders.</strong></p>







<p>That means that, theoretically, you can take as long as you’d like to grind through the Project and earn the rewards. It’s in line with the ongoing <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-trophy-display-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-trophy-display-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trophy Display Project</a>, which also carries over progress between the Expedition resets. </p>



<ul>
<li><strong>More Insider Gaming:</strong> <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-event-tracker-every-map-condition-schedule/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-event-tracker-every-map-condition-schedule/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders Map Condition Tracker</a></li>
</ul>



<p>However, that doesn’t mean that an end date won’t be added to the Project in the future. It could be months away yet, but it might be best not to leave it too late, especially if you’re interested in that bulk of Raider Tokens.</p>



<hr>



<p>What are your thoughts on the Shrouded Sky update in ARC Raiders? Share your thoughts in the official <a href="https://discord.gg/vwj7zdWxaW" id="https://discord.gg/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>. </p>



<p>For more ARC Raiders content, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/7-secret-loot-spots-you-need-to-know-in-arc-raiders/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/7-secret-loot-spots-you-need-to-know-in-arc-raiders/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">7 secret loot spots you need to know</a>, as well as <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hidden-bunker-arc-raiders-how-to-open-guide/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/hidden-bunker-arc-raiders-how-to-open-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to open the Hidden Bunker</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/arc-raiders-weather-monitor-system-project-guide-all-requirements-rewards-explained/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["Anyone found to be cheating will be permabanned" - Bungie outlines Marathon's robust networking and security features]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/bungie-outlines-marathon-networking-and-security-features</link>
            <guid>1444534</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Marathon_robot-enemies.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Marathon_robot-enemies.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Marathon_robot-enemies.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Marathon_robot-enemies.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Marathon_robot-enemies.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Marathon_robot-enemies.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Marathon_robot-enemies.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Marathon_robot-enemies.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Marathon_robot-enemies.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Bungie</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Excitement around <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/marathon">Marathon</a>'s launch next week seems to finally be a thing, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-come-has-come-for-you-to-judge-marathon-for-yourself-again-theres-a-new-server-slam-running-late-feb-into-march">this weekend's "server slam" aims to convince extraction shooter enjoyers</a> on the fence. Ahead of it, Bungie has outlined a frankly impressive effort regarding networking and security features that will be implemented from the get-go.</p>
<p>On 23rd February, the Sony-owned developer <a href="https://www.bungie.net/7/en/News/Article/marathonsecurity">shared a meaty blog post</a> that dives deep into what players can expect from the game's many layers of security and key network features. Needless to say, all of them are crucial to ensuring a smooth and fair online experience, but it's often that shooters targeting a competitive crowd don't launch in a robust-enough state.</p>
<p>First, Bungie has made Marathon's dedicated servers "fully authoritative on key combat and looting actions," meaning any "correction" of suspicious behaviour won't impact other players and their experience. It's combined with "client-side prediction and rewind" to ensure actions feel immediate. Moreover, it's promised that servers "carefully track each bullet to its target even with high packet loss." Consistent hit registration at launch in an online shooter? Imagine that.</p>
<p>When it comes to wall hacks and other cheats that might reveal the position of key items and players, a Fog of War system limits the regions of a map that individual player clients have knowledge of. "It also helps keep your position hidden from other players' clients." This isn't enough to guarantee full protection from hacks alone, but it's part of the game's arsenal to combat cheaters. On top of that, the security stack was rebuilt "from the ground up" for this game, and that will work alongside the familiar BattlEye solution.</p><p>There's also the matter of one's Internet connection going down mid-run. Each online game handles such events differently. In the case of Marathon, "you can reconnect and continue playing the run" like in other match-based shooters. "If connection recovery fails due to an issue with Bungie's server or network infrastructure, we will attempt to return the starting gear to all impacted players."</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Bungie</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Perhaps the biggest shocker comes near the end of the list of features, where Bungie states "anyone found to be cheating will be permabanned from playing Marathon forever." Yeah, no second chances. So, make sure you're not running anything suspicious while playing it.</p>
<p>In any case, the veteran online shooter developer, admits that "product security is never fully solved" and says it'll continue to invest in systems and infrastructure for as long as the game stays alive.</p>
<p>As an extra, we now also have confirmation Xbox players will automatically get <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/marathon-isnt-just-favouring-playstation-players-with-exclusive-cosmetics-xbox-and-steam-players-promised-bonus-loot-too">exclusive gun charms</a> when the game releases on 5th March:</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Marathon players on Xbox Series X|S will automatically receive the exclusive Emerald Clutch Weapon Charm and Emerald Catch Weapon Charm when Marathon releases on March 5. <a href="https://t.co/lOpdNfle71">pic.twitter.com/lOpdNfle71</a></p>— Marathon (@MarathonTheGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarathonTheGame/status/2026099758838816820?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 24, 2026</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>


        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/bungie-outlines-marathon-networking-and-security-features]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ambitious Fallout: New Vegas Van Buren remake mod locks in an early March release date for its second demo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ambitious-fallout-new-vegas-van-buren-remake-mod-locks-in-an-early-march-release-date-for-its-second-demo</link>
            <guid>1444528</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>"Within these walls messages are screened, rivalries simmer and order is absolute"</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-the-new-west-prison-demo-release-date-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-the-new-west-prison-demo-release-date-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-the-new-west-prison-demo-release-date-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-the-new-west-prison-demo-release-date-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-the-new-west-prison-demo-release-date-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-the-new-west-prison-demo-release-date-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-the-new-west-prison-demo-release-date-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-the-new-west-prison-demo-release-date-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-the-new-west-prison-demo-release-date-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Fallout: The New West team</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Not long after <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/fallout-new-vegas-van-buren-remake-mod-revelation-blues-has-a-new-name-and-a-second-demo-dropping-soon">changing their project's name</a> from Fallout: Revelation Blues to Fallout: The New West, the developers behind a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-new-vegas">New Vegas</a> mod remaking a cancelled Fallout game have settled on a release date for their second demo. The second publicly playable taste of this attempt to resurrect Van Buren - the version of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/fallout-3">Fallout 3</a> which was in development at Black Isle Studios before being cancelled in 2003 - is slated to arrive late next week.</p>
<!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Fallout: The New West Reveal Teaser" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KY5X0G_05h0?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Fallout: The New West Reveal Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KY5X0G_05h0?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/KY5X0G_05h0?autoplay=1" title="Fallout: The New West Reveal Teaser">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KY5X0G_05h0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>This second demo will arrive on March 5th and, unlike the Burham Springs demo the New West team <a href="https://www.vg247.com/fallout-new-vegas-mod-revelation-blues-demo-van-buren">put out last year,</a> it sets up an alternate New Vegas start which'll serve as the intro the the full mod. Interestingly, the modders look to have pulled that Burham Springs demo offline ahead of its follow-up releasing, with its <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/newvegas/mods/91191?tab=description">Nexus Mods page</a> noting that it's "currently not supported by the author(s) and/or has issue(s) they are unable to fix yet".</p>
<p>As for the upcoming demo, it'll drop you into Tibbets prison and likely task you with negotiating your release. I'm sure the robots and AI brains in change will conduct fair parole hearings.</p>
<p>"This experience offers players a new point of entry into the Mojave, beginning as a Prisoner under the observation of our watchful staff," developer Caveman6667 wrote in the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/867445710622556230/867471933725212702/1475708718787199080">Discord announcement</a> of the demo date. "Within these walls messages are screened, rivalries simmer and order is absolute. Each block is designed with purpose and every decision shapes your record. Tibbets is one vignette within a much larger world currently in development. This demo represents the opening gate. Your participation, feedback, and continued vigilance assist in its refinement."</p><p>As noted on <a href="https://falloutthenewwest.com/faq">their website</a>, the modders plans once this Tibbets demo is out are to eventually release The New West's entire first act as a vertical slice. Once complete, the mod'll tell "the same broad story envisioned by Fallout: Van Buren, but restructured and expanded to form a cohesive, playable experience". Drawing on themes and story beats from design documents for the cancelled game which have since gone public, The New West's tale will take place in an "alternate continuity that predates and reinterprets the events of Fallout: New Vegas". Its creators are also hoping to mesh together the more modern experience of playing New Vegas with some classic Fallout-esque mechanics outlined in the docs.</p>
<p>If it achieves its goals, the project sounds like it'll form a nicely funky bridge between the original two Fallouts and spiritual successor New Vegas. Now, to look up ways to convince a Protectron guard to help me hop a very tall and possibly electrified fence in preparation for March 5th.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ambitious-fallout-new-vegas-van-buren-remake-mod-locks-in-an-early-march-release-date-for-its-second-demo]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Quordle #1492: All Answers & Hints For February 24, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-quordle-1492-all-answers-hints-for-february-24-2026/</link>
            <guid>1444525</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Quordle takes the complexity of the original daily word game and ups the ante by having you solve four solutions at once. Your 100% attention suddenly needs to be diverted four ways, and completing the daily Quordle is tough without the right starting words or hints. February 24, 2026, Quordle is the #1491 edition of the puzzle, and there are four new words for you to find. This guide has hints and a helping hand to help you solve all four words.</p>



<p>Before the information comes thick and fast at you, make sure you give today’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/quordle/" id="3574" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Quordle</a> a go if you haven’t already!</p>







<h2 id="h-how-to-play-quordle-daily-word-game">How To Play Quordle Daily Word Game</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Rest assured, they will be tested. Image by Insider Gaming</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Quordle is different from other daily word games because it requires you to guess four words at once correctly, and you can do so on the official Quordle website.</strong></p>



<p>Before anything else, check out this set of instructions on finding and playing Quordle:</p>



<ol>
<li>Go to the <a href="https://beta.quordle.com/#/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Quordle</a> website.</li>



<li>You are shown four equal lines reminiscent of a Wordle setup.</li>



<li>Enter your first guess using the keyboard input at the bottom of the screen.</li>



<li>The game will fill out the first of nine lines for all four boxes.</li>



<li>A green box means the letter is correct AND goes in that exact spot on the grid.</li>



<li>A yellow box means the letter is correct BUT needs to go in a different spot on the grid.</li>



<li>A grey box means the letter DOESN’T feature at all.</li>



<li>Do this up to nine times to try to solve all four words.</li>
</ol>







<h2 id="h-best-quordle-tips-amp-tricks">Best Quordle Tips &amp; Tricks</h2>



<ul>
<li>Try to use as many of the five vowels as you can in your first two guesses.</li>



<li>Focus on solving words with more green and yellow boxes first.</li>



<li>Avoid reusing letters that are not applicable across any of the four answers.</li>



<li>Don’t be afraid to try the same letter twice in one word, as answers can be sneaky like that.</li>



<li>Play the Practice game first if you’re not used to Quordle, or need a warm-up before today’s new game!</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-quordle-hints-for-today-february-24-2026">Quordle Hints For Today, February 24, 2026</h2>



<h3 id="h-top-left-grid">Top-left grid</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong> A specific cow organ.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> Swap the first letter for another vowel, and you get a snake.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-top-right-grid">Top-right grid</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong> Something overcome by too much fire.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> A scorched appearance.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-bottom-left-grid">Bottom-left grid</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong> A type of soft toy.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> Rich, full, and luxurious.</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-bottom-right-grid">Bottom-right grid</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong> A Nike brand.</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong> “Diffused matter (such as smoke or fog) suspended floating in the air and impairing its transparency.”</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-starter-words-for-february-23-2026-quordle">Starter Words For February 23, 2026 Quordle</h2>



<p>You should consider using one or more of the following words to get you started with today’s new Quordle puzzle:</p>



<ul>
<li>Swear</li>



<li>Halos</li>



<li>Evade</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>SPOILER WARNING: The answers will be revealed next!</strong></p>



<h2 id="h-all-today-s-quordle-1492-answers-for-february-24-2026">All Today’s Quordle #1492 Answers For February 24, 2026</h2>



<p>Get ready for all four of today’s Quordle answers, starting from the top-left grid, then the top-right, then the bottom-left, and finally the bottom-right.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Quordle Grid</th><th data-align="center">Answer</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center">Top-left grid</td><td data-align="center">UDDER</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Top-right grid</td><td data-align="center">BURNT</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bottom-left grid</td><td data-align="center">PLUSH</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center">Bottom-right grid</td><td data-align="center">VAPOR</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-next-quordle-daily-game">When Is The Next Quordle Daily Game?</h2>



<p id="block-bc42def5-af74-42a4-abf5-f31a34e53dd6"><strong>Quordle is updated daily at 12 AM (Midnight) in your time zone and region, so the next game will start on February 25.</strong></p>



<p>The Quordle schedule is very consistent and always comes out at the same time each new day. </p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-quordle">What Is Quordle?</h2>



<p><strong>Quordle is a variation of the popular Wordle daily word game, but instead of giving you one word to solve, you must figure out four unique words at the same time.</strong></p>



<p>Needless to say, Quordle is MUCH harder than Wordle! There are days when it might be an achievement just to solve one of the four words. Whereas you can guess Wordle with your first answer, that’s impossible with Quordle. You need to be thinking on all cylinders with Quordle, and Insider Gaming strongly recommends you take the hints above on board and apply them to future Quordle puzzles.</p>



<p>Additionally, a new daily guide will be on the website for every new puzzle. Keep coming back each day for hints and solutions to the newest Quordle daily word games!</p>



<p>How did you find today’s Quordle? If you have any feedback on what you want to see added to these guides, share your thoughts via the free-to-join <a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>You should also check out IG’s other word game guides: </p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-mini-crossword-february-24-hints/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NYT Mini Crossword Hints Today—Answers For Tuesday, February 24</a></li>



<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-contexto-1255-hints-answer-for-february-24-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Today’s Contexto #1255: Hints &amp; Answer For February 24, 2026</a></li>



<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1711-hints-answer-february-24-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Today’s Wordle #1711: Hints and Answer for February 24, 2026</a></li>



<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-24-989/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NYT Connections Hints Today (#989)—Answers for Tuesday, February 24</a></li>
</ul>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-quordle-1492-all-answers-hints-for-february-24-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dosa Divas Preview – Is this 2026s spiciest RPG?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/24/dosa-divas-preview-is-this-2026s-spiciest-rpg/</link>
            <guid>1444510</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Naming your game after one of the tastiest foodstuffs on the planet is one way to strike a tone. Named after the beautiful Indian pancakes you’ll find at the best street food markets, it’s immediately clear that tasty treats lie at the very heart of Dosa Divas. That said, the colourful wrapper created by Outerloop Games is hiding something even more delicious inside.</p>
<p><iframe title="DOSA DIVAS - Release Date Trailer - Steam Demo Out Now" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bogYlMcNb80?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>There aren’t many games that give you the option to pout, photo modes notwithstanding, but that’s exactly what we found during the opening of our hands-on with Dosa Divas. We’re pouting because our sister Amani refuses to cook us some food, and once she gives in, that’s our first quest here. Collect some ingredients. The difference in Dosa Divas is that we’re going to do it in a mech.</p>


<p>It’s one heck of a mech, too. Goddess has the front end of a yellow Tuk Tuk, an old-school folding canopy, and at least one stick-on paper flower. It’s awesome. AND, it flaps its arms like a chicken to double jump. You can forget Gundam; this is the coolest mech of 2026.</p>


<p>Samara and Amani are the Dosa Divas, former restaurateurs turned Spirit-mech pilots, and who are able to enter the Preparation Realm to craft food and consumables through a series of mini-games. You select the ingredients – that’s a Bell Pepper here for the base, before added Basil for flavour. The pronunciation of “bay-zil” upsets me, but that’s the only wrinkle in an otherwise fun and tasty diversion.</p>
<p>The pair are about to set off on a road trip to see their parents – their first after Amani has been away for ten years – before they’re rudely interrupted by their other sibling, Lina, and her floating LinaMeals food billboard. Which she uses to insult the pair. Sam smashes the billboard up, and between that and a spot of sulking, it’s clear that a lot has happened, both in the last ten years, and between the sisters.</p>
<p>Perhaps most obviously, Lina has become a food-based overlord, controlling the populace with her LinaMeals and banning everyone else from actually cooking. She’s even got lawyers out and about to make sure everyone follows her rules. Fortunately, Samara and Amani aren’t about to let that stand, with a spot of turn-based combat coming into play whenever you’ve got someone standing in your way.</p>

<p>This is turn-based combat in the vein of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/05/05/clair-obscur-expedition-33-review/">Expedition 33</a> or <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/21/paper-mario-the-thousand-year-door-switch-review/">Paper Mario</a>, rewarding extra damage or defence if you can time the right button press with the action on screen. I really think that this has become my favourite feature in turn-based games, keeping you on your toes and giving you some much-needed interaction during battles.</p>
<p>The culinary influence continues into combat, whether that’s Sam using a massive Karahi wok to pummel enemies or needing to match your attacks to the enemies’ food weakness. There’s a handy readout like in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/12/03/octopath-traveler-0-review/">Octopath Traveller</a>, so you can easily remember that they’re weak to spicy or sour attacks, and just like Octopath, there’s also a boost function that lets you add extra attacks to your chosen action. It all comes together really well, and if you’re a fan of modern turn-based combat, Dosa Divas is doing it right.</p>

<p>Dosa Divas also looks and sounds absolutely brilliant. Its chunky, vibrant art style brings bags of character to the world, and everyone in it, with a real penchant for slightly off-kilter food-based visual gags and details. That’s all ramped up by funky, rock-infused riffs that are melded with more traditional Indian tones. The exceptional vibes are less surprising when you find out it’s coming from Outerloop Games, the Washington-based, minority-led team behind the incredible Thirsty Suitors and Falcon Age, and they’ve brought that same spirit to bear on Dosa Divas.</p>
<p>There aren’t many games that immediately lodge themselves in your psyche in the way that Dosa Divas has. Perfectly struck turn-based combat, killer art direction, and a sibling rivalry that’s enslaved the world set the tone for what looks to be one of 2026’s most intriguing indie releases.</p>
<p><em>Dosa Divas is launching on 14th April across PS5, Xbox Series X|S, Switch 1 &amp; 2 and PC, but you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/4316300/Dosa_Divas_Demo/">check out a demo now on Steam</a>.</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/02/24/dosa-divas-preview-is-this-2026s-spiciest-rpg/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Founder Thinks New Xbox CEO Will “Gently” Sunset Division as Microsoft’s Focus Is Its Core AI Business]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/xbox-founder-thinks-new-xbox-ceo-will-sunset-division-ai-business/</link>
            <guid>1444507</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><strong>Xbox</strong> founder and creator <strong>Seamus Blackley</strong> has just released <a href="https://gamesbeat.com/what-an-xbox-founder-thinks-of-the-new-xbox-ceo-seamus-blackley-interview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">an explosive interview to GamesBeat</a>, in which he doesn't mince words against <strong>Microsoft</strong>'s current strategy and also shares his opinion of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/microsoft-phil-spencer-retires-sarah-bond-resigns-asha-sharma-takes-over-xbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">newly appointed Xbox CEO</a>, <strong>Asha Sharma</strong>. According to Blackley, who first came up with the idea of a Microsoft console back in 1999, her mandate will be the same as a palliative doctor, ultimately sunsetting the whole division as Microsoft refocuses on its new core AI business.</p>



<p><em><strong>Xbox, like a lot of businesses that aren’t the core AI business, is being sunsetted</strong>. They don’t say that, but that’s what’s happening. I expect that the new CEO, Asha Sharma, <strong>her job is going to be as a palliative care doctor who slides Xbox gently into the night</strong>.</em></p>



<p><em>[...] The natural consequence of the focus on AI is that AI abstracts every problem from the minds of the executives who believe in it. We’re abstracting the problem of games as well. <strong>There’s a core belief, and you can see it in what Satya said, that AI will subsume games like it will subsume everything</strong>. The job of all these people is to just gently usher all of these business units into the new world of AI. That’s what you’re seeing here.</em></p>



<p><em>[...] It would have been shocking if they had somebody in there in a meaningful role who was passionate about games, passionate about the creator-driven business of games, because it would be in direct conflict with everything else Microsoft is doing. <strong>Microsoft is a company that is now about enabling its customers by enabling AI to drive things. That’s at odds with the auteur model of any art, but specifically of games</strong>. Microsoft doesn’t have the problem that Apple does, or that Netflix does, where they have an auteur-driven content model to manage. Games are the only place where they have a content business.</em></p>



<p>His fears are compounded by the fact that Asha Sharma <strong>previously served as president of Microsoft's CoreAI product portfolio</strong>. It doesn't help that some gamers <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/new-xbox-ceo-targeted-supposedly-using-ai-bot-x/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">have already accused her of using an AI bot to interact with followers on X</a></strong>, though she rejected those accusations, and she previously stated that she doesn't want to flood the Xbox ecosystem with "soulless AI slop".</p>



<p>Xbox gamers have been mostly worried about Microsoft sunsetting its console hardware business, <strong>which is definitely a more real concern</strong> given dwindling sales and the multiplatform strategy. At this stage, it seems a little premature to think about the whole division being axed, though of course, it could still happen at some point in the future. For now, though, Microsoft <strong>is still planning to release a new Xbox console</strong>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-next-gen-might-launch-2027-but-its-best-case-scenario/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">possibly next year</a>.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/xbox-founder-thinks-new-xbox-ceo-will-sunset-division-ai-business/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft's throne room rejigging has seen Sarah Bond take the bullet for marketing strategy which was "failing internally", report claims]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsofts-throne-room-rejigging-has-seen-sarah-bond-take-the-bullet-for-marketing-strategy-which-was-failing-internally-report-claims</link>
            <guid>1444504</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Report claims exec has been cited as "tough to work with" and dogmatic about the company's multiplatform vision</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/microsoft-leadership-change-bond-reportedly-blamed-for-marketing-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/microsoft-leadership-change-bond-reportedly-blamed-for-marketing-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/microsoft-leadership-change-bond-reportedly-blamed-for-marketing-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/microsoft-leadership-change-bond-reportedly-blamed-for-marketing-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/microsoft-leadership-change-bond-reportedly-blamed-for-marketing-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/microsoft-leadership-change-bond-reportedly-blamed-for-marketing-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/microsoft-leadership-change-bond-reportedly-blamed-for-marketing-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/microsoft-leadership-change-bond-reportedly-blamed-for-marketing-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/microsoft-leadership-change-bond-reportedly-blamed-for-marketing-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Microsoft</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>In case you missed it, Friday saw news arrive of a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-gaming-head-phil-spencer-is-retiring-replaced-by-an-ai-exec-who-promises-no-soulless-ai-slop">substantial corporate reshuffle at the top of Microsoft's gaming division</a>. CEO Phil Spencer was revealed to be retiring at the same time Xbox president Sarah Bond was revealed to have resigned, leaving new boss and former president of Microsoft CoreAI Asha Sharma to don the crown of green plastic.</p>
<p>A report from <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/883015/microsoft-xbox-new-ceo-shakeup-notepad?view_token=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJpZCI6IkpYeERHeWF6NUwiLCJwIjoiL3RlY2gvODgzMDE1L21pY3Jvc29mdC14Ym94LW5ldy1jZW8tc2hha2V1cC1ub3RlcGFkIiwiZXhwIjoxNzcyMjkwNjAwLCJpYXQiOjE3NzE4NTg2MDB9.getJ-3kspePX7CrVmely9uWHy0nEaJuj6YCKKbJMCfU&amp;utm_medium=gift-link">The Verge</a> has now offered a bit more detail as to how all this chair-switching went down, and unsurprisingly, it reads like an account from a struggling kingdom whose ruler's just announced plans to abdicate.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>According to the report, Spencer's spitting out to whichever planet retired execs live on had been in the works since last year, with "months of careful successor planning". All that careful planning ended in chaos when the announcement leaked a few days early on Friday, leaving Microsoft playing catch-up. Hence departing president Sarah Bond's <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7430753683912531968/">lengthy and bland departure post</a> not arriving at the same time. </p>
<p>As to why Bond's departed, rather than ending up as Spencer's successor, the report paints a picture of her as taking the lion's share of the blame for a much-disliked '<a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/11/14/this-is-an-xbox/">This Is an Xbox</a>' marketing push/wider strategy, which has seen Xbox emphasise their presence across multiple platforms and devices. Basically, rather than trying to herd folks towards Xbox consoles, the company have experimented with shouting that you can play Xbox games through apps on PC, handhelds, phones, and tellies.</p><p>The Verge report this campaign "offended many Xbox employees internally", and has subsequently been questioned in the face of Microsoft's decining hardware revenue. Now, we get to the bit of the report which to me reads most like the <a href="https://www.espn.co.uk/nba/story/_/id/44736507/lakers-luka-doncic-not-spoken-mavs-gm-nico-harrison-says-criticism-dallas-painful-want-talk-back">sort of thing</a> sports teams put out to control the narrative if, for example, behind-the-scenes drama between execs and star players requires a public scapegoat.</p>
<p>The report cites most current and former Xbox employees as being "relieved that Bond is leaving Microsoft", with more than one source alleging she's "been tough to work with, and built a team structure that meant if you didn’t follow the vision or questioned it, you were out". That said, Bond's ability to strike up relationships with companies and devs has gotten good reviews.</p>
<p>As the report notes, Bond was implementing the 'This Is an Xbox' strategy/ads while operating under Spencer's leadership, so it's noteworthy that she appears to be taking most of the flak for it. While the clandestine nature of machinations at behemoths like Microsoft likely means we'll never truly know who had the most hand in these calls, Bond being judged in stronger terms than the retiring senior exec she was once <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/what-happened-to-xbox-president-sarah-bond-amid-phil-spencers-retirement-and-asha-sharmas-promotion-long-term-protg-resigns">tipped to replace</a> - amid a lot more <a href="https://x.com/BethesdaStudios/status/2026002196375195891">positive eulogising</a> of his time at the top, and after years of being PR-spun as a relatable gamer-boss - is a bit eyebrow-raising.</p>
<p>That's not to say Bond - who, unlike Spencer, wasn't mentioned in the corporate email memos of Microsoft big boss Satya Nadella, new boss Asha Sharma, or newly promoted exec Matt Booty - didn't have a large hand in strategy, or behave in the way the Xbox staffers cited by The Verge claim. It all just seems rather convenient to pile the outgoing regime's failures at her door, after <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-layoffs-are-reportedly-underway-with-zenimax-and-king-employees-losing-their-jobs">a rough few years for Xbox</a>.</p><p>Meanwhile, new CEO Asha Sharma's reportedly facing concerns from some staff over her AI background, and whether her tenure'll see the company move away from consoles for good, with both being things she moved to reassure folks on in her email memo upon taking the gig.</p>
<p>So, there you go. A new face is on the throne. The old regime have been shown the door in whichever form was deemed acceptable to the baying crowds beyond the keep. The Microsoft gaming arm is dead, long live the Microsoft gaming arm.</p>

        </div>

      </article>




        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsofts-throne-room-rejigging-has-seen-sarah-bond-take-the-bullet-for-marketing-strategy-which-was-failing-internally-report-claims]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT Mini Crossword Hints Today—Answers For Tuesday, February 24]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-mini-crossword-february-24-hints/</link>
            <guid>1444498</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The NYT Mini Crossword is a popular, quick-to-complete word game to test yourself daily, but some of the puzzles can be difficult to complete.</p>



<p>If you’ve found yourself stuck on today’s&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tag/nyt-mini/">NYT Mini</a>, Insider Gaming has some helpful hints and all the answers for the NYT Mini Crossword on Monday, 24 February, 2026.</p>



<p id="block-a3d47262-a89d-4341-93f0-34626756e4b3"><em><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong>&nbsp;The following information includes spoilers on today’s edition of the NYT Mini Crossword. If you don’t want the answer given to you, stop scrolling.</em></p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-play-nyt-mini-crossword">How to Play NYT Mini Crossword</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Daily challenge. Image via NYT</figcaption></figure>



<p>The NYT Mini Crossword is available to play on the New York Times Games app or website, but, as of September 2025, a New York Times Game subscription is required.</p>



<p>The NYT Games Subscription is priced at $6.95 per month, but there are introductory offers available for other NYT subscriptions that include games access, which might be worth considering.</p>



<p>Without a Games subscription, access to the NYT Mini Crossword is blocked.</p>



<h2 id="h-nyt-mini-crossword-clues-feb-23">NYT Mini Crossword Clues (Feb. 23)</h2>



<p>Here are all the clues provided for the NYT Mini Crossword for February 24, 2026.</p>



<h3 id="h-across">Across</h3>



<p>1 – Goosebumps-inducing</p>



<p>6 – Buddy, informally</p>



<p>7 – Rub off, as pencil markings</p>



<p>8 – Enjoys a quiet weekend morning, perhaps</p>



<p>9 – David Szalay novel that won the 2025 Booker Prize</p>



<h3 id="h-down">Down</h3>



<p>1 – Section of a bookcase</p>



<p>2 – Color similar to salmon that’s also named for a sea creature</p>



<p>3 – Leave speechless</p>



<p>4 – Gets out of bed</p>



<p>5 – “Uff-da!”</p>



<h2 id="h-additional-clues-for-nyt-mini-feb-23">Additional Clues For NYT Mini (Feb. 23)</h2>



<p>Here are some additional clues to help you solve the NYT Mini Crossword on February 24, 2026.</p>



<h3 id="h-across-0">Across</h3>



<p>1 – 2000’s comedy series, ___ Movie</p>



<p>6 – Marge Simpson’s nickname for her husband</p>



<p>7 – Use the end of a pencil</p>



<p>8 – Lounging about</p>



<p>9 – Meaty part of human body</p>



<h3 id="h-down-0">Down</h3>



<p>1 – Storage platform</p>



<p>2 – Great Barrier Reef builders</p>



<p>3 – Blow away</p>



<p>4 – Batman movie, The Dark Knight ___</p>



<p>5 – Sounds terrible</p>



<h2 id="h-all-nyt-mini-crossword-answers-feb-23">All NYT Mini Crossword Answers (Feb. 23)</h2>



<p>Here are all the answers for the NYT Mini Crossword on February 24, 2026.</p>



<h3 id="h-across-1">Across</h3>



<p>1 – SCARY</p>



<p>6 – HOMIE</p>



<p>7 – ERASE</p>



<p>8 – LAZES</p>



<p>9 – FLESH</p>



<h3 id="h-down-1">Down</h3>



<p>1 – SHELF</p>



<p>2 – CORAL</p>



<p>3 – AMAZE</p>



<p>4 – RISES</p>



<p>5 – YEESH</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-next-game">When is The Next Game?</h2>



<p>The NYT Mini Crossword refreshes daily at 10 PM ET on weekdays and Saturdays, and at 6 PM ET on Sundays.</p>



<p>As such, the next NYT Mini Crossword will be available at 7 PM PT/9 PM CT/10 PM ET/3 AM GMT/2 PM AET.</p>



<h2 id="h-what-is-the-nyt-mini-crossword">What is The NYT Mini Crossword?</h2>



<p>The NYT Mini Crossword was introduced in 2014 as a shorter and quicker-to-complete game to accompany the main New York Times Crossword, which was initially released in 1942.</p>



<p>Until September 2025, the NYT Mini Crossword was free, but it has now been consolidated into a monthly NYT Games Subscription alongside several other popular games.</p>







<hr>



<p>Did you struggle with the NYT Mini Crossword today? Share your thoughts in the&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord</a>.</p>



<p>For more word games, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1711-hints-answer-february-24-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hints and answers for today’s Wordle</a>, and find out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-contexto-1255-hints-answer-for-february-24-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">clues for today’s Contexto</a>.</p>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-mini-crossword-february-24-hints/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[KRAFTON Pushes Even More Into AI R&D with New “Chief AI Officer”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/krafton-pushes-more-ai-rd-chief-ai-officer/</link>
            <guid>1444489</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>South Korean developer and publisher <strong>KRAFTON</strong> announced another step toward expanding its AI R&amp;D framework: the appointment of <strong>Kangwook Lee</strong> as the company's new Chief AI Officer (CAIO). Lee has actually been at Krafton since 2022 in the role of Head of KRAFTON AI; the promotion is a sign of the company's continued investment in AI research and development. As a reminder, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/the-ai-first-pubg-publisher-krafton-reaches-all-time-high-2b-in-revenue/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the company has been calling itself "AI First"</a></strong> for a while now.</p>



<p>Lee has already led major initiatives, including <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/nvidia-ace-to-power-dynamic-ai-characters-companions-and-bosses-in-pubg-naraka-bladepoint-inzoi-and-mir5/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the collaboration with NVIDIA to develop CPCs (Co-Playable Characters)</a></strong>, AI-driven companions designed to enable real-time interaction between players and in-game teammates. Those debuted in KRAFTON's life simulation game<span>&nbsp;<strong>inZoi</strong>, featuring the so-called <strong>Smart Zoi</strong> NPCs, which can adapt to the environment and respond to events</span> around them.</p>



<p>Soon, the technology will also be introduced in PUBG with the <strong>PUBG Ally</strong> system, built on NVIDIA ACE technology and running an SLM (Small Language Model) on-device. <strong>PUBG Ally NPCs can discuss strategies with players and adapt their playstyle accordingly</strong>. The NPCs can bring over requested items, assist in reviving teammates, and make independent decisions during looting, combat, and survival situations. They also work with voice-based interaction and already support English, Korean, and Chinese, with the first tests planned early this year in <strong>PUBG: BATTLEGROUNDS Arcade</strong>.</p>



<p>Under Lee’s leadership, KRAFTON’s AI strategy will focus on three core areas:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Elevating gameplay:</strong> KRAFTON will continue developing AI features to enhance immersion, responsiveness, and player interaction. <strong>Technologies such as CPCs complement human-designed gameplay systems, enabling studios to maintain full creative ownership and final decision-making authority</strong>. AI will be applied where it meaningfully enhances the player experience, while preserving the handcrafted elements that define each title.</li>



<li><strong>Supporting development teams:</strong> KRAFTON is investing in AI tools <strong>to help streamline repetitive or technical tasks, enabling developers to spend more time on creative planning, storytelling, and design</strong>. The company views AI as a means of <strong>supporting its workforce by reducing friction in production workflows and empowering teams to focus on their craft</strong>. AI-driven analytics and development tools operate using authorised and responsibly managed data in accordance with applicable privacy standards.</li>



<li><strong>Exploring long-term research opportunities:</strong> Building on its experience operating large-scale physics-based virtual worlds, <strong>KRAFTON is conducting long-term research into physical AI and robotics</strong> through a newly established entity, <strong>Ludo Robotics</strong>. This entity has operations in the United States and Korea. This research is in the early stages and focuses on software intelligence, using simulation environments to test and validate complex systems. <strong>Games remain KRAFTON’s core business</strong>, though, and future research initiatives are designed to build on the company’s foundational strengths in interactive technology.</li>
</ol>



<p>Most gamers still aren't on board with this, as evidenced most clearly <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/larian-studios-will-refrain-from-using-genai-tools-to-develop-concept-art-will-use-it-elsewhere/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">by the controversy sparked by Larian's usage of AI in the development of Divinity</a></strong>, but KRAFTON appears to have chosen its lane without much hesitation. Only time will tell whether they made the right move.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/krafton-pushes-more-ai-rd-chief-ai-officer/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Today’s Contexto #1255: Hints & Answer For February 24, 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-contexto-1255-hints-answer-for-february-24-2026/</link>
            <guid>1444486</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>Contexto is a word association game that gives you a new word to guess every single day. With every attempt, the AI algorithm determines how close your guess is to the daily answer based on thematic and contextual similarity.</p>







<p>Sometimes, though, no matter how experienced you are, the word you’re looking for can be incredibly vague and hard to deduce. Luckily for you, this guide is full of hints to give you a helping hand, but make sure you give today’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwipr4zrptGSAxWdREEAHYkSF0kQFnoECAwQAQ&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fcontexto.me%2F&amp;usg=AOvVaw21MfS02qcTAe3-U9GeyYlh&amp;opi=89978449" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Contexto</a>&nbsp;a go if you haven’t already!</p>



<h2 id="h-how-to-play-contexto">How To Play Contexto</h2>



<figure><figcaption>Time to guess. Image by Insider Gaming.</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Contexto is incredibly simple to play, but difficult to master. All you have to do is type words into the search bar, and the AI algorithm will tell you how close your word is to the answer.</strong></p>



<p>You’ll know how close your guess is based on the colour of the bar and the number next to it.</p>



<ul>
<li>Red includes guesses with the number 1,501 and above, meaning you’re way off from the secret word.</li>



<li>Orange includes guesses between 301 and 1,500, meaning you’re getting closer, but still some ways off.</li>



<li>Green includes guesses between 1 and 300, meaning you’re on the right track.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-best-contexto-tips-amp-tricks">Best Contexto Tips &amp; Tricks</h2>



<ul>
<li>Start off using broad terms, then narrow down once you’ve got under the 1,000 mark.</li>



<li>Try using Nouns first, and dip into verbs or adjectives once you’ve discovered the context.</li>



<li>Experiment with random words at times, especially as different forms of a root word can rank differently, such as work and worker.</li>



<li>Guess away, as unlike other word games like Wordle, you aren’t limited to a strict number of attempts.</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-best-starting-words-for-contexto">Best Starting Words For Contexto</h2>



<p><strong>Here are some great starting words to get you going with Contexto:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Thing</li>



<li>Person</li>



<li>Place</li>



<li>Animal</li>



<li>Work</li>



<li>Nature</li>



<li>Game</li>



<li>Concept</li>



<li>Idea</li>



<li>Food</li>
</ul>



<h2 id="h-contexto-hints-for-today-february-24-2026">Contexto Hints For Today, February 24, 2026</h2>



<p>Without giving away today’s Contexto answer, here are a few helpful hints to get you thinking in the right direction:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Hint 1:</strong>&nbsp;It’s a job or a hobby</li>



<li><strong>Hint 2:</strong>&nbsp;Needs a body of water</li>



<li><strong>Hint 3:</strong>&nbsp;Involves catching fish</li>
</ul>



<p>If they don’t help, then here are the nine closest words, going from tenth to second:</p>



<ul>
<li>Hunter</li>



<li>Bait</li>



<li>Trout</li>



<li>Fishery</li>



<li>Sailor</li>



<li>Boat</li>



<li>Boater</li>



<li>Fish</li>



<li>Angler</li>
</ul>







<h2 id="h-today-s-contexto-answer-for-game-1255-on-february-24-2026">Today’s Contexto Answer For Game #1255 On February 24, 2026</h2>



<p>If you’ve tried everything, and still can’t figure out today’s Contexto answer, then you can find it down below:</p>



<p><strong>Answer:</strong> Fisherman</p>



<p>A Fisherman is a person who catches fish for a living or for sport.</p>



<h2 id="h-when-is-the-next-contexto-game-after-1255">When Is The Next Contexto Game After #1255?</h2>



<p><strong>Contexto is updated daily at 12 AM or Midnight in your respective time zone, meaning the next game will start on February 25</strong></p>



<p>The Contexto schedule is very consistent, with a new game releasing at the same time every day.</p>



<hr>



<p>How did you find today’s Contexto? Share your thoughts in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/channels/1433093283558719611/1433112738133180426" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord Server</a>.</p>



<p>For more daily guides, check out IG’s other word game guides:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1711-hints-answer-february-24-2026/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/todays-wordle-1711-hints-answer-february-24-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wordle</a></li>



<li><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-24-989/" id="https://insider-gaming.com/nyt-connections-hints-solutions-february-24-989/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NYT Connections</a></li>
</ul>


        
            

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/todays-contexto-1255-hints-answer-for-february-24-2026/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP - Switch 2 Edition And Upgrade Delayed Again]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-switch-2-edition-and-upgrade-delayed-again</link>
            <guid>1444456</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>No lollipop for you</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="fcf1e455e71ee"><a title="Lollipop Chainsaw" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/fcf1e455e71ee/lollipop-chainsaw.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Dragami Games</em></figcaption></figure><p>In some <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/switch-2-noir-fueled-detective-fps-mouse-p-i-for-hire-has-been-slightly-delayed">other game delay news</a> this week, Dragami Games has announced <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Lollipop Chainsaw RePOP - Switch 2 Edition</a> (and its upgrade pack) will no longer arrive on 26th March 2026.</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://x.com/Dragami_Games/status/2026116124568641634">post on social media</a>, the team has revealed how "significant updates" for both the Switch 2 and Switch release have led to this delay. It doesn't go into any further details about this, but a new release date for Juliet's zombie-slaying adventure on Nintendo's latest hybrid platform will be announced when the team has completed its preparations.</p><div><figure data-videoid="8i2vvu-qeBQ" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8i2vvu-qeBQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="yt8i2vvu-qeBQ" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8i2vvu-qeBQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8i2vvu-qeBQ?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed4c3af8ghntmo&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Here's the developer's notice in full:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[Notice of Release Postponement]</p>
<p>LOLLIPOP CHAINSAW RePOP Nintendo Switch 2 Edition had been scheduled for release on March 26, 2026. However, due to the need for significant updates not only to the Nintendo Switch 2 version but also to the currently released Nintendo Switch version, we have made the difficult decision to postpone the release.</p>
<p>We sincerely apologize for the inconvenience caused to all fans who have been eagerly awaiting this title. We will announce the new release date as soon as preparations are complete.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>According to Dragami's previous update in January, the "Upgrade Pack" for this title (at least in Japan) is set to be a paid release.</p>
<p>When the Switch 2 version does eventually arrive, it will apparently include graphical enhancements, as well as improvements to the performance. Joy-Con 2 mouse support has also been announced and will be featured in an exclusive arcade-style mode, where you'll face off against waves of zombies using Juliet's Chainsaw Blaster and a turret.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:176339,197859 @ 1771932772 -->
<p>How do you feel about this delay? Will you be trying it out on the Switch 2 when it arrives? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer on Nintendo Life. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/lollipop-chainsaw-repop-switch-2-edition-and-upgrade-delayed-again]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon FireRed And LeafGreen Are Already "Best Sellers" On The Switch eShop Charts]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/pokemon-firered-and-leafgreen-are-already-best-sellers-on-the-switch-eshop-charts</link>
            <guid>1444453</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="4f22d1095210f"><a title="Pokémon FireRed and LeafGreen" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/4f22d1095210f/pokemon-firered-and-leafgreen.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Following a surprise announcement at the end of last week, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pokemon_firered_and_leafgreen">Pokémon FireRed and LeafGreen</a> from the Game Boy Advance generation are making a grand return on <strong>27th February 2026</strong>.</p>
<p>There has been a lot of conversation online about the Switch eShop versions, which are priced at <strong>£16.99 / $19.99</strong> each. Some trainers are ready for battle, but others are still questioning why Nintendo didn't make these classics available via the Switch Online service (or give fans both options).</p>
<p>Despite all this back-and-forth, it seems both titles are already making bank on the Switch eShop. Following <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/psa-pokemon-firered-and-leafgreen-switch-preloads-are-now-live">preorders going live last week</a>, we've now taken a look at the eShop, and at the time of writing, these GBA titles have already topped the Switch charts in the US, UK, Japan and Australia. <em>So, there's definitely some interest!</em></p><div><figure data-videoid="RLc1VHm8D80" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe id="ytRLc1VHm8D80" title="YouTube Video" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RLc1VHm8D80?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed43f22fxjhnrw&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>842k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<figure data-uuid="573b189aefb29"><a title="Pokémon FireRed and LeafGreen" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/573b189aefb29/pokemon-firered-and-leafgreen.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em><span></span> Image: Nintendo</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>As you may have already guessed, Pokémon FireRed (repping the Fire/Flying type Charizard) is leading the charge, with Pokémon LeafGreen in second place.</p>
<p>Nintendo has confirmed these Switch versions of the games will contain <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/we-thought-it-would-be-fun-nintendo-explains-why-pokemon-firered-and-leafgreen-arent-on-switch-online">the same content as the original releases</a>, and you can expect some modern solutions for the connectivity features. Support for <strong><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/pokemon_home">Pokémon Home</a></strong> has also been confirmed, and these titles can be played while using the GameChat feature.</p>
<p>Although these releases might be easy money for Nintendo, this doesn't necessarily guarantee we can expect to see other first-party retro titles on the eShop. According to an <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/we-thought-it-would-be-fun-nintendo-explains-why-pokemon-firered-and-leafgreen-arent-on-switch-online">official FAQ</a>, this is a special case marking Pokémon's 30th anniversary, and there are seemingly no plans to revive "Virtual Console types of offerings".</p>
<p>Nintendo says it intends to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/nintendo-seemingly-rules-out-virtual-console-revival-says-it-remains-focused-on-offering-classics-via-switch-online">remain focused on offering retro releases</a> for its Switch Online subscription service going forward.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/switch-eshop/related-articles:197795,197768,197796,197746 @ 1771933710 -->
<p>Have you pre-ordered these games yet? Which version are you planning to revisit? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/pokemon-firered-and-leafgreen-are-already-best-sellers-on-the-switch-eshop-charts]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Switch 2 Noir-Fueled Detective FPS 'Mouse: P.I. For Hire' Has Been Slightly Delayed]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/switch-2-noir-fueled-detective-fps-mouse-p-i-for-hire-has-been-slightly-delayed</link>
            <guid>1444441</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>April is the new March</p>
</section></header><section>

<p>The noir-style cartoon detective FPS <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mouse-p-i-for-hire">Mouse: P.I. for Hire</a> was scheduled to arrive on Switch 2 next month, but it seems there's been a slight delay.</p>
<p>Instead of its 19th March 2026 release, this title will launch for Nintendo's new hybrid system (and other platforms) on <strong>16th April 2026</strong>. In a new <a href="https://x.com/mousethegame/status/2026046752693092801">notice on social media</a>, Fumi Games &amp; PlaySide Studios says it wants to deliver the best game possible and just needs a few more weeks:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"As we approach the final stages of development, we want to ensure we are taking the extra time and care needed to make Mouse: P.I. for Hire an experience to remember. We remain unwavering in our goal to deliver you the best game we can, and that will take just an extra few weeks."</p></blockquote><blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>The same update mentions how the team is excited to share "more of the game" with followers in the lead-up to the release, so expect more updates soon! This isn't actually the first time Mouse: P.I. for Hire has been delayed. It also follows the announcement of the Switch 2 version in October last year.</p>
<p>You can find out a little more about this game in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/vintage-shooter-mouse-p-i-for-hire-blasts-onto-switch-2-in-march-2026">our previous story here on Nintendo Life</a> and an official developer "deep dive" documentary below. When it arrives, players can apparently expect "fast-paced FPS combat" and a thrilling single-player campaign with over 20 levels.</p>

<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:193107 @ 1771933941 -->
<p>Will you be checking out this game when it arrives in April? <em>Tell us below.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer on Nintendo Life. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2026/02/switch-2-noir-fueled-detective-fps-mouse-p-i-for-hire-has-been-slightly-delayed]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>