<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 18:36:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 76 Fans Should Be Excited About This Datamined Feature]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-76-fans-datamined-feature-pets/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-76-fans-should-be-excited-about-this-datamined-feature.921825/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-76-fans-datamined-feature-pets/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>This one has been a long time coming. </p>



<p>Fallout 76 has enjoyed a few months of rampant popularity thanks to the wildfire success of the Fallout TV series. From April onwards, Fallout 76’s player count skyrocketed on all platforms, and the community blew up overnight. It also helps that Bethesda Game Studios has pumped the post-apocalyptic MMORPG full of content updates, which has helped to keep things fresh and keep players engaged.</p>



<p>In a recent effort by a dataminer, it was found that a future update could bring about a major update that Fallout 76 fans have been holding out for since 2021.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-never-go-alone">Never Go Alone</h2>



<p>In 2021, Bethesda Game Studios laid out a bunch of plans regarding Fallout 76, and one of the items on that list was a companion mechanic that would allow players to run around with <strong>pets</strong>. It’s a common enough feature for MMORPGs, and even Fallout 76’s ‘sister MMO’, The Elder Scrolls Online, has a pet system – but they’re ‘non-combat’ pets.</p>



<p>Recently, <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/it-looks-like-fallout-76-is-finally-getting-one-of-its-most-requested-features" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Windows Central reported</a> on a datamining claim from a user named SugarBombsRADS. In a Discord server dedicated to uncovering unreleased content in Fallout 76’s files, this user found an image related to pets. It was one of the iconic ‘tutorial’ style images from Fallout 76, the three-image banner that explains how <strong>something </strong>works in the game. </p>



<p>Here’s the shot:</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>While ‘Allies’ have existed in Fallout 76 for quite some time, they’re unable to leave a player’s C.A.M.P., which often leaves Vault Dwellers feeling lonesome in the harsh and unwelcoming wasteland. The introduction of companions that can roam alongside users will be a game-changer, and the images suggest that it could go beyond just cats and dogs, with Vault Boy cuddling up to a Deathclaw.</p>



<p>It also seems that there will be interactions that the player can perform with their pet, treating them like Dogmeat in Fallout 4, for example. Can you imagine if you could assume control of a Scorchbeast or something and walk around with it by your side?</p>



<p>As with anything datamined, this content is unconfirmed and may never see the light of day, but it’s nice to know that after all this time, it’s potentially on the horizon.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, read about&nbsp;the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/witcher-3-character-creator-mod/">awesome new Witcher 3 mod</a> and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Create Your Own Witcher 3 Character With a New Mod]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/witcher-3-character-creator-mod/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/create-your-own-witcher-3-character-with-a-new-mod.921822/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/witcher-3-character-creator-mod/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>It was around two months ago that CDPR opened up the REDkit for modders focused on The Witcher 3. This invaluable resource serves as a free add-on to The Wild Hunt, giving modders unprecedented control over the game, and we’ve already seen some stunning creations emerge. Now, a new mod has surfaced called Custom Player Characters, and as the title suggests, it allows players to create their custom character with which they’ll enjoy 2015’s The Witcher 3: The Wild Hunt.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-change-everything">Change Everything</h2>



<p>I don’t know why you’d want to, but if you’ve ever imagined stripping Geralt of Rivia from his role in The Witcher 3 and playing as a fresh character, this is the mod for you. The Custom Player Characters mod, <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/witcher3/mods/5940" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">published by nikich340 on Nexus Mods</a> recently, allows users to build their player character from the ground up.</p>



<p>It’s pretty boundless – you can be a sorceress, a different Witcher, or something else entirely. With the character creation elements unlocked by the REDkit-backed mod, you can assume a completely different identity, and when combined with other mods (voice-based ones), you can even change how Geralt sounds, adopting a female voice if you’d like.</p>



<p>The Custom Player Characters mod even utilises new, ‘retargeted’ animations that make female bodies move more accurately. Also, if you choose to be a Sorceress, you’ll pick up a fresh magic-based combat system, assuming control of a set of spells that improve the more you use them.</p>



<p>It’s one of the most ambitious mods I’ve ever seen for The Witcher 3 – who will you play as?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/blumhouse-games-reveals-plans-for-future-titles-adaptations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Blumhouse Games revealing plans</a>&nbsp;for its slate of future titles in a new interview and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a></p>





									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dr Disrespect Cosmetics Pulled From Free-To-Play Shooter Following Allegations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dr-disrespect-cosmetics-pulled-from-free-to-play-shooter-following-allegations/1100-6524758/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dr-disrespect-cosmetics-pulled-from-free-to-play-shooter-following-allegations.921819/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dr-disrespect-cosmetics-pulled-from-free-to-play-shooter-following-allegations/1100-6524758/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524758">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/rogue-company/" data-ref-id="5000-501899">Rogue Company</a>, a free-to-play hero shooter from Smite and Paladins publisher Hi-Rez Studios, is removing its $20 Dr Disrespect skin from sale and refunding players who may have purchased it in the wake of allegations regarding the streamer having sent "inappropriate" messages to a minor in 2017.</p><p dir="ltr">In a statement posted by the official <a href="https://x.com/RogueCompany/status/1810028535882342577" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Rogue Company X account</a>, players were informed the skin had been disabled and refunds (in the form of Rogue Bucks) would be rolling out later this week for those who may have purchased the Dr Disrespect content.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HhObRmTB8Zw" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/HhObRmTB8Zw" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p dir="ltr">Dr Disrespect was heavily involved in the promotion of Rogue Company, and even collaborated on a map for the game in 2020 called The Arena alongside the debut of the game's official Dr Disrespect skin. It's currently unclear if the Dr Disrepect map, which heavily features his likeness, will also be removed, but it seems likely.</p><p dir="ltr">The streamer, whose real name is Guy Beahm, was banned from Twitch in 2020. His exclusive streaming contract with the streaming platform was also terminated, prompting Beahm to sue Twitch and later receive a settlement from the Amazon-owned company. At the time, the reasons for his ban were unknown, and Beahm himself claimed he was unaware of why he was banned from the platform.</p><p dir="ltr">However, following a number of recent reports from former Twitch employees who alleged Beahm had been involved in sending messages to a minor and attempting to meet up with them at TwitchCon, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dr-disrespect-addresses-misconduct-allegations-after-turtle-beach-ends-partnership/1100-6524501/" data-ref-id="1100-6524501">Beahm himself admitted to some of allegations</a>. He confirmed he did send what he called "inappropriate messages" to a minor, but said he never did anything "illegal" and did not meet the minor in question.</p><p dir="ltr">Since the allegations surfaced, a number of partners and brands have parted ways with Dr Disrespect, including Turtle Beach and the game studio he co-founded, The Midnight Society, which is working on an extraction shooter called Deadrop that was heavily promoted by the streamer. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dr-disrespects-twitch-ban-was-reportedly-due-to-messaging-a-minor/1100-6524455/" data-ref-id="1100-6524455">The Midnight Society in a statement said it was terminating its relationship with Dr Disrespect</a> immediately after investigating the allegations, and that "while these facts are difficult to hear and even more difficult to accept, it is our duty to act with dignity on behalf of all individuals involved, especially the 55 developers and families we have employed alongside our community of players."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft’s Xbox TV app now available on Amazon’s Fire TV Sticks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/8/24194333/microsoft-xbox-tv-app-xbox-cloud-gaming-amazon-fire-tv-stick-available-download</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft%E2%80%99s-xbox-tv-app-now-available-on-amazon%E2%80%99s-fire-tv-sticks.921801/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/8/24194333/microsoft-xbox-tv-app-xbox-cloud-gaming-amazon-fire-tv-stick-available-download<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Microsoft is launching its Xbox TV app on select Amazon Fire TV Sticks today. The app, which Microsoft first <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/27/24187164/xbox-cloud-gaming-tv-app-fire-tv-stick-amazon-launch">announced last month</a>, provides access to Xbox Cloud Gaming, allowing subscribers of Xbox Game Pass Ultimate to stream a variety of Xbox titles to some Fire TV devices.</p><p>The Xbox app will initially be available only on the Fire TV 4K Max (2023) and Fire TV Stick 4K (2023) and will be identical to the same app available on Samsung’s recent TVs and monitors. All you’ll need is a compatible Fire TV Stick, a Bluetooth-enabled wireless controller, and an Xbox Game Pass Ultimate subscription to stream Xbox games.</p><p>Microsoft is working to allow Xbox Cloud Gaming to stream your entire Xbox library, and not just titles that are part of Game Pass. That’s expected to arrive in the coming months, albeit likely with some games excluded due to publishers that aren’t willing to be part of Xbox Cloud Gaming.</p><div><figcaption><em>The Xbox TV app is also available on Samsung TVs and monitors.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Microsoft</cite></p></div><div><p>Microsoft previously promised that Xbox Cloud Gaming would&nbsp;<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/9/23159492/xbox-game-pass-cloud-gaming-library-owned-games-feature">support your existing game library by the end of 2022</a>, but that has been significantly delayed. Microsoft also&nbsp;<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/6/22/23770460/microsoft-xbox-xcloud-gaming-subscription">scrapped plans</a>&nbsp;to launch a dedicated subscription version of Xbox Cloud Gaming, and a dedicated <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/26/24186639/microsoft-xbox-cloud-console-keystone-patent-images">Xbox cloud gaming console</a> was canceled due to pricing issues.</p></div><p>The Xbox app launch on Amazon’s Fire TV Sticks marks the first time such an app has launched on a device other than Samsung’s TVs and monitors. Microsoft has been leaning into getting its Xbox TV app on more devices, rather than producing cloud gaming hardware. Microsoft also worked with Meta to launch an Xbox Cloud Gaming app <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/13/24000134/xbox-cloud-gaming-meta-quest-3-vr-headset">for Quest VR headsets</a>, and I’d expect to see this same Xbox app continue to show up on more devices in the future.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apex Legends Doubles The Price Of Keeping Up With Battle Passes In What It Promises Is A Good Deal For Players]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apex-legends-battle-pass-season-22-premium-ac-1851581142</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apex-legends-doubles-the-price-of-keeping-up-with-battle-passes-in-what-it-promises-is-a-good-deal-for-players.921786/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/apex-legends-battle-pass-season-22-premium-ac-1851581142<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Apex Legends</em> is revamping how its battle pass economy works in season 22 and it sounds expensive. Every season will now have two premium battle passes starting at $10 each and Apex Coins (AC) can no longer be used to purchase them. Weirdest of all is the fact that Respawn Entertainment seems to be presenting this all as good news for players.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196653" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="105" data-playlist="196653,194143,196626" data-current="196653"><div><p>The Week In Games: A Star Wars Classic Returns &amp; More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196653/196653_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22209.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/apex-legends-ranked-season-20-changes-rp-lp-mmr-trials-1851225999&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/apex-legends-ranked-season-20-changes-rp-lp-mmr-trials-1851225999">Here’s how <em>Apex Legends</em></a></span> battle passes have worked up through the current season 21: Upheaval. Every season there’s been a new pass with 110 ranks’ worth of rewards spread across three months. Players can grind the free track for the free rewards or pay 950 AC (roughly $10) to access the premium rewards as well. They can also go ahead and buy the Premium Battle Pass Bundle for 2800 AC (roughly $30) which includes the first 10 levels of the battle pass auto-completed and a bunch of additional rewards that aren’t included in it.</p><p>Here’s how it will work beginning with season 22 in August, as outlined in a new blog post <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ea.com/games/apex-legends/news/battle-pass-update&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ea.com/games/apex-legends/news/battle-pass-update" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">over on the<em> Apex Legends</em> website</a></span>. There will be two separate battle passes per season that have 60 ranks each. They will still cost $10 but can only be purchased for IRL money instead of AC. The Premium Battle Pass Bundle has been replaced by the Premium+ option which is $20 per battle pass and comes with 10 unlocked ranks plus 2 Legendary skin variants that are exclusive for a year, 10 Exotic Shards, and all Legends playable for the duration of the Battle Pass. The change comes alongside revamped battle pass rewards more generally to make the best rewards quicker to earn and more plentiful. </p><figure id="" data-id="fed6117e4fd69e7984645e668d00488e" data-recommend-id="image://fed6117e4fd69e7984645e668d00488e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1456" data-height="819" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A chart shows how Apex Legends seasons are changing. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A chart shows how Apex Legends seasons are changing. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Respawn Entertainment</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="fed6117e4fd69e7984645e668d00488e" data-recommend-id="image://fed6117e4fd69e7984645e668d00488e" data-format="jpg" data-width="1456" data-height="819" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A chart shows how Apex Legends seasons are changing. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>These and other changes have been summarized in a chart that looks as convoluted as you’d expect from an EA-published game. “We’ve seen the numbers, and things need to be more approachable and realistic for our global player community,” the blog post reads. “Each of these updated aspects allows us to make the Battle Pass more attainable and valuable for your time and money.” </p><p>But that value has come at a price. “To up the value going forward, each Premium Track Battle Pass will cost $9.99 USD and will come with the rewards expanded on above,” the post continues. “The decision to move from AC to real world currency is not one that we made lightly, but it does allow us to decrease the price of Premium+ for our community.” Despite the use of “decrease” there, players who want to stay current on their battle passes will actually be spending $40 per season rather than $30. Respawn did not immediately respond to a request for further clarification. </p><p>The move away from letting people purchase battle passes with AC is also likely to go over with the community like a lead balloon. Previously, dedicated players were able to take AC earned from previous seasons and invest it in new battle passes, essentially paying the grind forward and earning rewards with time and dedication instead of new spending. It’s not surprising that a company trying to make money would shut that down, but it’s hard to see how it nets out to a big win for players. Fans who play daily and want the full package will essentially now be paying the price of an<em> Elden Ring: Shadow of the Erdtree </em>DLC every three months. </p><p><em>Apex Legends</em> is far from the first game to effectively raise the price of its seasonal content. <em>Fortnite</em>, <em>Destiny 2</em>, and other games have increased the price of in-game currencies and season passes in the last year following a historic spike in inflation, or at least that’s what some of the companies behind those increases <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/fortnite-v-bucks-price-increase-season-1-map-1850966590&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/fortnite-v-bucks-price-increase-season-1-map-1850966590">said at the time</a></span>. EA, which now makes more money off of microtransactions than actually selling new games, earned <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2023/Electronic-Arts-Reports-Q4-and-FY23-Results/default.aspx&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2023/Electronic-Arts-Reports-Q4-and-FY23-Results/default.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$800 million</a></span> in net income in 2023. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Descendant Is A Fun But Forgettable Mash-up Of Better Games]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/first-descendant-looter-shooter-review-is-it-good-nexon-1851581126</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-descendant-is-a-fun-but-forgettable-mash-up-of-better-games.921783/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/first-descendant-looter-shooter-review-is-it-good-nexon-1851581126<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>The First Descendant,</em> Nexon’s new third-person sci-fi free-to-play online looter shooter is a lot like a bowl of so-so mac and cheese. I promise that opening sentence will make some sense by the end of this article, okay? </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195928" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="How Alan Wake 2 Builds Upon The 'Remedy-Verse'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="190" data-playlist="195928,196251,196395" data-current="195928"><div><p>How Alan Wake 2 Builds Upon The 'Remedy-Verse'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195928/195928_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195928/195928_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195928/195928_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195928/195928_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21446.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Released earlier this month on PS5, Xbox Series X/S, and PC, <em>The First Descendant</em> tells the story of a group of special, powerful people with cool abilities who are “descended” from ancient god-like beings. These special people—the Descendants—are the key to saving humanity and use their abilities (as well as guns and explosives) to fight back an invading alien force and giant inter-dimensional monsters. I’d tell you more but there’s not much more to explain. If this setup sounds a lot like other sci-fi movies or games, well you’ve picked up on what<em> The First Descendant</em> really is: a mish-mash of what came before combined into a package that is fun to play but hard to recommend.<br></p><p>Every part of <em>The First Descendant </em>feels like it was ripped out of other pre-existing live-service shooters, like <em>Destiny, Warframe, The Division, </em>and <em>Anthem</em>. You zip around levels like the space ninjas in <em>Warframe</em>, the combat is tight and snappy like <em>The Division</em>’s third-person gunplay, and many powers and abilities feel directly inspired by <em>Destiny</em>. (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/first-descendant-destiny-2-warframe-plagiarism-copy-1851580751&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/first-descendant-destiny-2-warframe-plagiarism-copy-1851580751">And some of the game looks to be literally ripped from Bungie’s FPS</a></span>…)<br></p><p><em>First Descendant </em>also lacks a consistent art style, beyond “just do what other games did.” The post-apocalyptic worlds you explore across the game’s main campaign don’t really gel with the anime heroes and their various cosmetic items. Similarly, <em>First Descendant</em> has a strange collection of enemy designs made up of baddies who appear to have fallen out of games like <em>Anthem, Destiny, </em>and <em>Outriders</em>. Some enemies look and act like creatures, others are more mechanical and robotic, a few look like weird space zombies, and then some are just dudes in hazmat suits. I was never really sure what I was fighting or how they all connected to each other beyond apparently being part of some big evil alien empire. And most stuff dies so fast that I didn’t really <em>need</em> to know what I was shooting.<br></p><p>As with all the games I’ve mentioned so far, <em>First Descendant </em>can be played solo or online with other players. Like <em>Destiny</em>, the open worlds you visit will contain other players who you can play with or ignore. These open worlds feature three to four missions that ask you to protect something, kill some stuff, collect a few things, or destroy a target. Repeat until you reach a larger, more involved mission aka an “Operation” aka a Strike from <em>Destiny. </em>And once you’ve done all that, the story moves forward a bit and you do it all again in a new location.<br></p><p>It’s mind-numbingly dull and if you’ve played any of these live-service looter shooters you’ll have done this song and dance a thousand times before. As with its story, art, enemies, and gameplay, <em>First Descendant </em>breaks no new ground or tries to do anything unique. It checks all the boxes it needs to check to be considered an online RPG shooter and doesn’t do much more.<br></p><p>And yet I keep playing. Not just because it’s my job and I have to play <em>First Descendant</em>. No, I keep playing even though there are other games I want to play instead. It’s not just because the game’s grappling hook feels nice and makes traversing its boring worlds a bit more enjoyable, though that helps. It’s not solely down to wanting to see numbers go up, though there’s plenty of that in Nexon’s shooter for those who love that kind of thing. <em>First Descendent </em>is like a bowl of mac and cheese at a crappy restaurant. Yes, I’m finally going to explain the metaphor.<br></p><figure id="" data-id="7995ad857b389c38f2f2287eaee606fd" data-recommend-id="image://7995ad857b389c38f2f2287eaee606fd" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows a character running as seen in The First Descendant. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An image shows a character running as seen in The First Descendant. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nexon</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7995ad857b389c38f2f2287eaee606fd" data-recommend-id="image://7995ad857b389c38f2f2287eaee606fd" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="An image shows a character running as seen in The First Descendant. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>I have a theory that as long as the noodles are cooked and there’s some cheese in the bowl, you can’t really be too mad at some warm macaroni and cheese. Sure, you can do more with mac and cheese. You can add bacon, bread crumbs, multiple cheeses, experiment with noodles, spices, sauces, etc. But in its most basic, by-the-book, no-thrills form, a bowl of mac is good and I’ll eat without complaint every time.<br></p><p>That’s how I feel playing <em>First Descendant.</em> It’s like eating a bowl of totally fine mac and cheese. In the moment, I enjoy it. I’m happy that I’m eating/playing. Yay, mac and cheese! Yay, snappy combat and loot! But the moment I pull myself away from<em> The First Descendant, </em>I quickly forget about it. It provides some comfort, sure, but ultimately, it offers nothing memorable or exciting. It does what it’s meant to do, it checks those boxes, and that’s it. Like a boring bowl of mac at some fast food joint or a friend’s house. Just enough to make you happy, but quickly forgotten.<br></p><p>So do I recommend you play <em>First Descendant</em>? Not really. If you’ve played <em>Destiny </em>or <em>Warframe </em>or other similar games it offers nothing new and does little to stand out. I guess if you’ve burned yourself out on other live-service shooters, it might be nice to take a break from those grinds and check out this new shiny grind instead. Still, I don’t think <em>First Descendant </em>will keep these kinds of players around for long, especially as its endgame treadmill to unlock new characters seems like a horrible slog and one which Nexon will gladly let you pay your way around.<br></p><p>But<em> The First Descendant </em>is also free and you might be thinking “Why not? I’ll give it a shot.” And I can’t blame you. If I was offered a free bowl of mac and cheese, all gooey and warm, I’d probably say yes, too. Just don’t expect any breadcrumbs or gouda. </p><p>&nbsp;.<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Strangest Lightsabers in the Star Wars Universe: From Dark Rey to Vernestra Rwoh]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/rey-double-red-lightsaber-star-wars-blade-pike-whip-switch-strangest</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-strangest-lightsabers-in-the-star-wars-universe-from-dark-rey-to-vernestra-rwoh.921777/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/rey-double-red-lightsaber-star-wars-blade-pike-whip-switch-strangest<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><em><strong>Warning:</strong></em><em> This article contains spoilers for Star Wars: The Acolyte Episode 5!</em></p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2015/05/27/star-wars-school-the-history-of-the-lightsaber">The lightsaber</a> is undoubtedly one of the coolest (albeit sadly nonexistent) weapons in all of pop culture. What's not to love about a laser sword that can cut through anything yet easily stow away in your pocket when not in use? Though as we've seen many times in the Star Wars universe, some Jedi and Sith aren't content to stick to the traditional lightsaber design. The Acolyte is just the latest Star Wars project to continue that proud tradition.</p><p>From double-bladed lightsabers to lightsaber pikes to a lightsaber rifle (?), here are the strangest and most noteworthy lightsaber designs in the Star Wars franchise, including a few from the classic Legends continuity.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The Strangest Lightsabers in the Star Wars Universe</h3></div></output><h2>Lumiya's Light-Whip</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/01-Lumiya-720x404.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>You have to give Marvel Comics credit for thinking outside the box on this one. Long before the days of villains like Darth Maul and Kylo Ren, 1985's Star Wars #95 featured one of the most unusual lightsaber designs ever conceived. Lumiya, former protege of Darth Vader himself, constructed a whip based on ancient Sith designs. Built from a combination of unbreakable Mandalorian iron and lightsaber crystals, this weapon is the only lightsaber that creates a flexible beam. Lumiya nearly overwhelmed Luke with this deadly weapon, forcing him to wield two sabers at once to stand a chance in battle.</p><h2>The Double-Bladed Lightsaber</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/02-Darth-Maul-720x404.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>The concept of a double-bladed lightsaber was introduced prior to The Phantom Menace, but this movie brought that weapon into the mainstream thanks to Darth Maul. Maul showed how deadly this weapon can be in the right hands, dominating two powerful Jedi at once. Similar doubled-bladed sabers have been used by characters like Savage Opress and Satele Shan.</p><h2>The Lightsaber Pike</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/Jedi-Temple-Guards-720x405.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>One of the more interesting variations of the double-bladed lightsaber is the lightsaber pike, a weapon used by the guards at the Jedi Temple on Coruscant. With a longer hilt and shorter blades, these sabers are designed to be used more like a staff than a traditional sword. The hilts also fold in half in a switchblade-style design, one that's started becoming more popular in the Star Wars universe.</p><h2>Pong Krell's Sabers</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/Pong-Krell-720x404.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Star Wars: The Clone Wars introduced a corrupt Jedi Master named Pong Krell who puts his own spin on the double-bladed lightsaber design. Krell's saber blades are longer, like Maul's, but the hilts fold in half, like the lightsaber pike. Krell is also the rare Jedi capable of wielding two double-bladed sabers at once, a feat only possible because of his incredible strength and extra arms.</p><h2>Mace Windu's Purple Saber</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/03-Mace-Windu-720x405.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Canonically, there's only one Jedi cool enough to wield a purple-bladed lightsaber. Lightsaber crystals almost always come in green, blue or red varieties, making Mace's saber quite the collector's item. We can't help but wonder what became of the weapon after Anakin sliced Mace's arm off in Revenge of the Sith.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2>Count Dooku's Saber</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/04-Count-Dooku-720x405.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Count Dooku was regarded as one of the finest swordsmen in the galaxy before defecting to the Sith. His lightsaber hilt features a unique, curved design, allowing for precise motions and strikes. This enhances the fencing-inspired fighting style Dooku has perfected. His protege, Asajj Ventress, wields a pair of similar sabers, though never quite as skillfully as her master.</p><h2>Darth Sidious' Sabers</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/05-Darth-Sidious-720x404.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Darth Sidious's sabers stand out both for their ornamental design and the fact that the hilts are so short. That makes sense, given that Sidious has taken great pains to conceal his Sith powers and keeps his sabers concealed within the folds of his robes.</p><h2>Ahsoka Tano's Sabers</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/06-Ahsoka-Tano-720x405.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>When Ahsoka Tano first appeared in Star Wars: The Clone Wars, she wielded a traditional green saber. But as the series progressed and Ahsoka became more confident in her abilities, she switched to the Jar'Kai style of combat, which focuses on dual sabers. Like a samurai, Ahsoka carries a standard-length blade and a shorter blade known as a shoto. Star Wars Rebels further sets her apart by making Ahsoka one of the rare Jedi to wield white lightsaber blades, with the blades also appearing in the live-action shows The Mandalorian and Star Wars: Ahsoka.</p><h2>Maris Brood's Sabers</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/07-Maris-Brood-720x1154.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Star Wars: The Force Unleashed introduced Maris Brood, a Jedi Padawan who falls to the Dark Side after the death of her master, Shaak Ti. Brood's twin sabers are inspired by tonfa sticks, with a perpendicular hilt design that allow her to hold her sabers at unusual angles.</p><h2>The Darksaber</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/08-Darksaber-720x405.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>The Darksaber is one of the oldest known lightsaber weapons in the Star Wars universe. Its archaic design results in a flat, angled blade that glows black and makes a distinctive hum. This blade has a long history with the warriors of Mandalore. Its creator, Tarre Vizsla, was the first Mandalorian inducted into the Jedi Order, and it's since been used by Mandalorians like Pre Vizsla and Sabine Wren. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/12/27/the-mandalorian-darksaber-moff-gideon-bo-katan-episode-8-black-lightsaber">The Darksaber also shows up in The Mandalorian's Season 1 finale</a> and played a key role in subsequent seasons.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2>Darth Malgus' Saber</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/09-Darth-Malgus-720x405.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Ancient Sith Lord Darth Malgus has one of the few lightsabers that can probably kill a man even when it's deactivated. The top of the hilt features two blade-like protrusions that make it seem as though Malgus carries an ax on the battlefield.</p><h2>Darth Chratis' Saber</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/10-Darth-Chratis-720x405.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Another powerful Sith Lord of the Old Republic era, Darth Chratis is notable for carrying a metal staff than can collapse in half and emit a lightsaber blade. The unusually long hilt gives Chratis extra reach in battle.</p><h2>Darth Bane's Lightsaber Pike</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/Sith_warrior_lightsaber_pike_bts-720x602.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>While the weapon the Jedi Temple Guards wield is called a lightsaber pike, The Clone Wars almost introduced a weapon even more in line with a traditional pike. This concept art shows the weapon intended to be used by Darth Bane in the Season 6 episode "Sacrifice." It's basically a long staff that emits a broad, tapered blade. But while Bane himself did appear in that episode, his weapon never made the cut.</p><h2>The Grand Inquisitor's Saber</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/11-Inquisitor-720x405.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Star Wars Rebels introduced the Inquistorius, an order of Dark Jedi charged with helping Vader wipe out the last of the Jedi. Each of these villains is equipped with a multi-purpose lightsaber. The hilt resembles nothing if not an identity disc from Tron, though it can also fold in half so that it looks like the hilt of a cutlass. These sabers can be used in either single or double-bladed mode. These weapons can also double as, well, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5sOvNYYH6Cs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">personal helicopters</a>.</p><h2>Kylo Ren's Saber</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/12-Kylo-Ren-720x404.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Kylo Ren wields an unusual crossguard saber that reflects his own unstable nature. The crystal powering his saber is cracked, requiring ports on either side of the hilt to vent the excess heat and plasma. The advantage is that Kylo's saber has two extra blades (or quillons) that he often uses to his advantage in battle.</p><h2>The Lightsaber Rifle</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/13-Jocasta-Nu-720x405.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>Jedi librarian Jocasta Nu may not seem capable of going toe-to-toe with Darth Vader and his Inquisitors, but she's a surprisingly scrappy fighter when the need arises. Jocasta leveled the playing field by attaching her ordinary blue lightsaber to a specially designed rifle. That rifle uses the lightsaber as fuel for its incredibly destructive blasts. Unfortunately, the rifle can only fire so many shots before the lightsaber burns itself out.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2>Rey's Switchblade Saber</h2><a href="https://oyster.ignimgs.com/wordpress/stg.ign.com/2019/08/14-Rey-720x405.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>In The Rise of Skywalker, Rey has a vision of herself wielding this deadly double-bladed lightsaber. This special weapon folds in half like Pong Krell and the Jedi Temple Guards' weapons, but the twist is that it can still be used as a twin-bladed weapon even folded. Now that it's been shown in the films (albeit as a vision), it's only a matter of time before we see someone wielding a similar blade for real.</p><h2>Vernestra Rwoh's Light-Whip</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/08/vernestra-using-lightwhip-1720452874764.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>While Lumiya has yet to make the jump from the classic Legends timeline to Disney's official Star Wars universe, the lightsaber whip has been canonized thanks to the High Republic initiative. A young Vernestra Rwoh wields one of these weapons in the books, while a much older version of the character appears (along with her saber) in The Acolyte.</p><h2>Qimir's Modular Lightsaber</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/08/pdx-062297-r-1720452887425.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>The Acolyte introduces Qimir/The Stranger, a Jedi-hating villain with a few tricks up his nonexistent sleeves. In addition to wearing a helmet and gauntlet made of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-acolyte-cortosis-powerful-lightsaber-battle-tool-live-action-debut">the lightsaber-shorting substance known as cortosis</a>, Qimir wields a red saber with a detachable secondary hilt. This allows Qimir to fight with a standard saber and a shorter shoto, similar to Ahsoka Tano.</p><p>For more on The Acolyte, check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-the-acolyte-review-disney-plus">our review of the first four episodes</a>, then find out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-the-acolyte-episode-3-the-last-jedi-theme">how the show continues the most important theme of The Last Jedi </a>and learn <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/with-two-episodes-left-the-acolyte-has-us-wondering-who-the-villain-really-is">why The Acolyte has us questioning who the real villain is</a>.</p><p><em>Jesse is a mild-mannered writer for IGN. Allow him to lend a machete to your intellectual thicket by </em><a href="https://twitter.com/jschedeen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>following @jschedeen on Twitter</em></a><em>.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Witcher 3 Mod Lets You Play as Fully Customizable Witcher or Sorceress with New Magic Combat System]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/witcher-3-mod-lets-you-play-as-fully-customizable-witcher-or-sorceress-with-new-magic-combat-system</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/witcher-3-mod-lets-you-play-as-fully-customizable-witcher-or-sorceress-with-new-magic-combat-system.921774/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/witcher-3-mod-lets-you-play-as-fully-customizable-witcher-or-sorceress-with-new-magic-combat-system<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>A mod for <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt">The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt</a> has added not just a fully customizable main character but also the option to play as a sorceress, which comes with its own quest line, combat system, and more.</p><p><a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/witcher3/mods/5940" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NexusMods user nikich340</a> created the Custom Player Characters mod, which lets players step away from role-playing Geralt of Rivia and instead create their own unique protagonist. Every character model in the game can be pulled from, with players able to mix and match body parts to create their ideal monster slayer.</p><p>The most impressive part of the mod comes in the sorceress additions, however. Not only can players, again, pull from every model in the game to create a custom character, but the mod adds its own combat system separate to how the main game plays.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The Witcher 3: Wild Hunt Custom Player Characters Mod by nikich340</h3></div></output><p>Instead of swinging swords at baddies, players instead wield spells such as blasting lightning, summoning tornadoes, and even turning into a cat. Abilities outside of combat allow portals to be made or lights to be cast in dark areas. A custom quest line walks players through these spells and teaches them new ones too.</p><p>This mod comes after the release of REDkit: <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-3-official-mod-support-arrives-this-month">an official modding tool for The Witcher 3 released by CD Projekt in May 2024</a>. The developer announced REDkit in November 2023, saying "it will allow you to create your own experiences in the game by making something completely new or editing existing quests and content."</p><p>REDkit has so far been used to create some wild and wacky mods for The Witcher 3, including <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/forget-roach-this-witcher-3-wild-hunt-mod-lets-you-ride-a-vicious-fiend">one that lets Geralt ride an enormous fiend instead of Roach</a> and another that <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/get-a-taste-of-the-witcher-remake-with-mod-that-puts-original-games-maps-in-the-witcher-3">recreates the original game in The Witcher 3's engine</a> ahead of <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-remake-will-be-open-world-cd-projekt-red-confirms">an official remake</a>. The most exciting addition so far perhaps comes through <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt-modder-restores-secret-ending-scrapped-by-cd-projekt">the discovery of a scrapped ending sequence, which was revived</a> using the toolkit.</p><p>Mods will be the only new content coming to The Witcher 3 going forward, of course, as while the game received <a href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/the-witcher-3-wild-hunt/Biggest_Changes_in_the_Next-Gen_Update">a PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X and S update in December 2022</a>, it otherwise won't get any more official content as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/every-cd-projekt-red-game-in-development">CD Projekt focuses on its wealth of other incoming projects</a>.</p><p>The highly anticipated next mainline Witcher game, codenamed Polaris, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-4-polaris-development-cd-projekt">is currently in development</a> but won't arrive until <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-4-polaris-is-at-least-three-years-away">2025 at the absolute earliest, and probably later</a>. There are two other Witcher games on the horizon too, including <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/the-witcher-remake-will-be-open-world-cd-projekt-red-confirms">the aforementioned remake of the original The Witcher</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/witcher-spin-off-project-sirius-has-a-new-framework-following-development-restart">a multiplayer spin-off</a>.</p><p><em>Image Credit: </em><a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/witcher3/mods/5940" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>nikich340 on NexusMods</em></a></p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[College Football 25: EA Sports Provides a First Look of Gameplay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-ea-sports-provides-a-first-look-of-gameplay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/college-football-25-ea-sports-provides-a-first-look-of-gameplay.921771/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-ea-sports-provides-a-first-look-of-gameplay<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>With roughly a week to go until <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/college-football-25">College Football 25</a> is released, EA Sports has shared the first look at gameplay for the upcoming college football simulation game.</p><p>The gameplay shows two people playing a match: college football content creator James "BordeauxYT" Bordeaux and Donovan Edwards. The latter is a running back for the University of Michigan Football team and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-25-release-date">one of three cover athletes for College Football 25</a>. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>In addition to voiceovers from Bordeaux and Edwards, we also have some commentary from EA Madden Championship Series broadcaster Nick Mizesko, College Football 25's design director Scott O'Gallagher, and gameplay designer Will Sykes.</p><p>To accompany the gameplay, we are provided commentary on some of the new changes we have seen in past coverage and briefly in other gameplay deep dives for College Football 25, such as the new passing mechanics, which provide three different colors signifying how safe and accurate someone is throwing the ball. Other features discussed in the gameplay include pitch types, the Stadium Pulse meter, and the new Wear &amp; Tear system.</p><p>In addition to a gameplay deep dive, EA Sports announced yesterday on social media that this week the company will reveal College Ultimate Team, the launch roster, and the new additions coming to fan-favorite game mode Road to Glory. </p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Big week of content coming.... It's starting to feel like GAME TIME‼️<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CFB25?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#CFB25</a> <a href="https://t.co/9CVe498u2f" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/9CVe498u2f</a></p>— EASPORTSCollege (@EASPORTSCollege) <a href="https://twitter.com/EASPORTSCollege/status/1809965484646752621?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 7, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>College Football 25 is the first game in the simulation college football gaming series since 2013's <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2013/07/05/ncaa-football-14-review">NCAA Football 14</a>. College Football 25 is also the first college football video game to include current student-athletes, and more importantly, the first to include <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-ncaa-football-players-comments">real-life student-athletes</a> playing for Divison 1 FBS football programs.</p><p>College Football 25 will be released for PS5 and Xbox Series X/S on July 16 for those who pre-order the Deluxe Edition or MVP Bundle, or July 19 for everyone else. For more, check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-best-overall-rated-teams"><u>the top 25 rated teams</u></a>, the best <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-best-offensive-teams"><u>offensive</u></a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-sports-college-football-best-defensive-teams"><u>defensive</u></a> teams, and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-toughest-places-to-play"><u>the toughest stadiums to play in</u></a>. If you want to hear IGN’s initial thoughts before the full release, check out our <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/college-football-25-preview-more-than-just-a-madden-clone"><u>hands-on preview</u></a>.</p><p><em>Taylor is a Reporter at IGN. You can follow her on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/TayNixster" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@TayNixster.</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Boy Advance shoot ’em up RPG Sigma Star Saga coming to modern consoles, PC in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/game-boy-advance-shoot-em-up-rpg-sigma-star-saga-coming-to-modern-consoles-pc-in-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-boy-advance-shoot-%E2%80%99em-up-rpg-sigma-star-saga-coming-to-modern-consoles-pc-in-2025.921768/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/game-boy-advance-shoot-em-up-rpg-sigma-star-saga-coming-to-modern-consoles-pc-in-2025<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Powered by Limited Run Games' Carbon Engine.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > WayForward Technologies [120 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/wayforward">WayForward</a> will release <a title="Genres > Shoot 'Em Up [710 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up">shoot ’em up</a> RPG <em><a title="Games > Sigma Star Saga [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sigma-star-saga">Sigma Star Saga</a></em> for modern consoles and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,614 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> in 2025, the companies announced. It will be powered by <a title="Companies > Limited Run Games [192 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/limited-run-games">Limited Run Games</a>‘ Carbon Engine. Specific platforms were not announced. <span id="more-897472"></span></p><p><em>Sigma Star Saga</em> first launched for Game Boy Advance on August 16, 2005.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via WayForward:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In the year 2005, WayForward took gamers across the galaxy to discover new worlds and alien species. Twenty years later, it’s time to go back! <em>Sigma Star Saga</em>—the Game Boy Advance science-fiction <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,604 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> that combines elements of 2D space <a title="Genres > Shooter [3,813 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shooter">shooter</a>s and <a title="Genres > RPG [16,410 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPGs</a>—is scheduled to return in 2025. Licensed by <a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,528 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco Entertainment</a> and powered by Limited Run Games’ Carbon Engine, this highly requested cult classic will be released on modern consoles and PC, as well as on a Game Boy Advance-compatible reproduction cart.</p><p>Featuring a unique mix of top-down planetary exploration and <a title="Genres > Side-Scrolling [707 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/side-scrolling">side-scrolling</a> shoot ’em up space battles, <em>Sigma Star Saga</em> casts players as Allied Earth Federation pilot Ian Recker, who infiltrates the alien Krill Empire as a double agent in a last-ditch effort to save mankind from their onslaught. To do so, Recker must work with both humans and the Krill, exploring six planets utilizing an ever-expanding set of tools and abilities, and jumping into the cockpit to engage enemy forces in intense shmup-style combat using more than 70 different Gun Data items. Gorgeous pixel-art graphics, epic boss battles, and a twist-filled story with multiple endings await.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Additional details about <em>Sigma Star Saga</em>, including information on platform availability and news about physical editions, will be shared in the months leading up to the game’s launch.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>The Game Boy Advance classic returns after 20 years!</li><li>Top-down RPG-style exploration mixed with <a title="Genres > Action [1,995 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>-packed space-shooter battles!</li><li>Survive as a double agent for the humans and the Krill, and discover the secret of the six planets.</li><li>Stunning pixel-art graphics and fantastic soundtrack.</li><li>Explore using tools like the Scanner, Krill Boots, Wings, and more.</li><li>Customize your ship with more than 70 different Gun Data items.</li><li>Branching story with multiple endings.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego Super Mario Piranha Plant Set Gets Extremely Rare Discount]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-super-mario-piranha-plant-set-gets-extremely-rare-discount/1100-6524761/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-super-mario-piranha-plant-set-gets-extremely-rare-discount.921765/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-super-mario-piranha-plant-set-gets-extremely-rare-discount/1100-6524761/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524761">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The Lego Super Mario Piranha Plant is on sale for the first time since launching late last year. While supplies last--and this could certainly sell out quickly--you can grab the popular Lego set for <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BXQ3M8JH?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">only $48 at Amazon</a> and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FLEGO-Super-Mario-Piranha-Plant-Build-Display-Brothers-Collectible-Adults-Teens-Authentically-Detailed-Posable-Figure-Birthday-Gift-Gamers-Fans-71426%2F2651673420%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Flego-super-mario-piranha-plant-set-gets-extremely-rare-discount%2F1100-6524761%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Walmart</a>. That's a 20% discount off its $60 retail price. With <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">Prime Day</a> set for next week (July 16-17), this is one of the many great early deals you can buy from Amazon and <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.walmart.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F565706%2F9383%3Fveh%3Daff%26sourceid%3Dimp_000011112222333344%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fshop%2Fdeals%3FathAsset%3DeyJhdGhjcGlkIjoiYTY4NmM3ZmUtMjMwNS00YTcxLWEzNjgtN2U3ZDMzYjBjZTI4IiwiYXRoc3RpZCI6IkNTMTAwfkNTMTAwfkNTMDQxIiwiYXRodHZpZCI6IjEifQ%3D%3D%26athena%3Dtrue%26subId1%3Dsubid_value&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Flego-super-mario-piranha-plant-set-gets-extremely-rare-discount%2F1100-6524761%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Walmart</a>.</p><p>Based on one of Mario's best-known enemies, the 540-piece Piranha Plant Lego set features posable elements--like a mount that can open and close and a bendable vine and leaves--and sits in a green pipe just like in the games.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4329838-legopiranha.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4329838" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4329838-legopiranha.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4329838"></a><figcaption>Lego Super Mario Piranha Planet</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1595/15950357/4329838-legopiranha.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr">Rather than the Lego Super Mario playsets that include interactive gameplay elements and simpler pieces, the Lego Piranha Plant is a more complex set intended for display. However, at just $60, it's also much more affordable than other Lego Nintendo sets that aren't designed for interactive play, such as <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Mighty-Bowser-Building-Collectible/dp/B0B3BZZWSL?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Mighty Bowser</a>, the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.target.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F81938%2F2092%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Flego-super-mario-nintendo-entertainment-system-set-71374%2F-%2FA-80130334&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Flego-super-mario-piranha-plant-set-gets-extremely-rare-discount%2F1100-6524761%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lego NES</a>, and the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fclick.linksynergy.com%2Fdeeplink%3Fid%3DVZfI20jEa0c%26mid%3D13923%26u1%3Dsubid_value%26murl%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.lego.com%2Fen-us%2Fproduct%2Fsuper-mario-64-question-mark-block-71395&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Flego-super-mario-piranha-plant-set-gets-extremely-rare-discount%2F1100-6524761%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Super Mario 64 Question Block</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">You should also check out <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LEGO-Bowsers-Muscle-Expansion-Collectible/dp/B0CGY1MQFD?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Amazon's deal on the Lego Super Mario Bowser's Muscle Car</a>. Normally $30, you can buy this cool set for $25. Though it does interact with other Lego Super Mario playsets, it also makes for a pretty awesome display piece. Target also has the <a href="https://clicks.trx-hub.com/xid/fandom_32094_gamespot?q=https%3A%2F%2Fgoto.target.com%2Fc%2F1804712%2F81938%2F2092%3FsubId1%3Dsubid_value%26u%3Dhttps%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Flego-super-mario-larry-39-s-and-morton-39-s-airships-buildable-expansion-toy-set-71427%2F-%2FA-87830625&amp;p=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamespot.com%2Farticles%2Flego-super-mario-piranha-plant-set-gets-extremely-rare-discount%2F1100-6524761%2F&amp;event_type=click" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Larry's and Morton's Airships Super Mario set</a> on sale for $56 (was $80). This particular Lego Mario set is exclusive to Target.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Respawn doubles Apex Legends' battle pass price in systemic overhaul]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/respawn-doubles-apex-legends-battle-pass-price-in-systemic-overhaul</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/respawn-doubles-apex-legends-battle-pass-price-in-systemic-overhaul.921762/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/respawn-doubles-apex-legends-battle-pass-price-in-systemic-overhaul<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content"><p><span>Image via Respawn Entertainment/EA.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Change is coming to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Apex Legends </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">once again. But instead of tweaking </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/apex-legends-next-season-brings-mid-match-character-leveling">characters</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> or providing </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-i-apex-legends-i-hits-player-count-peak-with-deathmatch-mode">new modes</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Respawn is shifting how the battle royale's battle pass works in the game's larger ecosystem.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Beginning with the upcoming </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.ea.com/games/apex-legends/news/battle-pass-update">Season 22</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the three-month passes can only be purchased with real-world money. Players could use in-game AC currency to buy said passes, but that process will be phased out.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Further complicating matters is that each Season will be split into </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>two </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">battle passes. The first Premium pass will cost $10 per half season, while the Premium+ pass (which offers extra in-game rewards) will be $20.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">So unless players stick with the free track, they may pay $20 or $40 for a full season. Per Respawn, the change was done to make things "more approachable and realistic for our global player community."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To show what the change to its season passes will look like, Respawn posted a graphic below showing old and future rewards for the Free, Premium, and Premium+ tracks. Under the half-season change, players seem to get more rewards for buying both passes than the original "one per season" format.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Developers are changing their season passes, but to what end?">Developers are changing their season passes, but to what end?</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Last year, 2K took a similar two-track season pass approach with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-i-nba-2k24-i-is-adding-a-second-20-season-pass-for-players-to-buy">NBA 2K24</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">Like with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Apex, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">that game's Pro and Hall of Fame passes were respectively $10 and $20, though it offered Pro players a chance to trade up if they forked over another $10.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Before that, Bungie bumped up the price of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Destiny 2's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">season passes from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/-i-destiny-2-i-s-season-pass-price-will-increase-says-bungie">$10 to $12</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. This new change from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Apex </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">may further signal a larger shift to come in how season passes are priced and in-game seasons become structured.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disco Elysium-inspired RPG Hollow Home is a memory of Mariupol from before Russia's invasion]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-inspired-rpg-hollow-home-is-a-memory-of-mariupol-from-before-russias-invasion</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disco-elysium-inspired-rpg-hollow-home-is-a-memory-of-mariupol-from-before-russias-invasion.921711/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/disco-elysium-inspired-rpg-hollow-home-is-a-memory-of-mariupol-from-before-russias-invasion<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>"We want to tell the story of the people, and how the city has changed."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_IxkEVAZ.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Galaktus / Twigames Inc</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>The Ukrainian city of Mariupol came under heavy bombardment during the opening months of Russia's invasion in 2022, a programme of artillery and air strikes that damaged or destroyed the majority of residential buildings and has killed or dispossessed thousands of people. It has now been occupied by Russia for almost two years, during which, as reported by the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-war-erasing-mariupol-499dceae43ed77f2ebfe750ea99b9ad9">Associated Press</a>, Russia has demolished, rebuilt and renamed much of the city, overwriting its Ukrainian heritage.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a>-inspired <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> Hollow Home is a memory of Mariupol from just before the war - not a 1:1 recreation, but a collection of details, colours, personalities and some familiar buildings, painstakingly amassed and offered up in the face of erasure. Speaking to me during a very brief demo at Digital Dragons in Poland this year, artist Anastasia Hlyniana called my attention to the plants jutting from old car tyres around the game's isometric map, which she says are a common sight in Mariupol.</p><!--more-->
<p>Hollow Home began development in 2022, just after Mariupol's occupation, and is partly based on journalistic coverage of the invasion, though its characters and story are fictional. It unfolds over 30 in-game days, beginning shortly before Russia's vicious attack, and casts you as 14-year-old Maksym, who must survive and help others to survive. There's no combat in Hollow Home, and apparently, no direct or "graphic" representation of violence. Instead, the game explores the impact of the war on civilians, and the decline of individual neighbourhoods as residents are killed or flee the city.</p>
<p>Hollow Home's pen-and-paper-style role-playing and splashy, graphic novel colours are immediately reminiscent of ZA/UM's game, but the English writing is relatively straight-laced and reverential, as you might expect given that the devastation of Mariupol is both a lived reality and still unfolding. "It's our perspective on what happened, and also we want to tell the story of the people, and how the city has changed," Hlyniana summarised.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_JXlbJ4g.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Galaktus / Twigames Inc</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Maksym gets a limited supply of action points each day, which you'll use to perform skills such as cooking and first aid, based on character traits such as Sociability and Handiness. During the opening, pre-war section of the game, however, these points are reserved for more innocent activities: clambering onto a roof to fix a satellite dish, telling fibs about why you're ditching school, beating your friend's high score at the arcade, and trying to chase away a bullying older boy. In the course of these teenage antics, you'll meet and map out a community of shopkeepers, car mechanics, nosy neighbours and local layabouts, all speculating about reports of troops massing on the border.</p>
<p>"Some places will be destroyed, some new places will arrive, like shelters, volunteer centres," Hlyniana explained. "Some people will die, some new people will come, and the game has several endings. We aim to have about 24 hours of gameplay, and it will contain about three districts of the city, so it will be one big, typical Ukrainian city."</p>
<p>At the risk of centring my own responses as somebody whose country is not currently under assault, it felt strange to hear the situation in Mariupol outlined in terms of video game reviewer preoccupations like playlength and choice of endings. Sadly, my language skills were not up to the task of asking Hlyniana how the developers feel about positioning this memorial work as a commercial product <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2362070/Hollow_Home/">on Steam</a>, where it must frame itself for consumption alongside RPGs for whom an apocalyptic setting is an escapist fantasy. Hollow Home is due for release in 2025.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Overwatch 2 Heroes As Transformers Look Pretty Sick, Actually]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-transformers-event-ramattra-reinhardt-skins-1851581064</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/overwatch-2-heroes-as-transformers-look-pretty-sick-actually.921702/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-transformers-event-ramattra-reinhardt-skins-1851581064<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="961e0c063b1ee788778562fdd3f60c63" data-recommend-id="image://961e0c063b1ee788778562fdd3f60c63" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Ramattra and Reinhardt clash in their Transformers skins." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Ramattra and Reinhardt clash in their Transformers skins." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Gif<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard Entertainment / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="961e0c063b1ee788778562fdd3f60c63" data-recommend-id="image://961e0c063b1ee788778562fdd3f60c63" data-format="gif" data-width="800" data-height="450" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Ramattra and Reinhardt clash in their Transformers skins." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Overwatch 2</em>’s latest collaboration gives four of its heroes skins based on <em>Transformers</em>. It <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/media/stories/transmission/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://overwatch.blizzard.com/en-us/media/stories/transmission/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">started with a comic</a></span> that seems to actually canonize the robots in disguise within Blizzard’s universe, rather than simply letting its characters “cosplay” something from a different property as it did with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/one-punch-man-doomfist-skin-season-3-event-saitama-1850078252&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/one-punch-man-doomfist-skin-season-3-event-saitama-1850078252"><em>One Punch Man</em></a></span> and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-cowboy-bebop-skin-cassidy-sombra-ashe-mauga-1851317241&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-cowboy-bebop-skin-cassidy-sombra-ashe-mauga-1851317241"><em>Cowboy Bebop</em></a></span>. And while I’m growing weary of Blizzard seemingly investing more time and energy in these collaborations than it is in expanding upon <em>Overwatch 2</em>’s own lore, the studio has also released an animated teaser trailer for the crossover that is so slick, I couldn’t help but be won over.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195460" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="122" data-playlist="195460,196880,192616" data-current="195460"><div><p>Overwatch 2's New Story Missions: Worth The Money?</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195460/195460_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20938.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The trailer shows Bastion, Ramattra, Reinhardt, and Illari all dressed up like different <em>Transformers</em> characters. Bastion is shown sporting Bumblebee’s signature yellow, Reinhardt swings his hammer as Optimus Prime, Illari takes flight as Arcee, and Ramattra puts his own transformative capabilities to work as Megatron. The animated trailer doesn’t really have any plot to it, but it’s action-packed and beautifully animated. It also has a nifty new arrangement of the <em>Transformers</em> theme. Kinda just makes me wish once again that Blizzard would dump all that money and talent into <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-mauga-a-good-day-animated-short-series-1851065584&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-mauga-a-good-day-animated-short-series-1851065584">an <em>Overwatch </em>animated series</a></span>. Come on, y’all. If you’re <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-story-missions-campaign-canceled-blizzard-1851345720&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-story-missions-campaign-canceled-blizzard-1851345720">reportedly canceling the story missions</a></span> in <em>Overwatch 2</em>, telling that story in an animated series would be the next best thing. Yeah, you’ve done <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-anime-genesis-story-missions-youtube-1850659770&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-anime-genesis-story-missions-youtube-1850659770">your online shorts</a></span>, but think bigger.</p><p>Check out the full teaser below:</p><p>Unfortunately, the video doesn’t show these skins in-game. But at the very least, <em>Overwatch 2 </em>players know who is getting something new when the <em>Transformers</em> collaboration launches tomorrow on July 9.</p><p><em>Overwatch 2 </em>is in the midst of its eleventh season, and the whole theme seems to be poking at millennial nostalgia, featuring not only the <em>Transformers </em>collaboration but also an homage to <em>Power Rangers </em>via the seasonal event and mythic skin. While that’s all well and good, the game still has some lingering issues with balance that players are having trouble with. Tanks are having trouble across the role, but Blizzard says it <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-tank-heroes-reinhardt-buffs-rework-nerf-1851567261&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/overwatch-2-tank-heroes-reinhardt-buffs-rework-nerf-1851567261">will be making adjustments to those heroes in a future update</a></span>.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disney Pixel RPG Pre-Registrations Are Now Live in Japan]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/disney-pixel-rpg-pre-registrations-are-now-live-in-japan/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disney-pixel-rpg-pre-registrations-are-now-live-in-japan.921699/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/disney-pixel-rpg-pre-registrations-are-now-live-in-japan/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Disney and GungHo Online Entertainment have announced a new mobile gaming title, Disney Pixel RPG. The latest game is set to arrive later this year, and the pre-registrations are live on the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/disney-pixel-rpg/id6502584695" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">iOS App Store </a>and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=jp.gungho.tri" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Google Play Store</a>. However, players should note that pre-registrations are only available in Japan, and the developers have yet to confirm the game’s availability in other regions. Learn more about Disney Pixel RPG below.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9J34RDSUVC/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14"></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<h2 id="h-disney-pixel-rpg-s-narrative-nbsp">Disney Pixel RPG’s Narrative &nbsp;</h2>



<p>Disney Pixel RPG is a playground for Disney fans, offering a diverse cast of characters to play as. The story unfolds in a chaotic realm, where diverse game worlds are interconnected, and a series of characters have assembled to save their respective game world. You’ll get to play Maleficent from an RPG, Mickey from a board game, Ariel from a rhythm game, Baymax, Genie, Pooh, Aurora, Stitch and more, each with their own unique abilities and captivating stories.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The game worlds are under a mysterious attack and are being broken down by the second. Once, they were all isolated, but they have suddenly come together. All of the characters are confused about what to do, and it is your role as a player to embark on this epic quest with them, save these game worlds from being destroyed, and restore order to this chaotic universe.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-gameplay-elements">Gameplay Elements</h2>



<p>Disney Pixel RPG offers a thrilling gameplay experience with its fast-paced battles. The controls are designed to be simple, ensuring that even newcomers to the genre can dive into the action. The addition of an auto-play feature further enhances the ease of play. You can also send groups of different Disney characters on expeditions to find resources while you’re away. To add a personal touch, you can create your own customizable avatar, complete with a range of Disney-themed clothing items.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, THQ Nordic recently revealed that Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed will arrive<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/disney-epic-mickey-rebrushed-is-coming-september-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> this September</a>. Also, Disney Dreamlight Valley devs recently announced a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/disney-dreamlight-valley-devs-announce-dungeons-dragons-project/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dungeons and Dragons project</a>. What are your views on Disney Pixel RPG? Let us know in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/blumhouse-games-reveals-plans-for-future-titles-adaptations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Blumhouse Games revealing plans</a>&nbsp;for its slate of future titles in a new interview and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2K Is Reportedly Remaking A Game, And Fans Are Filling In The Blanks]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2k-is-reportedly-remaking-a-game-and-fans-are-filling-in-the-blanks/1100-6524755/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2k-is-reportedly-remaking-a-game-and-fans-are-filling-in-the-blanks.921696/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2k-is-reportedly-remaking-a-game-and-fans-are-filling-in-the-blanks/1100-6524755/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6524755">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>It looks like 2K is remaking one of its games, but we don't know any more details about what the game could possibly be. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PS5/comments/1dxep09/report_2k_working_on_unannounced_remake/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Fans are taking guesses</a> at what they want to see, with names like BioShock, The Darkness, and Spec Ops: The Line popping up.</p><p>According to the LinkedIn page of a 2K 3D artist (found by <a href="https://mp1st.com/news/report-2k-working-on-unannounced-remake" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">MP1st</a>), 2K is working on an upcoming unannounced remake. However, the mention of the remake has since been removed, as well as any mention of a canceled project by Supermassive Games, called "Erebus." Some other projects that are listed in the profile are upcoming Mafia and BioShock games.</p><p>One possible remake candidate is the first BioShock, as that could drive future interest in the upcoming BioShock game. The first two BioShock games did get remasters for PS4 and Xbox One, but BioShock Infinite didn't. Fortunately, it's backward compatible on Xbox One and Xbox Series X|S.</p><p>Spec Ops: The Line is a cult-classic shooter that was <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/spec-ops-the-line-delisting-reason-revealed-director-comments-on-removal/1100-6520743/" data-ref-id="1100-6520743">delisted earlier</a> back in January due to licensing issues, which to some fans could make it a candidate for a remake. The Darkness is a first-person shooter that was released in 2007 and got a sequel in 2012. While that series has remained dormant since, the two games are also backward compatible on Xbox as well.</p><p>We've already known about the new <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/a-new-mafia-game-is-in-development/1100-6506973/" data-ref-id="1100-6506973">Mafia</a> and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-bioshock-game-is-now-in-development/1100-6472016/" data-ref-id="1100-6472016">BioShock</a> games, as 2K announced them back in 2022 and 2019, respectively. However, very few updates about them, if any, have appeared since. Until Dawn developer Supermassive Games <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/until-dawn-dev-supermassive-games-is-cutting-jobs/1100-6521363/" data-ref-id="1100-6521363">laid off employees earlier this year</a>, so it's possible that these cuts may have impacted Erebus.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Huge Spike in Player Count for Bloodborne before Elden Ring DLC]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/huge-spike-in-player-count-for-bloodborne-before-elden-ring-dlc/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/huge-spike-in-player-count-for-bloodborne-before-elden-ring-dlc.921678/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/huge-spike-in-player-count-for-bloodborne-before-elden-ring-dlc/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>With the release of the brand new DLC for Elden Ring, players returned to an older FromSoftware classic. While players were waiting to get lost in the <a href="https://wccftech.com/elden-ring-patch-1-12-3-brings-more-balance-tweaks-and-bug-fixes/">Shadow of the Erdtree</a>, they returned to Bloodborne.</p>
<p>Bloodborne has always had a huge cult following and has surged back in popularity even ten years later. While players are still waiting and hoping for the day that the game comes to PC, players who have access to the game via a PlayStation 4 or 5 have been jumping back into the game as they waited for the DLC to drop.</p>
<p>A report <a href="https://www.truetrophies.com/news/bloodborne-player-count-july-2024" target="_blank" rel="noopener">from TrueTrophies</a> found that Bloodborne's player count had spiked by a whopping 57% and even spiked by 11% once the DLC had officially dropped. This put Bloodborne back on the leaderboard and was that week's 65th most-played PlayStation game.</p>
<p>If players weren't sinking time into Bloodborne, there was also a rise in popularity for Dark Souls III during the wait for the Elden Ring DLC. However, the number of players who sunk time into Dark Souls III was significantly smaller, at a measly 5.6%.</p>
<p>It's fascinating to see that even ten years later, Bloodborne is still incredibly popular, with many people replaying it multiple times or even people playing it for the first time ever. The fan base has been asking for a 60 FPS patch or even a PC port for many years, but it seems that Sony is still ignoring their call in favor of other PlayStation games, such as Ghost of Tsushima and The Last of Us.</p>
<p>Whether Sony will ever release the rights of Bloodborne back to FromSoftware remains unanswered, and fans can only continue to hope and pray that a Bloodborne PC port will be announced at some point in their lifetime. FromSoftware <a href="https://wccftech.com/bloodborne-pc-port-miyazaki-not-opposed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">certainly isn't opposed</a>, but it's all in Sony's hands.</p>
<p>With Elden Ring being one of the biggest game releases in recent years and having some of the biggest hype for the DLC, it would be the perfect opportunity for Sony to drop an announcement like that and bring further buzz and excitement to those in the community, as well as making Bloodborne a more accessible game.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Piranha Bytes Senior Devs Form New Studio, Pithead Studio]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/piranha-bytes-senior-devs-form-new-studio-pithead-studio/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/piranha-bytes-senior-devs-form-new-studio-pithead-studio.921669/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/piranha-bytes-senior-devs-form-new-studio-pithead-studio/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Not even hours after news broke that Gothic developer <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gothic-developer-piranha-bytes-reportedly-shut-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Piranha Bytes has shut down</a>, news of a new studio formed by former senior developers has emerged. Jennifer and Bjorn Pankratz&nbsp;have announced the launching of Pithead Studio.</p>



<p>The announcement came via a <a href="https://x.com/PitheadStudio/status/1810222288484389201" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">post on social media</a> and a nearly six-minute video on YouTube. The video, with English subtitles, explains the decision from both Jennifer and Bjorn to start Pithead Studio as well as their plans for the company.</p>



<p>“In the future, we will focus on developing Indie Games,” Jennifer Pankratz said. </p>



<p>“Yes, we wanted to keep doing what we love. This seemed like the best way to do it,” Bjorn Pankratz added.</p>



<p>As far as the types of games the pair will be developing, that wasn’t revealed in the video. However, the pair said that every Monday they will be releasing a new video answering questions from the community about Pithead Studio’s future.</p>



<p>“We love to make video games that we personally enjoy playing, and this is exactly what we will do in the future,” Jennifer Pankratz said. “We hope you are looking forward to this as well.”</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="WE ARE BACK ⚒️🦉🦇 Pithead Studio TV" width="1200" height="675" src="about:blank" data-lazy-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lCOIsrbctNM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the latest update on <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/eve-vanguard-gets-update-from-ccp-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the development of EVE Vanguard</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and more.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gran Turismo 7 July Update Includes New Cars, A Track and More]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-7-july-update-includes-new-cars-a-track-and-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gran-turismo-7-july-update-includes-new-cars-a-track-and-more.921666/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-7-july-update-includes-new-cars-a-track-and-more/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Gran Turismo World Series 2024 is live in Montreal, featuring adrenaline-fuelled races between some of the best drivers in the world. During the event, a July Update trailer for Gran Turismo 7 was featured, detailing new tracks, cars and more arriving for the game. Learn more about the Gran Turismo July 7 update below.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Next update coming Thursday, 25 July!</p><p>The <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GT7?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GT7</a> July Update trailer was revealed during 'Gran Turismo World Series' 2024 Rd.1, currently taking place in Montréal, Canada 🇨🇦!</p><p>This update will include a variety of content such as new cars and a much-anticipated new track💪<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GTWS?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GTWS</a>… <a href="https://t.co/AE8l1dWtjs">pic.twitter.com/AE8l1dWtjs</a></p></div>— Gran Turismo (@thegranturismo) <a href="https://twitter.com/thegranturismo/status/1809703139421143374?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Gran Turismo 7’s July update is completely free, and it takes players to a breathtaking new region, Eiger Nordwand. It features lush greens and snow-covered peaks as you burn rubber across the scenic tracks. The update will be adding new physics, changing the way the car absorbs shocks and reacts to different types of tracks. Additionally, there are new Michelin tyres and fresh wheels to outfit your vehicles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Get ready for an adrenaline-pumping experience as you challenge Gran Turismo 7’s superhuman racing AI agent, GT Sophy, across Nurburgring 24-hour Autodrome Lago Maggiore. You can take part in this race and other races in some new whips, too; check out the complete list of new cars added to Gran Turismo 7 below:&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>Ferrari 430 Scuderia 2007</li>



<li>BMW M3 1997</li>



<li>Lamborghini Gallardo LP 560-4 2008</li>



<li>Genesis X Gran Racer Vision Gran Turismo Concept</li>



<li>Subaru Impreza Rally Car 1998</li>



<li>RUF RGT 4.2 2016</li>
</ul>



<p>Players can look forward to exploring all the new content in Gran Turismo 7’s July Update on July 25. In addition, you can check out what cars and world circuits were added in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-7-april-update-includes-new-cars-and-world-circuits/">previous update</a> and even get a glimpse of the special edition Gran Turismo <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gran-turismo-special-edition-bulgari-watch-unveiling-next-week/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bulgari Watch </a>released last year. Let us know how you feel about the upcoming update in the comments.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry news, you can read about a new report claiming Gothic developer&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gothic-developer-piranha-bytes-reportedly-shut-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Piranha Bytes shut down</a>&nbsp;last June and sign up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>