<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 18:58:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some Good And Bad News About Assassin's Creed Shadows On PC]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-always-online-steam-deck-ubi-connect-1851767074</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/some-good-and-bad-news-about-assassins-creed-shadows-on-pc.1122213/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-always-online-steam-deck-ubi-connect-1851767074<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-4-hour-preview-hands-on-review-1851745403&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-4-hour-preview-hands-on-review-1851745403"><em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em></a></span><em>,</em> the next mainline game in Ubisoft’s long-running historical fiction franchise,  is nearly here after <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-assassins-creed-shadows-delay-march-february-1851736266?_gl=1*a6t4x0*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MDc2NjIzOS4yMTguMS4xNzQwNzY2NDU2LjM1LjAuMA..&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-assassins-creed-shadows-delay-march-february-1851736266?_gl=1*a6t4x0*_ga*NzE0NzM5NTc5LjE3Mjk4Njg5MzU.*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MDc2NjIzOS4yMTguMS4xNzQwNzY2NDU2LjM1LjAuMA..">a few delays</a></span>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-leaked-online-stream-ubisoft-1851766144&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-leaked-online-stream-ubisoft-1851766144">a leak</a></span>, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-ubisoft-statement-yasuke-1851602337&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-ubisoft-statement-yasuke-1851602337">a lot of online yelling</a></span>. And if you were planning to play the game on Steam, well, I’ve got some good news and also, some bad news for Steam Deck owners. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195922" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="390" data-playlist="195922,196345,196470" data-current="195922"><div><p>Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21438.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/assassins-creed/news/4XbPPtFyQEtIMWrA9xVDmZ/assassins-creed-shadows-tech-qa&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/assassins-creed/news/4XbPPtFyQEtIMWrA9xVDmZ/assassins-creed-shadows-tech-qa" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On February 28, Ubisoft published a technical-focused Q&amp;A</a></span> about <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em>. In the post, they answered over a dozen fan questions about how the upcoming open-world stealth game will perform on consoles, specs needed on PC, upscaling and raytracing options, and more. And in this new post, Ubisoft confirmed that <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> on Steam won’t, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-connect-steam-assassin-s-creed-valhalla-1849809946&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/ubisoft-connect-steam-assassin-s-creed-valhalla-1849809946">like past many Ubisoft PC games</a></span>, require players to download and install Ubisoft Connect. </p><p>So yes, here’s the good news: According to Ubisoft, you won’t need to muck about with a separate launcher when playing <em>Shadows </em>via Steam. The company says that <em>Shadows </em>includes a “lite embedded version” of Ubisoft Connect in it. </p><p>However, you’ll still need to link your Steam account to a Ubisoft Connect account to play <em>Shadows</em>. Ubisoft promises this is a “one-time” thing and once you link the accounts you will be good to go, but it is still a weird barrier between Steam users and the game. And for those worried that this means you have to be online to play <em>Shadows</em>, that’s not the case. Ubisoft confirmed you only need an internet connection to install the game. Then you can play offline. </p><p>Now for some bad news: Steam Deck users won’t be playing <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> at launch. In today’s tech Q&amp;A, Ubisoft very bluntly responded to a question about <em>Shadows </em>on Steam Deck with: </p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><p>At launch, the game will not be compatible with Steam Deck, due to the fact it is below our minimum specs for PC.</p></blockquote><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/steam-deck-2024-big-games-unplayable-space-marine-2-pc-1851669933?_gl=1*1lj6v08*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MDc2NTY5Ni4xNy4xLjE3NDA3NjY1NjAuNjAuMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/steam-deck-2024-big-games-unplayable-space-marine-2-pc-1851669933?_gl=1*1lj6v08*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MDc2NTY5Ni4xNy4xLjE3NDA3NjY1NjAuNjAuMC4w">This isn’t surprising, as more and more games are struggling to run on the aging Steam Deck</a></span>. However, the fact that Ubisoft specified it won’t be playable <em>at launch</em> is interesting. Perhaps in a future update the company will add some Steam Deck options to make it playable on Valve’s portable PC. But if you don’t have a computer that can play <em>Shadows</em> and rely on a Steam Deck to play PC games, I’d hold off on buying the new <em>Assassin’s Creed.</em></p><p><em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> is nearly here. The game launches on Xbox Series X/S, PS5, and PC on March 20. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon Fans Are Hoping Legends: Z-A Will Bring a Certain Elemental Monkey Trio to Nintendo Switch at Last]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-fans-are-hoping-legends-z-a-will-bring-a-certain-elemental-monkey-trio-to-nintendo-switch-at-last</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-fans-are-hoping-legends-z-a-will-bring-a-certain-elemental-monkey-trio-to-nintendo-switch-at-last.1122210/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-fans-are-hoping-legends-z-a-will-bring-a-certain-elemental-monkey-trio-to-nintendo-switch-at-last<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">A complete PokéDex at last.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Yesterday's Pokémon Legends: Z-A gameplay reveal flooded us with new information about the upcoming Pokémon games set in a futuristic Lumiose City, including looks at dozens of Pokémon we should expect to see there. But one trio of monsters that fans were really hoping to see did NOT appear: the elemental monkeys Panpour, Pansage, and Pansear.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Why are fans so hung up on the monkey trio? It's a bit complicated. The three monkeys and their evolutions have been a part of an increasingly shrinking list of Pokémon that are currently unavailable in any Nintendo Switch game. If you want to truly catch 'em all, you still can, by transferring them from other Pokémon games pre-Switch to Pokémon Home. But at the moment, the following Pokémon are unavailable for capture natively in any Nintendo Switch Pokémon game:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Panpour</li><li>Pansage</li><li>Pansear</li><li>Simipour</li><li>Simisage</li><li>Simisear</li><li>Patrat</li><li>Watchog</li><li>Furfrou</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">This list used to be much longer, but Game Freak added a ton of new Pokémon in the DLC for Pokémon Scarlet and Violet that culled the list down to these nine. What's more, the trailer we saw yesterday showed both Patrat and Furfrou, confirming these two at least will be available in Legends: Arceus. And since Watchog evolves from Patrat, it's a safe bet it will be in the game too. So that just leaves the three monkeys.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The elemental monkey trio was first introduced in Pokémon Black and White, and are somewhat beloved by fans due to the unique way the player obtains them. In Black and White, the first Gym the player encounters will use a typing that the player's starter Pokémon is weak against. However, if the player visits a certain person in the Dreamyard, they'll receive the monkey that has an advantage against that Gym, making it easier to tackle. Their designs are also memorable for being based on the "Hear no evil, see no evil, speak no evil" wise monkeys of Japanese folklore.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/02/28/pokmon-legends-z-a-releases-in-late-2025-3-1740761188956.jpeg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Furfrou lets out a lakeside howl in Pokemon Legends Z-A.</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Realistically, the odds of the monkey trio showing up in Legends: Z-A are actually pretty good. It would be very surprising for Game Freak to leave them out of what could possibly be the last major Pokémon game on Nintendo Switch, and given that they appeared in the Kalos region PokéDex back in the day, it only makes sense for them to still be there in Z-A.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Even if the monkeys are included, there's still one other problem Game Freak needs to solve: Spinda. Spinda is catchable on Nintendo Switch in Brilliant Diamond/Shining Pearl, but due to an error in how the game reads its spot patterns, it cannot be transferred to Pokémon Home. You can still get a Spinda from pre-Switch games transferred to Home, but the weird stuck nature of Spindas on Switch means that the dizzy little bear could probably use a functional Z-A appearance too, if Game Freak feels amenable.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-legends-z-a-first-trailer-reveals-rooftop-running-gameplay-and-late-2025-release-window">first real look at Pokémon Legends Z-A</a> gave us a lot to take in, and we're still dissecting the footage to find all the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-fans-are-frantically-trying-to-work-out-how-pokemon-legends-z-a-connects-to-other-pokemon-games">connections between this and other, past Pokémon games</a>. You can catch up on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokemon-presents-february-2025-everything-announced">everything we saw at yesterday's Pokémon Presents right here</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Dev Issues Early Patch 7 Details, Teases Long-Awaited Horde Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-dev-issues-early-patch-7-details-teases-long-awaited-horde-mode</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-space-marine-2-dev-issues-early-patch-7-details-teases-long-awaited-horde-mode.1122207/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-dev-issues-early-patch-7-details-teases-long-awaited-horde-mode<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2</a> developer Saber Interactive and publisher Focus Entertainment have published early 7.0 update patch notes, while teasing the long-awaited Horde mode.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/166-february-community-update" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">community post</a>, the companies said the 7.0 update is in the works and a release date is coming. But it also outlined several awaited features it’ll bring:</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 Update 7.0:</h2><ul data-cy="list"><li>One Chapter Pack</li><li>One Champion Pack</li><li>Private PvP lobbies</li><li>A new weapon (only in PvE for now)</li><li>New Operation</li><li>Weapon perks rebalance</li><li>Class weapon loadouts rework</li><li>PvE Prestige Rank</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">The PvE Prestige Rank is perhaps of most interest to veteran players of Space Marine 2 looking for a new challenge or goal to work towards. Here’s how it works: once you reach level 25 on a class, you can buy a Prestige Level that will unlock a unique Prestige Perk.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Choose them wisely,” Focus and Saber said, “because you won’t be able to change your selected Prestige Perks before unlocking the four Prestige Levels.” On top of that power boost, each class will have a unique cosmetic reward that emphasizes the class’ iconic armour part.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Space Marine 2 will get Public Test Servers (PTS) on Steam only in March before Patch 7 comes out. This will give fans early access to the upcoming features and the chance to share feedback so the developers can refine the content ahead of launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Meanwhile, Focus and Saber teased the upcoming launch of Horde mode, a feature Space Marine 2 players have been looking forward to ever since the game came out last year.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“You’re very eager to get more info on the Horde Mode, it’s one of our top priorities right now,” Focus and Saber said.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“One thing we can say is that it will be very different from the Space Marine 1 Horde Mode, and that there are surprises we can’t wait for you to find out about.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Once we get really interesting things to show you about it, we will do it!</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Bear with us.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In the same post, Focus and Saber also <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-dev-stamps-out-live-service-game-talk-amid-backlash-to-fomo-community-events">stamped out live service game talk amid a backlash to 'FOMO' Community Events</a>. Last month, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/warhammer-40000-space-marine-2-publisher-addresses-community-complaints-about-a-lack-of-content-reveals-whats-coming-down-the-line"><u>Focus and Saber addressed growing frustration over a lack of content and outlined what players can expect from Space Marine 2 in the coming months</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Space Marine 2 enjoyed a record-breaking launch late last year, eventually shifting 5 million copies while becoming the fastest-selling Warhammer video game of all time.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds - How To Mount Monsters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-mount-monsters-guide/1100-6529799/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-how-to-mount-monsters.1122204/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-mount-monsters-guide/1100-6529799/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529799">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Wondering about how to mount monsters in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds/" data-ref-id="5000-612214"><strong>Monster Hunter Wilds</strong></a>? Terrifying beasts roam the countryside, and they're going to stomp on your character's head if you're not careful. However, if you manage to perform aerial attacks, you might be able to clamber on top of them and hang on for dear life. Our guide helps you with this particular mechanic so you can have an edge in combat.</p><h2>How to mount monsters in Monster Hunter Wilds</h2><p>You can mount monsters by performing aerial attacks. First, make sure that you have a melee weapon equipped. Then, be ready to do either of these two maneuvers:</p><ul><li>Jump off ledges while a creature is below you.</li><li>Jump off your <strong><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-seikret-customization-guide/1100-6529798/" data-ref-id="1100-6529798">Seikret mount</a></strong> while a target is at a lower height/lower stance.</li><li>Use your Slinger to grapple onto floating contraptions, vines, or insects, then drop down a creature that's below you.</li></ul><p>Then, while in mid-air, press the main attack button--i.e. Triangle on PlayStation 5, Y on Xbox Series X/S, or the left mouse button. If all goes well, your character should be able to cling onto a target's back, which leads to a minigame of sorts.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451992-monster-hunter-wilds-mount-monsters-guide-1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4451992" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451992-monster-hunter-wilds-mount-monsters-guide-1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4451992"></a><figcaption>Get ready to hop and wallop a giant beast on the head.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451992-monster-hunter-wilds-mount-monsters-guide-1.jpg"></figure><h3>What to do once you're on top of a monster?</h3><p>Assuming you're able to mount a monster in Monster Hunter Wilds, don't celebrate prematurely. First, take note of the control prompts and information on your screen:</p><ul><li>The upper-left corner of the screen shows your stamina meter. It will gradually drain while you're riding the creature.</li><li>Monsters will attempt to buck and toss you away. If this occurs, press and hold the brace button to minimize stamina depletion.</li><li>You can press the attack buttons to strike a monster's body parts. Once you've opened a wound, press the corresponding prompt--i.e. R1, RB, or Left Shift, depending on your control scheme. This lets you perform a Focus Strike that causes tremendous damage.</li></ul><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451993-monster-hunter-wilds-mount-monsters-guide-2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4451993" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451993-monster-hunter-wilds-mount-monsters-guide-2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4451993"></a><figcaption>Strike a wounded body part while you're mounted to perform a flashy finisher.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451993-monster-hunter-wilds-mount-monsters-guide-2.jpg"></figure><p>Apart from attacking outright, you may continue to move around a monster's body to find a specific weak spot that you want to target. You may also cause it to ram into walls, pillars, and other obstacles to temporarily stun it.</p><p>That does it for our guide on how to mount monsters in Monster Hunter Wilds. Note that your <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-ai-companions-sos-flare-guide/1100-6529744/" data-ref-id="1100-6529744"><strong>AI companions</strong></a> can also clamber on top of beasts, just in case you prefer to fight from afar.</p><p>Need more tips as you continue fighting deadly creatures and venture into lands unknown? We've got you covered in our Monster Hunter Wilds <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-guides-hub/1100-6529740/" data-ref-id="1100-6529740"><strong>guides hub</strong></a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/102004508015629188081?rel=author">Jason Rodriguez</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metro Developer Explains Confusing Studio Schism Ahead Of Franchise's 15th Anniversary]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/metro-developer-explains-confusing-studio-schism-ahead-of-franchises-15th-anniversary/1100-6529801/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metro-developer-explains-confusing-studio-schism-ahead-of-franchises-15th-anniversary.1122198/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/metro-developer-explains-confusing-studio-schism-ahead-of-franchises-15th-anniversary/1100-6529801/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529801">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>4A Games and 4A Games Ukraine might sound like part of the same organization, but as the Metro developer recently clarified, that's not actually the case anymore. In <a href="https://www.4a-games.com.mt/4a-dna/2025/2/28/4a-games-studio-update" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">an update</a>, 4A Games explained that though the majority of its workers remain in Ukraine, the other studio 4A Games Ukraine (now known as Reburn) is now a completely separate entity.</p><p dir="ltr">In the update, 4A explains that the original founders of the studio formed 4A Games Limited to create a new HQ in Malta with 50 members of their team back in 2014. When Metro Exodus was released in 2019, 4A Games Limited created a separate studio in Kyiv and hired roughly 50 employees from their existing Kyiv office 4A Games Ukraine, which then spun off into its own separate studio no longer affiliated with 4A or the Metro franchise, now called Reburn.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="728274737" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465719,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;La%20Quimera%20%7C%20Official%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:129,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/la-quimera-official-trailer\/2300-6465719\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465719\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465719\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465719\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465719&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465719,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6529801&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;metro-exodus,la-quimera&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,first-person,shooter&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-one,playstation-4,pc,stadia,linux,macintosh,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;deep-silver,square-enix,microsoft,spike-chunsoft&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;metro-2033&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;metro-2033&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465719},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465719\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4451050-laquimerakeyartwithlogo.png&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/ZgPtKvIu.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1740668400,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="ZgPtKvIu" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> La Quimera | Official Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">This name and studio confusion stems from Reburn's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/metro-dev-4a-games-rebrands-to-reburn-announces-new-sci-fi-fps-la-quimera/1100-6529689/">recent announcement</a> of its new project, La Quimera. It's described as a first-person shooter with a "heavy focus" on narrative, world design, and characters. The game's world and story have been created by Nicolas Winding Refn, best known for directing Drive and The Neon Demon, and it draws from Latin-American folklore.</p><p dir="ltr">4A Games was formed back in 2006 by former developers from Stalker: Shadow of Chernobyl studio GSC Game World. They are best-known for the Metro series, based on a series of novels by Russian author Dmitry Glukhovsky.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Islands And Trains Are Two Of My Favorite Things]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/islands-and-trains-steam-next-fest-demo-impressions-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/islands-and-trains-are-two-of-my-favorite-things.1122183/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/islands-and-trains-steam-next-fest-demo-impressions-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I was almost <em>scared </em>to open up<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/nextfest" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Steam's Next Fest tab</a> earlier this week. There are simply too many demos of too many good games going around; how would I even know where to start? Thankfully, Steam instantly made a very helpful suggestion: maybe try <em>this </em>demo first, since it's for a game you already have wishlisted.</p><p>That game is called <em>Islands And Trains</em>, and between the name and the screenshots you can probably tell where this is going. If you can't, here is perhaps the best elevator pitch for a video game I have ever seen:</p><blockquote><p>Craft tiny railway dioramas in a stress-free island sandbox. No rules or timers - just design, build, and enjoy.</p><span><blockquote></blockquote></span></blockquote><p>I don't know about you, but I <em>love</em> little trains. I hate stress, I love islands, I dig sandbox creation games. I hate rules and timers, and I really enjoy designing, building and...enjoying. So I smashed that install button, and 100MB later I was playing.</p><div><figure><p><iframe title="Islands &amp; Trains - New Teaser Trailer" width="710" height="399" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x8w-xEMce10?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></figure></div><p>Turns out, in a rare W for truth in advertising, <em>Islands And Trains</em> is everything it says it is! Imagine the free-form construction of "<em>Islanders</em>, <em>Dorfromantik</em> and <em>Townscaper</em>"--and I'm not being reductive here,<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1957760/Islands__Trains/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> those are three games the developers list as their primary inspiration on their own Steam page</a>--but here you also build a little rail network and get to watch little trains toot around towns, through tunnels and under waterfalls.</p><p>The sandbox toolkit is snappy, the cosmetic options are plentiful (if restricted, since this is a demo) and everything looks <em>gorgeous</em>. I really appreciate the depth you can get to here; you're responsible for shaping everything, from the terrain of the island itself to its hills, forests and waterways, so even if you hate trains (though how could you?), I think you could still find joy just building an island with a town and some rivers and farms on it.</p><p>Though by doing that you'd miss out on the game's best part: after building a little train, you get to control the train with a little throttle on the right of the screen, which is such a tiny flourish. As a model train diorama enjoyer, it’s been a delight every time I'd nudged it to start, then nudged it to stop perfectly outside of a little train station that doesn't even have any people on it, but which I imagine has people on it, because I also built them little streets and a little school and a little football pitch behind the school that looks out over the ocean.</p><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1957760/Islands__Trains/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Islands And Trains'</em> release date is TBA</a>, but being a sandbox game this demo lets you mess around with most of it; it's just the variety of options that are limited, so most of the stuff you can do here is the same as the full release, you just don't get as many buildings, terrain, climate or train options as you will when it's finally out.</p><figure><figcaption>There's the train controls on the bottom-right! You get to build everything AND move the little train!</figcaption></figure></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/chinese-cleaver-chefs-knife-caidao-cck-sbz"><h3>Everyone Should Have A Chinese Chef’s Knife</h3></a><p>My Chan Chi Kee KF1812 caidao is one of my most prized possessions and I use it for basically everything.</p></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Best Strikers to Unlock in Mecha BREAK]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/best-strikers-to-unlock-in-mecha-break/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/best-strikers-to-unlock-in-mecha-break.1122174/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/best-strikers-to-unlock-in-mecha-break/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Mecha BREAK is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/most-popular-demos-from-steam-next-fest-february-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">attracting far more players</a> than any other demo at the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/nextfest" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Steam Next Fest</a>, and those players have to decide which Striker (or mech) to unlock first. It takes a while to unlock all of the Mecha BREAK Strikers through the progression system, so knowing what the best ones are beforehand can make the task much easier.</p>



<p>After you complete the tutorial, you’ll have the default Striker Alysnes unlocked already. Once you’ve completed a few matches and some introductory tasks, you should have enough Matrix Credits to unlock these must-have Strikers in Mecha BREAK. <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/exclusive-interview-mecha-break-creator/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The game’s creator Kris Kwok may not be able to pick favorites</a>, but we can.</p>



<h2 id="h-best-strikers-to-unlock-in-mecha-break">Best Strikers to Unlock in Mecha BREAK</h2>



<h3 id="h-tricera">Tricera</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>Tricera only costs 3,200 Matrix Credits, a relative steal considering the cost of other Strikers and given how valuable he is. An Ultra-Heavy Defender, Tricera comes equipped with two sets of gatling guns, and its greatest strength is its unreal defensive capabilities. Its gatling guns can be fired at the same time, shredding opponent armor. Tricera can also transform into a nearly impenetrable turret mode, in which it can also deploy drones that heal itself and friendly units around it. When a defender is needed to hold down an objective in 6v6, there’s arguably no better option early on Tricera.</p>



<h3 id="h-welkin">Welkin</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>In contrast to the defensive capabilities of Tricera, Welkin is a melee offensive dynamo, costing 6,800 Matrix Credits to unlock. Equipped with a sick battle axe that bypasses enemy armor, Welkin’s signature ability is a stasis field that locks enemies in with you and a drone that deals additional damage and stagger. It e also has two smoke fields to get him out of tricky situations: a Jamming field that destroys enemy drones and blinds enemies facing you, and a Defense field that blocks and reduces incoming Energy damage. Close the distance on an enemy, pop the stasis field, and let the Axe go to work </p>



<h3 id="h-hurricane">Hurricane</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>Hurricane, another Ultra-Heavy Defender that costs 9,600 Matrix Credits, excels in creating areas that enemies will steer clear from. Its defensive field creates a large barrier that it and allies can take shelter in, and it can deploy Decoy Drones and Turret Drones to harass enemies. Hurricane’s primary fire Energy Blaster is worth charging up, as it deals continuous Area and Energy damage and will absolutely melt light attackers.</p>



<h3 id="h-skyraider">Skyraider</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p>Skyraider, a Medium Attacker that costs 45,000 Matrix Credits, is the perfect blend of firepower and mobility, and is worth saving up for. While standing, its Autocannon and Missile deal massive amounts of damage, with a Jamming Missile that allows for blocking damage and escape potential. Once it switches to its Aerial Assault form, it can dodge missiles or lock-ons, and utilize a Missile Dispenser that can target up to 12 different units. Skyraider is great for clearing out teamfights in 6v6, and is overall a strong choice in Mashmak extraction matches.</p>



<p>Is there a Striker in Mecha BREAK you prefer? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/call-of-duty-2025-in-development-for-last-gen-consoles.1711/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Insider Gaming Forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-sbmm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive interview with a developer</a>&nbsp;for Call of Duty’s SBMM system. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monster Hunter Wilds - How To Change Your Character's Appearance]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-change-appearance-guide/1100-6529797/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monster-hunter-wilds-how-to-change-your-characters-appearance.1122171/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-change-appearance-guide/1100-6529797/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529797">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Are you wondering about how to change your character's appearance in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds/" data-ref-id="5000-612214"><strong>Monster Hunter Wilds</strong></a> well after you've started the campaign? Yes, it's quite possible to alter your character's looks so you can bring down beasts in style. We've got a quick guide to help you with this particular facet.</p><div data-embed-type="toc"><p><span><strong>Table of Contents</strong> [<a data-toggle="collapse" href="#toc_list">hide</a>]</span></p><ul id="toc_list"><li><a href="#How_to_change_appearance_in_Monster_Hunter_Wilds">How to change appearance in Monster Hunter Wilds</a><ul><li><a href="#Changing_appearance_at_your_base">Changing appearance at your base</a></li><li><a href="#Changing_appearance_by_using_a_voucher">Changing appearance by using a voucher</a></li></ul></li></ul></div><h2 id="How_to_change_appearance_in_Monster_Hunter_Wilds">How to change appearance in Monster Hunter Wilds</h2><p>There are two ways for you to change the appearance of your Hunter, as well as your Palico companion:</p><ul><li>Make alterations via your tent at a Base Camp.</li><li>Use a Character/Palico Edit Voucher from the storefront where you purchased the game.</li></ul><h3 id="Changing_appearance_at_your_base">Changing appearance at your base</h3><p>If you just want a quick and easy way to change your character's appearance in Monster Hunter Wilds, simply interact with your tent at a Base Camp and go to the Appearance Menu tab. Select the Change Appearance option so you can tweak the following:</p><ul><li>Hair</li><li>Eyebrow/eyelash</li><li>Eye color</li><li>Mouth</li><li>Facial hair</li><li>Makeup/face paint</li><li>Voice pitch</li><li>Bearing</li><li>Clothing</li><li>Underclothes</li></ul><p>This is also where you can change your Palico's fur pattern/color, eyes, tail shape, and more.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451978-monster-hunter-wilds-change-appearance-1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4451978" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451978-monster-hunter-wilds-change-appearance-1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4451978"></a><figcaption>You can partially edit a few facets of your character, including their default clothing.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451978-monster-hunter-wilds-change-appearance-1.jpg"></figure><h3 id="Changing_appearance_by_using_a_voucher">Changing appearance by using a voucher</h3><p>As you may have noticed, there are a few options that you can't alter via your tent. For these tweaks, you're going to need a Character Edit Voucher (for your Hunter) or a Palico Edit Voucher (for your trusty cat companion).</p><p>If you go to the Monster Hunter Wilds store page of your chosen platform, you should see a Free Trial Version for these vouchers. Note that these are one-time use only.</p><p>To spend these vouchers, launch the game and choose your save file. You should notice the Edit Character option. Select this to completely tweak everything about your Hunter, including body type, skin tone, and voice type. It's basically akin to redoing character creation from the start of the campaign.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451980-monster-hunter-wilds-change-appearance-2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4451980" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451980-monster-hunter-wilds-change-appearance-2.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4451980"></a><figcaption>The Monster Hunter Wilds store page has vouchers that allow you to fully alter your character.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1816/18167535/4451980-monster-hunter-wilds-change-appearance-2.jpg"></figure><p>Once you've used up your Free Trial vouchers, your only recourse if you want to edit your character's looks down the line is to purchase more vouchers. These are the ones that are available in the store page:</p><ul><li>3x Character Edit Voucher: Three Voucher Pack: $6.99</li><li>3x Palico Edit Voucher: Three Voucher Pack: $6.99</li><li>3x Character and Palico Edit Voucher: Three Voucher Pack: $9.99</li></ul><p>That does it for our guide on how to change appearance in Monster Hunter Wilds. If you're keen on more tweaks, you can take a look at our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-customize-seikret-guide/1100-6529798/" data-ref-id="1100-6529798"><strong>Seikret customizations guide</strong></a>.</p><p>Need more tips as you continue fighting deadly creatures and venture into lands unknown? We've got you covered in our Monster Hunter Wilds <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-guides-hub/1100-6529740/" data-ref-id="1100-6529740"><strong>guides hub</strong></a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/102004508015629188081?rel=author">Jason Rodriguez</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA Online's Next Update Takes Flight In March]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-onlines-next-update-takes-flight-in-march/1100-6529794/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-onlines-next-update-takes-flight-in-march.1122165/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-onlines-next-update-takes-flight-in-march/1100-6529794/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529794">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Following the events of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/grand-theft-auto-v-review/1900-6414475/" data-ref-id="1900-6414475">Grand Theft Auto 5</a> and Grand Theft Auto Online, Trevor Philips Enterprises is no more. But Trevor Philips' former associate, Oscar Guzman, isn't going let that keep him down in the next expansion for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/grand-theft-auto-online-review/1900-6415473/" data-ref-id="1900-6415473">GTA Online</a>. Rockstar Games has announced that Oscar Guzman Flies Again will come in for a landing on March 4 with some potentially lucrative opportunities for players.</p><p>As laid out on <a href="https://www.rockstargames.com/newswire/article/255198oaok7o32/prepare-for-takeoff-in-gta-online-oscar-guzman-flies-again" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rockstar's site</a>, players can purchase McKenzie Field Hangar, an airstrip that's seen better days. It may not be much to look at, but Guzman plans to help players make a killing with new missions to sell and transport illegal arms. What McKenzie lacks in aesthetics, it more than makes up for as a staging ground where players can fly a Western Duster 300-H plane and the Buckingham DH-7 Iron Mule helicopter. There will also be an opportunity to steal the Eberhard Titan 250 D, a state-of-the-art gunship that belongs to Eberhard Munitions, a multinational aeronautics and munitions manufacturer.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4451941-gtaonlinemckenziefieldhangar.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4451941" data-ratio="0.56230769230769" data-width="1300" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4451941-gtaonlinemckenziefieldhangar.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4451941"></a><figcaption>The current state of McKenzie Field Hangar in GTA Online.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1837/18375603/4451941-gtaonlinemckenziefieldhangar.jpg"></figure><p>Rockstar's description also hints at a larger conflict between Eberhard Munitions and the player's character, courtesy of Guzman's get-rich quick scheme. The good news is that owning McKenzie gives players additional storage areas for personal aircraft.</p><p>GTA+ members will be able to claim the new Invetero Coquette D5 sports car for free at The Vinewood Car Club showroom, or get a 30% discount on the car when getting at McKenzie. Anyone who is a GTA+ member between March 4-May 8 will also be given a few previously released benefits, including a free-to-claim Principe Deveste Eight (Super), special Chameleon paints, liveries, clothing, and more.</p><p>With <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">Grand Theft Auto 6</a> on the horizon later this year, Take-Two CEO Strauss Zelnick recently indicated that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/take-two-boss-suggests-that-current-gta-online-could-continue-after-gta-6-releases/1100-6529517/" data-ref-id="1100-6529517">GTA Online may continue as a legacy title</a>. In the meantime, Rockstar promises that more info about the latest update will be released soon.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom responds to Monster Hunter Wilds PC performance problems with basic troubleshooting]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/capcom-responds-to-monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-problems-with-basic-troubleshooting/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom-responds-to-monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-problems-with-basic-troubleshooting.1122138/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/capcom-responds-to-monster-hunter-wilds-pc-performance-problems-with-basic-troubleshooting/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Today’s launch of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> has disappointingly been met with a wave of complaints from PC players over the game’s performance.</p>
<p>With the game’s Steam reviews rating sat at Mixed, Capcom has responded and offered some basic troubleshooting tips.</p>


<p>A post by the official Monster Hunter Status social media account says,&nbsp;“If you’re experiencing any initial issues with Monster Hunter Wilds on Steam, please try updating your graphics driver, turning off compatibility mode, and then readjust your settings.”</p>
<p>That’s all well and good, but&nbsp;<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-monster-hunter-wilds-pc-weve-got-issues">Digital Foundry’s analysis</a> of the PC version of the game highlights a number of fundamental issues that they found with the game. In particular, there’s a very lengthy shader compilation stage that could last 13 minutes on a Ryzen 5 3600. The automatic graphics settings seemingly fail to handle adjusting texture quality to match available VRAM on 8GB cards (leading to hefty stutters), and even if that’s adjusted, they continued to see stutters during camera movement. Even with more than 8GB VRAM, they suggest keeping texture settings reduced at this time, and suspect that there’s some issues with GPU-based DirectStorage texture decompression overloading the hardware.</p>
<p>This seems to be a bit more than just needing to have your drivers updated, and it’s yet another wonky PC game release – see <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/01/spider-man-2-pc-port-gets-a-rough-reception-over-performance-and-graphical-issues/">Spider-Man 2</a> at the end of January. Here’s hoping that further driver updates and some game tweaks in updates can help with performance as soon as possible.</p>

<p>Still, here’s <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/">Capcom’s troubleshooting steps</a>:</p>
<ol>
<li>Make sure you meet the minimum system requirements for the game.</li>
<li>Update your Video/Graphics Drivers.</li>
<li>Check for Windows Updates and ensure all of the latest programs are installed to your OS.</li>
<li>If you still experience issues, try performing a clean installation of the video driver set.</li>
<li>Update DirectX to the latest version.<br>
For details on how to update DirectX, please visit the Microsoft support page or Microsoft Download Center.</li>
<li>Add the game’s folder and files to your anti-virus program’s exception / exclusion list.<br>
Default Paths:<br>
C:\Program Files (x86)\Steam\SteamApps\common\MonsterHunterWilds<br>
C:\Program Files (x86)\Steam\SteamApps\common\MonsterHunterWilds\MonsterHunterWilds.exe</li>
<li>Add folder and files for Steam.exe to your anti-virus program’s exception / exclusion list.<br>
*Default Paths:<br>
C:\Program Files (x86)\Steam<br>
C:\Program Files (x86)\Steam\Steam.exe</li>
<li>Give administrator privileges to Steam.<br>
To run Steam.exe in administrator mode, right-click on the .exe file and select “Run as administrator.”</li>
<li>If you still experience issues, try logging into your PC in administrator mode and then run the game’s execution file (MonsterHunterWilds.exe).</li>
<li>Verify the game’s files on Steam.<br>
To verify your game’s files, follow these steps:<br>
(1) Restart your computer and launch Steam.<br>
(2) From the “Library” section, right-click on the game, and select “Properties” from the menu.<br>
(3) Select the “Installed Files” tab and click the “Verify integrity of game files” button.<br>
(4) Steam will verify the game’s files – this process may take several minutes.<br>
Important: One or more files may fail to verify. The files that fail to verify are local configuration files that should not be replaced as part of this process. You can safely ignore this message. If problematic files were detected during this process, Steam will automatically download and / or replace those files.</li>
<li>Disable Compatibility Mode for “MonsterHunterWilds.exe” if enabled.<br>
(1) Right click on “MonsterHunterWilds.exe” located in the following folder:<br>
C:\Program Files (x86)\Steam\SteamApps\common\MonsterHunterWilds<br>
*The above is the default location.<br>
(2) Go to Properties<br>
(3) Open Compatibility tab<br>
(4) Untick “Run this program in compatibility mode for:”<br>
If the above does not resolve the issue, please disable the Compatibility Mode for “Steam.exe” located in the folder below.<br>
C:\Program Files (x86)\Steam</li>
<li>If you still experience issues, please also try the troubleshooting steps on the Official Monster Hunter Wilds Troubleshooting &amp; Issue Reporting Thread posted on the Steam community page as they contain more detailed and additional steps that may help resolve your issue.<br>
*Some steps mentioned in this article is also mentioned in the troubleshooting guide below, but please try all the steps in the guide again.</li>
</ol>
<p>Source: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2246340/Monster_Hunter_Wilds/">Steam</a></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer: The Horus Heresy Roleplaying Game Announced for 2026]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-horus-heresy-roleplaying-game-2026</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-the-horus-heresy-roleplaying-game-announced-for-2026.1122135/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warhammer-horus-heresy-roleplaying-game-2026<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Games Workshop has revealed that it's releasing a roleplaying game based on the popular&nbsp;<em>Warhammer: The Horus Heresy&nbsp;</em>setting, and it's set to debut in 2026, with preorders opening up in summer.</p>

<p>The roleplaying game will begin with the massacre on Isstvan III, which saw Horus launching an Exterminatus attack on the planet, wiping out the vast majority of life. It's one of the major inciting incidents in the Horus Heresy mythology, and the one that uncovered Horus as the traitor he would come to be known as.</p>

<p>You and your compatriots will play as Legionary Consuls on the side of the Imperium of Man. Rather uniquely, you'll also create a secondary character like a Naval Commander or a Remembrancer, and you'll switch to playing as these characters "when their particular skills are required", according to Games Workshop.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warhammer-the-horus-heresy-roleplaying-game-battlefield.jpg?itok=V8O0PHCC 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warhammer-the-horus-heresy-roleplaying-game-battlefield.jpg?itok=deJBdZfN 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The Horus Heresy is one of&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40,000</em>'s most important events, and you'll get to experience it soon.</figcaption></figure><p>The&nbsp;<em>Horus Heresy&nbsp;</em>roleplaying game is being developed by Cubicle 7, whose name you might know from its previous efforts in the world of&nbsp;<em>Warhammer</em>. The studio's prior efforts include&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/warhammer-fantasy-roleplay-4th-edition-review" rel="nofollow">Warhammer Fantasy Role-Play</a>&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/warhammer-40k-roleplay-wrath-and-glory-stater-set-review" rel="nofollow"><em>Wrath &amp; Glory</em></a>.</p>

<p>Cubicle 7 head Dominic McDowall says that in the new game, you and your friends will get the chance to forge "legends" that will "rival those found in the classics" of the setting. He describes the Heresy itself as "as big as it gets" in the&nbsp;<em>Warhammer&nbsp;</em>universe.</p>

<p>If you're not familiar with the Horus Heresy, it's one of the most important events in the&nbsp;<em>Warhammer 40k&nbsp;</em>timeline. Horus Lupercal, one of the Emperor's sons and the Primarch of the Luna Wolves Space Marine Chapter, betrays the Imperium after being seduced by the Gods of Chaos.</p>

<p>While Horus and his traitor legions technically lose their war against the Imperium of Man, their efforts lead to the near-total destruction of the Emperor's body, which is now kept alive through constant horrifying sacrifice and venerated as "God-Emperor" among mankind.</p>




<p>It's a setting that has been covered in a number of Black Library novels, including the likes of Dan Abnett's&nbsp;<em>Horus Rising&nbsp;</em>and Aaron Dembski-Bowden's&nbsp;<em>The First Heretic</em>, among many others.</p>

<p>The&nbsp;<em>Warhammer: The Horus Heresy&nbsp;</em>roleplaying game's core rulebook and starter sets will launch in spring 2026, with pre-orders opening up this summer. Excitingly, Cubicle 7 also has an RPG in the works based on&nbsp;<em>Warhammer: The Old World</em>, so stay tuned for more on that.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty 2025 In Development For Last Gen Consoles]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-2025-in-development-for-last-gen/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-2025-in-development-for-last-gen-consoles.1122123/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-2025-in-development-for-last-gen/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>If you’re a Call of Duty fan who has yet to upgrade to a PlayStation 5 or Xbox Series X|S, it looks like you’ll be able to still keep your old system for at least another year. According to a new report, Call of Duty 2025 is in development for last gen PlayStation 4 and Xbox One.</p>



<p>The claim was first reported by <a href="https://x.com/charlieINTEL/status/1895228195471007981" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CharlieIntel</a> on Thursday night. Insider Gaming sources have since been able to corroborate the report that the game is in development for those platforms. Whether it actually releases on them is something that sources couldn’t confirm just yet.</p>



<h6 id="h-podcast-wonder-woman-canceled-and-is-it-the-games-media-s-fault">PODCAST: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/wonder-woman-canceled-and-is-it-the-games-medias-fault/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wonder Woman Canceled And Is It The Games Media’s Fault?</a></h6>



<p>In addition to the plans for the game to remain on PlayStation 4 and Xbox One, CharlieIntel speculates that the 13-year-old systems might be a reason why Warzone doesn’t have “two big maps at the same time”.</p>



<p>As far as why the game could continue on last-gen consoles, it likely has to do with the popularity on those platforms. Still, it has fans on social media split about the decision.</p>



<p>“Studios having to support 12 year old hardware is bad for the industry and holds back the full potential for games,” <a href="https://x.com/xSERP3NT/status/1895230590129185239" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">one user said</a>. “It’s time to move on.”</p>



<p>Said another: “Crazy but not surprising. Still a ton of ppl on there, and the game scales to low end hardware, [and the] game engine can even play on phones now as we saw with warzone mobile.”</p>



<p>What do you think of Call of Duty 2025 likely staying on last gen? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/call-of-duty-2025-in-development-for-last-gen-consoles.1711/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official Insider Gaming Forums.</a></p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-sbmm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">exclusive interview with a developer</a> for Call of Duty’s SBMM system. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Salty game dev comments, easier mods are inside Command & Conquer’s source code]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/02/command-conquer-source-release-promises-more-mods-and-updates-for-rts-legend/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/salty-game-dev-comments-easier-mods-are-inside-command-conquer%E2%80%99s-source-code.1122120/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/02/command-conquer-source-release-promises-more-mods-and-updates-for-rts-legend/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          
<p>Inside the source code are some wonderful reminders of what Windows game development from 1995 to 2003 was really like. One experienced modder <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/rwtema.bsky.social/post/3lj73vvrhr226">posted some gems on Bluesky</a>, like a "HACK ALERT!" text string added just to prevent the Watcom IDE from crashing because of a "magic text heap length" crash: "Who knows why, but it works," wrote that poor soul.</p>
<p>This writer's personal favorite is this little bit in <a href="https://github.com/electronicarts/CnC_Generals_Zero_Hour/blob/main/Generals/Code/Tools/WorldBuilder/src/RampOptions.cpp">the RampOptions.cpp file</a> in <em>Generals</em>, credited to John K. McDonald Jr., which expresses concerns about "TheRampOptions" existing with a set value:</p>
<p><code>if (TheRampOptions) {</code><br>
<code>// oh shit.</code><br>
<code>return;</code><br>
<code>}</code></p>
<p>In addition to helping out modders and entertaining experienced coders, the GPL-licensed source code releases do a lot to help preserve these games, such that they can be reworked to run on future platforms. Projects like <a href="https://www.openra.net/">OpenRA</a> and <a href="https://opensage.github.io/">OpenSAGE</a> already offer open source reimplementations of those games' code, but having the original source can only help. <em>C&amp;C </em>community stalwart Luke "CCHyper" Feenan worked with EA leaders to get the code back into a build-ready state and said in a press release that the updated code should make the classic games easier to patch in the future.</p>
<p>As part of the source code release, the&nbsp;<em>Command &amp; Conquer</em> team dropped off <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qN2gryZYz6g">35 minutes of footage</a>, newly found in the archives, of alpha and archive footage from the later Sage-engine based&nbsp;<em>Generals</em> and <em>Renegade</em> games.</p>
<figure><p><iframe allow="fullscreen" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qN2gryZYz6g?start=0&amp;wmode=transparent"></iframe></p><div>
    
    <p>
      Archival footage from alpha versions of <em>Command &amp; Conquer: Generals </em>and <em>Renegade</em>, released by EA as part of their source code release.

          </p>
  </div>
</figure>
<p>It's heartening to see that with the right combination of people and purpose, classic games can find renewed interest and longevity inside a big publisher.</p>


          
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Want To Change Up Your Look In Monster Hunter Wilds? It'll Cost You]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/want-to-change-up-your-look-in-monster-hunter-wilds-itll-cost-you/1100-6529795/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/want-to-change-up-your-look-in-monster-hunter-wilds-itll-cost-you.1122117/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/want-to-change-up-your-look-in-monster-hunter-wilds-itll-cost-you/1100-6529795/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6529795">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/monster-hunter-wilds/">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> is finally here, but one of its features has players scratching their heads: Players have to pay real-life money to edit their character if they decide they want to change up their initial look.</p><p dir="ltr">Players can create and customize their character for free at the beginning of the game, but if they decide they want to tweak that character later on, they'll have to cough up some real-world cash. This aspect of character customization wasn't shown in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/monster-hunter-wilds-review-new-frontier/1900-6418338/">review copies of the game</a>, so players weren't expecting to have to open their wallets every time they wish to change up their character's look.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="63136076" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465711,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Everything%20To%20Know%3A%20Monster%20Hunter%20Wilds&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:519,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/everything-to-know-monster-hunter-wilds\/2300-6465711\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465711\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465711\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465711\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465711&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465711,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6529795&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;monster-hunter-wilds&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;capcom&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;monster-hunter&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;monster-hunter&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465711},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465711\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1823\/18237460\/4448077-etkmhthumb.png&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/AIkadhEV.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1739904900,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="AIkadhEV" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465711" data-src="/videos/everything-to-know-monster-hunter-wilds/2300-6465711/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>Everything To Know: Monster Hunter Wilds</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p dir="ltr">The same also applies to re-customizing the Palico, a companion character who follows the main player-character throughout the game. On the bright side, this fee doesn't apply to changing up basic cosmetic features like hair, face/skin color, eyebrow color, makeup, or clothing. But making more in-depth changes will cost you.</p><p dir="ltr">How much will it cost you? Well, there's a number of options. Currently, an item called The Monster Hunter Wilds Character Edit Voucher Pack--which features three customization vouchers--is available to purchase for $6 USD. You can also purchase a three-voucher pack for the Palico, which also costs $6 USD. Another option is a voucher that costs $10 USD and allows players to re-build both their player-character <em>and</em> the Palico three times each.</p><p dir="ltr">Thankfully, Capcom is also providing all players with a voucher that allows them one additional chance to re-customize their character and the Palico for free. But once that token is gone, players will have to pay up if they want to significantly change their look.</p><p>Despite the rather unpleasant surprise regarding character re-customization, Monster Hunter Wilds is doing wildly well. There have been <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-is-having-some-problems-on-pc-but-capcom-is-here-to-help/1100-6529786/">some issues on PC</a>, but that hasn't stopped the game from <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-is-off-to-an-amazing-start-on-pc-smashing-through-several-steam-records/1100-6529783/">breaking records on Steam</a>, with over 1.2 million concurrent players. If you're looking for help on your journey through the Forbidden Lands, check out our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/monster-hunter-wilds-guides-hub/1100-6529740/">Monster Hunter Wilds guide hub</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Afterlove EP Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/afterlove-ep-review/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/afterlove-ep-review.1122096/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/afterlove-ep-review/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>There is only one thing truly certain about life, and that is death. One day we will pass on from this world, and we cannot know the day it will come for us. Accompanying death is grief – grief from the ones who love us and care about us. Grief does shatter you, remoulding you, and changing you. Sometimes that change is small and other times it is so significant, those around you do not recognise the person you have become. Afterlove EP is a game that explores grief following the death of a loved one, and how it can grip you.</p>
<p><iframe title="Afterlove EP - Date Announce Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/76BGWySi0C0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Afterlove EP has two central characters, though only one interacts with the wider world. Rama is a singer, songwriter, and guitarist for the band Sigmund Feud. He is also the character experiencing grief after the unexpected death of his girlfriend, Cinta. Cinta is not completely gone, however, and is the other central character. Her voice and memory is lodged inside Rama’s head, making comments and holding conversations with Rama. Rama can’t let Cinta’s voice go, having a knock on effect on his relationships with his friends. Sometimes Rama will have a conversation with Cinta, speaking his responses out loud which leads to confusion with his friends, adding to the strain as they struggle to follow what Rama is talking about.</p>


<p>The game is structured around choosing how Rama spends his day. There is an overarching time limit as Sigmund Feud has a gig at the end of the month, which could make or break them. The events of the game take place a year after Cinta’s death, and it is only now Rama is reaching out to his friends and bandmates, who have continued to live their own lives while Rama stayed in place. During the day, Rama can meet with people, do some busking, attend therapy, go to band practice. and wander around. To be honest, aside from finding photo locations to trigger memories, there isn’t much to do in this version of Jakarta when wandering about.</p>


<p>The band practice and therapy happen on specific days. You will get reminders for band practice, but for therapy you need to check the map and see if your therapist’s icon is showing up. The game is very much about people’s mental health and wellbeing, and not just Rama’s, though you will have the most insight with his. Going to therapy lets him unburden, while the therapist listens and helps him to process. Handily, I’m married to a therapist and asked to get her view on these interactions. Her verdict is that she would not have been so direct as Rama’s therapist is, but generally the representation was good but more counselling heavy.</p>
<p>Who Rama chooses to spend time also impacts the activities he takes part in. There is Regina, your friend Adit’s girlfriend, Mira who is Regina’s friend and a poet, and Satria who is works in the record store. Hanging out with Regina will focus on her life as a model, and the issues she is facing there. Mira will recommend you books and ask for help with a poetry show, while Satria jams out with friends in the park and invites you. All three are romance options too, though it seems very strange to have a friend’s girlfriend as an option as a love interest. Mira and Satria both have their own qualities, if you want to pursue those romances.</p>

<p>There has been an artistic decision in Afterlove EP to have Cinta as the only voiced character, outside moments when Rama is singing. This has the effect of making Cinta’s views much more prominent, even if she is a figment of Rama’s memories, drowning out the other characters. The voice acting is fine, though it can be a little too doting toward Rama.</p>
<p>As the name suggests, music is a major part of Afterlove EP too. There is a rhythm based game tucked in here, as well as a minigame where you choose lyrics while busking. The rhythm game is fine, though it is not always obvious which notes your inputs are corresponding to, and sometimes inputs will keep coming along the track even though the song has stopped.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, Afterlove EP has bugs and I was even softlocked out of continuing when getting close to the end. First, on a lot of scenes Cinta’s lines would flash up on screen, she would start to speak, and then the line would just auto skip so quickly that her voice would cut out and you wouldn’t have time to read it. Considering how the core focus of the game is about relationships and impact of choices, this is not a great thing as you lose context.</p>
<p>Additionally, you are presented with the purpose of managing relationships, but outside of a few conversations, you are a passenger as Rama gives his own responses. More player input to explore different ways the story could go would have been welcome. The softlock came when I had to have an important conversation with Mira. This task flagged up during the morning period of the day, but I couldn’t progress because I had nothing to do that could advance time. You can only speak to Mira in the evening at the bookshop, and I could not talk to anyone else, busk or do anything to move time forward to have this conversation. I searched high and low for Mira to no avail. I had to stop the game there as my last manual save was a couple of hours back, and the autosave loaded into this task with the same result.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jumping Jazz Cats pounces on a 10th April release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/jumping-jazz-cats-pounces-on-a-10th-april-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jumping-jazz-cats-pounces-on-a-10th-april-release-date.1122093/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/28/jumping-jazz-cats-pounces-on-a-10th-april-release-date/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The chaotic kitty multiplayer game <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/jumping-jazz-cats">Jumping Jazz Cats</a> is coming out for PC on 10th April, Team17 and developer Le Catnip Collective have announced – <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1951780/Jumping_Jazz_Cats/">a demo is available now</a> as part of Steam Next Fest.</p>
<p><iframe title="Jumping Jazz Cats | Release Date Announcement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gHFLIS65i_g?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Supporting multiplayer parties of up to 9 players online, or 4 in local split-screen, Jumping Jazz Cats opens up a world of mischief for your feline avatars as you explore a mansion of th Ellington Estate – named after the Duke, of course. There’s spiral staircases, opulent rooms and passageways filled with distractions. Not that you’ll really need them, you’re able to grind down handrails, swing on chandeliers, bounce from cushions, climb up curtains and more.</p>
<p>There’s 6 levels and 6 cat GIF inspired game types that blend co-op and competitive play. You’ll be off to the races, trying to win a collectathon, face off in teams and more. There’s a soundtrack of ten original jazz tracks that influence gameplay during the choruses.</p>

<p>It looks delightfully playful, and there’s plenty of cat customisation available with different body types, fur patterns and little costume pieces.</p>
<p><em>Source: press release</em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You'll need to pay to edit your Monster Hunter Wilds character beyond the first free redo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/youll-need-to-pay-to-edit-your-monster-hunter-wilds-character-beyond-the-first-free-redo</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/youll-need-to-pay-to-edit-your-monster-hunter-wilds-character-beyond-the-first-free-redo.1122090/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/youll-need-to-pay-to-edit-your-monster-hunter-wilds-character-beyond-the-first-free-redo<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Capcom yet again turning a big dial that says 'horse armor' on it</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/gesture.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Capcom</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>How long do you tend to spend creating a character in a video game? The correct answer is three hours. Four hours if it's a Bethesda game, because creating a character in a Bethesda game is like rewinding the Raiders Of The Lost Ark face-melting scene while shooting at your TV with Homer Simpson's Make-Up Gun. It takes patience to extract beauty or even just plain inoffensiveness from the Creation Engine's sticky coils.</p>
<p>Hang on, why am I being mean to Bethesda? I should be directing my snide remarks at Capcom. It turns out the scalliwags want you to pay a small fee to edit your <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/monster-hunter-wilds-walkthrough">Monster Hunter Wilds</a> character's voice, face and body structure more than once - so if you're buying today, you might want to spend a few more hours perfecting that Hunter physique at start-up.</p><!--more-->
<p>All this comes care of <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/monster-hunter-wilds-locks-character-editing-behind-microtransactions/">VGC</a>, who've spotted a Monster Hunter Wilds - Character Edit Voucher: Three-Voucher Pack <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3289620/Monster_Hunter_Wilds__Character_Edit_Voucher_ThreeVoucher_Pack/?curator_clanid=44795648">on Steam</a>, currently priced at £5.49, €6.99 or $6.99. Each voucher lets you "redo your character creation and debut a new look". The base game includes access to <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3289630/Monster_Hunter_Wilds__Character_Edit_Voucher_Single_Voucher_Free_Trial_Version/?curator_clanid=4777282">one of these vouchers for free</a>. There's a similar DLC voucher pack for your Palico, a catlike helper that accompanies you through the wastes.</p>
<p>In the grand scheme of nickel-and-diming I wouldn't call this abysmal, because I seldom feel the need to fundamentally redesign my character more than once. My current Monster Hunter Wilds character looks like an ailing prog rock musician, and I'm confident that's a vibe that'll carry me to the credits. Besides which, you can still give your Hunter a <em>cosmetic</em> makeover without handing over your lunch money to Capcom: the base game lets you "edit hair, eyebrow color, facial hair, makeup and clothing from the Appearance Menu in tent without using a voucher".</p>
<p>Still, it's a bit cheeky. A reminder that somewhere above the artwork you're enjoying sit a bunch of salivating men in bow ties and tophats, holding comically oversized knives and forks.</p>
<p>Capcom have form for this kind of thing. <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragons-dogma-2">Dragon's Dogma 2</a> came <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/critically-acclaimed-dragons-dogma-2-hits-mostly-negative-on-steam-after-players-raze-it-for-microtransactions">garlanded</a> with 21 pieces of DLC at launch, offering optional paid access to items used for fast travel, self-revival and hiring allies. It's more thematically appropriate to Monster Hunter, perhaps, in that Monster Hunter is a game about carving things up into sellable commodities and raw materials. Wilds has been on sale for a few hours and already has <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/dlc/2246340/">40 items of DLC</a> - I'd say they're flogging every part of the pig except the squeal, but there's probably a Squeal Voucher in the works.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[13 Things To Know Before You Start Playing Monster Hunter Wilds]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-tips-guides-items-pause-weapon-1851766658</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/13-things-to-know-before-you-start-playing-monster-hunter-wilds.1122081/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-tips-guides-items-pause-weapon-1851766658<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-review-ps5-open-world-rpg-capcom-1851766113&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/monster-hunter-wilds-review-ps5-open-world-rpg-capcom-1851766113">is the most streamlined game</a></span> in Capcom’s long-running action-RPG series. Worried that juggling menus and harvesting laundry lists of arcane animal parts sounds too overwhelming and boring? Fear not! <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> lets you (mostly) make the experience as simple or as complicated as you want. Dive in deep and get your hands dirty with the game’s myriad interlocking crafting and skill systems, <em>or </em>just hop onto your Seikret steed, bee-line for the next boss, and have a fun time whacking it until it falls over. The choice is yours. But no matter how you decide to play, here are a bunch of helpful tips for getting started in <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196742" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="254" data-playlist="196742,196452,196790" data-current="196742"><div><p>What Is Dragonsplague? Dragon’s Dogma 2’s Devastating Contagion Explained</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196742/196742_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22297.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><hr><h2 id="h664474"><a id=""></a>Choose your first weapon and learn it like a fighting game character</h2><p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds </em>will start you off with the Great Sword, one of its most powerful but also clunkiest weapons. I have been using it ever since, and love how heavy it feels and seeing those big damage numbers it puts up with each hit. But you might hate it. There are 14 weapons and it’s worth playing around with a few of them to see which actually feels best for you and your playstyle. </p><p>Each weapon is its own character in Monster Hunter Wilds, and learning all of its advantages, weaknesses, and quirks is a massive part of the game, like the difference between picking Ryu or Blanka in <em>Street Fighter</em>. I recommend against the Sword and Shield because blocking is boring. The Dual Blades, on the other hand, are lightning-quick and make fights feel like you’re shredding cabbage. Plus, they have a really cool Focus Strike animation. </p><h2 id="h664475"><a id=""></a>Make your secondary weapon a long-range one to start</h2><p>You can equip a second weapon and pull it out of your saddlebag mid-fight whenever you want. While the sky’s the limit for what kind of synergies come from this in the end game, it never hurts to make your secondary weapon long-range in case you need to shift up tactics or play more conservatively late into a fight. I like the Heavy Bowgun. It’s like shooting a rifle and has a nice burst option. </p><h2 id="h664476"><a id=""></a>Never hunt on an empty stomach</h2><p>Meals in <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> don’t give you bonuses so much as necessary buffs that become the foundation for each hunt you go on. There’s a handy list that will show you what stats your current ingredients will give you, with the main ones being health and stamina recovery. The great thing about cooking in the latest entry is that you can do it wherever you want, including right next to other monsters. Buy ingredients from vendors in your camp or pick them up on your way to the next hunt. </p><figure id="" data-id="d987fa326fd570000e625a1906bf8a02" data-recommend-id="image://d987fa326fd570000e625a1906bf8a02" data-format="jpg" data-width="1900" data-height="1068" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A village gives a gift to a Palico. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A village gives a gift to a Palico. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Capcom / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d987fa326fd570000e625a1906bf8a02" data-recommend-id="image://d987fa326fd570000e625a1906bf8a02" data-format="jpg" data-width="1900" data-height="1068" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A village gives a gift to a Palico. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h2 id="h664477"><a id=""></a>Don’t worry too much about exploring until you’ve rolled credits</h2><p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> is one of those games that doesn’t really get started until after it’s over. “Rolling credits” will happen at the end of the main campaign, but there are still more story quests that follow after that. This is the “late game,” which includes high-rank monsters and gear. This is when the game really opens up and exploration feels more natural and rewarding. Plus, all the rewards you get for your troubles are much more worthwhile. And personally, I think <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>’ base campaign is best played in as much of a straight shot as possible. The pacing is pretty breakneck with one big fight after another, culminating in some neat narrative reveals and a cool “final” boss fight. </p><h2 id="h664478"><a id=""></a>Make the SOS flare automatic if you’re tired of fighting alone</h2><p>SOS flares are what let other characters join your hunt. Shooting one up can either be manual or you can change the settings in the multiplayer menu to make it automatic at the start of each new hunt. While it can be fun and challenging to fight alone, it’s also good, and often much faster, to fight with a full squad of four. And if you don’t want to play with other humans, you can keep that party solely consisting of AI-controlled NPCs from the main story. They’ll heal you and do a decent job of taking aggro from monsters. </p><h2 id="h664479"><a id=""></a>Your  Seikret is you most powerful secret weapon</h2><p>The new mounts in <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> are called Seikrets. They don’t fight, but they will rapidly autopilot you through dense and confusing environments by simply pressing up on the D-pad. Normally, the end destination is whatever monster you’re hunting, but you can also select icons from the map and set them as waypoints to give the Seikret new directions. </p><p>They’re also extremely useful in fights. You can whistle for them to pick you up after getting knocked down. They’re a great way to build distance between you and a monster, or get out of the way of a big attack. Their saddlebags are also full of items to restock your supplies (left on the D-pad), including your secondary weapon (right on the D-pad). Most importantly, you can spring and then lunge off their back and press your heavy attack to hit monsters with aerial attacks, which is super fun. </p><figure id="" data-id="66916293bd220b2f52152f2b707d0f72" data-recommend-id="image://66916293bd220b2f52152f2b707d0f72" data-format="jpg" data-width="1900" data-height="1068" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Two hunters ride their mounts. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Two hunters ride their mounts. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Capcom / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="66916293bd220b2f52152f2b707d0f72" data-recommend-id="image://66916293bd220b2f52152f2b707d0f72" data-format="jpg" data-width="1900" data-height="1068" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Two hunters ride their mounts. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h2 id="h664480"><a id=""></a>Make inventory shortcuts for potions and traps</h2><p>One of the biggest pitfalls of Monster Hunter remains its cumbersome item menus. There’s nothing like getting stomped while trying to tab over from your first aid kids to your antidotes. Luckily, you can pick a handful of the most useful items, like your whetstone (gotta keep those weapons sharp!), electric traps, and potions, to equip as shortcuts in a radial menu. It’s still not the best, but a heck of a lot faster and easier than the regular inventory menu. </p><h2 id="h664481"><a id=""></a>Focus your attacks and pop wounds for maximum damage</h2><p><em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em> introduces a system called Focus that lets you hold down the left trigger to aim attacks or stab wounds to initiate Focus Strikes. These do lots of damage and are really satisfying to watch. They all break off extra monster parts for crafting that immediate get added to your inventory. To open up wounds you need to hit the same spots on a monster repeatedly. Once open, don’t waste time closing ’em up. The resulting Focus Strikes also knock the monster off balance, turning the best offense into a great defense as well. </p><h2 id="h664482"><a id=""></a>Always be climbing on those monsters’ backs</h2><p>Jumping off a higher platform or lunging from your Seikret and doing an aerial attack will occasionally pop you onto a monster’s back. Once there, you can stab to open a wound and move up and down its back to avoid being shaken off as your stamina depletes. When the screen starts to go dark you should hold the right trigger to hold on. Once you’ve got a few wounds opened up you can do a Focus Strike before getting thrown off. You’ll have to keep doing more aerial attacks to build up an invisible gauge before you can hop back on again. </p><h2 id="h664483"><a id=""></a>Don’t bother with crafting low ranking armor and weapons</h2><p>The natural loop of <em>Monster Hunter</em> is kill stuff to make stuff, and the pull of crafting new gear is strong. However, the actual stuff you can craft early on in <em>Wilds</em> is not. You can get through much of the first 15 hours of the game with just a couple sets of new armor and one or two upgrades to your main weapon. I’d recommend saving the rest of your resources for crafting high-rank gear once you’re in the late game. But definitely treat yourself once or twice over the main campaign to some cool looking armor which will then make you look extra ridiculous in all of the bespoke cutscenes.</p><figure id="" data-id="6c4be19b8cd169c6a09d0d8c8a2b5398" data-recommend-id="image://6c4be19b8cd169c6a09d0d8c8a2b5398" data-format="jpg" data-width="1900" data-height="1068" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Sandworms attack a hunter. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Sandworms attack a hunter. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Capcom / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="6c4be19b8cd169c6a09d0d8c8a2b5398" data-recommend-id="image://6c4be19b8cd169c6a09d0d8c8a2b5398" data-format="jpg" data-width="1900" data-height="1068" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Sandworms attack a hunter. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><h2 id="h664484"><a id=""></a>Capturing monsters instead of killing them can save time</h2><p>You don’t actually have to kill everything in <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>. You can capture your quarry instead. You’ll get basically the same items for doing so and while more complex, it can actually save time. That’s because you can capture a monster and subdue long before it’s actually dead. To do that, you just have to wait until it’s damaged enough that a skull icon appears next to it, at which point you can temporarily disable it with a shock or pitfall trap and then put it to sleep with a couple of tranquilizer bombs. This can be especially useful if you’ve already died a few times and are at risk of losing the entire hunt. </p><h2 id="h664485"><a id=""></a>Learn how to pause the game</h2><p>Hitting the options button doesn’t pause <em>Monster Hunter Wilds</em>, but that doesn’t mean the game can’t be paused. Instead, the pause button is hidden on a separate set of menus. Fortunately, you can select it and equip it to your quick action radial menu making it easy to pause without your character being left vulnerable. And don’t worry if you have to leave the game for a while. Instead of kicking you back to the main menu, you’ll simply be taken offline but your game will remain uninterrupted (which is great for suspended games and quick resume). What a novel idea!</p><h2 id="h664486"><a id=""></a>That glowing red line means the monster is about to kill you</h2><p>You might notice that when you’re health gets low a bright red glowing line appears between you and the monster that you’re hunting. That’s the game’s way of telling you that it’s next attack, if it hits, will “cart you,” i.e. sent you back to camp. When this happens you should a) get the hell out of the way, and b) heal up as fast as possible. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Can Buy A Ton Of Delisted Steam Games, Like Deadpool, On Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/delisted-steam-amazon-cheap-deadpool-family-guy-marvel-1851767027</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-buy-a-ton-of-delisted-steam-games-like-deadpool-on-amazon.1122078/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/delisted-steam-amazon-cheap-deadpool-family-guy-marvel-1851767027<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="886479a4c7721a38abb8a5877f8e7ee9" data-recommend-id="image://886479a4c7721a38abb8a5877f8e7ee9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Marvel / Fox / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="886479a4c7721a38abb8a5877f8e7ee9" data-recommend-id="image://886479a4c7721a38abb8a5877f8e7ee9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>Over 30 delisted Steam PC games are currently available to buy via Amazon. It’s unclear how long these games have been available, but considering the fact that digital Steam keys for some of these titles, like <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.kinguin.net/category/39238/marvel-ultimate-alliance-bundle-steam-cd-key&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.kinguin.net/category/39238/marvel-ultimate-alliance-bundle-steam-cd-key" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Marvel Ultimate Alliance</em>, can sell for hundreds of dollars online</a></span>, this is easily the cheapest and safest way to grab these digital games. The question is: How long will these delisted games remain available on Amazon?</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195922" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="390" data-playlist="195922,196345,195805" data-current="195922"><div><p>Is Alan Wake Worth Playing Before Its Sequel? | Total Recall</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195922/195922_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21438.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/Wario64/status/1895490485671911516&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/Wario64/status/1895490485671911516" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">On February 28, deals guru Wario64 began tweeting</a></span> Amazon store links for delisted Steam games. And weirdly, if you visit the store page for these games you’ll discover that Amazon is still willing to take your money for games that were delisted years ago. </p><p>I tested this and bought a digital copy of <em>Deadpool </em>on Amazon for $40. About a minute later I had a Steam code. I tested the code and it worked. I now own <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/deadpool-ps4-ebay-new-copies-prices-sealed-wolverine-1851611284&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/deadpool-ps4-ebay-new-copies-prices-sealed-wolverine-1851611284"><em>Deadpool</em></a></span><em> </em>on Steam. If you look around you’ll see people selling Steam codes for <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.g2a.com/deadpool-steam-key-global-i10000006276005&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.g2a.com/deadpool-steam-key-global-i10000006276005" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Deadpool </em>for over $200</a></span>. Yet I just bought it on Amazon for (the admittedly still high price of) $40.</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.steamgifts.com/discussion/za987/delisted-game-deals-amazon-2025-several-activision-games-are-back-in-stock-in-works&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.steamgifts.com/discussion/za987/delisted-game-deals-amazon-2025-several-activision-games-are-back-in-stock-in-works" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">According to this awesome list put together by user Realtione on SteamGifts.com</a></span>, there seem to be over 30 delisted PC games currently available on Amazon. These titles include <em>Family Guy: Back to the Multiverse, Tony Hawk’s Pro Skater HD, Jurassic Park: The Game, Dark Souls: Prepare To Die Edition</em>, and <em>Mortal Kombat Komplete Kollection. </em></p><p>Now, keep in mind that all of these games are priced at full retail. For example, if you want to buy <em>Family Guy: Back to the Multiverse</em>, you’d need to shell out $50. And these codes only work for people living in the United States. But hey, if you’ve been wanting a digital copy of<em> Marvel Ultimate Alliance</em> on PC, this is probably your best (and cheapest) option. </p><p>I do wonder how long this will last. I assume these are just old codes that Amazon has in its digital inventory and once the codes run out, that will be that. For some less popular  games, it could take a long time for PC codes to dry up. But I’d expect that <em>Deadpool </em>and other highly sought after Steam games will go fast, especially as these codes could be resold. So don’t wait too long to buy any of these delisted PC games or you might miss out. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When's the Right Time for Diablo 5? Blizzard's Rod Fergusson Wants Diablo 4 'To Be Around for Years... I Don't Know if It's Eternal']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/whens-the-right-time-for-diablo-5-blizzards-rod-fergusson-wants-diablo-4-to-be-around-for-years-i-dont-know-if-its-eternal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/whens-the-right-time-for-diablo-5-blizzards-rod-fergusson-wants-diablo-4-to-be-around-for-years-i-dont-know-if-its-eternal.1122072/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/whens-the-right-time-for-diablo-5-blizzards-rod-fergusson-wants-diablo-4-to-be-around-for-years-i-dont-know-if-its-eternal<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Diablo general manager Rod Fergusson opens his talk at DICE Summit 2025 by talking not about success, but about one of Diablo’s most high-profile failures: Error 37.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Error 37 was an error that appeared to players at the launch of Diablo 3, preventing them from accessing the game due to extremely high numbers of players all trying to join at once. The issue, which impacted massive amounts of players, resulted in widespread criticism of Blizzard’s handling of the launch, and <a href="https://venturebeat.com/games/diablo-iii-error-37-memes/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>even became meme-ified</u></a>. Blizzard eventually fixed the error and Diablo 3 was ultimately (with a lot of time and work) a success.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But understandably, Blizzard and Fergusson have been eager to avoid anything like that ever happening again, especially as Diablo evolves into a more complex live service endeavor than it’s ever been before, with frequent small updates, ongoing seasons, and major expansions planned at regular intervals. Diablo 4, moreso than any of its numbered predecessors, has embraced live service.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another Error 37, or something like it, would be catastrophic. Especially if Blizzard wants Diablo 4 to persist beyond its major content releases: a true live service juggernaut.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Diablo, Immortal</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">At DICE Summit 2025 in Las Vegas, I spoke with series general manager Rod Fergusson following his talk entitled: “Evolving Sanctuary: Building a Resilient Live-Service Game in Diablo IV.” On stage, Fergusson covered four key components to ensuring the resilience of Diablo 4: successfully scaling the game, keeping the content flowing, not getting too attached to purity of design, and keeping players updated on what’s coming at the expense of surprising them. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Throughout his talk, Fergusson reiterated the team’s goals of keeping players around regularly, consistently, and for the long haul. His descriptions of content roadmaps and seasons-ahead planning is a stark contrast to past numbered Diablo games - while the series is certainly no stranger to expansions and updates, Diablo appears to be committing to a live service trend that’s seeing massive AAA games stick around for much longer and change more rapidly and significantly than they ever have before, rather than leaning on new, numbered releases every few years.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So I asked him what the plan was: is Diablo 4 eternal, or rather, <em>immortal</em>? Is there a marker Fergusson is looking for to know when it’s time to move on to Diablo 5, or will Diablo 4 simply be <em>the</em> Diablo forever, similar to Blizzard’s endlessly popular MMO World of Warcraft?</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Maybe not forever, Fergusson replied. But certainly for a very long time, if he has his way.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“We want it to be around for years,” he said. “I don't know if it's eternal. I think Destiny tried and did that like, ‘This is a ten-year game,’ and then they quickly were not. We want people to see the road ahead, because we know that, to play a Diablo game, you're probably putting hundreds of hours in and we want people to know that we're respecting their time and that we're not just here and gone.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fergusson reminds me that there was over a decade between the release of Diablo 2 and 3, and another decade between Diablo 3 and 4. Granted, neither of these games had anything near the aggressive update cadence that Diablo 4 is planning. But they also didn’t have Fergusson at the helm, as he joined in 2020 after years of leading the Gears franchise. And Fergusson, for his part, believes in looking ahead…but not too far ahead.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>I learned my lesson about calling the shot too early.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">For instance, Fergusson announced in that same DICE Summit talk that Diablo 4’s second expansion <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/diablo-4s-next-expansion-after-vessel-of-hatred-wont-come-until-2026"><u>would not be arriving until 2026</u></a>. Despite originally planning for an expansion a year, the team’s timeline for Vessel of Hatred was extended when they moved staff working on the expansion onto necessary, immediate updates to the live game when Diablo 4 launched, and again when the first season dropped. There were 18 months between the launch of Diablo 4 and Vessel of Hatred, not 12 as planned. But when I ask Fergusson if 18 months is the new normal for expansions, he’s not willing to commit to a specific time frame. He knows better now.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“I learned my lesson about calling the shot too early. So I think giving, ‘Hey, you can relax for the next 11 months,’ is about as far as I want to go in this right now…We're not at a place where we want to put a stake in the ground and call it. Because we're still building it and learning from it…Our process is generally that we get internally to a place where we have the certainty to make a call, and then you get to a place where you publicly want to make that call. We're not at the public part yet.”</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Ruining the Surprise…on Purpose</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Fergusson’s caution is warranted here, especially as his team prepares to be more transparent than ever before about their future plans. Part of that is the aforementioned content roadmap, due to be shown off in April. Another element is the Public Test Realm, or PTR, where players who opt in can play through a version of upcoming patches before it’s pushed live to the wider public. Fergusson says in his talk that the team initially struggled with the decision to use features like a PTR or content roadmaps, for fear of spoiling the surprise for players. But he’s overcome that fear.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“You just realize that it's better to ruin the surprise for 10,000 people so that millions of people have a great season,” he said during his talk. “And even if you mess up PTR, even if whatever you're offering to them in the mechanics is bad, I would much rather have a bad week of a PTR than a bad three months trying to recover from putting in something that we were surprising players with and it turned out to be wrong.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“You can get really spun up on it,” he added to me later in our conversation. “And we've had it in the early days. We're like, ‘Oh, this got data mined, people know this.’ Okay, how many people saw it? And it’s on this Reddit thread, and there’s probably 8,000 people there. But we are going to have millions of people. So at the end of the day, it’s okay. We haven’t ruined the surprise for everybody.”</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It's better to ruin the surprise for 10,000 people so that millions of people have a great season.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">One challenge Fergusson’s facing now is that he wants to offer the PTR to more people, via consoles. Right now, players can only access the PTR via Battle.net on PC, which Fergusson says is due to certification challenges and the general difficulty of releasing new builds on consoles. But he says it’s something Blizzard is investing in, now with the support of parent company Xbox.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Another perk of Xbox, he says, is Diablo 4’s presence on Game Pass. Put simply, it lets Diablo amass as many players as possible. He compares it to why Blizzard decided to release Diablo 4 on Steam in addition to Battle.net - it was simply a matter of reaching more people.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“One of the things that's different from when you think of a live service that's behind a pay gate, like a premium live server, which is what Diablo is, versus a free-to-play live service like Diablo Immortal is, there's an opportunity easier to grow Immortal because there's no barriers to entry, right? Whereas, buying the boxed product or buying the main game is a barrier for some. So that's what Game Pass gets rid of, that barrier. You have this opportunity where you can see new Game Pass players coming in all the time, because they're just like, ‘Oh, I just got Game Pass. Oh, cool, that's in there?’ And off they go. So it is interesting in terms of sustaining continued new players.”</p><h3 data-cy="title3">All Hours Diablo</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">As we wrap up our conversation, I ask Fergusson about what he’s been playing lately, in hopes of getting a grip on what he’s inspired by. I ask if he’s picked up Path of Exile 2, and how he feels about people comparing it to Diablo 4. Fergusson disagrees with the comparison. “They’re very different games,” he says.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But he’s still trying to keep folks who love both games in mind for future updates. “A lot of people actually tell us, ‘do what you're going to do, but just do us a favor and don't line up your seasons over top of each other. Let me play one season for three weeks and let me play another season for three weeks. Don't make me have to pick and choose.’ So I get that. As a person who plays lots of games, I totally understand that.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">So what <em>is</em> Fergusson playing right now? He tells me his top three games of 2024 by playtime. In third place, NHL 24. In second, Destiny 2.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">And in first, no surprises here, it’s Diablo 4. He has 650 hours of Diablo 4 playtime on his home retail account alone, not counting work time. He tells me he’s currently playing Companion Druid, but he also just rolled a Dance of Knives Rogue. He just loves Diablo that much. Always has.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“It's something about the habit of the game,” he says. “I get interrupted from- I'm halfway through Cyberpunk, I'm halfway through Witcher 3, I'm halfway through Space Marines 2000. I get to these points where I am into a non-service game, then I get distracted by something shiny. But I have this habit of, I got to go do my daily in NHL to go open my free pack of cards, and I have to go play with my brother in Destiny 2 because this is what the game we play together on. And then I just...The reason I came to Diablo five years ago was because it was my favorite game to play. So just because I work and I work doesn't stop me from going home and playing it for hours and hours too.”</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Rebekah Valentine is a senior reporter for IGN. You can find her posting on BlueSky @duckvalentine.bsky.social. Got a story tip? Send it to rvalentine@ign.com.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>