<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 12:57:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spy Drops Is Randomly-Generated Metal Gear Solid for the Modern Era]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/spy-drops-metal-gear-stealth</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/spy-drops-is-randomly-generated-metal-gear-solid-for-the-modern-era.917931/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/spy-drops-metal-gear-stealth<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Rainy Frog and solo developer Rainy Night Creations have announced&nbsp;<em>Spy Drops</em>, a 3D stealth-action roguelite very heavily inspired by late-90s stealth classics like&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Syphon Filter</em>.</p>
<p><em>Spy Drops&nbsp;</em>casts you as a member of the titular Spy Drops team, a counter-terrorist organization dispatched to prevent an "eco-terrorist organization" from "wiping out all digital records and sending the world back to the Stone Age".</p>
<p>In true&nbsp;<em>Deus Ex&nbsp;</em>fashion, however, what begins as a simple mission quickly becomes more complex, and it's not long before you're questioning your mission objectives and "uncover[ing] a deeper conspiracy".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/spy-drops-announcement-gameplay.jpg?itok=Q2h33Uxt 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/spy-drops-announcement-gameplay.jpg?itok=55xDk-BB 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Spy Drops&nbsp;</em>isn't shy about its&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid&nbsp;</em>influence.</figcaption></figure><p>Gameplay-wise, if you've played&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear Solid</em>, you'll know roughly what to expect from&nbsp;<em>Spy Drops</em>; it's a pseudo-top-down 3D stealth-action game with an emphasis on remaining undetected and using non-lethal methods to deal with guards.</p>
<p>Unlike <i>Metal Gear</i>, however,&nbsp;<em>Spy Drops</em>' levels are randomly-generated, which strikes me as a bit of a shame; one of&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear</em>'s strengths was its iconic level design, so it seems a bit sad to throw that aspect of the game away.</p>
<p>Still, Rainy Frog says randomized missions guarantee a "tense gameplay experience", as you don't know what awaits you around each corner, ensuring that each player's "game will be different". Hmm. I'm not sure how true that is in practise.</p>
<p>To complete your mission, you'll have access to a host of gadgets, including drones, night vision goggles, mine detectors, and more, and you'll be able to take a variety of approaches to each mission as well.</p>

<p>As a huge&nbsp;<em>Metal Gear&nbsp;</em>fan, I've got my eye on this one, although I'm slightly troubled by the disclaimer on the Steam page that the developer has used generative AI "for dialogues (audio) and icons". Yuck.</p>
<p><em>Spy Drops&nbsp;</em>doesn't have a release date yet, but when it does arrive, it'll be available on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3034070/Spy_Drops/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor">PC</a> and Nintendo Switch. Watch this space for more info.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster Has Classic Frank and Even Chuck Skins, but Only if You Preorder]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-has-classic-frank-and-even-chuck-skins-but-only-if-you-preorder</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-has-classic-frank-and-even-chuck-skins-but-only-if-you-preorder.917928/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-has-classic-frank-and-even-chuck-skins-but-only-if-you-preorder<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster completely refreshes the original game but fans who don't love the revised character design of protagonist Frank West can switch back to the original — as long as they preorder.</p><p>The wholly single player game, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-release-date-revealed-will-run-in-4k-and-60fps-in-re-engine">which arrives September 19, 2024</a> at $50 or $60 for the Digital Deluxe Edition, comes with preorder bonuses too, publisher Capcom revealed in an X/Twitter post. Players gain access to the Frank West 2006 skin, the Chuck Greene Skin (from Dead Rising 2), and the Willamette Parkview Mall Bee skin alongside three music tracks.</p><p>This bonus content isn't included in the Digital Deluxe Edition content by default either despite it including myriad skin packs including ones from Resident Evil and Mega Man. Capcom hasn't announced post launch pricings for additional content but the original Frank West and other skins will likely be available for an additional cost.</p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Dead Rising (@DeadRising) <a href="https://twitter.com/DeadRising/status/1807912242991477189?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 1, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>While this is fairly standard for a 2024 video game, many fans have already expressed dislike for the updated Frank West model so will likely be frustrated to hear they can only mitigate that grievance by committing to buy the game early (or perhaps paying extra later).</p><p>"2024 Frank West looks like 2006 Frank West in 2024," one fan commented on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/1dtdef3/for_some_reason_capcom_decided_to_age_up_frank/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reddit</a>. "This Frank West 2006 outfit genuinely fixes the main issue I have with the remaster changes, so it's a bit mad to hide that behind a preorder bonus," X/Twitter user <a href="https://x.com/Toadsanime/status/1808202938226978905?t=034t2YZak3bSlU9DfGKo3A&amp;s=03" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Toadsanime</a> said. "But at least it's here."</p><p>The look isn't the only thing changing, however, as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/original-frank-west-voice-actor-says-capcom-didnt-ask-him-to-return-for-dead-rising-deluxe-remaster">original Frank West voice actor Terence J. Rotolo isn't returning for the remaster</a>. "I simply wasn't called for this mission," he said.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-release-date-revealed-will-run-in-4k-and-60fps-in-re-engine">Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster launches </a>with 4k graphics and 60 frames per second support and running in the RE Engine. Capcom has made quality of live improvements too, "fine tuned" the interface, added autosave functionality, and more.</p><p>In <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2006/08/07/dead-rising-review-2">our 8/10 review of the original Dead Rising</a>, IGN said: "Though Dead Rising may seem like a simple, mindless game when you first pick it up, it eventually reveals itself as a deeper experience."</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Plague Tale: Requiem headlines Humble Bundle's July Choice games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/a-plague-tale-requiem-headlines-humble-bundles-july-choice-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-plague-tale-requiem-headlines-humble-bundles-july-choice-games.917916/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/a-plague-tale-requiem-headlines-humble-bundles-july-choice-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>The bundle building team at Humble has detailed the games included in July's Choice bundle, with A Plague Tale: Requiem being a highlight.</p>
<p>Humble Choice is a subscription service which offers a monthly set of PC games for its members to own forever.</p>
<p>This month's selection of eight games are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>A Plague Tale: Requiem</li>
<li>Ghostrunner 2</li>
<li>Starship Troopers: Terran Command</li>
<li>Sticky Business</li>
<li>Zoeti</li>
<li>Figment 2: Creed Valley</li>
<li>Heretic's Fork</li>
<li>Hyperviolent</li>
</ul>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="A Plague Tale: Requiem - Gameplay Overview Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aaT4Q4NGm-A?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>A Plague Tale: Requiem - Gameplay Overview Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aaT4Q4NGm-A?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/aaT4Q4NGm-A?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>A Plague Tale: Requiem - Gameplay Overview Trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aaT4Q4NGm-A" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As with previous months, five percent of Choice membership will go towards charitable causes.</p>
<p>This month, Humble is supporting Covenant House, which is "dedicated to supporting young people facing homelessness and survivors of trafficking through unconditional love, absolute respect, and relentless support, in 34 cities across six countries". You can <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OjsV5BvoJPc">find out more about what Covenant House does here</a>.</p>
<p>(And a quick note - Eurogamer has covered Humble for years, but the company is now also a part of the same parent company, IGN Entertainment.)</p>
<p>As for the games themselves, A Plague Tale: Requiem (pictured above) is an incredibly emotional stealth action adventure, set in 14th century France.</p>
<p>Our Bertie called it a "brutal, spectacular adventure of love and sacrifice" in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/a-plague-tale-requiem-review-a-brutal-spectacular-adventure-of-love-and-sacrifice">Eurogamer's A Plague Tale: Requiem review</a>. "Requiem, simply put, is one of the finest adventures around," he wrote in 2022.</p>
<p>Ghostrunner 2 (pictured below), meanwhile, is a first-person slasher from One More Level. Bertie also gave the Ghostrunner sequel a whirl on its release, having been a big fan of the original.</p>
<p>"On the one hand, everything I like about the original is back. It's got the moves, it's got the sounds, it's got that garish cyberpunk cool, and it's got pace... Great," he wrote <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/what-weve-been-playing-134">after a few hours with Ghostrunner 2</a>. </p>
<p>"But on the other hand, it has a lot more stuff," Bertie continued, adding things such as the story "makes it all seem a bit messy and convoluted".
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_7ed2c1ee19d4b6f9d09959e5197349e6ce69e4f7.1920x1080.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>One More Level</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>You can check out this month's <a href="https://www.humblebundle.com/membership">full Choice bundle collection via Humble here</a>. Has anything taken your fancy?</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Banjo-Kazooie Game Is Currently on the Cards at Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/no-banjo-kazooie-game-is-currently-on-the-cards-at-xbox/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/no-banjo-kazooie-game-is-currently-on-the-cards-at-xbox.917913/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/no-banjo-kazooie-game-is-currently-on-the-cards-at-xbox/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ever since Rare was acquired by Microsoft in 2002, fans have been pining for the revival of its trademark IPs, such as Conker and Banjo-Kazooie.</p>
<p>Truth be told, Xbox did attempt to do something with those franchises in the first few years since the acquisition. Rare released Conker: Live &amp; Reloaded (featuring a remake of the original installment Conker: Bad Fur Day) on the original Xbox in 2005, while Banjo-Kazooie fans had to wait until 2008, when Rare released the brand new Nuts &amp; Bolts game for the Xbox 360.</p>
<p>However, Banjo-Kazooie: Nuts &amp; Bolts largely diverged from previous games in the platform franchise. Its gameplay was more focused on vehicle construction (which was excellent for the time, powered by Havok physics) rather than traditional platforming. The game's focus on building/crafting was certainly way ahead of its time, and it didn't sell nearly as well as Microsoft and Rare had hoped.</p>
<p>To this day, Nuts &amp; Bolts remains the latest entry in the series. It has been repackaged in Rare's Replay, released in 2015 for the UK studio's 30th anniversary, but there's been no more solace for Banjo-Kazooie fans from Rare, unless you count the Bear &amp; Bird Figurehead <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-sea-of-thieves-update-1-1-5-banjo-kazooie/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">added</a> a few years ago in Sea of Thieves. Thankfully, a few ex-Rare developers founded Playtonic and created a fairly successful spiritual successor, <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/yooka-laylee-on-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yooka-Laylee</a>, which is now getting a remaster called Yooka-Replaylee with improved art, animations, moveset, camera, controls, and soundtrack.</p>
<p>But are Rare and/or Microsoft planning to do anything with Banjo-Kazooie? According to Windows Central's Jez Corden, absolutely not. Speaking on the subject <a href="https://youtu.be/EbOmQqPNpsU?si=ZnxwFb-YbmGdU5qq&amp;t=1246" target="_blank" rel="noopener">during the latest XB2+1 podcast</a>, he said:</p>
<p><em>I can tell you right now, categorically, there is no Banjo game in development. As of the recording of this podcast, there is no Banjo game in development.</em></p>
<p>Rare is certainly busy with the continued support of Sea of Thieves, especially following the launch on PlayStation, and with the development of Everwild, which remains a mystery. Microsoft would have to choose an external partner to make a game based on the IP.</p>
<p>Would you like to see the dynamic duo return in some capacity, or should they be left in the past?</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam isn't the only place having a summer sale, as Itch.io launches its own sunny deals]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-isnt-the-only-place-having-a-summer-sale-as-itchio-launches-its-own-sunny-deals</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-isnt-the-only-place-having-a-summer-sale-as-itch-io-launches-its-own-sunny-deals.917907/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-isnt-the-only-place-having-a-summer-sale-as-itchio-launches-its-own-sunny-deals<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/itch-vs-steam-summer-sale-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / Graffiti Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>You might have seen that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/heres-how-were-all-spending-our-last-tenner-on-the-best-deals-in-the-steam-summer-sale">£10 will go a long way in the Steam summer sale</a>, but let me do you one better. Indie game store Itch.io has begun <a href="https://itch.io/sales">its own summer sale</a>, and for those willing to delve into its rainbow-coloured heap of throwaway toys and fun experiments, plenty of deals await.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The sale starts today and ends July 12th. There are quite a few tasty nuggets deep in the creases of this bargainous sofa. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/turnip-boy-commits-tax-evasion">Turnip Boy Commits Tax Evasion</a> sees a <a href="https://graffiti-games.itch.io/tbcte">hefty price slash</a><a></a>. Surreal JRPG <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hylics">Hylics</a> gets <a href="https://mason-lindroth.itch.io/hylics">the same</a>. Comedy browser censorship sim <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/hypnospace-outlaw">Hypnospace Outlaw</a> has <a href="https://jay-tholen.itch.io/hypnospace-outlaw">a chunky discount</a>. Architecturally unnerving refugee simulation <a href="https://gabriel-helfenstein.itch.io/north">North</a> has a <a href="https://gabriel-helfenstein.itch.io/north">big price cut</a>. And mildly unsettling Zelda-like <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/anodyne">Anodyne</a> is also <a href="https://han-tani.itch.io/anodyne">going cheap</a>. Yes, some of these are also currently discounted on Steam too, but I know some of you loathe Valve enough to never set digi-foot in their digi-mart. So this is a good alternative, a local car boot sale that will probably see creators get more money per sale. </p>
<p>Aside from games, Itch has also long been a good place for hobbyist developers to pick up <a href="https://itch.io/game-assets/on-sale">assets</a> and ultra-specific tools for game development. The bright <a href="https://johanpeitz.itch.io/picocad">low poly modeling tool PicoCAD</a> is on sale, for example, and so is chiptune music maker <a href="https://1oogames.itch.io/lovely-composer">Lovely Composer</a>. </p>
<p>One little tip: if you see nothing but sex games when you log into Itch, that's no surprise. Like Steam, it's a wild west of boobs in there. This can make it hard to find the stuff you're after. To hide the hodgepodge of horniness you can go to your <a href="https://itch.io/user/settings">user settings</a> and untick a box that says "Show content marked as adult in search &amp; browse". Or don't, I'm not judging. Some of that stuff is on sale too.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More Xbox Layoffs at Microsoft Inbound This Week, Tom Warren Claims]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/more-xbox-layoffs-at-microsoft-inbound-this-week-tom-warren-claims/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/more-xbox-layoffs-at-microsoft-inbound-this-week-tom-warren-claims.917904/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/more-xbox-layoffs-at-microsoft-inbound-this-week-tom-warren-claims/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Following <a href="https://wccftech.com/four-months-after-the-merger-with-activision-blizzard-microsoft-is-laying-off-1900-employees/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">layoffs this January</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-shuts-down-arkane-austin-tango-gameworks-and-a-couple-more-bethesda-softworks-studios/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">studio closures in May</a>, Microsoft is cutting more Xbox jobs this week, the Verge's Tom Warren has claimed.</p>
<p>Yesterday, Xbox's Jessie Thomas announced on X that her role at Microsoft was "eliminated". After this post on X, Tom Warren responded that more Xbox layoffs will be happening this week. While many suspected that it was just Thomas&nbsp;that was let go, Warren has now clarified that more individuals at Xbox will be losing their jobs. "more Xbox layoffs happening this week", Warren <a href="https://x.com/tomwarren/status/1808346995473433069" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote</a> some hours ago. "Microsoft laid off Jessie while she was on vacation". For those in the unknown, Thomas has been with Microsoft since 2015, and served as&nbsp;Senior Business PM of Culture Programs as of 2022.</p>
<p>An hour ago, The Verge reporter <a href="https://x.com/tomwarren/status/1808446740200149347" target="_blank" rel="noopener">clarified</a>, "as per my tweet, it’s not just one person".</p>
<p>While we haven't seen messages from other Microsoft/Xbox employees having been laid off today or earlier this week, it's likely that we'll be hearing more in the coming days. As always, we'll update you as soon as we learn more about this matter.</p>
<p>Earlier today we already reported that&nbsp;Tales of Kenzera ZAU Developer Surgent Studios <a href="https://wccftech.com/tales-of-kenzera-zau-surgent-studios-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">was hit by layoffs as well</a>. According to the studio, a dozen of people had to be let go.</p>
<p>Following the massive wave of layoffs at Microsoft this January, Microsoft announced the closure of three Xbox studios this May - affected studios included Tango Gameworks, Arkane Austin and several other Bethesda Softworks studios. After the announced studio closures, we <a href="https://wccftech.com/xbox-will-cut-more-jobs-arkane-tango-pitching-new-projects-before-closure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported that its expected that Xbox will be cutting more jobs</a>. Games Industry Analyst Rhys Elliott from <a href="https://www.midiaresearch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MIDiA Research</a> suggested that Xbox is refocusing on something more bigger. <em>"Xbox, despite its smart PR over the past years, likely sees these studio closures as a ‘’you need to break a few eggs to make an omelet’’ kind of situation" </em>he said back in May<em>. "It is a massive shame that those eggs are some of the most talented developers in the industry, and now their lives have been uprooted. "</em></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero Pre-Load Details Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/zenless-zone-zero-pre-load-details-revealed/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenless-zone-zero-pre-load-details-revealed.917901/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/zenless-zone-zero-pre-load-details-revealed/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Zenless Zone Zero, the upcoming action RPG by Genshin Impact creators Hoyoverse, arrives tomorrow, July 4, 2024, for PlayStation 5, Android, iOS and PC via Epic Games Store.</p>



<p>Interested players can pre-load Zenless Zone Zero through their respective platforms, which comes with a special bonus of up to <a href="https://zenless.hoyoverse.com/en-us/?no_entry=true&amp;reserve=true&amp;utm_source=sns&amp;utm_medium=CM_Twitter&amp;af_sub5=sns&amp;pid=CM_Twitter&amp;is_retargeting=TRUE&amp;af_reengagement_window=lifetime" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">100 free pulls and 80 Boopons</a>. These pulls and Boopons are valuable in-game resources that can be used to acquire influential A-Rank Agents, A-Rank W Engines, and more, giving you a head start in the game.</p>



<p>Hoyoverse recently highlighted the content you can access in New Eridu, the post-apocalyptic city from Zenless Zone Zero. This city is a sprawling metropolis with several distinct districts offering unique challenges and rewards. Players can explore ‘Random Play’, ‘Sixth Street’, ‘Lumina Square’ and ‘Scott Outpost’. The reception rate for limited Agents Ellen, Zhu Yuan, and W-Engine Deep Sea Visitor has also been boosted, making this the perfect time to jump into the game.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Zenless Zone Zero New Eridu Popular Content</p><p>Dear Proxies,<br>Zenless Zone Zero officially launches on 2024/07/04 at 10:00 (UTC+8).<br>Thank you all for your patience! The entrance to New Eridu is about to open!<br>Get your gear and keep hold of your Bangboo. Let's go!</p><p>※ For Proxies… <a href="https://t.co/ezN4JcZnX2">pic.twitter.com/ezN4JcZnX2</a></p></div>— Zenless Zone Zero (@ZZZ_EN) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZZZ_EN/status/1808433058628161711?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Furthermore, the game is packed with new content, including three thrilling story chapters, including the newly updated Chapter 3: The Midnight Pursuit. Players can also look forward to engaging in new Agent Story missions, such as ‘Koleda’s Story’, ‘Rina’s Story’, and ‘Lycaon’s Story’. </p>



<p>And that’s not all! There are four exciting new events to keep an eye out for when Zenless Zone Zero launches, including ‘Friendship Supervision’, ‘Watch Your Step’, ‘141 Exclusive Bazaar’, and ‘Don’t Get Greedy, Vicious Dogs Within’.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we gear up for the release of Zenless Zone Zero, check out Insider Gaming’s reports detailing the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/zenless-zone-zero-pc-requirements-answered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">system requirements</a> for the game and providing an <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/what-kind-of-game-is-zenless-zone-zero-answered/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in-depth look at what kind of game it is</a>. Are you planning to pre-load Zenless Zone Zero? We’d love to hear your thoughts in the comments below.&nbsp;</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tales-of-kenzera-zau-studio-hit-with-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">layoffs at the developer of Tales of Kenzera: Zau</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive shows, news, interviews, reviews, and</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elden Ring's new Thrusting Shields make Shadow of the Erdtree difficulty trivial, players say]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-rings-new-thrusting-shields-make-shadow-of-the-erdtree-difficulty-trivial-players-say</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elden-rings-new-thrusting-shields-make-shadow-of-the-erdtree-difficulty-trivial-players-say.917898/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-rings-new-thrusting-shields-make-shadow-of-the-erdtree-difficulty-trivial-players-say<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ELDEN-RING-Shadow-of-the-Erdtree-_-Official-Gameplay-Reveal-Trailer-2-32-screenshot-(2)-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>FromSoftware</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-tips-and-tricks">Elden Ring DLC</a> Shadow of the Erdtree introduced <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-thrusting-shield-locations">Thrusting Shields</a> as a new weapon type, but some players believe they're overpowered to the point of being "absolutely busted".
</p>
<p>
You may have spotted in the DLC's gameplay trailer the player character leaping through the air with a spiked shield. This is one of many new weapon types, with two shields to choose from: the Dueling Shield and Carian Thrusting Shield.
</p>
<p>
Both shields have the Shield Strike skill that uses the shield to attack. And if attacking and blocking at the same time seems overpowered, well it is.
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Elden Ring Shadow of the Erdtree | Official Gameplay Reveal Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8GDtwdMBhhI" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>

"New Thrusting shields are the strongest weapons in the entire game and it's not even close," wrote DamnHare on the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Eldenring/comments/1dtks1t/new_thrusting_shields_are_the_strongest_weapons/">Elden Ring subreddit</a>. "NG+ DLC was absolutely obliterated. Thrusting shields can be enchanted with any affinity/damage type that makes them extremely versatile. And it's just so much fun to slap the grace out of every single boss!"
</p>
<p>
Many others agree. As <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/rpg/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-players-are-sleepwalking-through-bossfights-with-the-dlcs-silly-pointy-shields/">PC Gamer</a> points out, the shields can be modified with any damage type and scaling and work particularly well with certain talismans like the Spear Talisman for extra counterattack damage, and the Two-Handed Sword Talisman for a two-handed damage boost.
</p>
<p>
You can also throw in the Sekiro-esque Deflecting Hardtear too to strengthen guard counters and voila, the ultimate tank build!
</p>
<p>
One response to DamnHare's post claimed the Thrusting Shields are "absolutely busted" and how that player beat the final boss. "Being able to guard counter to break poise while not worrying about timing and only taking chip damage is insane. Being able to just spam attacks and tank through everything only taking chip damage is insane," said Drstrangelove899. "The stamina drain from attacking through attack seems really minimal even against massive boss attacks. And its damage is really good as well, especially as its attacks are considered thrust and benefit from the spear talisman."
</p>
<p>
Here's Japanese X user pirochanbanzai showing just how effective this build can be.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aE0FmjAPc8g">YouTuber Larry Puss</a> has also put together a video of the build, explaining how it just requires players to spam two buttons (beware of boss spoilers in the video).

</p>
<p>
Of course, some players will prefer a different fighting style and may consider these tactics as cheap. But if you're struggling with bosses, you could consider changing your build to this. At the least, it's amusing how Soulsborne games have slowly moved away from tank builds only to find shields might just be the strongest weapons in Elden Ring after all.
</p>
<p>
It's also your cue to change up your weapon tactics from the base game and try one of the new weapon types. I, for one, have slapped bleed on the Dryleaf Arts to pummel dragons in the face - it's a lot of fun.
</p>
<p>
Many Shadow of the Erdtree players criticised the DLC for being too difficult and the game received a negative rating on Steam for this and performance issues. However, it's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/elden-ring-shadow-of-the-erdtree-dlc-has-recovered-to-a-mostly-positive-steam-rating">since turned this around and now has a "Mostly Positive" response</a>.


</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard difficulty options let you turn off death, and manually adjust enemy health]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-difficulty-options-let-you-turn-off-death-and-manually-adjust-enemy-health</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-difficulty-options-let-you-turn-off-death-and-manually-adjust-enemy-health.917895/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-difficulty-options-let-you-turn-off-death-and-manually-adjust-enemy-health<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"To make sure players of all abilities can show up."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Dragon-Age-The-Veilguard.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>BioWare</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/dragon-age-dreadwolf">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> will let you escape death entirely as part of its extensive difficulty customisation options, which will also let you manually adjust player and enemy health.
</p>
<p>
As detailed to <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/exclusive/2024/07/01/a-look-at-dragon-age-the-veilguards-difficulty-options-and-gameplay">Game Informer</a>, BioWare has included a range of set difficulty levels and a further option that offers more granular customisation of your play experience. 
</p>
<p>
The Veilguard's base levels are named Storyteller, Adventurer and Nightmare - the latter of which is a permanent choice, while the former options can be flitted between. There's also a further option, Unbound, which offers difficulty editing on the fly.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dragon Age: The Veilguard | Official Gameplay Reveal" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dragon Age: The Veilguard | Official Gameplay Reveal</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Dragon Age: The Veilguard gameplay reveal.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CTNwHShylIg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Unbound options include enabling aim assistance or auto-aim if you so choose, adjusting the difficulty of parrying enemy attacks, upping your own damage output, and even tweaking the general health pools of enemies and how much they'll press you in combat. Finally, there's an option to disable death entirely, so you'll never see a Game Over screen. 
</p>
<p>
"[None of these options] are a cheat," game director Corinne Busche told Game Informer. "It's an option to make sure players of all abilities can show up."  
</p>
<p>
BioWare lifted the lid on Dragon Age: The Veilguard last month after years in development. There's still no launch date, but the suggestion seems to be that the long-awaited role-playing game is now very close to release.
</p>
<p>
Eurogamer went hands-on with the game last month, and came away thoroughly impressed. "Whisper it, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/whisper-it-but-dragon-age-the-veilguard-has-me-thinking-the-unthinkable-it-looks-like-bioware-is-back">Dragon Age: The Veilguard has me thinking the unthinkable</a>: it looks like BioWare is back," our Chris Tapsell wrote. 
</p>




        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wuthering Waves was unleashed on the Steam Deck, but only for one day]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuthering-waves-was-unleashed-on-the-steam-deck-but-only-for-one-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wuthering-waves-was-unleashed-on-the-steam-deck-but-only-for-one-day.917892/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuthering-waves-was-unleashed-on-the-steam-deck-but-only-for-one-day<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Updates giveth, updates taketh away</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Wuthering-Waves-Steam-Deck-gameplay.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/wuthering-waves">Wuthering Waves</a>, that recent gacha <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> of anime styling and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuthering-waves-dialogue-and-writing-is-kind-of-bad">impenetrable jargonblasting</a>, just <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuthering-waves-really-really-doesnt-want-to-run-on-steam-deck">didn’t work on the Steam Deck</a> when it launched in May. It also doesn’t work right now. But for one brief, debatably glorious day on June 29th, it did. And thus, Deck owners who’d persevered through a slightly fiddly installation process (explained <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SuP-MtGV1IY">here</a> by YouTubesmith Deck Wizard) could finally take their first joyous steps into Wuthering Waves like a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SNpCn0nAlR0">David Hasselhoff-buoyed</a> East German in 1989.</p>
<p>Unlike the Hoff, it wouldn’t last. Within hours, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-steam-deck-games">Steam Deck</a> players were being booted back out of the game by a hitherto-unseen anti-cheat failure. What gives? Or gave?</p>
<!--more-->
<p>In short, Wuthering Waves’ 1.1 update seemingly altered said anti-cheat in such a way that enabled the game to launch on Linux-based operating systems, including the Deck’s SteamOS. Previously, it was possible to install the Windows version of the game launcher, but actually getting into the game itself proved impossible. Version 1.1 not only allowed the launcher to launch Wuthering Waves, but for the game to become fully playable, if by most accounts a bit slow on the Deck’s modest processing bits.</p>
<p>Still, before you could say "Absorption is only possible when your Data Bank’s level is equal to higher than the Tacet Discord’s level", or indeed understand whatever the fuck that means, a scary-looking "Anti-cheat system works error" message appeared to forcibly close Wuthering Waves back down. A follow-up update, it turns out, changed the game’s anti-cheat to again block out Linux devices. Only, after a few seconds of playing, as opposed to blocking the game launch entirely, which is a kind of progress? I guess?</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Wuthering-Waves-Steam-Deck-anti-cheat.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>That brings us to the here and now, where Wuthering Waves can still launch on the Steam Deck, and might even provide a few moments of wandering around in-game, but from what I’ve tested it’s only a matter of seconds before the anti-cheat message arrives. There’s no overt threat of a ban (or any other punishment), but yeah, I wouldn’t risk pushing it even if you spent that single day of freedom with a smile.</p>
<p>I nonetheless feel compelled to keep an eye on this (and indeed, thanks to reader Scotty for the tip). While I’m not particularly keen to play more Wuthering Waves, on the Steam Deck or anything else, I’ve now pumped enough of my time into setup and launch attempts that this specific game/hardware combo has become the blubberiest of white whales. You think another solo-manned <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-amazon-prime-day-pc-gaming-deals-2024">Prime Day</a> will kill me? Nah mate, it’ll be trying to trying to launch the magic waifus game on my handheld. Someone take over the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/steam-deck-academy">Steam Deck Academy</a> when I’m gone.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RoboCop Developer Teyon Is Recruiting for a New Action RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/robocop-developer-teyon-is-recruiting-for-a-new-action-rpg/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robocop-developer-teyon-is-recruiting-for-a-new-action-rpg.917889/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/robocop-developer-teyon-is-recruiting-for-a-new-action-rpg/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/robocop-rogue-city-gets-new-gameplay-trailer-september-launch-date/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RoboCop: Rogue City</a> developer Teyon is already recruiting for a new project, and it looks like the studio is planning to switch genres. The developer is known for making shooter games (they also released <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/terminator-resistance-enhanced-new-paint-over-rusted-chrome/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Terminator: Resistance</a>), but this time, they are making an action roleplaying game, as <a href="https://teyon.elevato.net/en/regularsenior-c-game-programmer,j,127" target="_blank" rel="noopener">revealed</a> in a job offer.</p>
<p><em>Teyon is an experienced development studio with numerous titles to his credit. We employ over 100 employees, and apart from Krakow, we are also located in Łódź, Warsaw and even Tokyo.</em><br>
<em>Teyon is looking for talented people who will support us with their skills, knowledge, and ideas in our upcoming project. This new action RPG game for PC and console will be developed by the team responsible for our previous titles, Terminator: Resistance and RoboCop: Rogue City.</em></p>
<p>This job ad also reveals that the unannounced action RPG project is being backed by a 'major publisher'. Both RoboCop: Rogue City and Terminator: Resistance were published by Nacon, which, however, cannot really be considered a big publisher. As such, Teyon (an independent studio) may have partnered with some other company for this one.</p>
<p>Both Terminator: Resistance and RoboCop: Rogue City garnered acclaim from fans due to their faithful adaptation of the source material from the respective sci-fi franchises. The latter game, in particular, was hailed by Nacon as the publisher's biggest-ever launch, exceeding sales estimates.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Banjo Kazooie is Not in Development, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/banjo-kazooie-not-in-development/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-new-banjo-kazooie-is-not-in-development-it%E2%80%99s-claimed.917886/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/banjo-kazooie-not-in-development/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Over the last couple of years, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/a-new-banjo-kazooie-game-is-coming-insider-claims/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">various claims have suggested</a> that a new Banjo Kazooie game has either been greenlit or in development. However, according to one reputable journalist and insider, that is simple not the case.</p>



<p>According to WindowsCentral’s Jez Corden in the latest <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EbOmQqPNpsU&amp;t=1246s&amp;ab_channel=JezC" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">XB2+1 podcast</a>, a new Banjo Kazooie is not in development. “I don’t know if never, but I can tell you right now, categorically, there is no Banjo game in development as of this podcast on the 26th of June 2024. There is no Banjo game in development right now.”</p>



<p>In the past, NateTheHate (under NateDrake on ResetEra) has made several claims that a Banjo Kazooie game has been greenlit and is in active development. In late 2023, he said, “It’s still an active project, but it didn’t get the green light until early last year.” He continued,&nbsp;“There is a lot to do, and development can change a lot (abandoned ideas, internal reboots, etc.).”</p>



<p>Banjo-Kazooie hasn’t seen a true main console entry since 2000’s Banjo-Tooie. There were a couple of handheld games in the early-mid 2000s — Banjo-Kazooie: Grunty’s Revenge and Banjo-Pilot for the Game Boy Advance. There was also Banjo-Kazooie: Nuts &amp; Bolts in 2008, but that game was such a deviation from the first two games, that it’s regarded more of a spin-off than anything else.</p>



<p>There seems to be a high demand for family-friendly games as of late, though. PlayStation’s Astro Bot “2” reveal saw tremendous traction online earlier this year, so we wouldn’t be surprised if Xbox is also floating around ideas on what they can do with its family-friendly IPs.</p>



<p>Would you like to see a new Banjo Kazooie game? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-battlefield-game-ever-going-offline/">the&nbsp;Battlefield games being taken offline</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive content</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The First Descendant Enjoys Big Player Numbers on Steam Despite ‘Microtransaction Hell’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-enjoys-big-player-numbers-on-steam-despite-microtransaction-hell</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-first-descendant-enjoys-big-player-numbers-on-steam-despite-%E2%80%98microtransaction-hell%E2%80%99.917883/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/the-first-descendant-enjoys-big-player-numbers-on-steam-despite-microtransaction-hell<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Nexon’s free-to-download looter shooter <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-first-descendant">The First Descendant</a> has enjoyed a huge launch on Steam but players have hit out at ultra aggressive microtransactions.</p><p>The First Descendant is a Warframe-esque action game designed to be played co-op with friends, with progression tied to a deep-rooted grind that involves completing missions and defeating bosses. Check out IGN's <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/the-first-descendant">The First Descendant review in progress</a> to find out what we think of the game so far.</p><p>But it’s the monetization that has sparked debate during the early days of The First Descendant’s launch, as well as issues giving players rewards they're owed that have forced Nexon into offering compensation.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>The First Descendant Screenshots </h3></div></output><p>Korean company Nexon, which is behind other multiplayer-focused free-to-play games such as Kartrider: Drift and Maplestory, launched The First Descendant with a packed cash shop that sells everything you’d expect from a game of this type: a premium battle pass, new characters, premium character and weapon skins, and even experience boosts and increased inventory capacity.</p><p>New characters, called Descendants, are sold for real-world money, but the premium virtual currency, Caliber, is sold in bundles that come in just under the cost of a new character itself, forcing players to buy more virtual currency than they need and, thus, having some left over.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/03/screenshot-2024-07-03-101622-1719998219426.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>The First Descendant has a premium currency sold for real-world money.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Caliber can only be obtained by buying it with real-world money or by buying the premium battle pass. There is currently no way to earn it through gameplay alone.</p><p>While you can grind (a lot) for new characters, you can save time by spending money to buy them. You can also pay to gain immediate access to an ‘Ultimate Descendant’, which is a Descendant with better stats and an exclusive skin. Expect to pay upwards of $55 for one.</p><p>The First Descendant also locks a paint to a skin, which means if you want to re-use a paint you’ve already obtained, perhaps from the premium battle pass, you have to spend real-world money on it again.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Some players have called The First Descendant “predatory” because of its monetization, while others have said it’s par for the course when it comes to games from Nexon. On Steam, The First Descendant has a ‘mixed’ user review rating, with many of the negative reviews focusing on the microtransactions, but others are also delivering their verdict on the gunplay and mechanics. One Steam user called the First Descendant “microtransaction hell.” Another said: “This game released with more real money purchasable items than actual gameplay mechanics.”</p><p>Even those who have spent money on microtransactions are having a tough time, Nexon apologized to players who have yet to receive items they paid for by offering compensation. “We will continue to strive to provide a more stable service,” Nexon said.</p><p>Here are the compensation details:</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Gold Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</li><li>Kyper Shard Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</li><li>Descendant EXP Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</li><li>Weapon Mastery EXP Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</li><li>2 x Matte Red Paints</li></ul><p>Despite all this, The First Descendant hit a Steam concurrent player count of 229,257, which was enough to put it in the top five most-played games on Valve’s platform. The game also launched on PlayStation and Xbox consoles, but Sony and Microsoft do not make player numbers available.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Legend of Zelda fan jailed for carrying six-inch Master Sword in public]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/legend-of-zelda-fan-jailed-for-carrying-six-inch-master-sword-in-public</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/legend-of-zelda-fan-jailed-for-carrying-six-inch-master-sword-in-public.917874/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/legend-of-zelda-fan-jailed-for-carrying-six-inch-master-sword-in-public<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>A Legend of Zelda fan has been sentenced to four months in prison, after being found in possession of a small replica of the series' Master Sword whilst out in public.</p>
<p>In June, Nuneaton resident Anthony Bray was arrested for "carrying a bladed article". CCTV operators noticed Bray with the Master Sword replica, which had a total blade length of six inches (see images below).</p>
<p>"The blade was inside a sheath and could be released from the sheath with the press of a button," reads the <a href="https://www.warwickshire.police.uk/news/warwickshire/news/2024/july/anthony-bray-sentenced-to-four-months-for-possession-of-replica-master-sword/">police press release</a>.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FQg2NCp1bQU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: With the death of Keystone, will Xbox give up its streaming console plans forever?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FQg2NCp1bQU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>When questioned, Bray said the Master Sword replica was purchased online as a fidget toy. Officers explained that despite this being the intended purpose, the blade "was in fact a sharply pointed item which could be used as a weapon and might put others in fear of it being used against them".</p>
<p>Bray maintained he would not have used the Legend of Zelda sword replica as an actual weapon. Bray did, however, acknowledge it could have been perceived as threatening.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/02-07-24-anthony-bray-topimage-lores-(1).png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Warwickshire Police</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"We take a zero tolerance to bladed articles in public, and Bray has fallen afoul of this," said Sgt Spellman of the Patrol Investigations Unit. "It is possible to find fidget toys that aren't six-inch blades. It is possible not to walk down the street holding them out in front of you.</p>
<p>"With a bit more self-awareness, Bray could have avoided contact with us completely."</p>
<p>Bray is now required to pay a victims' surcharge of £154 in addition to serving the aforementioned prison sentence.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nexon say sorry for The First Descendant launch bugs and performance issues with free cosmetics and boosters]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nexon-say-sorry-for-the-first-descendant-launch-bugs-and-performance-issues-with-free-cosmetics-and-boosters</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nexon-say-sorry-for-the-first-descendant-launch-bugs-and-performance-issues-with-free-cosmetics-and-boosters.917871/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/nexon-say-sorry-for-the-first-descendant-launch-bugs-and-performance-issues-with-free-cosmetics-and-boosters<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>And a round of Kyper Shards for all my friends!</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/The-First-Descendant-Alpha-cutscene.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun/Nexon</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Nexon's free-to-play looter-<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooter</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-first-descendant">The First Descendant</a> - "Nexon's Warframe", as the wags are calling it on Steam - launched this week and has <a href="https://tfd.nexon.com/en/news/2594639?headlineId=1015">encountered a few snags and snaffaroos</a>, including beta rewards not showing up, Easy Anti-Cheat not running correctly, frame-rate drops for people who downloaded in advance of release, and players finding their merry way to servers where no other players exist. Nexon are even now patching the game, and have plied players with in-game bonuses and cosmetics as an apology for the inconvenience.</p><!--more-->
<p>The bonuses basically consist of being able to level up faster and paint your guns red. Here's the rundown.</p>
<blockquote><p>- Gold Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</p>
<p>- Kyper Shard Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</p>
<p>- Descendant EXP Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</p>
<p>- Weapon Mastery EXP Gain Boost +30% (Duration 3 days)</p>
<p>- 2 x Matte Red Paints</p>
</blockquote>
<p>These boost items will activate immediately upon your claiming them from the mailbox, so you might want to save them for a happier time when you understand what the hell a Kyper Shard is. For context, The First Descendant pits you and up to three friends equipped with sci-firearms and accessories such as grappling hooks against the snobby alien Vulgus and a bunch of cursed war golems called Colossi. The latter are after the Ironheart, a mystic energy source said to lie somewhere on your home planet, Ingris. It sounds like Kyper Shards will help with all that. I think the red paint is more of a fashion thing.</p>
<p>All the talk of percentages might suggest a game of making numbers go up in proportion to the implosion of your grey matter, but speaking to Nic last week, the developers insisted that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-descendants-endgame-wont-be-about-meaningless-dps-or-piling-on-specs">The First Descendant's endgame won't be about "meaningless DPS" or "piling on specs"</a>. </p>
<p>While I don't have a review to share just yet, our hardware editor James Archer laid hands and eyes on a near-final preview build a week or so back, and concluded that <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-descendant-pc-performance-best-settings">The First Descendant's performance could still use a bit of love</a>. He was mixed, much like the current Steam user reviews, as to whether the game itself is worth the time. "I don't dislike The First Descendant," James wrote. "It has a good grasp of the numbers-go-up-yay appeal behind looter shooters. Sometimes you get to grapple onto a vast robot crab. The first evil alien overlord you fight is named Greg. Not bad, not bad."</p>
<p>James has also written about <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-descendant-steam-deck">The First Descendant's Steam Deck optimal Steam Deck settings</a>, commenting that "a mixture of Low and Medium seems like the best compromise".</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starfield Reaches New Level of Immersion on Consoles With New Interplanetary Travel Mod]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/starfield-interplanetary-travel-mod/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starfield-reaches-new-level-of-immersion-on-consoles-with-new-interplanetary-travel-mod.917868/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/starfield-interplanetary-travel-mod/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Starfield has just been made much better on Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S, thanks to a new mod that finally allows seamless interplanetary travel.</p>
<p>The<a href="https://creations.bethesda.net/en/starfield/details/473137ab-9f9a-42fa-8d4b-6b7536d63be0/IMPROVED_Sublight_Engine_Boost"> IMPROVED Sublight Engine Boost mod</a>, which is also available on PC, not only allows seamless interplanetary travel between planets and moons but also introduces tweaks for ship engines to make traveling more enjoyable, such as giving every engine extended boost time to make ships accelerate to great speeds. The ship's speed depends on the mass of the ship itself and how many engines are attached, but only Starborn ships are the ones capable of traveling at the fastest speed.</p>
<p>While this Starfield mod is still in early development, online reports say it already works great, so bearing with some of its issues is definitely Worth it to make the game more immersive than ever. Hopefully, Bethesda will take note and introduce a proper interplanetary system in future updates.</p>
<p>Starfield was updated multiple times since its release last year, but the best is definitely yet to come, thanks to the <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-crossed-14-million-players-will-get-annual-story-expansions-shattered-space-set-on-single-planet-is-far-harbor-sized/">annual story expansions</a> Bethesda is planning to release. The first one, Shattered Space, will be set on a single planet and will be as big as Fallout 4's Far Harbor DLC.</p>
<p>Starfield is now available on PC, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S. You can learn more about the game by checking out my <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/starfield-the-elder-space-scrolls/">review.</a></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EA sunsetting three Battlefield titles on Xbox 360 and PS3]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-sunsetting-three-battlefield-titles-on-xbox-360-and-ps3</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ea-sunsetting-three-battlefield-titles-on-xbox-360-and-ps3.917865/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ea-sunsetting-three-battlefield-titles-on-xbox-360-and-ps3<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA is sunsetting three Battlefield titles on Xbox 360 and PlayStation 3 later this month.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The publisher confirmed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield 3</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield 4</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield: Hardline</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will be removed from digital storefronts on Xbox 360 and PS3 on July 31, 2024. DLC and "all extra related content" will also be pulled from sale.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Online services for these titles on these platforms will end on November 7th, 2024. While the online components of these titles close for these platforms, if you own the game, you will still be able to play the single-player component," </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/BattlefieldComm/status/1806689437352341764">added EA</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield 3 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">will remain playable on PC, while </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield 4</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Battlefield: Hardline</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> will remain playable on PC, Xbox One, and PlayStation 4.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">EA regularly delists older titles and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://help.ea.com/en-gb/help/faq/list-of-ea-games-that-have-gone-away/">on its website</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> explains that "some games go away for legal reasons, or because players are asking for resources elsewhere."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The publisher maintains a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.ea.com/en-gb/legal/service-updates/a-h">regularly updated list</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> of titles facing an online services shutdown and will be giving others the chop in the coming months including </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>FIFA 22</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Disney Sorcerers Arena</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">News of online service shutdowns that render key multiplayer components unplayable or result in products being pulled from shelves often prick the ears of game preservationists. Fortunately, all three Battlefield titles remain playable on other platforms (for now).</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard’s customisable difficulties look genuinely great for accessibility]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-age-the-veilguards-customisable-difficulties-look-genuinely-great-for-accessibility</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard%E2%80%99s-customisable-difficulties-look-genuinely-great-for-accessibility.917850/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dragon-age-the-veilguards-customisable-difficulties-look-genuinely-great-for-accessibility<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Invincibility is "an option to make sure players of all abilities can show up" says game director</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/combat_1.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>EA</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Alongside the usual standard and nightmare modes, upcoming <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dragon-age-dreadwolf">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a> (née Dreadwolf) will ship with a fully tweakable set of difficulty options called ‘Unbound’, letting you customise everything from parry timings to invincibility.<!--more-->
</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://www.gameinformer.com/exclusive/2024/07/01/a-look-at-dragon-age-the-veilguards-difficulty-options-and-gameplay">Game Informer</a>, the list of adjustables includes options to change “how wayfinding helps you in-game,” an aim assistance feature including a full-on auto-aim option, and combat timing and parry windows split into easy, normal, and harder selections. You can make enemies hit stronger or less so, and give them more or less health. There’s an option to adjust what the GI piece calls “enemy pressure”, which I’m assuming is how aggressively and frequently they attack. You can also make yourself invincible at any time, like I used to do as a small annoying child inventing the rules to games as they went along. Ah, but I think you'll find I have infinity plus <em>two</em> laser guns, actually. </p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dragon Age: The Veilguard | Official Gameplay Reveal" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dragon Age: The Veilguard | Official Gameplay Reveal</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/CTNwHShylIg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CTNwHShylIg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>"[None of these options] are a cheat," game director Corinne Busche told GI. “It's an option to make sure players of all abilities can show up." Alongside these options, Busche told GI that players can additionally “can look forward to similar accessibility and approachability options” as those you might expect, although there’s no exact confirmation yet on what these might entail. Either way, there’s a real advantage to these sort of difficulty options even if you never plan on using them, I think. Keeping things like wayfinding as a tweakable parameter frees up the default experience to be a little less overt with its signposting, and perhaps a little more interesting with its combat.</p>
<p>“I am definitely in mourning for the less kinetic, more strategic Dragon Age that might have been, but I'm more excited for Veilguard than I thought I'd be after copping the first trailer,” Edwin wrote of the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-first-45-minutes-of-dragon-age-the-veilguard-feel-as-much-like-mass-effect-2-as-inquisition">45 minute hands-on-seat-rests preview</a> he bore witness to at this Summer Games Fest past. “If Veilguard can carve out the cruft without reducing party members to sidekicks, it could be the soft reboot this long-absent RPG series needs.”</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Citizen devs Cloud Imperium fined for discriminating against autistic programmer over work-from-home request]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-citizen-devs-cloud-imperium-fined-for-discriminating-against-autistic-programmer-over-work-from-home-request</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-citizen-devs-cloud-imperium-fined-for-discriminating-against-autistic-programmer-over-work-from-home-request.917847/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/star-citizen-devs-cloud-imperium-fined-for-discriminating-against-autistic-programmer-over-work-from-home-request<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>UK tribunal finds that company "treated the claimant unfavourably" due to disability</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/star-citizen_d2yRJaM.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Cloud Imperium</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>A UK employment tribunal have ordered <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/star-citizen">Star Citizen</a> developer Cloud Imperium to pay around £27,748 - approximately $35,230 - in compensation for discriminating against former senior programmer Paul Ah-Thion, who was dismissed in 2022 after his requests to work from home following an office move were denied.</p><!--more-->
<p>Ah-Thion, who is autistic, joined Cloud Imperium in 2018. As reported by <a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/cloud-imperium-games-discriminated-against-disabled-employee-with-return-to-office-policy">Game Developer</a>, he was based at the space sim developer's former offices in Wilmslow, before Cloud Imperium instructed employees to work from home in line with UK Covid pandemic lockdown requirements. In 2021, following the cessation of more stringent social distancing measures, Cloud Imperium opened a new headquarters in Manchester, and required staff to return to the office.</p>
<p>Ah-Thion, however, had found that working from home allowed him to avoid what he describes as the exhaustion and distress of working on Cloud Imperium's premises. The article doesn't go into detail about this, but it's worth noting here that many autistic people have <a href="https://employmentautism.org.uk/managing-workplace-sensory-issues/">great difficulty</a> with the sensory environment and social expectations of in-office work, unless proper accommodations are made.</p>
<p>Ah-Thion applied for a permanent remote working arrangement following the mandated return to the office, but was quickly denied by Cloud Imperium. The two parties went back and forth over the request, and Cloud Imperium eventually dismissed Ah-Thion in July 2022, citing performance issues related to his remote working setup. During the <a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/654cfca75d60950011bec8aa/Mr_P_Ah-_Thion_v_Cloud_Imperium_Games_Limited_2406047_2022.pdf">subsequent employment tribunal</a>, Cloud Imperium claimed he was unable to meet certain job criteria, such as mentoring junior staffers, when working remotely.</p>
<p>The tribunal, however, rejected many of Cloud Imperium's justifications for the dismissal, noting that in the absence of a formal investigation of Ah-Thion at the time, "concern about the claimant's performance seemed rather retrospective". According to a Cloud Imperium witness at the trial,  the company never formally asked Ah-Thion to return to the office, despite their alleged misgivings about the impact of remote-working on his performance.</p>
<p>The tribunal also found that Cloud Imperium "failed to give any evidence to suggest why they could not monitor [Ah-Thion's performance] successfully remotely whilst he was working from home" and that "there is no evidence that working from home would have failed to achieve the respondent's legitimate aim of ensuring the acceptable performance of a senior gameplay programmer". As such the tribunal's conclusion is that Cloud Imperium "treated the claimant unfavourably because of something arising in consequence of his disability", and that the company could have offered the <a href="https://www.autism.org.uk/advice-and-guidance/professional-practice/employment-adjustments-tips">reasonable adjustment</a> of letting him work from home.</p>
<p>"We find there was a failure of the respondent to understand the nature of the claimant's autism," the judgement comments. "It was a condition of his autism that he struggled with his duties to act as a coach, reviewer and mentor to the junior members of the team. The evidence shows that the claimant was struggling to do this when he worked in the office."</p>
<p>Game Developer also has some comment from Ah-Thion himself, who calls attention to what he calls a "tick-box mentality" to looking after disabled workers at companies who think that "sending a manager on a two-hour course about a disability is all they need to do". 

"I've been fighting this by myself for two years, and being autistic made the whole process especially challenging," he told the site. "But we're lucky to have the employment tribunal system, where an ordinary person can actually find justice without having to bankrupt themselves on legal fees."</p>
<p>"It was clear to me from the start that CIG didn't want people to work from home after the expense of their new Manchester office, and worked backwards from that to retroactively conjure up reasons why my request should be denied, something they continued to do right up until the final tribunal hearing - all while ignoring disability legislation. It was gratifying that the tribunal saw through them as easily as they did." The legislation Ah-Thion refers to here is presumably the UK's <a href="https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2010/15/contents">2010 equality act</a>.</p>
<p>Cloud Imperium are far from the only company to have shed staff in the course of ordering a return to the office. In December 2023, Activision Blizzard announced plans to end hybrid remote/in-office work for QA staff based in Minneapolis, Austin and El Segundo, in what the ABK Workers Alliance <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/activisions-ending-of-hybrid-working-for-qa-staff-leaves-our-most-vulnerable-employees-behind-says-union">described as a round of "soft layoffs"</a>, with some staff potentially forced to leave due to being immunocompromised or the sheer financial cost of the commute. Rockstar announced <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/rockstar-reportedly-orders-gta-6-developers-to-end-hybrid-working-in-the-name-of-quality-and-polish">the end of hybrid working</a> in February 2024, citing a mixture of concerns about "quality and polish" together with security considerations in regards to GTA 6. By contrast, Crytek <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/crytek-make-working-from-home-a-permanent-option-for-staff">made working from home a permanent option for staff</a> in April 2022.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sword Art Online Fractured Daydream release date set as October 4th]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/03/sword-art-online-fractured-daydream-release-date-set-as-october-4th/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sword-art-online-fractured-daydream-release-date-set-as-october-4th.917841/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/03/sword-art-online-fractured-daydream-release-date-set-as-october-4th/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Bandai Namco has announced that Sword Art Online Fractured Daydream will be released on October 4th. This upcoming game in the Sword Art Online series concentrates its main focus on multiplayer gameplay, enabling up to twenty players to collaborate and confront the formidable challenges found within Alfheim Online. Additionally, a new story trailer has been unveiled, providing a glimpse into the story that players will encounter in Sword Art Online Fractured Daydream.</p>
<p><iframe title="SWORD ART ONLINE Fractured Daydream — Story Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/amjCHqUtIZY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The gist of the story is that the Galaxia system, which powers Alfheim Online, has become corrupted and uncontrollable. This malfunction leads to the collision of different versions of the world, creating an entirely new reality. Characters from various Sword Art Online arcs are brought together in this unique realm, causing former enemies to join forces as they strive to reset the timeline and return to their original worlds.</p>
<p>Pre-orders have gone live today for the three versions of Sword Art Online Fractured Daydream, which are the Standard, Digital Deluxe, and Digital Premium editions. The standard edition will include the game and a pre-order bonus of the Demon King costume set. The Digital Premium edition includes the game, the Character Pass Volume 1 giving access to DLC 1 and DLC 2 of Worlds Beyond, a bonus stamp set, and the Prism Heart costume set. The Digital Deluxe edition includes all of the above plus the digital artbook and soundtrack, and the Wild Joker dress. Those who pre-order the Premium or Deluxe versions will get three days early access too, along with the Demon King costume set.</p>

<p>Sword Art Online Fractured Daydream has been confirmed for PC, PS5, Xbox Series X|S, and Switch.</p>
<p><em>Source: Press Release</em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 5 Evil Soul Mod is An Interesting New Horror-Themed Gameplay Mod]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/gta-5-evil-soul-mod-is-an-interesting-new-horror-themed-gameplay-mod/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-5-evil-soul-mod-is-an-interesting-new-horror-themed-gameplay-mod.917838/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/gta-5-evil-soul-mod-is-an-interesting-new-horror-themed-gameplay-mod/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The freshly-released GTA 5 Evil Soul mod is a horror-themed gameplay mod that aims to terrify players.</p>
<p>Created by modder 'AlexDevilish', the Evil Soul mod for Rockstar's 2013 title (<a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-fall-2025-confirms-take-two/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">which keeps outselling more recent AAA releases</a>), is currently in beta and puts players in a nightly setting between 00:00 and 03:00 in which they need to survive the horror. The creator doesn't recommended this mod for the 'younger' players to those fainthearted. "Experience lights being cut off and watch everyone around you die and burn", the description of the mod reads. "and watch objects float around you like in the horror movies you used to watch. She is not so merciful as she watches you observing the terror around you."</p>
<p>According to the odder, "something" is watching over you when using this horror mod. And this "something" is evil, and not happy.</p>
<p>In order for this mod to work, users will need to download and install the ScriptHook V plugin.</p>
<p>Those interested can <a href="https://www.nexusmods.com/gta5/mods/902?tab=files" target="_blank" rel="noopener">download the Evil Soul mod from Nexusmods here</a>. We've included a gameplay video of the mod in action below. As you might have guessed, this mod is only available for the PC version of GTA 5.</p>
<p><iframe title="Something Is Watching You (GTA V) Evil Soul Mod Ghost" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AiyEn4c4JIM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>GTA V is available worldwide now across PC and consoles. As <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-fall-2025-confirms-take-two/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">covered</a> back in May of this year, Rockstar is currently gearing up to release the highly-anticipated next entry in the series, GTA 6, in Fall 2025. GTA 6 is expected to have a map <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-6-map-two-times-bigger-gta-v/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">size two times bigger than GTA 5's map size</a>.</p>

			<p>News Source: <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.dsogaming.com/mods/evil-soul-is-a-new-horror-themed-mod-for-grand-theft-auto-5/" target="_blank">Thanks</a></p>	

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Your paper RPG character sheet itself is under attack in CrossOver: Roll For Initiative]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/your-paper-rpg-character-sheet-itself-is-under-attack-in-crossover-roll-for-initiative</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/your-paper-rpg-character-sheet-itself-is-under-attack-in-crossover-roll-for-initiative.917829/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/your-paper-rpg-character-sheet-itself-is-under-attack-in-crossover-roll-for-initiative<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/crossover-roll-for-initiative-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>MicroProse Software</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>The tabletop equivalent of “buying books and reading them are two different hobbies” is surely the difference between buying sexy tabletop <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG</a> manuals and actually dragging your mates on to Discord for a few hours to stumble your way through a module. It’s the dogeared Fighting Fantasy from a carboot sale kid in me, I think. Something about reading worldbuilding snippets organised into numbered tables just hits in a way a novel doesn’t. Such tantalising ephemera is the name of the game in Microprose-published <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/crosssover-roll-for-initiative">CrossOver: Roll For Initiative</a>. It’s a wave defense where you play match-3 to collect dice, then spend them on fireballs and mace swings to stop tiny bastards from marauding all over your actual character sheet and attacking your stats.</p>

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="CrossOver: Roll For Initiative Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Lq80cJWoXk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>CrossOver: Roll For Initiative Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Lq80cJWoXk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9Lq80cJWoXk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Lq80cJWoXk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>The titular ‘roll for initiative’ is a D6 roll before the start of a round to see how many bonus seconds of prep you get, although you can pause and take stock at any time. “Hardcore match-3 RPG puzzle meets action-strategy tower defence. Far from a casual game!” is how it describes itself. This is a silly way to sell your game, since the screenshots and concept already convinced me to try the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1713080/CrossOver_Roll_For_Initiative/">Steam demo</a> anyways. You did not need to brag to me about how pendulously engorged deez D10s are. I might even suggest that using the words “Hardcore” and “not casual” in your description makes you come across like a dickhead, inanimate store page. Still, I forgive you, because CrossOver is delightfully novel, good coffee-break fun, and very easy to understand, despite its blustering.</p>
<p>You get a single move to create a line of three dice in the match-3 tray, and different abilities cost different dice. I <em><strong>think </strong></em>the tray is seeded so more powerful dice are rarer, though I can’t be sure. Seems like there’s a lot of variety too, even in the limited demo build. Some spells do damage, some slow down the tiny pixel enemies attacking you or carry other status effects. There are also different classes and species to play, so you do actually get to customise your own character sheet before choosing a module from your virtual bookshelf.</p>
<p>I am falling back on both mine and Edwin’s default stance of the Marge Simpson school of potato critique here, but despite the trademark, clut-intricate Microprosaic UI: It's neat! I especially liked the CYOA encounters, with monochrome fantasy art, that bookend main sessions as you travel across a map. These are deeply confusing in regards to what level of meta the game is operating on, but not everything can be Princess Bride I guess. So yeah! Aside from the store description making me want to actually quote Princess Bride, this one’s well worth the download click if you want some, uh, casual dice fun.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SWORD ART ONLINE Fractured Daydream Is Out on October 4, Offering Large Scale Multiplayer Action]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/sword-art-online-fractured-daydream-is-out-on-october-4-offering-large-scale-multiplayer-action/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sword-art-online-fractured-daydream-is-out-on-october-4-offering-large-scale-multiplayer-action.917814/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/sword-art-online-fractured-daydream-is-out-on-october-4-offering-large-scale-multiplayer-action/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Nearly five months after the <a href="https://wccftech.com/sword-art-online-fractured-daydream-is-a-large-scale-co-op-multiplayer-game-with-raids-for-up-to-20-players/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">game's announcement</a>, Bandai Namco has now confirmed the final launch date for SWORD ART ONLINE Fractured Daydream. The large-scale multiplayer action game will debut on October 4 for PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series S|X, and Nintendo Switch.</p>
<p>Digital pre-orders are already open, offering customers the choice between three editions: Standard, Deluxe, and Premium. All pre-orders (except for the Standard Edition on Switch, for some reason) will get the Demon King costume set freebie, which can be equipped on the SKIN tab of the CUSTOMIZE screen after completing the first story mission.</p>
<p>The Digital Deluxe Edition of SWORD ART ONLINE Fractured Daydream is priced at $84.99 and includes three days of early access, Character Pass Vol.1 (DLC 1 Worlds Beyond 1 and DLC 2 Worlds Beyond 2), a Bonus Stamp Set, and a Prism Heart Costume Set. Finally, the Premium Edition is priced at $99.99 and adds a Wild Joker Dress and a digital artbook + soundtrack combo to the aforementioned items.</p>
<p>Here's the official overview provided by the developers:</p>
<p><em>Galaxia, a new system allowing players to relive the past, has been added to ALfheim Online; however, Galaxia spins out of control causing players from all over time and space to be displaced! To set the timeline back on track, Kirito must work with fallen friends...and foes.</em></p>
<p><em>Each with their own specific role on the battlefield, SAO characters from various arcs are gathered to fight. Team up with a total of 20 players from around the world in 1 of 5 parties comprised of 4 players each for multiplayer co-op action.</em></p>
<p><em>True to the SWORD ART ONLINE series, join a raid party and prepare for a fight with high difficulty bosses together! How you prepare for the fight is the key to victory!</em></p>
<p><iframe title="SWORD ART ONLINE Fractured Daydream — Story Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/amjCHqUtIZY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Steam page for SWORD ART ONLINE Fractured Daydream also provides info on the minimum and recommended PC requirements.</p>
<div data-os="win">
<div><p><strong>MINIMUM:</strong></p><ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><strong>OS:</strong> Windows 10 / Windows 11 64-bit</li>
<li><strong>Processor:</strong>&nbsp;AMD Ryzen 3 3100 / Intel Core i5-8400</li>
<li><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;8 GB RAM</li>
<li><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;AMD Radeon RX 580 / Nvidia GeForce GTX 780</li>
<li><strong>DirectX:</strong>&nbsp;Version 11</li>
<li><strong>Storage:</strong>&nbsp;45 GB available space</li>
<li><strong>Additional Notes:</strong> Estimated performance: 1080p/60fps with graphics settings at "Low" in 20-player multiplayer mode. Framerate might drop in graphics-intensive scenes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div><p><strong>RECOMMENDED:</strong></p><ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><strong>OS:</strong> Windows 10 / Windows 11 64-bit</li>
<li><strong>Processor:</strong>&nbsp;AMD Ryzen 5 3600 / Intel Core i7-10700K</li>
<li><strong>Memory:</strong>&nbsp;16 GB RAM</li>
<li><strong>Graphics:</strong>&nbsp;AMD Radeon RX Vega 64 / Nvidia GeForce RTX 2060</li>
<li><strong>DirectX:</strong>&nbsp;Version 11</li>
<li><strong>Storage:</strong>&nbsp;45 GB available space</li>
<li><strong>Additional Notes:</strong> Estimated performance: 1080p/60fps with graphics settings at "High" in 20-player multiplayer mode. Framerate might drop in graphics-intensive scenes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crow Country Review – Scream Park Fun]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/03/crow-country-review-scream-park-fun/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/crow-country-review-%E2%80%93-scream-park-fun.917811/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/03/crow-country-review-scream-park-fun/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="gp-content-wrapper">

	<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

		<meta itemprop="mainEntityOfPage" itemtype="https://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope="" content="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/07/03/crow-country-review-scream-park-fun/">
		<meta itemprop="headline" content="Crow Country Review – Scream Park Fun">			
		
		<meta itemprop="author" content="Steve C">			
		<meta itemprop="datePublished" content="2024-07-03">
		<meta itemprop="dateModified" content="2024-07-03">
		
		
			
		
								
		
			

																		
		<div itemprop="text">
			
			<p>Although there has been a relative deluge of high quality indie games released over the past few months, Crow Country has been at the top of my wishlist since I checked out the demo last year. Offering a combination of classic survival horror gameplay and PS1-influenced aesthetics, it nails both and offers a gaming experience that manages to feel innovative and nostalgic at the same time.</p>
<p><iframe title="Crow Country - Launch Trailer | PS5 Games" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YP2gQszmHM4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>When you first start up Crow Country the retro aesthetic hits you with its fusion of pre-rendered backgrounds and polygonal characters. Such is the wave of nostalgia that it took me a while to realise that you can freely move the camera to examine the environments rather than being restricted to fixed angles. Once you do pick up on this full control however, you’ll quickly find that the various locations have items, secrets, and hidden details to find throughout. The visual design is excellent and interactive spots are easy to distinguish despite the initially busy artstyle.</p>


<p>You play as Special Agent Mara Forest, a mysterious investigator and firearms expert who may be more than they first seem. Mara is sent to investigate the derelict theme park, Crow Country, after a missing person’s report is filed for the park’s owner. Once Mara makes it to Crow Country, however, it soon becomes clear that there is something odd happening there. The narrative is revealed skilfully through a series of notes and newspaper articles scattered around the park, alongside conversations with the few survivors you meet along the way.</p>


<p>Beginning with a trusty pistol and a trunk full of bullets (handy for when you run out in the early game) Mara can find a range of traditional weapons to help her fight off the many strange creatures she faces. While many of these can be avoided in classic survival horror fashion, doing so can lead areas to become especially crowded and dangerous when tracking back – and tracking back is something you’ll be doing a lot of during Crow Country’s runtime. The map is relatively small but every space plays an important part with many packed with puzzles to solve and enemies to deal with.</p>
<p>Controls are smooth and responsive with classic and modern options available. Perhaps most crucially, the devs have thought to offer tank controls on the D-pad and modern on the analogue stick, a feature that I have long argued all survival horror games should have. That being said, the tank controls are less essential here than in fixed camera games and I mostly stuck with the modern ones. My only real criticism of the game is the lack of Resident Evil style snap aiming as it can sometimes be difficult to judge angles (although laser sights are hidden around the map for each of your weapons).</p>

<p>The puzzles here are refreshingly logical on the whole and offer a pleasant aspect of gameplay rather than any particular roadblock. Most revolve around finding the right item and using it in the correct spot but there are more complicated riddles which hide secrets across the map. Solving these is optional but the rewards will definitely help you out – whilst finding all of them is needed to unlock the higher completion ranks. Much like recent Resident Evil games, finishing with a better rank gives you special items to play through again, and a Hard mode is in the works for a free addition soon.</p>
<p>Crow Country isn’t an especially long game, but what’s here is so well designed that it’ll leave you wanting more without feeling short-changed. My initial playthrough took about four hours and then I ran through a second time in the no combat mode to hunt for the secrets I missed. I’ll be looking to aim for the Platinum by doing at least one more run to get the S rank as well so there’s a decent amount of content.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

			
		</div>

		
				
	<div id="gp-summary">
		<p>Summary</p><p>
		The aesthetics, densely packed environment and, at times, challenging combat go together to create a really enjoyable survival horror experience that results in Crow Country promising to be a sleeper candidate for my game of the year.	</p></div>
		

	<div id="gp-review-results">

									<div id="gp-good-points">
						<p>Good</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Nice mix of traditional and original</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Logical puzzles</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Interesting storyline</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
				
									<div id="gp-bad-points">
						<p>Bad</p>
						<ul>
														
								<li><i></i>Possibly a little short</li>
														
								<li><i></i>Lack of snap-on aiming</li>
													</ul>
					</div>
							
			</div>

					
	
						
			
			

			
					
		
					
 
	
	
				
	</article>

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tales of Kenzera ZAU Developer Surgent Studios Hit by Layoffs; “This Hurts Deeply”, Studio Founder Says]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/tales-of-kenzera-zau-surgent-studios-layoffs/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tales-of-kenzera-zau-developer-surgent-studios-hit-by-layoffs-%E2%80%9Cthis-hurts-deeply%E2%80%9D-studio-founder-says.917808/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/tales-of-kenzera-zau-surgent-studios-layoffs/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Surgent Studios, the developer behind the recently-released Tales of Kenzera ZAU, is the next game studio hit by layoffs.</p>
<p>Following a massive way of layoffs this year at numerous studios, including both large and smaller developers, the studio founded by actor Abubakar Salim is now also hit by layoffs. Some days ago, several developers at the studio already <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/raysura.bsky.social/post/3kw6b3osppn2f" target="_blank" rel="noopener">suggested</a> that layoffs <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7213858949022785538/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">would be inbound</a>, and on X, the studio has <a href="https://x.com/surgentstudios/status/1808216664145576284" target="_blank" rel="noopener">now confirmed</a> that a "dozen people" will be losing their jobs.</p>
<p><em>"Unfortunately, Surgent has joined the growing number of games studios impacted by layoffs this year with over a dozen people affected"</em>, the official statement from the studio reads.</p>
<p><em>"It's a difficult time in the games industry, but we remain incredibly proud of our entire team's work on ZAU and of the praise it has received from critics and players alike. Our focus now is on supporting those affected, continuing our work on ZAU, and looking to the future with out next creative projects."<br>
</em></p>
<p>Following this dreadful news, founder Salim also <a href="https://x.com/Abzybabzy/status/1808221598983544959" target="_blank" rel="noopener">took to X</a> to address the layoffs and to ask for help from the community in finding new positions for those affected. "Thank you so much to those who have checked in", he wrote. "This hurts deeply. This isn't the news I wanted to share today."</p>
<p>He added, "So to be delivering this news today really sucks. I know we're not alone here, but that doesn't make it easier. The focus now is to continue supporting those affected in anyway we can. I will be replying to this with links to posts from our affected team members."</p>
<p>We can only wish those affected by the layoffs and Surgent Studios the best going forward.</p>
<p>Published by EA under the EA Originals labels,&nbsp;Tales of Kenzera: ZAU was released back in April of this year for PC and consoles. We spoke highly of the Metroidvania our<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/tales-of-kenzera-zau-review-spiritual-healing" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> launch review</a> back then.</p>
<p><em>Tales of Kenzera: ZAU proves that innovation isn't always necessary to craft a compelling experience. With its heartfelt story, compelling protagonist, and solid metroidvania gameplay featuring excellent pacing, Zau's journey is one that resonates, especially for those grappling with similar grief to the young shaman.</em></p>
<p><iframe title="Tales of Kenzera ZAU 4K Gameplay DLAA, Max Settings" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vzvU9JyMvo4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NASCAR Reveals Landmark Integration With Fortnite’s Rocket Racing]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nascar-integration-with-rocket-racing/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nascar-reveals-landmark-integration-with-fortnite%E2%80%99s-rocket-racing.917805/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nascar-integration-with-rocket-racing/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>NASCAR has announced a first-of-its-kind link-up with Fortnite, with the arrival of the all-new Chicago Street Course map in Rocket Racing, the fresh and popular side mode that makes up a key part of Fortnite’s ecosystem. It has been six months since Rocket Racing was released in Fortnite alongside Fortnite Festival, the Guitar Hero-like mode that has proven to be a rampant success.</p>



<p>With the recent announcement, NASCAR confirmed that further activations will make their way into the Fortnite landscape, but it all begins with the Chicago Street Course.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-the-perfect-blend">The Perfect Blend</h2>



<p>Speaking <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7213931787578732546/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">in a statement</a> published on LinkedIn, the Managing Director of Gaming and Esports at NASCAR, Nick Rend, said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>The Chicago Street Course map lets players navigate multiple routes, master the art of speed, drift, and avoid obstacles in intense multiplayer races or solo time trials. This launch comes ahead of the real-life Chicago Street Race taking place in Grant Park on July 6-7, giving fans and new players alike an immersive preview of the event.</p>



<p>Looking ahead to 2025 and beyond, we have exciting plans to bring more NASCAR elements to the Fortnite platform. Stay tuned for updates on new tracks, licensed vehicles, and other immersive experiences that will connect with our fans in innovative ways.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It’s available on all platforms in both single-player and multiplayer formats, and it promises to blend ‘the excitement of real-world NASCAR events with Rocket Racing’s dynamic gameplay mechanics.’</p>



<p>Over time, more brands are finding their way into the Fortnite ecosystem with custom creations. The UEFN was just the start, and the 2.0 version combined with the unparalleled opportunities it presents has blown the landscape wide open. If it wasn’t enough that Fortnite has partnered with the likes of Marvel, DC, Netflix, and all manner of super-sized corporations over the years, the new model now allows brands to set up their presence in Fortnite and use the platform as a free marketing opportunity.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-battlefield-game-ever-going-offline/">the&nbsp;Battlefield games being taken offline</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive content</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom Acquires Animation Studio For Just $27,000]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/capcom-acquires-minimum-studios/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom-acquires-animation-studio-for-just-27-000.917799/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/capcom-acquires-minimum-studios/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Capcom has just announced the acquisition of Minimum Studios, an animation company that has worked with Capcom extensively in the past. Minimum specialises in face and body animation and most recently contributed to the development of Dragon’s Dogma 2. The Taiwanese company was acquired through a share purchase, with Capcom paying the equivalent of just $27,000 to secure the studio. </p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-bolstering-effort">Bolstering Effort</h2>



<p><a href="https://www.capcom.co.jp/ir/english/news/html/e240701.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">In a statement</a> published by Capcom to announce the acquisition, it was said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>Based in Taiwan, Minimum Studios’ strength lies in animation production for consumer home video game development, and the studio has carried out work on major Capcom titles in the past. Capcom decided to make the studio its subsidiary company to sustainably bolster its developmental and technological capabilities, aiming to achieve its long-term management goal of 100 million units in annual sales.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Recently, Capcom confirmed the ongoing development <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/capcom-confirm-new-resident-evil-game/">of a new Resident Evil game</a>, which is being led by the director of Resident Evil 7. Nothing is known about the game, but it was said that it’s going to be a substantial offering, suggesting it’ll be bigger than recent titles, including Resident Evil Village.</p>



<p>Capcom also lifted the lid on the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dead-rising-deluxe-remaster-release-date/">Dead Rising Deluxe Remaster</a> last week. It has been dubbed more of a remake than a remaster, and it’s coming on September 19.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-battlefield-game-ever-going-offline/">the&nbsp;Battlefield games being taken offline</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive content</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ubisoft Made An OP XDefiant Ability Even More OP]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/op-xdefiant-ability-ubisoft/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ubisoft-made-an-op-xdefiant-ability-even-more-op.917793/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/op-xdefiant-ability-ubisoft/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Ubisoft’s first season is officially here and players are exploring all it has to offer, from the new GSK faction to the fresh weapons introduced to bolster the already considerable line-up. However, there’s one part of the recent update that’s proving to be a sticking point with players worldwide.</p>



<p>When ushering in Season One, Ubisoft tweaked the ‘Spiderbot’ ability that’s basically the bread and butter of the DedSec faction, making it so that you can no longer instantly remove it from your face when it jumps at you and attacks.</p>



<p>This has understandably vexed fans the world over.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-impossible-to-defend">Impossible to Defend</h2>



<p>The Spiderbot has been an issue since players started unlocking and running the DedSec faction in Ubisoft’s fresh first-person shooter. It scurries along the floor almost unnoticed and then leaps at your face, stunning you for a few seconds before imploding. When it hits, you can’t see and you’re rendered almost completely immobile – and if that doesn’t sound bad enough, consider that there’s almost no way to defend against it.</p>



<p>If you see it fast enough, you can shoot it, or you can hack it if <strong>you’re </strong>playing as a DedSec faction member. The go-to defence originally was to look down and shoot, which 90% of the time would result in the Spiderbot instantly falling off. It could have been a bug, but it worked.</p>



<p>Now, Ubisoft has updated the Spiderbot and made it so that this defence tactic doesn’t work. If you don’t see it coming, it’s tough – you’re going to be stunned, and that’s that. Now, players are running the Spiderbot en-masse, with entire teams taking up the DedSec mantle to get their hands on this OP ability that can lock off a squad’s ability to fight in a matter of seconds.</p>



<p>Awkward.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/best-battlefield-game-ever-going-offline/">the&nbsp;Battlefield games being taken offline</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to our YouTube channel</a>&nbsp;for exclusive content</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shueisha Games On! live stream set for July 17]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/shueisha-games-on-live-stream-set-for-july-17</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shueisha-games-on-live-stream-set-for-july-17.917778/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/shueisha-games-on-live-stream-set-for-july-17<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Focused on Shueisha Games titles exhibiting at BitSummit Drift.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Shueisha Games [25 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/shueisha-games">Shueisha Games</a> will host its first official online information program “Shueisha Games On!” on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20240717T1100" rel="noopener" target="_blank">July 17 at 20:00 JST</a>, the company <a href="https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000024.000116303.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. You will be able to watch it on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCeKg5FFGV75S8q8Ws5zLYMw" rel="noopener" target="_blank">YouTube</a>. <span id="more-896622"></span></p><p>Shueisha Games On! will feature the latest information on titles from Shueisha Games, including in-depth looks and talks with creators. The first broadcast will feature voice actress Shiina Natsukawa and comedia Kuracchan of the comedy duo Gattsukitaika, and provide the latest information on various titles from Shueisha Games, with a focus on those exhibiting at BitSummit Drift from July 19 to 21.</p><p>Visit the Shueisha Games On! official website <a href="https://sgon.shueisha-games.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>. Follow the program on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/ShueishaGamesON" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Modern retro stealth action’ game Spy Drops announced for Switch, PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/modern-retro-stealth-action-game-spy-drops-announced-for-switch-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/%E2%80%98modern-retro-stealth-action%E2%80%99-game-spy-drops-announced-for-switch-pc.917772/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/modern-retro-stealth-action-game-spy-drops-announced-for-switch-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Low-polygon 3D stealth action updated with modern effects.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Rainy Frog [16 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/rainy-frog">Rainy Frog</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Rainy Night Creations [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/rainy-night-creations">Rainy Night Creations</a> have announced “modern retro stealth <a title="Genres > Action [1,984 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>” game <em><a title="Games > Spy Drops [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/spy-drops">Spy Drops</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,596 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,590 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3034070/Spy_Drops" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>). <span id="more-896617"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3034070/Spy_Drops" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Modern retro stealth action.</p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> PlayStation generation, low-polygon, 3D stealth action updated with modern effects such as lighting and shadows, randomly generated levels, modern equipment, and head-to-head local <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [345 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a>.</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>An eco-terrorist organization is threatening to plunge the world into digital darkness, wiping out all digital records and sending the world back to the stone age. As a member of the counter terrorist Spy Drops team you are tasked with neutralizing the threat, but soon begin to question the mission objectives and uncover a deeper conspiracy.</p><p><strong>Covert Black Ops</strong></p><p>Dropped behind enemy lines, your covert ops are to infiltrate infrastructure and undertake secret ops that includes gathering intel, installing spy devices and rescuing prisoners.</p><p><strong>Randomized Missions</strong></p><p>Mission layouts are randomly generated producing a tense gameplay experience as you never know what is around the next corner. Everyone’s game will be different.</p><p><strong>Tackle the Mission Your Way</strong></p><p>Explore enemy bases room-by-room, choosing how to tackle each one. You can dodge, hack or shot cameras, knock out or kill guards, stick to the mission objective or explore further. Scout the area first with a drone, hide in lockers, or even use sponge boots to move around quieter. <a title="Genres > Stealth [65 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">Stealth</a> is always rewarded and you will earn more experience for not killing and remaining undetected.</p><p>You select what equipment to take on each mission, choosing from a range of items and weapons such as drones, hacking devices, night vision googles, sniper rifles, taser guns, mine detectors and many more. New equipment is researched and added as the game progresses.</p><p><strong>Dream Catcher</strong></p><p>Accumulate Target Points by extracting intel from unconscious guards using the Dream Catcher. You cannot extract any intel from dead bodies so always avoid killing when possible.</p><p><strong>Level Up</strong></p><p>Gain experience to level up your stats including health, stamina, aiming accuracy and luck.</p><p><strong>Spy Against Spy</strong></p><p>Go up against a friend in local head-to-head multiplayer!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Nostalgic, low-polygon, 3D stealth action.</li><li>Randomized mission layouts, enemies and items.</li><li>Modern effects including real time lighting and shadows, changing times of day and varying weather conditions.</li><li>Choose what equipment to take and how to tackle each mission.</li><li>Tense stealth action with enemies that can see your shadow and hear your footsteps.</li><li>Original character designs by acclaimed Japanese studio <a title="Companies > ArtePiazza [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/artepiazza">ArtePiazza</a>.</li><li>An intriguing story of cyber terrorism set in modern-day, exploring the challenges of the world adapting to new resources and technologies including AI.</li><li>Go up against a friend in local head-to-head multiplayer with spy against spy!</li><li>Three distinctively different environments: Military base, jungle and desert, each with different areas, obstacles and challenges.</li><li>Elaborate boss fights!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. Visit the official website <a href="https://www.spy-drops.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Spy Drops Announcement Trailer (Nintendo Switch, Steam)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y7-e5kekAkg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Homura Hime playable at BitSummit Drift]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/homura-hime-playable-at-bitsummit-drift</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/homura-hime-playable-at-bitsummit-drift.917754/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/homura-hime-playable-at-bitsummit-drift<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Kyoto-based expo runs from July 10 to 21.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>A demo for <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2022/01/3d-action-game-homura-hime-announced-for-pc">January 2022-announced</a> 3D bullet hell <a title="Genres > Action [1,984 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Homura Hime [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/homura-hime">Homura Hime</a></em> will be playable for the first time at BitSummit Drift from July 19 to 21, publisher <a title="Companies > PLAYISM [247 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/playism">PLAYISM</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Crimson Dusk [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/crimson-dusk">Crimson Dusk</a> announced. <span id="more-896571"></span></p><p>At the Kyoto expo, players will be able to experience the beginning of the game, including a tutorial, as well as “spectacular boss battles.”</p><p>The full game is planned for release for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,590 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1820000/Homura_Hime/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date has yet to be announced.</p><p>Get the latest details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>BitSummit Drift Demo</strong></p><p><em>Homura Hime</em> will have a playable demo at BitSummit Drift, an indie game event to be held in Miyako Messe, Kyoto, Japan from July 19 to July 21, 2024.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>At the event, visitors can experience the beginning of the game, from the tutorial where players learn the basics, to spectacular boss battles. This is Homura Hime’s first ever playable demo showcase, so please visit the III booth if you have the chance!</p><p>Please check the official BitSummit Drift website for more details.</p><p><strong>About the Game</strong></p><p><em>Homura Hime</em> is inspired by Japanese anime and aims to perfectly recreate the rich and varied art direction and expressiveness of the genre, and does so as a 3D action game where you dodge enemy barrages from all directions and engage in tense, exhilarating combat.</p><p>Alongside <em>Homura Hime</em>, fight against archdemons possessed by deviant emotions, and get closer to discovering the truth behind both the archdemons and her own veiled legacy.</p><p>Keep up fast and flashy combos by parrying and dodging enemy attacks in this game’s characteristic action gameplay, and learn new skills and combos to further flesh out your playstyle.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Homura-Hime_2024_07-02-24_002.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Homura-Hime_2024_07-02-24_003.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Homura-Hime_2024_07-02-24_004.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Homura-Hime_2024_07-02-24_005.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>Crimson Dusk</strong></p><p>The developer of this game is the Taiwanese indie team Crimson Dusk, formed in May 2020.In 2018, Sam revealed the prototype of <em>Homura Hime</em>, a project he started on his own while he was a student, at a contest. It received a lot of positive feedback, and from there, Crimson Dusk was formed.</p><p><strong>The Story</strong></p><p>Welcome to a world where humans and demons coexist. Souls harboring strong emotions and deep regrets at their time of death are transformed into archdemons. Archdemons have the power to corrupt the foundation of the world and contaminate their surroundings. <a title="Companies > Creature [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/creature">Creature</a>s tainted by this demonic power turn into lowly monsters that operate solely on raw instinct.</p><p>Faced with the threat to the world posed by five extremely powerful demon girls, the High Priestess is forced to dispatch Homura Hime—the “Flame Princess” and the strongest exorcist of them all—and her aide, Ann, who are now entrusted with the divine mission of purifying the world and defeating all demons.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Homura-Hime_2024_07-02-24_006.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Homura-Hime_2024_07-02-24_007.jpg"></a></figure></blockquote><p>View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/homura-hime/july-2-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_896568"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Co-op isometric action adventure game Dune Crawl announced for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/co-op-isometric-action-adventure-game-dune-crawl-announced-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/co-op-isometric-action-adventure-game-dune-crawl-announced-for-pc.917751/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/co-op-isometric-action-adventure-game-dune-crawl-announced-for-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>From GUNHEAD and Wytchwood developer Alientrap.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em><a title="Games > GUNHEAD [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/gunhead">GUNHEAD</a></em> and <em><a title="Games > Wytchwood [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/wytchwood">Wytchwood</a></em> developer <a title="Companies > Alientrap [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/alientrap">Alientrap</a> has announced <a title="Genres > Co-Op [183 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> isometric <a title="Genres > Action [1,984 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,600 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > DuneCrawl [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dunecrawl">DuneCrawl</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,590 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (Steam). A release date was not announced. <span id="more-896541"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Alientrap:</p><blockquote><p><em>DuneCrawl</em> is a cooperative, isometric action adventure game where players take on the roles of desert faring privateers. Gameplay can be described as <em>The Legend of Zelda</em> meets <em><a title="Games > Sea of Thieves [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/sea-of-thieves">Sea of Thieves</a></em>.</p><p>Together, players explore the dust seas by piloting their Dune Crawler, a gigantic walking crustacean festooned with cannons and treasure maps.</p><p>Travel through sprawling, lush, hand drawn environments to unfold the story surrounding the mystery of the Dune Crawlers. Interact with quest-giving NPCs, defend the local towns from bandits, discover hidden plunder, ride armored scarabs and defend your title as the greatest freebooter this side of the seven sands.</p></blockquote><p>View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/dunecrawl/july-2-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_896549"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>