<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 13:54:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here are the PlayStation Plus games for June]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/here-are-the-playstation-plus-games-for-june</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/here-are-the-playstation-plus-games-for-june.882780/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/here-are-the-playstation-plus-games-for-june<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Days of Play kicks of tomorrow.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Tomb-Raider-Legend_keg1JAX.jpg?width=1200&amp;height=1200&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Crystal Dynamics</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Sony has announced next month's PlayStation Plus games.</p>
<p>From 4th June, all PS Plus members will be able to get their hands on the following three games:</p>
<ul>
<li>SpongeBob Squarepants: The Cosmic Shake</li>
<li>AEW Fight Forever</li>
<li>Streets of Rage 4</li>
</ul>
<p>Then on 11th June, those on the Premium tier will also be able to get their hands on the following PS2 games, as part of the Classics Catalogue:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tomb Raider Legend</li>
<li>Star Wars: The Clone Wars</li>
<li>Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus</li>
</ul>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: Is the closure of Hi-Fi Rush and Redfall's studios a sign the Xbox Game Pass publishing model is failing?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Dx4fu4H6us" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Star Wars: The Clone Wars, you may recall, was previously suspected to be coming to the service when a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/star-wars-the-clone-wars-looks-to-be-joining-ps-plus-next-month">PlayStation Store listing was spotted earlier in the month</a>.</p>
<p>And wait, there is more still. As part of this year's Days of Play celebration, Sony is also adding a number of additional PlayStation 5 and PS4 games throughout the month. Extra and Premium subscribers will see the following added into the service's Game Catalogue:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dredge - PS4, PS5 (available 29th May)</li>
<li>Lego Marvel Super Heroes 2  - PS4 (available 31st May)</li>
<li>Cricket 24  - PS4, PS5 (available 5th June)</li>
<li>Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas The Definitive Edition -  PS4, PS5 (available 7th June)</li>
</ul>
<p>Meanwhile, for those PS VR2 users, the following bonus games are coming for Premium members on 6th June:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ghostbusters: Rise of the Ghost Lord</li>
<li>Walkabout Mini Golf</li>
<li>Synth Riders</li>
<li>Before Your Eyes</li>
<li>The Walking Dead: Saints &amp; Sinners - Chapters 1 &amp; 2</li>
</ul>
<p>And, if you ever fancied giving WWE 2K24 a go, you will be able to do so as part of a new trial starting for Premium members tomorrow, 29th May.</p>

<p>As part of its Days of Play festivities, Sony is offering up to a 30 percent discount on PS Plus subscriptions between 29th May and 9th June. Additionally, current members can get 25 percent off PlayStation Plus Extra, or save 30 percent off their Playstation Plus Premium for the remainder of their membership when they upgrade their memberships between 29th May and 12th June. You can find out more on the <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/05/28/get-ready-days-of-play-celebration-kicks-off-on-may-29/?sf273351869=1">PlayStation Blog</a>.</p>
<p>For a full list of games available on Sony's subscription service, be sure to check out our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-plus-games-list-premium-extra-this-month-6300">guide to PlayStation Plus here</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Announces Legend of Zelda LEGO Set For September 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-announces-legend-of-zelda-lego-set-for-september-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-announces-legend-of-zelda-lego-set-for-september-2024.882777/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-announces-legend-of-zelda-lego-set-for-september-2024/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In <a href="https://x.com/NintendoAmerica/status/1795444496399786102" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new post</a> on Twitter/X, Nintendo announced a new 2-in-1 LEGO set based on The Legend of Zelda, featuring the Great Deku Tree. </p>



<p>The previously rumored set will be available on September 1, 2024. Nintendo also revealed a brief teaser of the set, revealing the design and figures included. </p>



<p>However, it did not confirm the exact pricing for the set. This will likely be a more expensive set, since it is a 2-in-1 release. </p>



<p>The teaser also showcases the packaging, which confirms the set is intended for older fans of ages 18 and up. The box also reveals this set will include 2500 pieces. This is fairly large compared to similar video game-themed sets, such as the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sonic-the-hedgehog-getting-four-new-lego-sets-later-this-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">play-friendly Sonic sets</a> or the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-animal-crossing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Animal Crossing LEGO sets</a>.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>LEGO has consistently been able to successfully appeal to video game fans, thanks to a variety of original games and crossovers. </p>



<p>Most recently, reports surfaced of a collaboration between LEGO and PlayStation for a game called “LEGO Horizon Adventures.” Insider Gaming <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/lego-horizon-adventures/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recently reported</a> that the game would be “Horizon Forbidden West but Lego.”</p>



<p>Besides the remarkable new LEGO set, Legend of Zelda fans are also looking forward to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-legend-of-zelda-is-finally-getting-a-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the movie adaptation</a>. There have been various updates on the film since it was announced in November 2023. </p>



<p>The most recent Legend of Zelda game, Tears of the Kingdom, sold <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tears-of-the-kingdom-10-million-copies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">10 million copies in just 3 days</a> after it launched in 2023.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming news, you can read about Sony confirming that PlayStation’s Days of Play promotion will <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-confirms-playstation-days-of-play-returns-on-may-29-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">return on May 29</a> this year, and sign up to receive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Announces Free PS Plus Games For June 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sony-announces-free-ps-plus-games-for-june-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-announces-free-ps-plus-games-for-june-2024.882774/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sony-announces-free-ps-plus-games-for-june-2024/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>As part of its <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-confirms-playstation-days-of-play-returns-on-may-29-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PlayStation Days of Play announcement</a>, Sony <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/05/28/get-ready-days-of-play-celebration-kicks-off-on-may-29/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">also revealed</a> the three games that will be free for PlayStation Plus (PS Plus) subscribers in June 2024. </p>



<p>Starting June 4, PS Plus members will be able to add three games to their library: Streets of Rage 4 (2020), AEW Fight Forever (2023), and SpongeBob SquarePants: The Cosmic Shake (2023). </p>



<p>Like all monthly PlayStation Plus games, players can add them to their library to claim them at any time during the month they’re available. Once added, they can be installed and played at any time as long as you have an active membership.</p>



<p>Currently, PS Plus members can claim EA Sports FC 24 (PS4, PS5), Ghostrunner 2 (PS5), Tunic (PS4, PS5), and Destiny 2: Lightfall (PS4, PS5). Destiny 2: Lightfall, Ghostrunner 2, and Tunic will all be available to claim from May 7 – June 3. EA Sports FC 24, however, will be available until June 17.</p>



<p>Those on the higher PS Plus Premium and Extra tiers will have access to the aforementioned games <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/red-dead-redemption-2-12-other-games-coming-to-playstation-plus-game-catalog/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">as well as 13 additional games coming</a> to the service.</p>



<hr>



<p>What do you think of the free PS Plus games from Sony for June 2024? For more Insider Gaming, check out the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragons-dogma-2-hits-3-million-copies-sold/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">latest sales milestone for Dragon’s Dogma 2</a>, and don’t forget to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to the Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World War I survival horror game CONSCRIPT launches in 2024 for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/world-war-i-survival-horror-game-conscript-launches-in-2024-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world-war-i-survival-horror-game-conscript-launches-in-2024-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc.882771/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/world-war-i-survival-horror-game-conscript-launches-in-2024-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Team17 [165 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/team17">Team17</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Catchweight Studio" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/catchweight-studio">Catchweight Studio</a> will release World War I <a title="Genres > Survival [276 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a> horror game <em><a title="Games > CONSCRIPT" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/conscript">CONSCRIPT</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,088 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,376 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,728 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,177 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,366 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,165 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1286990/CONSCRIPT/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a title="Companies > Epic Games [338 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store, and <a href="https://www.gog.com/en/game/conscript" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GOG</a> in 2024, the companies announced. A physical edition will follow the digital release. A PC demo will be available via Steam on June 10. <span id="more-885455"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1286990/CONSCRIPT/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>CONSCRIPT</em> is a survival horror game inspired by classics of the genre—set in 1916 during the Great War. <em>CONSCRIPT</em> will blend all the punishing mechanics of older <a title="Genres > Horror [410 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">horror games</a> into a cohesive, tense, and unique experience.</p><p>In <em>CONSCRIPT</em>, you play as a French soldier searching for his missing-in-<a title="Genres > Action [1,857 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> brother during the Battle of Verdun. Will you be able to search twisted trenches, navigate overrun forts, and cross no-mans-land to find him, and ensure a home goes unbroken?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Plan</strong><ul><li><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> classic and methodical survival horror gameplay in a unique historical setting: the Battle of Verdun.</li><li>Highly re-playable with various difficulty settings, multiple endings, unlockable costumes and bonus weapons.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Survive</strong><ul><li>Fend off a variety of enemy soldiers and combatants with a variety of World War I melee weapons and firearms.</li><li>Survive in an intense, harrowing atmosphere boosted by a unique pixel art aesthetic and oppressive sound design.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Explore</strong><ul><li>Navigate intricate level design that promotes item <a title="Genres > Management [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management</a> and route planning, whilst solving complex environmental puzzles.</li><li>Distinct World War I-themed areas that intertwine and overlap.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>“With <em>CONSCRIPT</em>, I aimed to immerse players in the grim reality of World War I while delivering the tense, gripping gameplay that survival horror fans know and love,” said Catchweight Studio founder and solo developer Jordan Mochi in a press release. “I can’t wait to bring this experience to both PC and console players later this year and am especially excited to see the game on the shelves.”</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="CONSCRIPT | Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BI4WAG5Fb8w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix shutting down two Dragon Quest mobile games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/square-enix-shutting-down-two-dragon-quest-mobile-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-shutting-down-two-dragon-quest-mobile-games.882768/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/square-enix-shutting-down-two-dragon-quest-mobile-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Dragon Quest Champions and Keshi Keshi will cease operations by the end of July</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Square Enix will be shutting down two of its Dragon Quest mobile games in Japan.</p>
<p>Action RPG <a href="https://x.com/DQ_Champ/status/1793522384865312941">Dragon Quest Champions</a> and puzzle game <a href="https://x.com/DQkeshikeshi_PR/status/1793522247413502280">Dragon Quest Keshi Keshi</a> will be shut down by the end of July, as announced on social media for both games.</p>
<p>Champions will cease operations on July 30, 2024, followed by Keshi Keshi on July 31.</p>
<p>Co-developed by Koei Tecmo's Omega Force, Champions launched in June 2023 following a beta test in February. Keshi Keshi released in December 2021, and was co-developed by NHN PlayArt.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Robot Dreams’ director founded an animation studio just to adapt a graphic novel he loved]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24163570/robot-dreams-oscar-best-animated-feature-interview-director</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/robot-dreams%E2%80%99-director-founded-an-animation-studio-just-to-adapt-a-graphic-novel-he-loved.882759/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24163570/robot-dreams-oscar-best-animated-feature-interview-director<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>If you buy something from a Polygon link, Vox Media may earn a commission. See our <a href="https://www.polygon.com/pages/ethics-statement" target="_blank">ethics statement</a>.</p><div>
  <p id="fbq1fP">In 2018, when director Pablo Berger was thinking about his next movie, he happened to crack open one of his favorite graphic novels, a short, wordless story about a dog and a robot, best friends who are separated and drift apart. Berger had read <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Robot-Dreams-Sara-Varon/dp/1250073502?tag=polygon05-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank" has-subtag="true" data-cdata="{&quot;rewritten_url&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Robot-Dreams-Sara-Varon/dp/1250073502?ascsubtag=___pl__p_23927611__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder\u0026tag=polygon05-20&quot;,&quot;subtag_max_length&quot;:99,&quot;subtag_delim_length&quot;:3,&quot;subtag_key&quot;:&quot;ascsubtag&quot;,&quot;subtag_data&quot;:{&quot;ascsubtag&quot;:&quot;___pl__p_23927611__m_m-placeholder__s_s-placeholder__t_w__c_c-placeholder__r_r-placeholder__d_d-placeholder&quot;,&quot;tag&quot;:&quot;polygon05-20&quot;},&quot;encode_subtag&quot;:false}">Sara Varon’s <em>Robot Dreams</em></a> before, but the reread caught him off guard. </p>
<p id="Tv73ol">“This time, when I got to the end of the book, that last act, I was so moved by the story, it brought me truly to tears,” Berger told Polygon in an interview ahead of the film’s limited theatrical release. “I was so shaken by the story. Right there at that moment, I thought there was something very special about the book. That’s when I decided to adapt it and make an animated film — even if it was something new for me.”</p>
<p id="x6aZwS">Varon’s book is a surprisingly poignant look at the ephemeral nature of friendships, and Berger was determined to capture that in his movie. He’d written and directed three celebrated, successful live-action feature films — <em>Torremolinos 73</em>, <em>Abracadabra</em>, and Spain’s 2012 Academy Award submission, <em>Blancanieves</em>. But making an animated movie would be different. Very different. </p>
<p id="akdf6n">“I was truly very frightened about starting the production,” he says. “But I like challenges. It didn’t block me. It really excited me, the fact that it was something new.”</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462367/2._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1716901211_5397_99033" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25462367,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gGZ_LMbXoUD3ufesID4nf3dJgXQ=/0x0:3225x1753/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3225x1753):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462367/2._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/u9FEQ_FSp2O5-0NaM22Dv9AdHmQ=/0x0:3225x1753/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3225x1753):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462367/2._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/w0MH4apS3jE3tralp9U4YsxNcXM=/0x0:3225x1753/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3225x1753):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462367/2._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k3P_FPbWjmSNnB6zC4GEKJrOzDo=/0x0:3225x1753/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3225x1753):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462367/2._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lh9rYxj3mhTYRGsjnPAVnmAOR_g=/0x0:3225x1753/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:3225x1753):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462367/2._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8q5RTV-HcEZT8Oou2aPupKrR98w=/0x0:3225x1753/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:3225x1753):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462367/2._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nhO3wLMaI6rHM8sau_qTsIxAhnY=/0x0:3225x1753/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:3225x1753):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462367/2._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J8Jt_bFkGESQH6DWXlTaWyxkMVU=/0x0:3225x1753/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:3225x1753):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462367/2._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i2ReB5GMbQyJHSGGlrxOxez9alQ=/0x0:3225x1753/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3225x1753):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462367/2._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Neon</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="SaW6xK">But despite his lack of experience, Berger’s <em>Robot Dreams</em> captures the book’s surprising poignancy, while using the extra space of a feature-length film to expand on its central relationships. It’s set in 1980s New York City, in a world populated by anthropomorphic animals. When one of them, Dog, feels lonely and isolated, he orders a robot companion. And after a whirlwind summer together, bonding over <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qfi9JpgMc2U">Earth, Wind &amp; Fire’s “September,”</a> they become best friends. </p>
<p id="gJeJ0X">But an outing to Coney Island leaves Robot powered down and stranded on the beach, and when Dog returns to rescue him, he finds the beach closed for the rest of the year. The remainder of the movie follows what happens to the two of them in their time apart, and how they forge new connections while never forgetting each other. It’s a lovely reverie on friendship, and the space we hold in our hearts for those we left behind (in this case, pretty physically and literally). </p>
<p id="eXZBtS">Following a limited release, <em>Robot Dreams</em> was nominated for the Best Animated Feature Oscar, alongside <a href="https://www.polygon.com/reviews/23742233/spider-man-across-spider-verse-review"><em>Spider-Man: Across the Spider-Verse</em></a>, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23759647/nimona-netflix-comic-changes-nd-stevenson"><em>Nimona</em></a>, and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23797923/how-do-you-live-boy-and-the-heron-hayao-miyazaki-review"><em>The Boy and the Heron</em></a>. The movie finally debuts in American theaters this summer, starting with a small release in New York City on May 31. Berger is excited to see his movie gain more traction after its surprise Oscar appearance, especially since it’s a story he is so passionate about. That passion was what fueled the production, despite the challenges for a first-time animation director. And there were some big challenges. Originally, Berger was set to work with Irish animation studio Cartoon Saloon (<a href="https://www.polygon.com/entertainment/2020/9/15/21438560/wolfwalkers-review-apple-tv-plus"><em>Wolfwalkers</em></a>, <em>The Secret of Kells</em>) for<em> Robot Dreams</em>. But production hit a snag during the COVID-19 pandemic, and Berger had to pivot. </p>
<p id="VWGo6C">“Suddenly, we had to create our own studios in Spain,” he says. “So we called them pop-up studios, because we had to create them from scratch. We had to find the offices, buy the computers, hire animators and artists from all over Europe, and create a pipeline. So that was really hard.”</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462363/6._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1716901211_1419_99034" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25462363,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OHp1fCdR7pcATq7lOUwkTWR5HD8=/0x0:1998x1080/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462363/6._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/q1WXjx59Z1MfzTuA9X5QwB_pYag=/0x0:1998x1080/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462363/6._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ghSNgpyALrSMiCZWrlbWjtPnIgM=/0x0:1998x1080/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462363/6._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F4urAHy53nFOjN3qFd0-cwefDqU=/0x0:1998x1080/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462363/6._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2mKoJ4KF8LXD6LZ8qCd3GTKuYE4=/0x0:1998x1080/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462363/6._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gwb5hRIUsTCpuosLaZhrY4mHDMY=/0x0:1998x1080/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462363/6._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/j8tDUAJgefN86z3MqsDMzTb5qS0=/0x0:1998x1080/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462363/6._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IiOHG-jiex6kbLOljIyAYbXFctw=/0x0:1998x1080/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462363/6._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_kk5fp65IrIpXExOWDky3MjoIPg=/0x0:1998x1080/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462363/6._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Neon</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="PmfR95">Berger quickly learned some key differences between production on a live-action movie and an animated one. For one, there are no individual department heads for hair and makeup or camera on an animated movie; it all falls under the art department. And there are no actors in a movie without dialogue; the animators handle all the “acting.”</p>
<p id="oMqAUC">“At the same time, I had to achieve the same goal,” says Berger. “Three-dimensional, emotional, believable performances.” </p>
<p id="MEIp5T">Berger tells us that in his live-action work, he talks with actors and looks deep in their eyes in order to draw out the most emotionally truthful performance he can. And with <em>Robot Dreams</em>, he wanted to take the same approach — just a little bit adjusted, of course, since there were no actors to make that connection with. </p>
<p id="39wYvq">“When I was looking at the animation of the drawings, I looked at the pupils of the characters,” he explains. “So basically, to bring a truthful, believable performance that could move the audience, that the audience could have empathy for Dog and Robot.”</p>
<p>  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462362/4._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1716901211_7872_99035" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25462362,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qqrn6YNyKKxcxNmCzcLeykXxsMw=/0x0:1998x1080/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462362/4._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/JwyjnSdZ4ysL2Mmk3FUsaCNbdzQ=/0x0:1998x1080/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462362/4._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IKN-eKGwb6Rp5ndsgEgQ3isSuCg=/0x0:1998x1080/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462362/4._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cvzm1Kvw7QgBe1h8UJhdZjNFm2s=/0x0:1998x1080/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462362/4._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/S1bqTrWkVTKdCJpFqGjAAgimONo=/0x0:1998x1080/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462362/4._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uUr94w9jWyg1aJm_gIss14t3zHY=/0x0:1998x1080/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462362/4._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DrX5-p7IcUaKShRnpG36aEED4SM=/0x0:1998x1080/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462362/4._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/C95vQfcMr5eGl4WXzlWjCWuNJbw=/0x0:1998x1080/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462362/4._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/E7rkwd_Da5d7kKJGnSFYPsq3Z74=/0x0:1998x1080/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1998x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25462362/4._Robot_Dreams___2023_Arcadia_Motion_Pictures__Lokiz_Films__Noodles_Production__Les_Films_du_Worso.png 1920w" sizes="90vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Neon</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


</p>
<p id="95QKXB">Berger says he enjoyed every minute working on <em>Robot Dreams</em>, and he would happily do another animated film in the future. There’s a lingering prejudice, especially in the United States, against animation, seen primarily as a medium for children’s movies. But Berger, like <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23511107/guillermo-del-toro-pinocchio-interview-netflix-monsters">Guillermo del Toro</a> and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/tv/2020/7/2/21311449/clone-high-revival-new-episodes-lord-miller-mtv-lawrence-season-2-gandhi">Phil Lord and Christopher Miller</a> before him, is a firm believer that animation isn’t a genre. </p>
<p id="DINWCB">“Animation is just a way to tell the story. And animation is not only for kids. There are so many great animated films that could be for kids, but could be for adults,” he says, citing the likes of <em>Persepolis</em>, <em>The Triplets of Belleville</em>, and <a href="https://www.polygon.com/animation-cartoons/21267907/studio-ghibli-movies-watch-guide-totoro-spirited-away-miyazaki-takahata-films">Studio Ghibli’s filmography</a>. While <em>Robot Dreams </em>is family-friendly, Berger says his studio never made any compromises in the filmmaking process in order to appeal to children. In fact, aiming at a specific audience was the last thing on his mind. </p>
<p id="tSedp4">“I like to make an analogy with film. Films, for me, they are like a lasagna. And there are different layers. Every audience gets a different layer,” he says. “In a way, it looks back to when I was a kid and I saw the same film as my parents. Some of the films that are released in the last decades seem that they’re catered for [just] cinephiles, or for commercial [audiences], or for children. I think [<em>Robot Dreams</em>] really is for a very wide audience.” </p>
<p id="z5W2Pj"><small><em>Robot Dreams </em></small><small>opens in New York City on May 31, and will eventually roll out into theaters nationwide.</small></p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Confirms PlayStation Days of Play Returns on May 29, 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/sony-confirms-playstation-days-of-play-returns-on-may-29-2024/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sony-confirms-playstation-days-of-play-returns-on-may-29-2024.882756/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/sony-confirms-playstation-days-of-play-returns-on-may-29-2024/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In an <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/05/28/get-ready-days-of-play-celebration-kicks-off-on-may-29/?sf273351644=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official blog</a> today, Sony announced that PlayStation’s Days of Play 2024 is coming on May 29, featuring new discounts and activities. </p>



<p>Today’s blog confirms Days of Play will last from “May 29 at 12:01 AM through June 12 at 11:59 PM local time in each region.”</p>



<p>PlayStation players will get access to new, celebratory avatars throughout Days of Play. Sony also announced the PlayStation Plus Monthly Games lineup for June, and bonus titles for the Game Catalog and more.</p>



<p>Some highlights include Star Wars: The Clone Wars for PS2, and Dredge for PS4 and PS5 on day one of the event. Later, the definitive edition of Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas for PlayStation 4 and PlayStation 5 is coming on June 7.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Some of the Days of Play activities will include a community challenge, new Stars campaigns, and an Esports tournament.</p>



<p>The announcement confirms a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-days-of-play-event-coming-end-of-may-2024-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recent report by Dealabs</a>, which also claimed the event would return on May 29. Dealabs also mentioned some discounts, and PlayStation did announce some notable sales today.</p>



<p>Sony will offer $50 off a PlayStation 5 and the PlayStation 5 Digital Edition. Additionally, there will be $100 off PlayStation VR2. Although, a March report suggested that Sony paused PS VR2 production because the device <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sony-pauses-psvr2-production-sales/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wasn’t selling enough</a>.</p>



<p>Between May 29 and June 9, fans can also save “up to 30% on a 12-month membership plan” for PlayStation Plus. </p>



<p>Other Days of Play 2024 deals include discounts for key titles such as Marvel’s Spider-Man 2, Rise of the Ronin, and more.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming updates, you can read about Dragon’s Dogma 2 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragons-dogma-2-hits-3-million-copies-sold/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reaching 3 million units sold</a>, and sign up to receive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon’s Dogma 2 Hits 3 Million Copies Sold]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragons-dogma-2-hits-3-million-copies-sold/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon%E2%80%99s-dogma-2-hits-3-million-copies-sold.882753/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragons-dogma-2-hits-3-million-copies-sold/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In <a href="https://x.com/DragonsDogma/status/1795387174453395631" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new post</a> on Twitter/X, Capcom confirmed that Dragon’s Dogma 2 has reached 3 million copies sold. </p>



<p>The Dragon’s Dogma 2 team officially thanked “3 million Arisen who have embarked on adventures” for their continued support. </p>



<p>In the first week of April, Capcom previously announced that Dragon’s Dogma 2 had <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragons-dogma-2-2-million-units/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sold 2.5 million units</a>. This gives fans an idea of the game’s healthy sales pace. </p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Thank you to the 3 million Arisen who have embarked on adventures in Dragon's Dogma 2! We are grateful for your continued support.</p><p> – The Dragon's Dogma 2 Team <a href="https://t.co/jMZL6DUxxE">pic.twitter.com/jMZL6DUxxE</a></p></div>— Dragon's Dogma (@DragonsDogma) <a href="https://twitter.com/DragonsDogma/status/1795387174453395631?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>Dragon’s Dogma 2 first launched in March 2024 to strong critical reviews. However, it also <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragons-dogma-2-microtransactions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">faced early backlash</a> over microtransaction concerns, and Capcom’s approach surrounding them. Some fans also noted performance issues, among other flaws.</p>



<p>Still, data showed that Dragon’s Dogma 2 was the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragons-dogma-2-was-march-2024s-best-selling-game-in-us/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best-selling game of March 2024</a> in the US. </p>



<p>In fact, the combined revenue boost from Dragon’s Dogma 2 and the latest Street Fighter ultimately encouraged Capcom to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/capcom-raises-earnings-forecast-following-dragons-dogma-2-boost/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">raise its earnings forecast</a>. </p>



<p>As a result, Capcom’s revised forecast for the year ending March 31st, 2024, increased from 40 to 43.3 million yen in net income. </p>



<p>So, despite some early criticism toward Dragon’s Dogma 2, it seems the game will continue to perform well. The series first began in May 2012, so it celebrated another major anniversary last week. The devs also took that opportunity <a href="https://x.com/DragonsDogma/status/1793932038778814900" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">to thank players</a> on Twitter. </p>



<p>Dragon’s Dogma 2 is available now on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S. </p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest gaming industry updates, you can read about Tango Gameworks <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/tango-gameworks-2-games/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">developing two unannounced games</a> before its closure, and sign up to receive the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rainbow Six Siege Fans Boo $9.99 A-Month Membership Announcement]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/rainbow-six-siege-fans-boo-999-a-month-membership-announcement</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rainbow-six-siege-fans-boo-9-99-a-month-membership-announcement.882747/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/rainbow-six-siege-fans-boo-999-a-month-membership-announcement<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Ubisoft has announced a $9.99 a month membership for its shooter <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/tom-clancys-rainbow-six-siege">Rainbow Six Siege</a> — and it’s not going down well with the core fanbase.</p><p>Rainbow Six Siege, which is not a free-to-play game, recently revealed the second season of Year 9, dubbed Operation New Blood, and with it Ubisoft also introduced the R6 Membership.</p><p>Here’s the official blurb from Ubisoft:</p><blockquote>Active Membership holders will enjoy monthly drops of exclusive content that includes time-limited gear, animated Legendary skins, 10x Battle level skips, a Bravo Pack and access to the Premium Battle Pass for $9.99/month or a discounted $79.99/year.</blockquote><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/05/28/screenshot-2024-05-28-124720-1716896851309.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: Ubisoft.</figcaption></figure></output><p>It’s safe to say this membership has not gone down well with core Siege fans, many of whom are pointing out that the game costs money to buy and already has various microtransactions as well as a battle pass. As revealed by a TikTok clip posted by Royza Gaming, below, the announcement of the R6 Membership specifically was booed by fans during the BLAST R6 Major Manchester 2024 event for Rainbow Six Siege that took place over the weekend.</p><blockquote cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@royzagaming/video/7373343581811133704" data-video-id="7373343581811133704"> <section> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@royzagaming?refer=embed" target="_blank" title="@royzagaming" rel="noopener noreferrer">@royzagaming</a> New siege membership <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/r6?refer=embed" title="r6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#r6</a> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/r6siege?refer=embed" title="r6siege" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#r6siege</a> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/r6update?refer=embed" title="r6update" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#r6update</a> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/royzagaming?refer=embed" title="royzagaming" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#royzagaming</a> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-7373343772052048657?refer=embed" target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - Royza" rel="noopener noreferrer">♬ original sound - Royza</a> </section> </blockquote> <p>Another <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Rainbow6/comments/1d151ny/live_reaction_to_r6_membership/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">clip</a> posted by redditor I-Am-Bodge also showed the booing at the R6 Membership announcement. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/R6ProLeague/comments/1d24h0d/comment/l603gm8/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">According to  I-Am-Bodge</a>, when a prerecorded video announced the R6 Membership, some in the audience chanted “greedy bastards.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Siege isn’t the first live service to offer a premium membership, but it compares poorly to those from other games in terms of value. The R6 Membership is even being compared unfavorably to the Fortnite Crew subscription, which is for a free-to-download game. "Although yeah you can simply ignore it (and I'm aware this system isn't tailored for people like me for example), that doesn't take away to how shitty is both the intention of making a subscription at the life-point of this game and overall how bad of a deal it is," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Rainbow6/comments/1d14f55/comment/l5rkrhn/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">redditor Jesus_PK commented.</a></p><p>There are now <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Rainbow6/comments/1d1ky4a/lets_boycott_membership_system/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">calls to boycott the R6 Membership</a>, although such calls have been met with scepticism by many within the community. As Rainbow Six Siege nears its 10th year on sale, Ubisoft is under pressure to continue to grow money made from the game, just as other publishers are with their own live services. But it will also be mindful of community sentiment, and the strength of feeling from some core players about how the game is monetized now and in the future.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PlayStation Plus Monthly Games; bonus Game Catalog, PS VR2, and PS2 Classics Catalog titles for June 2024 announced]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/playstation-plus-monthly-games-bonus-game-catalog-ps-vr2-and-ps2-classics-catalog-titles-for-june-2024-announced</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/playstation-plus-monthly-games-bonus-game-catalog-ps-vr2-and-ps2-classics-catalog-titles-for-june-2024-announced.882741/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/playstation-plus-monthly-games-bonus-game-catalog-ps-vr2-and-ps2-classics-catalog-titles-for-june-2024-announced<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vr2">PS VR2</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Days of Play 2024 promotion announced.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,839 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a> has <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/05/28/get-ready-days-of-play-celebration-kicks-off-on-may-29/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a> its Days of Play 2024 promotion, which includes details on the full June 2024 Monthly Games lineup for <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [45,103 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Plus Essential members, as well bonus Game Catalog titles for Extra and Premium members, and <a title="Platforms > PS VR2 [182 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vr2">PlayStation VR2</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS2 [37 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps2">PlayStation 2</a> Classics Catalog titles for Premium members. <span id="more-885427"></span></p><p>Get the details below.</p><blockquote><h2><span>Monthly Games</span></h2><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/PlayStation-Days-of-Play_05-28-24_001.jpg"></a></figure><p>Available from June 4 for all PlayStation Plus members.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><em><a title="Games > AEW: Fight Forever [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/aew-fight-forever">AEW: Fight Forever</a></em> (PS5, PS4)</li><li><em><a title="Games > SpongeBob SquarePants: The Cosmic Shake [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/spongebob-squarepants-the-cosmic-shake">SpongeBob SquarePants: The Cosmic Shake</a></em> (PS5, PS4)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Streets of Rage 4 [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/streets-of-rage-4">Streets of Rage 4</a></em> (PS4)</li></ul><h2><span>PlayStation VR2 Games</span></h2><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/PlayStation-Days-of-Play_05-28-24_002.jpg"></a></figure><p>Available from June 6 for PlayStation Plus Premium members.</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > Before Your Eyes" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/before-your-eyes">Before Your Eyes</a></em> (<a title="Platforms > PS VR [20 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps-vr">PS VR</a>2)</li><li><em><a title="Games > Ghostbusters: Rise of the Ghost Lord [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ghostbusters-rise-of-the-ghost-lord">Ghostbusters: Rise of the Ghost Lord</a></em> (PS VR2)</li><li><em>Synth Riders</em> (PS VR2)</li><li><em><a title="Companies > Walkabout [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/walkabout">Walkabout</a> Mini Golf</em> (PS VR2)</li><li><em><a title="Games > The Walking Dead: Saints &amp; Sinners [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-walking-dead-saints-sinners">The Walking Dead: Saints &amp; Sinners</a></em> (PS VR2)</li><li><em><a title="Games > The Walking Dead: Saints &amp; Sinners - Chapter 2: Retribution [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/the-walking-dead-saints-sinners-chapter-2-retribution">The Walking Dead: Saints &amp; Sinners – Chapter 2: Retribution</a></em> (PS VR2)</li></ul><h2><span>PlayStation 2 Classics Catalog</span></h2><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/PlayStation-Days-of-Play_05-28-24_003.jpg"></a></figure><p>Available from June 11 for Premium members.</p><ul><li><em>Star Wars: The Clone Wars</em></li><li><em>Sly Cooper and the Thievius Raccoonus</em></li><li><em>Tomb Raider Legend</em></li></ul><h2><span>Game Catalog</span></h2><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/PlayStation-Days-of-Play_05-28-24_004.jpg"></a></figure><p>Available in Game Catalog on the specified dates for Extra and Premium members.</p><ul><li><em>Dredge</em> (PS5, PS4) – May 29</li><li><em>LEGO Marvel Super Heroes 2</em> (PS4) – May 31</li><li><em>Cricket 24</em> (PS5, PS4) -June 5</li><li><em>Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas – The Definitive Edition</em> (PS5, PS4) – June 7</li></ul><p>The full Game Catalog lineup will be announced later in June.</p><h2><span>Game Trials</span></h2><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/PlayStation-Days-of-Play_05-28-24_005.jpg"></a></figure><p>Available on May 29 for Premium members.</p><ul><li><em><a title="Games > WWE 2K24 [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/wwe-2k24">WWE 2K24</a></em> (PS5, PS4)</li></ul><h2><span>Other Content</span></h2><p><strong>PlayStation Plus Avatars</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/PlayStation-Days-of-Play_05-28-24_006.jpg"></a></figure><p>Starting May 29, all players can access avatars that commemorate some of the popular titles that will be offered through PlayStation Plus during Days of Play. Users can claim them on the <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/ps-plus/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Plus website</a> or via the Days of Play page on the <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,088 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> or <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,728 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> console.</p><p><strong><em><a title="Games > EA Sports FC 24 [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/ea-sports-fc-24">EA Sports FC 24</a></em></strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/PlayStation-Days-of-Play_05-28-24_007.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>EA Sports FC 24</em> will be available to claim as part of the May lineup of Monthly Games until June 18.</p><p><strong>Exclusive <em><a title="Games > Roblox [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/roblox">Roblox</a></em> Pack</strong></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/PlayStation-Days-of-Play_05-28-24_008.jpg"></a></figure><p>Starting June 3, all PlayStation Plus members will be able to download a <em>Roblox</em> Pack that includes an avatar for Felix Freezebeard the Yeti.</p></blockquote><p>For more on Days of Play, including discounts on PlayStation 5 consoles and select titles available from May 29 to June 12 as part of the promotion, visit <a href="https://blog.playstation.com/2024/05/28/get-ready-days-of-play-celebration-kicks-off-on-may-29/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PlayStation Blog</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Reveal Trailer: Get A First Look At 2024's Call Of Duty Game At 10 AM ET]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-reveal-trailer-get-a-first-look-at-2024s-call-of-duty-game-at-10-am-et/1100-6523744/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-reveal-trailer-get-a-first-look-at-2024s-call-of-duty-game-at-10-am-et.882738/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-reveal-trailer-get-a-first-look-at-2024s-call-of-duty-game-at-10-am-et/1100-6523744/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523744">

            
            
  


    


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container" data-in-content-placements="[{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-incontent-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:1,&quot;minElements&quot;:2},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:4,&quot;minElements&quot;:5}]},{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-banner-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:7,&quot;minElements&quot;:8},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:10,&quot;minElements&quot;:11},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:13,&quot;minElements&quot;:14}]}]">
                <p>The first trailer for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/" data-ref-id="1100-6523361">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> is coming today, May 28, at 7 AM PT / 10 AM ET. The trailer will be a live-action video that provides the first look at the new Call of Duty game. Whether or not this trailer contains any gameplay footage, however, remains to be seen.</p><p>The thumbnail shows a person that many on the internet believe to be Saddam Hussein, and many are taking this to be proof that the game is indeed set, at least partially, during the Gulf War or more generally during conflicts in the Middle East. The trailer's thumbnail also contains coordinates that point to the <a href="https://x.com/charlieINTEL/status/1794886368696701395" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">location of Hussein's palace.</a></p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V08UPqchVgQ" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/V08UPqchVgQ" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Hussein, the former president of Iraq who was sentenced to death by hanging, wouldn't be the first real-life political leader to appear in a Call of Duty Black Ops game. Manuel Noriega, the former dictator of Panama, was featured in Black Ops II. Noriega <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/activision-scores-call-of-duty-legal-victory-as-no/1100-6423233/" data-ref-id="1100-6423233">unsuccessfully sued Activision</a> over his appearance in the game.</p><p>Black Ops 6 is in the works at Raven Software and Treyarch and is reported to release in October, and it sounds like it'll <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-leak-reveals-its-coming-to-game-pass-day-one/1100-6523742/" data-ref-id="1100-6523742">launch day one on Game Pass</a>. Activision and Microsoft will <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-announced-described-as-dark-new-chapter/1100-6523660/" data-ref-id="1100-6523660">further showcase Black Ops 6 on June 9 as part of a special broadcast dedicated entirely to the next entry in the FPS series. </a></p><p>For more, check out GameSpot's rundown of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/" data-ref-id="1100-6523361">everything we know about the next Call of Duty. </a>Black Ops 6 will join Call of Duty: Warzone, Call of Duty: Warzone Mobile, and Call of Duty: Mobile on the market at the same time.</p>
  
                        
        
    
    
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bleach: Brave Souls coming to Xbox One, Switch this summer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/bleach-brave-souls-coming-to-xbox-one-switch-this-summer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bleach-brave-souls-coming-to-xbox-one-switch-this-summer.882729/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/bleach-brave-souls-coming-to-xbox-one-switch-this-summer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Currently available for PlayStation 4, PC, iOS, and Android.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > KLabGames [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/klabgames">KLabGames</a> will release fere-to-play 3D <a title="Genres > Action [1,857 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action game</a> <em><a title="Games > Bleach: Brave Souls [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bleach-brave-souls">Bleach: Brave Souls</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,177 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> and <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,366 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> this summer, the developer <a href="https://www.klab.com/en/press/release/2024/0528/bleach_brave_souls_switch_xbox_release.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-885421"></span></p><p><em>Bleach: Brave Souls</em> first launched in 2015 and has since achieved over 90 million downloads worldwide. It is currently available for PlayStation 4, <a title="Platforms > PC [20,165 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a>, iOS, and Android with support for English, Japanese, French, and Traditional Chinese language options.</p><p>KLabGames is working on expanding its game development onto multiple platforms and devices based on a multi-purpose content strategy, in order to ensure a greater number of players worldwide have a chance to play its games.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Leak Reveals It's Coming To Game Pass Day One]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-leak-reveals-its-coming-to-game-pass-day-one/1100-6523742/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-leak-reveals-its-coming-to-game-pass-day-one.882723/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-leak-reveals-its-coming-to-game-pass-day-one/1100-6523742/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523742">

            
            
  


    


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container" data-in-content-placements="[{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-incontent-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:1,&quot;minElements&quot;:2},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:4,&quot;minElements&quot;:5}]},{&quot;adType&quot;:&quot;mobile-banner-plus&quot;,&quot;placements&quot;:[{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:7,&quot;minElements&quot;:8},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:10,&quot;minElements&quot;:11},{&quot;placeIndex&quot;:13,&quot;minElements&quot;:14}]}]">
                <p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/" data-ref-id="1100-6523361">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> will launch day one on Game Pass, according to a new leak. The Game Pass app is reportedly sending out push notifications to some users to alert them that Black Ops 6 "is coming to Game Pass on day one later this year!"</p><p>Reporter Tom Warren <a href="https://x.com/tomwarren/status/1795387942837612562" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">discovered</a> that the push notification sends users to an <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/05/28/play-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-day-one-game-pass/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Xbox blog post</a> with the URL "play-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-day-one-game-pass." The blog post is reportedly going up at 7 AM PT / 10 AM ET, which is the same time that the Black Ops 6 reveal trailer goes out.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/tomwarren/status/1795385251306324292" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">the Xbox Game Pass app on iOS / Android is notifying people that Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 "is coming to Game Pass on day one later this year!" <br>it looks like an announcement is due today 👀 <a href="https://t.co/FBRteX5Nkl" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/FBRteX5Nkl</a></p>  — Tom Warren (@tomwarren) <a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1795385251306324292?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 28, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Black Ops 6 is in development at Treyarch and Raven Software (with assistance from Activision's network of other global studios) and is reportedly launching this October. It is said to be the first Call of Duty game ever made on a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/" data-ref-id="1100-6523361">four-year development cycle</a>, and expectations are high.</p><p>All of Microsoft's first-party games launch into Game Pass, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-on-game-pass-is-not-guaranteed-microsoft-having-internal-debates-about-it-report/1100-6523291/" data-ref-id="1100-6523291">many were wondering if this would also be true for Call of Duty titles now that Microsoft owns the series</a>. From the looks of it, that will be the case, though it remains to be seen if the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/cod-on-game-pass-is-not-guaranteed-microsoft-having-internal-debates-about-it-report/1100-6523291/" data-ref-id="1100-6523291">reported Game Pass price hike is coming</a>.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kEjmwoVrF0g" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kEjmwoVrF0g" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Keep checking back with GameSpot for more on Black Ops 6. For now, you can take a look at GameSpot's rundown of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-duty-2024-release-date-trailer-news/1100-6523361/" data-ref-id="1100-6523361">everything we know about Black Ops 6.</a></p>
  
                        
        
    
    
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Larian did "a bit of crunch" on Baldur's Gate 3 due to unforeseen challenges]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/larian-did-a-bit-of-crunch-on-baldurs-gate-3-due-to-unforeseen-challenges</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/larian-did-a-bit-of-crunch-on-baldurs-gate-3-due-to-unforeseen-challenges.882720/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/larian-did-a-bit-of-crunch-on-baldurs-gate-3-due-to-unforeseen-challenges<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Director Swen Vincke emphasised the team "didn't overly crunch," and staff were paid overtime</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Baldur's Gate 3 director Swen Vincke touched upon crunch at Digital Dragons last week, saying that while Larian's team didn't "overly crunch" during development, you "always have a little bit" of overtime when trying to finish a project of that scope.</p>
<p>Vincke made these comments during a Q&amp;A at the Polish conference, as reported by <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/rpg/baldurs-gate-3-had-less-crunch-than-larians-previous-rpgs-but-its-director-says-you-will-always-have-a-little-bit-of-overtime/">GamesRadar</a>. Answering a question about whether challenges encountered during Baldur's Gate 3's development resulted in crunch, Larian's CEO said:</p>
<p>"Certainly less on BG3 than we did in the past. It would be a lie to say that we didn't. We had things happen that we didn't foresee."</p>
<p>He mentioned Larian's structure, with its global offices relaying with each other when working on a project, often avoiding overtime falling on any one office.</p>
<p>But when overtime did occur, staff was paid for it (which isn't necessarily a standard in games), with offices mostly empty by 8pm and occupied "very, very, very rarely" on weekends. He added that the overtime wasn't "as long as you would consider crunch."</p>
<p>He said: "We didn't overly crunch, but we did have to do a bit of crunch. And I think, to be honest, you will always have a little bit when you're trying to finish something, especially when there's so much complexity that needs to be brought together."</p>
<p>Larian announced the <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/larian-to-expand-with-warsaw-office">opening of its seventh office in Warsaw, Poland just last week</a>.</p>
<p>We <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/larian-after-baldurs-gate-3-we-have-ambitions-to-make-really-good-rpgs-and-thats-sufficient">talked to Vincke earlier this year about life post-Baldur's Gate 3</a>, why the team is moving on, and solving the industry's unsustainable growth.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tango Gameworks was Developing 2 Unannounced Games Before Closure]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/tango-gameworks-2-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tango-gameworks-was-developing-2-unannounced-games-before-closure.882714/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/tango-gameworks-2-games/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>A developer at Tango Gameworks has revealed that the studio was working on at least 2 unannounced titles before the studio’s closure.</p>



<p>The information comes courtesy of Tsuyoshi Okugawa’s LinkedIn page, which was first spotted by Twitter user <a href="https://x.com/bogorad222/status/1795393325023060194?s=46&amp;t=w9td4FZz74Qwy4DLK4vbiA">@bogorad222</a>. According to his LinkedIn page, he was working on two unannounced titles.</p>



<p>“Unannounced Title Graphics Programmer 2024” and “Unannounced Title Lead Programmer 2023-2024”, his LinkedIn profile reads.</p>



<p>One of these titles is almost certainly the Ghostwire: Tokyo sequel that was leaked during the Microsoft x Activision FTC hearing, which leaked that the game would be released during FY24. As for the second game, it’s highly speculated that it would be a sequel to Hi-Fi Rush. </p>



<p>Unfortunately, Microsoft announced Tango Gameworks would be closing as a part of a restructuring that would see four studios close. The other three studios were Arkane Austin, Alpha Dog Studios, and Roundhouse Games.</p>



<p>“These changes are not a reflection of the creativity and skill of the talented individuals at these teams or the risks they took to try new things,” Booty said in the email. “I acknowledge that these changes are also disruptive to the various support teams across ZeniMax and Bethesda that bring our games to market. We are making these tough decisions to create capacity to increase investment in other parts of our portfolio and focus on our priority games,” it was said in an internal email to staff.</p>



<p>Would you have liked to see Ghostwire: Tokyo and Hi-Fi Rush sequels? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-game-pass-day-one/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6 will be announced for Xbox Game Pass Day One later today</a>, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">sign up for the Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Citizen Pushes Through the $700 Million Raised Mark and No, There Still Isn’t a Release Date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/star-citizen-pushes-through-the-700-million-raised-mark-and-no-there-still-isnt-a-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-citizen-pushes-through-the-700-million-raised-mark-and-no-there-still-isn%E2%80%99t-a-release-date.882708/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/star-citizen-pushes-through-the-700-million-raised-mark-and-no-there-still-isnt-a-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Star Citizen has now raised over $700 million according to figures from developer Cloud Imperium Games.</p><p>The developer behind the controversial space sim makes revenue publicly available on its <a href="https://robertsspaceindustries.com/funding-goals" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">website</a>, which at the time of this article’s publication shows Star Citizen has raised $701,186,615. CIG calls this money “funds raised.”</p><p>CIG even breaks down the revenue by recent months, weeks, and hours. At its lowest point on the morning of May 28, Star Citizen brought in $42,886 in one hour, about $1.5 million yesterday, May 27, $10,883,513 last week, and $4,753,264 for the month of April (things appear to have picked up considerably in May after the launch of the <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-citizen-alpha-323-patch-is-largest-to-date-adds-first-native-animals">Alpha 3.23: Adventure Beckons update</a>).</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Star Citizen - Alpha 3.23: Adventure Beckons Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Star Citizen is considered one of the most controversial projects in all video games. Over the 12 years since its crowdfunding drive began, it's been called many things including a scam by those who wonder whether it will ever properly launch. Its virtual space ships, some of which cost hundreds of dollars, are often the focus of criticism.</p><p>Alpha 3.23 launched two months after <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-citizen-10-twinkles-on-the-horizon-dev-says-12-years-and-669-million-later"><u>CIG began talking about Star Citizen’s 1.0 launch being within sight</u></a>, over a decade after the game released its first crowdfunding drive. CIG chief Chris Roberts has said 2024 will see the launch of Star Citizen Alpha 4.0, and that the developer is working to bring features developed for <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/squadron-42"><u>Squadron 42</u></a>, the standalone story-based game starring the likes of Mark Hamill and Gillian Anderson, to the persistent universe portion of the game “at an accelerated rate”.</p><p>This is all building up to Star Citizen 1.0, which, Roberts has said, “is what we consider the features and content set to represent ‘commercial’ release.” However, there is still no release date or even release window for Star Citizen 1.0. CIG will share the roadmap later this year, it has said.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Leak claims 2K Sports working on new FIFA game, releasing this year]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/leak-claims-2k-sports-working-on-new-fifa-game-releasing-this-year/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=leak-claims-2k-sports-working-on-new-fifa-game-releasing-this-year</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/leak-claims-2k-sports-working-on-new-fifa-game-releasing-this-year.882702/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/leak-claims-2k-sports-working-on-new-fifa-game-releasing-this-year/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=leak-claims-2k-sports-working-on-new-fifa-game-releasing-this-year<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="216" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">It’s been a long time since we had a true competitor to EA Sports in the soccer simulator world, but according to new rumors, 2K Sports is working on a new <em>FIFA </em>game that will supposedly be released this year. </p> <p data-characters="448" data-current-count="448" data-injectable="true">In a post by MohPlay Inc. on <a href="https://x.com/mohplay_inc_/status/1793985090231451777" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">X</a>, formerly Twitter, they claimed that 2K Sports had reached a partnership with football’s governing body FIFA to develop a new series to rival <em>EA Sports FC</em>. The tweet claims that <em>FIFA 2K25</em> is set to launch this year, just in time for the 2026 FIFA World Cup. This development timeline seems very quick, unless 2K were already working on a soccer game and landed the licensing after development had already begun.</p>
 <p data-characters="285" data-current-count="285" data-injectable="false">This story was then corroborated by Insider Gaming’s Mike Straw, who suggested there was “more smoke to this,” and that nobody was willing to talk to him about it on the record, before suggesting that an announcement was coming “sooner rather than later.”</p> <figure data-current-count="585" data-injectable="true"><div> <blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">More smoke to this. No one is willing to talk to me on the record about it, but we could be getting an announcement of a new partnership sooner rather than later <a href="https://t.co/cy6gqGGftl">https://t.co/cy6gqGGftl</a></p>— Mike Straw of Insider-Gaming.com (@MikeStrawMedia) <a href="https://twitter.com/MikeStrawMedia/status/1794529425247109424?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 26, 2024</a></blockquote> </div></figure>
 <p data-characters="421" data-current-count="421" data-injectable="true">This matches up with rumors from earlier in the year that suggested 2K and FIFA were in discussions, following the split between EA Sports and FIFA in 2023. The pair, who had worked together since the release of <em>FIFA International Soccer</em> in 1993, could not come to terms on a licensing agreement for the <em>FIFA </em>name, with EA Sports eventually deciding to move on without the branding and releasing <em>EA Sports FC 24</em> in 2023. </p>
 <p data-characters="237" data-current-count="237" data-injectable="false">This would mark the first major competitor to EA Sports in a while, as while Konami’s <em>Pro Evolution Soccer</em> was a true rival to <em>FIFA</em> in the mid-2000s, its <em>eFootball</em> successor has failed to make a dent in the footballing juggernaut. </p> <p data-characters="319" data-current-count="556" data-injectable="false">As we’ve seen in the past, competition is good for everyone, as it forces developers to up their games to keep ahead of their competition. Of course, take this all with a pinch of salt until we get confirmation from FIFA or 2K Sports, but as a fan of the game, I’d love to see someone take it to EA Sports. </p>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genshin Impact developer's upcoming urban action RPG lands summer release date]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/genshin-impact-developers-upcoming-urban-action-rpg-lands-summer-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/genshin-impact-developers-upcoming-urban-action-rpg-lands-summer-release-date.882690/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/genshin-impact-developers-upcoming-urban-action-rpg-lands-summer-release-date<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Zenless Zone Zero arrives in July.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Zenless-Zone-Zero-header.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>HoYoverse</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/how-to-pre-register-zenless-zone-zero-9435">Zenless Zone Zero</a> has secured itself a release date.</p>
<p>The upcoming free-to-play RPG from the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/genshin-impact-tier-list-best-characters-main-dps-healer-support-9026">Genshin Impact</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/honkai-star-rail-tier-list-best-characters-dps-damage-support-healer-9321">Honkai: Star Rail</a> team is set to release across Android, iOS, PC and PS5 on 4th July. This date was previously suspected, when <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/pre-registrations-for-genshin-impact-honkai-star-rail-developers-next-game-open">Apple's App Store on mobile said the game was "expected" on 4th July</a> here in the UK.</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Zenless Zone Zero - State of Play Announcement Video | PS5 Games<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G4I61egYGdg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"Dear Proxy, Thank you for your ongoing interest in and support of Zenless Zone Zero," the team shared on <a href="https://x.com/ZZZ_EN/status/1795304091759047142">social media platform X</a> earlier today. "We look forward to meeting you on Sixth Street when entry to New Eridu is granted."</p>
<p>As a general point, while Zenless Zone Zero's official release date is 4th July, those across the pond in the US will get it on 3rd July due to time zones. You can check out our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zenless-zone-zero-release-date-times-9435">Zenless Zone Zero timings guide here</a> for more information.</p>
<p>In the meantime, you are currently able to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/how-to-pre-register-zenless-zone-zero-9435">pre-register for Zenless Zone Zero</a>, which will allow you to get your hands on some <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zenless-zone-zero-pre-registration-rewards-9435">rewards</a> in the process.</p> <div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>After an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/genshin-impact-developer-teases-next-project-zenless-zone-zero">initial tease</a>, HoYoverse - which manages all of miHoYo's global operations outside of China - revealed Zenless Zone Zero is an action role-playing game and described it as an urban fantasy title and an "attempt to further explore action-oriented gameplay".</p>
<p>Our Jessica took part in a closed beta for Zenless Zone Zero towards the end of last year, stating the game would be "brilliant if it didn't keep wasting your time".</p>
<p>"There's something missing from Zenless Zone Zero. Armed with a deep combat system, new urban setting, and roster of characters easy to love, it seemed like developer miHoYo was teed up for another win after recent successes Genshin Impact and Honkai: Star Rail... and yet after playing its second beta, I'm left more confused than anything else," she wrote in our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zenless-zone-zero-would-be-brilliant-if-it-didnt-keep-wasting-your-time">Zenless Zone Zero preview feature</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anthology of the Killer is out now, bringing murder to your doorstep]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/anthology-of-the-killer-is-out-now-bringing-murder-to-your-doorstep</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/anthology-of-the-killer-is-out-now-bringing-murder-to-your-doorstep.882687/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/anthology-of-the-killer-is-out-now-bringing-murder-to-your-doorstep<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/anthology-of-the-killer-thecatamites-2.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Stephen "thecatamites" Gillmurphy</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>A whopping 1000 corpses have been found in our ongoing investigation into <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/anthology-of-the-killer">Anthology of the Killer</a>, Rock Paper Shotgun can reveal. The bodies were discovered in the aforementioned murder mystery "video game", which <a href="https://thecatamites.itch.io/anthology-of-the-killer">is out now on itch.io</a>. Following our previous reports we can confirm that exposure to the game's crime-infested city can cause severe disorientation, confusion, uncontrolled fits of laughter, and moderate enlightenment. The streets here are so dense with crime that entire apartment blocks must shutter at night. When Rock Paper Shotgun reported the 1000 corpses to detectives, we were told this was "normal" and "appropriate".</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Anthology of the Killer was last sighted at the IGF Awards, where it <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/eH67as6A7Og?feature=shared&amp;t=4478">won the Nuovo Award</a>, traditionally given to experimental games that "push the boundaries". Those dangerous boundaries continue to be pushed by the game's principal creator, Stephen "thecatamites" Gillmurphy. The enigmatic perpetrator of these, yes, entirely fictional murders, has now released his felonious software upon the public at large, demanding a reprehensible $6 for the death-fuelled interactive entertainment. That is the price of one entire pain au chocolat from Caffè Nero! Or perhaps half au chocolat, please check our latest economics editorial for clarity on this matter.</p>
<p>It is believed that Anthology of the Killer follows the daily life of one "BB", an employee of a life insurance firm who prints zines on the side using company resources. This innocent and hardworking young woman is soon thrown into a twisting nightmare of crime, living out nine episodes of terror including Voice of the Killer, Eyes of the Killer, Blood of the Killer, Heart of the Killer, Drool of the Killer, and many Others of the Killer. A soundtrack composed by similarly shadowy entity Tommy Tone is also present, causing fear and/or amusement in unequal measure to those with ears. Ears of the Killer is also included.</p>
<p>Please see <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-worry-im-a-murderer-award-winning-comedy-anthology-of-the-killer-is-out-next-week">our previous reports on this matter</a> for more information. Stay safe.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD FSR 3 Frame Generation Boosts Immortals of Aveum Performance by 72% on Xbox Series X, Delivering a Responsive Experience]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr-3-frame-generation-immortals-of-aveum-performance-boost-72-xbox/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/amd-fsr-3-frame-generation-boosts-immortals-of-aveum-performance-by-72-on-xbox-series-x-delivering-a-responsive-experience.882684/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr-3-frame-generation-immortals-of-aveum-performance-boost-72-xbox/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>AMD FSR 3 Frame Generation could be a game changer even in the console space, as its first implementation delivers an impressive performance boost and a responsive experience.</p>
<p>The tech experts at Digital Foundry took a look at how AMD's frame generation technology works in <a href="https://wccftech.com/amd-fsr-3-lands-on-consoles-with-immortals-of-aveum-update-pc-implementation-also-improved/">Immortals of Aveum</a> on Xbox Series X, highlighting how the tech generally boosts performance by 72%. In areas where the game runs in the 40, 60 FPS range, AMD FSR3 Frame Generation essentially delivers a high refresh rate experience. Additionally, the experience felt very responsive, close to a 60 frames per second or more experience, convincingly producing an image that looks like a proper 120 FPS game or close to it. The fact that AMD's Frame Generation is capable of boosting performance so well in a Unreal Engine 5 game makes its first implementation on consoles even more impressive.</p>
<p>However, AMD FSR 3 Frame Generation on consoles still requires some work. In Immortals of Aveum, for example, it still uses FSR 2 upscaling, which doesn't really look good in the game. Additionally, it introduces some small visual artifacts, and it doesn't apply to interface elements. It also brings some issues in cutscenes, causing some second-long pauses that are very noticeable, but thankfully, this issue is not present during gameplay, although some camera motions don't look as smooth as they should be at over 60 frames per second. Still, AMD FSR 3 Frame Generation bodes extremely well for the future, even in its current state, as it makes more visually advanced games a little bit more viable at high frame rates.</p>
<p><iframe title="DF Direct Weekly #164: FSR3 Console Frame-Gen Tested! Hellblade 2 Reaction, IGN Buys Gamer Network" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7rYGOCfgabs?start=106&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>More information on AMD FSR 3 Frame Generation, which works on any relatively recent GPU from any vendor on PC, on its <a href="https://www.amd.com/en/products/graphics/technologies/fidelityfx/super-resolution.html">official website.</a></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Game Pass app has confirmed Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 for day one]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/28/the-game-pass-app-has-confirmed-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-for-day-one/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-game-pass-app-has-confirmed-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-for-day-one.882675/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/28/the-game-pass-app-has-confirmed-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-for-day-one/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It seems someone over at Microsoft has a pressed a button rather earlier than they should have as the Game Pass app has just announced that Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 will be coming to the service on day one of launch.<br>
</p>
<p>This is the latest leak in regards to Call of Duty and game Pass,&nbsp; Jez Corden confirmed the news <a href="https://x.com/JezCorden/status/1795324954084528632?t=CJxBNvGUwOfKfkFLvmCGIw&amp;s=19">over of Twitter&nbsp;</a> and last week The Wall Street Journal also&nbsp; reported that Microsoft had made up their mind and would bring the next Call of Duty game straight into Game Pass when it launches later this year.</p>


<p>This year’s COD has been confirmed to be Call of Duty: Black Ops 6, as Activision follow up on a teaser site and leaked newspaper advertising with a formal announcement. The game will debut during the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/04/30/xbox-games-showcase-and-a-redacted-direct-confirmed-for-june-9th/">Xbox Showcase on 9th June</a> with a Black Ops 6 Direct to follow immediately afterwards.</p>
<p><iframe title="wake up (rushmore) #thetruthlies" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RxIHyfwUrTg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The advertising came with copies of USA Today in a promotional supplement that show’s the game’s logo, title and some in-universe news stories. In particular there’s the defacing of Mount Rushmore, which also appeared on <a href="https://thetruthlies.com/6/">the Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 teaser website</a> yesterday.</p>

<p>That teaser site features an analogue TV which you can scroll through six channels, some of which give static, but the first of which shows Mount Rushmore’s defacement, and the sixth of which tunes in to News 6, with faux reporting of monuments around the world also being defaced.</p>
<p>The hope is that this will be a major boost to Xbox Game Pass subscriber counts, across both Xbox and PC, and since COD will not be a platform exclusive for a long, long time, should preserve a lot of the overall profitability of the franchise with the majority of gamers still happy to buy the games outright on PlayStation in particular. A large portion of the money that Call of Duty makes also comes from the free-to-play Warzone game mode.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/GamingLeaksAndRumours/comments/1d2cl6a/game_pass_app_notifications_says_call_of_duty/">Reddit</a> / <a href="https://x.com/JezCorden/status/1795324954084528632?t=CJxBNvGUwOfKfkFLvmCGIw&amp;s=19">Twitter</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Yakuza was "flat out rejected" by Sega in its first proposal, says series creator]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/yakuza-was-flat-out-rejected-by-sega-in-its-first-proposal-says-series-creator</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/yakuza-was-flat-out-rejected-by-sega-in-its-first-proposal-says-series-creator.882672/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/yakuza-was-flat-out-rejected-by-sega-in-its-first-proposal-says-series-creator<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Now one of its top sellers.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-dondoko-island-reveal.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sega</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Sega initially "flat out rejected" the first proposal for Yakuza, as it wouldn't attract the masses.
</p>
<p>
That's according to series creator Toshihiro Nagoshi on the latest <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nxz5fP2iaeY">News Picks video</a>, in which he discusses the origins of the series (thanks <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/news/like-a-dragon-creator-talks-about-sega-flat-out-rejecting-the-first-yakuza-game-thinking-it-wouldnt-sell/">Automaton</a>).

</p>
<p>
The Like A Dragon series (Yakuza in the West) debuted in 2015, but initially wasn't seen as a profitable idea.
</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Like A Dragon: Infinite Wealth opening movie<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J5_RjgvQQBo" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>

At this time in the industry, Japanese games no longer dominated sales. "This led to a mindset of making games that would appeal to the masses, games that could sell anywhere and to anyone. Many producers, including myself, thought this way," said Nagoshi.  
</p>
<p>
"But this mindset wasn't really leading to a solution, and I saw many game proposals gradually become watered down as producers bent over to change things the way management instructed them to."
</p>
<p>
However, when Nagoshi pitched the concept of Like a Dragon to Sega, "it was flat out rejected," he said. "After all, it was completely contrary to what I mentioned earlier about attracting the masses. Children wouldn't be able to play it, and it wasn't catered to women nor overseas audiences. In this sense, there was no way for it to be approved without resistance."
</p>
<p>
Nagoshi believed the game's strong identity would make it a commercial success, though admitted the route to approval was "quite forceful".
</p>
<p>
He also did not want the game to affirm violence, despite its Yakuza subject. "I wanted it to be a game that makes you want to do your best to live another day," he said. "I remember reminding people of this frequently."
</p>
<p>
It's perhaps surprising Sega was initially reluctant to green light the game, considering it's now one of its top franchises alongside Sonic and the Persona series. Nagoshi was clearly right that its strong Japanese identity would result in global appeal.
</p>
<p>
The latest in the series, Infinite Wealth, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-hits-1m-sales-in-first-week">sold 1m units in its first week</a> and was the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-is-series-biggest-steam-launch-to-date">series' biggest Steam launch ever</a>.


</p>
<p>
As a whole, the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sega-sammy-reports-best-financial-performance-for-a-decade-despite-european-studio-disappointment">series has sold 21.3m units</a> (as per November 2023).
</p>
<p>"Violent stakes once again meet zany shenanigans in Like A Dragon: Infinite Wealth, the series' much-improved second RPG," reads our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/like-a-dragon-infinite-wealth-review">Like A Dragon: Infinite Wealth Eurogamer review</a>.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft announce Call Of Duty: Black Ops 6 Game Pass launch alongside teaser trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-announce-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-game-pass-launch-alongside-teaser-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-announce-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-game-pass-launch-alongside-teaser-trailer.882669/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-announce-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-game-pass-launch-alongside-teaser-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Truth = lies, lies = truth</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/blackops6_qLgCnfG.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Microsoft</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/call-of-duty-2024">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</a> will be the first Call Of Duty to launch on Microsoft Game Pass, according to a notification that went out this morning via the Xbox Game Pass app for iPhone and Android. "Just announced: Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 is coming to Game Pass on day one later this year!" it reads. Sounds like a solid confirmation from me, though Microsoft and Activision have yet to start bellowing the news from any of Call of Duty’s official pulpits.</p><!--more-->
<p>As reported by <a href="https://x.com/tomwarren/status/1795385251306324292">Tom Warren</a> of the Verge, the notification links to a currently unpublished blog, which suggests that it has gone out early by accident. Look at me go, joining the dots. The addition of COD to Game Pass has been <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-next-call-of-duty-will-launch-on-game-pass-on-day-one-reports-say">much rumoured</a>, with one former Microsoft senior PR describing it as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/game-passs-only-outside-shot-for-sustainability-is-to-get-gta-6-or-call-of-duty-says-former-microsoft-senior-pr-lead">vital if the subscription service is to ever become "sustainable"</a>.</p>
<p>It all follows the more-deliberate release of a Black Ops 6 teaser trailer, below, which is certainly very Black Operational in being a woozy smear of period newsreel footage, close-ups of eyes, and vocodery voices urging you to discover the truth, although please bear in mind that the truth is a lie. By logical extension, are lies truth? In that case, let me swiftly add that Call Of Duty: Black Ops 6 is actually a double-A immersive sim with an emphasis on dialogue puzzles, set in a pastel-coloured Soulslike dystopia under the friendly regard of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-2024-revealed-as-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-a-dark-new-chapter">a Capitol-wearing giga-wolf</a>. </p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="open your eyes #thetruthlies" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kEjmwoVrF0g?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>open your eyes #thetruthlies</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kEjmwoVrF0g?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kEjmwoVrF0g?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kEjmwoVrF0g" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>The trailer seemingly confirms that this year’s codpiece is indeed strapped to the groin of the first Gulf War, as per <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-next-call-of-duty-is-a-black-ops-game-set-during-the-first-gulf-war-according-to-reports">a report last November</a>. There are fleeting glimpses of Margaret Thatcher, Saddam Hussein and OG George Bush, together with a shot of Glowering Silhouette Man from the first Black Ops. Doubtless there will be shooting of some kind, though my dream of lopping Thatcher’s head off and using it to petrify people like the Medusa’s head in GOW remains a few kilometres over the horizon of probability.</p>
<p>Still, remember that lies are truths, and as such, that this year’s Call Of Duty is definitely a pen-and-paper journalling game that’s only available in Malta. Roll with it, you apes! Anything’s possible! Look, they’re <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/call-of-duty-is-getting-in-the-gundam-robot">putting Call Of Duty in Gundam now</a>!</p>
<p>There’s a big Black Ops 6 segment coming at Microsoft’s Summer Games Fest showcase on June 9th. Hopefully it'll clear a few things up, or at least give us some nicely remastered period music to hum along to.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon’s Dogma 2 Breaks 3 Million Units Sold Milestone]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dragons-dogma-2-breaks-3-million-units-sold-milestone/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon%E2%80%99s-dogma-2-breaks-3-million-units-sold-milestone.882666/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dragons-dogma-2-breaks-3-million-units-sold-milestone/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>This morning, CAPCOM <a href="https://x.com/DragonsDogma/status/1795387174453395631?" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced </a>through Twitter/X that Dragon's Dogma 2 has now sold over three million units across all platforms. The game had reached the 2.5 million units milestone <a href="https://wccftech.com/dragons-dogma-2-sales/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">in early April</a>.</p>
<p>According to Circana, <a href="https://wccftech.com/dragons-dogma-2-final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-npd-circana-march-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">it outsold every game in North America this past March</a>. Moreover, it has already managed to outsell the combined sales of previous franchise entries. Such great sales performance from Dragon's Dogma 2 (and other titles) <a href="https://wccftech.com/capcom-announces-upward-revision-for-earnings-forecast-following-favorable-dragons-dogma-2-sales/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">allowed CAPCOM to revise upward its earnings forecast</a>:</p>
<p><em>In our core Digital Contents business, in addition to Street Fighter 6, the latest title in the Street Fighter series, being met with broad acclaim globally, Dragons Dogma 2 was released in the fourth quarter and has performed favorably. Further, sales grew for catalog titles consisting primarily of past titles from major series due to their steady popularity. Altogether, this has led us to expect earnings for this business to exceed our plan.</em></p>
<p>Users can now <a href="https://wccftech.com/dragons-dogma-2-mod-adds-path-tracing-and-other-rt-options-including-performance-boost/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">add built-in path tracing to the game on PC</a>. However, the lack of a proper denoiser makes it less than ideal. Here's what I wrote about Dragon's Dogma 2 in my review:</p>
<p><em>The original game was an amazing foundation to build upon, and yet CAPCOM seemed content with keeping the same strengths without improving much on the weaknesses. Twelve years later, though, the effect cannot be the same. Still, make no mistake: Dragon's Dogma 2 is a highly enjoyable fantasy action/adventure with RPG elements that will provide you with about 40 hours of pure fun. Its peerless sense of exploration, meaty combat system, and stunning visuals will motivate you throughout the entire playthrough. Just don't expect to find a fantasy world simulator or, indeed, a narrative worth remembering.</em></p>
<p>Following this sales performance, it is highly likely that CAPCOM will release some DLC for Dragon's Dogma 2, although no plan has been shared as of yet.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Victims and parents of Uvalde school shooting sue Activision]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/victims-and-parents-of-uvalde-school-shooting-sue-activision</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/victims-and-parents-of-uvalde-school-shooting-sue-activision.882663/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/victims-and-parents-of-uvalde-school-shooting-sue-activision<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Lawsuit claims gunman bought gun after using it in Call of Duty: Modern Warfare</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Parents and victims of the 2022 Robb Elementary School shooting in Uvalde, Texas are suing Activision and its parent company Microsoft.</p>
<p>As reported by <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/24/us/uvalde-gun-instagram-activision-lawsuit.html">The New York Times</a>, dual <a href="https://www.politico.com/f/?id=0000018f-acc4-d34e-afcf-bdd6a4660000">lawsuits were filed</a> in California and Texas last Friday, which marked the second anniversary of the shooting where 19 children and two teachers were killed by an 18-year-old gunman.</p>
<p>Instagram and its parent company Meta were also included in the suit, in addition to gun manufacturer Daniel Defense, for their alleged role in "grooming" the teenager into becoming a shooter.</p>
<p>Activision was described as being "the most prolific and effective marketer of assault weapons in the United States," referring to <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/activision-made-a-secret-deal-for-gun-product-placement-in-call-of-duty">alleged gun product placement</a> in the Call of Duty games.</p>
<p>The suit claimed that within a week of the gunman downloading Call of Duty: Modern Warfare in 2021, he bought a gun that had been featured in the game and used in promotional material.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for Activision said (via <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/uvalde-shooting-families-wrongful-death-lawsuit-meta-activision-daniel-defense/">CBS News</a>): "The Uvalde shooting was horrendous and heartbreaking in every way, and we express our deepest sympathies to the families and communities who remain impacted by this senseless act of violence. Millions of people around the world enjoy video games without turning to horrific acts."</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/uvalde-school-shooting-victims-sue-activision-claiming-its-the-most-prolific-marketer-of-weapons-in-the-us">ESA also issued a statement</a> in which the organisation said the claims of the lawsuit were "baseless."</p>
<p>"We are saddened and outraged by senseless acts of violence," it said. "At the same time, we discourage baseless accusations linking these tragedies to video gameplay, which detract from efforts to focus on the root issues in question and safeguard against future tragedies.</p>
<p>"Many other countries have similar rates of video gameplay to the United States, yet do not see similar rates of gun violence."</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jury backs Bungie in lawsuit against cheat maker Aimjunkies]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/jury-backs-bungie-in-lawsuit-against-cheat-maker-aimjunkies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jury-backs-bungie-in-lawsuit-against-cheat-maker-aimjunkies.882660/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/jury-backs-bungie-in-lawsuit-against-cheat-maker-aimjunkies<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bungie has won its lawsuit against </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Destiny 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> cheat maker Aimjunkies.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/stephentotilo/status/1794154042190700617">As noted by Game File reporter Stephen Totilo</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, a jury awarded the PlayStation-owned studio $63,210 in damages and rejected a counterclaim from Aimjunkies that alleged Bungie illegally accessed one of its computers.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">David Schaefer, founder of Aimjunkies parent company Phoenix Digital, said the company intends to fight the ruling and will move to dismiss the verdict before pursuing an appeal.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bungie, however, claims the result is a win for both the studio and its players. "We are grateful for the diligence, professionalism, and care exercised by the Judge, his staff, and the Jury," said Bungie lawyer James Barker. "We're committed to our players and will continue to protect them against cheats, including taking this and future cases all the way to trial."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Aimjunkies was first sued by Bungie in 2021. </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/25/24164679/bungie-anti-cheating-lawsuit-jury-trial-aimjunkies-copyright-violation-victory">As highlighted by The Verge</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, it was alleged the company hacked </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Destiny 2 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">to access code that could be used to create cheats. Some of the complaints from that suit eventually went to arbitration and Bungie was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/destiny-2-cheat-maker-aimjunkies-ordered-to-pay-4-4m-to-bungie">awarded $4.4 million in damages and </a></span><span data-testid="content-text">fees.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The judge overseeing the case found Aimjunkies had violated DMCA provisions by reverse engineering </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Destiny 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to develop and subsequently sell cheats. Bungie also successfully argued that Aimjunkies had breached the terms of the Limited Software License Agreement signed by players before violating the DMCA.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Aimjunkies is currently in the process of appealing that decision.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">News Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer news editor Chris Kerr is an award-winning journalist and reporter with over a decade of experience in the game industry. His byline has appeared in notable print and digital publications including Edge, Stuff, Wireframe, International Business Times, and&nbsp;</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="http://pocketgamer.biz/">PocketGamer.biz</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Throughout his career, Chris has covered major industry events including GDC, PAX Australia, Gamescom, Paris Games Week, and Develop Brighton. He has featured on the judging panel at The Develop Star Awards on multiple occasions and appeared on BBC Radio 5 Live to discuss breaking news.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox just accidentally leaked Black Ops 6 on Game Pass at launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/xbox-just-accidentally-leaked-black-ops-6-on-game-pass-at-launch/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=xbox-just-accidentally-leaked-black-ops-6-on-game-pass-at-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/xbox-just-accidentally-leaked-black-ops-6-on-game-pass-at-launch.882657/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/xbox-just-accidentally-leaked-black-ops-6-on-game-pass-at-launch/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=xbox-just-accidentally-leaked-black-ops-6-on-game-pass-at-launch<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="231" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><em>Call of Duty</em> coming to Xbox Game Pass has been a topic of discussion since Microsoft’s acquisition of Activision was announced. Now, Xbox may have accidentally revealed that <em>Black Ops 6 </em>will be on Game Pass from release day. </p> <p data-characters="277" data-current-count="277" data-injectable="false">Teasers for the next installment of the <em>Call of Duty </em>franchise dropped throughout last week, eventually leading to the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/call-of-dutys-black-ops-6-logo-has-been-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">official <em>Black Ops 6</em> reveal</a> on May 23. While we expect it to drop in Autumn 2024, we weren’t sure if it would be available on Game Pass on release day. </p> <p data-characters="224" data-current-count="501" data-injectable="true">It appears that will be the case; however, after a notification from the Xbox Game Pass mobile app appeared, it said: “Just announced: <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</em> is coming to Game Pass on day one later this year!”</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>A nice notification to receive. Image via Quelanight2324 on Reddit. </figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="247" data-current-count="547" data-injectable="true">Microsoft insider JezCorden moved quickly to throw support behind the news, writing that he expects to see the official announcement of <em>BO6</em> on Game Pass “sometime this week,” but wasn’t able to give an exact date for the reveal. </p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><div> <blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I think you can expect to see the official announcement from Xbox / Microsoft that Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 is going to Xbox Game Pass from day one some time this week. <a href="https://t.co/EXqTZfelQu">https://t.co/EXqTZfelQu</a></p>— Jez (@JezCorden) <a href="https://twitter.com/JezCorden/status/1795325273875038238?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 28, 2024</a></blockquote> </div></figure> <p data-characters="429" data-current-count="729" data-injectable="true">While Microsoft president Sarah Bond had previously stated that all titles from their developers would appear on Game Pass, there was still some uncertainty around <em>Call of Duty</em>. While it was expected that older titles would be added to the platform, the decision to release this year’s game on the service on launch day is huge, especially considering that <em>CoD</em> games regularly dominate the year’s best-seller charts. </p>
 <p data-characters="383" data-current-count="383" data-injectable="false">How this will affect sales of the FPS title remains to be seen, but it marks a seismic shift for the franchise and could help to boost player count when people don’t have to drop $70 to try the game out. With the success of <em>CoD</em>‘s free-to-play battle royale <em>Warzone</em> already bringing players back to the franchise, it feels like a golden age of <em>CoD</em> could be upon us again. </p>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silent Hill announcement stream scheduled for this week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-announcement-stream-scheduled-for-this-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/silent-hill-announcement-stream-scheduled-for-this-week.882651/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-announcement-stream-scheduled-for-this-week<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Be afraid, be Mary afraid.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Silent-Hill-f_4mYrZgV.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Konami</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>Konami has announced a second Silent Hill Transmission show.</p>
<p>This show will cover game updates, another look at the Return to Silent Hill film adaptation, and merch, Konami said.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Eurogamer Newscast: Will Konami succeed bringing Silent Hill back from the dead?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5i2f34an1uc?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Eurogamer Newscast: Will Konami succeed bringing Silent Hill back from the dead?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5i2f34an1uc?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/5i2f34an1uc?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Eurogamer Newscast: Will Konami succeed bringing Silent Hill back from the dead?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5i2f34an1uc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>While Konami has kept further specifics for the show under wraps, I have a few ideas for what we can expect. First of all, I am sure we will see more of the Silent Hill 2 Remake, and perhaps even get a release date. Back in January, a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-gives-2024-release-window-to-metal-gear-solid-delta-snake-eater-and-silent-hill-2-remake">promotional video from PlayStation</a> appeared to suggest the remake would be released at some point this year.</p>
<p>As for gameplay, the Silent Hill 2 Remake team may want to redeem itself after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bloobers-silent-hill-2-remake-gets-fresh-airing-in-combat-focused-trailer">an earlier combat-focused trailer</a> failed to wow audiences. In fact, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/even-bloober-team-wasnt-a-fan-of-silent-hill-2-remakes-combat-focused-trailer">developer Bloober said this previous teaser failed to "capture the spirit of the game"</a>, adding Konami was responsible for marketing. Then, just last month, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-remake-developer-is-excited-and-very-confident">Bloober stated it was "very confident" and "excited" about Silent Hill 2 Remake</a>.</p>
<p>Another game I expect we may see on Thursday is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-f-announced-from-resident-evil-reverse-developer">Silent Hill: f</a>, which was first announced in 2022 during the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/everything-announced-in-konamis-silent-hill-october-2022-showcase">first Silent Hill Transmission show</a>. It was revealed with a goosebump-inducing trailer that made my skin crawl, and it is making my skin crawl again just thinking about it. This particular release will be the first new mainline game for the series in over a decade. </p>
<p>We may also see more of <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-townfall-is-a-new-entry-to-the-series-from-stories-untold-developer-no-code">Silent Hill: Townfall</a>, which was announced at the same time as f.</p>
<p>Film-wise, I am also expecting a release date for Return to Silent Hill, along with a cinematic trailer. Last year, it was announced that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/return-to-silent-hill-casts-war-horses-jeremy-irvine-as-james">War Horse's Jeremy Irvine had been cast as James</a> in the upcoming release, with Hannah Emily Anderson playing his "true love", presumably Mary.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/silent-hill-2-film-leak-suggests-plot-changes-new-character-and-cast-update">leaked film synopsis for Return to Silent Hill</a> previously stated James will return to Silent Hill looking for "his lost love Mary Crane" (in the game, James returns to Silent Hill in search of his wife Mary Shepherd-Sunderland, suggesting the characters may not be married in this adaptation).</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>Consider this your invitation letter to Silent Hill. ✉️</p><p>Tune in May 30 at 4 p.m. PDT to our SILENT HILL YouTube channel for the second installment of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SILENTHILL?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SILENTHILL</a> Transmission where we'll share game updates, a deeper look at the film, and new merch.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SILENTHILL?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SILENTHILL</a> <a href="https://t.co/5RHc2nGUWB">pic.twitter.com/5RHc2nGUWB</a></p></div>— Konami (@Konami) <a href="https://twitter.com/Konami/status/1795228491539005800?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 27, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>Silent Hill Transmission will air on the Silent Hill YouTube channel on 30th May, at 4pm PDT. That's midnight for those of us here in the UK.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest 3 HD-2D remake teased]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-quest-3-hd-2d-remake-teased</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-3-hd-2d-remake-teased.882648/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-quest-3-hd-2d-remake-teased<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dragon-quest-slime.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Square Enix</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Square Enix has teased a HD-2D remake of Dragon Quest 3.
</p>
<p>
Yesterday, 27th May, was Dragon Quest day, celebrating the release of the original Dragon Quest game in Japan in 1986.
</p>
<p>
The short tease was shared on social media platform X featuring the Dragon Quest 3 logo with the words "The legacy begins". The post reads "The legend of Erdrick draws near", Erdrick being the most common name to refer to the third game's protagonist - chronologically the first in the series, though some fans are hoping for remakes of the first three games together.
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: Is the closure of Hi-Fi Rush and Redfall's studios a sign the Xbox Game Pass publishing model is failing?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Dx4fu4H6us" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>

In the corner of the video is a HD-2D logo, while platforms listed are Switch, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X/S, Steam and Windows.
</p>
<div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>
So while this isn't yet a full announcement, it's easy to deduce what game this is.
</p>
<p>
A <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-quest-12-takes-the-long-running-rpg-series-down-a-darker-path">HD-2D remake of Dragon Quest 3 was first revealed on Dragon Quest day in 2021</a>, with a video of the game in motion (see below) developed by Team Asano (Octopath Traveler, Triangle Strategy). This latest tease, then, is the first we've heard of the game since.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="『HD-2D版 ドラゴンクエストIII』ティザームービー" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oFkbeCsEDrk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>『HD-2D版 ドラゴンクエストIII』ティザームービー</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oFkbeCsEDrk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/oFkbeCsEDrk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Dragon Quest 3 HD-2D remake tease<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oFkbeCsEDrk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>

<p>
It's unknown when the full reveal will be as there's no date in the tease, but perhaps it'll appear in a showcase during <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/summer-game-fest-2024-conference-schedule-all-dates-times-streams">Summer Game Fest</a>? Leaker <a href="https://x.com/MbKKssTBhz5/status/1795062186391273783">Midori</a> believes it'll be seen at the next Nintendo Direct.
</p>
<p>Dragon Quest 3 first released on the NES in 1988 and has seen a number of re-releases since then, including on SNES and Game Boy.</p>
<p>
Series creator Yuji Horii also shared a post with a brief update on Dragon Quest 12, the next major game in the series, stating he wants to make something worthy of the posthumous work of the two people who passed away.
</p>
<p>
That would be <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tributes-shared-as-dragon-ball-creator-akira-toriyama-passes-away">artist Akira Toriyama</a> who passed away earlier this year, and composer Koichi Sugiyama who passed away in 2021 at the age of 90.
</p>
<div>

<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>

<p>
A number of Dragon Quest spin-off games have been released in recent years, but the next game in the series is highly-anticipated. Until then, check out the well-received <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-quest-11-s-edition-review-an-epic-rpg-revisited-and-redefined">Dragon Quest 11 S</a> - it's available everywhere, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playstation-plus-games-list-premium-extra-this-month-6300">including PS Plus</a>.

</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zenless Zone Zero gets a release date of July 4th, plus a trailer with lots of kicking]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenless-zone-zero-gets-a-release-date-of-july-4th-plus-a-trailer-with-lots-of-kicking</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/zenless-zone-zero-gets-a-release-date-of-july-4th-plus-a-trailer-with-lots-of-kicking.882645/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenless-zone-zero-gets-a-release-date-of-july-4th-plus-a-trailer-with-lots-of-kicking<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>In the vast <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/wuthering-waves-release-date">Wuthering Waves</a>-shaped shadow that has descended across gaming comes an announcement from HoYoverse, publishers of quite large gacha gubbins 'em up, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/genshin-impact-3-7-release-time">Genshin Impact</a>. The studio's follow-up <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenless-zone-zeros-closed-beta-has-started-offering-glimpses-of-its-genshin-impact-style-combat">Zenless Zone Zero</a> is now set to release on July 4th. For anyone who hasn't yet heard of the bright cyberpunk character action game, I guess now's your chance to look at the slick anime visuals in the new trailer below and go "hmmm", with either a songful note of eye-widening interest or the suspicious rumble of a free-to-play skeptic.  Your choice.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Lycaon Character Demo - &quot;Wolfishly Charming&quot; | Zenless Zone Zero" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8OqyvAXbgiQ?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Lycaon Character Demo - "Wolfishly Charming" | Zenless Zone Zero</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8OqyvAXbgiQ?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8OqyvAXbgiQ?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8OqyvAXbgiQ" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>That housekeeping wolf has got legs. Zenless Zone Zero is set in the futuristic city of New Eridu, an urban cybertopia under threat from the interdimensional beasts that erupt from invasive gateways called Hollows. As the hero conscripted in the city's hour of need, you have to navigate the Hollows and wreck the baddies. What this looks like from trailers, betas and marketing material is a sorta-roguelike jaunt through a grid of CRT television screens, with a lot of flashy combat and big boss battles along the way. Jeremy has a more thorough <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/zenless-zone-zero-release-date-details-everything-we-know">summary of what you do in Zenless Zone Zero</a>, for anyone interested. </p>
<p>The <a href="https://zenless.hoyoverse.com/en-us/news/123831">release date announcement</a> comes quite soon after the release of Wuthering Waves, a Genshin-esque adventure about (as far as I can tell) a gaggle of anime stereotypes all tattooed with their favourite .wav file. Considering how widely played Genshin Impact appears to have been, the release of similar games chasing its sparkly coattails feels inevitable. Whether these new contenders appeal with the same forcefulness remains to be seen. I've been playing Wuthering Waves a bit and it's not capturing me a whole lot. Zenless Zone Zero looks more my style of hack-the-planet nonsense but we'll have to wait until July to see if its jet-legged lycanthropes are enough to keep things lively. Meanwhile, total keeners can <a href="https://act.hoyoverse.com/zzz/event/e20240528landing-2byyms">pre-register with HoYoverse</a>, we're told.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest III HD-2D Will Launch by the End of the Current Fiscal Year; Entire Loto Trilogy Is Getting Remastered]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-entire-loto-trilogy/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-will-launch-by-the-end-of-the-current-fiscal-year-entire-loto-trilogy-is-getting-remastered.882642/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-iii-hd-2d-entire-loto-trilogy/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Dragon Quest III HD-2D won't take much longer to release, and it will be accompanied by a rather welcome surprise, according to rumors circulating online.</p>
<p>Speaking on X/Twitter, Midori, who proved to be an extremely reliable insider in the past few months, revealed that the game will be released by the <a href="https://x.com/MbKKssTBhz5/status/1795158319201440033?t=Rp2_AO2_VycztqA91P3iuQ&amp;s=19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">end of the current fiscal year</a>, so by the end of March 2025. Additionally, it seems like Square Enix is remastering in 2D-HD the entirety of the <a href="https://x.com/MbKKssTBhz5/status/1795163362344472878" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Loto trilogy</a>, which comprises the first three entries in the series. <a href="https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-3-hd-is-coming-to-switch-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc/">Yesterday's teaser</a> kind of gives it away, as it mentioned the legend of Erdrick, which is the main focus of the Loto trilogy.</p>
<p>If Dragon Quest III HD-2D will indeed be accompanied by the remasters of its predecessors, playing these games will be a great way to prepare for the release of<a href="https://wccftech.com/dragon-quest-xii-the-flames-of-fate-is-being-co-developed-by-orca-dev-is-recruiting-unreal-engine-5-staff/"> Dragon Quest XII: The Flames of Fate</a>. Very little is currently known about the game besides the fact that it will be powered by Unreal Engine 5 and will feature an overhaul of the series' classic turn-based combat system.</p>
<p>Dragon Quest III HD-2D will launch on a yet-to-be-confirmed release date on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, Xbox Series S, and Nintendo Switch. We will keep you updated on the game and the other rumored remasters as soon as more information becomes available, so stay tuned for all the latest news.</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Day One Game Pass Will be Announced Today]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-game-pass-day-one/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-day-one-game-pass-will-be-announced-today.882639/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-game-pass-day-one/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Earlier today, people woke up to a new notification from Xbox that Black Ops 6 will be coming to Xbox Game Pass Day One.</p>



<p>The message read, “Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 is coming to Game Pass on day one later this year!” Which diverted people to this link on <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/05/28/play-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-day-one-game-pass/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Xbox Wire</a>. As pointed out by the URL, the announcement is expected to be made today, May 28th, 2024. </p>



<p>Later today, Black Ops 6 will reveal its live-action trailer for Black Ops 6, which will presumably coincide with the announcement of Day One Game Pass. </p>



<p>Following the rumours on Black Ops 6 going to Game Pass last week, new rumours began to emerge that the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/microsoft-to-make-changes-to-xbox-game-pass-tiers-because-of-call-of-duty-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">move will result in changing to Game Pass tiers</a>, which could imply increases are soon on their way. Currently, there’s Xbox Game Pass Core for console that replaced Xbox Live Gold for $9.99/month, Game Pass PC for $9.99/month, and Xbox Game Pass Ultimate that covers both console and PC for $16.99/month.</p>



<p>Insider Gaming understands that Call of Duty Black Ops 6 is expected to launch on October 25, 2024. The game will be fully revealed during the Xbox Games Showcase on June 9th, 2024. Immediately after, it will be given an exclusive Black Ops 6 direct, during which the developers are expected to discuss some of the game’s features and story in more depth.</p>



<p>What do you think of Black Ops 6 coming to Game Pass Day One? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the news about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/silent-hill-transmission-event/">the new Silent Hill showcase</a>, and don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/">sign up for the Insider Gaming Newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft alert confirms Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 day one Xbox Game Pass launch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-alert-confirms-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-day-one-xbox-game-pass-launch</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/microsoft-alert-confirms-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-day-one-xbox-game-pass-launch.882627/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/microsoft-alert-confirms-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-day-one-xbox-game-pass-launch<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_EcwsdUg.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>@mr__matthieu</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 will be a day one launch via Xbox Game Pass, a Microsoft notification has now seemingly confirmed. 
</p>
<p>
Users of the Xbox Game Pass app for iPhone and Android have this morning received a notification that states: "Just announced: Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 is coming to Game Pass on day one later this year!"
</p>
<p>
As first reported by <a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1795385251306324292">Tom Warren</a>, the notification includes a link to a currently-unpublished blog post on Xbox.com, likely set to go live in the near future. 
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: Is the closure of Hi-Fi Rush and Redfall's studios a sign the Xbox Game Pass publishing model is failing?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Dx4fu4H6us" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
News that Black Ops 6 will launch via Xbox Game Pass isn't a huge surprise - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/call-of-duty-2024-will-launch-into-xbox-game-pass-microsoft-has-reportedly-decided">The Wall St Journal previously reported that Microsoft had now made the decision earlier this month</a>.
</p>
<p>
But the question remains whether <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/there-will-be-changes-to-xbox-game-pass-when-call-of-duty-is-added-says-industry-insider">Microsoft will take advantage of Black Ops 6's status to change Xbox Game Pass' pricing or tier structure somehow</a> - which would also help recoup some of the money that players would otherwise have spent on $70 copies.
</p> <div>
<div data-domain="twitter.com"><blockquote><div dir="ltr" lang="en"><p>the Xbox Game Pass app on iOS / Android is notifying people that Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 "is coming to Game Pass on day one later this year!" </p><p>it looks like an announcement is due today 👀 <a href="https://t.co/FBRteX5Nkl">pic.twitter.com/FBRteX5Nkl</a></p></div>— Tom Warren (@tomwarren) <a href="https://twitter.com/tomwarren/status/1795385251306324292?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 28, 2024</a></blockquote></div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</p></div>
<p>
Microsoft will fully show off Black Ops 6 in a dedicated hour-long presentation after its June Xbox Showcase event, which will once again take place alongside other events from Ubisoft and (its expected) Nintendo during the old E3 conference week.
</p>
<p>Eurogamer has contacted Microsoft for more.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>