<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 05:57:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Free-to-play MMO action RPG Crystal of Atlan launches May 28 for PS5, PC, iOS, and Android worldwide]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/free-to-play-mmo-action-rpg-crystal-of-atlan-launches-may-28-for-ps5-pc-ios-and-android-worldwide</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/free-to-play-mmo-action-rpg-crystal-of-atlan-launches-may-28-for-ps5-pc-ios-and-android-worldwide.1175088/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/free-to-play-mmo-action-rpg-crystal-of-atlan-launches-may-28-for-ps5-pc-ios-and-android-worldwide<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Pre-launch item pack pre-orders now available.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [383 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">Free-to-play</a> massively <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [490 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> online <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,597 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Crystal of Atlan" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/crystal-of-atlan">Crystal of Atlan</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,356 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PC [23,021 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via client download and <a title="Companies > Epic Games [349 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/epic-games">Epic Games</a> Store, iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/bn/app/crystal-of-atlan/id6453111576" target="_blank" rel="noopener">App Store</a>, and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.crystal.usad&amp;hl=en_US" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Play</a> on May 28 worldwide, developer <a title="Companies > Nuverse [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/nuverse">Nuverse</a> announced. <span id="more-961693"></span></p><p>Pre-orders for two separate item packs are currently available via <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [47,468 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> Store. The packs include the following content:</p><ul><li><strong>Pack I</strong> ($9.99 / £7.99 / €9.99 / ¥1,540) – <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP6477-PPSA24519_00-0397206641195982" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Store</a><ul><li>Phantasium Pass (15 Days) (x1)</li><li>Starting Pack (x1)</li><li>Arcanite of Brocade (x10)</li><li>Top-up Point (x720)</li></ul></li><li><strong>Pack II</strong> ($19.99 / £15.99 / €19.99 / ¥3,080) – <a href="https://store.playstation.com/en-us/product/UP6477-PPSA24519_00-0087619783955507" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PlayStation Store</a><ul><li>Phantasium Pass (30 Days) (x1)</li><li>Advanced <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,241 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">Adventure</a>r’s Manual (x1)</li><li>Starting Pack (x1)</li><li>Arcanite of Brocade (x15)</li><li>Top-up Point (x1,440)</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        </li></ul><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Nuverse:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Crystal of Atlan</em> is a Magicpunk massively multiplayer online action RPG where you can immerse yourself in a Magicpunk world, to combat, to build your skills, and to uncover the secrets with the team.</p><p>Embark on a wondrous journey of Magic and Machinery!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Smooth Combos and Exhilarating Combat</strong> – Every combo leads to different outcomes. The exhilarating and fluid combat system offers seamless control over both skill casts and character movement, giving you a sense of effortless mastery.</li><li><strong>Refreshing Air Combos to Unlock a New Combat Style</strong> – In addition to the X/Y axis focus of mainstream 3D games, you can experience combats on Z-axis, offering a refined aerial combat experience that innovates the traditional MMORPG combat style.</li><li><strong>Multiple Classes to Choose, Combos of Your Own</strong> – Multiple classes to choose from, all unlocked from the start, each with over 20 skill combinations, providing ample room for players to experiment.</li><li><strong>Challenging Team Battles</strong> – You can experience various multiplayer elements, including <a title="Genres > Co-Op [255 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">co-op</a> dungeons and a guild fleet system, allowing you to connect with like-minded friends.</li><li><strong>A Unique Magicpunk World</strong> – Embark on an epic journey through a fantastical world where magic and technology intertwine. As a free-spirited adventurer, uncover the secrets of ancient Atlan ruins and confront powerful factions.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Crystal of Atlan</em> first launched for PC, iOS, and Android in China on July 14, 2023.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Magician Class Display</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="Magician Class Display" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6p6jJyAfcNo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="CoA魔導士新転職ー「マジシャン」PV初公開" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GZsvd5TsnuI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jiro Ishii announces crowdfunding campaign for new Shibuya Live-Action Adventure Game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/jiro-ishii-announces-crowdfunding-campaign-for-new-shibuya-live-action-adventure-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/jiro-ishii-announces-crowdfunding-campaign-for-new-shibuya-live-action-adventure-game.1175085/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/jiro-ishii-announces-crowdfunding-campaign-for-new-shibuya-live-action-adventure-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Ishii aiming to create a title that surpasses 428: Shibuya Scramble.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Game designer and <em>428: Shibuya Scramble</em> executive producer Jiro Ishii has announced the launch of a new “Shibuya Live-<a title="Genres > Action [2,702 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">Action</a> Adventure Game.” Led by general director Ishii and screenwriter Yukinori Kitajima, the project will be a live-action <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,241 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> set in Shibuya. Platforms and a release date were not announced, but a crowdfunding campaign will launch via <a href="https://ubgoe.com/projects/923" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ubgoe</a> on May 28. <span id="more-961606"></span></p><p>Cast members of the project include <a title="Companies > Mas" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/mas">Mas</a>akazu Arai, who played Keima Amemiya in <em>Machi: Unmei no Kousaten</em>, and Fumio Kitagami, who played Minoru Minorikawa in <em>428: Shibuya Scramble</em>.</p><p>The game itself will use an “ensemble drama” system—a synchronized story with multiple protagonists, in which players experience a multiple-perspective structure that shifts between each character’s viewpoint.</p><p>In a message, Ishii said that <em>428: Shibuya Scramble</em> was created as a successor to the live-action adventure game <em>Machi: Unmei no Kousaten</em>, with the goal of surpassing it. He expected that a game would eventually come along to surpass <em>428: Shibuya Scramble</em> as well. But over 20 years later, no such title has emerged. At one point, Ishii approached various game companies about a follow-up project, but those discussions fell apart, as many were more concerned with marketing and business than the core of the project. For a time, he even distanced himself from such projects. Ultimately, Ishii and his team decided to develop the new title independently.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sting announces board game-style RPG VIractal for PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/sting-announces-board-game-style-rpg-viractal-for-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sting-announces-board-game-style-rpg-viractal-for-pc.1175073/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/sting-announces-board-game-style-rpg-viractal-for-pc<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Launching first in Early Access.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><em>Dokapon</em> series developer <a title="Companies > Sting [84 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sting">Sting</a> has <a href="https://twitter.com/sting_pr/status/1916688964129591710" target="_blank">announced</a> <em><a title="Games > VIractal" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/viractal">VIractal</a></em>, a board game-style <a title="Genres > RPG [17,204 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> coming to <a title="Platforms > PC [23,021 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2909580/VIractal/" target="_blank">. </a>It will launch first in Early Access, where it will remain for six months to a year. A release date has yet to be announced. It will support English, Japanese, Korean, Traditional Chinese, and Simplified Chinese language options. <span id="more-961613"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2909580/VIractal/" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Deep in a throbbing headache, you awaken in a strange, unfamiliar room.</p><p>A dim light flickers; a lone board game sits quietly at the center.</p><p>Rain drums on windows that reveal nothing but swirling fog.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Knowing nothing else, you hear a voice whisper from nowhere.</p><p>Make ready. “Let’s all play this mysterious board game together!”</p><p>An unshakable sense of dread fills your chest as you reach forward.</p><p>Gently, reality begins to melt into fantasy.</p><p>Everything fades, and the game begins.</p><p><strong>Your Journey Begins With a Single Roll of the Dice</strong></p><p>A board game-style RPG where heroes journey through the miniature world of “Viractalia.”</p><p>Your movement depends on the roll of the dice—but the key to victory lies in your hand and how you build your deck!</p><p>Embark on your own unique adventure in a world where strategy and luck are perfectly intertwined!</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_961620"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Freely Explore a Procedurally Generated Miniature World</strong>&nbsp;– Each time you play, the whimsical yet intricate world transforms before your eyes! With limited time to explore, every step is full of excitement: What will happen next? What will I find?</li><li><strong>A Fusion of Card Battles and <a title="Genres > Board Game [55 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/board-game">Board Game</a> <a title="Genres > Strategy [239 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">Strategy</a></strong> – Use a wide variety of cards to defeat your enemies! Collect countless cards and build your own custom deck and powerful combos!</li><li><strong>Dice-Based Movement With the DP System</strong>&nbsp;– “I rolled a big number… but I only want to move one space?” Don’t worry—no roll is ever wasted! Unused movement points are converted into DP, a special resource that can be spent to power up events or give you the edge in battle.</li><li><strong>Dynamic Events and Meaningful Choices</strong> – On your journey, you’ll encounter unique and colorful events. Your decisions may grant you powerful abilities… or change the course of your <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,241 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> entirely!</li><li><strong>Play Solo or With Friends</strong> – Whether you’re diving in solo or adventuring with others, you’re in for a good time! Online <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [490 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> is supported—and who knows? Something special might happen just for you when you’re playing online…</li><li><strong>Where Strategy and <a title="Series > Fate [66 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/fate">Fate</a> Collide</strong> – The fate you entrust to the dice, and the cards you choose with care—every move you make weaves your story. A fresh adventure awaits board game lovers, card game fans, and strategy enthusiasts alike.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/viractal/april-27-2025/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="VIractal - Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gqhcqn55faU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last Of Us Season Two, Episode Three Recap: On The Road Again]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-season-2-episode-3-recap-review-ellie-dina-1851778010</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-last-of-us-season-two-episode-three-recap-on-the-road-again.1175055/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-season-2-episode-3-recap-review-ellie-dina-1851778010<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Hey folks. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-tv-season-2-episode-joel-abby-death-reaction-1851777264&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-tv-season-2-episode-joel-abby-death-reaction-1851777264">Y’all feeling alright</a></span> after <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-max-season-2-episode-2-joel-abby-death-1851776976&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-max-season-2-episode-2-joel-abby-death-1851776976">last week’s harrowing episode</a></span> of <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-season-2-hbo-max-show-review-joel-ellie-abby-1851774661&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-season-2-hbo-max-show-review-joel-ellie-abby-1851774661"><em>The Last of Us</em></a></span>? Everybody have a productive therapy session to talk about <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-max-show-joel-death-abby-kills-reaction-1851777068&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-max-show-joel-death-abby-kills-reaction-1851777068">your TV peepaw’s death</a></span>? Alright, cool, because we’re gonna spend this week’s episode doing more therapy and leaning harder into the show’s worst tendencies. Strap in, folks. I’m about to start swinging.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197544" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="4 Essential Tips to Survive Clair Obscur: Expedition 33’s Brutal First Hours" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="197544,197541,197533" data-current="197544"><div><p>4 Essential Tips to Survive Clair Obscur: Expedition 33’s Brutal First Hours</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197544/197544_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197544/197544_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197544/197544_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23069.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><h2 id="h460501"><a id=""></a><strong>Post trauma</strong></h2><p>We open on the bloody aftermath of the battle in Jackson. Corpses, human and infected, are scattered across the small town. But the body we linger on didn’t come from the massive clash; it’s Joel’s. In a somber moment, Tommy (Gabriel Luna) comes to the morgue to see his big brother. He starts to clean his arm and sees the broken watch on his wrist. He gives his brother one more longing look and tells him to “give Sarah [his] love” before getting back to work.</p><p>Last week, I was admittedly pretty dismissive of some of these smaller added moments of grief the show adds to what was in <em>The Last of Us Part II</em>, the game on which this season is based. Ellie crawling to Joel’s body and cuddling up to him felt performative to me in the moment, and maybe that was more me reacting to the show’s broader lack of restraint than to the scene itself. But this scene with Tommy landed for me because we got remarkably little of Tommy’s grief in <em>Part II</em>, and because it wasn’t led up to by 10 minutes of monologuing and telling me what to feel. Tommy is speaking to Joel, not to the audience.</p><p>We then see a bustling hospital full of the injured from the battle. Ellie is also here after Manny kicked her in the chest and seemingly collapsed one of her lungs. She’s breathing weakly through a chest tube as she wakes, but immediately starts screaming as she remembers what Abby did to Joel until she’s sedated. Cut to credits.</p><p>We then jump forward to three months later. Things are warming up, and Jackson has made good progress rebuilding after the battle against the horde. Ellie, meanwhile, has also made good progress and is getting her final check-up with the doctors after her injuries. But she has to see one more person before she can leave the hospital: Gail (Catherine O’Hara).</p><p>As I said in the episode one recap, Gail is one of my least favorite additions in the show, not because O’Hara isn’t wonderful, but because she facilitates some of the show’s worst tendencies. Ellie, clearly telling Gail what she thinks she wants to hear, now unloads about how she misses Joel, laments that the “last time” they spoke was the New Year’s dance fiasco, and says that your final moments with someone shouldn’t define your life with them. Then when the conversation veers into when Joel supposedly “wronged” her, Ellie says she doesn’t know what he could have meant and wishes she could have “let him off the hook” for that, but that she’ll also need to “let herself off the hook” for not being able to do so.</p><figure id="" data-id="f6a607174edbd21bb0dc343fa3516066" data-recommend-id="image://f6a607174edbd21bb0dc343fa3516066" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Tommy stands in the morgue. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Tommy stands in the morgue. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->HBO</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f6a607174edbd21bb0dc343fa3516066" data-recommend-id="image://f6a607174edbd21bb0dc343fa3516066" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Tommy stands in the morgue. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Gail lets Ellie go but seems mostly unconvinced by her performative response to her line of questioning. And as soon as they’re done, Ellie’s chipper facade falls away quickly, and the smile disappears from her face as quickly as she put it on. The irony of this scene is that Ellie is speaking aloud the things she will eventually learn, even if she doesn’t believe any of it right now. She pulls off a convincing enough performance to leave the facility, but there was still part of me that felt suspicious of this exchange after the show has already proven it doesn’t trust its audience to follow along. I can’t help but look at this scene and feel like it’s meant to tell viewers what Ellie <em>should</em> be feeling rather than the feelings of fury she does right now. A therapist approved all these lines of thought, right? That’s the only way she’s deemed of sound mind to walk around the citizens of Jackson once again. In a vacuum, the scene is fine and illustrates that Ellie is still very much wrestling with debilitating anger and doesn’t trust the adults in her life, but again, every time <em>The Last of Us </em>describes the themes of the source material in no uncertain terms, I’m left wondering why showrunner Craig Mazin has made these blunt edits. Does he not have faith in the viewers to get it, or is he making up for what he perceives as a weak link in the game’s writing?</p><p>Speaking of showing instead of telling, we now get the show’s version of one of <em>The Last of Us Part II</em>’s best sequences: Joel’s home. After Ellie is released from the hospital, she heads home, and instead of going straight to her shed, she goes to Joel’s big empty house. Flowers and tributes cover the white picket fence. They’ve been there for months, but this is the first time Ellie’s seen them. To Abby, Joel was a murderer. To Ellie, he was a complicated father figure. To the people of Jackson, he was a beloved member of their community. There are different versions of each of us in the minds of everyone we’ve ever met, and the truth is we all exist somewhere in the middle. That’s why people come away from <em>The Last of Us Part II</em> with such contrasting feelings: because the entire game is about that concept.</p><p>One nice touch the show adds to this segment is that Ellie has a room in Joel’s house that wasn’t present in the game. Though the mattress is no longer here and is now in the shed out back, the rest of the room looks largely untouched. It’s covered in astronaut stickers, old sketches, and toys. It feels like a childhood bedroom, whereas her new space gives off something more like college burnout. The brief shot we see of the old room illustrates how much Ellie has grown up, but maybe also how Joel probably felt left behind. He has this snapshot of a younger version of his surrogate daughter in his own home. No wonder he didn’t understand the rift between them as she grew up.</p><p>Then we reach the gut punch: Joel’s bedroom. It’s full of unfinished wood carving projects he’ll never return to, but it also has a small red box sitting on the bed. Inside, Ellie finds the last of Joel’s belongings: his broken watch from Sarah and his trademark revolver. Ellie only takes the latter before turning to leave, but also takes a moment to stop in Joel’s closet and take a whiff of his leather jacket. Then she finally allows herself to cry before this moment is interrupted by Dina (Isabela Merced) calling to her from the lower floor.</p><p>Her friend brings with her two things: cookies and information. She says that, when visiting Ellie in the hospital, she’d hid that she knew most of Abby’s group’s names because the doctors told her not to tell Ellie anything that might upset her while she was recovering. Ellie is furious because Joel’s killers now have a three-month head start, but Dina, being the more level-headed person in the room, reminds her that if you want to find someone and you know where they’re going to be, you should let them get there. Then Dina reminds Ellie that she loved Joel, too. In <em>Part II</em>, Dina went to Seattle because she’s a ride or die, but the show is giving her more personal stakes in seeing justice for Joel because they had a relationship of their own. It’s a good change; a lot of Dina’s characterization—such as her relationship with her family’s Jewish history—is lost without the ambient dialogue between her and Ellie in the early game, so this helps fill out her character more in a way I appreciated.</p><p>Dina runs down what she knows, including the names of most of the group and a wolf patch she saw on their gear with the initials “W.L.F.” She recalls a story Eugene told her before his passing about subsets of civilian militia that were trying to fight FEDRA, the government agency that turned fascist after the cordyceps outbreak, including one called the Washington Liberation Front. They don’t know what they’re up against, but hopefully it’s not too much for them to handle.</p><p>But rather than head out immediately, Ellie and Dina go to see Tommy. He’s hesitant because the town is still recovering and not in any position to send out a squad of vengeful soldiers. Ellie says Joel would have already been halfway to Seattle by now, a claim which Tommy rebuts, saying that he’d only take that kind of risk to save someone he cared about, not to seek revenge (I don’t know about that one, chief). If they’re going to do this, they have to go through Jackson protocol, which means taking it to Maria and the town’s council. Ellie isn’t thrilled, but Tommy says he’ll back her, and lets Dina know that if she holds back information again, there will be consequences. As the girls leave, Tommy tells Ellie that they buried the dead after the attack south of town, if she wants to visit. Ellie says she will when she’s on the way to Seattle. Tommy said in episode one that Ellie and Joel were the exact same person, and her self-assured stubbornness in this moment is giving Pedro Pascal. To her, this whole song and dance is just another obstacle in the way of something inevitable. She can’t imagine any other possibility.</p><h2 id="h460502"><a id=""></a><strong>Literal and metaphorical scars</strong></h2><p>We’ve spent a lot of time in Jackson these past few episodes, so this next scene gives us a preview of what to expect in Seattle. We open on a lone man walking through a forest wearing a tattered trench coat, sporting a shaved head, and with twin scars across his face. He whistles to a group of similarly dressed people elsewhere in the forest, and one of the adults asks a young girl to translate the meaning of the whistles, which were orders to keep moving as there was no danger present. The group apparently doesn’t know where they’re headed, but there’s a “reason” for this pilgrimage with no known destination. There was a war happening wherever they’re fleeing from, and the prophet they once followed has been dead for a decade, so she can’t protect them. But they keep her spirit alive by following her teachings. To do this, they have to keep themselves safe, which is why they’re armed with hammers and bows. Just as the girl says she feels safe, another whistle comes from the lookout, warning the group of incoming danger. They hide in the forest, and the girl asks if it’s “demons,” to which the man replies that it’s “wolves.” On that ominous note, the show pops back over to Dina’s sketch of the wolf patch she saw on Abby’s clothes.</p><p>If you felt that was disorienting, I wouldn’t blame you, but these people with all their cultish language and archaic weaponry are the Seraphites, a cult in Seattle that is at war with the W.L.F. As we get close to the Emerald City, some of the uglier parts of the series to unpack will start to become more prominent, as the violence between the Seraphites and W.L.F. is inspired by the ongoing conflicts in Palestine and Israel which have only escalated in the years since the game came out. This isn’t me projecting; series director Neil Druckmann <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://time.com/7275781/the-last-of-us-controversy-israel-gaza/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://time.com/7275781/the-last-of-us-controversy-israel-gaza/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">has said as much</a></span>. The actual specifics of how <em>The Last of Us </em>portrays its fictional war, and how Druckmann’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.instagram.com/druckmann/p/CyHFe56SrN6/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.instagram.com/druckmann/p/CyHFe56SrN6/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">public pro-Israel reaction</a></span> to the ongoing real-world conflict have justifiably colored the interpretations and experiences of the series for many players, are a lot to untangle and dissect. It’ll be some time before the show really dives into this plot thread and we really need to dig into it in these recaps, but I felt it was important context to bring up now as we begin our journey to Seattle, where this storyline becomes more prevalent.</p><figure id="" data-id="0186a3a773b814a6f310a2cb8736c754" data-recommend-id="image://0186a3a773b814a6f310a2cb8736c754" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Jackson council." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Jackson council." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->HBO</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0186a3a773b814a6f310a2cb8736c754" data-recommend-id="image://0186a3a773b814a6f310a2cb8736c754" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="The Jackson council." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Ellie, meanwhile, is training for the upcoming fight. Jesse is impressed that she’s bounced back so quickly after being hospitalized, but not impressed enough to be forthcoming with her about the upcoming council meeting. Now that he’s on the council, he can’t discuss his or anyone else’s votes, even as Ellie tries to appeal to their friendship. As a sign of good faith, he does give Ellie some advice, telling her to write her thoughts down and read them to everyone in the meeting. Ellie dismissively takes this as a sign that she’s “stupid,” but Jesse says it’s because she’s angry, and her inability to take that well-meaning advice as such is further proof of that.</p><p>Unfortunately for Ellie, she has a lot of time to organize her thoughts at the council meeting because her revenge tour is not the only issue on the agenda. Some folks came to talk more mundane shit like livestock. But when the topic of sending people to Seattle comes up, Ellie isn’t the first one to take the stand, it’s a woman who points out that Jackson lost a lot more people that day than just Joel. Things are too fragile right now, she says, to send a large group chasing after Abby’s crew. Another man stands up and says that they should separate themselves from the raiders and murderers by showing mercy. Then, Ellie finds an unexpected ally (see what I did there) in Seth, who says that those murderers don’t deserve mercy. The town bigot is the only one to support vengeance for the man who knocked him on his prejudiced ass the night before he died. Seth says that they’ll be back to finish the job if Jackson doesn’t send someone after them.</p><p>When <em>The Last of Us Part II</em> came out, there were criticisms that the game boiled down to a metatextual scolding about something obvious to most civilized people: violence is bad, actually. Revenge is <em>not </em>it. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/the-last-of-us-part-ii-the-kotaku-review-1844006193&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/the-last-of-us-part-ii-the-kotaku-review-1844006193">Even <em>Kotaku</em>’s review</a></span> by Riley MacLeod touches on this, with him writing, “Late one night, I paused the game and asked myself aloud if the developers thought I was stupid, if they thought the existence of violence had just never occurred to me before.” I never felt this kind of condescension when I played the game, largely because I viewed revenge as one piece of the puzzle, rather than the full thing, but I can’t shake that feeling when I watch the show. I <em>really</em> felt it in this scene that sounded like a podcast of people debating the morality of <em>The Last of Us Part II</em>. The show’s heavy-handed dialogue continues to feel weirdly patronizing, like it needs to make sure you have considered every nuance that should feel.</p><p>Finally, Ellie is allowed to speak. She followed Jesse’s advice and wrote her thoughts down to read. She says she doesn’t want revenge, she wants justice. Then she points out that if they do nothing, no one will do anything because no one else is fighting for Jackson. Ellie appeals to the community aspect Jesse has been hammering into her head, and points out that while the rest of the world is full of dangerous “strangers,” she wants to know that the people of Jackson can count on each other. This is a version of Ellie we’ve seen who is very jaded toward the idea of community, and it’s unclear if this is her trying to appeal to the sensibilities of the council or if it’s a last-ditch effort to convince herself that there is a community for her here. While Joel may have been a beloved member of Jackson, Ellie has been ostracized by several people in this small town. Her discomfort has been ignored by the adults in her life, her desires have often been denied to her because they think they know better, and yet all that’s ever been said to her is that the good of the community comes first. If she’s supposed to be part of that fellowship, why are her needs never a priority? Whatever her reasoning, Ellie knows now that she can’t count on Jackson because the council votes against her proposal. A wave of relief fills the room, but Ellie silently walks out.</p><p>It’s now Tommy’s turn to see the town counselor. He tracks Gail down at a tee-ball game and she has her own theories about Ellie’s speech. Tommy’s worried that Ellie’s going to do something reckless, and Gail asks if he believes Ellie’s words at the council meeting. She says that the girl is a “liar.” Tommy says she doesn’t want Ellie to go down the same path as Joel, who would also come up with justifications for every violent act he carried out in this desecrated world. Gail asks if Ellie might have learned this behavior from Joel, but says that “nurture” can only do so much, and that if violence is who Ellie is, it wasn’t because Joel taught her to be. She also says that some people can’t be saved, and as much as Tommy would like to change that, it’s probably true of Ellie, as well.</p><p>Alrighty, so <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-max-season-2-episode-1-recap-review-s2e1-1851775994&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-max-season-2-episode-1-recap-review-s2e1-1851775994">I alluded to this conversation in my episode one recap</a></span>, and I consider it one of the most disappointing in all of season two. <em>The Last of Us</em> showrunner Craig Mazin has <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NHEUXYgR7Zw&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NHEUXYgR7Zw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">talked at length</a></span> about how he believes Ellie to be a naturally violent individual, and it shows in the sadism she expresses in season one. This is a marked change from how the character was portrayed in the first game, which showed her having no proclivity towards violence, just a desire to be trusted to carry it out when it was necessary. When it became clear that Mazin’s choice to make Ellie more intrinsically violent for the show was made in a misguided attempt to lean into Ellie’s violent tendencies in season two, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-show-ellie-bella-ramsey-violent-heart-1850224988&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-hbo-show-ellie-bella-ramsey-violent-heart-1850224988">I wrote about</a></span> how the only reason Ellie’s shift towards violence in <em>Part II</em> works is because that game goes out of its way to show that she’s not cut out to inflict the kind of violence she learned from Joel. There are scenes in the game that have Ellie trying and failing to use Joel’s exact interrogation techniques, and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.tiktok.com/@infectedtlou/video/7487678655087283502&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@infectedtlou/video/7487678655087283502" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Druckmann and game actor Ashley Johnson have spoken</a></span> in <em>Part II Remastered</em>’s commentary about how the point was to show how Ellie was very different from her surrogate father, and that this violence may have been innate to who he was, but not her.</p><p>Without getting too specific about future episodes, I still find the show’s suggestion that Ellie’s sadism and anger are just part of who she is to be both a misguided change and a fundamental misunderstanding of the story of <em>The Last of Us Part II</em>. Where some changes, like revealing Abby’s motivations early or heavily implying that Ellie had some kind of reconciliation with Joel, undercut the narrative tension of the source material but leave character dynamics intact, this shift just lets Joel off the hook for who Ellie grew up to be and colors her grief-driven crusade as more of a tantrum that needs to be managed rather than as the actions of woman lashing out at a life that has taken most of the things she’s ever wanted from her. Ellie’s arc in these games is so much more complex than anger issues, and I find the show’s vision of her violence to be so one-dimensional. Violence is a language characters use to express everything from love to hatred in <em>The Last of Us</em>, and it’s one that the show barely knows how to read.</p><p>Back in her shed, Ellie is doing exactly what Tommy feared: something stupid. She’s got guns and supplies spread around her space and is clearly gearing up to head out by herself. Dina arrives and points out how an arsenal and canned food isn’t enough to reach Seattle and kill Abby. She has no plan, no route, no map; just a switchblade and a dream. Dina’s not here to talk her out of it, she’s here to make sure she doesn’t get herself killed on the way. In another life, Dina would be the one who plans the girls’ two-week overseas vacation down to booking the flights and itinerary, where Ellie gets to be a passenger princess who just has to show up.</p><p>Ellie thanks Dina as she leaves, to which Dina replies that she could have just asked. Ellie says she didn’t realize that, and if she’s become this jaded toward the community of Jackson, it makes sense that she wouldn’t even feel like she could rely on her best friend. But hopefully, Dina’s actions quell any of her fears. As the two prepare to leave with their horse Shimmer, they’re sent off by none other than Seth. He offers Ellie his rifle, some supplies, and a few words of encouragement. Ellie is skeptical the whole time, even scoffing at the notion that revenge for Joel is a collective cause between the two of them. But as they leave, the two exchange a silent handshake. Maybe bigots can grow. A radical thought.</p><figure id="" data-id="5d32215c92fd559c4e20269cdf7060de" data-recommend-id="image://5d32215c92fd559c4e20269cdf7060de" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Ellie kneels down in front of Joel's grave." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Ellie kneels down in front of Joel's grave." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->HBO</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="5d32215c92fd559c4e20269cdf7060de" data-recommend-id="image://5d32215c92fd559c4e20269cdf7060de" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Ellie kneels down in front of Joel's grave." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>But before we head out, Ellie has one more place she needs to go. She and Dina stop at a graveyard just south of Jackson and find one marked “Joel Miller, beloved brother and father.” Ellie unwraps some coffee beans and spreads them over the soil, lingers for a moment, then silently turns to leave. I’m glad the show displays some restraint here, because it would not have surprised me if Ellie had voiced everything she ever wanted to say to Joel, as that’s often the show’s M.O. Instead, we got an understated moment with a cute nod to Joel’s coffee fixation. It’s good.</p><h2 id="h460503"><a id=""></a>Washington bound</h2><p>We skip forward a bit as Dina and Ellie play games to pass the time on horseback. Dina asks Ellie about her first kill. She says she won’t talk about the first one (we don’t need to relive <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-tlou-s1e7-left-behind-ellie-riley-hbo-mall-1850161819&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-tlou-s1e7-left-behind-ellie-riley-hbo-mall-1850161819">Riley’s tragic fate</a></span>), but she does tell her about her and Joel’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-tlou-s1e5-henry-sam-hbo-kathleen-kansas-city-1850104162&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-tlou-s1e5-henry-sam-hbo-kathleen-kansas-city-1850104162">time in Kansas City</a></span>. Dina says she’s sorry Ellie had to go through that, which surprises our funky little lesbian. “I shoot a guy and you feel sorry for me?” “I’m just loyal like that,” Dina replies.</p><p>The pair’s trip is put on hold as a storm passes over them. That’s how you know they’re getting closer to Seattle. They set up a tent, and it’s clear that Ellie is unsure what to do with all this closeness. Just as the girls are about to get some shuteye, Dina turns the lantern on and says she wants to talk about <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-part-2-season-dance-dina-ellie-scene-ep1-1851776130&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/last-of-us-part-2-season-dance-dina-ellie-scene-ep1-1851776130">New Year’s Eve and their big kiss</a></span>. You know, before Seth ruined it. Ellie seems to have stopped reading into it because they were both intoxicated, but Dina wants to know how Ellie would rate it. Ellie isn’t looking to play along, and when Dina reminds the room that she’s “not” gay, Ellie finally gives her a number: six. Dina doesn’t believe this rating, but when Ellie tells her she can go back to Jesse if she wants something better, Dina reveals she already did. That’s seemingly resolved that issue.</p><p>By this point in <em>Part II</em>, Dina and Ellie were established as girlfriends, and all the romantic tension was gone in favor of two girls getting to know each other in this new context. I’m okay with the show taking a different approach to this, as a lot of the relationship building between Ellie and Dina is lost when we can’t spend hours wandering around Seattle and chatting. Introducing Dina and establishing their relationship as quickly as the game does probably wouldn’t work for TV, so replacing it with some “will they/won’t they” awkwardness is probably the right call. A lot of fans were disappointed that this meant one of the best scenes between the two in Jackson, which involved <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fa6MHj2eFV8&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fa6MHj2eFV8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">passing weed back and forth among other activities</a></span>, went out the window. But we’re making up for some lost ground in this scene, so I’m willing to see where this goes and weigh in later.</p><p>Dina asks if Jesse seems sad to Ellie, and she replies without hesitation that he does, though neither of them is sure why. Dina thinks maybe that’s just who he is. At least, she hopes so. Because if it’s not, then maybe she makes him feel that way. Before the two drift off to sleep, Dina tells Ellie she “wasn’t <em>that</em> high” when they kissed. Girl, you’ve got some decisions to make.</p><p>The two get back on the road in the morning, and are just about 10 miles out of Seattle when they come across the aftermath of some kind of battle. Bodies of the Seraphite crew from earlier in the episode are scattered across the trail, and as Dina investigates further, she runs back to Ellie to puke in the bushes. Ellie goes to see what elicited such a response and finds their bodies decomposing. Dina apologizes for her sickness, pinning it on the smell. Ellie guesses from the caliber of the various bullet casings at the scene that this might have been Abby’s crew. Now they have another reason to feel vindicated in coming all this way.</p><p>Then we finally reach Seattle. From a distance, you would have no idea there’s a war happening here. Dina says there might not be that many wolves for them to deal with, to which Ellie says there are about to be “a whole lot less.” Dina asks if that was a cool action movie line from the <em>Curtis &amp; Viper</em> movies Joel loved so much. Ellie says that one was all her; she was just trying to sound like a badass. “You don’t need to try,” Dina whispers in her ear. Girlypop, don’t play like this when you’ve got a man waiting for you back home. (Do it. Give in to the gay thoughts.)</p><p>Spaking of wolves, we see the first sign of life from Abby’s crew. Manny (Danny Ramirez) is keeping watch from the remains of the Space Needle, and luckily doesn’t see the Jackson girlies as he gives the all-clear for a W.L.F. crew to move through the city. While Ellie and Dina may be expecting a small group of heavily armed bandits, the group Manny clears to move through the city is sporting tanks, military-grade weapons and armor, and is moving like a well-trained unit. Ellie’s rage may have brought her this far, but she’s gonna need a lot more than that to fight her way through Seattle to Abby.</p><hr><p>New episodes of <em>The Last of Us </em>premiere on Sundays at 9 p.m. Eastern on Max.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: 11th Gen iPad, Visions of Mana, Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-27-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-deals-today-11th-gen-ipad-visions-of-mana-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii-and-more.1175004/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-27-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The weekend is officially here, and we've rounded up the best deals you can find! Discover the best deals for April 20 below:</p><h2 data-cy="title2">11th Gen iPad for $299</h2><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219548"><div id="219548" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>New Apple iPad 11-inch: A16 chip, 11-inch Model - 128GB</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">First up, you can save $50 off the newest iPad. Powered by the A16, the newest <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/apple-ipad-11th-generation">11th-generation iPad</a> is an exceptional addition to any workspace. You can use this device with both <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-ipad-accessories">Apple Pencil and Magic Keyboard Folio</a> to make the most out of it without having to go for the iPad Air or iPad Pro. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Visions of Mana for $34.99</h2></div><div id="219546" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Visions of Mana - Amazon Exclusive Edition (PS5)</h3></p></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219547"><div id="219547" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Visions of Mana - Amazon Exclusive Edition (XSX)</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Visions of Mana released at the end of August, and it's available on sale for the first time this weekend. This is the first new Mana game in almost two decades, starring a cast of characters on a quest to save the world. In <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/visions-of-mana-review">our 8/10 review</a>, we stated, "Visions of Mana finally brings the long-dormant classic RPG series into the modern age, looking great and playing even better thanks to multi-layered class and skill systems that interact in clever ways."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition for $49.99</h2></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219525"><div id="219525" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-review">Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition</a> brings the long-requested Wii U game to Nintendo Switch with numerous quality-of-life updates and features. There's also even an added epilogue story chapter with a new ending for the game, which likely will directly lead into the future of the series. With a soundtrack by Hiroyuki Sawano and a massive world to explore, Xenoblade Chronicles X is a game you can easily spend hundreds of hours in.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Razer Huntsman V2 TKL for $74.99</h2></div><div catalogid="c1e24b32-f264-4725-ad01-ca010d75866c" id="218975"><div id="218975" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Razer - Huntsman V2 TKL Wired Optical Purple Clicky Switch Gaming Keyboard with Chroma RGB Backlighting - Black</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Best Buy has the Razer Huntsman V2 TKL Mechanical Keyboard for just $74.99 today. This keyboard features clicky optical switches that feel much lighter than most other mechanical switches out there, as you can get up to true 8000Hz polling rate for lower input latency. The Huntsman V2 TKL features doubleshot PBT caps, which are more durable and sturdy to ensure longer life. Another key offering of this keyboard is the detachable USB-C cable, so you won't need to worry about wrapping your cable around when moving. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Persona 5 + Persona 5 Royal: Official Design Works for $57.31</h2></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219528"><div id="219528" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Persona 5 + Persona 5 Royal: Official Design Works</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're a fan of Persona 5, this is the ultimate item for you. This Official Design Works contains 544 pages of artwork across both Persona 5 and Persona 5 Royal. You'll find character illustrations, promotional art, rough concepts, detailed creator commentary, and even an interview with Shigenori Soejima.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Dragon's Dogma 2 for $30</h2></div><div catalogid="c1e24b32-f264-4725-ad01-ca010d75866c" id="218963"><div id="218963" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Dragon's Dogma 2 - PS5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">You can score Capcom's massive RPG for just $30 this weekend at Amazon. We gave the game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragons-dogma-2-review">an 8/10 in our review</a>, stating, "It is a retelling and reimplementation of all of those wonderful ideas from the 2012 cult-classic, including an awesome dynamic world and some of the best combat in the genre that integrates a subtle but amazingly complex physics system."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth for $32.99</h2></div><div catalogid="2ff7d09a-b0a9-4e86-814c-cfc6c610f0de" id="215988"><div id="215988" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth is $32.99 at Woot right now, making this the lowest we've ever seen the RPG. The massive adventure across the planet to track Sephiroth was one of the biggest games of 2024, and it's absolutely a must-play game. A 40+ hour main story awaits, with over 35 side quests available after you clear the story. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Kiki's Delivery Service Film Comic: All-in-One Edition</h2></div><div catalogid="e6885feb-e2cc-4564-8cab-d909366ae6b1" id="217832"><div id="217832" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Kiki's Delivery Service Film Comic: All-in-One Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Studio Ghibli has produced many of the most beloved anime films ever, and Kiki's Delivery Service is a prime example. If you wish to experience this film in a new way, the Kiki's Delivery Service Film Comic: All-in-One Edition is a great way to do so! This hardcover book contains the entire film across 584 pages - perfect for any Ghibli fan.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Resident Evil 3 for $19.93</h2></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219527"><div id="219527" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Resident Evil 3 - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">You can save $10 off the PS5 version of Resident Evil 3 this weekend at Amazon. In <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-3-final-review">our 9/10 review</a>, we wrote, "Resident Evil 3 is a wonderful continuation of Capcom’s latest remake efforts. Although its just-okay multiplayer mode falls short of the bar set by its magnificent single-player campaign, the latter does such a good job at balancing 2020 gameplay and a classic Resident Evil tone that I recommend it without reservations."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii for $49.99</h2></div><div id="218604" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="cfa18f2c-871b-4e5d-b0de-58054ce7acd9"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii - PlayStation 4</h3></p></div><div catalogid="cfa18f2c-871b-4e5d-b0de-58054ce7acd9" id="218605"><div id="218605" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii - Xbox Series X</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest Like a Dragon game stars everyone's favorite ex-yakuza, Goro Majima, on an adventure to sail the seas as a pirate. When Majima wakes up unable to remember anything about himself, he embarks on a quest to regain his memories, and of course, in true Like a Dragon fashion, things get crazy. This is the lowest we've seen this game so far, so be sure to pick up a copy while you can.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Star Wars Outlaws Limited Edition for $29.12</h2></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219526"><div id="219526" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Star Wars Outlaws - Limited Edition (Amazon Exclusive), Xbox Series X</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, Star Wars Outlaws for Xbox Series X is on sale for $29.12 at Amazon. We gave the game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-review">a 7/10 in our review</a>, writing, "Star Wars Outlaws is a fun intergalactic heist adventure with great exploration, but it’s hindered by simple stealth, repetitive combat, and a few too many bugs at launch."</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 27, 2025 8:00 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Elder Scrolls Online rolls out premium feature to all for free but these players are not happy about it]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-online-rolls-out-premium-feature-to-all-for-free-but-these-players-are-not-happy-about-it</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-elder-scrolls-online-rolls-out-premium-feature-to-all-for-free-but-these-players-are-not-happy-about-it.1174929/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-online-rolls-out-premium-feature-to-all-for-free-but-these-players-are-not-happy-about-it<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"So, why exactly are we still paying for stuff?"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/elder-scrolls-online-gold-road-screen.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Zenimax Online Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>While there's been a lot of chatter about <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remake">The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion Remastered</a> <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesda-reveals-the-elder-scrolls-4-obivion-remake-gameplay">since it stealth-dropped earlier in the week</a>, Oblivion isn't the only Elder Scrolls game getting some love this week - The Elder Scrolls Online has confirmed its Scribing system is coming for free to all players.</p>
<p>It's still a little way off - an <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/306130/view/502823294872846628">update</a> on the official Steam page suggests we'll get it sometime in July - but the team wanted to share the news now as Scribing will be available in the Crown Store from Monday for those playing on the test server, whereas previously, it had only been available to those who owned the premium Gold Road chapter.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Oblivion Tips for New Players - How To Make Money in Oblivion Fast and More!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JBiRsqE9xC8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Oblivion Tips for New Players - How To Make Money in Oblivion Fast and More!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JBiRsqE9xC8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/JBiRsqE9xC8?autoplay=1" title="Oblivion Tips for New Players - How To Make Money in Oblivion Fast and More!">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Here's our Zoe with some Oblivion tips for new players.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JBiRsqE9xC8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"Scribing is coming to the base game, free for all players as a claim in the Crown Store, in mid-July with an associated Golden Pursuit! You will see Scribing in the Crown Store on the PTS on Monday as part of this testing," the team announced.</p>
<p>This means the ESO is "not selling Scribing in the Crown Store", and if you missed the associated Golden Pursuit, "you will still be able to claim Scribing from the Crown Store, as this is a permanent move for it to the base game".</p>
<p>"There will be a short window from June to July with the launch of Update 46 and the Gold Road zone moving to ESO Plus and the Crown Store where players who do not currently own Scribing will not be able to purchase/gain access to it," the update concluded.</p>
<p>Not everyone's happy about the news, however, particularly as Bethesda has <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/306130/eventcomments/599650845622061974?snr=1_2108_9__2107&amp;ctp=2#c599650845622072180">confirmed</a> "nothing is planned at this time" to compensate players who've previously paid to access Scribing.</p>
<p>"What about the people who paid for it originally, though?" <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/306130/eventcomments/599650845622061974?snr=1_2108_9__2107#c599650845622070777">asked</a> one player. "Is anything getting added to the chapter for us? It's been less than a year and the new chapter is already getting depreciated."</p>
<p>"I just bought this the other month, do I get a refund?" <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/306130/eventcomments/599650845622061974?snr=1_2108_9__2107&amp;ctp=2#c599650845622071201">questioned</a> another.</p>
<p>In response, a Bethesda rep said: "No, nothing is planned at this time. However, the Scribing Golden Pursuit is rewarding AND equally available to both those who have already invested time into Scribing, and first-time Scribers. In fact, those who have used Scribing over the last year may find some tasks faster and easier to complete."</p>
<p>"So, why exactly are we still paying for stuff?" <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/app/306130/eventcomments/599650845622061974?snr=1_2108_9__2107&amp;ctp=2#c599650845622074789">said</a> one respondent. "Suddenly, everything will be available for free to everyone. First the dungeons are stripped from ESO+, now a system goes free that's not even been part of the game for a full year.</p>
<p>"Free stuff for everyone is great (I 100% support sub classes being free), but stripping all the advantages from paying customers, there's less and less incentive to actually buy anything."</p>
<p>ICYMI, Oblivion Remastered stealth-launched just five days ago, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-has-clocked-up-over-4-million-players-in-less-than-5-days">it's already clocked up over four million players</a>. Remade by port developer Virtuos' Paris studio, in collaboration with Bethesda, this new version is a ground-up remake built in Unreal Engine 5, designed to run at 4K 60fps. Earlier today, however, we reported that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/psa-the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-microsoft-store-update-accidentally-deletes-upscaling-options-from-player-settings">a Microsoft Store patch, released "for a few backend tweaks", has inadvertently impacted UI and graphical settings</a> for some players.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Umamusume: Pretty Derby – English version launches June 26]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/umamusume-pretty-derby-english-version-launches-june-26</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/umamusume-pretty-derby-%E2%80%93-english-version-launches-june-26.1174905/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/umamusume-pretty-derby-english-version-launches-june-26<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Pre-registration begins April 28.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The English version of <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [383 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> horse girls <a title="Genres > Racing [244 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/racing">racing</a> <a title="Genres > Simulation [723 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em>Umamusume: Pretty Derby</em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PC [23,021 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3224770/Umamusume_Pretty_Derby/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, iOS via App Store, and Android via Google Play on June 26, <a title="Companies > Cygames [274 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cyberagent/cygames">Cygames</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/umamusume_eng/status/1916479480308420635" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a>. Pre-registration will start on April 28. <span id="more-961603"></span></p><p><em>Umamusume: Pretty Derby</em> first launched for iOS and Android on February 24, 2021 in Japan. In Japan, PC versions are available via <a title="Companies > DMM Games [80 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/dmm-games">DMM Games</a> Player and Google Play Games.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its Steam page:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Umamusume: Pretty Derby</em> is ready to race! Scout featured trainees and supporters as you navigate the immersive sports life simulation through the game’s in-depth training system and top-of-the-line 3D graphics!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>Umamusume. They are born to run. They inherit otherworldly names, and are inspirited by dreams most dramatic and wonderful. Now, they run ever forward. That, is their destiny. No one knows how the races that lie in their futures will end. Even so, they continue to run, aiming only toward the goal in front of them.</li><li>Each and every one of the runners sports a unique charm. It’s up to you, the trainer, to lead them down the path of victory! You have but one goal—raise your Umamusume to her fullest potential and help turn her greatest dreams into reality. In order to reach these newfound heights, it’s your job to participate in—and win—as many races as possible! Triumph awaits those who train hard and work to communicate. Only by cooperating will you take the crown!</li><li><a title="Companies > Experience [211 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the thrilling stories of historic racers, such as:<ul><li>Special Week (Voice: Azumi Waki)</li><li><a title="Companies > Sile" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sile">Sile</a>nce Suzuka (Voice: Marika Kono)</li><li>Tokai Teio (Voice: Machico)</li><li>Oguri Cap (Voice: Tomoyo Takayanagi)</li><li>Gold Ship (Voice: Hitomi Ueda)</li><li>Vodka (Voice: Ayaka Ohashi)</li><li>Daiwa Scarlet (Voice: Chisa Kimura)</li><li>Mejiro McQueen (Voice: Saori Onishi)</li><li>Symboli Rudolf (Voice: Azusa Tadokoro)</li><li>Rice Shower (Voice: <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ka Iwami)</li><li>Haru Urara (Voice: Yukina Shuto)</li><li>Nice Nature (Voice: Kaori Maeda)</li><li>…and so many more—over 20 Umamusume are searching for a trainer to help them achieve their goals!</li></ul></li><li>Cheer for your favorite Umamusume and immerse yourself in exhilarating races and stunning performances in breathtaking 3D graphics. Up to 18 Umamusume compete in races against each other for first place—watch them go as you tune in to the game’s incredibly realistic live commentary. And of course, stick around after the race to support the victor during a dazzling winning concert! Whether on the racetrack or the stage, raise the roof to each exciting new performance!/blockquote&gt;</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below. Visit the official English website <a href="https://umamusume.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p><h2><span>Official Trailer: Faster Than Anyone</span></h2><p><iframe title="Umamusume: Pretty Derby – Official Trailer | Faster than Anyone" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p2JQAyGlQ6Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle selling faster on PS5 than Steam and Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-selling-faster-on-ps5-than-steam-and-xbox</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-selling-faster-on-ps5-than-steam-and-xbox.1174902/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-selling-faster-on-ps5-than-steam-and-xbox<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>Compared to Steam, MachineGames' first-party game is selling 28% faster on PS5.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Indy-looks-surprised-in-Indiana-Jones-and-the-Great-Circle.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Eurogamer/Bethesda</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> is selling faster on PS5 than it did on Steam and Xbox, with over 100,000 copies sold since its launch last week.</p>
<p>That's according to <a href="https://alineaanalytics.com/blog/indiana_jones_article/">Alinea analyst Rhys Elliott</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/xboxs-indiana-jones-is-selling-fastest-on-ps5-despite-releasing-months-later/">VGC</a>), who quite rightly adds the caveat that the "overwhelming majority" of Xbox players "came in via Game Pass" and therefore didn't need to "buy" the game if they were members of Xbox's subscription service.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Review" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ASn8vBoC0X4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Review</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ASn8vBoC0X4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ASn8vBoC0X4?autoplay=1" title="Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Review">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle Review.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ASn8vBoC0X4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>That said, it's thought that in less than a week, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle has sold 28 percent faster on PS5 than PC, shifting 117.2K copies on PS5 compared with Steam's 91.2K in the same timeframe.</p>
<p>Alinea posits The Great Circle has been played by around five million players on Xbox.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Indiana_image_1.webp?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Alinea Analytics</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-features-detailed">PS5 edition gets a handful of new features over Xbox</a>, including DualSense compatibility, which gives you a visual indicator if enemies are on the lookout for Indy. Performance wise, Indiana Jones and the Great Circle "benefits from frictionless loading", as well as "selective installation that prioritises your system language, and SSD optimisation, ensuring a seamless experience with faster streaming and loading".</p>
<p>The game also included a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/topics/ps5-pro">PS5 Pro</a> enhanced label on its release, which gives users higher and more consistent framerates when playing, as well as better image clarity thanks to its native 4K resolution and advanced ray tracing.</p>
<p>We awarded Indiana Jones and the Great Circle five stars on its release. "Indiana Jones really feels like he comes full circle (sorry) in this latest adventure. At long last, there's an Indy game that nails both the puzzles and the kind of action we know so well from the films, and it does so with wit, charm, and a real eye for spectacle," Katharine Castle wrote in <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review">Eurogamer's Indiana Jones and the Great Circle review</a>.</p>
<p>"Indiana Jones and the Great Circle makes a successful leap on to PS5 platforms and despite its delayed release, everything we loved about the Xbox experience is intact," Digital Foundry's Thomas wrote in his review of the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2025-indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-on-ps5-excellent-game-solid-port">PS5 Indiana Jones and the Great Circle port</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Long Dark's final episode is "largest to date" with "two to three times as much cinematic and story content"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/the-long-darks-final-episode-is-largest-to-date-with-two-to-three-times-as-much-cinematic-and-story-content</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-long-darks-final-episode-is-largest-to-date-with-two-to-three-times-as-much-cinematic-and-story-content.1174896/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/the-long-darks-final-episode-is-largest-to-date-with-two-to-three-times-as-much-cinematic-and-story-content<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"The episode can't just be good; it has to be great."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/d5ed527c982908195f4be4fe8ccb707b0388561c.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Hinterland</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>The Long Dark's final episode, Episode Five, is the "largest episode to date", featuring "between two to three times as much cinematic and story content" as preceding episode Four and about "three-to-four times as big".</p>
<p>Addressing fans in a lengthy <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/305620/view/512956388211687524?l=english">Steam update</a>, Hinterland founder and creative director, Raphael van Lierop said the team "won't be sharing much detail about the episode until he first teaser", but it includes "quite a few systems we haven't used in other episodes".</p>
<p>"We know many of you - like us - have been waiting for years for this story to be completed. And once it's done, we can never go back. So that's really on our minds. The episode can't just be good; it has to be great," van Lierop added.</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="The Long Dark 2: Blackfrost World Premiere Trailer from The Game Awards 2024" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NIAiNhlghY4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>The Long Dark 2: Blackfrost World Premiere Trailer from The Game Awards 2024</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NIAiNhlghY4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NIAiNhlghY4?autoplay=1" title="The Long Dark 2: Blackfrost World Premiere Trailer from The Game Awards 2024">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Blackfrost: The Long Dark 2 announcement trailer.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NIAiNhlghY4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"There are a lot of story threads to tie up across all the episodes, to wrap up the Wintermute storyline, but also to set the stage for the future of The Long Dark, so we have to take you to several different places and hear from a lot of new people," the director added (thanks, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/305620/view/512956388211687524?l=english">PC Gamer</a>). "Because of what the story needs, we've focused on narrative more than we have traditionally, and the mission flow for Episode Five is probably more linear than previous episodes as a result."</p>
<p>There will be "many" new locations - "everything in the episode is new to the game and the world, so these will all be places you’ve never seen before" - and as "this final episode of the story has you playing as both Mackenzie and Astrid, you'll also be seeing some of the key characters from previous episodes, so...there's a lot!"</p>
<p>"We're also using new motion-capture tech for our team, to attempt to deliver an ever higher bar for story delivery than we have achieved so far," he added. "These are all things that exist outside the context of Survival Mode, although some of the work in Tales helped set the foundation of some of the things we're attempting in Episode Five.</p>
<p>"I can confidently say that Episode Five will be the most ambitious thing we've done on The Long Dark at Hinterland to date. I know that won't mean much to you until you have it in your hands, but hopefully that gives you some sense of the ambition behind the episode."</p>
<p>The update also confirmed that Tales from the Far Territory expansion is now complete, further visual enhancements are being trialled with the test team, with improvements to shadows, fog, anisotropic filtering, enhanced draw distances, terrain blending, motion blur, and more on the way, albeit "mainly apply to high-end PCs or the top-end consoles".</p>
<p>There'll also be an update for PlayStation and Xbox players in mid-late June.</p>
<p>Nearly a year after <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-long-dark-dev-teases-unannounced-survival-game-that-might-just-be-the-long-dark-2">teasing</a> an 'unannounced survival game' that looked suspiciously like <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-long-dark">The Long Dark</a> 2, developer Hinterland's has officially unveiled its snowy survival sequel. It's called <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/snowy-survival-game-the-long-dark-is-heading-to-the-city-in-sequel-blackfrost">Blackfrost: The Long Dark 2 and it's coming to Steam early access in 2026</a>.</p>
<p>While our first tease of The Long Dark 2 in January didn't go much beyond a slow pan across a slightly ramshackle room, Hinterland's The Game Awards <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NIAiNhlghY4">announcement trailer</a> shows considerably more, with the wilderness action of its predecessor now expanded to cover towns and even cities gripped by the apocalyptic winter.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 sales top one million]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-top-one-million</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-top-one-million.1174875/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-top-one-million<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Another major milestone achieved.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Total sales for <a title="Genres > Turn-Based RPG [1,161 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/turn-based-rpg">turn-based RPG</a> <em><a title="Games > Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a></em> have surpassed one million units in just three days after release, publisher <a title="Companies > Kepler Interactive [50 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/kepler-interactive">Kepler Interactive</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Sandfall Interactive [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sandfall-interactive">Sandfall Interactive</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/expedition33/status/1916409440011444331" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-961593"></span></p><p><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em> launched for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [9,356 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [7,114 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [23,021 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1903340" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/expedition-33-b3240d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> on April 24. It is also available via Game Pass.</p><p>The game <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2025/04/clair-obscur-expedition-33-sales-top-500000">sold 500,000 units</a> just one day after its release.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Kepler Interactive:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Lead the members of Expedition 33 on their quest to destroy the Paintress so that she can never paint death again. Explore a world of wonders inspired by Belle Époque France and battle unique enemies in this turn-based RPG with real-time mechanics.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Year by Year, She Erases Us</strong></p><p>Once a year, the Paintress wakes and paints upon her monolith. Paints her cursed number. And everyone of that age turns to smoke and fades away. Year by year, that number ticks down and more of us are erased. Tomorrow she’ll wake and paint “33.” And tomorrow we depart on our final mission: Destroy the Paintress, so she can never paint death again. We are Expedition 33.</p><p><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em> is a ground-breaking turn-based RPG with unique real-time mechanics, making battles more immersive and addictive than ever. Explore a fantasy world inspired by Belle Époque France in which you battle devastating enemies.</p><p><strong>Reactive Turn-Based Combat</strong></p><p>In this evolution of <a title="Genres > JRPG [1,618 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/jrpg">JRPGs</a>, real-time <a title="Genres > Action [2,702 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a>s enhance the heart of turn-based combat. Craft unique builds for your Expeditioners that fit your playstyle via gear, stats, skills, and character synergies. Open an active dimension in combat—dodge, parry, and counter in real time, chain combos by mastering attack rhythms, and target enemy weak points using a free aim system.</p><p><strong>Tomorrow Comes</strong></p><p>With only one year left to live, join <a title="Companies > Gust [807 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games/gust">Gust</a>ave, Maelle, and their fellow Expeditioners as they embark upon a desperate quest to break the Paintress’ cycle of death. Follow the trail of previous expeditions and discover their fate. Get to know the members of Expedition 33 as they learn to work together against impossible odds.</p><p><strong>A Hauntingly Beautiful World</strong></p><p>Explore an enchanting realm populated by surreal adversaries. Wander through breathtaking landscapes, from the Island of Visages to the Forgotten Battlefield, discovering secrets and hidden quests along the way. Find allies of fortune in creatures of legend and recruit special companions, access new travel methods and discover secret areas in the World Map.</p><p>Experience the debut game from Sandfall Interactive, fully realized in Unreal Engine 5 with stunning graphics and a heartbreaking soundtrack.</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout creator says he was "ordered to destroy" source code that the studio has since "lost"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-creator-says-he-was-ordered-to-destroy-source-code-that-the-studio-has-since-lost</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-creator-says-he-was-ordered-to-destroy-source-code-that-the-studio-has-since-lost.1174854/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-creator-says-he-was-ordered-to-destroy-source-code-that-the-studio-has-since-lost<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"I had that in digital form and was ordered to destroy it."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fallout-og.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Black Isle Studios/Bethesda</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Fallout creator Tim Cain has revealed that he was "ordered to destroy" all of his notes, code, and prototypes from his days at Fallout's original developer and publisher, Interplay, and as a result, no original source code or assets remain.</p>
<p>Making the admission on a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=F707wIeTX2g">new YouTube video</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/fallout/fallout-creator-tim-cain-says-he-was-ordered-to-destroy-his-personal-archive-of-the-rpgs-development-individuals-and-organizations-actively-work-against-preservation/">GR+</a>), Cain explained that he was told to destroy everything after he left the Fallout studio, having been told that the studio would "be the archive keeper".</p>
<p>Cain later learned, however, that it "lost it".</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="How To Build Lucy, The Ghoul, and Maximus in Fallout 4" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kbvXnjr14c8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>How To Build Lucy, The Ghoul, and Maximus in Fallout 4</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kbvXnjr14c8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kbvXnjr14c8?autoplay=1" title="How To Build Lucy, The Ghoul, and Maximus in Fallout 4">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>How To Build Lucy, The Ghoul, and Maximus in Fallout 4.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kbvXnjr14c8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"There's a lot of organisations out there that demand to be the archive keeper, and then they do a terrible job at it," Cain said. "They lose the assets they were in charge of keeping. This has happened multiple times in my career.</p>
<p>"When I left Fallout, I was told 'you have to destroy everything you have', and I did. My entire archive. Early design notes, code for different versions, prototypes, all the GURPS code – gone.</p>
<p>"When they finally, a few years after I left, contacted me and said 'oops, we lost it' I thought they were trapping me into 'we're going to sue you if you say you have it.' Turns out, no, they really lost it."</p>
<p>Cain said the experience shows why programs like <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/gog-announces-preservation-program-aims-to-maintain-game-compatibility-with-modern-and-future-systems">GOG's preservation work</a> are so important.</p>
<p>"Individuals and organisations actively work against preservation," Cain added. "The amount of stuff that's been lost about Fallout and its early development saddens me. I had it. I had that in digital form and was ordered to destroy it.</p>
<p>"So many other games that came out in the '70s, and '80s and '90s - the code is gone. The art assets are gone. Sure, you can try to crack open the databases and pull out those things, but you're only getting the final stuff. You're not getting the original source code or art[work]. I think it's even happening for the '00s and the '10s and probably now in the '20s. Stuff is being lost."</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-creator-tim-cain-is-a-big-fan-of-the-tv-show">Cain has plenty of praise for Amazon's TV adaptation</a>, saying of the show: "They had huge sets with amazing production values on them... Amazing props. The acting was phenomenal. It was just surreal to watch Fallout recreated in real life like that."</p>
<p>In related Bethesda news, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remake">The Elder Scrolls 4: Oblivion Remastered</a> stealth-dropped just five days ago, but <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/the-elder-scrolls-4-oblivion-remastered-has-clocked-up-over-4-million-players-in-less-than-5-days">it's already clocked up over four million players</a> and<a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/theres-already-almost-100-mods-for-oblivion-remake-even-without-official-support-from-bethesda"> already has over 100 mods available for it</a>, even though <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bethesda-say-no-official-mod-support-for-its-oblivion-remaster">Bethesda said it won't offer any official mod support</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get Started Strong In Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 And The Oblivion Remaster]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-beginner-tips-oblivion-1851777870</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/get-started-strong-in-clair-obscur-expedition-33-and-the-oblivion-remaster.1174818/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-beginner-tips-oblivion-1851777870<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="cfd38382c3ad572b059dd6d94e1a2004" data-recommend-id="image://cfd38382c3ad572b059dd6d94e1a2004" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="in-house-art" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sandfall Interactive / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Sandfall Interactive<!-- -->, <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Ubisoft / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Bethesda / Brandon Morgan / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Sandfall Interactive<!-- -->, <!-- -->Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo / Kotaku<!-- -->, <!-- -->Bethesda<!-- -->, <!-- -->Marvel Games</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="cfd38382c3ad572b059dd6d94e1a2004" data-recommend-id="image://cfd38382c3ad572b059dd6d94e1a2004" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>This week saw the release of both <em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 </em>and <em>The Elder Scrolls IV: Oblivion Remastered</em>, and we’ve got tips for getting you started on the right foot regardless of which one you might be playing. We’ll also help you master the meta for <em>Marvel Rivals </em>season 2 and make the most of your hideout in <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows.</em></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="79fe2026a8dc711cfca2f19f6cf16eaf" data-recommend-id="image://79fe2026a8dc711cfca2f19f6cf16eaf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Gustave looks up as petals fall around him." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Gustave looks up as petals fall around him." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sandfall Interactive / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="79fe2026a8dc711cfca2f19f6cf16eaf" data-recommend-id="image://79fe2026a8dc711cfca2f19f6cf16eaf" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Gustave looks up as petals fall around him." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-rpg-review-in-progress-1851777402&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-rpg-review-in-progress-1851777402"><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a></span><em> </em>has a lot of moving parts in its turn-based battle system. Though the RPG does a decent job of introducing things to you slowly, by the time you have a full party, you’re juggling pretty distinct characters with bespoke playstyles and trying to find some way to make them fit together. Part of the fun is experimenting with different characters, ability sets, and combos to find what works best for you, so I won’t try to influence your playstyle too much. Still, I do have a few early game tips to help you on your expedition. - Kenneth Shepard <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-tips-pictos-stains-stances-1851777496&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-tips-pictos-stains-stances-1851777496">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="f9483cd8eae4816d289bbc58fae29b47" data-recommend-id="image://f9483cd8eae4816d289bbc58fae29b47" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A character attacks a monster with magical cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A character attacks a monster with magical cards." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sandfall Interactive</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f9483cd8eae4816d289bbc58fae29b47" data-recommend-id="image://f9483cd8eae4816d289bbc58fae29b47" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A character attacks a monster with magical cards." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>If you’ve been itching for an RPG that mixes old-school turn-based combat with a penchant for modern flair, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-rpg-review-in-progress-1851777402&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-rpg-review-in-progress-1851777402"><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em></a></span> is probably on your radar. Considering its stunning art style, immersive and rewarding combat system, and genuinely compelling narrative, it’s hard to blame you for being interested.  - Billy Givens <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-how-long-to-beat-1851777481&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-how-long-to-beat-1851777481">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="c125c5f8ba2225eea9295f62787c095b" data-recommend-id="image://c125c5f8ba2225eea9295f62787c095b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows the player character chatting with an NPC." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows the player character chatting with an NPC." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c125c5f8ba2225eea9295f62787c095b" data-recommend-id="image://c125c5f8ba2225eea9295f62787c095b" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A screenshot shows the player character chatting with an NPC." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The world of <em>Oblivion Remastered</em> allows for a lot of leeway in how you approach situations, whether you’re sneaking by guards, sword fighting like a swashbuckler, slinging magic spells, or, perhaps, talking your way out of situations. The latter often proves the most challenging for one reason: the persuasion minigame. It can be an absolute pain—unless you have a ton of gold to bribe every character. But worry not; we’re here to help! Here’s how the persuasion minigame in <em>Oblivion Remastered</em> works! - Brandon Morgan <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-persuasion-mini-game-wheel-npc-1851777514&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-persuasion-mini-game-wheel-npc-1851777514">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="bfcf0d12bd301c235a90181216340e2d" data-recommend-id="image://bfcf0d12bd301c235a90181216340e2d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The hideout entrance in Assassin’s Creed Shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The hideout entrance in Assassin’s Creed Shadows." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Ubisoft / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bfcf0d12bd301c235a90181216340e2d" data-recommend-id="image://bfcf0d12bd301c235a90181216340e2d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The hideout entrance in Assassin’s Creed Shadows." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Recent titles in the <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> franchise offered something extra besides stealthy assassinations and roaming exploration. In between stabby murders, you could expand a base. <em>Valhalla</em> had a settlement you could expandand now in <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> introduces a hideout you can <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-hideout-customization-unlock-1851772163&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-hideout-customization-unlock-1851772163">customize to your liking</a></span>. It’s a fun way to earn a sense of belonging within the game world while taking advantage of unique buffs. You won’t spend too much time at your hideout, but learning how to upgrade it in <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> is still a welcome reprieve! - Brandon Morgan <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-best-hideout-upgrades-1851777321&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/assassins-creed-shadows-best-hideout-upgrades-1851777321">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="9939c0916b38b0cd58fc2187430fe83c" data-recommend-id="image://9939c0916b38b0cd58fc2187430fe83c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1917" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="An official screenshot overlooking the Imperial City in Oblivion Remastered." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An official screenshot overlooking the Imperial City in Oblivion Remastered." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="9939c0916b38b0cd58fc2187430fe83c" data-recommend-id="image://9939c0916b38b0cd58fc2187430fe83c" data-format="jpg" data-width="1917" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="An official screenshot overlooking the Imperial City in Oblivion Remastered." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The moment you exit the sewers in <em>Oblivion Remastered</em>, you’re greeted by a sprawling open world filled with unique points of interest, enemies that want to do you harm, and quests that take place inside of paintings, task you with delving into dungeons, or send you on murderous missions. It’s a lot to sort through for a new player. To help you gain your footing, we’ve compiled a few tips on what to do first in <em>Oblivion Remastered</em>! - Brandon Morgan <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-starting-tips-guild-arena-potions-1851777734&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-starting-tips-guild-arena-potions-1851777734">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="4898379614d43fc629b2154a6450f8b9" data-recommend-id="image://4898379614d43fc629b2154a6450f8b9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A row of Mr. Fantastic's dressed up in a fancy suit stretches back into a cave." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A row of Mr. Fantastic's dressed up in a fancy suit stretches back into a cave." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Marvel Games</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="4898379614d43fc629b2154a6450f8b9" data-recommend-id="image://4898379614d43fc629b2154a6450f8b9" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A row of Mr. Fantastic's dressed up in a fancy suit stretches back into a cave." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>Season 2 of <em>Marvel Rivals </em>is here, and there are quite a few balance changes and additions to mark its arrival. A new battle pass, the Flower of Krakoa, is here alongside an incredible new character, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-emma-frost-psionic-seduction-season-2-1851775737&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-emma-frost-psionic-seduction-season-2-1851775737">Emma Frost</a></span>. Let’s go over what’s changed in the meta for this wildly popular superhero shooter. - Brian Barnett <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-season-2-changes-rocket-raccoon-emma-fros-1851777338&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/marvel-rivals-season-2-changes-rocket-raccoon-emma-fros-1851777338">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="7e02355d3866e3f1f8c160ae756beaba" data-recommend-id="image://7e02355d3866e3f1f8c160ae756beaba" data-format="jpg" data-width="1408" data-height="792" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="An early-game mount, the Armored Nag, in Oblivion Remastered." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="An early-game mount, the Armored Nag, in Oblivion Remastered." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Bethesda / Brandon Morgan / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="7e02355d3866e3f1f8c160ae756beaba" data-recommend-id="image://7e02355d3866e3f1f8c160ae756beaba" data-format="jpg" data-width="1408" data-height="792" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="An early-game mount, the Armored Nag, in Oblivion Remastered." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>The world of <em>Oblivion Remastered</em> features one of the greatest fantasy adventures in gaming. But with a world of this size, how does one traverse vast expanses of land without succumbing to goblins and bandits along every twist and turn? Fast travel is nice, but then you miss out on all the lush detail added into this new version of the game. It’s tough, but a fully armored and highly nimble mount should do the trick! Here’s how to get your first horse in Oblivion to make travel a bit more luxurious! - Brandon Morgan <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-horse-armor-free-stables-how-to-get-1851777703&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/oblivion-remastered-horse-armor-free-stables-how-to-get-1851777703">Read More</a></span></p></div><div><div data-video-id="197544" data-monetizable="true" data-position="kinjavideo" data-video-title="4 Essential Tips to Survive Clair Obscur: Expedition 33’s Brutal First Hours" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="180" data-playlist="197544" data-current="197544" id="197544"><div><p>4 Essential Tips to Survive Clair Obscur: Expedition 33’s Brutal First Hours</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" playsinline="" poster="https://no.kinja-img.com/image/upload/c_fill,h_542,pg_1,q_60,w_965/197xrjaz7466rpng.png" data-poster="https://no.kinja-img.com/image/upload/c_fill,h_542,pg_1,q_60,w_965/f8674eda1cf6977b771b769ad2014473.png" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197544/197544_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197544/197544_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197544/197544_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/23069.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><p><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em> is a (mostly) traditional turn-based role-playing game and your first few hours are pretty important</p></div><div><figure id="" data-id="e2f40163eb8ef564310cae4b18fd6d56" data-recommend-id="image://e2f40163eb8ef564310cae4b18fd6d56" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Gustave looks off camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Gustave looks off camera." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Sandfall Interactive</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e2f40163eb8ef564310cae4b18fd6d56" data-recommend-id="image://e2f40163eb8ef564310cae4b18fd6d56" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="Gustave looks off camera." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em> is a deep and lengthy role-playing adventure with multiple characters, each with skill trees to flesh out. So, of course, as you advance through the game and unlock new skills, you’ll find that you can optimize your characters’ synergy with one another.  - Billy Givens <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-skills-gustave-lune-maelle-1851777515&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-skills-gustave-lune-maelle-1851777515">Read More</a></span></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloodlines 2 Dialogues Are Maze-like to Avoid People Beelining for the Good Choices]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bloodlines-2-dialogues-are-maze-like-to-avoid-people-beelining-for-good-choices/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloodlines-2-dialogues-are-maze-like-to-avoid-people-beelining-for-the-good-choices.1174809/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/bloodlines-2-dialogues-are-maze-like-to-avoid-people-beelining-for-good-choices/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Now that Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2 <a href="https://wccftech.com/bloodlines-2-to-launch-in-october-game-is-done-with-only-polishing-left/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">has a firm release window of October 2025</a>, new developer The Chinese Room (which <a href="https://wccftech.com/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-comes-fall-2024-developed-by-the-chinese-room/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">replaced</a> Hardsuit Labs a few years ago) has discussed the long-awaited role-playing game sequel in an exclusive interview that appeared in the <a href="https://fave.co/42tOSlw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">latest issue of PC Gamer magazine</a>.</p>
<p>Speaking of the game's dialogues, Game Director Alex Skidmore emphasized that they will feel like a maze, partly to avoid people just heading straight toward the standard good choice options.</p>
<p><em>We ultimately want narrative exploration, so each of those dialogue trees is a kind of maze. So we didn’t want people to sort of switch off and go, ‘I’m looking for the good choice, or the Paragon choice’. Because the moment you do that, you’re always going to press top right or whatever.</em></p>
<p>Even though this new iteration of Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2 will put players in the role of an Elder vampire called <a href="https://wccftech.com/phyres-role-in-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-explained-in-latest-developer-diary/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Phyre</a> (rather than the newly created Thinblood originally imagined by Hardsuit Labs), The Chinese Room made sure to leave plenty of room for players to interpret the character however they want. Narrative Director Ian Thomas explained:</p>
<p><em>We’re deliberately leaving space for the player. If we went, ‘Here is your character, they’re like this, they have done this, all of these things,’ actually, in a way, it’s not important that they know all that backstory – at least to start with, because we are dumping them into a new and unfamiliar situation.</em></p>
<p><em>How we show the status of the character is in other people’s reactions to that character. And so, rather than saying at the beginning, you’re a legend, we build that by people’s reactions to you. Then there’s the power level, which I think would show pretty heavily very early on. The first time you accidentally punch a guy across a room, which I think is very different from the start of Bloodlines 1.</em></p>
<p>At the start of the game, Phyre, who is waking up after a long slumber, is bound and stripped of most of their Elder powers. However, even in this state, they're still a force to be reckoned with. Lead Sound Designer Tessa Verplancke adds:</p>
<p><em>They’re much more quiet. Their foley doesn’t make as much noise because even without their powers, even when they’re nerfed, they’re way more silent than all the rest of them. You can feel how strong and powerful they are. Even if you can’t use all of their powers, when they’re climbing up things, they don’t even need to have a little exertion when they do it. So even in their movements, they’ve been made to be more powerful audibly, and you can subtly tell that nothing is really difficult for you.</em></p>
<p>We expect to learn much more about Bloodlines 2 over the next five months or so. Stay tuned for more info.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33’s battles are best when you break them]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/656552/clair-obscur-expedition-33-battles</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33%E2%80%99s-battles-are-best-when-you-break-them.1174806/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/games/656552/clair-obscur-expedition-33-battles<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</em> has flashy, thrilling battles, but the best thing about them is how you can twist the game’s many systems to your advantage. The turn-based RPG combat might feel familiar, but it offers a lot of ways to customize your approach to battles so that you can do absolutely devastating amounts of damage.</p><p>In <em>Expedition 33,</em> you play as a group of Expeditioners who aim to destroy The Paintress, a mysterious being that erases everyone of a certain age every year. In battles, you can have up to three of your party participating in a fight, and should they all die, you can call in your teammates who are in reserve to try and finish off the enemies. </p><p>To show you how deep the rabbit hole can go in customizing your team, here’s my approach to building out just one character, the fencer Maelle. Every character can equip three “Pictos,” which offer passive buffs like giving you the defense-boosting Shell status at the start of a fight. But after you win a few fights with a Pictos equipped, other characters can <em>also</em> equip the Pictos as a “Lumina” by using “Lumina Points,” which you accumulate through leveling up and by using a resource you can find in the game.</p><div><p><cite>Image: Kepler Interactive</cite></p></div><p>When you mix and match Pictos and Luminas to stack complimentary bonuses, things really get going. For my version of Maelle, I set a combination of Pictos and Luminas that could let her deal potentially enormous amounts of damage, especially if a lucky critical hit and a coin-flip 200 percent damage buff went through. But as a counterbalance to Maelle’s huge power, some of the Pictos and Luminas also increased the amount of damage she <em>received</em>, so I added defensive ones that helped her better withstand hits.</p><p>In battle, each character also has a unique mechanic that, when used properly, lets you make their attacks more effective. Maelle, for example, relies on different “stances” that you can shift into: an offensive stance that increases the damage you give but also the damage you receive, a defensive stance that reduces the damage you take, and a “virtuous” stance that does 200 percent damage but can be harder to set up.</p><p>With Maelle, you can move into the different stances based on which of your six different “skills” you use in battle — and like with Pictos and Luminas, those are also customizable and have their own traits and potential synergies. </p><p>It can be a lot to manage, and the game often helps in battles by adding a little sparkle to suggest a move for your current situation. But even within the first few hours of the game, I was able to grasp the potential of what was possible with the battle system. And with Maelle, when I nailed the combination of setting up the right stance and a lucky break from my Pictos and Luminas, I regularly could absolutely demolish my foes by dealing thousands of points of damage. (A late-game Pictos that let me exceed 9,999 points of damage in a single hit was particularly welcome.)</p><p>That’s just my approach with one character; each of the other party members has their own playstyles to experiment with and potential skills to use. Your equipped weapons are an element to consider, too. The game shines when everyone’s abilities and skills line up perfectly for a series of explosive hits, and it’s especially satisfying when things come together to melt down a tricky boss’s health bar.</p><p>I definitely didn’t use <em>Expedition 33</em>’s battle system, which makes things easy to experiment with, to its fullest. Once I found a combination of characters and skills that I liked, I rarely deviated from them. But I have lots of ideas on how to try things differently for a hard mode run — I’m sure there are a lot more ways to absolutely break the game.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloodlines 2 Dialogues Are Maze-like to Avoid People Beelining for the Good Choices]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/review/bloodlines-2-dialogues-are-maze-like-to-avoid-people-beelining-for-the-good-choices/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloodlines-2-dialogues-are-maze-like-to-avoid-people-beelining-for-the-good-choices.1174773/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/review/bloodlines-2-dialogues-are-maze-like-to-avoid-people-beelining-for-the-good-choices/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Now that Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2 <a href="https://wccftech.com/bloodlines-2-to-launch-in-october-game-is-done-with-only-polishing-left/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">has a firm release window of October 2025</a>, new developer The Chinese Room (which <a href="https://wccftech.com/vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-comes-fall-2024-developed-by-the-chinese-room/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">replaced</a> Hardsuit Labs a few years ago) has discussed the long-awaited role-playing game sequel in an exclusive interview that appeared in the <a href="https://fave.co/42tOSlw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">latest issue of PC Gamer magazine</a>.</p>
<p>Speaking of the game's dialogues, Game Director Alex Skidmore emphasized that they will feel like a maze, partly to avoid people just heading straight toward the standard good choice options.</p>
<p><em>We ultimately want narrative exploration, so each of those dialogue trees is a kind of maze. So we didn’t want people to sort of switch off and go, ‘I’m looking for the good choice, or the Paragon choice’. Because the moment you do that, you’re always going to press top right or whatever.</em></p>
<p>Even though this new iteration of Vampire: The Masquerade - Bloodlines 2 will put players in the role of an Elder vampire called <a href="https://wccftech.com/phyres-role-in-vampire-the-masquerade-bloodlines-2-explained-in-latest-developer-diary/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Phyre</a> (rather than the newly created Thinblood originally imagined by Hardsuit Labs), The Chinese Room made sure to leave plenty of room for players to interpret the character however they want. Narrative Director Ian Thomas explained:</p>
<p><em>We’re deliberately leaving space for the player. If we went, ‘Here is your character, they’re like this, they have done this, all of these things,’ actually, in a way, it’s not important that they know all that backstory – at least to start with, because we are dumping them into a new and unfamiliar situation.</em></p>
<p><em>How we show the status of the character is in other people’s reactions to that character. And so, rather than saying at the beginning, you’re a legend, we build that by people’s reactions to you. Then there’s the power level, which I think would show pretty heavily very early on. The first time you accidentally punch a guy across a room, which I think is very different from the start of Bloodlines 1.</em></p>
<p>At the start of the game, Phyre, who is waking up after a long slumber, is bound and stripped of most of their Elder powers. However, even in this state, they're still a force to be reckoned with. Lead Sound Designer Tessa Verplancke adds:</p>
<p><em>They’re much more quiet. Their foley doesn’t make as much noise because even without their powers, even when they’re nerfed, they’re way more silent than all the rest of them. You can feel how strong and powerful they are. Even if you can’t use all of their powers, when they’re climbing up things, they don’t even need to have a little exertion when they do it. So even in their movements, they’ve been made to be more powerful audibly, and you can subtly tell that nothing is really difficult for you.</em></p>
<p>We expect to learn much more about Bloodlines 2 over the next five months or so. Stay tuned for more info.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon release date set for May 23rd]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/27/tainted-grail-the-fall-of-avalon-release-date-may-23rd/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tainted-grail-the-fall-of-avalon-release-date-set-for-may-23rd.1174758/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/04/27/tainted-grail-the-fall-of-avalon-release-date-may-23rd/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Publisher Awaken Realms has announced that Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon, the follow up to Tainted Grail: Conquest, will be getting its full 1.0 release on May 23rd. The game will be available on PC, PS5, and Xbox Series XS. If you are unfamiliar with Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon, it is an open world fantasy action RPG with a branching storyline.</p>
<p><iframe title="Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon - Release Date Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/utDgF27366E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon will have three regions open to exploration including the Misty Horns of the South, the sun drenched Cuanacht, and the wintry Forlorn Swords. Across these three regions there will be over 200 side quests, more than 250 individual non playable characters, over 400 weapons and shields to equip yourself with, an inventory of over 50 spells, dozens of dungeons to explore, more than 100 enemy types, and the main quest will apparently have hundreds of endings based upon your actions and decisions. Another big addition for the full release of Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon will be the inclusion of a third person perspective, where before the game was going to be a solely first person perspective title.</p>
<p>Awaken Realms has also stated that applications are now open to help test the 1.0 build of Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon, and if you are interested you have to fill the <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScZHEbudX-V0ZE50XFt7nCfT1I8mXRgni95Ny8QAZ9repB_nA/viewform">Tainted Grail: The Fall of Avalon 1.0 version playtest</a> form. If your application is successful you will gain access to the main release of the game, though some content will still be missing, and an exclusive Discord channel to provide feedback directly to the development team.</p>

<h2><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/06/02/tainted-grail-conquest-review/">Tainted Grail: Conquest Review</a></h2>
<p>In our Tainted Grail: Conquest review, Jason said, <em>“Any game so good that you can’t resist doing just one more battle in is a game well worth paying attention to, and Tainted Grail definitely manages that.”</em></p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=utDgF27366E">YouTube</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A PS1 kei truck, jungle beats, and an eery vibe combine to make Easy Delivery Co., a game where there's "definitely no secrets"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-ps1-kei-truck-jungle-beats-and-an-eery-vibe-combine-to-make-easy-delivery-co-a-game-where-theres-definitely-no-secrets</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-ps1-kei-truck-jungle-beats-and-an-eery-vibe-combine-to-make-easy-delivery-co-a-game-where-theres-definitely-no-secrets.1174671/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-ps1-kei-truck-jungle-beats-and-an-eery-vibe-combine-to-make-easy-delivery-co-a-game-where-theres-definitely-no-secrets<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
There isn't a huge list of things that'll immediately sell me on your game, but there is one that'll draw me in without fail pretty much every single time: you can drive around in a kei truck. Now, admittedly, there are very few games where you can actually do this, the delightful <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/promise-mascot-agency">Promise Mascot Agency</a> being the most recent one. There's the yet to be released <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2961860/Honcho/">Honcho</a> from the devs behind <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/landlords-super">Landlord's Super</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/jalopy">Jalopy</a>, you can bet your bottom dollar I'll be playing that one. And now, there's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/easy-delivery-co">Easy Delivery Co.</a>, a game with a kei truck that isn't exactly what it says on the tin.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
In Easy Delivery Co., you are an <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/animal-crossing">Animal Crossing</a> by way of PS1 game-esque cat character, who drives around a kei truck in a snowy mountainside town delivering different things. That indie PS1 aesthetic can obviously feel a bit overdone in some cases now, but Easy Delivery Co. just looks right, a bit dreary, a bit lonely even, yet with a hint of goofiness about it. Good stuff!
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Easy Delivery Co. | Official Reveal Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_hTyizqcLV8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Easy Delivery Co. | Official Reveal Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_hTyizqcLV8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_hTyizqcLV8?autoplay=1" title="Easy Delivery Co. | Official Reveal Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_hTyizqcLV8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>
The game's Steam page notes that there's "definitely no secrets", which between you and me I think might just be a lie. Apparently the soundtrack is made up of lo-fi, drum 'n' bass, and jungle tracks, a real late '90s, early 2000s arcade racer vibe it seems. Oh, and there's a four-player split-screen co-op <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-racing-games">racing</a> mode too? Dang, this game was just made to be played on a CRT, something I'll be doing as soon as I'm able to.
</p>
<p>
According to a press release developer Sam C is inspired by games like Animal Crossing, but also <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-long-dark">The Long Dark</a>, a pairing of games I would never think to make in my life, except here I am craving just that. No release date in sight for Easy Delivery Co. bar "later this year", so in the meantime you can <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3293010/Easy_Delivery_Co/">wishlist it on Steam here</a>, and check out its demo too!

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Square Enix if that Nier Reincarnation thing you're teasing isn't a port I won't be your friend any more]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/square-enix-if-that-nier-reincarnation-thing-youre-teasing-isnt-a-port-i-wont-be-your-friend-any-more</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/square-enix-if-that-nier-reincarnation-thing-youre-teasing-isnt-a-port-i-wont-be-your-friend-any-more.1174659/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/square-enix-if-that-nier-reincarnation-thing-youre-teasing-isnt-a-port-i-wont-be-your-friend-any-more<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Seriously, I mean it this time</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nier-reincarnation.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=70&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Square Enix</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I'm sure like me, some of you would really like another <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/nier">Nier</a> game. A Nier 3, if you will, except I won't, because it already came out and it was called <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/nier-reincarnation">Nier Reincarnation</a>. Unfortunately it was also a free-to-play mobile game, and as most mobile games are destined for, it shut down last year rendering it completely unplayable. Nier celebrated its 15th anniversary this year, so far with no big announcements, though there is a new website that's slowly sharing bits of a special novel. And curiously enough, it appears to be teasing something Nier Reincarnation related.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
As spotted by <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/thewillarowe.bsky.social/post/3lnnoessmzk2k">journalist Willa Rowe</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/square-enix-is-teasing-something-nier-related-again-in-a-cryptic-website-update">IGN</a>), the website is doing something a bit odd. At the end of the <a href="https://www.jp.square-enix.com/nier-anniversary/15th-novel/e58f8b/space/">most recently released chapter</a>, there's some kind of computer log, a cryptic bit of text that specifically references the official Japanese website for Nier Reincarnation. In fact the specific wording leading up to the link to said website says "recovery protocol initialised."
</p>
<p>
There's even some lore stuff teased when you right click and view page source, referencing characters called Her and Him that appeared in Reincarnation, as well as a reference to The Cage, the main setting of the game. It's all a bit odd, suitably Yoko Taro, and of course has me and everyone else hoping that this is suggesting some kind of Nier Reincarnation re-release/ port is on the way.
</p>
<p>
Here's the thing <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>: I'd really like it if you did that. I didn't manage to catch up to the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-rpgs">RPG's</a> main story in time, and even if I put all of the combat stuff on autopilot it's just not the same watching cutscene compilations on YouTube.
</p>
<p>
We can only assume that some kind of Nier project <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/big-cool-weirdo-yoko-taro-may-or-may-not-be-working-on-something-that-may-or-may-not-be-nier">will be coming, some time, eventually, maybe</a>, though it would be nice for an actual bit of news. Or, like, a <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/nier-automata">Nier Automata</a> re-release with an equally annoying name to write as <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/nier-replicant">Nier Replicant ver. 1.22</a> blah blah blah's that adds a lore critical sword or whatever.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Deals Today: Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition, Star Wars Outlaws, and More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-26-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-best-deals-today-xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-star-wars-outlaws-and-more.1174656/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-deals-for-april-26-2025<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Get in the robot.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The weekend is officially here, and we've rounded up the best deals you can find! Discover the best deals for April 20 below:</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition for $49.99</h2><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219525"><div id="219525" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/xenoblade-chronicles-x-definitive-edition-review">Xenoblade Chronicles X: Definitive Edition</a> brings the long-requested Wii U game to Nintendo Switch with numerous quality-of-life updates and features. There's also even an added epilogue story chapter with a new ending for the game, which likely will directly lead into the future of the series. With a soundtrack by Hiroyuki Sawano and a massive world to explore, Xenoblade Chronicles X is a game you can easily spend hundreds of hours in.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Razer Huntsman V2 TKL for $74.99</h2></div><div catalogid="c1e24b32-f264-4725-ad01-ca010d75866c" id="218975"><div id="218975" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Razer - Huntsman V2 TKL Wired Optical Purple Clicky Switch Gaming Keyboard with Chroma RGB Backlighting - Black</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Best Buy has the Razer Huntsman V2 TKL Mechanical Keyboard for just $74.99 today. This keyboard features clicky optical switches that feel much lighter than most other mechanical switches out there, as you can get up to true 8000Hz polling rate for lower input latency. The Huntsman V2 TKL features doubleshot PBT caps, which are more durable and sturdy to ensure longer life. Another key offering of this keyboard is the detachable USB-C cable, so you won't need to worry about wrapping your cable around when moving. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Persona 5 + Persona 5 Royal: Official Design Works for $57.31</h2></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219528"><div id="219528" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Persona 5 + Persona 5 Royal: Official Design Works</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're a fan of Persona 5, this is the ultimate item for you. This Official Design Works contains 544 pages of artwork across both Persona 5 and Persona 5 Royal. You'll find character illustrations, promotional art, rough concepts, detailed creator commentary, and even an interview with Shigenori Soejima.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Dragon's Dogma 2 for $30</h2></div><div catalogid="c1e24b32-f264-4725-ad01-ca010d75866c" id="218963"><div id="218963" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Dragon's Dogma 2 - PS5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">You can score Capcom's massive RPG for just $30 this weekend at Amazon. We gave the game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragons-dogma-2-review">an 8/10 in our review</a>, stating, "It is a retelling and reimplementation of all of those wonderful ideas from the 2012 cult-classic, including an awesome dynamic world and some of the best combat in the genre that integrates a subtle but amazingly complex physics system."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Resident Evil 3 for $19.93</h2></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219527"><div id="219527" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Resident Evil 3 - PlayStation 5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">You can save $10 off the PS5 version of Resident Evil 3 this weekend at Amazon. In <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/resident-evil-3-final-review">our 9/10 review</a>, we wrote, "Resident Evil 3 is a wonderful continuation of Capcom’s latest remake efforts. Although its just-okay multiplayer mode falls short of the bar set by its magnificent single-player campaign, the latter does such a good job at balancing 2020 gameplay and a classic Resident Evil tone that I recommend it without reservations."</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii for $49.99</h2></div><div id="218604" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger" catalogid="cfa18f2c-871b-4e5d-b0de-58054ce7acd9"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii - PlayStation 4</h3></p></div><div catalogid="cfa18f2c-871b-4e5d-b0de-58054ce7acd9" id="218605"><div id="218605" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii - Xbox Series X</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The latest Like a Dragon game stars everyone's favorite ex-yakuza, Goro Majima, on an adventure to sail the seas as a pirate. When Majima wakes up unable to remember anything about himself, he embarks on a quest to regain his memories, and of course, in true Like a Dragon fashion, things get crazy. This is the lowest we've seen this game so far, so be sure to pick up a copy while you can.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Star Wars Outlaws Limited Edition for $29.12</h2></div><div catalogid="6608a815-01bc-4b8c-a11c-ef8e90a434f6" id="219526"><div id="219526" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>Star Wars Outlaws - Limited Edition (Amazon Exclusive), Xbox Series X</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Finally, Star Wars Outlaws for Xbox Series X is on sale for $29.12 at Amazon. We gave the game <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/star-wars-outlaws-review">a 7/10 in our review</a>, writing, "Star Wars Outlaws is a fun intergalactic heist adventure with great exploration, but it’s hindered by simple stealth, repetitive combat, and a few too many bugs at launch."</p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Apr 26, 2025 7:42 pm</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You can start ringing the new Skate's death knell, because EA says it's online only]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-start-ringing-the-new-skates-death-knell-because-ea-says-its-online-only</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-can-start-ringing-the-new-skates-death-knell-because-ea-says-its-online-only.1174626/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/you-can-start-ringing-the-new-skates-death-knell-because-ea-says-its-online-only<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
I think to properly convey my severe dislike of always online games I'd probably need more space and time than what an average RPS news article provides, but I'll try to contain myself on this one. You see, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/companies/electronic-arts">EA's</a> just started up this new thing it calls <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/skate/news/the-grind-vol-one?isLocalized=true">The Grind</a> (like what you do on a skateboard, get it?), which they describe as their "platform to talk directly to you, the community." The first volume had quite a few questions from expectant skaters about the upcoming <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/skate">Skate</a> reboot, one of the first being whether or not it'll have an offline mode. Can you already guess from my tone so far that it won't?
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>
Because, as EA put it, "the simple answer" is "no." They go on to explain that the "game and city are designed to be a living, breathing massively multiplayer skateboarding sandbox that is always online and always evolving. You’ll see bigger things evolve, like changes to the city over time, as well as smaller things, like live events and other in-game activities." According to EA, this isn't possible without a live connection, which I'm sure might actually have a technical justification, it just stinks a bit.
</p>
<p>
My guess is that they want to Fortnite-ify Skate so that the city can change in substantial ways, which is a cool concept! It just also means you're eventually bound to get situations like <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-crew">The Crew</a> where the game is just unplayable (which has resulted in a lawsuit, and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-crew-2-is-getting-an-offline-mode-play-test-and-it-unsurprisingly-wont-have-all-of-its-online-features">offline modes for The Crew 2 and Motorfest</a>). Maybe EA will add in an offline mode eventually so that the game will last longer than the live service fad, but I won't put any bets on it.
</p>
<p>
In terms of other, less annoying details, EA do still plan to launch Skate into early access some time in 2025 at least. They also clarified that "there will be 'cool' things for you to earn and customize your character without having to spend real cash," if you're someone that likes your <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-free-pc-games">free-to-play games</a> to be completely free. New areas won't be paywalled either, and there's no sort of pay-to-win element. Still don't like the online-only stuff, but all of that sounds good at least.

</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>