<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:08:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warner Bros. Games Head David Haddad to Step Down After 12 Years]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warner-bros-games-david-haddad-stepping-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warner-bros-games-head-david-haddad-to-step-down-after-12-years.1089999/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/warner-bros-games-david-haddad-stepping-down<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Warner Bros. Games head David Haddad is to leave his position after 12 years, according to a new report. His successor has not yet been appointed.</p>

<p>According to a Variety <a href="https://variety.com/2025/digital/news/warner-bros-games-chief-david-haddad-exit-1236283177/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">report</a>, Haddad plans to stay on with Warner Bros. Games for a three-month period while the company searches for a successor. He'll also be helping to oversee the transition to said successor, which is pretty standard behavior for departing corporate execs.</p>

<p>Streaming and games head JB Perrette says Haddad's departure comes at a time when the company's "release schedule is lighter", which, Perrette says, will help "minimize disruption" and allow the WB Games team to "smoothly prepare for its next record-breaking title".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/warner-bros-games-david-haddad-suicide-squad.jpg?itok=8nNMI2tm 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/warner-bros-games-david-haddad-suicide-squad.jpg?itok=cOthYWxV 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>David Haddad, who oversaw the release of games like&nbsp;<em>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League&nbsp;</em>during his tenure, is leaving Warner Bros. Games.</figcaption></figure><p>Later today, Perrette and Haddad will hold a town hall meeting to brief WB Games employees on Haddad's decision and provide additional information.</p>

<p>Variety, citing a source "close to the situation", says that there aren't any plans for the wider Warner Bros. to sell off its gaming division, and that the goal is to focus on finding a replacement for Haddad.</p>

<p>Unlike <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/plaion-koch-media-ceo-stepping-down" rel="nofollow">other execs</a> who have recently <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/insomniac-ceo-founder-ted-price-steps-down" rel="nofollow">departed their companies</a>, Haddad won't be retiring full stop; he says he's looking forward to the "next chapter" of his career and that he will continue to enthusiastically support the studio's future work.</p>

<p>While Haddad's departure may have been voluntary, he and WB Games haven't had the best year on the whole. February's&nbsp;<em>Suicide Squad: Kill the Justice League&nbsp;</em>served as the company's flagship title for the year, but it <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/suicide-squad-kill-justice-leagues-sales-disappointed-hogwarts-legacy-is-big-win" rel="nofollow">performed disastrously</a>, contributing to a massive writedown for Warner Bros.</p>

<p><em>Suicide Squad&nbsp;</em>wasn't the only failure for Warner Bros. this year, either; the full release of fighting game&nbsp;<em>MultiVersus&nbsp;</em>also <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/multiversus-flop-warner-bros-100m" rel="nofollow">proved a disastrous flop</a>, costing the company $100 million.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/hogwarts-legacy-warner-bros-games-david-haddad.jpg?itok=f9_zYjwX 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/hogwarts-legacy-warner-bros-games-david-haddad.jpg?itok=XxdEgnYI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Haddad also oversaw successes like&nbsp;<em>Hogwarts Legacy</em>.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Suicide Squad</em> and&nbsp;<em>MultiVersus</em>&nbsp;may have been a failure (and one that reportedly <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rocksteady-layoffs-end-of-2024" rel="nofollow">contributed to layoffs</a> at developer Rocksteady), but Haddad also oversaw massive successes at WB Games during his tenure.</p>

<p>Wizarding World RPG&nbsp;<em>Hogwarts Legacy&nbsp;</em>has proven an <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/hogwarts-legacy-sales-30m" rel="nofollow">enduring commercial hit</a> for the company, and it was also revealed recently that fighting game&nbsp;<em>Mortal Kombat 1&nbsp;</em>has <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/mortal-kombat-1-sales" rel="nofollow">passed the five million sales mark</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[7 Of Last Year's Best-Selling Games Didn't Even Come Out In 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/best-selling-games-2024-hogwarts-legacy-dragon-ball-1851746095</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/7-of-last-years-best-selling-games-didnt-even-come-out-in-2024.1089996/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/best-selling-games-2024-hogwarts-legacy-dragon-ball-1851746095<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>One of the biggest developments in gaming isn’t just the growing number of games to play, with thousands more being released every year, but how sticky the biggest blockbusters are, monopolizing players’ money and attention long after they’ve come out. And not just live-service multiplayer games either. New sales data shows how over a third of 2024's best selling games, like <em>Elden Ring</em>, came out years ago. </p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196055" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="227" data-playlist="196055,195624,196358" data-current="196055"><div><p>6 Things To Know Before Starting Persona 5 Tactica</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196055/196055_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21584.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lgg2dhbzzk2n&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lgg2dhbzzk2n" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Market research firm Circana released its list</a></span> of the top-20 best-selling games of 2024 for the U.S. on Thursday, and it shows for just how long some old games are sticking around. Perennial favorites like <em>Grand Theft Auto V</em> (2013) and <em>Minecraft </em>(2011) always show up on these lists, but single-player RPGs like <em>Elden Ring</em> (2022) and <em>Hogwarts Legacy</em> (2023) are now too. In fact if you remove the EA Sports MVP Bundle, which includes <em>Madden 25 </em>and <em>Sports FC 25</em>,  games already on the list elsewhere, then over a third of the top-20 list includes old games:</p><blockquote data-type="BlockQuote"><ol data-type="List" data-style="Number"><li><em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</em></li><li><em>EA Sports College Football 25</em></li><li><em>Helldivers II </em></li><li><em>Dragon Ball: Sparking Zero </em></li><li><em>NBA 2K25 </em></li><li><em>Madden NFL 25</em></li><li><strong><em> Call of Duty: Modern Warfare III (2023) </em></strong></li><li><em>EA Sports FC 25 </em></li><li><strong><em>Elden Ring </em></strong></li><li><em>EA Sports MVP Bundle </em></li><li><strong><em>Hogwarts Legacy </em></strong></li><li><em>Dragon’s Dogma II </em></li><li><em>WWE 2K24 </em></li><li><em>MLB: The Show 24 </em></li><li><strong><em>Grand Theft Auto V </em></strong></li><li><strong><em>Minecraft </em></strong></li><li><em>Final Fantasy VII: Rebirth </em></li><li><em>Tekken 8 </em></li><li><strong><em>Marvel’s Spider-Man 2 </em></strong></li><li><strong><em>NBA2K24</em></strong>﻿</li></ol></blockquote><p>It’s hard to come up with any unifying theory of why these seven games (<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-20-best-selling-games-of-2023-in-the-us.816495/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-20-best-selling-games-of-2023-in-the-us.816495/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">three more than 2023</a></span>) remained such huge sellers last year. Annual sports games like <em>NBA 2K24</em> and <em>Call of Duty</em>’s unparalleled popularity have historically helped them stick around months after release. <em>GTA V</em> is required to play<em> GTA Online</em>, which continues to be one of the most popular multiplayer games, and the launch of <em>GTA VI </em>is closer than ever. And every year there’s a new generation of kids getting hooked on <em>Minecraft</em>. </p><p><em>Elden Ring</em> was no doubt helped by its GOTY contender expansion,<em> Shadow of the Erdtree</em>, coming out in 2024. And <em>Hogwarts Legacy</em>? Well, who knows. It hit Switch in late 2023 and finally started getting its price slashed in half during recent sales. <em>Spider-Man 2</em>, meanwhile, seems like people’s go-to game when they upgrade to a PS5 for the first time.</p><p>Other notable takeaways from last year’s best-selling games are that not a single Nintendo first-party game charted, a testament to what a week year overall it was for the console despite a late breakout in <em>Mario Party Jamboree</em>. <em>Star Wars Outlaws</em> didn’t chart at all either. In fact a Ubisoft game hasn’t charted in the top 10 since 2020's <em>Assassin’s Creed Valhalla</em>, no doubt part of its calculous in delaying <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em> a second time for extra polish as the family-owned publisher battles for survival. </p><p><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em> was another high-profile absence. In addition to not making the list despite its predecessor eventually selling over 10 million, it wasn’t a top-20 best-selling game for December 2024 either, less than two months after it launched. Publisher EA <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/Electronic-Arts-Pre-Announces-Preliminary-Q3-FY25-Results/default.aspx&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://ir.ea.com/press-releases/press-release-details/2025/Electronic-Arts-Pre-Announces-Preliminary-Q3-FY25-Results/default.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">released its preliminary financial early pointing</a></span> to the action-RPG coming in severely under expectations with 1.5 million players for the quarter, 50 percent below its forecast. Whether that was an unrealistic goal to make up for the game’s notoriously long and difficult development cycle is another matter. </p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 Becomes First Game To Support DLSS 4]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-becomes-first-game-to-support-dlss-4/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cyberpunk-2077-becomes-first-game-to-support-dlss-4.1089990/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/cyberpunk-2077-becomes-first-game-to-support-dlss-4/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-85476">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Nvidia is releasing its new GeForce RTX 5090 graphics cards on January 30, and with it comes the release of the next generation of Deep Learning Super Sampling (DLSS). On Thursday, CD Projekt Red released a new update for Cyberpunk 2077 to account for the new technology, making it the first game to officially support DLSS 4.</p>



<p>With support for DLSS 4 being added, Cyberpunk 2077 will allow the use of Nvidia’s new multi-frame generation technology that is launching exclusively for the next-gen RTX 50 series graphics cards. This technology helps with overall performance using AI to generate more frames while you play.</p>



<p>In addition to Cyberpunk 2077, DLSS 4 will be available with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dlss-4-to-launch-with-support-for-75-games-and-apps/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at least 75 games</a> when it launches.</p>



<p>You can check out the PC-specific notes from CD Projekt Red below.</p>



<ul>
<li>Added support for DLSS 4 with Multi Frame Generation for GeForce RTX 50 Series graphics cards, which boosts FPS by using AI to generate up to three times per traditionally rendered frame – enabled with GeForce RTX 50 Series on January 30th. DLSS 4 also introduces faster single Frame Generation with reduced memory usage for RTX 50 and 40 Series. Additionally, you can now choose between the CNN model or the new Transformer model for DLSS Ray Reconstruction, DLSS Super Resolution, and DLAA on all GeForce RTX graphics cards today. The new Transformer model enhances stability, lighting, and detail in motion.</li>



<li>Fixed artifacts and smudging on in-game screens when using DLSS Ray Reconstruction.</li>



<li>The Frame Generation field in Graphics settings will now properly reset after switching Resolution Scaling to OFF.</li>
</ul>



<p>Are you going to pick up a new RTX 50 series GPU when they launch to take advantage of the new features in games like Cyberpunk 2077?&nbsp;Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/threads/1336/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the final year-end <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/video-game-hardware-sales-fall-29-for-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">video game hardware sales data</a> for 2024.&nbsp;And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warner-bros-david-haddad/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warner-bros-david-haddad/">Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment President David Haddad is Leaving The Company</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment has announced that its president David Haddad will leave the company.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/video-game-hardware-sales-fall-29-for-2024/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/video-game-hardware-sales-fall-29-for-2024/">Video Game Hardware Sales Fall 29% For 2024</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>After a small November boost, video game hardware sales ended 2024 on a down note, falling nearly 30% for the year in the United States.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-space-time-smackdown-expansion-reveal/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-space-time-smackdown-expansion-reveal/">Pokemon TCG Pocket Has Revealed Their Space-Time Smackdown Expansion&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Pokemon TCG Pocket has just revealed their Space-Time Smackdown expansion through a new trailer. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-was-decembers-best-selling-video-game/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-was-decembers-best-selling-video-game/">Call Of Duty: Black Ops 6 Was December’s Best-Selling Video Game</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 was the best-selling video game in the United States for December 2024, according to the latest sales data.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025 is the Year of the RPG – Upcoming RPG Games We’re Excited About]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/2025-is-the-year-of-the-rpg-upcoming-rpg-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2025-is-the-year-of-the-rpg-%E2%80%93-upcoming-rpg-games-we%E2%80%99re-excited-about.1089984/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/2025-is-the-year-of-the-rpg-upcoming-rpg-games/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Like many of you, I don’t have much time these days to invest hundreds of hours into a single game. I usually run through a new release, play the campaign once, and enjoy multiplayer wherever possible. But when it comes to role-playing games, I can’t help myself. I collect them, leaving many in my backlog for a rainy day. Well, 2025 will be another big year for RPGs, with titles such as Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 and The First Berserker: Khazan on the way!</p>



<h2 id="h-upcoming-rpgs-in-2025-with-release-dates">Upcoming RPGs in 2025 – With Release Dates!</h2>



<p>First and foremost, it’s important to note that we don’t have official release dates for every RPG mentioned here. As such, many of them may be pushed out of 2025 to 2026 and beyond. For titles like The Elder Scrolls VI and The Witcher 4, we’re not even going to bother mentioning them past this point, as there’s no way they’ll realistically launch this year.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Tales of Grace f Remastered – January 17</strong></li>



<li><strong>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth – January 23</strong></li>



<li><strong>Citizen Sleeper 2: Starward Vector – January 23</strong></li>



<li><strong>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 – February 4</strong></li>



<li><strong>The Legend of Heroes: Trails Through Daybreak II – February 14</strong></li>



<li><strong>Avowed – February 18</strong></li>



<li><strong>Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii – February 21</strong></li>



<li><strong>Monster Hunter Wilds – February 28</strong></li>



<li><strong>Assassin’s Creed Shadows – March 20</strong></li>



<li><strong>Atelier Yumia: The Alchemist of Memories &amp; the Envisioned Land – March 21</strong></li>



<li><strong>The First Berserker: Khazan – March 27</strong></li>



<li><strong>Rune Factory: Guardians of Azuma – May 30</strong></li>
</ul>







<h2 id="h-upcoming-rpgs-without-release-dates">Upcoming RPGs Without Release Dates</h2>



<p>Several upcoming role-playing games are rumored to be released in 2025, though there are no specific release dates yet. It’s still early in the year, so fingers crossed!</p>



<ul>
<li>ArcheAge Chronicles</li>



<li>Borderlands 4</li>



<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>Dragon Quest I &amp; II HD-2D Remake</li>



<li>Fable</li>



<li>Moonlighter 2: The Endless Vault</li>



<li>Pokemon Legends: Z-A</li>



<li>Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2</li>



<li>Wuchang: Fallen Fathers</li>
</ul>



<p>Oh, and here’s hoping we see Black Myth: Wukong on Xbox Series X|S this year, too!</p>



<p>What’s the one RPG you’re most excited to play? Let us know in the comments, or visit the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming community forums</a> to discuss RPGs with us!</p>



<hr>



<p>Speaking of upcoming RPGs, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/rebel-wolves-dawnwalker-bandai-namco/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rebel Wolves’ Dawnwalker will be published by Bandai Namco</a>, but we don’t expect it in 2025.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warner Bros. Games president David Haddad to step down]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/warner-bros-games-president-david-haddad-to-step-down</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warner-bros-games-president-david-haddad-to-step-down.1089981/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/warner-bros-games-president-david-haddad-to-step-down<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Haddad to remain on board for the next three months as company seeks replacement.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Warner Bros. Games [641 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/warner-bros-games">Warner Bros. Games</a> president David Hadddad will step down after 12 years of leading the company’s interactive entertainment division, the company announced. <span id="more-940031"></span></p><p>Haddad will stay on board with the company for the next three months as parent company Warner Bros. Discovery seeks his replacement and to help oversee the transition.</p><p>“David has thoughtfully and purposefully chosen a time when our release schedule is lighter which will help minimize disruption to our ongoing projects and strategic plans and allow this team to smoothly prepare for its next record-breaking title,” Warner Bros. Discovery global streaming and games CEO and president JB Perrette said, via <a href="https://variety.com/2025/digital/news/warner-bros-games-chief-david-haddad-exit-1236283177/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Variety</a>.</p><p>Haddad commented, “I am so proud of everything we’ve accomplished together at Warner Bros. Games during my time with the company. It has been an absolute pleasure working on and building our iconic gaming franchises, and I will continue to be an enthusiastic supporter of this talented team’s future endeavors. I look forward to working on the next chapter of my career and will always be grateful for my time with Warner Bros. Games.”</p><p>Here is the full internal note sent to staff from Perrette announcing Haddad’s exit:</p><blockquote><p>Global Games Team,</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>I wanted to share with you the news that after 12 incredible years leading [Warner Bros. Discovery] Games, David Haddad has decided to depart the company.</p><p>On behalf of David Zaslav and all of us at WBD, I want to express my deepest gratitude to David for his phenomenal work and passion during his time here. With the support and incredible efforts of this whole team, David has led WB Games to numerous accomplishments over the years, both creatively and commercially. His vision, talent and passion have helped build one of the most successful and admired gaming companies in the industry and navigated some of the biggest changes and challenges as well.</p><p>From transitioning a physical software company into a digital-first gaming operation to organically building a successful <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [360 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> mobile business to developing and publishing multiple billion-dollar games and franchises—including <em><a title="Games > Hogwarts Legacy [25 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/hogwarts-legacy">Hogwarts Legacy</a></em>, <em>Game of Thrones Conquest</em>, and <em>Golf Clash</em>—to delighting more Mortal Kombat fans than any time in the franchise’s 30+ year history, the journey has been nothing short of extraordinary.</p><p>David has thoughtfully and purposefully chosen a time when our release schedule is lighter which will help minimize disruption to our ongoing projects and strategic plans and allow this team to smoothly prepare for its next record-breaking title. David has also graciously agreed to stay on through the next three months as we kick-off a search to fill this important leadership role and will help ensure a smooth transition. This transition period will also provide me with additional opportunities to engage directly with the Games leadership, and I look forward to getting even more immersed with all of you and in this incredible business.</p><p>I fully appreciate that particularly after 12 years with the same leader and boss, change can be hard and uncomfortable (in our industry and at WBD we have certainly had our fair share). But it also brings opportunity, a chance for healthy new perspectives, and the ability to create the next incredible chapter for our fans and business… and I’m excited to embark on that with you.</p><p>I’m sure you have many questions due to this news, so David and I will be gathering with you at the scheduled Town Hall shortly. You may have more questions than we have answers right now, but we want to respond to what we can.</p><p>Thankfully we will have some more time to celebrate and thank David, but I know you’ll join me in this initial congratulations and thank you for this remarkable chapter he has led.</p><p>—JB</p></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Aggregation Platform CriticDB Wants to Go "Beyond Traditional Aggregation"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/criticdb-announced-beyond-traditional-aggregation</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-aggregation-platform-criticdb-wants-to-go-beyond-traditional-aggregation.1089954/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/criticdb-announced-beyond-traditional-aggregation<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>TechRaptor's very own Rutledge Daugette, along with several other members of the editorial team at our lovely little site, have announced CriticDB, a brand new review aggregator site that plans to "go beyond" traditional aggregation.</p>

<p>Rutledge describes <a href="https://criticdb.com/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">CriticDB</a> as a "new video game review aggregation and game discovery platform". As you've probably guessed from that, it'll aim not only to aggregate professional reviews, but also to help you find games you might have missed.</p>

<p>At launch, the site will aggregate over 75 outlets' reviews (and that includes us here at TechRaptor, of course), and the team anticipates it will launch with more than 20,000 reviews across over 2,000 game pages.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/criticdb-game-page-lies-of-p.jpg?itok=quPyEsCI 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/criticdb-game-page-lies-of-p.jpg?itok=sepylObG 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You'll be able to check out over 2,000 game pages at launch on CriticDB.</figcaption></figure><p>According to Rutledge's brief, CriticDB puts three pillars at the center of its mission:</p>

<ul><li>Collecting reviews and previews from around the web</li>
	<li>Connecting gamers with games they might have missed</li>
	<li>Helping outlets and PR to connect more easily</li>
</ul><p>Rutledge also says he wants the site to be a "positive force in the industry", highlighting "great work and games" that may otherwise go unnoticed. The site is also geared towards its users; the point is to create a "community-driven" platform.</p>

<p>On CriticDB, you'll be able to browse professional and user reviews (although Rutledge says user reviews will only be submittable by those who subscribe to the paid Pro user tier), follow outlets and creators, and create lists with various different parameters.</p>

<p>Those lists include favorites, wishlists, and even played and beaten games, so it looks like CriticDB might also be gunning for the crowns of the likes of Backloggd.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/criticdb-search-function-insert.jpg?itok=69Dilk6P 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/criticdb-search-function-insert.jpg?itok=Gk88Z9KE 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>CriticDB will feature a robust search function as well as plenty of user-centric features.</figcaption></figure><p>CriticDB users can create game pages for titles that are missing from the site's database, and they can also create links between similar games, helping other users to find games in their niche. Leaderboards will be available for users who create and link the most games, too.</p>

<p>Game pages consist of info like game release dates, listings for developers and publishers, and genres, as well as which platforms you can play the game on. Naturally, you'll also find CriticDB's signature "similar games" list, which will, if all goes well, have been at least partially curated by the site's community.</p>

<p>If you've ever found yourself wanting to find certain outlets, such as minority-owned platforms or independent sites, CriticDB will feature outlet tags to let you search for specific terms as well.</p>

<p>When it comes to the platform's future, Rutledge says the new site has a "robust roadmap" through which it will "expand...its features" throughout 2025. Some of the features coming to the platform include the following:</p>

<ul><li>An XP system and&nbsp;badges for profiles</li>
	<li>Outlet and&nbsp;author following</li>
	<li>On-site notifications for new releases of your wishlisted games and&nbsp;more</li>
</ul><p>If you're an outlet or a creator, you can also apply to be included on the platform when the <a href="https://criticdb.com/" rel="nofollow">review aggregation platform</a> launches on January 30th, so make sure you add it to your bookmarks for then.</p>

<hr><p><em>Disclosure: CriticDB was created and is run by several members of the TechRaptor editorial team.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dwarf Fortress Steam edition's Adventure Mode is out today]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-fortress-steam-editions-adventure-mode-is-out-today</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dwarf-fortress-steam-editions-adventure-mode-is-out-today.1089951/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-fortress-steam-editions-adventure-mode-is-out-today<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Featuring some lovely sounding tutorials</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/dwarf-fortress-adventure-mode.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Bay12 Games/Kitfox</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dwarf-fortress">Dwarf Fortress</a>'s Adventure mode - a procedurally generated campaign that lets you approach the famously dense colony <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-simulation-games">sim</a> like a more traditional roguelite - is now out as a free update <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/975370/Dwarf_Fortress/">on Steam</a>. The game represents perhaps the most cavernous, yawping blind spot in my entire pile of shame. I do own it, but I'm yet to play. I've already read a great deal of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/the-basement-of-curiosity">extended wordery</a> on its merits - please, sell it to me in the comments in seven words or less. Here's a trailer:</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Dwarf Fortress Adventure Mode - Out Now - Official Release Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7zY0UxSxTzU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Dwarf Fortress Adventure Mode - Out Now - Official Release Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7zY0UxSxTzU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/7zY0UxSxTzU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7zY0UxSxTzU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Graham most definitely has played it though, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-fortress-the-detailed-roguelike-thats-easy-to-play">calling</a> its older incarnation "a good way to experience the charms of its procedural world and high level of simulation". Personal anecdotes and experience are great and all, but what I really want is some deeply impersonal bullet-pointed features from a store page. Here are Adventure Mode's:</p>
<blockquote><ul>
<li>Go anywhere! Explore any civilization, earn a reputation, and recruit followers to join you</li>
<li>Experience your fortress and the simulation in a new, more embodied way</li>
<li>Explore mythical dungeons to find magical items, artifacts, and fill your quest journal</li>
<li>Hints of mythology and magic as a start of future simulation enrichment to come</li>
<li>An additional hour of music from Dabu and Simon Swerwer, presented as a second volume of the original soundtrack</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>As Graham <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dwarf-fortresss-adventure-mode-getting-tutorials-and-more-direction-in-the-sandbox">covered here</a>, Adventure Mode sounds tailored for aspirant beardlings such as a myself, with a focus on tutorialisation and a more personal feel, since you only play a single character. Here's some further insight from co-creators Tarn and Zach Adams</p>
<blockquote><p>“In our earliest conception of the game you were meant to lose...  lose for a reason! Even before your fortresses existed in a huge procedurally generated world, they were destroyed and became haunted ruins you could explore in an RPG-style adventure. Years later, as our fantasy worlds have grown and become more complex, the Adventure Mode experience is so much more impressive.  Now the entire world is connected in ways you can actually see.  Visit the far off lands that send caravans to your fortresses, or seek out and slay the monsters that have troubled your dwarves before.  The extensive combat system only viewed from afar in Fortress Mode is now yours to use to inflict violence on your enemies...  or if you choose, travel the world and recite poetry to a room full of wombat men."</p></blockquote>
<p>W…wombat men, you say?</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Capcom Experimenting With Generative AI to Create 'Hundreds of Thousands of Unique Ideas' Needed to Build In-Game Environments]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-experimenting-with-generative-ai-to-create-hundreds-of-thousands-of-unique-ideas-needed-to-build-in-game-environments</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/capcom-experimenting-with-generative-ai-to-create-hundreds-of-thousands-of-unique-ideas-needed-to-build-in-game-environments.1089942/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/capcom-experimenting-with-generative-ai-to-create-hundreds-of-thousands-of-unique-ideas-needed-to-build-in-game-environments<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Prototype will reportedly reduce costs and speed up development.</h2></div><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Capcom is experimenting with generative AI to create the "hundreds of thousands" of ideas needed for in-game environments.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As video game development costs rise, publishers are increasingly looking to controversial AI tools to speed up work and cut costs. Call of Duty <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/activision-reportedly-sold-an-ai-generated-call-of-duty-modern-warfare-3-cosmetic">reportedly sold an "AI-generated cosmetic"</a> for Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 3 in late 2023, and fans <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-fans-give-black-ops-6s-zombie-santa-loading-screen-the-finger-amid-ai-slop-backlash">accused Activision of using generative AI again for a loading screen last year</a>. EA said in September that <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-says-ai-is-the-very-core-of-its-business-what-does-that-mean">AI was "the very core" of its business</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a new interview with <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/ja/topics/customers/capcom-generating-ideas-with-generative-ai?hl=ja" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Google Cloud Japan</u></a>, Kazuki Abe, a technical director at Capcom who has worked on huge titles like Monster Hunter: World and Exoprimal, explained how the company is experimenting with implementing AI in its game development processes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“One of the most time-consuming and labor intensive parts of game development is coming up with hundreds of thousands of unique ideas,” Abe explained <a href="https://automaton-media.com/en/game-development/capcom-is-experimenting-with-generative-ai-to-help-generate-the-hundreds-of-thousands-of-ideas-needed-for-game-development/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>(via Automaton</u></a>). He added that designs for things like televisions require their own unique designs, logos, and shape. “Including unused ones, we ended up having to come up with hundreds of thousands of ideas,” he continued.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Multiple proposals are needed for the thousands to tens of thousands of these kinds of objects per game, and each proposal includes illustrations needed to communicate the idea to the art director and artists as well as text, Abe explained.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Seeing room for efficiency improvements, Abe created a system where generative AI could read various game design documents and an AI could output the ideas, enhancing development speed and efficiency, delivering feedback for itself in the process and further refining output.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">His prototype, which taps into multiple AI models such as Google Gemini Pro, Gemini Flash, and Imagen has apparently received positive feedback from internal development teams. The result of implementing the AI model would ultimately “reduce costs significantly” compared to doing them all by hand, while also improving quality.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Right now, Capcom’s experimentation with AI models appears to be limited to just this system, leaving other aspects of game development, such as ideation, gameplay, programming, and character design firmly in the hands of humans.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sayem is a freelancer based in the UK, covering tech &amp; hardware. You can get in touch with him at @sayem.zone on Bluesky.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy 7 Remake Part 3 Development Takes Another Big Step Forward]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-development-takes-another-big-step-forward/1100-6528974/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-development-takes-another-big-step-forward.1089939/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-development-takes-another-big-step-forward/1100-6528974/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528974">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Almost a year after Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth was released for PS5, development on the final chapter of the remake trilogy has taken another big step forward. Series producer Yoshinori Kitase revealed that the story scenario for the third game was completed by the end of 2024 and that he's "very satisfied with it."</p><p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.famitsu.com/article/202501/30815" rel="nofollow ">Famitsu</a> (via <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3s-story-completed-producer-very-satisfied-as-development-continues-without-delay" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>), Kitase and game director Naoki Hamaguchi added that development on the third game began right after Rebirth was completed and that there have been no delays yet on its progress.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1545750286" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465581,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REBIRTH%20%7C%20PC%20FEATURES%20TRAILER&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:150,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-pc-features-trailer\/2300-6465581\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465581\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465581\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465581\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465581&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465581,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6528974&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;final-fantasy-vii-rebirth&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,role-playing&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,pc&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;square-enix&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;final-fantasy&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;final-fantasy&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465581},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465581\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4424747-33.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/HxyRdMJR.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1736434080,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="HxyRdMJR" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465581" data-src="/videos/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth-pc-features-trailer/2300-6465581/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>FINAL FANTASY VII REBIRTH | PC FEATURES TRAILER</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p>Kitase also mentioned that creative director Tetsuya Nomura was tasked with making certain that the game's conclusion will be respectful to the original Final Fantasy 7 while also giving the series a satisfying conclusion.</p><p>"I'm very satisfied with it, so I'm sure the fans will be satisfied with the final chapter," Kitase said.</p><p>The next Final Fantasy Remake chapter likely won't be a timed Playstation exclusive either, as Kitase was quizzed about the game possibly being locked to PlayStation 6. "For those who have played FF7 Remake on PS4 and FF7 Rebirth on PS5, I think there may be some concern that the third work will be for the next-generation console," Kitase said to <a href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/865/G086563/20250121053/" rel="nofollow ">4Gamer</a> (via <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/final-fantasy-7-remake-part-3-wont-be-a-ps6-exclusive-producer-promises/" rel="nofollow ">VGC</a>). "No, you can rest assured about the next one."</p><p>This ties into <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/square-enix-reveals-aggressive-multiplatform-target-plans-with-catchy-new-name/1100-6523394/">Square Enix's new multiplatform strategy</a>, as the company revealed a new strategy last year to help it secure long-term growth. <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/square-enix-says-final-fantasy-16-and-final-fantasy-7-rebirth-didnt-meet-sales-expectations/1100-6526552/">Rebirth and 2023's Final Fantasy 16 failed to meet sales expectations</a> for the company--although sales figures haven't been revealed yet--but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/2024s-best-selling-games-in-the-us/2900-5106/" data-ref-id="2900-5106">Rebirth was the 17th best-selling game in the US for 2024</a> and it launches today for PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket Reveals Space-Time Smackdown Set Release Date And Shows Off New Cards]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-new-set-lucario-sinnoh-dialga-palkia-1851746013</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pocket-reveals-space-time-smackdown-set-release-date-and-shows-off-new-cards.1089906/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-new-set-lucario-sinnoh-dialga-palkia-1851746013<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="a034bd3f4bdd1726a937481f0f35c601" data-recommend-id="image://a034bd3f4bdd1726a937481f0f35c601" data-format="png" data-width="1174" data-height="660" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A mythic pokemon appears on a smartphone. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A mythic pokemon appears on a smartphone. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->The Pokemon Company / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a034bd3f4bdd1726a937481f0f35c601" data-recommend-id="image://a034bd3f4bdd1726a937481f0f35c601" data-format="png" data-width="1174" data-height="660" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="A mythic pokemon appears on a smartphone. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><em>Pokémon TCG Pocket</em> is closing out January with a bang. The hit mobile game is getting a much-needed content refresh later this month in the form of a new set called Space-Time Smackdown. Two separate booster packs will feature Dialga and Palkia on their covers, the legendaries from <em>Pokémon Diamond</em> and <em>Pearl</em>. The set arrives alongside the addition of card trading, a long awaited feature <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-trading-rules-gold-cards-date-1851741957&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-trading-rules-gold-cards-date-1851741957">we also just got some more controversial new details about</a></span>. </p><p>Space-Time Smackdown  goes live January 30. In addition to Dialga and Palkia, the set will feature other Pokémon new to <em>TCG Pocket</em>, including Lucario and Sinnoh region starters Turtwig, Chimchar and Piplup. A trailer for the expansion teased other cards and new illustrations for existing ones as well. There will seemingly be over 140 cards available from the new packs, making Space-Time Smackdown smaller than the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-poke-gold-price-1851744809&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-poke-gold-price-1851744809">starting Genetic Apex set, but twice the size of the Mythical Island set released in December</a></span>. </p><p>When it comes to trading, which will be added to the game on January 29, we already knew that players would be limited to exchanging cards at 1-star rarity and below. This was already rubbing players the wrong way, since crown rarity cards—like gold Charizard Ex—are the hardest to get and the only ones many diehard fans are still chasing. </p><p>Now, Creatures Inc. and DeNA have revealed the currencies players will need to trade with one another in addition to the rarity restrictions. The development team revealed players will need both trade hourglasses <em>and</em> trade tokens to exchange cards. Given current cooldowns, it certainly seems like this will limit players to just a few trades a week unless they spend money, though we still don’t know if or how <em>TCG Pocket</em>’s premium currency will factor into the new social mechanic. </p><p>Players also won’t be able to trade cards from First Space-Time Smackdown to start with either. The development team previously told fans it was looking at the negative feedback for the trading rules, but it doesn’t seem like it plans to change course anytime soon. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy VII Remake Part Three currently nine months into development, not next-gen exclusive]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-three-currently-nine-months-into-development-not-next-gen-exclusive</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-three-currently-nine-months-into-development-not-next-gen-exclusive.1089903/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-three-currently-nine-months-into-development-not-next-gen-exclusive<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>"Development is progressing smoothly."</span>
      </p></div><div><p>The untitled third entry in the&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > Final Fantasy VII Remake [107 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-fantasy-vii-remake">Final Fantasy VII Remake</a></em> project, following&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy VII Remake</em> and&nbsp;<em><a title="Games > Final Fantasy VII Rebirth [27 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth">Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</a></em>, is currently about nine months into development, according to director Naoki Hamaguchi. <span id="more-940012"></span></p><p>“Regarding the third game, we started working on it immediately after finishing <em>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</em>—around March or April 2024—so we’ve already been in development for about nine months,” Hamaguchi told <a href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/865/G086563/20250121053/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">4Gamer.net</a> in an interview for the release of the <a title="Platforms > PC [22,181 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> version of <em>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</em>. “Our goal for 2024 was to solidify the gameplay experience we were aiming for with the third entry of the <em>Remake</em> project, and we put together a great build that aligns with the team’s overall direction and vision.</p><p>“Starting in 2025, we’ve entered the phase of building and refining the game based on the plan we’ve established, and development is progressing smoothly and at a good pace, following the schedule I initially laid out. I can’t say when I’ll be able to share more information, but please stay tuned.”</p><p>Producer Yoshinori Kitase added, “When it comes to large, story-driven <a title="Genres > RPG [16,943 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> projects, the pace of development depends heavily on whether the story itself is fully locked in. For the third game’s story, after I received the scenario from [scenario write Kazushige] Nojima, I asked him to give it a greater sense of completeness since this is the final game. We just wrapped that up a few days ago, so I feel that things are progressing smoothly.”</p><p>While <em>Final Fantasy VII Remake</em> originally released on <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,613 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, sequel <em>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</em> released on <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,694 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> without a PlayStation 4 version. Asked whether users can expect the third game to follow the trend of only being available on the next generation of consoles, Kitase laughed and said, “No, no, don’t worry about that next time.”</p><p>Earlier in the interview, 4Gamer.net asked Hamaguchi why the&nbsp;<em>Final Fantasy VII Remake</em> games have had staggered releases on PC, rather than launching day and date with their <a title="Platforms > PlayStation [46,779 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation">PlayStation</a> versions.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Hamaguchi explained, “First off, the&nbsp;<em><a title="Series > Final Fantasy [136 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/final-fantasy">Final Fantasy</a></em> brand and franchise, and by extension, <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,329 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a>, have built a very strong partnership with <a title="Companies > Sony Interactive Entertainment [4,943 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sony-group-corporation/sony-interactive-entertainment">Sony Interactive Entertainment</a>. I strongly hope this continues going forward. However, it’s also true that we are no longer in an era where limiting the hardware on which you can play&nbsp; offers only substantial benefits. In fact, we’ve been seeing more and more cases where [Sony Interactive Entertainment]’s titles are being released for PC in addition to PlayStation 5.</p><p>“Through this&nbsp;<em>Remake</em> project, we also realized this shift, and have <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/square-enix-announces-new-medium-term-business-plan-square-enix-reboots-and-awakens-3-years-of-foundation-laying-for-long-term-growth">announced</a> as a company that we will be gearing towards multiplatform development. New [intellectual property] will be developed along these lines, so I personally believe it to be inevitable that console and PC versions will be released at the same time, or extremely close to each other, going forward.”</p><p>Later on in the interview, after Kitase’s comment about the third game not being exclusive to the next generation of consoles, Hamaguchi said,. “As I said earlier, going forward, [Square Enix] plans to release titles across a wide range of platforms so that more people can enjoy them. While I can’t make any promises at this point, we want our games to be played by as many people as possible, so we’ll do our best.”</p><p><em>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</em> first launched for PlayStation 5 on February 29, 2024. The PC version launched via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2909400/FINAL_FANTASY_VII_REBIRTH/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/final-fantasy-vii-rebirth" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Games Store</a> today.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Trading Card Game Pocket's Second Set Is All About Sinnoh]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-trading-card-game-pockets-second-set-is-all-about-sinnoh/1100-6528976/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-trading-card-game-pockets-second-set-is-all-about-sinnoh.1089897/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-trading-card-game-pockets-second-set-is-all-about-sinnoh/1100-6528976/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528976">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Since its launch in October, Pokemon Trading Card Game Pocket has quickly become one of Pokemon's most popular mobile apps, achieving the <a href="https://press.pokemon.com/en/releases/Pokemon-Trading-Card-Game-Pocket-Celebrates-60-Million-Downloads-Since" rel="nofollow ">60 million download mark</a> in only two months--and at least one player hitting <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-pocket-player-has-spent-a-ludicrous-amount-of-money-on-the-game/1100-6528963/">over 50,000 individual cards in their collection</a>. Today, The Pokemon Company confirmed details on the game's first major expansion, Spacetime Smackdown, which is set to launch on January 30.</p><p dir="ltr">Spacetime Smackdown places a spotlight on the Diamond and Pearl generation of Pokemon, as it highlights species introduced in the Sinnoh Region--with legendary Pokemon Dialga and Palkia taking center stage on the set's two pack options. All three starter Pokemon from Sinnoh--Turtwig, Chimchar, and Piplup--will make their Pokemon TCG Pocket debut in this new set, along with the fan favorite Fighting-type Lucario.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1165025019" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465623,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Pok%C3%A9mon%20TCG%20Pocket%3A%20Space-Time%20Smackdown%20%7C%20Coming%20Soon%21&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:48,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/pokemon-tcg-pocket-space-time-smackdown-coming-soon\/2300-6465623\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465623\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465623\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465623\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465623&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4432497-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/7yp5Dn1V.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1737645780,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="7yp5Dn1V" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> Pokémon TCG Pocket: Space-Time Smackdown | Coming Soon!</p>
      </div>
<p>The Pokemon Company has also confirmed that the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-tcg-pocket-is-finally-adding-a-trading-system/1100-6528883/" data-ref-id="1100-6528883">previously announced trading feature</a> will be added to Pokemon TCG Pocket on January 29, one day before the launch of Spacetime Smackdown. Players will be able to trade cards with registered friends in the app using two new items--Trade Hourglasses and Trade Tokens.</p><p dir="ltr">The trade feature will have some limitations, however, as only cards from Genetic Apex and Mythical Island can be selected for trade. Furthermore, trades will be limited to cards of certain rarities, and cards must be traded for cards of the same rarity in order for the trade to be successful.</p><p dir="ltr">Pokemon Trading Card Game Pocket is available to download now for free on both iOS and Android devices.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Of The Most Stylish Racing Games Is Getting An Offroading Successor]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-of-the-most-stylish-racing-games-is-getting-an-offroading-successor/1100-6528978/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/one-of-the-most-stylish-racing-games-is-getting-an-offroading-successor.1089894/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/one-of-the-most-stylish-racing-games-is-getting-an-offroading-successor/1100-6528978/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6528978">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Funselektor and Strelka Games have announced Over the Hill, a new stylish driving game that takes the elegant presentation established in <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/art-of-rally/" data-ref-id="5000-496661">Art of Rally</a> and applies it to offroading.</p><p>Officially stylized in all lowercase letters as "over the hill," this new indie racing game will hit many of the same notes as 2020's Art of Rally. That previous racer from Funselektor stood out in a sea of indie games because of its stylish presentation that stripped back all the fluff common in rally racing games. Its controls and car handling still felt authentic, like a simulation racing game, but Art of Rally plays from a top-down perspective and lets players drive through vibrant tracks. Over the Hill takes many of those design tenants and applies them to a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/expeditions-a-mudrunner-game/" data-ref-id="5000-599973">MudRunner</a>-style offroad exploration game.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1912498343" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465620,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;over%20the%20hill%20-%20Announcement%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:48,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/over-the-hill-announcement-trailer\/2300-6465620\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465620\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465620\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465620\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465620&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4432489-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/CXPljgpb.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1737644160,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="CXPljgpb" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> over the hill - Announcement Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p>In Over the Hill, players explore different offroading locales connected by portals. It supports single-player and co-op with up to four player, and Funselektor populated each area with many challenges to complete and hidden collectibles to find. It won't always be easy to drive from one point to another, as players will have to account for Over the Hill's day-night cycle, dynamic weather, and other environmental obstacles that require tools to overcome. Over the Hill plays quite differently from Art of Rally, but Funselektor founder Dune Casu explained why the studio went this route for a follow-up.</p><p>"After having developed several games about motorsport, we wanted to go off-track by offering players a vast world to lose themselves at a slower pace," Casu said in a press release. "In a way, this game is similar to the experience I've had journeying across North America in my trusty camper van. There's something special about being in the wilderness in the middle of nowhere, from the peace, the sounds of nature, and less distraction from the civilized world. I hope this game can really drive that feeling home.</p><p><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2929250/over_the_hill/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Over the Hill</a> will launch on PC via Steam sometime in 2025.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/107508578270426893025?rel=author">Tomas Franzese</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Circana US Sales Data Reveals 2024's Top-Selling Games]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/circana-us-sales-data-2024-top-selling-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-circana-us-sales-data-reveals-2024s-top-selling-games.1089882/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/circana-us-sales-data-2024-top-selling-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>US sales analysis group Circana has released its gaming industry sales data for 2024 as a whole, and you'll never guess which of the year's biggest releases topped the charts.</p>

<p>As ever, this data comes from Circana's Mat Piscatella on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lgg2dhbzzk2n" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Bluesky</a>, and it crowns none other than&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6&nbsp;</em>as the year's best-selling title.</p>

<p>That's not surprising given that Microsoft has called&nbsp;<em>Black Ops 6</em>'s launch <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/call-of-duty-series-sales-black-ops-6-launch" rel="nofollow">the franchise's biggest yet</a>, but it will probably come as something of a relief given that the game was also made available <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-will-be-on-game-pass-day-1" rel="nofollow">on Game Pass on day one</a>. Looks like that decision didn't do much to dampen its sales.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-best-selling-game-us-sales-data-circana.jpg?itok=dA1uCHGo 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-best-selling-game-us-sales-data-circana.jpg?itok=f442NDfx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Black Ops 6&nbsp;</em>has, perhaps unsurprisingly, taken the crown of 2024's best-selling game in the US.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Black Ops 6</em>'s performance will also doubtless come as a relief to Microsoft and Activision given how much the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ballooning-call-of-duty-budgets" rel="nofollow">series' budgets appear to have ballooned</a> in recent years;&nbsp;<em>Call of Duty&nbsp;</em>really is too big to fail, so it'll be reassuring that this one didn't.</p>

<p>In second place on the all-format sales chart, it's&nbsp;<em>EA Sports College Football 25</em>, which, again, won't come as much of a surprise given that the game recently swiped the crown of the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/ea-sports-college-football-25-best-selling-sports-game" rel="nofollow">best-selling sports game in US history</a>.</p>

<p><em>Helldivers 2</em>, which was sitting at <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sony-financials-helldivers-2-sales" rel="nofollow">12 million sales at last count</a>, takes third place, while the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dragon-ball-sparking-zero-sales-3m" rel="nofollow">hugely successful</a>&nbsp;<em>Dragon Ball: Sparking! Zero&nbsp;</em>takes fourth place.&nbsp;<em>NBA 2K25&nbsp;</em>is in fifth.</p>

<p>In terms of platform-specific charts, it's a tussle between&nbsp;<em>Black Ops 6&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>EA Sports College Football 25&nbsp;</em>for PlayStation and Xbox, with&nbsp;<em>Black Ops 6&nbsp;</em>topping <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lgg2djbuyk2n" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Sony's chart</a> and&nbsp;<em>College Football&nbsp;</em>reaching number one on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lgg2dkxnp22n" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Microsoft's</a>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/ea-sports-college-football-25-circana-us-sales-data.jpg?itok=Bn96CzFP 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/ea-sports-college-football-25-circana-us-sales-data.jpg?itok=DUTTzKXX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>EA Sports College Football 25&nbsp;</em>has sold remarkably well.</figcaption></figure><p>Since neither game was released on the Nintendo Switch, it probably won't come as a surprise to learn that both&nbsp;<em>Black Ops 6&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>College Football 25&nbsp;</em>are completely absent from Nintendo's table.</p>

<p>Instead, it's topped by&nbsp;<em>Super Mario Party Jamboree</em>, with&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe&nbsp;</em>taking up second place and&nbsp;<em>The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom&nbsp;</em>in third.&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart&nbsp;</em>really is unstoppable, eh?</p>

<p>You can check out Piscatella's full Bluesky thread, which begins with data specific to December 2024 then widens up to encapsulate the whole year, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matpiscatella.bsky.social/post/3lgg2ddgpqc2n" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">right here</a>. As always, it's worth a look if you're a numbers nerd!</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't Nod's Lost Records: Bloom & Rage Part 2 Delayed By a Month]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lost-records-bloom-rage-part-2-delayed</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dont-nods-lost-records-bloom-rage-part-2-delayed-by-a-month.1089879/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lost-records-bloom-rage-part-2-delayed<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Don't Nod has delayed the second part of upcoming adventure game <i>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage</i>. The game's second chapter is now set to launch around a month later than its originally-intended release date.</p>

<p>In an FAQ answering questions about&nbsp;<em>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage</em>, Don't Nod says the delay was put into effect in order to give the devs time to "refine the experience, address more bugs, and enhance the storytelling". It sounds like the usual delay reasoning, by and large.</p>

<p>The studio says that it's "confident" the delay will allow it to "provide you with a richer experience", and that it has "a little something up [its sleeve] on social media to keep you entertained in the time between the two Tapes" (i.e. chapters).</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/dont-nod-lost-records-bloom-rage-second-part-delayed.jpg?itok=MXcUjlpo 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/dont-nod-lost-records-bloom-rage-second-part-delayed.jpg?itok=v_Hv5wXx 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage</em>'s second part will be delayed by around a month.</figcaption></figure><p>The second part of&nbsp;<em>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage</em>, which is also known as "Rage",&nbsp;is now set to arrive on April 15th. This delay won't affect the first part (also known, surprisingly enough, as "Bloom"), which is still set to launch on February 18th.</p>

<p>If you're wondering exactly what&nbsp;<em>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage&nbsp;</em>is, Don't Nod's FAQ explains it pretty succinctly: it's a "single-player experience focused on narrative exploration" that revolves around four friends confronting the dark secrets of something that happened to them 27 years ago.</p>

<p>You'll be able to navigate between the 1995 and 2022 timelines and "shape both narratives" as you go, uncovering the truth of the sleepy Michigan town of Velvet Cove and what may or may not lie beneath its surface (spoilers, though: something definitely does).</p>




<p>This isn't the first time the game has been delayed in some form or another. <em>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage&nbsp;</em>was originally set for release in 2024, but back in <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lost-records-bloom-and-rage-delay" rel="nofollow">June last year</a>, Don't Nod pushed its launch back to 2025.</p>

<p>The studio will no doubt be banking on&nbsp;<em>Lost Records</em>' success for two reasons: to offset the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/dont-nod-financials-first-half-2024" rel="nofollow">recent underperformance</a> of some of its games and to launch what is supposed to be a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/lost-records-bloom-and-rage-by-life-is-strange-devs-is-first-game-in-much-larger" rel="nofollow">wider universe of interconnected media</a>.</p>

<p><em>Lost Records: Bloom &amp; Rage&nbsp;</em>will launch on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1902960/Lost_Records_Bloom__Rage/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a>, <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/lost-records-bloom-and-rage/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a>, and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/lost-records-bloom-rage/9n3f1lw9hc6c" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. The first part is due to arrive on February 18th, and the second will be released on April 15th.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokémon TCG Pocket's Next Set Is a Diamond and Pearl-Themed Booster Called Space-Time Smackdown]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-pockets-next-set-is-a-diamond-and-pearl-themed-booster-called-space-time-smackdown</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-tcg-pockets-next-set-is-a-diamond-and-pearl-themed-booster-called-space-time-smackdown.1089867/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-pockets-next-set-is-a-diamond-and-pearl-themed-booster-called-space-time-smackdown<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Pokémon Trading Card Game Pocket's next set is a Diamond and Pearl-themed booster called Space-Time Smackdown, and it launches next week.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Pokémon Company revealed the set arrives January 29 in a trailer, below, but its <a href="https://www.pokemon.com/us/pokemon-news/explore-pokemon-tcg-pockets-newest-expansion-space-time-smackdown" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">website</a> currently lists a January 30 date. Space-Time Smackdown includes the likes of Dialga ex and Palkia ex alongside the generation four starter Pokémon: Turtwig, Chimchar, and Piplup.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Despite being the second full set, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-pocket-reveals-mew-led-set-coming-next-week-and-60-million-download-milestone">unlike the expansion set that was Mythical Island</a>, Space-Time Smackdown features between just 140 and 150 cards. This should make it significantly easier to complete compared to set one, Genetic Apex, which includes 286 cards. It's unclear if this 140 to 150 number includes the alternate art pieces, however, which could bump up that number by a few dozen.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">"Are you ready to rumble? Discover a whole new expansion’s worth of cards in Pokémon Trading Card Game Pocket," The Pokémon Company said. "Legendary Pokémon Dialga and Palkia from the Sinnoh region have bent time and space to rule the battlefield as dimension-altering Pokémon ex.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The Space-Time Smackdown expansion features over 140 cards including exciting Pokémon ex cards, new Trainer cards, and gorgeous immersive cards ready to bring you into the wondrous world of Pokémon."</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-pocket-trading-unveiled-but-is-so-poorly-received-the-developers-had-to-respond">The widely panned trading feature</a> was also confirmed to arrive alongside this set.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Pokémon TCG Pocket arrived in October and follows the standard mobile and free-to-play game model, flooding players with rewards in the first few days before soon drying up, with spending real-world money the only real way to re-experience that early thrill outside of the occasional set drop like this one.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Completing Genetic Apex without spending money, for example, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/it-takes-almost-2-years-to-complete-just-the-first-pokmon-tcg-pocket-set-unless-you-spend-money">will take players around two years according to one estimate</a>, while <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/pokmon-tcg-pocket-player-reveals-exactly-how-long-it-takes-to-complete-the-first-set-after-spending-1500">those looking to make it rain can wrap up the collection after dropping around $1,500</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red Solstice 2: Survivors Ultimate Edition now available for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, and Xbox One]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/red-solstice-2-survivors-ultimate-edition-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/red-solstice-2-survivors-ultimate-edition-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one.1089864/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2025/01/red-solstice-2-survivors-ultimate-edition-now-available-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-and-xbox-one<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Includes the base game and all downloadable content.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > 505 Games [294 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/digital-bros/505-games">505 Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Ironward [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/ironward">Ironward</a> have released <a title="Genres > Real-Time Strategy [114 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/real-time-strategy">real-time strategy game</a> <em><a title="Games > Red Solstice 2: Survivors Ultimate Edition [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/red-solstice-2-survivors-ultimate-edition">Red Solstice 2: Survivors Ultimate Edition</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,694 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [6,595 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,613 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, and <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,716 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a> for $29.99, the companies announced. <span id="more-894748"></span></p><p><em><a title="Games > Red Solstice 2: Survivors" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/red-solstice-2-survivors">Red Solstice 2: Survivors</a></em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/768520/Red_Solstice_2_Survivors/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on June 17, 2021. <em>Red Solstice 2: Survivors Ultimate Edition</em> includes the base game and all previously released downloadable content.</p><p>Here is an overview of the <em>Ultimate Edition</em>, via 505 Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Plan your strategy and undertake real-time combat missions, in this sequel to the best-selling tactical game, Red Solstice!</p><p>The <em>Red Solstice 2: Survivors Ultimate Edition</em> contains the base game, as well as all previously released downloadable content, including new story lines, classes, maps, and much more!</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Prove yourself in this tactical science-fiction <a title="Genres > RPG [16,943 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg">RPG</a> combining real-time strategy with real-time combat, playable in single-player or <a title="Genres > Co-Op [228 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer/co-op">cooperative</a> with up to three friends.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Real-Time <a title="Genres > Strategy [214 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/strategy">Strategy</a> Controls</strong> – Plan your moves and issue orders to your squad in real-time.</li><li><strong><a title="Genres > Survival [370 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">Survival</a> Strategy</strong> – <a title="Series > Mana [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/mana">Mana</a>ge your resources, research new technologies, and build up your base to survive.</li><li><strong>Real-Time Tactical Battlefield</strong> – Engage in intense combat with the mutant infestation.</li><li><strong>Combat Missions</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> three different mission types.</li><li><strong>Three Mission Types</strong> – Over 15 main missions and more than 30 side missions included in the base game, with each having a different mission type (exploration, <a title="Genres > Stealth [73 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/stealth">stealth</a>, and survival).</li><li><strong>Unique Classes</strong> – Choose from a variety of classes to suit your playstyle.</li><li><strong>Four-Player Cooperative Play</strong> – Play with up to three friends in online cooperative including cross-play between PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 4 / Xbox Series and Xbox One.</li><li><strong>Powerful Weapons</strong> – Wield a variety of powerful weapons to take down the mutants.</li><li><strong>Biomass Infestation</strong> – The biomass infestation is constantly evolving, so you’ll need to adapt your strategies accordingly.</li></ul><p>The Ultimate Edition Includes:</p><ul><li><strong>The base game</strong>.</li><li><strong>Skins</strong> – The <em>Red Solstice 2: Survivors Ultimate Edition</em> includes the Frogsheoth Armor and Dragon in-game skins.</li><li><strong>Howell-Barrex Inc.</strong> – New campaign story, UBAS (Universal <a title="Games > Biped [6 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/biped">Biped</a>al Armored System), Engineer Suit and new tech tree. Including 11 story and five secondary missions.</li><li><strong>Condatis Group</strong> – New campaign story, Psychic Suit, platoons, and new game feel. Including 10 story and seven secondary missions.</li><li><strong>Insurgents</strong> – New campaign story, weapon modding, and new tech tree. Including 13 story and 13 secondary missions.</li><li><strong>M.E.R.C.S.</strong> – New campaign story, drivable vehicles, and new tech tree. Including 10 story and 14 secondary missions.</li><li><strong>Over 70 additional critical strike missions</strong> added to the base game and campaigns.</li><li><strong>Additional 12 grand missions</strong> added (three per campaign).</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Red Solstice 2 | Console Launch - Ultimate Edition Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7DRwbHsaczI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Celeste Devs Cancel Next Game Earthblade Due to Studio "Disagreement"]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/earthblade-canceled-celeste-devs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/celeste-devs-cancel-next-game-earthblade-due-to-studio-disagreement.1089843/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/earthblade-canceled-celeste-devs<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Celeste&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Towerfall&nbsp;</em>studio Extremely OK Games has revealed that its ambitious Metroidvania platformer&nbsp;<em>Earthblade&nbsp;</em>has been canceled owing to an internal studio dispute.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://exok.com/posts/2025-01-22-earthblade-final-update/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on the official EXOK website titled "Final&nbsp;<em>Earthblade&nbsp;</em>Update" (just in case you weren't absolutely sure the game was done), the studio describes the cancellation as "a huge, heartbreaking, and yet relieving failure". EXOK head Maddy Thorson says the decision to cancel was actually made in December.</p>

<p>According to Thorson, a "fracture" began forming in 2024, with her and coworker Noel Berry on one side and art director Pedro Medeiros on another. Specifically, the dispute revolved around "the IP rights of&nbsp;<em>Celeste</em>", and it's a dispute Thorson says she "won't be detailing publicly".</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/earthblade-canceled-celeste-developers-platforming.jpg?itok=VVIxJQhI 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/earthblade-canceled-celeste-developers-platforming.jpg?itok=MB3WBn6G 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ambitious-looking Metroidvania&nbsp;<em>Earthblade&nbsp;</em>has been canceled.</figcaption></figure><p>The dispute, which Thorson calls "a very difficult and heartbreaking process", was eventually resolved, but she and Berry eventually agreed to go their separate ways with Medeiros, who originally announced his departure from EXOK <a href="https://x.com/saint11/status/1857481536335131092" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">back in November</a>.</p>

<p>Thorson says that the dispute with Medeiros caused her and Berry to take a look at&nbsp;<em>Earthblade&nbsp;</em>and ask themselves whether continuing its development would be "worth the pain". Together, they concluded that working on the game had become "exhausting", leading them to "admit defeat".</p>

<p>She also goes on to say that fans shouldn't blame Medeiros, and that he and the team on his game&nbsp;<em>Neverway&nbsp;</em>"aren't the enemy". Treating them as such will make you unwelcome "in any EXOK community", she says.</p>




<p>If you're wondering exactly what&nbsp;<em>Earthblade&nbsp;</em>is (or was), it was an exploration-based action platformer that would have offered "seamless exploration, challenging combat, and countless mysteries to pick apart".</p>

<p>Originally <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/earthblade-revealed-as-new-game-from-celeste-developers" rel="nofollow">revealed in 2021</a>, EXOK announced in early 2024 that&nbsp;<em>Earthblade&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/celeste-creator-earthblade-delayed" rel="nofollow">wouldn't be coming out that year</a>. It's very likely the studio had already begun to grapple with the problems that would cause the game's cancellation even then.</p>

<p>As for what's next for EXOK, Thorson says the goal now is to "wipe the slate clean" and to "refocus...back to smaller-scale projects". We'll have to wait and see where that goes in future.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>