<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 09:55:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["AI protections remain the sticking point" for today’s SAG-AFTRA game actor strike]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ai-protections-remain-the-sticking-point-for-todays-sag-aftra-game-actor-strike</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ai-protections-remain-the-sticking-point-for-today%E2%80%99s-sag-aftra-game-actor-strike.937395/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/ai-protections-remain-the-sticking-point-for-todays-sag-aftra-game-actor-strike<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>"We’re not going to consent to a contract that allows companies to abuse AI to the detriment of our members", says president</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/yakuza-kiryu-singing.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>SEGA</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>As of today, the The Screen Actors Guild-American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (SAG-AFTRA) has called a strike of the Interactive Media Agreement - effectively, video game voice acting, motion capture work, and other roles, the full list of which can be found <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/contracts-industry-resources/contracts/video-game-strike/ima-strike-notice-members">here</a>. The strike comes after over 18 months of negotiations with some of gaming’s largest companies - including Activision, EA, Insomniac, Take-Two, and WB Games - over AI protections.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Any game looking to employ SAG-AFTRA talent to perform covered work must sign on" to agreements <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sag-aftra-members-who-work-video-games-go-strike">specified in a post</a> by the guild, “These agreements offer critical AI protections for members."</p>
<p>"We’re not going to consent to a contract that allows companies to abuse AI to the detriment of our members," said president Fran Drescher. "Enough is enough. When these companies get serious about offering an agreement our members can live — and work — with, we will be here, ready to negotiate."</p>
<p>"The video game industry generates billions of dollars in profit annually. The driving force behind that success is the creative people who design and create those games," said national executive director and chief negotiator Duncan Crabtree-Ireland. "That includes the SAG-AFTRA members who bring memorable and beloved game characters to life, and they deserve and demand the same fundamental protections as performers in film, television, streaming, and music: fair compensation and the right of informed consent for the AI use of their faces, voices, and bodies."</p>
<p>"Eighteen months of negotiations have shown us that our employers are not interested in fair, reasonable AI protections, but rather flagrant exploitation," said Interactive Media Agreement Negotiating Committee Chair Sarah Elmaleh. "We will not leave any of our members behind, nor will we wait for sufficient protection any longer. We look forward to collaborating with teams on our Interim and Independent contracts, which provide AI transparency, consent and compensation to all performers, and to continuing to negotiate in good faith with this bargaining group when they are ready to join us in the world we all deserve."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/best-immersive-sims-deus-ex-mankind-divided-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Eidos Interactive</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The strike was <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23885558/sag-aftra-strike-authorization-negotiation-video-game-voice-actors">voted for</a> in 2023, and marks the second of it’s type since 2016, where videogame actors at SAG-AFTRA went on strike for almost a year. This January, SAG-AFTRA struck a deal to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/actors-union-sag-aftra-strike-deal-to-allow-ai-voice-replicas-and-video-game-stars-are-understandably-pissed">allow AI voice replicas under licence</a> with company REPLICA, which drew criticism from several prominent actors who felt blindsided and betrayed by the development. "I would humbly consider myself one of the top voice actors working in games," wrote <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/deus-ex-human-revolution">Deux Ex</a> actor Elias Toufexis. "From what I'm seeing, no one asked any of my peers either."</p>
<p>Last December, union ZeniMax Workers United <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/microsoft-and-zenimax-union-reach-first-of-its-kind-agreement-over-usage-of-ai-tools-in-gamedev">came to a "first of its kind" agreement</a> with Microsoft over the usage of AI tools in game development. Per the agreement, ZeniMax will "provide notice to the union in cases where AI implementation may impact the work of union members," with the union able to bargain.</p>
<p>AI remains a hot button issue, to put it mildly, and undoubtedly a factor in the staggering number of layoffs across the industry over the past two years, as the sort of people who choose to involve themselves in art despite seemingly have nothing but contempt for both artists and the art itself jump on cost-cutting measures with avaricious glee.</p>
<p>This strike, at least, comes at the end of a week filled with heartening developments, with two large wall-to-wall unions formed under Microsoft by workers at <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/bethesda-game-studios-developers-ecstatic-to-announce-a-241-strong-wall-to-wall-union">Bethesda Game Studios</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/over-500-world-of-warcraft-developers-at-blizzard-have-voted-to-form-microsofts-biggest-wall-to-wall-union">at Blizzard</a>. If you want to find out whether a game you either play or are looking forward to playing is under the scope of the strike, you can search <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/videogamestrike#production_search_result">here</a>. If anyone harasses anyone over this, I will personally escort you to the nearest bin and seal the lid with hot glue. Don’t be a scab now.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver I & II Remastered May Be in the Works]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-i-ii-remastered/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-i-ii-remastered-may-be-in-the-works.937392/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-i-ii-remastered/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The two Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver games could get remastered in the future, judging from some pictures taken during this year's San Diego Comic-Con.</p>
<p>As shared on the <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-i-ii-remastered-branding-seen-at-sdcc.937002/">ResetERA forums</a> by user Mama Robotnik, two statues depicting Cain and Raziel are being shown during the event with a Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver I &amp; II Remastered branding. The attached QR Code leads to a Dark Horse newsletter sign-up, so something is definitely brewing. Original developer Crystal Dynamics has yet to make any announcement, but with the branding being out, it's likely that one is not too far off in the future.</p>
<p>It has been a very long time since the release of any Legacy of Kain game. The final one, <a href="https://wccftech.com/legacy-of-kain-defiance-looks-incredible-with-reshade-ray-tracing/">Defiance</a>, was released back in 2003, bringing a close to both Kain and Raziel's stories and, apparently, the series as a whole. The game was supposed to be followed by the multiplayer title Nosgoth, which reached an open beta stage in early 2015 but was eventually canceled with the servers shutting down in 2016. Hopefully, the two remasters will pave the way for more remasters to offer modern players the chance to experience the entirety of the series and a new entry in what I personally consider one of the best gaming series of all time.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SAG-AFTRA Videogame Strike Now in Effect Due to AI Concerns, Potentially Leading to Game Delays]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/sag-aftra-videogame-strike-now-in-effect-due-to-ai-concerns-potentially-leading-to-game-delays/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sag-aftra-videogame-strike-now-in-effect-due-to-ai-concerns-potentially-leading-to-game-delays.937386/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/sag-aftra-videogame-strike-now-in-effect-due-to-ai-concerns-potentially-leading-to-game-delays/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Yesterday, SAG-AFTRA <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sag-aftra-members-who-work-video-games-go-strike" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced</a> that its members have voted on a videogame strike after over a year and a half of negotiations with game developers and publishers.</p>
<p>24 of the 25 sticking points have been agreed upon. However, the remaining point is a big one: AI. SAG-AFTRA president Fran Drescher said in a statement:</p>
<p><em>We’re not going to consent to a contract that allows companies to abuse A.I. to the detriment of our members. Enough is enough. When these companies get serious about offering an agreement our members can live — and work — with, we will be here, ready to negotiate.</em></p>
<p>National Executive Director &amp; Chief Negotiator Duncan Crabtree-Ireland stated:</p>
<p><em>The video game industry generates billions of dollars in profit annually. The driving force behind that success is the creative people who design and create those games. That includes the SAG-AFTRA members who bring memorable and beloved game characters to life, and they deserve and demand the same fundamental protections as performers in film, television, streaming, and music: fair compensation and the right of informed consent for the A.I. use of their faces, voices, and bodies. Frankly, it’s stunning that these video game studios haven’t learned anything from the lessons of last year - that our members can and will stand up and demand fair and equitable treatment with respect to A.I., and the public supports us in that.</em></p>
<p>Interactive Media Agreement Negotiating Committee Chair Sarah Elmaleh added:</p>
<p><em>Eighteen months of negotiations have shown us that our employers are not interested in fair, reasonable A.I. protections, but rather flagrant exploitation. We refuse this paradigm – we will not leave any of our members behind, nor will we wait for sufficient protection any longer. We look forward to collaborating with teams on our Interim and Independent contracts, which provide A.I. transparency, consent and compensation to all performers, and to continuing to negotiate in good faith with this bargaining group when they are ready to join us in the world we all deserve.</em></p>
<p>For its part, Audrey Cooling, a spokesperson for the main negotiation group that includes Activision Productions Inc., Blindlight LLC, Disney Character Voices Inc., Electronic Arts Productions Inc., Formosa Interactive LLC, Insomniac Games Inc., Llama Productions LLC, Take 2 Productions Inc., VoiceWorks Productions Inc., and WB Games Inc, stated:</p>
<p><em>We are disappointed the union has chosen to walk away when we are so close to a deal, and we remain prepared to resume negotiations. We have already found common ground on 24 out of 25 proposals, including historic wage increases and additional safety provisions. Our offer is directly responsive to SAG-AFTRA’s concerns and extends meaningful AI protections that include requiring consent and fair compensation to all performers working under the IMA. These terms are among the strongest in the entertainment industry.</em></p>
<p>While such strikes in the gaming industry aren't nearly as crippling as they are for movies or TV shows, they could still result in delays. The massively anticipated GTA 6 could be one of those games, according to a quick search in <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/videogamestrike#production_search_result" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SAG-AFTRA's videogame status database</a>.</p>
<p>Needless to say, let's hope an agreement can be reached shortly.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earth Defense Force 6 players on Steam will only need to sign into Epic once, say publishers in apology for "lack of advance notice"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/earth-defense-force-6-players-on-steam-will-only-need-to-sign-into-epic-once-say-publishers-in-apology-for-lack-of-advance-notice</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/earth-defense-force-6-players-on-steam-will-only-need-to-sign-into-epic-once-say-publishers-in-apology-for-lack-of-advance-notice.937377/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/earth-defense-force-6-players-on-steam-will-only-need-to-sign-into-epic-once-say-publishers-in-apology-for-lack-of-advance-notice<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>Ant-agonising requirements</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ss_0283233911baf1012766df91c7a121a7cf32058b.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>SANDLOT</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/earth-defense-force-6">Earth Defense Force 6</a> players on Steam aren’t happy about having to sign into the Epic Games Store, it seems. The latest entry in the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-co-op-games">co-op</a> ant-control shooter launched yesterday, and critics reckon it's a decent time. Still, it’s currently sitting at an angry red 'mostly negative' on Steam. In response, D3PUBLISHER have put out an <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2291060/view/4361257526914035378?l=english">apology statement</a>, reassuring players that this third-party log in will only be required once.</p>

<p>"For this game, to enhance cross play and online functionality. Online play requires signing in to your Epic Games account. We apologize for the lack of advance notice," reads the statement. "Signing in to your Epic Games account is required the first time you play online. Usually, once you sign in for the first time, you will not need to sign in again." It then goes on to give helpful instructions for creating a free Epic account.</p> <figure>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/io_UDlG6KyY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" height="113" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" title="EARTH DEFENSE FORCE 6 - Release Date Trailer" width="200"></iframe><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span>
</figure>
<p>That "lack of advance notice" part seems to be key. While the game’s Steam page has now been updated to show that the game requires an Epic Online Services account for online play, D3PUBLISHER neglected to inform players beforhand. Personally, I feel it’s worth everyone signing up for Epic anyway, because free things are nice, but it does seem like the sort of thing it would have been triflingly easy for the publisher to be transparent about instead of apologising after the fact.</p>
<p>This doesn't mean it's likely any less disheartening for the developers, however, and I do often wonder about the logistics of having two seperate user review categories on Steam so these kind of issues don't spill over into tarnishing the perception of a game's actual quality. Although, even typing this now, I can sense how utterly naive that probably sounds. No-one wants double the clown emojis. </p>
<p>This is the first title in the Earth Defense Force series to require such a third party login. It is not the first in the series to require that you kill an alarming number of big ants, however. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/earth-defense-force-5-review">I quite liked</a> Earth Defense Force 5 when I played it for review. "A thoroughly confident and largely successful game that seems solely designed for you and some mates to laugh with it, at it, and at yourselves until the frogs come home," wrote I. "It’s camp, sure, but as Susan Sontag put it, 'Oh no! The bugs, they’re everywhere! The frogs! They’re too big!'" I have since learned that quote was anachronistic, however. It was actually John Waters.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BioShock Film Is Still Going Forward, Albeit with a Reduced Budget]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/bioshock-film-is-still-going-forward-albeit-with-a-reduced-budget/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bioshock-film-is-still-going-forward-albeit-with-a-reduced-budget.937374/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/bioshock-film-is-still-going-forward-albeit-with-a-reduced-budget/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>In February 2022, Take-Two and Netflix <a href="https://wccftech.com/bioshock-movie-adaptation-in-the-works-at-netflix/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">partnered</a> to create a live action film adaptation of the BioShock game franchise. Around six months later, we <a href="https://wccftech.com/bioshock-film-adaptation-will-be-directed-by-hunger-games-francis-lawrence/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">learned</a> that Francis Lawrence, the director of Hunger Games, Constantine, I Am Legend, Sparrow, and Slumberland, would be taking care of the project.</p>
<p>Later that year, Lawrence himself <a href="https://wccftech.com/bioshock-movie-has-ken-levine-involved-in-some-capacity-director-explains-what-makes-the-ip-unique/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">talked</a> about what makes BioShock unique. He also confirmed that franchise creator Ken Levine would be involved in some capacity.</p>
<p>We haven't heard any further news about the BioShock film for a long while. Now, Variety has <a href="https://variety.com/2024/film/news/bioshock-movie-scaled-down-netflix-more-personal-1236085711/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">published</a> some news that came out of San Diego Comic-Con 2024, where producer Rory Lee said in a panel:</p>
<p><em>The new regime has lowered the budgets, so we’re doing a much smaller version. … It’s going to be a more personal point of view as opposed to a grander, big project.</em></p>
<p>That's all Lee had to share about the project, though he also confirmed that Francis Lawrence is still attached to direct. The thing is, the movie director also has many other movies to handle.</p>
<p>Production is currently ongoing for The Long Walk (an adaptation of the 1979 dystopian horror novel penned by Stephen King). The script of the long-awaited Constantine 2 is currently being written, as revealed at SDCC 2024, and I Am Legend 2 is being prepared as well. Moreover, Lawrence is also in talks to direct yet another The Hunger Games prequel titled Sunrise on the Reaping.</p>
<p>There's no word yet on when the BioShock movie will be produced, then, or even on the cast. Fans can't even take solace from any new games, as Cloud Chamber is still <a href="https://wccftech.com/bioshock-team-ramps-up-recruitment-with-30-job-offers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recruiting</a> for its next installment, hinting that the release is still a few years off. There was, however, a recent <a href="https://wccftech.com/bioshock-4-screenshot/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">leak</a> showing off the user interface and a ricochet gun.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TRIBE NINE ‘Shinagawa Chapter’ gameplay trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/tribe-nine-shinagawa-chapter-gameplay-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/tribe-nine-%E2%80%98shinagawa-chapter%E2%80%99-gameplay-trailer.937344/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/tribe-nine-shinagawa-chapter-gameplay-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Four minutes of new footage.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Akatsuki Games [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/akatsuki/akatsuki-games">Akatsuki Games</a> and <a title="Companies > Too Kyo Games [61 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/too-kyo-games">Too Kyo Games</a> have released a new gameplay trailer for <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [294 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> “extreme <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,253 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a>” <em><a title="Games > TRIBE NINE [4 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tribe-nine">TRIBE NINE</a></em> dubbed “Shinagawa Chapter.” <span id="more-901467"></span></p><p>Get the latest details below.</p><blockquote><p><strong>Revealing 17 Characters and ONe <a title="Companies > Creature [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/creature">Creature</a>(?) Appearing in the Global Beta Test!</strong></p><p>Alongside familiar characters from the anime, some new characters are also making their debut! <a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the immersive world and engaging story shaped by these diverse characters.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/TRIBE-NINE_2024_07-26-24_002.jpg"></a></figure><ul><li>Yo Kuronaka (voiced by Chiaki Kobayashi)</li><li>Sui Yakumo (voiced by Masaya Fukunishi)</li><li>Tsuki Iroha (voiced by Yuko Natsuyoshi)</li><li>Q (voiced by Junichi Suwabe)</li><li>Hyakuichitaro Senju (voiced by Ayumu Murase)</li><li>Miu Jujo (voiced by Tomoyo Kurosawa)</li><li>Koishi Kohinata (voiced by Marina Inoue)</li><li>Jio Takinogawa (voiced by Takahiro Sakurai)</li><li>Tsuruko Semba (voiced by Konomi Kohara)</li><li>Kazuki Aoyama (voiced by Shoya Chiba)</li><li>Enoki Yukigaya (voiced by Reina Kondo)</li><li>Yutaka Gotanda (voiced by Wataru Komada)</li><li>Eiji Todoroki (voiced by Kensho Ono)</li><li>Roku Saigo (voiced by Kenichiro Matsuda)</li><li>Minami Oi (voiced by Misato Murai)</li><li>Zero (voiced by Akira Ishida)</li><li>Kazuma Ichinose (voiced by Toshiyuki Morikawa)</li></ul><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><em>TRIBE NINE</em> is an extreme action RPG where groups of teens endure multiple losses and devise strategies to overcome formidable foes. Dive into a crazy <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,640 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> with unique characters in a meticulously crafted world with a variety of art styles by the same creators of the <em><a title="Series > Danganronpa [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/danganronpa">Danganronpa</a></em> series.</p></blockquote><p><em>TRIBE NINE</em> will be available for for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,734 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2376580/TRIBE_NINE/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a>, iOS, and Android. A release date has yet to be announced. A <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/tribe-nine-pc-closed-beta-test-set-for-august-9-to-15">PC closed beta test</a> will run from August 9 to 15. Read more about the game <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/06/tribe-nine-game-first-trailer-details-and-screenshots">here</a>.</p><p>Watch the trailer below. View a set of screenshots and character artwork <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/tribe-nine/july-26-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Gameplay Trailer: Shinagawa Chapter</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="TRIBE NINE | Gameplay Trailer: Shinagawa Chapter" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U7Q7Vxx8Lb4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="『トライブナイン』ゲームプレイトレーラー シナガワ篇" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wEx1ekhN-1A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Traditional Chinese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="『TRIBE NINE』遊戲畫面預告 品川篇" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/70XK3Rx3p1Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_901474"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves adds Billy Kane]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-adds-billy-kane</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-adds-billy-kane.937320/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-adds-billy-kane<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Kane returns with a deep grudge against Terry Bogard.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Billy Kane will be a playable character in <em><a title="Games > Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves [7 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves">Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</a></em>, <a title="Companies > SNK Corporation [391 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/snk">SNK</a> announced. <span id="more-901159"></span></p><p>Here is his character description, via SNK:</p><blockquote><p><strong>Billy Kane</strong> (voiced by Chris Sharpes in English, Masaki Masaki in Japanese)</p><p>As a loyal right-hand man to the infamous Geese Howard, Billy has taken the reins of the Howard Connection following his late mentor’s demise. Though he now leads the syndicate, he is consumed by the challenge of guiding his bereaved family of associates into a new era. One thing remains certain amidst the darkness and turmoil: Billy harbors a deep grudge against Terry Bogard, the man responsible for his master’s death.</p></blockquote><p><em>Fatal Fury: City of the Wolves</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,531 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,979 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,731 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,734 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2492040/FATAL_FURY_City_of_the_Wolves/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> and <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/garou-city-of-the-wolves-556c5a" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a> in early 2025.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below. View a new set of screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves/july-26-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span>Billy Kane Trailer</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe title="FATAL FURY: CotW ｜BILLY KANE" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e-XEdURwdeU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe title="餓狼伝説CotW ｜ビリー・カーン" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NLh2iAOOPnk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_901161"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fatal Fury: City Of The Wolves Adds Bo-Staff-Wielding Veteran Billy Kane To Its Roster]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-adds-bo-staff-wielding-veteran-billy-kane-to-its-roster/1100-6525287/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-adds-bo-staff-wielding-veteran-billy-kane-to-its-roster.937317/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-adds-bo-staff-wielding-veteran-billy-kane-to-its-roster/1100-6525287/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525287">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">During the ChinaJoy video game convention in Shanghai today--and less than a week after <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/kevin-rian-returns-in-fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-vice-and-mature-join-kof-xv/1100-6525133/">revealing Kevin Rian's return at Evo 2024</a>--SNK unveiled the next character to join the Fatal Fury: City Of The Wolves roster. Billy Kane, the bo-staff-wielding rival of Terry Bogard, will once again face off against his old foe in this new game.</p><p dir="ltr">The reveal trailer shows Billy using his bo staff in battle to give him extra range with attacks. A few of his most recognizable moves can be seen in the trailer, including his helicopter spinning attack, and he can still imbue the staff with fire for extra damage and flashy combos.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1476497809" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464674,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;FATAL%20FURY%3A%20City%20of%20the%20Wolves%EF%BD%9COfficial%20Billy%20Kane%20Character%20Gameplay%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:104,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves-official-billy-kane-character-gameplay-reveal-trailer\/2300-6464674\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464674\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464674\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464674\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464674&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464674,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6525287&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;fatal-fury-city-of-the-wolves&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;2d,action,fighting&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x,pc,playstation-4&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;snk-corporation&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;fatal-fury&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;fatal-fury&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464674},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464674\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4340420-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/OtYrmpOc.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1721966400,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="OtYrmpOc" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> FATAL FURY: City of the Wolves｜Official Billy Kane Character Gameplay Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<figure data-embed-type="gallery" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340395-billy2.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340396-billy3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340397-billy4.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340398-billy5.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340399-billy6.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340400-billy7.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340401-billy8.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340402-billy9.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340403-billy10.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340404-billy11.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340405-billy12.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340406-billy13.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4340395,1300-4340396,1300-4340397,1300-4340398,1300-4340399,1300-4340400,1300-4340401,1300-4340402,1300-4340403,1300-4340404,1300-4340405,1300-4340406" data-resize-urls="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340395-billy2.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340396-billy3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340397-billy4.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340398-billy5.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340399-billy6.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340400-billy7.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340401-billy8.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340402-billy9.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340403-billy10.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340404-billy11.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340405-billy12.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/square_avatar/3/37852/4340406-billy13.jpg"><p>Gallery</p>     <img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340395-billy2.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340396-billy3.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340397-billy4.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340398-billy5.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340399-billy6.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340400-billy7.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340401-billy8.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340402-billy9.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340403-billy10.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340404-billy11.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340405-billy12.jpg,https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4340406-billy13.jpg"></figure><p dir="ltr"><span>In City Of The Wolves, Billy finds himself leading the Howard Connection--previously led by series antagonist Geese Howard--after Geese's defeat and death. He is said to "harbor a deep grudge" against Terry for causing Geese's death, and he is looking to exact some revenge against his rival as a result.</span></p><p dir="ltr">Billy is the eighth character to join the City Of The Wolves roster, as he follows recent additions Kevin Rian, Marco Rodrigues, and B. Jenet. He has been playable in multiple Fatal Fury and King Of Fighters entries in the past, with his most recent appearance coming as a downloadable fighter in The King Of Fighters XV.</p><p dir="ltr">In other SNK news, the company recently re-released SNK Vs. Capcom: SVC Chaos on PC and consoles after announcing the revival at Evo 2024 last weekend. Elsewhere in fighting game news, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/tekken-8-is-bringing-back-heihachi-and-adding-a-new-story-chapter/1100-6525174/">Heihachi Mishima is set to return in Tekken 8</a> despite being thrown into a volcano at the end of the previous game, while Guilty Gear Strive will introduce its first-ever guest character--Lucy from Cyberpunk: Edgerunners--as part of its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/videos/guilty-gear-strive-season-4-official-teaser-trailer/2300-6464646/">Season 4 content</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">Fatal Fury: City Of The Wolves is set to launch in early 2025 for Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Castle of Shikigami III – Steam version crowdfunding campaign launched with console stretch goal]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/castle-of-shikigami-iii-steam-version-crowdfunding-campaign-launched-with-console-stretch-goal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/castle-of-shikigami-iii-%E2%80%93-steam-version-crowdfunding-campaign-launched-with-console-stretch-goal.937308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/castle-of-shikigami-iii-steam-version-crowdfunding-campaign-launched-with-console-stretch-goal<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Cosmo Machia hopes to re-release to shoot 'em up game.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Cosmo Machia [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/cosmo-machia">Cosmo Machia</a> has launched a <a href="https://camp-fire.jp/projects/view/771718" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Campfire crowdfunding campaign</a> to release <a title="Genres > Shoot 'Em Up [719 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up">shoot ’em up game</a> <em>Castle of Shikigami III</em> for <a title="Platforms > PC [20,734 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via Steam. <span id="more-901368"></span></p><p><em>Castle of Shikigami III</em> first launched for <a title="Genres > Arcade [57 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a> in February 2006 in Japan, followed by PC on September 29, 2006, and <a title="Platforms > Xbox 360 [9,999 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-360">Xbox 360</a> and <a title="Platforms > Wii [241 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/wii">Wii</a> on December 13, 2007. The Wii version was the only version to launch in the west, debuting on May 13, 2008 in North America.</p><p>Cosmo Machia is seeking three million yen (approx. $19,495 USD) in funding to release the PC version via Steam, with a 15 million yen (approx. $97,474 USD) stretch goal to also port the game to “the latest console(s).” If the campaign achieves a stretch goal of 20 million yen (approx. $130,054 USD), it will port the entire <em>Castle of Shikigami</em> series to console(s), starting with the original <em>Castle of Shikigami</em> already available for PC via Steam.</p><p>According to the campaign page, Cosmo Machia has received materials from original developer <a title="Companies > Alfa System [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/meteorise/alfa-system">Alfa System</a>, and has already begun work on porting the arcade version to PC.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via the back of the Wii version’s physical edition:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Welcome to the Castle of Nightmares!</p><p>Journey to the country of Alcaland and unravel the mystery behind its missing people. As one of ten powerful psychics summoned to solve the incident, and you strong enough to delve Into the depths of the Swan Castle and discover the truth, or will you succumb to its nightmare?</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Revel in 55 different scenarios with fully voiced dialogue!</li><li><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> the game as it was meant to be played in vertical mode!</li><li>Dodge a neverending barrage of bullets alone or with a mend!</li><li>Maximize your score and firepower as you graze enemy gunfire!</li></ul></blockquote></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic pulling Fortnite from "rent collector" mobile stores as it readies own EU shop]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-is-pulling-fortnite-from-rent-collector-mobile-stores-as-it-readies-own-eu-shop</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-pulling-fortnite-from-rent-collector-mobile-stores-as-it-readies-own-eu-shop.937239/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-is-pulling-fortnite-from-rent-collector-mobile-stores-as-it-readies-own-eu-shop<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"Even if those stores offer us a special deal for our own games."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fortnite-swole-fish.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Epic Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
This summer, Epic Games finally gets its wish when, thanks to new EU regulations, it's launching its own digital store on iOS and Android. And ahead of its arrival, the company has announced it's removing Fortnite and other Epic games from what it calls "rent collector" competing stores, "even if those stores offer us a special deal for our own games."
</p>
<p>
In its <a href="https://www.epicgames.com/site/en-US/news/epic-s-new-game-strategy-for-mobile-stores">announcement post</a>, Epic first confirms developers selling games on its on its new mobile store will be subject to the same 12 percent fee seen on its PC digital storefront (zero percent if a developer uses a third-party payment system). It then reveals plans to pull its own games from some competing stores. More specifically, it says it'll be "ending distribution partnerships with mobile stores that serve as rent collectors without competing robustly and serving all developers fairly, even if those stores offer us a special deal for our own games."
</p>
<p>
It's also pulling Fortnite and its other titles from the Samsung Galaxy Store, in what it calls "protest of Samsung's anticompetitive decision to block side-loading by default" on its devices. Conversely, Epic says it's planning to brings its own mobile games to stores that "give all developers a great deal". One of these will be the <a href="https://altstore.io/">indie-focused AltStore</a>.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: Does the loss of day one launches make Xbox Game Pass pointless?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lEc8ghseTIk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: Does the loss of day one launches make Xbox Game Pass pointless?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lEc8ghseTIk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/lEc8ghseTIk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: Does the loss of day one launches make Xbox Game Pass pointless?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lEc8ghseTIk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
The reason for all this, it insists, is that "we want to do everything we can to support other stores that strive to bring all developers their own great deals." Of course, it probably also helps that by manoeuvring its games from major to minor competing stores, it's pretty much guaranteeing most Fortnite traffic on mobile will come through its own store, where it won't need to pay a cut on its revenue at all.
</p>
<p>
Epic has been battling to return to iOS ever since Fortnite was booted out of Apple's ecosystem in 2020, when Epic <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-boss-pledges-more-legal-action-as-supreme-court-dismisses-apple-lawsuit-appeals">deliberately circumvented</a> contractually mandated App Store payment mechanisms within its Fortnite iOS app. Attempts to reverse Apple's decision through legal means have largely been unsuccessful in the US, with courts <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-boss-pledges-more-legal-action-as-supreme-court-dismisses-apple-lawsuit-appeals">predominantly ruling in Apple's favour</a> as time has gone on. However, the EU's Digital Markets Act has now provided the Fortnite maker with a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-secures-ios-developer-account-europe-mobile-store-and-fortnite-launch-this-year">means of getting its foot back in the door</a> - in the EU at least.
</p>
<p>
The Epic Games Store is set to launch on iOS in the EU and Android worldwide later this year. Epic has also <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-says-its-bringing-fortnite-and-the-epic-games-store-to-ios-in-the-uk-next-year">said</a> it'll be bringing Fortnite and its store to iOS in the UK in the "second half of 2025". That announcement might be a little premature, however, given there's still much to be determined around the UK's new Digital Markets, Competition and Consumers Act.
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sandbox dating simulation game Date Everything announced for PS5, Xbox Series, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/sandbox-dating-simulation-game-date-everything-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sandbox-dating-simulation-game-date-everything-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc.937230/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/07/sandbox-dating-simulation-game-date-everything-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>From a studio of voice actors turned developers.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Team17 [170 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/team17">Team17</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Sassy Chap Games" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sassy-chap-games">Sassy Chap Games</a>, a studio made up of voice actors turned developers Ray Chase, Robbie Daymond, Max Mittelman, and Amanda Hufford, have announced <em><a title="Games > Date Everything" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/date-everything">Date Everything</a></em>, a sandbox dating <a title="Genres > Simulation [527 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> featuring over 100 datable characters. It will be available for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,531 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,731 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,702 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,734 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2201320/Date_Everything/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>. A release date was not announced. <span id="more-901389"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2201320/Date_Everything/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Date Everything</em> brings an exciting new twist on the dating simulator genre. Your BFA in customer service unfortunately goes to waste as you lose your job to AI. But… a mysterious stranger sends a gift—magical glasses called “dateviators”—which make your house come alive and dateable!</p><p>Each dateable object will open up, have their own stories and potentially become your lovers, friends, or enemies. With an exhaustive Who’s Who of voice actors keeping you company on your journey!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li>100 datable characters.</li><li>Fully voice acted.</li><li>Branching narratives.</li><li>At least three endings per dateable character.</li><li>Puns galore!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Date Everything | Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dlxxzmOXRf0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guilty Gear Strive Producer Talks Lucy From Cyberpunk Edgerunners - Evo 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/guilty-gear-strive-producer-talks-lucy-from-cyberpunk-edgerunners-evo-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/guilty-gear-strive-producer-talks-lucy-from-cyberpunk-edgerunners-evo-2024.937209/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/guilty-gear-strive-producer-talks-lucy-from-cyberpunk-edgerunners-evo-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Guilty Gear Strive is now entering its fourth year of content updates, and despite now earning the reptutation as being the "old man" on the block, especially when put side-to-side with more recent releases like Street Fighter 6, Tekken 8, and Mortal Kombat 1, Strive is still continuing on just as strong as ever.</p><p>Which brings us to Evo 2024, where Arc System Works made perhaps their biggest announcement involving Guilty Gear Strive to date: In addition to two returning characters, Dizzy and Venom, and one brand new character, Unika, they would also be adding their first guest character to the roster: Lucy from Cyberpunk Edgerunners. I got a chance to catch up with Guilty Gear Strive Producer Ken Miyauchi to find out how this surprising collaboration came to be, along with getting some insight regarding Strive's future. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p><strong>IGN: We learned that Lucy from Cyberpunk Edgerunners is going to be in Strive. Can you talk a little bit about how long this has been in the works and how this collaboration came around?</strong></p><p><strong>Ken Miyauchi, Guilty Gear Strive Producer: </strong>So yeah, we've tried to find who will be a good guest character for Guilty Gear Strive. And we've been doing this work since 2023, actually. And we've been talking to CD PROJEKT RED because our lead artist, Hidehiko Sakamura, is actually a big fan of The Witchers series. And we've been in talks with CD PROJEKT RED, and then there was several conversation going on and that kind of led to the decision to get Lucy from Cyberpunk Edgerunners.</p><p><strong>Now, I'm not opposed to the idea of Lucy, but Lucy's not the main character of Cyberpunk Edgerunners, David is. What made you want to go with Lucy instead of David?</strong></p><p><strong>Miyauchi: </strong>So I cannot talk much about why because that might spoil what we are trying to do. But there is a reason we decided Lucy. Of course, I personally wanted to see David with Sandevistan, but yeah, so I can't talk about it right now, but I hope people will figure [it] out in the future.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p><strong>Is there any kind of collaboration happening between you and Studio Trigger who made the Cyberpunk Edgerunners anime? Are you working together with them to make Lucy happen in Strive?</strong></p><p><strong>Miyauchi: </strong>Honestly, we've been in talks with CD PROJEKT RED directly, not through Trigger, but if there could be any kind of collaboration that we [would] be able to do with Trigger, I'd like to do [it]. But that's still not in [the] plan.</p><p><strong>Another thing that you guys announced, which is something that you've talked about in the past, is the 3-on-3 mode. Can you talk a little bit about what makes this mode different than something like Dragon Ball FighterZ or a Marvel vs Capcom?</strong></p><p><strong>Miyauchi: </strong>So you'll eventually see the game mechanics explanation from our website or social post. So what makes the Team of 3 unique compared to the other games is that people will play at the same time, not just you controlling the character and doing the 1v1 in one screen. So I'm just going to explain the first layer of this game mechanic. The team will be formed with one main role and two assist roles, and the two assist roles will be able to select their skills to interact in the battle.</p><p><strong>Oh, interesting.</strong></p><p><strong>Miyauchi: </strong>And of course, during the battle, the assist players can switch with main players or assist player can interact into the battle with their own character in certain condition. Well the game mechanics-wise in the open beta test, I think people will be able to find out in tutorial, there's a Team of 3 tutorial mode in open beta test. So I hope people will figure out how they can utilize the new game mechanics that's exclusive for team of 3.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p><strong>And then another character that I'm sure people are very excited for is Dizzy. Can you talk a little bit about how Dizzy is going to perform in this iteration of Guilty Gear? And specifically, I saw that she was Queen Dizzy, can you talk a little bit about what the significance of that is?</strong></p><p><strong>Miyauchi: </strong>I want to explain the details, but I'll keep it secret for now why she's called Queen Dizzy. I had the same question when I first received [the] Queen Dizzy name from Daisuke Ishiwatari. There's a interesting story going on and you if actually see the trailer, you might find some hint of why she's called Queen. But for more details I'd like to say please look forward to actual her arcade story mode.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>There's a interesting story going on and you if actually see the trailer, you might find some hint of why she's called Queen. </p></div><p><strong>And then other characters that were announced were Venom and Unika, from the anime. I know they're probably early on development, but is there anything you can tell us about how those characters are going to play in Strive?</strong></p><p><strong>Miyauchi: </strong>So yeah, Venom, and also Unika, I can't explain the details of how their battle styles are for now. I think Venom is going to be quite similar to how he played in the past series, but sort of like how we've been doing, [it won't be] exactly same as the past series. Because if you want to play his past series style, you can play for example Xrd or XX. At the same time there is certain type of [uniqueness] in what makes Venom, Venom. And we would like to keep that as his gameplay. Regarding Unika, anything that I talk about her is going to spoil the anime series. So I'm going to expect people to watch the anime and then also try to maybe bring up their own theory of how she's going to play in the game play and check her actual game style later.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p><strong>Did you ever expect Strive to be going this strong for this long? It had a lot of entries at Evo this year.</strong></p><p><strong>Miyauchi: </strong>Yeah. I'm actually very, very surprised to see that we've been getting [consistently] over 2000 [entrants], throughout all the years of Evo for now. And I'm really, really happy that communities are supporting our game. And it's achieved all because I think the Guilty Gear community is very enthusiastic and they keeps wanting to support the game, and really appreciate it, and I really want to pay back their support with Gear Guilty updates.</p><p><strong>Is there anything you can tell us, any kind of hints you can give us about what to expect mechanically from the updates that you're bringing to Season 4?</strong></p><p><strong>Miyauchi: </strong>In a Developer's Backyard just a month ago that I released, I kind of talked about what's coming in the next few months, which are the Battle Balance updates, the minor version, it's coming out at the end of this month. And also the major one is coming sometime... I don't remember when I said this, but I think it's around October, end of October timing. </p><p>But the minor updates is more of mainly targeted to those characters who have less chance of getting access to their potential. So more of, buffs to those characters. And also adjusting on some of the universal mechanics such as the burst meter gain and also the positive bonus kind of thing. And also we have some changes to Roman Canceling mechanics on some of the invincible moves. So those are coming in the next character balance update. And I think this update will sort of shake up some meta in the current competitive fighting scene and I hope people will look forward to it.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p><strong>Beyond new mechanics, is there any kind of intention of improving some of Strive's more, let's say, base level features? Are we ever going to get frame data in training mode? Are we ever going to get matchmaking that doesn't go through the lobby system? Anything like that in the works?</strong></p><p><strong>Miyauchi: </strong>So those are updates that I've been always thinking that I want to accomplish, I mean, implement in some point. This is just from the producer perspective, I've been always talking about it with director. And we are always talking about when we'll be able to do this update. And currently we announced the new updates that's coming in next, which is the Team of 3, and the development on Team of 3 is going so hard right now. And once we release that, I think we'll be able to take our hands on those updates. So I'd like players to look forward to them, too.</p><p><strong>I apologize for this in advance because I feel like I ask you this every single time that I've talked to you, but insta-kills, fans love them. It's one of the things that I think fans love the most about the Guilty Gear series. What are the chances of them still making their way into Strive? And if it's something that you've thought about, are there any unique challenges involved with implementing insta-kills into Strive?</strong></p><p><strong>Miyauchi: </strong>So implementing instant kills is something that we would also like to do, and I do agree that it's some, how do I say, very, very unique mechanic that presents Guilty Gear. So we would like to make that happen sometime in the future. I can't tell when will that be possible because developing instant kill actually takes a lot of time. And also the character animations, emotions, which makes instant kills very, very unique and cool, will take a lot of time developing.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Implementing Instant Kills is something that we would also like to do. </p></div><p>We try to make it unique because we animates them by frame, by frame. And if the instant kill motions are long and cool, that means we have to have more time to make sure every pattern looks cool, right? And if we decide to implement instant kill to all characters, that means we have to develop that to all characters, which is almost nearly equal to developing maybe two characters. So we'll try to find a chance. Our team has been expanding still even now, we have our motion designers and animators recruited in our team and our team is getting bigger. So I'm looking, please look forward to future updates if we'll be able to do it.</p><p><strong>Final question, I'm asking this of pretty much everyone that I'm talking to here at Evo, but we've just crossed a milestone of Rollback netcode, everyone kind of has rollback netcode now. It's now become standard among fighting games. I think fighting games are a lot better for it. What do you think is the next step for fighting game evolution across the genre?</strong></p><p><strong>Miyauchi: </strong>That's something that we've been also discussing among the development team. Of course, as you know, Arc System Works has been making fighting games and we'll continue making fighting games. And if we make new fighting games, we'll always discuss about what will be something that we can bring, revolutionize the fighting game, how do I say, industry. And I don't have the answers yet or I can't share any answers for it, but I will be always thinking about it. And I honestly think the community right now, fighting game community right now, is in the best form of the current era. In the past, there was always... I mean, I wish if I would be a player in this fighting game era right now, people are expecting more and more fun things to the fighting game and we'll try to find out what we'll be able to provide to the community.</p><p><em>Mitchell Saltzman is a Senior Producer at IGN. You can find him on Twitter </em><a href="https://www.twitter.com/jurassicrabbit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@JurassicRabbit</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Doesn’t Stray Far from Overwatch but it’s Super Fun Regardless]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-doesnt-stray-far-from-overwatch-but-its-super-fun-regardless</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-doesn%E2%80%99t-stray-far-from-overwatch-but-it%E2%80%99s-super-fun-regardless.937203/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/marvel-rivals-doesnt-stray-far-from-overwatch-but-its-super-fun-regardless<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Doctor Doom needs you to run some 6v6 matches.</h2></div><section><p>Marvel Rivals is not attempting to reinvent the wheel. When it was first unveiled earlier this year, the gut response—from fans and skeptics alike—was that it looked a whole lot like an Overwatch facsimile with licensed Marvel heroes and villains filling in the roles abdicated by Genji, Winston, and Roadhog. After jumping into the closed beta for a few hours, I can confirm all of those suspicions. This is a hero shooter that has studied the established formula hard, but so far, that has resulted in an experience that's flashy, polished, and ready to get under your skin.</p><p>Like most multiplayer games, Marvel Rivals glosses over the specifics for why this alliance of superheroes has decided to beat each other to death over a variety of team-based objectives. (It has something to do with a partnership between two different versions of Doctor Doom. Beyond that, who knows?) But everything else here should be very familiar to anyone who's spent time in a big, bouncy arena shooter. You'll be split into two teams of six players, with rosters categorized into basic tank, support, and DPS roles, all of whom are blessed with a variety of unique abilities and an Ultimate that charges up over the course of the game. Victory will be achieved if you can move a payload to the end of its route, or if you're able to camp on a control point, and all of the action takes place in blooming battlefields plucked from the greater Marvel canon. Remind you of anything?</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Yes, Rivals takes its cues from Overwatch much more than it does from Valorant or Team Fortress 2. The tactics here aren't built around twitchy gunplay. In fact, a sizable chunk of its cast aren't wielding firearms at all, and across the board, they tend to absorb a ton of bullets before keeling over. Naturally, that makes Rivals more approachable to those who are turned off from traditional shooters. Do you want to toss up protective magical barriers and weave portals to teleport around the map? Dr. Strange might become your main. Would you rather bring a wide arsenal of munitions to the fight and try to win with your well-hewn Call of Duty skills? Then The Punisher might be more your speed.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>A sizable chunk of its cast aren't wielding firearms at all, and across the board, they tend to absorb a ton of bullets before keeling over.</p></div><p>The asymmetry in each of these heroes is genuinely staggering. Developer NetEase has clearly dedicated a lot of time and resources into making sure the vividness of the Marvel fantasy is able to come to life within the narrow confines of a hero shooter. Consider Iron Man, who operates like a mobile artillery unit, throwing out huge splashes of damage to anyone below him. Star-Lord, meanwhile, has two blasters in his holster that automatically reload whenever he dashes forward. String those together correctly, and you can absolutely melt the lifebar of whoever was unlucky enough to be caught out of position.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Rivals also does a good job of emphasizing one of the great traditions in comic books: team-up abilities, where two heroes combine their strengths and start wrecking shop. These are character-specific, and they often play off of the relationship between the heroes within the Marvel universe as a whole. For instance, Rocket Raccoon can leap onto the shoulders of his old pal Groot, hooking him up with damage reduction and added mobility. It's a cool wrinkle, and one that sounds difficult to balance. Ideally, at high levels, Marvel Rivals won't boil down to matches that feature a prescribed set of established synergies, and still allow players to express their own creativity with their compositions.</p><p>Because even now, in its unfinished state, Marvel Rivals is beautifully rendered. The characters are all gorgeously exaggerated and rippling with muscles, far more reminiscent of a comic shop in 1997 than anything from the MCU. The maps themselves are equally resplendent and surprisingly modular. (Take aim at a wall, and you might be able to blast it to smithereens.) And perhaps most importantly, Rivals seems equally attuned to the whims of a select few esports-adjacent diehards, and those who simply want to burn off a weeknight crushing the opposition with The Hulk. The package that NetEase has put together here is rock solid. Let's hope it stays thrilling when it jumps to live servers.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eagle-Eyed SDCC Fans Think They've Spotted a Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver 1 and 2 Remaster Tease | SDCC 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/eagle-eyed-sdcc-fans-think-theyve-spotted-a-legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-and-2-remaster-tease-sdcc-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/eagle-eyed-sdcc-fans-think-theyve-spotted-a-legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-and-2-remaster-tease-sdcc-2024.937200/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/eagle-eyed-sdcc-fans-think-theyve-spotted-a-legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-and-2-remaster-tease-sdcc-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">The devil is in the detail.</h2></div><section><p>San Diego Comic-Con 2024 officially kicks off today, and eagle-eyed fans are already spotting hidden announcements appearing at the convention. One video game fan in particular noticed branding for what looks like an unannounced remaster of Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver 1 and 2.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Legacy of Kain: "Soul Reaver I &amp; II Remastered" branding seen at SDCC <a href="https://t.co/IjCLDVEEpN" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/IjCLDVEEpN</a> <a href="https://t.co/WCS94tUl1u" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/WCS94tUl1u</a></p>— Wario64 (@Wario64) <a href="https://twitter.com/Wario64/status/1816560879355244667?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">July 25, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Over on ResetEra, user Mama Robotnik <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-i-ii-remastered-branding-seen-at-sdcc.937002/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted pictures</a> from the SDCC show floor showing statues based on the Legacy of Kain series. Alongside the statue is a sign with the branding "Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver I &amp; II Remastered." However, Crystal Dynamics has not officially confirmed an official remaster for either of these games. IGN has reached out to Crystal Dynamics for comment.</p><p>Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver was first released in 1999 for the PS1 and PC, while its direct sequel, Soul Reaver 2, was released in 20001 for PS2 and PC. Both games are part of the dark fantasy action RPG series, though the franchise has remained dormant for decades. The last entry, Legacy of Kain: Defiance, was released in 2003 for PS2, PC, and the original Xbox. </p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/07/25/placeholder-logo-1719713665411-1721938467935.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Crystal Dynamics and Bit Bot Media announced a prequel graphic novel for The Legacy of Kain: Soul Revaer was in the works | Image Credit: Crystal Dynamics / Bit Bot Media</figcaption></figure></output><p>Though the series was neglected for years, hopes for the franchise's return surfaced in October 2022 when Crystal Dynamics <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/crystal-dynamics-asking-fans-new-legacy-of-kain-game">published a survey</a> asking fans if they would like to see a new game from the Legacy of Kain series. A few months after the survey was released, Crystal Dynamics owner's Embracer group revealed that it <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/new-legacy-of-kain-looks-likely-as-embracer-receives-strong-fan-response">received 100,000 responses</a>, hinting that a new game could be in development. </p><p>Last month, Crystal Dynamics and Bit Bot Media announced that it was publishing <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-returns-in-new-prequel-graphic-novel">a new prequel novel</a> titled Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver—The Dead Shall Rise. However, a release date for the graphic novel has yet to be revealed. </p><p>In <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2000/01/27/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-review">our review of the original Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver</a>, IGN wrote: "Legacy of Kain takes everything that makes the horror genre compelling and improves on it in nearly every way. Ending aside (what's wrong with a cliff-hanger now and then?), Kain is easily my favorite Dreamcast game so far, and is a great choice for your growing collection."</p><p>You can catch up on <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/san-diego-comic-con-2024-everything-announced">everything announced at SDCC 2024 right here</a>.</p><p><em>Taylor is a Reporter at IGN. You can follow her on Twitter </em><a href="https://twitter.com/TayNixster" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>@TayNixster.</em></a></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic will bring Fortnite to third-party iOS app stores]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/25/24206372/epic-games-fortnite-third-party-ios-app-stores-altstore</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/epic-will-bring-fortnite-to-third-party-ios-app-stores.937188/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/25/24206372/epic-games-fortnite-third-party-ios-app-stores-altstore<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Epic Games plans to bring <em>Fortnite</em> to the third-party iOS app store AltStore PAL, which is only available in the EU. The company made the announcement in <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.epicgames.com%2Fsite%2Fen-US%2Fnews%2Fepic-s-new-game-strategy-for-mobile-stores">a Thursday blog post</a> about its strategy for mobile stores, and it says it expects to announce support for “at least two other third-party stores soon.”</p><p>While Epic says that it plans to “bring our own mobile games including <em>Fortnite</em> to other mobile stores that give all developers a great deal,” it didn’t provide a specific timeline. In addition to <em>Fortnite</em>, Epic also plans to bring <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/24/22345184/rocket-league-sideswipe-android-ios-announced"><em>Rocket League Sideswipe</em></a><em> </em>to AltStore PAL, spokesperson Natalie Munoz tells <em>The Verge</em>. </p><p>When reached for comment, AltStore’s Riley Testut pointed to Epic’s post and said that “we’re very excited to be bringing <em>Fortnite</em> and more to AltStore PAL.”</p><p>The company is also working on bringing <em>Fortnite</em> to iOS in <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/1/24189982/fortnite-is-getting-closer-to-a-return-on-ios-in-the-eu">the EU</a>, which it says will happen “soon,” and launching its own app store <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/20/24106711/heres-what-epics-mobile-app-store-might-look-like">on iOS and Android</a>. </p><p>Epic also announced that “we will be ending distribution partnerships with mobile stores that serve as rent collectors without competing robustly and serving all developers fairly, even if those stores offer us a special deal for our own games.” Epic is presumably talking about Apple and Google here, given the company’s disputes with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/28/24158911/apple-v-epic-evidentiary-hearing-app-store-payments">both</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/policy/2024/6/25/24185450/epic-google-catalog-access-library-porting-estimated-cost">companies</a> over their app store practices. Munoz declined to comment.</p><p>Epic also plans to pull <em>Fortnite</em> and other apps (<em>Rocket League Sideswipe</em> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/2/9/23592866/epic-games-postparty-clips-app-fortnite-rocket-league"><em>Postparty</em></a>, according to Munoz) from Samsung’s Galaxy Store. The company cites two factors as to why. One is Samsung’s “Auto Blocker” feature that blocks sideloading by default (though you can turn the feature off, <a href="https://9to5google.com/2024/07/23/samsung-galaxy-sideloading-android-apps/">according to <em>9to5Google</em></a>). Another is “public revelations in the US Epic v. Google lawsuit of ongoing Google proposals to Samsung to restrain competition in the market for Android app distribution,” presumably referring to initiatives like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23959932/epic-v-google-trial-antitrust-play-store-fortnite-recap">Project Banyan</a>, which <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/13/23959284/samsung-devices-are-responsible-for-half-or-more-of-the-revenue-google-receives-from-google-play-rig">Google gave up on</a>.</p><p>Apple, Google, and Samsung didn’t immediately reply to a request for comment.</p><p><em><strong>Update, July 25th</strong>: Added details from Epic about what apps it will remove from the Galaxy Store.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver 1 & 2 remaster hints surface at Comic-Con]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-2-remaster-hints-surface-at-comic-con</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-2-remaster-hints-surface-at-comic-con.937185/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-1-2-remaster-hints-surface-at-comic-con<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Crystal Dynamics' game is 25 in August.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/soul-reaver-legacy-of-kain.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Crystal Dynamics</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Crystal Dynamics' beloved dark fantasy action-adventure series Legacy of Kain could be poised to receive the remaster treatment, if newly sighted branding at Comic-Con is to be believed.
</p>
<p>
As spotted by a user on <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-i-ii-remastered-branding-seen-at-sdcc.937002/">Resetera</a>, logos for an unannounced "Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver 1 &amp; 2 Remastered" were included on display plaques accompanying statues of game characters Kain and Raziel at this week's Comic-Con San Diego show.
</p>
<p>
A Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver graphic novel prequel, The Dead Shall Rise, was recently announced by Dark Horse Comics, and GameSpot has now <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/soul-reaver-remasters-seemingly-confirmed-by-a-statue-at-comic-con/1100-6525310/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f">received confirmation</a> from the publisher's VP of product development and sales that this is due to release in August.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="DF Retro: Legacy of Kain Soul Reaver - A Classic Revisited on PS1/PC/Dreamcast!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ni13xjHvwu4?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>DF Retro: Legacy of Kain Soul Reaver - A Classic Revisited on PS1/PC/Dreamcast!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ni13xjHvwu4?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ni13xjHvwu4?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Digital Foundry Retro: Legacy of Kain Soul Reaver.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ni13xjHvwu4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Given the Dark Horse logo also appears on the (now removed) Comic-Con plaques, it's hard not to speculate the graphic novel and remaster might arrive in tandem - particularly as the first Soul Reaver game is 25 years old on 16th August this year.
</p>
<p>
Hints that Crystal Dynamics might be considering a Legacy of Kain revival first surfaced in 2022, when the developer <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/crystal-dynamics-wants-your-thoughts-on-legacy-of-kain">sent out a survey</a> asking if recipients would be interested in seeing the series - which spanned five titles between 1996 and 2003 - make a comeback.
</p>
<p>
Over 100,000 people responded positively, to which Crystal Dynamics CEO Phil Rogers <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/crystal-dynamics-hears-legacy-of-kain-fans-loudly-and-clearly-following-huge-survey-response">replied</a>, "Rest assured, we hear you loudly and clearly, and we'll continue to update you on the 'what if' possibilities ahead for Legacy of Kain in the future." Since then, parent company Embracer has embarked on an <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/embracer-has-now-laid-off-8-of-staff">devastating programme of layoffs and project cancellations</a>, making a Legacy of Kain revival seem unlikely - but here we are now.
</p>
<p>
Legacy of Kain: Soul Reaver 1 &amp; 2 were written and directed by Amy Hennig - perhaps best known as the creative director on <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/naughty-dog">Naughty Dog</a>'s Uncharted series - and the series celebrated its 20th anniversary back in 2019. If you're curious to learn more, Eurogamer's former editor-in-chief Wesley Yin-Poole <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/as-legacy-of-kain-soul-reaver-turns-20-lets-remember-why-it-was-brilliant">recalled why the series was so brilliant</a> at the time.
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lego’s newest retro art piece is a 1,215-piece Super Mario World homage]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/?p=2039293</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego%E2%80%99s-newest-retro-art-piece-is-a-1-215-piece-super-mario-world-homage.937155/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/?p=2039293<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <h4>
      let's-a-go    —
</h4>
            
            <h2 itemprop="description">$130 set is available for preorder now, ships on October 1.</h2>
                    </div><div itemprop="articleBody">
                                    
  




<!-- cache hit 60:single/related:3601478978e982c2bb52e8b858bd6434 --><!-- empty -->
  <div>
    <ul>
              <li data-thumb="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-2-150x150.jpeg" data-src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-2.jpeg" data-responsive="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-2-980x654.jpeg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-2.jpeg 2560" data-sub-html="#caption-2039361">
          <figure>
            
                          <figcaption id="caption-2039361">
                <span></span>
                                  <p>
                    The Lego Mario &amp; Yoshi set is an homage to 1990's <em>Super Mario World</em>.                  </p>
                                                  <p><span></span>
                                          The Lego Group                                      </p>
                              </figcaption>
                      </figure>
        </li>
              <li data-thumb="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-1-150x150.jpeg" data-src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-1.jpeg" data-responsive="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-1-980x653.jpeg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-1.jpeg 2560" data-sub-html="#caption-2039360">
          <figure>
            
                          <figcaption id="caption-2039360">
                <span></span>
                                  <p>
                    From the front, it looks like a fairly straightforward re-creation of the game's 16-bit sprites.                   </p>
                                                  <p><span></span>
                                          The Lego Group                                      </p>
                              </figcaption>
                      </figure>
        </li>
              <li data-thumb="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-3-150x150.jpeg" data-src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-3.jpeg" data-responsive="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-3-980x653.jpeg 1080, https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/mario-world-lego-3-1440x960.jpeg 2560" data-sub-html="#caption-2039362">
          <figure>
            
                          <figcaption id="caption-2039362">
                <span></span>
                                  <p>
                    Behind the facade are complex mechanics that move Yoshi's feet and arms and bob his body up and down, to make him look like he's walking. A separate dial opens his mouth and extends his tongue.                   </p>
                                                  <p><span></span>
                                          The Lego Group                                      </p>
                              </figcaption>
                      </figure>
        </li>
          </ul>
  </div>

<p>Nintendo and Lego are at it again—they've announced another collaboration today as a follow-up to <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2020/03/lego-teams-up-with-nintendo-for-super-mario-brick-based-game/">the interactive Mario sets</a>, the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2020/07/this-200-lego-nes-set-features-a-scrolling-8-bit-mario/">replica Nintendo Entertainment System</a>, the <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2021/09/2064-piece-lego-set-recreates-super-mario-64-in-miniature-for-170/">unfolding question mark block</a> with the&nbsp;<em>Mario 64&nbsp;</em>worlds inside, and other sets besides.</p>
<p>The latest addition is <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/product/super-mario-world-mario-yoshi-71438?cmp=REF-202407-Mario_Yoshi_Laun">an homage to 1990's&nbsp;<em>Super Mario World</em></a>, Mario's debut outing on the then-new 16-bit Super Nintendo Entertainment System. At first, the 1,215-piece set just looks like a caped Mario sitting on top of Yoshi. But a look at the back reveals more complex mechanics, including a hand crank that makes Yoshi's feet and arms move and a dial that opens his mouth and extends his tongue.</p>

<p>Most of the Mario sets have included some kind of interactive moving part, even if it's as simple as the movable mouth on the <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/aboutus/news/2023/september/lego-super-mario-piranha-plant">Lego Piranha Plant</a>. Yoshi's mechanical crank most strongly resembles the NES set, though, which included a CRT-style TV set with a crank that made the contents of the screen scroll so that Mario could "walk."</p>
<p>The Mario &amp; Yoshi set is available to preorder from Lego's online store for $129.99. It begins shipping on October 1.</p>
<p>Lego has also branched out into other video game-themed sets. In 2022, the company began selling <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2022/07/recapture-the-fun-of-the-1980s-game-crash-with-legos-240-atari-2600-replica/">a replica Atari 2600,</a> complete with faux-wood paneling. More recently, Lego has collaborated with Epic Games on <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/themes/fortnite">several <em>Fortnite</em>-themed sets</a>, including<a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/product/battle-bus-77073"> the Battle Bus</a>.</p>

        <p><em>Listing image by The Lego Group</em></p>
                                                      </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video Game Voice Actors Are Going On Strike Over AI: "Enough Is Enough"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/video-game-voice-actors-are-going-on-strike-over-ai-enough-is-enough/1100-6525312/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/video-game-voice-actors-are-going-on-strike-over-ai-enough-is-enough.937152/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/video-game-voice-actors-are-going-on-strike-over-ai-enough-is-enough/1100-6525312/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525312">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>SAG-AFTRA members who work in video games have voted to strike due to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sag-aftra-may-call-immediate-strike-over-lack-of-ai-protections-for-voice-actors/1100-6525228/">concerns about AI</a>, after more than a year and a half of unfruitful negotiations regarding the Interactive Media Agreement--a contract that many major gaming companies must stick to when creating big-budget games. The strike will go into effect at 12:01 AM PT on July 26.</p><p dir="ltr">"Any game looking to employ SAG-AFTRA talent to perform covered work must sign on to the new Tiered-Budget Independent Interactive Media Agreement, the Interim Interactive Media Agreement, or the Interim Interactive Localization Agreement," reads the <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sag-aftra-members-who-work-video-games-go-strike" rel="nofollow ">press release announcing the strike</a>. "These agreements offer critical AI protections for members."</p><p dir="ltr">SAG-AFTRA has been <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/video-game-actors-strike-looking-more-possible-bargaining-talks-apparently-going-nowhere/1100-6517812/">struggling to come to an agreement</a> on AI usage in game development for months--specifically the use of AI in place of human voice actors and motion-capture performers. In January, SAG-AFTRA <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sag-aftra-approves-ai-voice-acting-for-video-games/1100-6520224/">signed a controversial agreement</a> with AI voice software company Replica Studios. The agreement, which essentially approved AI voice acting in video games, was criticized by voice actors, many of whom <a href="https://x.com/blumspew/status/1744854178869211228" rel="nofollow ">claimed they were never consulted</a> about the agreement.</p><p dir="ltr">The convenience bargaining group SAG-AFTRA is currently negotiating with includes the following gaming studios:</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Activision Productions Inc.</li><li dir="ltr">Blindlight LLC</li><li dir="ltr">Disney Character Voices Inc.</li><li dir="ltr">Electronic Arts Productions Inc.</li><li dir="ltr">Formosa Interactive LLC</li><li dir="ltr">Insomniac Games Inc.</li><li dir="ltr">Llama Productions LLC</li><li dir="ltr">Take 2 Productions Inc.</li><li dir="ltr">VoiceWorks Productions Inc.</li><li dir="ltr">WB Games Inc.</li></ul><p>It's not immediately clear which games will be affected by the strike, but delays would be more likely to happen for games that are still in early in development, rather than anything close to launch. There's no telling how long the strike itself will last.</p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ea-boss-explains-why-ai-will-be-good-for-gaming/1100-6518421/" data-ref-id="1100-6518421">EA has already voiced support</a> for the use of AI in its games, Ubisoft is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ubisoft-is-trying-to-make-ai-npcs-that-have-real-conversations/1100-6521970/" data-ref-id="1100-6521970">experimenting with AI NPCs</a> that can have "real conversations," and the devs behind The Finals have also <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-finals-dev-defends-ai-voices-says-its-not-trying-to-replace-humans/1100-6518802/" data-ref-id="1100-6518802">defended its use of AI voice-acting</a>. Other entities in the gaming industry have taken a stand against AI, with Epic Games CEO <a href="https://x.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1815480189163651375" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tim Sweeney stating</a>, "Game companies shouldn’t receive generative AI voice training rights on dialog recording sessions," and Valve <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-developers-will-need-to-disclose-ai-use-on-steam/1100-6520235/" data-ref-id="1100-6520235">requiring developers to disclose the use of AI</a> in any games they list on Steam.</p><p dir="ltr">"Eighteen <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sag-aftras-talks-with-video-games-industry-ends-with-no-resolution/1100-6518071/" data-ref-id="1100-6518071">months of negotiations</a> have shown us that our employers are not interested in fair, reasonable AI protections, but rather flagrant exploitation," Interactive Media Agreement Negotiating Committee Chair Sarah Elmaleh said of the strike. "We refuse this paradigm--we will not leave any of our members behind, nor will we wait for sufficient protection any longer. We look forward to collaborating with teams on our Interim and Independent contracts, which provide AI transparency, consent and compensation to all performers, and to continuing to negotiate in good faith with this bargaining group when they are ready to join us in the world we all deserve."</p><p dir="ltr">SAG-AFTRA members working in film and television previously <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sag-aftra-reaches-tentative-agreement-with-studios-ending-actors-strike/1100-6519028/" data-ref-id="1100-6519028">went on strike in 2023</a>, with the use of AI being one of the biggest issues in the negotiations.</p><p dir="ltr">“We’re not going to consent to a contract that allows companies to abuse AI to the detriment of our members," added SAG-AFTRA President Fran Drescher. "Enough is enough. When these companies get serious about offering an agreement our members can live--and work--with, we will be here, ready to negotiate.”</p><p>Gaming studios have already responded to the strike, voicing disappointment with SAG-AFTRA's decision. <a href="https://www.threads.net/@stephentotilo/post/C926Hrwv6hX/?xmt=AQGzs7BeSoaLArMKg_xcrbtwzkXz6ENTZQgginvkfJZ2sw" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"><br></a></p><p>"We are disappointed the union has chosen to walk away when we are so close to a deal, and we remain prepared to resume negotiations," said Audrey Cooling, the IMA spokesperson for the video game producers party. "We have already found common ground on 24 out of 25 proposals, including historic wage increases and additional safety provisions. Our offer is directly responsive to SAG-AFTRA’s concerns and extends meaningful AI protections that include requiring consent and fair compensation to all performers working under the IMA. These terms are among the strongest in the entertainment industry."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video Game Voice Actors Strike Over AI]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/sag-aftra-video-game-voice-actor-strike</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/video-game-voice-actors-strike-over-ai.937143/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/sag-aftra-video-game-voice-actor-strike<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Following prolonged negotiations with many of the biggest companies in video games, the Screen Actors Guild-American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (SAG-AFTRA) has called for a video game performer and voice actor strike, beginning on July 26. Try as they might, the two sides have been unable to see eye to eye on the issue of AI.&nbsp;</p><p>“The video game industry generates billions of dollars in profit annually," said SAG-AFTRA national executive director and chief negotiator Duncan Crabtree-Ireland in a statement to Aftermath. "The driving force behind that success is the creative people who design and create those games. That includes the SAG-AFTRA members&nbsp;who&nbsp;bring memorable and beloved game characters to life, and they deserve and demand the same fundamental protections as performers in film, television, streaming, and music: fair compensation and the right of informed consent for the AI use of their faces, voices, and bodies. Frankly, it’s stunning that these video game studios haven’t learned anything from the lessons of last year - that our members can and will stand up and demand fair and equitable treatment with respect to AI, and the public supports us in that."</p><p>Workers can now strike at ten companies: Activision, Blindlight, Disney Character Voices, EA, Epic, Formosa Interactive, Insomniac Games, Take-Two, VoiceWorks, and WB Games.</p><p>The aforementioned companies released their own joint statement:</p><p>“We are disappointed the union has chosen to walk away when we are so close to a deal, and we&nbsp;remain&nbsp;prepared to resume negotiations," the companies said via a spokesperson. "We have already found common ground on 24 out of 25 proposals, including historic wage increases and&nbsp;additional&nbsp;safety provisions.&nbsp;Our offer is directly responsive to SAG-AFTRA’s concerns and extends meaningful AI protections that include&nbsp;requiring&nbsp;consent and fair compensation to all performers&nbsp;working under the [Interactive Media Agreement]. These terms are among the strongest in the entertainment industry.”</p><p>SAG-AFTRA membership first voted in favor of authorizing a strike <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23885558/sag-aftra-strike-authorization-negotiation-video-game-voice-actors" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in 2023</a>, which the union’s national board <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sag-aftra-national-board-meets-videoconference-national-board-unanimously-gives-chief-negotiator" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">followed last week</a> by granting Crabtree-Ireland authority to call a strike if need be. This is the second video game voice actor strike, with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2016%E2%80%932017_video_game_voice_actor_strike" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the first</a> lasting nearly a year between 2016 and 2017. As a result, actors received a pay raise, though residuals and matters pertaining to vocal stress – other central issues at the time – did not make it into the contract, prompting criticism from some actors.</p><p>At the beginning of this year, SAG-AFTRA again faced controversy when it <a href="https://aftermath.site/sag-aftras-ai-voice-acting-deal-was-a-powder-keg-waiting-to-go-off" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">struck a deal with a company called Replica</a>, with the goal of making it easy for “professional voice over artists to safely explore new employment opportunities for their digital voice replicas with industry-leading protections tailored to AI technology” and “allowing AAA video game studios and other companies working with Replica to access top SAG-AFTRA talent.” This turned out to be a one-off deal with a single company rather than the broader Interactive Media Agreement over which SAG-AFTRA members had authorized a strike, but performers still felt blindsided by the decision.</p><p>Now workers are going to battle to secure their rights across the board.&nbsp;</p><p>“Eighteen months of negotiations have shown us that our employers are not interested in fair, reasonable AI protections, but rather flagrant exploitation, said video game performer and SAG-AFTRA&nbsp;Interactive Media Agreement negotiating committee chair Sarah Elmaleh. "We refuse this paradigm – we will not leave any of our members behind, nor will we wait for sufficient protection any longer. We look forward to collaborating with teams on our interim and independent contracts, which provide AI transparency, consent and compensation to all performers, and to continuing to negotiate in good faith with this bargaining group when they are ready to join us in the world we all deserve."&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SAG-AFTRA authorizes video game actor strike over AI]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/sag-aftra-authorizes-video-game-actor-strike-over-ai</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sag-aftra-authorizes-video-game-actor-strike-over-ai.937125/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/sag-aftra-authorizes-video-game-actor-strike-over-ai<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">After a year and a half of negotiating for a better contract, performers union </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sag-aftra-members-who-work-video-games-go-strike">SAG-AFTRA has authorized a strike</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for all members working in games under the organization's Interactive Media agreement. The strike commences at 12:01 am on July 26 (so, shortly after midnight tonight) and any game studio looking to employ SAG-AFTRA-signed talent—for voice work, motion capture performance, on-screen talent, or similar services—must sign one of the new agreements listed in the union's post.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">These include the Tiered-Budget Independent Interactive Media Agreement, the Interim Interactive Media Agreement, or the Interim Interactive Localization Agreement. According to the SAG-AFTRA site, those contracts are acceptable to the union because they include "critical AI protections for members."</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="AI protections are at the heart of this strike">AI protections are at the heart of this strike</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As the post notes, negotiations began in November 2022, and it lists major studios like Take 2 Productions, EA, Activision, WB Games, and more as part of the convenience bargaining group. It states, "although agreements have been reached on many issues important to SAG-AFTRA members, the employers refuse to plainly affirm, in clear and enforceable language, that they will protect all performers covered by this contract in their A.I. language."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Simply put, this strike is largely due to the members seeking protection from potentially exploitative genAI technology. An unscrupulous studio looking to cut costs could hire a performer once and then use the assets&nbsp;to generate content without the actor's consent or compensation for their performance. The SAG-AFTRA members contend that this possibility—and others that lack explicit consent regarding the re-use of a performance—is harmful and undervalues their labor.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sarah Elmaleh, Interactive Media Agreement negotiating committee chair (and prolific video game voice actor, with credits in games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Final Fantasy XV</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fortnite</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Hi-Fi Rush</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">) closes out the post with a statement to that effect.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">“Eighteen months of negotiations have shown us that our employers are not interested in fair, reasonable A.I. protections, but rather flagrant exploitation," said Elmaleh. "We refuse this paradigm—via we will not leave any of our members behind, nor will we wait for sufficient protection any longer. We look forward to collaborating with teams on our Interim and Independent contracts, which provide A.I. transparency, consent and compensation to all performers, and to continuing to negotiate in good faith with this bargaining group when they are ready to join us in the world we all deserve."</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Editor-in-Chief, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Danielle is the editor-in-chief of Game Developer, with previous editorial posts at Fanbyte, VICE, and Polygon. She’s also a lecturer in game design at the Berklee College of Music, and a hobbyist game developer in her spare time.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US video game performers announce strike over ongoing AI concerns]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/us-video-game-performers-are-striking-over-ongoing-ai-concerns</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/us-video-game-performers-announce-strike-over-ongoing-ai-concerns.937101/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/us-video-game-performers-are-striking-over-ongoing-ai-concerns<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>UPDATE: Producers respond, "remain prepared to resume negotiations".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/sag-aftra-video-game-strike.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>SAG-AFTRA</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><strong>UPDATE 26/07/24:</strong> Video game producers negotiating as part of the Interactive Media Agreement have responded to news of the SAG-AFTRA strike.</p>
<p>"We are disappointed the union has chosen to walk away when we are so close to a deal, and we remain prepared to resume negotiations," reads a statement from spokesperson for the video game producers party to the Interactive Media Agreement, Audrey Cooling, shared with Eurogamer.</p>
<p>"We have already found common ground on 24 out of 25 proposals, including historic wage increases and additional safety provisions. Our offer is directly responsive to SAG-AFTRA's concerns and extends meaningful AI protections that include requiring consent and fair compensation to all performers working under the IMA. These terms are among the strongest in the entertainment industry."</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>ORIGINAL STORY 25/07/24:</strong> Video game performers within United States actors union SAG-AFTRA have voted to go on strike starting Friday, 26th July, after "more than than a year and a half of negotiations" with major game companies over the use of AI have failed to reach a deal.
</p>
<p>
SAG-AFTRA members initially <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sag-aftra-members-overwhelmingly-vote-in-favour-of-authorising-video-game-strike">voted in favour</a> of (but did not immediately take) strike action last September, after the union failed to reach a consensus with video game producers - including Activision, Warner Bros, EA, Take-Two, and Disney - while attempting to negotiate a successor to the Interactive Media Agreement, which covers members' work on games.
</p>
<p>
At the time, SAG-AFTRA said companies had refused to offer acceptable terms on critical issues, including wages in-line with inflation, protections around exploitative uses of AI, and job safety.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Newscast: Does the loss of day one launches make Xbox Game Pass pointless?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lEc8ghseTIk?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Newscast: Does the loss of day one launches make Xbox Game Pass pointless?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lEc8ghseTIk?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/lEc8ghseTIk?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Newscast: Does the loss of day one launches make Xbox Game Pass pointless?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lEc8ghseTIk" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Then, this March, SAG-AFTRA national executive director and chief negotiator Duncan Crabtree-Ireland confirmed the strike was still likely to go ahead after the union had failed to reach a deal with companies regarding AI protections. "We want to make sure the implementation [of AI] is human-centred and focused on augmentation [of production], not replacement of people," he explained, adding that "consent and compensation" for members whose work is used by AI engines is also one of the union's aims.
</p>
<p>
And now, with a deal still not agreed upon, union members have officially called a strike, effective Friday, 26th July, at 12:01am. "Although agreements have been reached on many issues important to SAG-AFTRA members," the union wrote in a <a href="https://www.sagaftra.org/sag-aftra-members-who-work-video-games-go-strike">statement announcing the strike</a>, "the employers refuse to plainly affirm, in clear and enforceable language, that they will protect performers covered by this contract in their AI language."
</p>
<p>
"We're not going to consent to a contract that allows companies to abuse AI to the detriment of our members," SAG-AFTRA president Fran Drescher added in the statement. "Enough is enough. When these companies get serious about offering an agreement our members can live - and work - with, we will be here, ready to negotiate."
</p>
<p>
Many video game performers, including <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/solid-snake-and-commander-shepard-stars-discuss-threat-of-ai-on-voice-acting">Solid Snake actor David Hayter and Commander Shepard actor Jennifer Hale</a>, have voiced their concerns about AI and its impact on their work in recent times. In March this year, Eurogamer spoke to several BAFTA-nominated <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-a-critical-success-with-critical-failures">Baldur's Gate 3</a> actors, who <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/baldurs-gate-3-actors-reveal-the-darker-side-of-success-fuelled-by-ai-voice-cloning">revealed the darker side of success</a>, fuelled by AI voice cloning.
</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>