<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 22:54:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It’s time to squad up in this preview from Apple’s Mythic Quest spinoff series]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/633884/mythic-quest-side-quest-the-last-raid</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/it%E2%80%99s-time-to-squad-up-in-this-preview-from-apple%E2%80%99s-mythic-quest-spinoff-series.1141827/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/633884/mythic-quest-side-quest-the-last-raid<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/charles-pulliam-moore">Charles Pulliam-Moore</a> <span>is a reporter focusing on film, TV, and pop culture. Before The Verge, he wrote about comic books, labor, race, and more at io9 and Gizmodo for almost five years.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Aside from cutscenes, most of <em><a href="https://www.theverge.com/tv-reviews/24350444/mythic-quest-season-4-review-apple-tv-plus">Mythic Ques</a>t </em>takes place in the real world. But Apple’s upcoming <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/14/24296445/mythic-quest-season-4-premiere-date-side-quest">spinoff series <em>Side Quest</em></a> will give us a much better look at what the game looks like from within.</p><p>While some of <em>Side Quest</em>’s four episodes focus on people’s lives outside of and away from <em>Mythic Quest</em>, the final episode, titled “The Last Raid,” takes place within the fictional MMORPG and follows high schoolers Devon (Van Crosby), Kelly (Melanie Brook), Rory (Alice Wen), Seth (David Andrew Calvillo), and Freddie (Justin Jarzombek) setting out to fight powerful bosses. In this exclusive clip from the episode, the kids have been playing <em>Mythic Quest </em>for years and made an annual tradition of taking on big raids to commemorate becoming friends in the game.</p><p>“The Last Raid” makes <em>Mythic Quest </em>(the game) look a bit like a dated <em>World of Warcraft </em>clone compared to cutscenes from <em>Mythic Quest</em>’s (the series) more recent seasons. But the episode, and the rest of <em>Side Quest</em>, may offer a better sense of what keeps players returning to <em>Mythic Quest</em>.</p><p>The entire season hits Apple TV Plus on March 26th.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Verdansk Tac Map Reveal Uncovers 19 POIs and Water]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/verdansk-tac-map-reveal-pois/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/verdansk-tac-map-reveal-uncovers-19-pois-and-water.1141821/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/verdansk-tac-map-reveal-pois/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Verdansk returns to Call of Duty Warzone on April 3, more than three years after it disappeared from the iconic battle royale title. It’s penned as being a last-ditch effort for Activision to retain players, and it’s arguably the biggest thing to happen to the game since it was <strong>removed </strong>in December 2021.</p>



<p>Today, the Verdansk Tac Map was revealed on social media, uncovering the full suite of POIs and some tidbits of information about the ‘new old’ map – including <strong>water on land</strong>.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-same-but-different">Same But Different</h2>



<p>Verdansk is almost entirely unchanged in the new graphic published <a href="https://x.com/CallofDuty/status/1903129487123849371" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">by Call of Duty</a> on social media. The POIs are the same as they were five years ago when the game was first released:</p>



<ul>
<li>Dam</li>



<li>Military Base</li>



<li>Quarry</li>



<li>Airport</li>



<li>TV Station</li>



<li>Storage Town</li>



<li>Superstore</li>



<li>Stadium</li>



<li>Lumber</li>



<li>Boneyard</li>



<li>Train Station</li>



<li>Hospital</li>



<li>Downtown</li>



<li>Farmland</li>



<li>Port</li>



<li>Prison</li>



<li>Park</li>



<li>Promenade</li>



<li>Hills</li>
</ul>



<p>Where you land first is entirely up to you, but those hot spots likely haven’t changed over the last half-decade.</p>



<figure></figure>







<p>Eagle-eyed fans have spotted a couple of telling sights on the new Verdansk Tac Map, though. It looks as though we’ll have water extending throughout the map in the form of rivers, which wasn’t a thing when the map was first released in March 2020. It seems like the updated railway line is also present, which means the train could be coming back.</p>



<p>It has also been noted that classic weapons could be making a comeback for the return of Verdansk. As players, we passed through so many metas back then that there’s a wealth of weaponry for Activision’s teams to choose from.</p>



<p>Aside from that, Verdansk looks as good as it ever did. Could this be a Fortnite OG kind of resurgence that brings millions of players back to Warzone overnight? Perhaps. We’ll know for sure on April 3.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/atomfall-review-rebellion-curveball/">our review for Atomfall</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[European Commission Targets Exploitive Virtual In-Game Currency Practices]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/european-commission-targets-exploitive-virtual-in-game-currency-practices/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/european-commission-targets-exploitive-virtual-in-game-currency-practices.1141812/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/european-commission-targets-exploitive-virtual-in-game-currency-practices/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The European Commission and the Consumer Protection Cooperation Network have published a new set of guidelines covering the purchasing of in-game virtual currency today. These new principles were applied after the CPC Network found a game developer to be engaged in a number of practice deemed “harmful to children.”</p>



<h2 id="h-the-european-commission-has-launched-a-probe-into-star-stable-online">The European Commission Has Launched a Probe into Star Stable Online</h2>



<p>On March 20th, The CPC Network <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_25_831" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">claimed</a> that that a number of commercial practices from Star Stable Entertainment AB were deemed “particularly harmful to children” in their game, Star Stable Online. These practices allegedly include “direct appeals to children in the advertisements,” the use of pressuring techniques, a lack of clear and transparent information, and failing to ensure that influencers promoting the product were disclosing commercial content.</p>



<p>The developers of the children’s game where you collect, accessorize, and race horses now have a month to address the issues highlighted by the CPC Network. However, these issues have made the CPC Network see “the need for European consumers to be better protected.” Thus, they have <a href="https://commission.europa.eu/document/download/8af13e88-6540-436c-b137-9853e7fe866a_en?filename=Key%20principles%20on%20in-game%20virtual%20currencies.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">published</a> seven “key principles” on in-game virtual currencies:</p>



<ol>
<li>“Price indication must be clear and transparent.” This effectively requires games to list the real-world money equivalent on any in-game virtual currency or in-game digital content.</li>



<li>“Practices obscuring the cost of in-game digital content and services should be avoided.”</li>



<li>“Practices that force consumers to purchase unwanted in-game virtual currency should be avoided.”</li>



<li>“Consumers should be provided with clear and comprehensive pre-contractual information.”</li>



<li>“Consumers’ right of withdrawal should be respected.” </li>



<li>“Contractual terms should be fair and written in plain and clear language.”</li>



<li>“Game design and gameplay should be respectful of different consumer vulnerabilities.”</li>
</ol>



<p>The CPC Network hopes these principles will “will help create a safer, more transparent experience for players,” but will also continue to monitor EU gaming companies and “may take further actions if harmful practices continue.” All the newly established principles are based on pre-existing EU consumer laws.</p>



<p>Are virtual currency practices too exploitive of children? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/apple-arcade-is-reportedly-unprofitable-without-apple-one-bundle/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Apple Arcade’s reported low usage and profits</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every Luigi Game on the Nintendo Switch in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/all-luigi-games-on-nintendo-switch-in-order</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-luigi-game-on-the-nintendo-switch-in-2025.1141809/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/all-luigi-games-on-nintendo-switch-in-order<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">As any younger sibling who grew up on Mario platformers knows, Luigi is gaming's ultimate Player 2. Nintendo's green-capped member of the Mario Bros. has lived a lifetime in the shadow of his older twin Mario, only stepping out for a taste of solo stardom in his ghostbusting Luigi's Mansion series.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As we move closer to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-2"><u>Switch 2</u></a>, we’re celebrating another console generation of Luigi and Player 2s everywhere with a complete list of every Luigi game on Switch.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><h2 data-cy="title2">How Many Luigi Games Are on Switch?</h2><p data-cy="paragraph"><strong>There are 17 games on Switch that let you play as Luigi</strong>. He’s the main character in only two games (Luigi’s Mansion 2 HD and Luigi’s Mansion 3) and the co-lead in one (Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership). </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Every Luigi Game on Switch</h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Luigi’s Mansion 3 (2019)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/luigismansion3-1741991010832.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Luigi’s first starring role on Switch was in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/10/28/luigis-mansion-3-review"><u>Luigi’s Mansion 3</u></a>, the third entry in the character’s only solo series to date. Luigi’s Mansion 3 sees our timid hero and his green gooey clone team up with Professor E. Gadd to battle ghosts and save his friends from King Boo’s haunted hotel.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Luigi’s Mansion 2 HD (2024)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/mansion2hd-1741990924534.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/luigis-mansion-2-hd-review"><u>Luigi’s Mansion 2 HD</u></a> is a remake of the 2013 Nintendo 3DS game Luigi’s Mansion: Dark Moon. This second game in the spooky series sees Luigi ghostbusting his way through the mansions of Evershade Valley to once again capture King Boo and save his brother.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership (2024) </h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/10/09/marioluigibrothership-finalpreview-blogroll-1728514682488.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Sure, it's not exclusively a 'Luigi game,' but <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-and-luigi-brothership-review">Mario &amp; Luigi: Brothership</a> certainly puts the brothers on even footing. Brothership is the first release in the Mario &amp; Luigi series since Paper Jam in 2014. Players take on the role of both brothers, who must traverse puzzles and platforming challenges to restore the kingdom of Concordia. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">Every Other Game You Can Play as Luigi on Switch </h2><h3 data-cy="title3">Mario Kart 8 Deluxe (2017)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/mk8-1741991217577.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">The first Switch game to feature Luigi as a playable character was <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/04/20/mario-kart-8-deluxe-review"><u>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe</u></a>. Luigi appears as a middleweight racer with a well-balanced stat distribution that slightly favors speed and handling. His appearance in an ad for the original Wii U version of Mario Kart 8 spawned the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pAZ1Bvxb0b8" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Luigi Death Stare meme</u></a>.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Mario + Rabbids Kingdom Battle (2017)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/kingdombattle-1741991199324.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Luigi next appeared in the Nintendo-Ubisoft collaboration <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/08/28/mario-rabbids-kingdom-battle-review"><u>Mario + Rabbids Kingdom Battle</u></a>. The tactical RPG features both Luigi and Rabbid Luigi, a Rabbid who dresses (and often behaves) like his human counterpart, as possible party members.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Mario Tennis Aces (2018)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/tennisaces-1741991188916.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Luigi hit the court as one of 16 playable launch characters in 2018’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/06/20/mario-tennis-aces-review"><u>Mario Tennis Aces</u></a>. As is often true for Luigi in Mario sports games, he’s a balanced, “all-around” character in Aces. His specialty shot, Pipe Cannon, blasts him into the air to set him up for a powerful spike.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Super Mario Party (2018)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/supermarioparty-1741991178802.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Luigi is one of 20 playable characters in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/10/03/super-mario-party-review"><u>Super Mario Party</u></a>. The younger of the Mario Bros. has appeared alongside his brother in every Mario Party game to date, including the two others further down this list. This is the first Mario Party game released for Switch and Nintendo’s ninth best-selling game on the platform, <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/en/finance/software/index.html" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>according to the company</u></a>.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Super Smash Bros. Ultimate (2018)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/smash-1741991162057.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Luigi appears in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/12/06/super-smash-bros-ultimate-review"><u>Super Smash Bros. Ultimate</u></a> as an unlockable character. He is one of 12 characters to be playable in all five Smash games. According to <a href="https://luminosity.gg/news/smash-ultimates-3rd-official-tier-list" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>LumiRank’s</u></a> 2025 tier list, which compiled the opinions of 93 ranked Smash players, Luigi is an A+-tier fighter and the 18th best overall.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">New Super Mario Bros. U Deluxe (2019)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/deluxeu-1741991084079.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Luigi is a playable character in the 2019 platformer <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/01/09/new-super-mario-bros-u-deluxe-review"><u>New Super Mario Bros. U Deluxe</u></a>. This is an expanded version of NSMBU for Wii U that includes the expansion New Super Luigi U. Luigi stars as the main character in this expansion, which incorporates his higher jump, remixes levels from the base game, and adds a 100-second timer to each level.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Super Mario Maker 2 (2019)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/mariomaker2-1741991064587.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Alongside Mario, Toad, and Toadette, Luigi is one of four playable characters in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/06/26/super-mario-maker-2-review"><u>Super Mario Maker 2</u></a>. The level-building platformer allows players to create their own Mario levels using assets from Super Mario Bros., Super Mario Bros. 3, Super Mario World, New Super Mario Bros. U, and Super Mario 3D World.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Super Mario 3D World + Bowser’s Fury (2021)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/mario3dworld-1741990999080.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Like the original Wii U release, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-3d-world-bowsers-fury-review"><u>Super Mario 3D World + Bowser’s Fury</u></a> can be played entirely as Luigi. Here, he controls similarly to Mario, albeit with a slightly higher jump and slightly less traction, making him play a bit more ‘floaty’ and ‘slippery’ than his red-capped counterpart.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Mario Golf: Super Rush (2021)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/golfsuperrush-1741990986408.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Luigi hit the links with Mario and friends in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-golf-super-rush-review"><u>Mario Golf: Super Rush</u></a>. One of 22 playable characters, he boasts decent control and excellent speed stats, making him a great option for Super Rush’s new Speed Golf mode. His special shot, Ice Flower Freeze, freezes the ground upon the ball’s impact, creating a hazardous area for opponents.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Mario Party Superstars (2021)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/partysuperstars-1741990975616.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Luigi returns for the second iteration of Mario Party on Switch: <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-party-superstars-review"><u>Mario Party Superstars</u></a>. Unlike Super Mario Party before it, Superstars is not an original game but rather a modern collection of minigames, boards, and mechanics from the series’ past.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Mario Strikers: Battle League Football (2022)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/strikersbattleleague-1741990962863.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-strikers-battle-league-review"><u>Mario Strikers: Battle League Football</u></a>, the latest Mario soccer/football game, features Luigi as one of 16 playable characters. Luigi is a well-balanced footballer who excels in technique, a skill that determines a character’s ability to dribble, curve their shot, and shoot accurately. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">Mario + Rabbids Sparks of Hope (2022)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/sparksofhope-1741990948847.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Luigi (and Rabbid Luigi) returned for Ubisoft and Nintendo’s tactical sequel, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-rabbids-sparks-of-hope-review"><u>Mario + Rabbids Sparks of Hope</u></a>. Luigi is labeled a Sneak Attacker due to his ranged weaponry and low health.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Super Mario Bros. Wonder (2023)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/wonder-1741990936908.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-bros-wonder-review"><u>Super Mario Bros. Wonder</u></a>, the latest 2D Mario platformer, features Luigi as a playable alternative to Mario. The difference between the two characters here is purely aesthetic, as the Mario Bros. play identically to one another.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Super Mario Party Jamboree (2024)</h3><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/14/jamboree-1741990911653.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Unsurprisingly, Luigi is playable in <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/super-mario-party-jamboree-review"><u>Super Mario Party Jamboree</u></a>, the biggest and arguably best game in Nintendo’s flagship party series. In addition to being a playable character, Luigi appears as part of Jamboree’s new Buddy mechanic, where he has the chance to change a player’s dice rolls from their initial numbers to 10s.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">What's Next for Luigi? </h2><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The next time you'll be able to play as Luigi is a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-9-every-character-track-and-vehicle-confirmed-for-the-nintendo-switch-2-game">new Mario Kart game</a>, expected to release alongside the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/tech/nintendo-switch-2">Switch 2</a>, that features double the usual amount of racers. Yes, that means <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-kart-9-first-look-suggests-24-person-races-are-coming-to-the-nintendo-switch-2-game">24 racers</a> on each track. Otherwise, I'm sure Mario will bring Luigi along for whatever his next adventure is. Plenty more games are <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/all-the-games-reportedly-set-for-release-on-nintendo-switch-2">rumored</a> to be releasing with Nintendo's next console generation, and the next updates will likely come out of a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-direct-announced-for-april">Nintendo Direct scheduled for April 2</a>. </p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Jordan covers games, shows, and movies as a freelance writer for IGN.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Is Impressive, But Does The Story Work?]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-story-yasuke-podcast-revie</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-is-impressive-but-does-the-story-work.1141800/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-story-yasuke-podcast-revie<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows </em>is out in the world, and the long dread of its release has finally dissipated. But is the game any good? <a href="http://://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-seasons-change-nature-review" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">It’s gorgeous</a>, but does it succeed in the narrative it’s trying to tell? And how does it balance historical accuracy with having a good time? On the latest episode of Aftermath Hours, we talk about it.</p><p>I have been pretty high on what I’ve played on <em>Assassin’s Creed Shadows</em>, as has Luke. But being only a measly 28 or so hours into the game and only just having gotten Yasuke as a playable character, we decided to bring a ringer on to the pod who has, you know, actually finished the game. To that end we invited my old friend and games writer Yussef Cole to give some perspective after submitting a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/03/18/arts/assassins-creed-shadows-review.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fairly critical review</a> of the game for The New York Times. We talk about what the game does right and wrong, its place in the series generally, and how that fits into the context of Japan, Yasuke’s context in Japanese history, and the perennial problem of accuracy versus “having fun” that plagues all of these games.&nbsp;</p><p>You can follow Yussef on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/youmeyou.bsky.social" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bluesky</a>. Yussef also co-edits <a href="https://bulletpointsmonthly.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bulletpoints Monthly</a>, a website dedicated to longform games criticism.&nbsp;</p><p>You can find this week's episode below and on<a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/7qtlX6MNeEoyNuHBU0chUJ?si=a2f12b75911f43cb" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Spotify</a>,<a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/aftermath-hours/id1727407094" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Apple</a>, or wherever else you prefer to listen to podcasts. If you like what you hear, make sure to leave a review so that we can eventually build a beautiful minka-style house for the Aftermath crew to work in while painting beautiful sumi-e style paintings about gaming.&nbsp;</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/assassins-creed-shadows-seasons-change-nature-review"><h3>Assassin’s Creed Shadows Gets Nature Right</h3></a><p>In Assassin's Creed Shadows, nature is the star of the show.</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/valnet-report-freelance"><h3>Report: Valnet Blacklisted Freelancers Who Complained About Pay Rates</h3></a><p>A new report from The Wrap highlights low pay and a list of blacklisted writers at the company</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/uvw-cwa-video-game-union-microsoft-trump-musk"><h3>CWA And Video Game Workers Launch New Industry-Wide Union Anyone Can Join, Even If They’ve Been Laid Off</h3></a><p>With the Department of Labor and National Labor Relations Board under attack by Trump, CWA is trying something old and new</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Arcade is Reportedly Unprofitable Without Subscription Bundle]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/apple-arcade-is-reportedly-unprofitable-without-apple-one-bundle/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/apple-arcade-is-reportedly-unprofitable-without-subscription-bundle.1141761/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/apple-arcade-is-reportedly-unprofitable-without-apple-one-bundle/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Apple Arcade, the mobile gaming subscription service, is reportedly one of several Apple services suffering from low usage and profits. It’s been reported in the past that payouts to developers have been declining for years, and if it weren’t included in the Apple One bundle, it would be considered unprofitable.</p>



<h2 id="h-25-of-apple-arcade-users-during-it-first-years-were-on-free-trials">25% of Apple Arcade Users During it First Years Were on Free Trials</h2>



<p>The information comes, ironically, from tech and business news outlet The Information, who <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/apple-streaming-losses-top-1-billion-year" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reported</a> that Apple is losing over $1 billion a year on its streaming service, Apple TV+. The report also mentions other Apple services that are supposedly not performing well, including Apple Arcade.</p>



<p>“Apple Arcade, for example, had only 2 million users in its first year after it launched in 2019, with roughly 25% of them on free trials, according to one person with direct knowledge of the figures,” reads The Information’s report. “Without Apple One, some services, such as Apple Arcade and Fitness+, likely wouldn’t be profitable.” Apple One is a subscription bundle introduced in 2020 that offers access to Apple Music, Apple TV+, Apple Arcade, and iCloud storage, with a Premier plan option that includes Apple News+ and Apple Fitness+ as well.</p>



<p>Apple Arcade was launched only a year prior in 2019, offering direct access to paid games without advertisements or in-app purchases. 71 games were included at launch, and developers like Capcom, Sega, Bandai Namco, and Devolver Digital partnered with Apple to create games for the service. But <a href="https://mobilegamer.biz/inside-apple-arcade-axed-games-declining-payouts-disillusioned-studios-and-an-uncertain-future/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a report</a> from Neil Long at Mobilegamer.biz from last year claimed that payouts to developers had been declining for year, and that a “shitload” of projects had been canceled. One developer reportedly told Long that the Apple Arcade service had “the smell of death” around it. Still, Apple <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/final-fantasy-trials-of-mana-and-more-coming-to-apple-arcade-this-month/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">added 10 new games to the service just this past January</a>.</p>



<p>Are Apple Arcade’s days numbered? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/playstation-controllers-could-run-on-solar-energy-in-the-future/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sony’s new patent for a solar-powered PlayStation controller</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Upcoming Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation Superdrop Brings Burst of Variety]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/upcoming-secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-superdrop-brings-burst-of-variety</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/upcoming-secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-superdrop-brings-burst-of-variety.1141746/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/upcoming-secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-superdrop-brings-burst-of-variety<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Wizards of the Coast has announced a Secret Lair superdrop for <a href="https://techraptor.net/games/magic-the-gathering" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"><em>Magic: The Gathering</em></a>. The lengthy Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation superdrop will contain nine special drops for fans of the game to pick up, with a special promo card for those that go all in.</p>

<h2>The Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation Superdrop Announcement</h2>

<p>In the official <a href="https://magic.wizards.com/en/news/announcements/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-superdrop" rel="nofollow">store page</a>, Wizards of the Coast outlines the cards in the Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation superdrop. As the name implies, the cards in this superdrop are chaotic and sporadic. As if the person in charge wasn't around to approve them.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-spongebob-meme-cards.jpg?itok=AwPuvRi2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-spongebob-meme-cards.jpg?itok=0buJQmb4 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The first three drops in the superdrop are the previously announced <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/spongebob-secret-lair-brings-iconic-cartoon-to-magic-gathering" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Spongebob Squarepants Secret Lairs</a>. Want to wield Mr. Krabs or Sandy Cheeks as Legendary Creatures or just cast meme-art versions of Counterspell and Force of Despair? These are the cards to pick up.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-dragonlord-card-artwork.jpg?itok=IxnkUZQ6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-dragonlord-card-artwork.jpg?itok=bDcYs2ax 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The fourth drop in the Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation superdrop is all about dragons. The <em>They Grow Up So Fast</em> drop showcases five different dragonlord cards. Each card is reversible. One side shows the dragon as a recently hatched wyrmling. the other shows them fully matured. This drop contains the following cards:</p>

<ul><li><em>Dragonlord Atarka</em></li>
	<li><em>Dragonlord Dromoka</em></li>
	<li><em>Dragonlord Kologhan</em></li>
	<li><em>Dragonlord Ojutai</em></li>
	<li><em>Dragonlord Silumgar</em></li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-garden-buds-card-artwork.jpg?itok=olZliX4E 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-garden-buds-card-artwork.jpg?itok=E8KJPcgo 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>For those with an eye for nature, the fifth drop is for you. The <em>Garden Buds</em> drop showcases nature or forest-dwelling cards in a trippy artstyle courtesy of Jordan Crane. The cards featured in this drop are as follows:</p>

<ul><li><em>Ashaya, Soul of the Wind</em></li>
	<li><em>Elvish Reclaimer</em></li>
	<li><em>Harrow</em></li>
	<li><em>World Shaper</em></li>
	<li><em>Horn of Greed</em></li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-tragic-romance-artwork.jpg?itok=Oh6dpFgv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-tragic-romance-artwork.jpg?itok=-yv75yRj 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Drop six is for those that have indulged in a bit of fantasy romance. Aptly named <em>Tragic Romance</em>, this drop contains four cards with artwork straight out of a harlequin romance novel showcasing art by Abigail Larson. Those four cards are:</p>

<ul><li><em>Skithiryx, the Blight Dragon</em></li>
	<li><em>Kaalia of the Vast</em></li>
	<li><em>Angel of Despair</em></li>
	<li><em>Master of Cruelties</em></li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-twisted-toons-cards.jpg?itok=KxfwWXC4 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-twisted-toons-cards.jpg?itok=MbsPPp4y 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>In a complete pivot in tone is the seventh drop. The <em>Twisted Toons</em> drop sports an early 20th century cartoon look straight out of Fleisher Studios. If you like old-school Disney, or played a lot of Cuphead, these cards may catch your eye. Those cards are.</p>

<ul><li><em>Silence</em></li>
	<li><em>Winds of Abandon</em></li>
	<li><em>Culling of the Weak</em></li>
	<li><em>Fatal Push</em></li>
	<li><em>Young Wolf</em></li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-pick-em-and-stick-em-artwork.jpg?itok=FYlJGkfx 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-pick-em-and-stick-em-artwork.jpg?itok=nRujkfKD 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>The eighth drop in the Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation superdrop is yet another switch in tone. The <em>Pick 'Em and Stick 'Em</em> drop is a candy coated dose of bright, colorful fluff. It even has sheets of stickers to customize those cards further. The drop contains the following:</p>

<ul><li><em>Thalia, Heretic Cathar</em></li>
	<li><em>Clever Impersonator</em></li>
	<li><em>Hedron Crab</em></li>
	<li><em>Pitiless Plunderer</em></li>
	<li>Treasure Token</li>
</ul><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-class-of-87-artwork.jpg?itok=yjCvLUQE 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/secret-lair-our-boss-is-on-vacation-class-of-87-artwork.jpg?itok=-edc-THw 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>Last but not least is the S<em>ecret Lair: Class of '87</em> drop. As the name implies, this drop reimagines several cards as high school yearbook photos. The artwork by Stephen Andrade and Scott Okumura even goes that extra mile with era-specific stylized text. The cards in this drop are:</p>

<ul><li><em>Aesi, Tyrant of Gyre Strait</em></li>
	<li><em>Anje Falkenrath</em></li>
	<li><em>Chulane, Teller of Tales</em></li>
	<li><em>Radha, Heart of Keld</em></li>
</ul><p>All nine drops in the Secret Lair Our Boss Is On Vacation superdrop is available in both non-foil (MSRP $29.99) and foil (MSRP $39.99). In addition, if you spend more than $150 on a single order, you will receive a rainbow foil Deadeye Navigator promo card at no additional charge. The superdrop will be available March 24.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There's A Lot Of Cool Dinosaur Games To Be Excited About]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dinosaur-games-dino-crisis-jurassic-park-horror-pc-ps5-1851771664</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/theres-a-lot-of-cool-dinosaur-games-to-be-excited-about.1141743/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/dinosaur-games-dino-crisis-jurassic-park-horror-pc-ps5-1851771664<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="c5fd0c70df2137d2dfc1588c4de5cf50" data-recommend-id="image://c5fd0c70df2137d2dfc1588c4de5cf50" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Annapurna / Jaw Drop / Saber / Universal / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="c5fd0c70df2137d2dfc1588c4de5cf50" data-recommend-id="image://c5fd0c70df2137d2dfc1588c4de5cf50" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="false" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>A decade ago, in a poorly written post on my terrible old blog that I won’t link to here, I pondered why we didn’t have more dinosaur games. At the time I blamed it on technical limitations and a focus on zombie-filled wastelands, and the lack of good dinosaur games made me really sad. So I’m happy to report that in 2025 we have a bunch of new dinosaur games to get excited about, and not all of them are <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/jurassic-world-rebirth-trailer-every-dinosaur-mutant-1851755947&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/jurassic-world-rebirth-trailer-every-dinosaur-mutant-1851755947"><em>Jurassic Park</em>-related</a></span>. </p><p>Just yesterday,<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/future-games-showcase-2025-trailers-painkiller-1851771551&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/future-games-showcase-2025-trailers-painkiller-1851771551"> during the Spring Future Games Show</a></span>, another new dinosaur game was announced: <em>Deathground</em>, a co-op survival horror game featuring dangerous dinos. And it’s just one of many upcoming games that look to be trying to fill the <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/capcom-survey-dino-crisis-sequel-remake-onimusha-okami-1851235768?_gl=1*1rb6268*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MjU4NjY3MS4yMi4xLjE3NDI1ODc0MzMuNTguMC4w&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/capcom-survey-dino-crisis-sequel-remake-onimusha-okami-1851235768?_gl=1*1rb6268*_ga*MTc0MjY2NTg1OS4xNzQwMzc1OTc4*_ga_V4QNJTT5L0*MTc0MjU4NjY3MS4yMi4xLjE3NDI1ODc0MzMuNTguMC4w">creepy, <em>Dino Crisis</em>-shaped void</a></span> that currently exists because Capcom won’t remake or develop a new entry in the franchise. </p><p>So let’s take a look at some of the potentially awesome dinosaur games coming to a video game console or PC near you. (Oh and spoilers, but none of the games listed in here have release dates, so who knows how long we’ll have to wait to play them.)</p></div></div><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/jurassic-park-survival-fps-action-trailer-game-awards-1851083053&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/jurassic-park-survival-fps-action-trailer-game-awards-1851083053">Announced back in 2023</a></span>, <em>Jurassic Park: Survival</em> is an upcoming first-person survival horror game being developed by Saber Interactive. Since its announcement we’ve not heard or seen much else about the project, but we know it’s still in the works. Let’s hope this game is better than <em>Trespasser</em>.</p></div><div><p>Set to be published by Annapurna Interactive, <em>The Lost Wild</em> is also a first-person survival horror game set on a jungle-covered island filled with hungry dinosaurs and abandoned science facilities. The trailers we’ve seen for this upcoming dino game look amazing, and if it plays as well as it looks we might be in for a terrifying treat.</p></div><div><p>Stop me if you’ve heard this before. <em> Compound Fracture</em> is a spooky first-person game featuring dinosaurs and dilapidated facilities where questionable science took place. However, unlike the other games on this list, <em>Compound Fracture</em> is designed to look and play more like a 1990s game, complete with some lovely looking low res textures. I’m very excited to see more of this indie game in the future.</p></div><div><p>This is the most recently announced game on our list and while it has some similarities to  the other dinosaur games we’ve looked at, including its FPS perspective and focus on horror, <em>Deathground </em>will support online co-op. Also, the dinosaurs in this upcoming survival horror multiplayer game have feathers. I’ll let you decide how you feel about that.</p></div><div><p>While many of the games on this list are directly inspired by <em>Jurassic Park </em>and its lush tropical jungles, <em>Paleophage </em>is clearly riffing on recent <em>Resident Evil</em> remakes with its more urban setting and third-person camera. That sounds great to me! If this game is half as good as the recent <em>RE4 </em>remake and also has dinosaurs in it, I’ll be perfectly satisfied.</p></div><div><p>Not every upcoming dinosaur game is a survival horror adventure. Take <em>Turok Origins</em>, which was announced in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/turok-origins-new-game-saber-space-marine-third-person-1851720969&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/turok-origins-new-game-saber-space-marine-third-person-1851720969">December 2024</a></span> and looks to be a co-op third-person shooter set in the strange prehistoric alien universe of <em>Turok</em>. It’s being developed by the company behind S<em>pace Marine 2.</em></p></div><div><p>Published by TinyBuild, <em>Ferocious </em>is described by its devs as an old-school, action-packed FPS set on a tropical island inhabited by dangerous mercs and even more dangerous dinos. Simple premise, but the game basically looks like <em>Far Cry </em>+ dinosaurs and that’s a formula that has me excited to play. </p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Okay, But What If Severance Ended Here?]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/severance-season-2-finale-helly-mark-gemma-3-renewal-1851771662</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/okay-but-what-if-severance-ended-here.1141713/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/severance-season-2-finale-helly-mark-gemma-3-renewal-1851771662<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The most surprising thing for me about the end of <em>Severance</em>’s second season was how few questions I still had when it was all over. Apple TV’s dystopian workplace thriller is a mystery box show, and yeah, there are still plenty of unsolved puzzles on the Lumon severed floor, but when the credits started rolling, I wasn’t frantically looking for a stinger that might tease what comes next.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><figure id="" data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><span data-id="afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-recommend-id="image://afpvuwnfoibrncd6upmy" data-format="png" data-width="800" data-height="88" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>Severance</em>’s season finale, “Cold Harbor,” finally takes us across the finish line the show has meticulously guided us to for the past 10 episodes. The innie and outie of Mark Scout (Adam Scott) communicate by camcorder, walking in and out of a severed cabin to discuss a game plan to get Gemma (Dichen Lachman), Outie Mark’s wife, out from the depths of Lumon’s testing floor before the corporation puts her out to pasture. Innie Mark realizes that if he goes along with the plan to save Gemma and expose Lumon for kidnapping her, it will likely sink the company and lead to the dissolution of the severed floor, leading to the “deaths” of every innie on the floor.</p><p>Outie Mark believes that the people working on the severed floor are going through a “nightmare” that is nothing more than torture. But Innie Mark doesn’t view it that way. Sure, he knows Lumon should be stopped, but he envisions a life with Helly (Britt Lower), even if it’s only eight hours long most days. It’s only half a life, but it’s one he would rather fight for than give up for a woman he doesn’t even know. The recorded back and forth between both Marks goes south, and then Cobel (Patricia Arquette) tells Innie Mark plainly that there is no honeymoon ending for him and Helly. Mark’s reintegration may allow his innie’s memories to live on, but there’s no version of events in which he and Helly get to live out the lives they’ve been dreaming of. At least, that’s what everyone is telling him.</p><p><em>Severance </em>has spent much of its second season exploring just how different innies and outies are from one another. Are certain parts of us innate, even without all the memories and trauma that shape us? Was her familiarity why Mark couldn’t tell that Helly’s outie was spying on them for half the season? Could the undeniable parallels carried between innies and outies be why Dylan (Zach Cherry) was drawn to his wife both in and out of the severed floor? For Helly, the question of whether or not certain parts of us are innate is fatalistic. She has tried to differentiate her innie self from her cutthroat corporate heiress outie, just for her father (Michael Siberry) to tell her that he sees more of the fire of her ancestor and Lumon founder Kier Eagan in the severed version of her than he ever did the daughter he raised. Conversely, Dylan finds hope in his innie’s reassured confidence because maybe it means that spirit is in him too, deep down. Irving (John Turturro) and Burt (Christopher Walken) may have had no recollection of their workplace love affair but <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/severance-ep-9-season-2-burt-irving-relationship-gay-1851770084&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/severance-ep-9-season-2-burt-irving-relationship-gay-1851770084">were still drawn to each other on the surface</a></span>.</p><p>That’s the introspective angle, but <em>Severance </em>is also clear about how these bisected personalities are two different entities and only one gets any say in either of their lives, like an overbearing parent to their offspring. During the recorded conversation between the Marks, the outie starts to call the gradually more defiant innie a “child,” as if wanting to have his own life, one that’s no longer dictated by someone who only cared to know anything about him when he needed something, was the equivalent of an unruly kid throwing a tantrum. Mark and his inner circle may be the “good guys,” but they’re not that different from Helly’s outie who, in season one, also condescended to her innie like a controlling parent. Lower’s delivery of “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rc8hut6vMG0&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rc8hut6vMG0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">I am a person. You are not</a></span>” rang in my head as Mark tried to tell his innie that he should give his life for Gemma so his outie could have a happy ending. Innies were always tools to be forgotten by even the most well-meaning Lumon employee, and though Mark tries to reason with his other half, the mask falls off as his frustration gives way to dehumanization. Eventually, the bittersweet fatalism wins out and the innie agrees to save his outie’s wife.</p><p>Gemma’s jailbreak requires the cooperation of both versions of Mark as they move between floors, and “Cold Harbor” does a stellar job of illustrating the disorienting disconnect of swapping between severed personalities in rapid succession. Outie Mark wakes up with a gun in his hand and accidentally kills a man in an elevator. Innie Mark gets control back minutes later in a blood-soaked liplock with Gemma in the same elevator. Between the swaps, the show, which normally avoids explicit physical violence in favor of the psychological kind, here sees that restraint give way at last as the worst of Lumon’s goons finally facing a workplace uprising they’ve long deserved. But at the operation’s core is a conflicted Innie Mark who wants to live, has been told there’s no version of this where he and Helly get to run off into the sunset, and thinks the only way he can do anything with his final hours is to save Gemma and take down the company that “killed” Irving’s innie and so many others.</p><p>So how do you end a season that has spent the past 10 episodes wondering if a person with divided memories can ever see eye to eye with someone who essentially birthed them into a workplace they can never leave? There is no real compromise between both Marks, as the innie will lose the only life he’s ever known if he helps his outie bring his wife home. You do it with a final five minutes that leaves audiences devastated, and me quietly wishing the show could end on this stunning note. Mark’s innie gets Gemma to the exit and she’s finally able to escape. But when she turns around, her husband’s other half is hesitating at the door. If he walks through, he will hand the keys over to his outie and he doesn’t know if he can trust his outie to reintegrate. Even if he did, would this shared life even come close to resembling the one he wants? Then, Helly approaches from behind and calls his name.</p><figure id="" data-id="a38a286c441fced630a0931ecd97066a" data-recommend-id="image://a38a286c441fced630a0931ecd97066a" data-format="jpg" data-width="2843" data-height="1600" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Helly and Mark run down a hallway." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Helly and Mark run down a hallway." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Apple</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="a38a286c441fced630a0931ecd97066a" data-recommend-id="image://a38a286c441fced630a0931ecd97066a" data-format="jpg" data-width="2843" data-height="1600" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Helly and Mark run down a hallway." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>As a connoisseur of choice-based games, I could almost see the <em>Life Is Strange </em>decision UI on the screen as Mark thought about what to do next. Does he leave with his outie’s wife, who is crying and begging him to open the door and walk through, or does he choose his own happiness somewhere on this hellish severed floor? Gemma’s cries are harrowing; she’s finally reunited with her husband just to watch him walk away, holding hands with someone else. My god, what a note to end on.</p><p>Rebellion has been at the center of every episode of <em>Severance</em> this season. Throughout the Apple TV series, Lumon has treated asking questions, breaking rules, and defying orders as an immature endeavor against the inevitable. The corporation and its founder have an infinite wisdom that no worker should ever doubt. Innies are immature and bull-headed and are getting in the way of what their outies demand of them. This is the same condescension many misguided parents force upon a teenager who is breaking from the mold they were supposed to fill. We’re often taught that teenage rebellion is a phase one grows out of and regrets as they get older, but in truth a person, no matter how young, advocating for themselves and their ability to choose is just a basic human reaction to being told who and what you’re supposed to be. Innies have only ever been told they’re like tools, meant to live and die for the cause of the workplace, and are merely an extension of the “real” person who can discard them at any moment. Mark denying his outie’s wishes and deciding to run hand-in-hand with Helly to the deepest parts of the Lumon maze in hopes that they could spend even just a few more minutes together is the only conclusion this story could have possibly reached. All the slow burn was worth it. I know <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/severance-season-3-renew-finale-adam-scott-ben-stiller-1851771552&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/severance-season-3-renew-finale-adam-scott-ben-stiller-1851771552">there’s going to be a third season</a></span>, but god, it would have been incredible if this had been the end.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Netflix Boss Explains Why Company Killed The AAA Multiplayer Game From Halo Veteran]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/netflix-boss-explains-why-company-killed-the-aaa-multiplayer-game-from-halo-veteran/1100-6530293/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/netflix-boss-explains-why-company-killed-the-aaa-multiplayer-game-from-halo-veteran.1141710/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/netflix-boss-explains-why-company-killed-the-aaa-multiplayer-game-from-halo-veteran/1100-6530293/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530293">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Netflix was working on a AAA multiplayer shooter with a team that included Halo and Destiny veteran Joe Staten, but <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/netflix-shutters-aaa-game-studio-led-by-overwatch-and-halo-vets/1100-6527313/" data-ref-id="1100-6527313">the game and the studio were scuttled</a> in 2024. Why? One of Netflix's top gaming bosses, Alain Tascan, said in an interview that this project did not align with the company's goals.</p><p>"I don't want this move to be seen as, 'We're not going to do big ambitious games,'" <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-03-21/netflix-bets-big-on-video-games-with-broad-new-strategy" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Tascan told Bloomberg</a>. "It was just the genre of the game... I don't think was matching the platform. This team was really good at what they were doing, but we wouldn't have been the best partner for them to express their skills and their expertise."</p><p>The shift away from this game came amid a wider shakeup at at Netflix's film and TV divisions that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-what-kind-of-movies-netflix-wants-to-focus-on-going-forward/1100-6522677/" data-ref-id="1100-6522677">calls for fewer, less-expensive releases that aim for higher quality.</a> </p><p>Netflix is now focused on four main areas for its upcoming games slate, including party games, kids games, narrative games, and "mainstream" games. These titles will be made for phones and to be beamed to TVs via Netflix's own streaming systems--and won't come to Xbox or PlayStation consoles.</p><p>For years already, Netflix has been <a href="https://help.netflix.com/en/node/132197" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">testing streaming games directly to your TV or computer</a>, in addition to launching games for mobile.</p><p>"It's a little bit like a musician, we start copying a few things and then at one point we're going to find our voice," Tascan said. "I don't know how long it's going to take exactly, but I'm very bullish about us finding our voice."</p><p>Just this week, <a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/spry-foxs-spirit-crossing-comes-to-netflix-later-this-year" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Spry Fox announced Spirit Crossing for Netflix</a>, while Shenmue designer Yu Suzuki's new game <a href="https://www.netflix.com/tudum/articles/steel-paws-mobile-game-news" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steel Paws</a> was released in February. </p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard Gets Surprise Free Weapon DLC After Months Without an Update]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-gets-surprise-free-weapon-dlc-after-months-without-an-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-gets-surprise-free-weapon-dlc-after-months-without-an-update.1141689/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-gets-surprise-free-weapon-dlc-after-months-without-an-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">BioWare has almost entirely moved on from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/dragon-age-the-veilguard"><u>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</u></a>, but that isn’t stopping its remaining team from sneakily adding a small DLC weapons pack to the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragon Age fans gathered in shock after the RPG’s Steam page was updated to include free add-on content in the form of the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3281890/Dragon_Age_The_Veilguard_Rooks_Weapons_Appearance_Offer/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Rook’s Weapons Appearance Offer</u></a> yesterday. It’s not much but still more than welcome considering EA had previously signaled that Dragon Age: The Veilguard wouldn’t receive much support in the future. As its <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-patch-notes-sure-make-it-sound-like-biowares-basically-done-with-the-game-now"><u>fifth patch</u></a> promised that future updates would largely focus on tackling game-breaking bugs all the way back in January, brand-new content feels like a bit of a miracle – even if it’s not much.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Strangely, the Rook’s Weapons Appearances bundle is only available to those who currently own the game and those who purchase it on PC by April 8, 2025. There’s no description of what is specifically included in the bundle either, though <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DragonAgeVeilguard/comments/1jg2036/comment/miwt2nm/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>players have worked out</u></a> that it grants access to a set of Watchful skins that can be accessed in their Rook’s in-game room. It's unclear if the offer will become available for PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X | S versions of the game.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Even if these appearances aren't the most, uh, beautiful things ever,” one <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/id/sissy_the_siren/recommended/3281890/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Steam review says</u></a>, “they do give spooky eldritch horror vibes!”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"It's cosmetic DLC, but it's essentially free DLC for a game that's practically no longer getting newer content," <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DragonAgeVeilguard/comments/1jg2036/comment/miy533l/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one Redditor said</a>. "I'll live with that."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragon Age: The Veilguard launched to positive reviews from critics in October but, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ea-ceo-says-dragon-age-the-veilguard-failed-to-resonate-with-a-broad-audience-gamers-increasingly-want-shared-world-features"><u>according to EA</u></a>, failed to “resonate with a broad enough audience.” Lead members of its team announced they would be <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/dragon-age-developers-reveal-theyve-been-laid-off-after-bioware-puts-full-focus-on-mass-effect"><u>leaving BioWare in late January as much of its staff was either laid off or moved to other roles within the company</u></a>. At the time, EA told IGN that the studio had shifted to <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mass-effect-5-bioware-doesnt-require-support-from-the-full-studio-ea-moves-some-staff-to-other-teams"><u>put its “full focus” on the next Mass Effect</u></a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Dragon Age: The Veilguard joined the lineup of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/4-months-after-launch-dragon-age-the-veilguard-headlines-playstation-plus-march-2025-lineup"><u>PlayStation Plus March 2025 titles</u></a>, just four months removed from its launch. No other plans for its future have been announced.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Michael Cripe is a freelance contributor with IGN. He's best known for his work at sites like The Pitch, The Escapist, and OnlySP. Be sure to give him a follow on Bluesky (@mikecripe.bsky.social) and Twitter (@MikeCripe).</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 10 Best Assassin's Creed Games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/best-assassins-creed-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-10-best-assassins-creed-games.1141686/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/best-assassins-creed-games<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">The <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/assassins-creed-games-in-order">Assassin's Creed series</a> has had us globetrotting through history since its debut in 2007. From Renaissance Italy to Ancient Greece, Ubisoft's open world series has explored a wonderful variety of locations and settings, ensuring each conspiracy-packed game is a (semi) educational window into the past. Such an approach has made the series unique among its genre stablemates, which tend to whisk us away to fantasy lands or sprawling modern-day metropolises. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">While the bones of Assassin's Creed have mostly remained the same across its 14 mainline entries, the series has undergone a lot of changes over the years, including new takes on player progression and ever-expanding worlds.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">But which Assassin's Creed games are the best of the bunch? It's a tough question. After much deliberation (and only a handful of arguments), though, we’ve eventually agreed on the top 10 mainline entries in the series.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">So, without further ado, here are our top 10 Assassin’s Creed games.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">The 10 Best Assassin's Creed Games</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Playing the latest game in the series? Check out our </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/wikis/assassins-creed-shadows"><em>Assassin's Creed Shadows guide</em></a><em>. </em></p><h2 data-cy="title2">10. Assassin's Creed: Revelations</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets1.ignimgs.com/2011/06/06/assassins-creed-revelations-20110606095314825-3464823.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Ubisoft</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-revelations">Assassin’s Creed: Revelations</a> wrapped up Altair Ibn-La-Ahad and Ezio Auditore’s stories, and, despite some unremarkable additions like the Den Defense mode, it was a memorable and thrilling send off. From flying down ziplines in Constantinople to hanging out with Leonardo Da Vinci, Revelations was packed full of fascinating adventures. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Ezio and Altair’s final chapter was, in a way, both a sign of things to come and a celebration of what came before. Not only did we get one final fling with these two after seeing them grow and learn from lives full of adventure, but we had a chance to say goodbye to the first era of Assassin’s Creed.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">9. Assassin's Creed Syndicate</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets2.ignimgs.com/2015/09/24/acssc63previewsasylumzipline1443101428jpg-9b2cc6.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Ubisoft</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Assassin’s Creed games are often as defined by their locations as they are their protagonists, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-syndicate">Assassin's Creed Syndicate</a>’s 19th Century Victorian London in the throes of industrialization may be the most memorable of the bunch. Sneaking around factories, racing horse-drawn carriages down the street, and even fighting Jack the Ripper all ground Syndicate in a setting that, while still fantastical, feels real.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Contributing to this sense of place is the string-heavy score from Journey composer Austin Wintory that doesn’t sound like anything else in the series before or after: dueling protagonists Jacob and Evie Fry even have their own soundtracks. It’s a small touch, but it’s one in a string of small touches that makes Syndicate’s world cohesive. Also, it’s hard to recall any game this side of Bloodborne that lets you fight this effectively with a cane.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">8. Assassin's Creed Valhalla</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2022/12/01/assassinscreedvalhallafinalcontent-blog-1669914922538.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Ubisoft</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-valhalla">Assassin's Creed Valhalla</a> didn’t reinvent the wheel like Origins did, but it did make some pretty substantial changes. Combat is weightier and more impactful than ever before; traditional side quests have been replaced by world events, making exploration and discovery much more organic; and the absurd amount of loot you’d have to organize and sift through was toned down substantially, making rewards feel much more valuable on the whole.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eivor might not be our favorite of the Assassin’s Creed protagonists, but her (or his) story is an engaging one, and is one of the best blendings of historical fantasy and mythology that the series has ever seen. Fans of Norse mythology are treated with a feast; not only do the sagas play a major role within the main campaign, but an entire game-length expansion set in the world of Thor and Odin practically turns Valhalla into a cousin of God of War. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">7. Assassin's Creed: Brotherhood</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/02/13/ss-c79ca0fa59bedea20c24e2ac0c2735e7ce2f3ae6-1920x1080-1739442669756.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Ubisoft</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-brotherhood">Assassin’s Creed Brotherhood</a> continues the story of Ezio Auditore da Firenze, cementing him as a fan-favorite protagonist for the series. It trades the diverse locations of Assassin’s Creed 2 for an expanded version of Rome and its surrounding countryside and builds on the new mechanics introduced in Assassins Creed 2 – swimming, property management, firearms, and recruitable allies. This chapter of Ezio’s story is filled with charm, wit, and drama, and, thanks to its updated combat, we got to be the aggressive combat assassin we all wanted to be.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It was also the first game in the series to introduce multiplayer, allowing players to step into the shoes of the Templars to see who among their friends truly was the best assassin or hunter. It may not have advanced the formula as much as its predecessor, but it’s still cherished by many as one of the very best. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">6. Assassin's Creed Origins</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/02/13/ss-1a0ab42e93e51c48ad9a6bda7f408958e09a43b0-1920x1080-1739443042212.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Ubisoft</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Origins marked a turning point in the series. It was the game that turned Assassin’s Creed from a stealth-focused action-adventure, into a straight-up open world RPG with a size and scope rivaled only by very few games. But even setting the historical significance of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-origins">Assassin’s Creed Origins</a> aside, it’s important to note that it’s also just a damn good Assassin’s Creed game. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Its central story involving Bayek and Aya, who initially set out to find justice for their murdered son and ultimately wind up founding the order that would eventually become the Assassin’s Brotherhood, is extremely compelling; the world of ancient Egypt is a marvel to explore; and while many facets of its mechanics were improved in later games, the shift to loot-based progression and a more action <a href="https://www.ign.com/lists/top-100-rpgs" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RPG</a> style of combat was just the kind of shot in the arm that the series needed to reinvigorate it in the eyes of fans.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">5. Assassin's Creed Unity</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets2.ignimgs.com/2014/06/09/acuscreencombatsworde31406094pmpst1402143761jpg-b685a9.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Ubisoft</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">After the tipsy sway of Black Flag’s pirate protagonist Edward Kenway, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-unity">Assassin’s Creed Unity</a> was a return to the tone of original Assassin’s Creed. As the first AC game to be exclusively released on Xbox One and PlayStation 4 (alongside PC of course), Assassin’s Creed Unity was a graphical powerhouse for its time, boasting enormous crowds of NPCs walking through the streets of a near 1:1 accurate recreation of Paris. Even today, it’s still remarkably handsome to look at.  </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Unfortunately, Unity’s launch was a bit of a bumpy ride. A cavalcade of bugs, glitches, and an intensely overburdened map meant it was quickly written off by many. However, in the years since it has (thanks to several patches) blossomed into a firm favourite among Assassin’s Creed fans. Its enhanced movement system resulted in arguably the most fluid and elegant parkour the series has ever seen, which in turn allowed for excellent hit-and-run tactics. Its main assassination missions are also a series highpoint, offering a multitude of ways to infiltrate locations and bury your blade deep in a target’s neck. And frankly, seeing Notre Dame in all its glory makes AC Unity well worth the price of admission.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">4. Assassin's Creed Shadows</h2><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/03/19/acs-1742375176700.jpg" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p data-cy="paragraph">Feudal Japan is the most-requested setting for an Assassin’s Creed game of all time, and so Ubisoft faced towering expectations when it finally decided to visit the Sengoku period. Thankfully, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin’s Creed Shadows</a> was exactly what the series needed; it brings the focus back to assassinations, putting increased emphasis on stealth and infiltration. And while still expansive, the open world and RPG elements are more restrained than those in Odyssey and Valhalla, resulting in a tighter, more balanced experience. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">For the first time since Syndicate, Shadows features two playable protagonists. Naoe’s toolkit is rooted in stealth, while Yasuke is a brutal fighter who captures the period’s samurai fantasy. While Shadows is best experienced from a mix of both perspectives, taking control of Naoe and making use of her grappling hook and climbing abilities allows you the full freedom to explore what is undoubtedly the series’ most astonishing world, complete with landscapes that dynamically change with the shifting of the seasons. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">3. Assassin's Creed Odyssey</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/02/13/ss-16fc551879ac299dca68839da90f89d9e624db48-1920x1080-1739442948351.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Ubisoft</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-odyssey">Assassins’ Creed Odyssey</a> takes Origins’ combat style and new-found focus on role-playing, adds some extra ingredients to the mix, then sets it all against the sprawling backdrop of Ancient Greece, aflame with the war between Athens and Sparta. It’s an enormous, vibrant game, with some of the most stunning vistas we’ve seen in the series; both at land and sea (naval warfare returns here, and it’s wonderful). </p><p data-cy="paragraph">The new spin on Assassin’s Creed’s notoriety system sees you hunted across these environments, in a series of cat-and-mouse chases that are the most tense in any Assassin’s Creed to date, while the nation struggle system sees you fighting large scale battles in the name of Athens or Sparta. It’s also got a relatively compelling story for a game that can take 60-odd hours to beat, with some eccentric sidequests, fronted by a genuinely charismatic protagonist - whether you play as a male or female. Even after you finish Odyssey, there’s still so much to plunder and discover, and it’s a delight to simply exist in its world.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">2. Assassin's Creed 2</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2025/02/13/ss-d3967a58038cc5e59332bb0043ab1ca343112bc6-1920x1080-1739442866992.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Ubisoft</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">In many ways, we have <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-ii">Assassin’s Creed 2</a> to thank for not only proving the formula works but for also giving us the defining analogy of a video game sequel fulfilling the promise of its underwhelming original. Though later entries would add even more depth, ACII made assassination missions more dynamic, with increased flexibility in how you approached objectives, more options for hiding or causing distractions, better combat, and better mobility with the ability to actually swim. New catacomb missions let players put their parkour skills to the test, the upgradeable homebase villa gave players a reason to keep investing in picking up collectibles and coins, and new weapons and gear from everyone’s favorite video game character, Leonardo da Vinci, kept gameplay fresh. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">All of these changes were also connected to a beautifully realized Italian Renaissance era that introduced an all-time protagonist, Ezio Auditore da Firenze, and meaningful additions to the current-day story that brought the two time periods together in the wildest way possible. I mean, you fistfight the pope only to have an otherworldly deity speak through Ezio to Desmond in the present day. It was an unforgettable ending to an entry that proved how incredible Assassin’s Creed could be. </p><h2 data-cy="title2">1. Assassin's Creed 4: Black Flag</h2><output><figure><a href="https://assets2.ignimgs.com/2013/12/10/ac4bfdlc12500x1400jpg-885d49.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption data-cy="caption">Image credit: Ubisoft</figcaption></figure></output><p data-cy="paragraph">After a long run of assassin protagonists, Black Flag tried something different, introducing us to a main character who was a pirate first, and an assassin second - and the ensuing adventure thrived because of it. It introduced a massively entertaining sandbox playground in the Caribbean, featuring a plethora of islands teeming with treasure and activities to embark upon - and an upgrade system that made the idea of hunting wild animals and harpooning something other than a chore. Instead of relegating the idea of sailing as means to an end, it built upon the framework of Assassin’s Creed 3’s naval combat to make nautical adventures the shining point of Black Flag. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Whether it was hunting hapless merchant ships or bracing against some of the toughest buccaneers ever to sail the seas, attacking other ships cemented itself as something too good to pass up any time one floated by on screen. Aided by its impressive seamless transition from land to sea, it allowed the freedom of choice for players to either sail circles around enemy ships while blasting them to pieces, or ramming head on to leap onto the enemy ship, before unloading a brace of pistols like a whirling dervish. Not only did <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-black-flag">Assassin’s Creed 4: Black Flag</a> cement itself as one of the greatest in the series, it has easily become one of the greatest pirate games to immerse yourself in as well.</p><div id="every-assassins-creed-game-tier-list" data-cy="tierlist-view-trigger"><p><h3 data-cy="title3">Every Assassin's Creed Game Tier List</h3><h3>Every Assassin's Creed Game Tier List</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>You may also like: The </em><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-games-like-assassins-creed"><em>Best Games Like Assassin's Creed</em></a><em>.</em></p><p data-cy="paragraph">And there you have it! Those are our top Assassin’s Creed games. Disagree with the ranking? Think another entry should have been on the list? Let us know your favorite Assassin’s Creed in the comments.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Upcoming Assassin's Creed Games</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">If you're wondering what's coming next in the world of Assassin's Creed, there are a few titles to keep on your radar. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows">Assassin's Creed Shadows </a>has just released and sees you following the path of both a shinobi and samurai in Feudal Japan. <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-jade">Assassin's Creed Jade</a>, set in ancient China, is also in the works for mobile devices, but has no confirmed release date yet. If that's not enough Assassin's Creed goodness for you, beyond those we have <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/assassins-creed-codename-hexe">Assassin's Creed: Codename Hexe</a> to look forward to, the mysterious and occult-looking adventure that's set to bring new ideas to the series. </p><div data-cy="playlist-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="title3">Assassin's Creed: The Complete Playlist</h3><p>From 2007's debut title to the upcoming console, PC, mobile, and VR projects, here is the entire Assassin's Creed series in one list. Log in to track which ones you've played.</p></div></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Dramatic Half-Life Deal That Altered The Fate Of Valve Forever]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-dramatic-half-life-deal-that-altered-the-fate-of-valve-forever/1100-6530291/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-dramatic-half-life-deal-that-altered-the-fate-of-valve-forever.1141674/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-dramatic-half-life-deal-that-altered-the-fate-of-valve-forever/1100-6530291/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530291">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>One of Valve's most popular games, 1998's Half-Life, could have been the one and only game the company ever released, until a deal was struck that changed the company's fate forever. Monica Harrington, Valve's first chief marketing officer, said at the Game Developers Conference that publisher Sierra had the option for two more games, and after the first Half-Life became a gigantic success, Valve attempted to renegotiate with Sierra.</p><p>The terms of the deal, Harrington said, was that Valve would fund all but $1 million of the development costs of Half-Life's sequels, with Sierra retaining IP rights and giving Valve back 15% of revenue. "It felt insane," Harrington said, as reported by <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/fps/valve-would-never-ship-another-game-former-exec-forced-half-life-publishers-hand-by-saying-gabe-newell-and-the-team-would-pivot-away-from-game-dev/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">GamesRadar</a>.</p><p>Harrington said that if she and her husband Mike Harrington were to make real money out of being co-owners of Valve at the time, she knew Valve's prospects had to be "much, much brighter," and that included renegotiating with Sierra.</p><p>After getting the OK from Valve co-founder Gabe Newell, Harrington worked with Valve's attorney to hammer out a strategy for getting Half-Life's IP rights back, for the original Half-Life and all future titles. But how?</p><p>Harrington said she pushed for Valve and Sierra to strike a deal with the threat that Valve would abandon making games altogether if Sierra didn't come to the table. "Valve would never ship another game," Harrington recalled of the bargaining tactic.</p><p>"It wasn't an idle threat--we weren't going to take on all of the risk to make other people rich," Harrington said. "Besides, I knew Gabe had interesting ideas that had nothing to do with games."</p><p>One of those ideas was for Valve to create an <a href="https://medium.com/@monicah428/the-early-days-of-valve-from-a-woman-inside-bf80c6b47961" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">"online entertainment platform" with Amazon</a>, but this fell through. In the end, Valve won back control of the Half-Life series from Sierra. Valve went to release Half-Life 2 in 2004 and later the VR title Half-Life: Alyx in 2020--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-of-the-year-2020-half-life-alyx/1100-6485617/" data-ref-id="1100-6485617">that game won GameSpot's Game of the Year</a>. Valve's massively popular Counter-Strike series also traces its roots back to Half-Life, originating as a mod for that game.</p><p>Valve is much more than a game developer today, as it owns and operates the massively popular PC game store Steam. Companies have attempted to buy Valve over the years, but the company remains independent. Newell, for his part, has become a billionaire and now <a href="https://luxurylaunches.com/transport/gabe-newell-luxury-yachts.php" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">owns a half-dozen yachts that are valued at over $1 billion.</a></p><p>One criticism of Valve today is that the company no longer releases many games, instead focusing more on Steam and hardware with its Steam Deck. It does have more games in the works, though, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/valve-finally-acknowledges-deadlock-a-new-game-people-have-been-playing-for-months/1100-6526115/" data-ref-id="1100-6526115">including a 6v6 MOBA called Deadlock.</a> There is still no word on <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/half-life-3/">Half-Life 3</a>, however.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin's Creed Shadows' Snow Actually Melts When The Sun Comes Out]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-snow-actually-melts-when-the-sun-comes-out/1100-6530289/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassins-creed-shadows-snow-actually-melts-when-the-sun-comes-out.1141644/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-snow-actually-melts-when-the-sun-comes-out/1100-6530289/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530289">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows/">Assassin's Creed Shadows</a> is finally here, and players are just beginning to explore <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/assassins-creed-shadows-review-shinobi-simulator/1900-6418344/">the game's wide and wonderful open world</a>. Though that world includes many delightful little details that add a touch of realism to the game, it also includes a feature not commonly seen in open-world RPGs: snow that actually melts.</p><p dir="ltr">Most games featuring significant amounts of snow don't do much with it beyond allowing player-characters to leave footprints in the fresh, powdery precipitation. But Assassin's Creed Shadows take things a step further, with snow that actually responds to the in-game world's weather patterns.</p><p>Players can encounter snowstorms and other types of weather patterns in Assassin's Creed Shadows. But one eagle-eyed player noticed that not only does the snow melt, it melts slowly--after the sun has come out--rather than doing so instantly.</p><p dir="ltr">The player shared their findings on Twitter (formally known as X), uploading a video of Assassin's Creed Shadows co-protagonist Naoe sitting on her horse right after a snowstorm. As the sun begins peeking between the clouds, the snow on the ground begins to disappear. But it's not an instant transition--the footage is sped up significantly, as the snow slowly melts in a realistic manner.</p><p dir="ltr">Whatever you think of Ubisoft's latest time-traveling parkour adventure--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/assassins-creed-shadows-review-shinobi-simulator/1900-6418344/">GameSpot enjoyed it</a>--it's hard to argue that the game's beautiful vistas and detailed environments are anything short of stunning.</p><p>For more information on the latest entry in the Assassin's Creed franchise, check out our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/assassins-creed-shadows/guides/">Assassin's Creed Shadows guides hub</a>, where you can learn <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-increase-health-in-assassins-creed-shadows/1100-6530218/">how to raise your HP</a>, how to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/assassins-creed-shadows-resources-hideout-upgrade/1100-6530217/">get more resources to upgrade your hideout</a>, and--perhaps most importantly--<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/how-to-get-more-mon-or-money-in-assassins-creed-shadows/1100-6530216/">how to increase your income</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Assassin's Creed Shadows strengthened Ubisoft's process for bringing history to life]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/how-making-assassin-s-creed-shadows-strengthened-ubisoft-s-process-for-bringing-history-to-life</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-assassins-creed-shadows-strengthened-ubisofts-process-for-bringing-history-to-life.1141641/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/how-making-assassin-s-creed-shadows-strengthened-ubisoft-s-process-for-bringing-history-to-life<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The Assassin's Creed series is commonly praised for its stealth-action gameplay and iconic protagonists, but it would be fair to say that its greatest achievements lie in recreating sprawling historical settings for open-world exploration. Nearly 20 years since its debut, Ubisoft is now taking the series to historical Japan with </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Assassin's Creed Shadows. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">It's a setting that many fans of the series have wanted to see, and currently enjoying increased popularity due to FX's recent tv series Shogun.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">While the historical setting of Japan has been the subject of many games, particularly the likes of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Ghost of Tsushima</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, seeing it through the lens of Assassin's Creed is interesting. After all, this is a series that blends historical political conflicts with sci-fi and action-laden twists and the approach lends an opportunity to spotlight some often understated elements the history and politics of the era, while also reveling in the series' style of stealth gameplay and open world action.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Though the shift to historical Japan seemed like an obvious turn for the series (ninjas seem like a natural fit for the Order of Assassins), the developers at Ubisoft Quebec expressed that—just like previous entries—bringing the series to Japan required education and a need to highlight different perspectives of the era.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/-it-s-okay-to-make-a-small-game-astro-bot-director-nicolas-doucet-says-tiny-ideas-contain-huge-potential" target="_self" data-discover="true">'It's okay to make a small game:' Astro Bot director Nicolas Doucet says tiny ideas contain huge potential</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Speaking with creative director Jonathan Dumont during a visit to Ubisoft Quebec in early 2025, he explained what drew the team to the setting, given it was historical period of great change.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Why Assassin's Creed finally went to Japan">Why Assassin's Creed finally went to Japan</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The series featured multiple protagonists for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Syndicate</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Odyssey</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Valhalla</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Assassin's Creed Shadows </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">goes about it differently by focusing on </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/the-dual-protagonists-of-assassin-s-creed-shadows-enabled-the-series-jump-to-feudal-japan">two unique characters</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> with different gameplay styles and different perspectives on the changing era of Japan. The main narrative centers on the historical African samurai Yasuke (played by Tongayi Chirisa) and his new life in Japan, and Naoe (played by Masumi Tsunoda), a female ninja seeking to live up to her family's legacy to seek revenge, all set against the backdrop of the growing conflicts of the Sengoku period, with historical figures such as Oda Nobunaga, Tokugawa Ieyasu, and outside Western influences paving the way for radical change in Japan.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"You always try to look for the thing that grabs you as a creator. For </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Assassin's Creed Odyssey</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, we chose Greece because we found the pull was the philosophy of that time, and that it was an era where that departed the land of myths to an age of reasoning with people like Socrates becoming more known," said the creative director. "So with Japan, what interested us was the nuance of the era's communities and the different sides of everything. It was a morally grey time period and the start of a global conflict in Japan as Western nations were coming to the country during that era of unification."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/consume-me-wins-grand-prize-nuovo-award-at-the-2025-igf-awards" target="_self" data-discover="true">'Consume Me' Wins Grand Prize, Nuovo Award at the 2025 IGF Awards</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to Dumont, some of the reasons why Ubisoft hadn't made an Assassin's Creed game set in Japan sooner were timing, developer availability, and limitations of the tech to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="http://gamedeveloper.com/programming/7-how-assassin-s-creed-shadows-makes-environments-look-great-up-close-and-at-a-distance">fully realize feudal Japan's architecture and surrounding wilderness</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that changes with in-game seasons. With </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Shadows</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the developers not only saw an opportunity for the series to spotlight this era of Japan, but also showcase the atmosphere and changing culture of a country after the Western world cast its sights on it—all honed through the lens of Assassin's Creed and its focus on history's secret assassins.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This setting was such a pivotal time in Japan's history, and the country became a melting pot, and life changed so dramatically during these 30 years of unification," said the creative director. "Cities were being built around castles, the samurai went from being guardians protecting [rural property] to becoming now centered around the city, and it also led to urbanization—like commerce changed quite a bit because there was such a demand at war, and so the merchants at that time became very rich, and they climbed the social ladder. All that made it such an interesting era to explore for Assassin's Creed."</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/how-civilization-vii-s-powerful-narrative-system-helps-players-experience-unique-parts-of-history" target="_self" data-discover="true">How Civilization VII's powerful narrative system helps players experience unique parts of history</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This aspect of cultural change and exchange is reflected in Yasuke's story, one of the central characters of Shadows and the series' first protagonist based on a real person. During the game's prologue, players see him as an enslaved person brought to Japan by Jesuit missionaries, and on the opening walk to Oda Nobunaga's compound, citizens view him as a curiosity and comment on his black skin. After meeting with the feudal lord, Yasuke eventually begins a new life in Japan and trains as a samurai under Nobunaga, which sets him on a path to partnership with Naoe as they navigate 15th-century Japan.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Unfortunately, Yasuke's appearance has garnered attention from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_self" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/yves-guillemot-denounces-assassin-s-creed-shadows-racist-malicious-backlash">certain corners of the internet</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> who neither appreciate his inclusion as a protagonist in the game nor his place in real history— despite the fact that he's already appeared in other games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Nioh </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Samurai Warriors</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. What this inherently racist criticism from these communities fails to consider is that Yasuke's place during this time period makes a compelling case for him as a protagonist and puts him very much in line with Assassin's Creed's focus on the strange, secret history of humanity.</span></p><p>Image via Ubisoft.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Image via Ubisoft.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Moreover, the developers felt Yasuke's experience as a foreigner in Japan would allow a global audience of players to see themselves in his journey as he immerses himself in the culture of the country.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This approach has precedent in the realm of popular fiction. James Clavell's 1975 book Shogun and the 2024 TV series of the same name introduce the fictional British sailor John Blackthorne (</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Adams_(samurai)">himself based on historical figure William Adams</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">) as an audience point-of-view character.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Becoming students of history">Becoming students of history</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One particular detail that Dumont highlighted during the production was that Yasuke actor Tongayi Chirisa embodied the kind of mindset that they wanted for the character, possessing an open mind and a "student's mentality." This was the kind of aspect that they wanted for the character, but also a perspective that he wanted the developers to have as well when trying to develop Japan for AC.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"I always think of making games like these as going back to school; you have to go back to the learning process—you look back on what you know, then look at what you're learning, and then compare that to what's out there in pop culture," said Dumont. "So it's really about being students ourselves, trying to learn as much as possible and being humble about it. It can be difficult to portray somebody else's culture, so you try to have a lot of people who can inform you or help you make the right choices. Traveling to Japan was awesome, working with the specialists was great, and all that changed how we viewed the setting and how we developed it as well."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Alongside Yasuke is Naoe, the second playable protagonist who focuses on stealth gameplay and the traditional 'assassin' experience. In a way, Naoe is an outsider like Yasuke, and her experience represents the spiritual and emotional element of the game that highlights the harmony between nature and humanity.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One of Naoe's side activities hidden throughout the open world are meditation rituals, which open up side missions to see her growth as a ninja from her father's training. One major activity that players can engage in is the town builder, an Animal Crossing-style mode focusing on building a community of allies and creating a town of your own. In this way, players will be able to see the details of the architecture and culture of the time, as well as how people find unity during difficult times.</span></p><p>Image via Ubisoft.</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Image via Ubisoft.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Working on this game completely changes how we perceive architecture, and how much nature and humanity are linked together in harmony in Japan," said Dumont. "When you go into temples and shrines and the wilderness, it's very clear that there's a strong connection with everything. We didn't understand at the start of this project, but as we did our research in Japan, we realized we needed to focus more on that. So, looking at everything, we were like, "Oh yeah, okay! We need to spend more time on that," and it's made our experience all the better."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In a clear shift away from 2020's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Valhalla</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Shadows </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">focuses on a more tightly designed world, which aims to put a clear spotlight on a period of Japan that's opening itself up to the larger world and how the protagonists build up a community. According to Dumont, this all taps into the game's core themes of unity and community, which he says is "the importance of taking care of each other."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">While </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Assassin's Creed Shadows</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> does focus on the traditional AC style of experience where players engage in brutal combat, pull off assassinations of key targets, and parkour across an open-world during a chaotic period, the deep historical research creates a surprisingly inviting and wholesome tone, one that breaks new ground in the world of games inspired by the dramatic history of Feudal Japan.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributor</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Alessandro Fillari is a writer/editor who has covered the games, tech, and entertainment industries for more than 12 years. He is based in the San Francisco Bay Area.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>