<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 14:28:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Harry Potter’s Heirs Would Hate This, LEGO Is Selling the Hogwarts Castle Set for Pennies on the Dollar]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/harry-potters-heirs-would-hate-this-lego-is-selling-the-hogwarts-castle-set-for-pennies-on-the-dollar-2000631765</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/harry-potter%E2%80%99s-heirs-would-hate-this-lego-is-selling-the-hogwarts-castle-set-for-pennies-on-the-dollar.1316509/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Harry Potter is one of LEGO’s most beloved franchises, and the <em>Hogwarts Castle and Grounds</em> set has earned a stellar 4.8 out of 5-star rating on Amazon with over 1,800 reviews backing it up. <strong>LEGO’s official website shows zero discounts</strong> on this flagship model and maintains the strict pricing the company is known for. But Amazon isn’t playing by those rules.</p>
<p>Right now, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4207/">this 2,660-piece castle has dropped from $169 to just $135, marking an all-time low for the best-selling Harry Potter LEGO set</a>. This deal is accessible to everyone, including non-Prime members, which makes it even more appealing.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4207/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A Complete Miniature Replica of the Wizarding School</h2>
<p>It is the first L<strong>EGO brick model that includes the entire Hogwarts Castle and its grounds in a single build</strong>. Earlier sets focused on a solitary tower, classroom, or section, but this 2,660-piece model presents the entire campus to you in one continuous display. The construction includes the Main Tower with its signature pointed roof, the Astronomy Tower where the students study the stars, the Great Hall where banquets and ceremonies take place, as well as several courtyards and cross-bridges that lead to various sections of the castle.</p>



<p>The scale allows the LEGO designers to include recognisable details without overwhelming builders with tens of thousands of pieces. You will construct <strong>the Chamber of Secrets hidden beneath the school, the Winged Key room of Harry’s first-year nightmare, the Potions Classroom where Snape taught in the dungeons, and the large Chessboard Chamber from the Philosopher’s Stone challenges</strong>. The grounds surrounding consist of the Boathouse where students arrive by boat, the Black Lake in front, the greenhouses for Herbology class lessons and the Whomping Willow that attacks anything getting too close.</p>
<p>Other features recreate scenes from around the film series: The Durmstrang Ship comes out of the lake just as it did when Durmstrang participants arrived during the Triwizard Tournament in Goblet of Fire. The powder-blue Beauxbatons Carriage is present on the grounds, representing the arrival of the French school of magic. The crashed Ford Anglia is a part of the Forbidden Forest trees after the failed flight by Ron and Harry in Chamber of Secrets.</p>
<p>The finished model measures <strong>13.5 inches wide, 10 inches in depth, and 8.5 inches in height</strong>, large enough to be seen on a shelf or desk but not big enough to require special furniture. The build is supported on a highly detailed baseplate that is sculpted as the grounds of the castle with textured areas representing grass, pathways, and water. There is a gold mini-figure statue representing the Hogwarts architect which you can put near the nameplate “Hogwarts Castle” or in the corner of the baseplate to give it an extra visual touch.</p>
<p>For $135 for 2,660 pieces, you are <strong>paying around 5 cents per brick which is excellent value in the price system of LEGO</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4207/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/harry-potters-heirs-would-hate-this-lego-is-selling-the-hogwarts-castle-set-for-pennies-on-the-dollar-2000631765]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Consume Me is a raw and funny memoir in video game form]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/games/791220/consume-me-review-steam</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/consume-me-is-a-raw-and-funny-memoir-in-video-game-form.1316500/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>There’s a lot of math in diet culture. It’s all numbers — calories in, calories burned — and a constant tally running in one’s head. In some ways, disordered eating can be considered a disturbed sort of strategy game, which is precisely why Jenny Jiao Hsia and AP Thomson’s <em>Consume Me</em> works so well. The autobiographical game detailing Hsia’s teenage years is a darkly funny, honest peek into the desire to shape one’s life and body through food.</p><p>Food in <em>Consume Me </em>— tomatoes, kale, and pasta rendered as <em>Tetris</em> blocks — are assigned “bites,” a stand-in for calories. Jenny’s (the character, not the developer, who we’ll refer to using her last name, Hsia) lunch ritual is organizing these blocks on a plate, carefully selecting the pieces, and arranging them to both keep her full but stay under her self-imposed bite limit. It’s the sort of math that’s familiar in video games, but flipped upside down by the influence of controlled, disordered eating. This is <a href="https://www.eater.com/pop-culture/2019/10/25/20917488/food-in-video-games-pac-man-history-women-on-food-soleil-ho-book-excerpt">no glossy-egged, open-faced croque madame from <em>Final Fantasy XV</em></a>, a dish that is as beautiful as it is powerful.</p><p>In most video games, food means strength: <em>Final Fantasy XV</em>’s croque madame awards a bonus that increases attack damage. A cabbage in <em>Skyrim</em> restores a single health point. When Link eats a mushroom skewer in <em>The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</em>, his hearts are restored. <em>Consume Me</em> uses the familiar language of video game stats to cleverly flip the expectations. Reduced back down simply to numbers, food is no longer a source of power. It’s something to control, to fear. Hsia introduces Jenny’s diet — her teenage diet, because this is a memoir, after all — as the first of many all-consuming goals that will, supposedly, add up to the perfect life.</p><p>It begins simply, with Jenny’s mother criticizing her weight. The solution there, of course, is to diet, which is represented in <em>Consume Me</em> as a <em>Tetris</em>-esque minigame. The diet, which eventually is made clear as disordered eating, acts as an anchor throughout several years of Jenny’s life, spanning dating, friendships, and getting into college. <em>Consume Me</em> works so brilliantly because dieting and the other minigames aren’t just simple interactive elements, but are designed in service of the story. Dieting forces the player into the mindset of eating disorder math. And it’s not only the calculations of bites, but how those bites influence the rest of Jenny’s life — if Jenny has too many bites at lunch, she’ll need to exercise during her free time, which means she’ll have to choose between neglecting her schoolwork or her boyfriend. (Eat too little, though, and Jenny will end up bingeing on hot chips before bed, often undoing any bite deficit.)</p><p>It’s the impossible reality of being a teenage girl. Expectations are a <em>Tetris</em> board in which the bricks never stop coming. When you’ve cleared a row — being pretty and smart — another shape is inevitably right behind. <em>Consume Me</em> takes place over the days that make up weeks of Jenny’s life, in which the player must min-max her decisions by playing through different minigames, each of which ups Jenny’s skills or knocks something off a checklist but takes away precious, limited time. And every decision, even simply staying up late, feels dire, because in this reality, it is.</p><p>Reading, for example, is a minigame in which the player has to keep Jenny’s eyes on the book as her head spins, dodging rogue thoughts of her pup, boyfriend, or body. Exercising is the practice of corralling Jenny’s flailing arms into the correct positions. They’re all chaotic in the same ways <em>WarioWare</em> microgames are, matching the air of anxiety that lingers around Jenny’s life. Failing any of Jenny’s main goals means having to start over, either redoing a day or an entire week. It’s not necessarily hard to complete Jenny’s goals, but it does require anxious strategy, which is the point. <em>Consume Me</em> nails the mindset of its teenage protagonist.</p><p>Years pass in <em>Consume Me</em>, and Jenny’s goals shift and change slightly; those goals are dictated to her through a dysmorphic version of herself she talks to in the mirror. But diet remains non-negotiable throughout the entirety of the playable parts of the game. And that makes sense: disordered eating is so rarely just about food and image. It can also be about the illusion of control of one’s life through one’s body. Even as Jenny’s priorities change, bites always remain. Until, suddenly, they don’t.</p><p><em>Consume Me</em> ends with a jump forward 10 years, skipping over any sort of resolution to her eating disorder. But it’s clear that something’s happened in that decade — maybe partially related to the jarring religious awakening that hits toward the end of the game — because food is no longer a running tally in Jenny’s life. A sausage is no longer three blocks long, a visualization of its 200 or so bites. It’s just a sausage. She thinks about food, image, and diet still, but it’s no longer the undercurrent of her life.</p><p>There’s a risk in having <em>Consume Me</em> end without some distinct resolution, but it’s just another example of why the game works: it’s a confident memoir that doesn’t shy away from the messy bits.</p><p><sub>Consume Me <em>is available now <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fstore.steampowered.com%2Fapp%2F2359120%2FConsume_Me%2F" rel="sponsored">on Steam</a></em>.</sub></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTgxNzU2"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Nicole Carpenter</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/games/791220/consume-me-review-steam]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Report: Call Of Duty: Black Ops 6 On Game Pass Cost Microsoft $300 Million In Lost Sales]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/report-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-on-game-pass-cost-microsoft-300-million-in-lost-sales-2000631659</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/report-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-on-game-pass-cost-microsoft-300-million-in-lost-sales.1316497/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Last year’s <em>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6</em> was the first entry in the hit multiplayer military shooter to launch day-one on Game Pass in what reportedly turned out to be an expensive experiment for Microsoft. According to <em>Bloomberg</em>, making the game available for free to paid subscribers on console and PC cost the tech giant $300 million in lost sales of the 2024 best-seller. That data point adds some interesting context to Microsoft’s controversial decision to hike the price of Game Pass Ultimate by 50 percent this week.</p> <p>A defining feature of Game Pass was the decision early on to release first-party games like <em>Forza Horizon 5</em> and <em>Halo Infinite</em> on the service day-and-date. <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-10-03/xbox-s-game-pass-hike-shows-cost-of-lost-call-of-duty-sales?accessToken=eyJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiIsInR5cCI6IkpXVCJ9.eyJzb3VyY2UiOiJTdWJzY3JpYmVyR2lmdGVkQXJ0aWNsZSIsImlhdCI6MTc1OTUyNzI0MywiZXhwIjoxNzYwMTMyMDQzLCJhcnRpY2xlSWQiOiJUM0lWRFNHUFFROVIwMCIsImJjb25uZWN0SWQiOiJGRUIzODlCNUI2ODI0RTY0QjY5MENEODE1RTBDREZGRCJ9.D1EObQzg2KlvqBoXPyEm5Yn-DznTYaVWC3okI5aX3AU"><em>Bloomberg</em> reports</a> that this move was “controversial internally” due to the likelihood of cannibalizing sales of big games that take a lot of time and money to develop. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/8/24151814/microsoft-xbox-layoffs-strategy-changes-arkane-tango"><em>The Verge</em> reported</a> last year that a similar debate arose around the decision of whether to put <em>Call of Duty</em> on Game Pass or not.</p>

 <p>The former long-time head of Activision, Bobby Kotick, went on record during the 2023 FTC trial over Microsoft’s acquisition of the company saying that he didn’t think adding games like <em>Call of Duty</em> to subscription services made “commercial sense.” “I have a general aversion to the idea of multi-game subscription services,” he <a href="https://www.windowscentral.com/gaming/activision-ceo-wouldnt-put-call-of-duty-other-titles-on-xbox-game-pass">said at the time</a>. “Maybe part of it is being in Los Angeles and having large, big media companies move their content to these subscription streaming services and the business results have suffered.”</p>

 <p>But following the acquisition, Microsoft did exactly that. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/october-2024-sales-charts-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-sparks-xbox-game-pass-subscription-surge">According to Circana’s U.S. market data</a>, sales of 2024’s <em>Black Ops 6 w</em>ere 23 percent higher than <em>Modern Warfare 3</em> sales over the same period, but&nbsp;82 percent of those sales were on PlayStation compared to Xbox and PC. Subscription gaming services also saw a 16 percent jump year-over-year following the release of<em> Black Ops 6</em>.</p>

 <p>If the move cost the company $300 million in lost sales, Microsoft would have needed around 15 million players to subscribe to Game Pass Ultimate for one month to make that up, or just 1.25 million over the course of an entire year. The numbers would be more dramatic for the even cheaper Game Pass PC tier where Call of Duty is also now available day-and-date. The price hikes this week change that math. Now, even if <em>Black Ops 7</em> saw a similar drop in sales, Microsoft would need only 10 million new sign-ups for Ultimate in November to fill the gap, or just 834,000 over the length of a year.</p>

 <p>This week’s Game Pass overhaul shows Microsoft is essentially continuing to back off its original day-one commitment. Game Pass Premium is the same price Game Pass Ultimate was a few years ago, but will only get first-party Xbox games a year after they’re out and it’s not guaranteed to get<em> Call of Duty</em> games at all. This might not be the last major change we see to the service in the near future, either. The company <a href="https://kotaku.com/xbox-game-pass-streaming-free-ad-supported-report-price-increase-2000631520">is reportedly testing a “free” ad-supported tier</a> that will be exclusively cloud gaming and could keep raising prices on the higher tiers if it thinks a core audience will stick around.</p> <p><em>Bloomberg</em> reports that Microsoft CFO Amy Hood has “asked Xbox to find other ways to increase profit.” Instead of growing its share of the gaming market, the company now seems content to extract more from those already paying it.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/report-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-on-game-pass-cost-microsoft-300-million-in-lost-sales-2000631659]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In Case of Emergency, This 1500W Portable Power Station Is a Lifesaver and It’s Now Selling for Pennies]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/in-case-of-emergency-this-1500w-portable-power-station-is-a-lifesaver-and-its-now-selling-for-pennies-2000631757</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/in-case-of-emergency-this-1500w-portable-power-station-is-a-lifesaver-and-it%E2%80%99s-now-selling-for-pennies.1316494/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Power outages during storms, camping trips without reliable electricity, tailgating events that need a blender for frozen drinks, remote work setups in RVs, or simply keeping your essential devices running during emergency situations… These scenarios share one common frustration: <strong>being disconnected from power when you need it most</strong>.</p>
<p>A portable power station solves this problem by providing reliable electricity anywhere and gives you the freedom to charge laptops, run small appliances, or keep medical devices operational during blackouts. If you’ve found yourself in any of these situations wishing you had backup power,<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3722/"> the Jackery Explorer 1000 is currently at a record low of $429, down from $799</a>. This <strong>46% discount</strong> makes one of the most capable portable power stations accessible for people who need reliable energy independence.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3722/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>The Explorer 1000 holds 1,070 watt-hours of capacity in <strong>an incredibly light 23.8-pound package</strong>. This held energy translates to usable use like powering a mini-fridge for roughly 10 hours, charging a laptop over multiple work sessions, or keeping your phone charged dozens of times through. The unit can <strong>output 1,500 continuous watts via its three pure sine wave AC receptacles</strong> and can surge a maximum of 3,000 watts momentarily as appliances come online.</p>



<h2>Charges Faster Than You’d Ever Imagine</h2>
<p>Jackery designed this power station <strong>using ChargeShield 2.0 technology</strong> which enables full recharge in one hour when you activate emergency mode via the accompanying app. That’s due to intelligent charging algorithms that push maximum current safely into the lithium iron phosphate battery cells. The standard charge time stands at 1.7 hours which strikes a balance between fast charging and maintaining long-term battery health by minimizing heat gain during charging. For perspective, most other power stations you’ll find take four to six hours for a full charge.</p>



<p>LiFePO4 battery chemistry delivers outstanding longevity over conventional lithium-ion cells. This<strong> battery retains over 70% of its capacity after 4,000 full charge cycles</strong>, or over a decade of moderate use if you’re cycling the battery every week. Lithium iron phosphate cells also handle extreme temperatures more robustly and represent less fire hazard than traditional lithium-ion batteries.</p>
<p>The port choice caters to modern charging needs with t<strong>wo USB-C ports offering 100 watts of power delivery, a USB-A port, a 12-volt automotive port, and the usual three AC ports</strong>. A 100-watt USB-C port can charge new MacBook Pros, iPads and high-end Android phones at maximum speed without requiring separate power bricks.</p>
<p>At $429, this power station is practically half its regular price but provides the capacity and functionality that makes portable power stations really useful and not novelty items.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3722/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/in-case-of-emergency-this-1500w-portable-power-station-is-a-lifesaver-and-its-now-selling-for-pennies-2000631757]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Review: KUUKIYOMI 4: Consider It Nintendo Switch 2 Edition - Delightfully Silly, With Plenty Of Dark Laughs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/kuukiyomi-4-consider-it-nintendo-switch-2-edition</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/review-kuukiyomi-4-consider-it-nintendo-switch-2-edition-delightfully-silly-with-plenty-of-dark-laughs.1316482/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section>
<figure><a title="KUUKIYOMI 4: Consider It Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 1 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159360/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure><p>We reported on the Switch 2 version of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kuukiyomi-4-consider-it-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Kuukiyomi 4: Consider It</a> having arrived with new features, including a bunch of exclusive mouse-mode content, and as a result of that, well, I agreed in writing <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/random-kuukiyomi-4-consider-its-switch-2-edition-uses-mouse-mode-in-neat-ways-while-poking-fun-at-nintendo">in the comments</a> that I'd review it. Thanks, past me. Thanks a bunch.</p>
<p>I jest, of course. This is an off-kilter Japanese series that had completely passed me by, and after seeing the Switch 2 port trailer, I simply had to give it a go. It's right up my street.</p>
<p>So, what have we actually got here? Well, Kuukiyomi 4: Consider It is the latest in a series that has already seen a few releases on Switch 1, and the entire concept revolves around you being placed in situations where you must <em>consider</em> a suitable action or solution to often awkward — or just plain weird — social situations. Will you consider being considerate? Or will you take every opportunity you can to mess people around?</p>
<figure><a title="KUUKIYOMI 4: Consider It Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 2 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159354/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>There's a coming together of a very funny art style here; it's the sort of game that does a very good line in incredibly stupid facial expressions that amuse whilst also nailing precisely an awkward feeling, with situations that manage to raise, at the very least, a wry smile. You can see the pain in the eyes of these NPCs at points. The terror of human interaction writ large. I can't stop laughing.</p>
<p>Starting with the original game's contents, which you play with the Switch 2's normal, non-exclusive inputs, you push through some 100 scenarios that, well, I'm not going to spoil many of them here, because the entire fun is in seeing what comes next. But I have howled at my screen a few times due to the underlying social tension being nagged at.</p>
<p>This is a game that asks us, "Why do humans read the air?" And those facial expressions I was just on about, combined with the oddness of the scenarios, and then multiplied by the very real awkward silence (we all know the one) that transpires as you consider what to do...man, this game nails the squeaky bum tension so hard.</p>
<figure><a title="KUUKIYOMI 4: Consider It Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 3 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159358/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Will you shift seats on a train to let a couple sit together? Will you put your dirty mouth around the water font and drink from it when nobody is looking? Will you sit at the table beside the girl in the cafe or go sit alone at the bar? I'm sweating already.</p>
<p>Alongside these social aspects, you also have lots of curveballs, one or two of which I'll admit to not really even understanding, and honestly, there's something about sweating over sitting next to a stranger one moment, and then moving your Joy-Con around to simulate trying to find a Wi-Fi phone signal the next, that really brings things right down to the level of crushing reality. In the best way possible, you understand.</p>
<p>Playing through the game's scenarios in the main solo campaign mode, you'll be graded after every handful of levels to ascertain just how considerate you are being, or as the game puts it, your "ability to read the atmosphere will be diagnosed."</p>
<figure><a title="KUUKIYOMI 4: Consider It Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 4 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159361/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>This is where the main sticking point with this game will be. You see, it's not taking itself particularly seriously, and so even when you're presented with the ludicrously in-depth results of your attempts to be nice, it's mostly all played for laughs. So don't expect to find seriousness for even a second. It's really all just for japes, and so there may not be enough of a hook for those who don't gel with the humour. Luckily, I'm covered in gel right now.</p>
<p>Aside from the vanilla game's 100 main mode scenarios, you also get a 'Consider It Together' multiplayer mode that asks you and your associates a bunch of questions before diagnosing your 'compatibility', plus a handful of quick games that you'll unlock as you play (again, no spoilers) and a few extra minigames to boot. So there's plenty to do, even before you add in the Switch 2's new sections, where the mouse mode fun happens.</p>
<p>In the main new mode, you use either one of your Joy-Con in mouse mode to navigate 20 new levels, and I'm happy to report that they are some of the best in the entire thing. Mostly aimed at the console itself, I got a lot of laughs out of cheeky takes on 120fps gaming, how the console's mic works, and what HDR stands for.</p>
<figure><a title="KUUKIYOMI 4: Consider It Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 5 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159363/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>It's all very silly and delightfully tongue-in-cheek. The Switch 2 port also lands with five two-player mouse-made games to play against a pal for added value. Again, I'm not going to ruin them here, as seeing what pops onto the screen next is what it's all about.</p>
<p>Being that the art style is so stark and spartan, there are zero issues in terms of performance, and really the only negative that I'd level at Kuukiyomi 4 is that, as much as it's great that it doesn't take anything too seriously, it does have an inherent lack of focus or drive. If you want something with some challenge, this is not that, even if it does let you re-run and improve your results. However, even this has been remedied to a degree in the NS2 Edition by the addition of achievements, which give you something to work towards, whilst also providing a few more laughs by challenging you to consider it in some not-so-obvious ways. Did I just unlock a 'cheevo' for letting my head fall all the way to one side during a haircut? You're goddamn right I did.</p>
<figure><a title="KUUKIYOMI 4: Consider It Nintendo Switch 2 Edition Review - Screenshot 6 of 6" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/screenshots/159355/large.jpg"></a><figcaption>Captured on Nintendo Switch 2 (Handheld/Undocked)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Given its cheerful pricing, honestly, it's a hard thing to knock if you're looking for some cheap laughs that can also hit home harder than you'll expect at points.</p>
<p>Now, prepare to relive the unbearable tension of...moving out of the way to let someone off the train!</p>
</section><section id="conclusion"><h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Kuukiyomi 4: Consider It! is a delightfully silly little game that also provides plenty of dark laughs, clever digs, and unbearable social tension thanks to a brilliantly executed collection of scenarios.</p>
<p>Not every level is gonna have you howling, and some of them don't even really make any sense, but I'll be damned if I haven't been well-entertained for my money and made to laugh plenty whilst also being reminded that, at best, I am deeply inconsiderate.</p></section>

</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch-2/kuukiyomi-4-consider-it-nintendo-switch-2-edition]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ditch Your iPad, Amazon’s New Gaming Tablet at 40% Off Is Flying Off the Shelves]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ditch-your-ipad-amazons-new-gaming-tablet-at-40-off-is-flying-off-the-shelves-2000631749</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ditch-your-ipad-amazon%E2%80%99s-new-gaming-tablet-at-40-off-is-flying-off-the-shelves.1316476/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Gaming on tablets has exploded in popularity, with more players discovering that pairing a Bluetooth or Wi-Fi controller with a portable screen creates an incredibly flexible gaming setup. The problem? A decent iPad Pro will set you back $800, and even the base iPad hovers around $400. If you’re looking for a capable tablet experience without the Apple tax, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4479/">Amazon’s Fire Max 11 represents the company’s most powerful tablet to date, and it’s currently hitting an all-time low at $139, down from $229</a> (64GB model, with lockscreen ads). This is the <strong>newest model in Amazon’s lineup</strong>, and seeing it <strong>drop 39% during Prime Big Deal Days</strong> makes it an accessible entry point for streaming and casual gaming.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4479/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>Fire Max 11 is all <strong>about its huge 11-inch screen</strong>, packing 2.4 million pixels into a 2000 x 1200 screen. That means text is readable enough to read ebooks or browse web pages, with videos and games benefitting from clear detail that does not force you to squint at blurry images. The screen is blue light low emission certified, which is something that stops eye strain when viewing for extended periods.</p>
<h2>Performance That Keeps Up With Your Entertainment</h2>
<p>Underneath the aluminum shell is an <strong>octa-core processor and 4 GB of RAM</strong> to offer a seamless experience for multitasking scenarios like keeping multiple browser tabs open while streaming background music. The eight cores divide the load evenly and never permits stuttering and lag that plagues lower-end tablets when jumping between applications. Wi-Fi 6 connectivity offers quicker data transfer rates and improved performance in busy network conditions so you can stream 1080p content on the couch even while family members are bandwidth-thirsty on their own devices.</p>



<p>The build quality of the tablet is a balance of portability and ruggedness <strong>through the aluminum frame and reinforced glass display</strong>. Amazon states it’s <strong>three times more durable than the iPad 10.9-inch in tumble tests</strong> which involve dropping the tablet repeatedly from specific heights onto hard surfaces.</p>
<p><strong>Battery life is 14 hours of continuous use,</strong> or a couple days’ worth of normal usage patterns if you’re not watching a whole season in one sitting. You get 64 GB of storage built-in at this price point, and you can expand capacity to 1 TB with a microSD card.</p>
<p>The stylus pen and keyboard case option turn the Fire Max 11 into a productivity tablet able to do email, note taking and document editing. The tablet includes a three-month trial of Microsoft 365 Personal so you can use Word, Excel, and PowerPoint with full cloud syncing across all your devices. The 8 MP front camera provides excellent video quality when using Zoom calls, so it’s perfect for remote work or keeping in touch with distant family members.</p>
<p>This is a great value for budget-minded customers who want current features without premium prices, make sure you don’t miss that Prime Day deal on Amazon.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4479/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/ditch-your-ipad-amazons-new-gaming-tablet-at-40-off-is-flying-off-the-shelves-2000631749]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dyson Silently Offloads V11 Inventory on Amazon, Now 40% Off at a Record-Low Price]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dyson-silently-offloads-v11-inventory-on-amazon-now-40-off-at-a-record-low-price-2000631741</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dyson-silently-offloads-v11-inventory-on-amazon-now-40-off-at-a-record-low-price.1316467/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Dyson is the ultimate luxury in vacuum cleaners and it sets standards that competitors try to copy but never quite match. The brand’s combination of <strong>advanced performance and sleek design</strong> remains unrivaled in the industry. If you’ve been looking for a new-generation cordless stick vacuum without dropping $1,500 on the latest Dyson flagship model, the V11 <em>Origin</em> is a great breakthrough moment in Dyson’s evolution.</p>
<p>This was the first model to truly enter the <em>“new gen”</em> era of cordless cleaning power <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4478/">and seeing it drop to $399 from $629 on Amazon is unprecedented</a> (nearly 40% off right now). The British company seems to be clearing inventory on earlier models, possibly to push consumers toward their premium $1,000+ options later.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4478/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>The <strong>Dyson V11 Origin delivers 185AW of suction, 60% more cleaning power than previous Dyson models</strong>. We’re talking about the difference between surface-level dust removal and deep extraction of embedded dirt from carpet fibers and hard floor crevices. The <strong>motor spins at up to 125,000 revolutions per minute</strong>, and it generates the kind of cyclonic force that pulls allergens, pet dander, and fine particles from every surface in your home.</p>
<h2>Three Intelligent Modes That Actually Make Sense</h2>
<p>The V11 has <strong>three different power modes</strong> that respond to real-world cleaning conditions. <em>Auto mode</em> takes advantage of sensors integrated into the vacuum to detect floor type and change suction automatically, balancing cleaning performance with battery life. <em>Eco mode</em> gets the most out of battery life for quick maintenance cleaning sessions, allowing you up to 60 minutes of steady use when you’re just doing a few quick touch-ups around the house. <em>Boost mode</em> lets out all the suction power for tough messes like ground-in cereal crumbs or tracked-in mud, but it does drain the battery faster.</p>



<p>The LCD display informs you of the mode you’re in, total amount of runtime remaining to the last second, and maintenance alerts when the filters must be cleaned or clogs form.</p>
<p>The Motorbar cleaner bar head itself is worth an accolade because it solves one of the greatest annoyances of vacuum ownership: Normal brush rolls become tangles of hairballs of mess within minutes of operation and you have to stop and snip away the mess with scissors. <strong>Dyson created this head on a spiral brush bar that actively untangles snarled hair</strong> and petting fur while you clean. The cleaner head automatically adjusts between carpets and hard floors, which makes a tight seal that doesn’t let dirt seep underneath.</p>
<p><strong>Converting the V11 into handheld mode</strong> is a matter of seconds by letting go of the wand which turns it into an all-around cleaning device for cleaning above floors. The whole-machine <strong>filtration system captures 99.99% of particles with a diameter of 0.3 microns</strong> or smaller such as most common allergens, bacteria, and mold spores.</p>
<p>This deal is unprecedented and it’s one of our favorite Prime Day deals right now.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4478/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/dyson-silently-offloads-v11-inventory-on-amazon-now-40-off-at-a-record-low-price-2000631741]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This Dell 16″ Laptop (2TB SSD, 64GB RAM, Core 7) Is $3,400 Off, Amazon Is Selling Out All Laptops]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-dell-16-laptop-2tb-ssd-64gb-ram-core-7-is-3400-off-amazon-is-selling-out-all-laptops-2000631607</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-dell-16%E2%80%B3-laptop-2tb-ssd-64gb-ram-core-7-is-3-400-off-amazon-is-selling-out-all-laptops.1316458/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>The laptop market has become impossibly crowded with dozens of brands and hundreds of models, which makes it very difficult to know where to start. If you want a safe bet backed by decades of reliability and support infrastructure, <strong>Dell remains one of the smartest choices you can make</strong>.</p>
<p>Within Dell’s lineup, there’s something for every budget and every use case. Right now, if you want maximum performance at the absolute lowest price, Amazon has dropped a deal that borders on absurd: The <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4475/">Dell Inspiron 16 with upgraded specs (Intel Core 7, 64GB DDR5 RAM, 2TB SSD) has plummeted to $1,195 from its typical $4,599 price</a>, which is a <strong>74 percent discount</strong> that requires a double-take to believe.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4475/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>The Intel Core 7 150U processor boasts <strong>10 cores and 12 threads with a turbo frequency of up to 5.4GHz</strong> and provides processing capability that tackles high-end workloads without pause. The 150U is part of Intel’s newest family of mobile processors using their power-efficient architecture, optimizing performance and battery life through smart power management.</p>
<h2>Huge Upgrades That Transform Daily Computing</h2>
<p>The memory and storage configuration makes it stand apart from bread-and-butter retail models. <strong>With 64GB of DDR5 RAM</strong>, you can have a bunch of browser tabs open, virtual machines and background processes simultaneously without any system slowdown. DDR5 is a generation improvement over DDR4 with exponentially greater data transfer rates, improved power efficiency and greater performance under heavy multitasking loads.</p>


<p>The 2TB SSD has enough space for your whole digital life without constant file management anxiety. You can have your whole software suite installed, store years of photos and video, download enormous game collections and store local backups without even approaching capacity limits. SSD technology means all loading nearly at the same instant, from system booting to application launching to file copying.</p>



<p>The<strong> 16-inch FHD+ touchscreen uses a 1920×1200 resolution with a 16:10 aspect ratio</strong> that gives you more vertical space than typical 16:9 screens. It comes in handy while working with documents, spreadsheets, or code when you’d rather see more content without scrolling. The 300-nit brightness delivers clarity in light rooms and the touchscreen feature (no need to use it if you don’t want to) delivers convenience for faster interactions when the keyboard gets too formal.</p>
<p><a href="https://gizmodo.com/download/windows-11-pro">Windows 11 Pro includes</a> enterprise-grade features like BitLocker encryption, remote desktop, and domain join functionality that are not included in Home versions. The Copilot key provides direct access to Microsoft’s AI assistant.</p>
<p>Connectivity includes Wi-Fi 6E for extremely fast wireless speeds on supporting networks, <strong>Bluetooth for peripherals, USB-C and USB-A ports for legacy and newer devices, HDMI output for external monitors, and an SD card reader</strong> for photographers transferring files from cameras.</p>
<p><strong>Battery life is 80 percent after just 60 minutes of charging</strong>, minimizing downtime when you simply need to have power ready at an instant between classes or meetings.</p>
<p>For $1,195, you’re getting technology that would otherwise cost three or four times that much.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4475/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-dell-16-laptop-2tb-ssd-64gb-ram-core-7-is-3400-off-amazon-is-selling-out-all-laptops-2000631607]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After Selling Out, Amazon Brings Back 50-Pack Pokemon Cards at a New Record Low]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/after-selling-out-amazon-brings-back-50-pack-pokemon-cards-at-a-new-record-low-2000631600</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-selling-out-amazon-brings-back-50-pack-pokemon-cards-at-a-new-record-low.1316446/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Building a Pokemon card collection from the ground up involves that you focus on quantity before hunting down specialty holographic Charizards or first edition old cards. The smart thing to do is to get a few inexpensive bulk packs like this and accumulate a solid base of cards that can be traded, sorted and used to build decks. You will have some duplicates in a bunch of packs but that is exactly what you want when you are just starting out: Duplicates become currency amongst friends and fellow collectors, and having the ability to have multiple copies of useful cards allows you to build functional decks without decreasing your collection.</p>
<p>There’s a <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4271/">50-card miscellaneous lot that has dropped to an all-time low of $5 on Amazon from its usual $10 price point</a>, and it just came back in stock after selling out last week. You’re going to want to move quick because these bulk lots are short-lived.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4271/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>The appeal here is simple value. <strong>For $5 for 50 cards, you’re paying 10 cents per card</strong>&nbsp;which is effectively floor price on Pokemon cards no matter what format. The <strong>individual booster packs cost $4 to $5 and contain only 10 to 11 cards</strong>, so you’d be paying $20 to $25 to get the same quantity through the traditional retailing method. This bulk approach bypasses the thrill of opening the sealed pack and the very low chance of obtaining ultra-rare cards but it provides you with maximum number of cards for minimum amount of money.</p>
<h2>Random Draw Gives Diverse Sets</h2>
<p>The pack includes <strong>random cards of all Pokemon series</strong> that represent the entire history of the trading card game from the very beginning Base Set to the most recent issues. You’ll receive a mix of core Pokemon cards with basic, Stage 1, and Stage 2 Pokemon from various generations and energy cards to power up attacks while playing. Randomization guarantees each lot acts as a surprise grab bag. You might receive popular Pokemon like Pikachu, evolutions of Eevee or starting Pokemon, or you might receive under-the-radar creatures from later generations.</p>



<p>Energy cards within such lots serve important gameplay functions. Energy cards on your Pokemon need to be played in order for the Pokemon Trading Card Game to use their attacks, with different Pokemon types requiring such energy types as Fire, Water, Grass, Lightning, Psychic, Fighting, Darkness, Metal, or Fairy. Possessing a solid base of energy cards enables you to actually build playable decks rather than simply gathering cards for their visual reasons.</p>
<p><strong>Duplicates are to be expected even in one 50-card lot</strong>. This is part of bulk card collections where the packaging process is more about speed than making each card unique. In reality, duplicates are less important than you’d imagine. Basic Pokemon cards and energy cards are intended to show up in multiples throughout your deck because competitive decks would have multiple copies of the same card.</p>
<p>The set is Amazon’s top-selling collectible card game set and deck, with over 20,000 sales in the past month alone.&nbsp;For $5, you’re getting the best value way to start a Pokemon collection or build upon one. The record-low price and recent stock shortages mean this won’t last long. If you’re even remotely interested in Pokemon cards, buying four or five of these lots puts you at 200 to 250 cards for $20 to $25, an immediate collection with high trading value.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4271/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/after-selling-out-amazon-brings-back-50-pack-pokemon-cards-at-a-new-record-low-2000631600]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Community: Played A Great Switch Game We Missed? Send Us Your Hot Tips]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/community-played-a-great-switch-game-we-missed-send-us-your-hot-tips</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/community-played-a-great-switch-game-we-missed-send-us-your-hot-tips.1316443/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>2 hot to stop</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="911a6fe063b06"><a title="Captain Toad Star" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/911a6fe063b06/captain-toad-star.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>It's that time of year for our six-monthly <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/tags/reader-recommendations">Games We Missed round-up</a>, when you lovely people flag great Switch games that slipped through Nintendo Life's nets. And this is the first edition since Switch 2 launched!</p>
<p>While we've done our utmost to keep up with every new Switch 2 game after 25 of them dropped on 5th June, there have already been a handful we weren't able to cover - although we <em>did</em> manage to catch up with <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/bokura-planet">Bokura: Planet</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kuukiyomi-4-consider-it-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Kuukiyomi 4</a>, both of which we enjoyed immensely (spoilers for the Kuukiyomi review that'll be going live later today!). And Switch 1 has kept up its relentless release rate, with publishers pumping out all sorts of jewels glinting in the ever-churning eShop slop. Missing some good 'uns is unavoidable, unfortunately.</p><div><figure data-videoid="C1rrCdi_XjA" data-start="0" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1"><div><iframe title="YouTube Video" src="javascript:''" data-src-fallback="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C1rrCdi_XjA?rel=0&amp;hd=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;modestbranding=0&amp;autohide=1" data-consent="targeting" type="text/html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" width="890" height="501" data-src-primis="https://live.primis.tech/live/liveView.php?s=117114&amp;vp_content=embed3be067nxuqho&amp;schain=1.0,1!ziffdavis.com,22392450815,1"></iframe><p>Subscribe to <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1">Nintendo Life</a> on <a rel="noopener" href="https://www.youtube.com/nintendolife?sub_confirmation=1"><span>YouTube</span><span>836k</span></a></p>
</div></figure></div>
<p>Back in April, in <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/community-38-switch-games-we-missed-as-recommended-by-you">Part 10</a> (blimey!) of this community series, you highlighted a chunky 38 titles, including such gems as <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/bzzzt">BZZZT</a> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/haiku_the_robot">Haiku the Robot</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/howl">Howl</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/a_tiny_sticker_tale">A Tiny Sticker Tale</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/promise_mascot_agency">Promise Mascot Agency</a>.</p>
<p>So, ahead of the next instalment, it's callout time! If you'd like to highlight a Switch 1 or Switch 2 game that we haven't reviewed, send us your recommendations and we'll showcase the best in Part 11.</p>
<p>Remember — and this is a point that is frequently forgotten when people send their recommendations! — <strong>we won't be reviewing these games</strong>. We want to shine a light on games that we weren't able to when they launched. Make sure to carefully read the submission guidelines below if you want to see your entries included in the feature:</p>
<h2>Submission guidelines</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>100-word limit</strong> - Keep it brief! A history of the genre and deep-dive into every mechanic is unnecessary. Concentrate on what the game is about, what sets it apart from other games, and why you enjoyed it.</li>
<li><strong>One entry per game</strong> - Feel free to send your thoughts on multiple games, but there's no need to duplicate.</li>
<li><strong>Choose only games that we haven't reviewed on the site</strong> - To check if a Nintendo Life review exists, simply type the name of the game into the search box at the very top of the page (look for the magnifying glass icon in the top left corner) and click on the game page that appears. If there's no review, and it doesn't appear in a previous <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/tags/reader-recommendations">Reader Recommendations</a> feature (which will also appear on the game page if it exists), you're good to go!</li>
</ul>
<h2>How to send a recommendation</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Head to Nintendo Life's</strong> <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/contact?subject=gems"><strong>Contact page</strong></a> <strong>and select the subject "Switch eShop Hidden Gems"</strong> from the drop-down menu (it's already done for you in the link above). Type your name, email, and beautifully crafted message into the appropriate box, hit send, and Bob's your uncle!</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><em>We're looking forward to seeing what you recommend!</em></p></section></article><div><p>Gavin first wrote for Nintendo Life in 2018 before joining the site full-time the following year, rising through the ranks to become Editor. He can currently be found squashed beneath a Switch backlog the size of Normandy.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/dartmonkey"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('dartmonkey');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/community-played-a-great-switch-game-we-missed-send-us-your-hot-tips]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Something for the Weekend – 04/10/25]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/04/something-for-the-weekend-04-10-25/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/something-for-the-weekend-%E2%80%93-04-10-25.1316431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It might have been the launch of one of the PS5’s biggest exclusives yet, in the form of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ghost-of-yotei">Ghost of Yotei</a>, this week, but it was EA and Microsoft that stole the headlines away with the former announcing plans to be bought out by Saudi Arabia, and Xbox Game Pass getting a massive price increase. Let’s dive in and see what else has happened this week.</p>
<h2>In the News This Week</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/01/xbox-game-pass-ultimate-2025-price-increase-ubisoft-fortnite-crew/">Xbox Game Pass Ultimate gets Ubisoft+ Classics, Fortnite Crew and a ridiculous price increase</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/30/avalanche-liverpool-to-close-after-contraband-is-put-on-hold/">Avalanche Liverpool to close after Contraband is put on hold</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/28/electronic-arts-saudi-investment-fund-trump/">Electronic Arts goes private, will be owned by the Saudi’s and Trump’s Son In law</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/30/sag-aftra-make-a-fresh-statement-on-the-use-of-synthetic-ai-performers/">SAG-AFTRA make a fresh statement opposing the use of synthetic AI performers</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/02/demeo-x-dungeons-dragons-battlemarked-get-a-november-release-and-a-steam-next-fest-demo/">Demeo x Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Battlemarked get a November release and a Steam Next Fest demo</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/01/the-last-caretaker-launches-into-early-access-this-november/">The Last Caretaker launches into early access this November</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/02/moonlighter-2-the-endless-vault-has-been-delayed-until-november/">Moonlighter 2: The Endless Vault has been delayed until November</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/02/rejoice-its-2025-and-you-can-buy-brand-new-atari-7800-cartridges/">Rejoice! It’s 2025 and you can buy brand new Atari 7800 cartridges</a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/02/playstation-is-coming-to-magic-the-gathering-again/">PlayStation is coming to Magic the Gathering, again!</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<h2>Games in Review &amp; Featured Articles</h2>
<p>A ton of games passed through our reviews this week, with not one but two LEGO games!</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/01/digimon-story-time-stranger-review-an-old-school-creature-collector-with-modern-trimmings/"><strong>Digimon Story Time Stranger</strong></a> – PS5, XSX|S, <strong>PC</strong> – 8/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/30/super-mario-galaxy-super-mario-galaxy-2-review-a-thoroughly-sensible-40th-birthday-party/"><strong>Super Mario Galaxy + Super Mario Galaxy 2</strong></a> – <strong>NSW2</strong>, NSW – 8/10 (<strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nsqJgE7y2fc">video review</a></strong>)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/03/lego-party-review/"><strong>LEGO Party</strong> </a>– PS5, XSX|S, PS4, XBO, <strong>NSW</strong>, PC – 8/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/29/ea-sports-fc-26-review/"><strong>EA Sports FC 26</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, NSW2, PS4, XBO, NSW, PC – 8/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/29/blippo-review/"><strong>Blippo+</strong> </a>– <strong>NSW</strong>, PC, Playdate – 7/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/02/lego-voyagers-review/"><strong>LEGO Voyagers</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, NSW2, PS4, NSW, PC – 7/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/30/uboat-console-review/"><strong>UBOAT</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S – 6/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/02/nicktoons-the-dice-of-destiny-review/"><strong>Nicktoons &amp; The Dice of Destiny</strong></a> – PS5, XSX|S, <strong>NSW</strong>, PC – 6/10</li>
<li><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/02/discounty-review/"><strong>Discounty</strong></a> – <strong>PS5</strong>, XSX|S, PS4, XBO, NSW, PC – 5/10</li>
</ul>
<p>Beyond the reviews, I went hands on with <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/29/jurassic-world-evolution-3-preview-when-a-mummy-dino-and-a-daddy-dino-love-each-other-very-much/"><strong>Jurassic World Evolution 3</strong></a> as it brings natural dino breeding into the mix, while Dom delivered previews of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/30/tiny-metal-2-preview-this-is-how-you-advance-grid-based-war/"><strong>Tiny Metal 2’s</strong></a> revamped turn-based strategy, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/02/ball-x-pit-preview-devolvers-got-great-balls-of-hellfire/"><strong>Ball X Pit</strong></a> and its ball bouncing antics, and the slick and stylish upcoming roguelite <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/03/morbid-metal-preview-forging-a-slick-stylish-shapeshifting-roguelite/"><strong>Morbid Metal</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Rounding out the week, <strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/03/what-we-played-super-mario-galaxy-digimon-story-time-stranger-hades-2/">What We Played</a></strong> featured Super Mario Galaxy, Digimon Story Time Stranger &amp; Hades 2.</p>

<h2>Trailer Park</h2>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/09/28/watch-over-eight-minutes-of-the-relic-first-guardian-gameplay/">Watch over eight minutes of The Relic: First Guardian gameplay</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe title="The Relic: First Guardian - Extended Gameplay Trailer (Coming Early 2026)" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4dasDB7PohU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/03/the-kpop-demon-hunters-have-dropped-into-fortnite-for-some-demon-rush-pve/">The KPop Demon Hunters have dropped into Fortnite for some Demon Rush PvE</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe title="KPop Demon Hunters Takes Over Fortnite" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5ipctlvNePk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/03/skate-season-1-arrives-next-week-to-get-you-looking-hesh-fresh/">Skate Season 1 arrives next week to get you looking Hesh &amp; Fresh</a></strong></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="skate. | Early Access Season 1 Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-Mi9EKoBCSg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2>Your Achievements</h2>
<p>Let’s see what you’ve been playing?</p>
<ul>
<li>TSBonyman checked in with an update of his gaming antics, having run through plenty more No Man’s Sky with the custom ship designing, a cheap copy of Atomic Heart which impressed with its style, but less so its gameplay, and the System Shock remake for some classic immersive sim action. He’s also enjoyed&nbsp;Steamworld Dig 2 and Steamworld Heist, which are still lovely indie games.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s the round up for this week’s round up, enjoy the weekend, and we’ll catch you for more gaming shenanigans next week!</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/10/04/something-for-the-weekend-04-10-25/]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Talking Point: What Are You Playing This Weekend? (4th October)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-what-are-you-playing-this-weekend-4th-october</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/talking-point-what-are-you-playing-this-weekend-4th-october.1316419/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<figure data-uuid="1c013d19cc799"><a title="Mario Galaxy" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/1c013d19cc799/mario-galaxy.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure><p>The weekend!</p>
<p>Before we dive into what we're playing, let's do a little recap of this week, hm? First up, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/reviews/nintendo-switch/super-mario-galaxy-plus-super-mario-galaxy-2">our review</a> for <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch/super_mario_galaxy_plus_super_mario_galaxy_2">Super Mario Galaxy + Super Mario Galaxy 2</a> for the Switch went live, so you should definitely check that out. <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/nightdive-studios-just-wont-stop-announces-yet-another-remaster">Nightdive Studios announced yet another remaster</a> coming to consoles, and the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/nintendo-switch-2-system-update-20-5-0-is-now-live-here-are-the-full-patch-notes">Switch 2 received a vital update</a>, adding some all-important stability.</p>
<p>Our dear friend <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/09/video-after-six-wonderful-years-zion-is-leaving-nintendo-life">Zion has also left to pursue a new role</a>, so we're very, very sad, but also very, very happy for him. Do reach out and say your goodbyes if you haven't already!</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:188925,188827 @ 1759586601 -->
<h2>Gavin Lane, Editor</h2>
<p>This weekend I'll hopefully get back to <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/star-wars-outlaws">Star Wars Outlaws</a> - it's had an update since I last played, so I'm interested to see what effect that's had. I'm also keen to crack into <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/final-fantasy-tactics-the-ivalice-chronicles-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Final Fantasy Tactics</a>, and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/ufo_50">UFO 50</a> is sitting on my home screen, giving me a cheeky little wink every time I fire up my Switch. It'd be rude not to.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, I've had a copy of <a href="https://www.pushsquare.com/games/ps4/last_guardian">The Last Guardian</a> sitting under the TV for about a year, and with GOTY approaching <em>of course</em> the urge to play games totally unrelated to 2025 is gripping me. Hey, I just finished 2017's <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/hollow_knight">Hollow Knight</a>, so why not try a winner from 2016 next? <em>*head in hands*</em></p>
<p>Actually, my instinct is to ignore games completely this weekend and deep-dive into videos, specifically YouTube videos featuring our recently departed (from the company - he's okay, everyone!) Zion<del>-from-Nintendo-Life</del>. The video chaps do such brilliant work, yet I often don't have the time to properly check it out. Having watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2qQv6IDHAvM">his last chat video</a>, I'm itching to go back into the archives and (re)watch some of the many brilliant videos Zion's created over the years. Top man, that Mr. Z. He will be missed.</p>
<p>(Just to reiterate, he ain't dead - we'll absolutely be keeping in touch!)</p>
<p>Have a good one, folks.</p>

<h2>Ollie Reynolds, Staff Writer</h2>
<p>I'm still playing <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/super_mario_galaxy_2">Super Mario Galaxy 2</a> this weekend, because of course I am. What a game, man. I'm also keen to play a bit more <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hades-ii-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Hades II</a>, but I feel like I might need to put that one off a bit until I'm in the right mood.</p>
<p>I also got Final Fantasy Tactics: The Ivalice Chronicles, so that's on my radar. Again, I've got a lot on right now, so chances are I'll probably just chill out with some Galaxy 2 before I get properly invested in a new game.</p>
<h2>Jim Norman, Staff Writer</h2>
<p>I’m away in Paris this weekend, so Switchin’ might have to take a backseat for a little while, but it feels fitting that the hours spent on the Eurostar are filled with a game all about <em>love</em>. Okay, it’s Hades II and okay, I don’t actually know whether it’s all that much about love, but it does feature Aphrodite, the goddess of love, so that has to carry my imagery some way, right?</p>
<p>Either way, I’ve only got a couple of roguelike runs under my belt at this point, but <em>boy</em> does it feel good to be back in a Hades mood! Getting to grips with attacks, building up my weapons arsenal, wooing gods with Nectar, this is all the good stuff that I’ll be looking fondly back on in a couple of weeks.</p>
<p>Death to Chronos, and all that, dear readers. Have a good one!</p>

<h2>Gonçalo Lopes, Contributor</h2>
<p>An excellent mech game that I skipped last week has will be my go-to game this weekend. I have about half the missions cleared on <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/switch-eshop/gearbits">Gearbits</a> and I hope to tackle the remaining ones before Monday hits. Hades II progress continues, with every run brining another titbit to the story of Melinoë. Hope to find some time to revisit both Mario Galaxies, really fond memories of a simpler time in my life.</p>
<p>UFO 50 report: 26 of 50 games played. Made it past the halfway mark! Caramel Caramel is excellent but Porgy is the biggest challenge of the week. Pesky, pesky giant shark...</p>
<p>Game of the week is (yet again!) Star Wars Outlaws. Tatooine is far bigger than I was expecting with vast open desert areas, secret caves, Jawas and if I squint really, really hard I can pretend I’m on Arrakis. Looking forward to reaching the main end game story arch.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>Well, that's what we have planned for this most Mario of weekends, but what about you? Let us know your weekend picks in the following poll.</em></p>

</section></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/features/talking-point-what-are-you-playing-this-weekend-4th-october]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WWE 2K25 'John Cena Farewell Tour' DLC Out This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/wwe-2k25-john-cena-farewell-tour-dlc-out-this-month</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wwe-2k25-john-cena-farewell-tour-dlc-out-this-month.1316380/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>"The last time is now"</p>
</section></header><div><section>
<figure data-uuid="e22b136e785c8"><a title="John Cena" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/e22b136e785c8/john-cena.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: 2K Games</em></figcaption></figure><p>The WWE series recently debuted on the Switch 2 in July with the release of <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/wwe-2k25">WWE 2K25</a>, and it will soon be getting some special DLC that you might not have seen coming.</p>
<p>It's a 'John Cena Farewell Tour Edition Pack', celebrating the career of the wrestling legend. It will be arriving on 16th October 2025 and comes with five items. Price details have not been revealed just yet.</p>
<p>This set includes John Cena (WrestleMania 41), John Cena ’04 (Dr. of Thuganomics), Brock Lesnar, Ron Cena and Five Cena Farewell Tour T-Shirts (cosmetic). Here's a quick teaser of what's to come:</p>

<p>This news follows 2K recently revealing the shutdown of online features and services for the same title. If you want to find out more about this recent wrestling release, be sure to take a look at our review.</p>
<p>We were pleased to report the Switch 2 version keeps the action "smooth and silky". even when piling on wrestlers in Royale Rumble.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:185642 @ 1759587681 -->
<p>Have you tried out WWE 2K25 on the Switch 2 yet? How are you finding the experience so far? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section>
<p>[source <a title="External Link: https://gonintendo.com/contents/53587-wwe-2k25-john-cena-farewell-tour-edition-pack-coming-oct-16th-2025" rel="noopener" href="https://gonintendo.com/contents/53587-wwe-2k25-john-cena-farewell-tour-edition-pack-coming-oct-16th-2025">gonintendo.com</a>]</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-info/d078d3b194f13f823916d26124344cdb @ 1759585796 --></div></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/wwe-2k25-john-cena-farewell-tour-dlc-out-this-month]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phantom Blade Zero Is A Delightfully Punishing Action-RPG]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/phantom-blade-zero-is-a-delightfully-punishing-action-rpg</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/phantom-blade-zero-is-a-delightfully-punishing-action-rpg.1316374/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Often, we attach a certain descriptor to the fans of particular gaming genres. Someone might be a shooter aficionado or a puzzle expert, maybe a sports enthusiast, each eliciting a certain image that we might associate with a particular audience. Then there are the lovers of tough action games, those of us who take joy in friction, revel in the struggle. Or as we like to call ourselves, sickos.   At Tokyo Game Show 2025, this sicko went hands-on with Phantom Blade 0, the highly anticipated upcoming action RPG from S-Game. With an arsenal of ferocious weapons, brutal finishers, and savage enemies, it has all the makings of a bloody good time. After an hour of uninterrupted combat, boss battles, and more than a few deaths, I came away with one question: how soon can I schedule my sick days?</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Sophisticated Swordplay</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">You play as Soul, an assassin framed for the murder of the head of his order. Our journey with him in this demo begins at the bottom of the canyon. After just a few steps, we encounter an enemy camp. There will be no easing into battle, as a pair of foot soldiers charge, followed by a spear-wielder mounted on a horse, while a bowman in a nearby tower takes aim. If it’s a fight they want, it’s a fight they’ll get, as I pull out my sword and start jockeying for position.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Phantom Blade 0 PlayStation Showcase Trailer</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Phantom Blade 0 is an action game, first and foremost.  Combatants, you included, have a health bar and a Sha-Chi meter. The former does exactly what you’d expect, while the latter acts as a mix of stamina, skill, power, and energy for special attacks. It’s not stamina-based combat in the strict Soulslike sense; you can do things like throw out basic attacks or dodge without fear of losing your ability to defend yourself. But you do need it to fuel your more powerful Sha-Chi (aka heavy) attacks, and it is consumed while blocking. If you or an enemy runs out of Sha-Chi, you become breached, which breaks your stance and leaves you extremely vulnerable until it refills. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The best option isn’t necessarily to go in sword-a-flailing, like in Ninja Gaiden, or  take turns parrying like in Sekiro; it’s almost like a middle ground where elements of both converge.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">I take a few arrows for my trouble, but manage to carve through the small detachment. As the enemy's health and Sha-Chi drops, I’m able to execute finishers, aka dazzling flourishes that eliminate enemies in brutal and bloody ways. As I push forward, I come across a small bell suspended from a short wooden stand. With a flick, it rings out, revealing a portion of the map. This also functions as a respawn area and fast travel point, similar to a bonfire from Dark Souls. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Executing a block just as an attack arrives allows you to parry the blow, and I learned quickly that these aren’t just a defensive option; they are an essential part of combat. Not only do they negate incoming damage without draining your Sha-Chi, but they also deplete that of the attacker. Sure, you might be able to breach one enemy with pure aggression, but against tougher foes or groups, all of whom are only too eager to start beating on you at once, that’s not going to cut it.  The best option isn’t necessarily to go in sword-a-flailing, like in Ninja Gaiden, or  take turns parrying like in Sekiro; it’s almost like a middle ground where elements of both converge, giving the combat a very distinct feeling as you push forward, invite attacks, then parry and riposte. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">That’s not to say there isn’t a place for dodging. Enemies launch special attacks called Brutal Moves and Killer Moves; the former are meant to be parried, the latter dodged. Using the right type of defense results in you performing a Ghostep, a really slick-looking teleport dodge that leads directly into a counterattack. That comes in handy as I climb the rickety scaffolding up the cliffside. I stealth kill one swordsman on the climb, but fail to get a spearman, and have to rely heavily on those Ghosteps as he and the three buddies he calls over take turns trying to turn me into a pincushion.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">Death is Only the Beginning</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">My first death comes around 15 minutes into my demo. After fighting across several isolated platforms, I face off against a pair of spear users. I strike one down quickly, but eat too many shots in my aggression. I try to take a more measured approach with the second, though, and as soon as I try to create space, I’m killed by an explosive arrow from some far-off archer. My life ends, punctuated with a crimson “Dead” scrawled across the screen. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Moments later, I awaken at the Bell stand from before. Unlike a Souls game, where visiting a Site of Grace or equivalent brings fallen enemies back to life, everyone I’ve defeated remains dead. There are no runes to collect, or battles to be refought, but that doesn’t mean death is without consequences. Soul has 66 days to complete his mission, and every death costs him one of them. Now, how strict that limit is or whether or not we can get days back is unclear, but I certainly feel the pressure to stay alive and not waste any of that potentially limited time by dying if I can avoid it. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I decide it’s time to switch up my armaments a bit. Soul can equip two weapons for general combat, and two Phantom Edges, which are limited-use items, like a powerful bow and arrow or Man-Cutter, an enormous halberd that can crush enemies with a charged smash attack. Each weapon has unique combinations and comes with some sort of perk or special ability. Sanguine, your default long sword, can launch a rapid succession of tumbling attacks, which is great for shredding a breached enemy. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I had been leaning on Seamless Death, a pair of Chakram-like weapons that can be used for fast up close combinations, or thrown to do solid damage from a distance. Now I decide to give Jagged Edge, the enormous greatsword, a go, as I return to the site of my death and enact my revenge on the remaining spear soldier. I have to run to avoid the incoming fire from the bowman across the chasm, and eventually find a route to some platforms I can use to get across, executing an excellent wall-run into an instant kill of a swordsman I caught unawares along the way. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I ring a bell here, establishing a new respawn point, and jump down towards another pair of bow-and-arrow-equipped enemies. I land atop one, executing a throw-and-stab combo to kill him in one fell swoop, then separate the head and body of his buddy with a finisher, creating a satisfying fountain of blood. A short while later, I’m ambushed by a pair of dagger wielders; rather than defeat them with my blade, I call upon Flaming Mane, one of my Phantom Edges. This takes the form of a flame-spewing lion mask, quickly burning up both of my adversaries, opening the way for me to advance. </p><h3 data-cy="title3">Revel in the Struggle</h3><p data-cy="paragraph">Eventually, I reach a large open area at the bottom of the cliffs. After fighting through a few groups of enemies, it’s time to take on my first boss. Enter Wan Jun “Coppermaul”, a towering figure built like The Butcher from Diablo, with a massive warhammer that perfectly matches his sheer mass. I quickly learn he fights dirty too, as he scatters dirt into my face with his weapon, covering the screen to obscure my visibility. Getting caught in that proves a fatal mistake as he grabs me, lines me up, and crushes me with a swing that would make Cal Raleigh proud. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Undeterred, I return to give him another go. His wild swings are powerful, but I quickly get the timing down to parry most of his attacks, taking large chunks out of his Shi-Chi with each combination. Once he is breached, I press the attack hard using the Soft Snake Sword, a flexible, almost whip-like blade that dishes damage quickly. There are a few dicey moments, but the thrill of victory is mine as I take down the giant. It’s a cool fight, and a solid example of how important learning boss patterns on the fly will be. I add Bashpole, as his weapon is called, to my arsenal as a Phantom Edge. Using it to smash through a wooden floor to reach a new passageway, I press on. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Curiosity gets the better of me and I make a hasty retreat, leaving the Red Wraith behind – a decision that would come back to haunt me...</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The next boss comes as a complete surprise. As I made my way through some sort of village, I climbed to the roof of a round building. Standing dramatically atop a small spire at the center was Red Wraith. It was an intimidating entrance despite her smaller frame, made doubly so by the total lack of cutscene, gate, or any other sort of forewarning. She immediately presses the attack with her longsword and some sort of thrown blade, but I manage to Ghosteps to quickly break her guard. Something seems off, though – the fight seems almost too easy, which doesn’t go unnoticed by Soul, and he suggests that we could leave her be and flee if we wanted. Curiosity gets the better of me and I make a hasty retreat, leaving the Red Wraith behind – a decision that would come back to haunt me.  </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">A few skirmishes later, I reach the final boss of the demo, the Chief Disciple of the Seven Stars. He leads a team of six other warriors, and, even as a veteran of many, many action games, I have to admit this is one of the more impressive boss fights in recent memory. Each warrior has their own health bar, including the Chief Disciple, with the boss's health bar, and they seamlessly switch between acting independently and striking as one. One moment I’m isolating one enemy, chipping away at their health, then suddenly the entire group converges on me with a coordinated thrust attack from all directions, as my perfectly timed dodge allows me to leap their collective attack, and land gracefully upon the combined tips of all their weapons. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s a gorgeous spectacle, and each time I chip away at the Chief Disciple's health in this intricate dance of steel, his followers heal him, sacrificing their own health in the process. I continuously chip away at the group, using a leaping smash from Bashpole to send everyone flying when I’m in danger of being overwhelmed. As their numbers dwindle, the Chief Disciple changes tactics, giving away his health to make sure there are at least three followers at his side at all times. This proves his folly, as I take advantage of his rapidly diminishing strength and drop him with a thrown barrage from Seamless Death. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The fight wa= sn’t over yet, however. His three disciples scattered to a trio of towers, throwing out what resembled thread. The boss, now called the Chief Disciple’s Fallen Hope, rose from the ground like some abomination of a marionette, and the battle began anew. This time it was strictly a 1v1, his ferocious attacks now coming with him dangling as he rushed me with melee attacks and threw a screen-filling barrage of his own threads. Even this I thought I could handle, until I heard a voice call out, “Nothing can separate us, not even in Death!” The Red Wraith had returned, and the combined fury of both bosses was more than I could handle.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I died. Then I died again. And again. Each rematch began at the start of the marionette phase, but time and time again I fell when the Red Wraith arrived, my decision to be merciful earlier haunting me. But dammit if I didn’t learn just a little more each time, get to that last phase with just a little more health each attempt. As I threw myself at what seemed like an impossible fight just a few attempts earlier, I began to see the windows to attack, until finally, my heart pounding in my chest, I struck down the Red Wraith with a leaping finisher from my Seamless Death, withstood the enraged counterattack from The Disciple’s Lost Hope, and severed his strings and head with one last swipe of my sword. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">There are three difficulty options to choose from, but even at the default setting that I played at, Phantom Blade 0 is hard, and I loved that about it. It never felt cheap; it just demanded more from me. In just over an hour of play, I was easily ten times the player I was when I started. It’s a feeling of achievement that is reserved for the very best action games on the planet. If the rest is anything like what I played at TGS, I feel like there’s a real chance that Phantom Blade 0 might be one of those games. </p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/phantom-blade-zero-is-a-delightfully-punishing-action-rpg]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Is Going All In, Its 4.9-Rated Star Wars R2-D2 Set Is Selling for Pennies]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/lego-is-going-all-in-its-4-9-rated-star-wars-r2-d2-set-is-selling-for-pennies-2000631589</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-is-going-all-in-its-4-9-rated-star-wars-r2-d2-set-is-selling-for-pennies.1316362/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Star Wars remains LEGO’s most coveted license with countless sets from the franchise earning exceptional ratings from builders worldwide. The adorable R2-D2 droid exemplifies this success perfectly and boasts a 4.9 out of 5 stars across thousands of reviews. By fortunate timing, this set has just dropped to an all-time low on Amazon, and it’s flying off the shelves: <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4474/">At $79 down from its usual $99 price, this 1,050-piece building experience delivers both a satisfying construction project and a display piece</a> that captures one of cinema’s most iconic characters in brick form.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4474/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>No introduction is needed to any Star Wars aficionado for R2-D2. The clever astromech droid has appeared in every but the most insignificant Star Wars films and TV shows and saves the heroes with technological magic and unflinching perseverance time and again. This LEGO set remains true to R2’s charm with meticulous care for detail and playful interactive features. The completed model stands <strong>over 9 inches high, 6 inches wide, and 4 inches deep</strong>, which makes a grand impression without taking up too much of your shelf real estate.</p>



<h2>Interactive Details That Bring R2-D2 to Life</h2>
<p><strong>R2-D2’s dome head will rotate 360 degrees</strong> so that you can pose him like he’s scanning his surroundings or reacting to droids and minifigures across from him. This rotating system uses LEGO Technic parts hidden in the build to create smooth motion without loosening after extended periods. The <strong>third leg that is removable also flexes and folds</strong>, emulating R2’s movement from the films in which he transitions from his stable three-legged form to his faster two-wheeled wheel mode. An <strong>attachable periscope</strong> replica’s the sensor that sticks out of R2’s dome during recon missions and other attachable tools wink to the many various gadgets he’s dispatched throughout the saga, from arc welders to drink service trays.</p>
<p>The set includes a <strong>bonus 25th Anniversary Darth Malak minifigure</strong> and celebrates LEGO Star Wars’ quarter century milestone. Darth Malak is from the well-loved Knights of the Old Republic video game and belongs to the wider Star Wars universe beyond the films. Including him not only provides collectibility but also provides you with an option for a display other than R2-D2 himself.</p>



<p>The building <strong>experience uses 1,050 pieces</strong> and offers a number of hours of enjoyable constructing that is <strong>appropriate for 10 years and up</strong>. LEGO instruction guides guide you through the construction with numbered bags that organize pieces by build phase, precluding the overwhelming feeling of pouring all pieces into one heap.</p>
<p>For $79, you’re getting excellent value for an officially licensed LEGO set of this size and sophistication. Star Wars fans, here is your opportunity.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4474/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/lego-is-going-all-in-its-4-9-rated-star-wars-r2-d2-set-is-selling-for-pennies-2000631589]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Helldivers 2 Dev Explains Why The Game Takes Up So Much Space On PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-dev-explains-why-the-game-takes-up-so-much-space-on-pc/1100-6535217/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/helldivers-2-dev-explains-why-the-game-takes-up-so-much-space-on-pc.1316359/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535217">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Have you ever noticed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/helldivers-2/" data-ref-id="5000-589428">Helldivers 2</a> takes up a lot more room on PC than it does on either Xbox Series X|S or PlayStation 5? At 150GB, the game is roughly three times bigger on PC than on consoles. According to Arrowhead game studio deputy technical director Brendan Armstrong, the reason why is that Helldivers 2 is still catering to a small segment of PC users.</p><p>In a lengthy post on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/543369627969783286" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Steam</a>, Armstrong wrote that Helldivers 2's install footprint is so large because most of it is duplicated for the benefit of players who still use mechanical hard disk drives. It's an antiquated process that features duplicate data grouped close together in order to reduce loading times. Armstrong notes that the duplication is not necessary for players who have long since upgraded to solid state drives, but Arrowhead has had difficulty determining how many players remain on mechanical HDDs.</p><p>"How many Helldivers 2 players are still using mechanical HDD? The truth is that we don't currently know," Armstrong wrote. "Even the Steam user surveys are unable to give us data on mechanical HDD use in the overall gamer population. Our best estimates put it at around 12% of all PC gamers, but the data is very unreliable and relies on a lot of extrapolations. Until we can more accurately determine the number of mechanical HDDs that Helldivers 2 is installed on, it is difficult to know how many players will be impacted by reducing the amount of data duplication. Even if that number is small, keep in mind that the load time for each player dropping into a mission is determined by the slowest member of the squad."</p><p>Armstrong laid out some potential solutions and noted that the next update will make some progress towards shrinking the file size. However, he warns that players may not notice the difference "because the new stuff we've added will eat those gains." For a medium-term solution, Arrowhead plans to bundle common assets together rather than featuring so many duplicate files. The downside is that it will make the game slightly slower for mechanical HDD users, but he hopes to keep the load times to "less than 30 seconds."</p><p>Going forward, Arrowhead will also work to improve its engine and improve compression techniques that reduce the need for duplication. However, Armstrong added that the studio doesn't know yet if the impact on load times will make this an infeasible solution.</p><p>Arrowhead Game Studio CEO Shams Jorjani recently stated that the team's goal for Helldivers 2 is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-devs-arent-making-sequel-plans/1100-6535043/" data-ref-id="1100-6535043">to keep it going forever</a>, rather than moving on to Helldivers 3. The studio also released <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-patch-tackles-cave-crashes-and-audio-bugs/1100-6534782/">a patch that tackled cave crashes and audio bugs</a>. More recently, Arrowhead acknowledged a long <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-update-planned-for-october-with-bigger-performance-pieces-needing-more-time/1100-6534979/" data-ref-id="1100-6534979">list of problems to address</a>, including "issues including performance drops, stability hiccups, freezes, and the annoying audio bugs." An update is planned for later this month, but many of those issues may take more time to fix.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/helldivers-2-dev-explains-why-the-game-takes-up-so-much-space-on-pc/1100-6535217/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ICYMI: Switch 2 Available For Purchase At The My Nintendo Store (US)]]></title>
            <link>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/icymi-switch-2-available-for-purchase-at-the-my-nintendo-store-us</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/icymi-switch-2-available-for-purchase-at-the-my-nintendo-store-us.1316350/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">
<article id="article">
<header><section>
<p>Get yours today</p>
</section></header><section>
<figure data-uuid="eb7152ddbb7ea"><a title="Nintendo Switch 2" href="https://images.nintendolife.com/eb7152ddbb7ea/nintendo-switch-2.large.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Image: Zion Grassl / Nintendo Life</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you're still considering a Switch 2 and happen to be located in the US, Nintendo has issued a reminder on social media that its new system is now available for purchase on the My Nintendo Store. According to the fine print, no invitation is required, but purchase limits apply.</p>
<p>There are three different bundles currently available. You've got the base package including the Switch 2 for $449.99, the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/mario-kart-world">Mario Kart World</a> bundle for $499.99, and last but not least, the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/pokemon-legends-z-a-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Pokémon Legends: Z-A</a> – Nintendo Switch 2 Edition bundle for $499.99, which is releasing the same day as the game on 16th October 2025.</p>

<p>If you're seeking other options, you can check out <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/guides/where-to-buy-nintendo-switch-2">our guide on where to buy a Switch 2</a> here on Nintendo Life. It covers the US, UK, and other parts of the world, and also lists various retailers you can purchase the new system from.</p>
<p>The Switch 2 sold over 3.5 million units worldwide in less than a week, and by the end of the first month, it had sold more than 6 million units globally. Nintendo is now gearing up for the holiday season with not only Mario Kart and Pokémon, but also new games in the <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Zelda</a>, <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/kirby-air-riders">Kirby</a> and <a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/games/nintendo-switch-2/metroid-prime-4-beyond-nintendo-switch-2-edition">Metroid</a> series.</p>
<!-- cache: html:nintendolife.com/ssl/nintendo-switch-2/related-articles:180157,185922,183867 @ 1759587157 -->
<p>Have you got your hands on the Switch 2 yet? <em>Let us know in the comments.</em></p></section></article><div><p>Liam is a news writer and reviewer across Hookshot Media. He's been writing about games for more than 15 years and is a lifelong fan of many iconic video game characters.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.nintendolife.com/authors/Liam_Doolan"><span></span> Author Profile</a></li><li><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/liamdoolan.bsky.social"><span></span> Bluesky</a></li><li><a onclick="return replyTo('Liam_Doolan');" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/#"> Reply</a></li></ul>
</div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2025/10/icymi-switch-2-available-for-purchase-at-the-my-nintendo-store-us]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Luna Controller for PC and Mac Is Now 2x Cheaper Than a Sony Controller, Amazon Clearing Final Stock]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/luna-controller-for-pc-and-mac-is-now-2x-cheaper-than-a-sony-controller-amazon-clearing-final-stock-2000631580</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/luna-controller-for-pc-and-mac-is-now-2x-cheaper-than-a-sony-controller-amazon-clearing-final-stock.1316341/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Amazon has taken serious steps towards positioning itself in gaming, from acquiring Twitch to developing Luna, its cloud gaming service. Amazon also recognized that the Xbox and PlayStation controllers both command high prices that do not benefit all, especially if you game primarily on PC or mobile. That’s where Luna controller comes in as the smart choice: It’s designed for cross-platform gaming without the console tax, <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4473/">and right now it’s dropped to a record low of $39 from its usual $69 price for Prime Big Deals Day</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4473/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>Luna controller was <strong>specifically built for Amazon’s Luna cloud game system</strong>&nbsp;but to call it a single-use controller would be a fallacy. This controller supports <strong>Windows, Mac, Fire TV, Fire tablet, iPhone, iPad, Chromebook, and Android</strong>, which gives you greater mobility than native controllers can. The real innovation lies in the way it connects: You can use it <strong>via WiFi, Bluetooth, or USB</strong> depending on your needs and device.</p>



<h2>Three Connection Methods for Maximum Flexibility</h2>
<p>The WiFi connection is best when you are gaming with Luna games since it skips your computer or phone completely. Traditional controllers transfer input to your device and your device forwards them to the server. Luna controller talks directly to the server and eliminates precious milliseconds. If you ever felt like your character responds slowly while cloud gaming, this setup fixes that problem.</p>



<p>For non-Luna gaming, Bluetooth mode turns it into a standard wireless controller to play with any Bluetooth-enabled device. That provides mobile gaming, emulators or Steam games on your laptop without needing a separate controller. The USB option provides a wired setup for Windows and Mac, free from any wireless interference and offering zero lag when you need every single frame in competitive gaming.</p>
<p>The <strong>screen-switiching technology provides a fluid gaming experience</strong>: You can start playing a Luna game on your Fire TV in the living room, pause while dinner is ready, then pick up where you left off on your iPad in bed that night. Progress is synced up across devices instantly and the controller just reconnects without requiring setup process.</p>



<p><strong>Tilted thumbsticks make hand position easy</strong> during extended sessions, positioned asymmetrically such as Xbox controllers (not symmetrical like PlayStation). The thumbsticks have potentiometers that track subtle motion, important when aiming in shooters or executing fine maneuvers in racing games. Easy-access bumpers are placed on the controller where your index fingers prefer to rest and the triggers at the bottom offer incremental resistance. The analog triggers read how far you’re pressing them which is useful in racing games where you don’t want to rush your throttle or in shooters where you’re attempting to sneak up on a shot.</p>
<p>For $39, you’re paying a controller that’s roughly half as much as an Xbox or PlayStation official controller but comes with some connectivity options they lack.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4473/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/luna-controller-for-pc-and-mac-is-now-2x-cheaper-than-a-sony-controller-amazon-clearing-final-stock-2000631580]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Discord customer service data breach leaks user info and scanned photo IDs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/792032/discord-customer-service-data-breach-hack</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/discord-customer-service-data-breach-leaks-user-info-and-scanned-photo-ids.1316314/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span id="follow-author-standard_article_details-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></p> <p><span>is a senior reporter covering technology, gaming, and more. He joined The Verge in 2019 after nearly two years at Techmeme.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>One of Discord’s third-party customer service providers was compromised by an “unauthorized party,” <a href="https://discord.com/press-releases/update-on-security-incident-involving-third-party-customer-service">the company says</a>. The unauthorized party gained access to “information from a limited number of users who had contacted Discord through our Customer Support and/or Trust &amp; Safety teams” and aimed to “extort a financial ransom from Discord.” The unauthorized party “did not gain access to Discord directly.”</p><p>Data potentially accessed by the hack includes things like names, usernames, emails, and the last four digits of credit card numbers. The unauthorized party also accessed a “small number” of images of government IDs from “users who had appealed an age determination.” Full credit card numbers and passwords were not impacted by the breach, Discord says.</p><p>The company is notifying impacted users now over email. If your ID might have been accessed, Discord will specify that. Discord also says it revoked the support provider’s access to Discord’s ticketing system, has notified data protection authorities, is working with law enforcement, and has reviewed “our threat detection systems and security controls for third-party support providers.”</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTIz"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Jay Peters</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/news/792032/discord-customer-service-data-breach-hack]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This 65W Wall Charger Is 44% Off on Amazon, and It Juices Up Your Mac and iPhone at Once]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/this-65w-wall-charger-is-44-off-on-amazon-and-it-juices-up-your-mac-and-iphone-at-once-2000631566</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/this-65w-wall-charger-is-44-off-on-amazon-and-it-juices-up-your-mac-and-iphone-at-once.1316311/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Apple’s official 20W charger costs $20 on their website, and you get exactly one USB-C port for that price. Meanwhile, <em>Ugreen</em> is offering a deal through Amazon that’s frankly absurd: <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4472/">their 65W charger with four ports (including three USB-C) is currently 44 percent off, dropping from $42 to just $23</a>. From a value perspective, this is wild.</p>
<p>Ugreen has built its entire reputation around safety and reliability which makes this price point even more remarkable. You’re getting more than three times the power output, four times the ports, and GaN technology that makes everything safer and more efficient, all for three dollars more than Apple’s most basic single-port option.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4472/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>The <strong>Ugreen Nexode 65W has enough juice to charge a MacBook Air to a 51 percent level in 30 minutes</strong>, which is critical when you’re rushing out the door and notice your laptop is running on fumes. That <strong>65W rating can handle power-sucking devices like the MacBook Pro</strong>, iPad Pro or even a Steam Deck at full throttle. The <strong>charger intelligently distributes power</strong> across its four ports based on what’s connected, so you can simultaneously charge your laptop, phone, tablet, and wireless earbuds without needing multiple wall outlets or a power strip cluttering your desk.</p>
<h2>GaN Technology Makes All the Difference</h2>
<p>GaN stands for gallium nitride and it is a semiconductor material that’s replaced traditional silicon in modern chargers. GaN devices switch at much higher voltages and are quicker than silicon and generate less heat and providing more efficient electrical conversion. The payoff in real life is a charger that’s significantly smaller than earlier 65W versions and that operates cooler and safer as well. The foldable plug design means you can simply toss it into your bag without the prongs scratching your laptop or sticking anything.</p>
<p>The built-in safety features are <strong>overheating prevention and overcurrent protection</strong> which proactively monitor power flow and heat. When the charger detects something irregular, it automatically corrects or shuts off to protect your devices. This is crucial since cheap chargers can kill battery health in the long term or, worse still, cause electrical fires.</p>



<p>The four-port design changes the way you charge: <strong>Three USB-C ports and one USB-A port</strong> will accommodate pretty much every device in your life. The USB-A port is great for older accessories like Bluetooth speakers, Kindle e-readers or wireless mouse dongles that still have not upgraded to USB-C. All three of the USB-C ports have Power Delivery support, the fast-charging protocol used by iPhones since iPhone 8, Galaxy and Pixel phones, and all new laptops.</p>
<p>For $23, you’re acquiring a charging solution which can replace multiple single-port chargers yet take up less space and deliver higher performance.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4472/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/this-65w-wall-charger-is-44-off-on-amazon-and-it-juices-up-your-mac-and-iphone-at-once-2000631566]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mac Mini M4 Is Going for Pennies, Apple Is Quietly Offloading Stock on Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/mac-mini-m4-is-going-for-pennies-apple-is-quietly-offloading-stock-on-amazon-2000631565</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mac-mini-m4-is-going-for-pennies-apple-is-quietly-offloading-stock-on-amazon.1316302/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Apple is probably the most discount-averse brand in tech. The company protects its premium image and does everything possible to avoid price cuts, at least on its official website where full retail pricing remains sacred. But something interesting is happening behind the scenes: Apple seems eager to move inventory of its excellent Mac Mini M4, which launched just a year ago and remains their latest desktop offering.</p>
<p>The performance is absolutely wild, and right now the price is exceptionally sweet. This <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4124/">Amazon-exclusive deal drops the M4 Mac Mini 256GB to $499 from its usual $599 price, and you don’t need a Prime membership to grab it</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4124/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>The M4 Chip Redefines Desktop Computing</h2>
<p>The Mac Mini has always been Apple’s <strong>answer to people who want macOS power without paying for a display, keyboard, or mouse</strong> they already own. This 2024 version takes that concept and shrinks it even further while dramatically increasing performance. The computer measures just five inches by five inches, a footprint so compact it fits perfectly next to any monitor without dominating your desk space. You can store it behind a display, stash it in a cabinet, or place it wherever you’d like to have an entire desktop computer minus the bulk.</p>



<p>The <strong>M4 chip in this Mac Mini features a 10-core CPU and a 10-core GPU</strong> and with performance that makes every experience lightning-fast and fluid. The chip has <strong>16GB unified memory</strong> that operates differently than traditional RAM. Unified memory architecture has the GPU and CPU access the same pool of memory, meaning there is no data bottleneck of transferring data between various memory systems.</p>
<p>The 256GB SSD storage delivers rapid boot times and speedy application loading, but do be mindful of your own storage requirements as Mac Mini storage isn’t user-upgradeable once you’ve bought it. The SSD read and write data at speeds that’ll leave conventional hard drives looking positively ancient and that’s important when you’re dealing with large files or virtual machines.</p>
<p>Connectivity has also gotten much better in this generation: The <strong>back panel houses Thunderbolt ports, HDMI output, and Gigabit Ethernet</strong> for high-speed wired internet access. <strong>Front-facing USB-C ports and a headphone jack</strong> debuted for the first time on Mac Mini to eliminate the goofy reach-around to plug in a flash drive or place headphones. Thunderbolt capability enables daisy-chaining multiple 4K displays or connecting high-speed external storage at the same speed as the internal SSD.</p>
<p>The Mac Mini runs all your important software at lightning speed. <a href="https://gizmodo.com/download/microsoft-365">Microsoft 365</a>, Adobe Creative Cloud and thousands of other apps are optimized for Apple silicon, delivering performance way beyond many pricier Windows desktops. If you’re already working with an iPhone or iPad within the Apple ecosystem, the integration is seamless.</p>
<p>Right now, Apple’s refusal to provide discounts makes this price truly stand out in particular.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/4124/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/mac-mini-m4-is-going-for-pennies-apple-is-quietly-offloading-stock-on-amazon-2000631565]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Save On PS5-Compatible SSDs Ahead Of Amazon's Prime Big Deal Days]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-on-ps5-compatible-ssds-ahead-of-amazons-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6535148/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/save-on-ps5-compatible-ssds-ahead-of-amazons-prime-big-deal-days.1316299/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6535148">

            
            
    


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>While Amazon's Prime Big Deal Days officially begin on October 7, several <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">products are already seeing discounts ahead of the event</a>. This includes steep price cuts for the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DQ9K7S1Q?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Crucial P310 1TB</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DQBQZ9LX?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">2TB M.2 SSDs</a>, which are down to their <strong>lowest prices ever</strong>. The 1TB model is $75 (was $96) while the 2TB version is $112 (normally $145). These internal SSDs come with a built-in heatsink, meaning they work out of the box with all PS5 models, as well as PCs that support the NVMe M.2 format. These are great deals if you're looking to add a bit of extra space to your computer or console during the busy fall release season. However, we don't know how long these deals will be available--in fact, we've already seen similar early Prime Big Deal Days discounts on other SSD models sell out--so it's worth grabbing one of these internal drives while you can</p><p>Note that a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0F3WKYQPS?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">4TB version</a> of the Crucial P310 NVMe M.2 SSD is also available; however, it is not currently on sale and can only be purchased from third-party sellers. However, we have a few alternative options if you're shopping around, including Samsung's popular <a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Workstations-Compatible-Playstation-MZ-V9P4T0CW/dp/B0BHJGV9WR?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Samsung 990 Pro</a>. It's available in 1TB, 2TB, and 4TB capacities, and all of them are also on sale (though they're noticeably more expensive than the Crucial lineup). These support speeds up to 7,450MB/s, and while that speed difference is negligible on PS5, it could be useful if you're installing the drive on a PC.</p><p>If you're looking for something more affordable, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lexar-Heatsink-Internal-Compatible-LNM790X001T-RN9NU/dp/B0CGKPPZY9?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lexar's NM790 SSD Gen4 NVMe M.2 SSDs</a> are also on sale. The 1TB model is down to just $70 (was $95), while the 2TB version is $130 (was $165), and the 4TB model is $240 (normally $305).</p><p>For those who need more than 4TB of space, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DBQP4F3Z?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">WD_Black 8TB SN850P</a> with a heatsink is seeing a slight discount to $615 (was $650). That's a hefty price to be sure, but you can get quite a bit of use out of an 8TB drive like that. Check out the list below for all of the early Prime Big Deal Days discounts on internal SSDs with heatsinks below, and then head over to our <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/amazon-prime-day-deals/">Prime Big Deals Day hub</a> to see even more early discounts from Amazon's sale--and check back when the full sale is live October 7 and 8 to see the best price cuts on games, Blu-rays, hardware, and more.</p><h2>More Deals on Internal NVMe M.2 SSDs with Heatsinks</h2><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DQ9K7S1Q?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Crucial P310 NVMe M.2 SSD with heatsink</a> - 1TB</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DQBQZ9LX?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Crucial P310 NVMe M.2 SSD with heatsink</a> - 2TB</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lexar-Heatsink-Internal-Compatible-LNM790X001T-RN9NU/dp/B0CGKPPZY9?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lexar NM790 SSD Gen4 NVMe M.2 SSD with heatsink</a> - 1TB</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lexar-Heatsink-Internal-Compatible-LNM790X001T-RN9NU/dp/B0CGKHGMW5?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lexar NM790 SSD Gen4 NVMe M.2 SSD with heatsink</a> - 2TB</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lexar-Heatsink-Internal-Compatible-LNM790X001T-RN9NU/dp/B0CGKY9K2Y?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Lexar NM790 SSD Gen4 NVMe M.2 SSD with heatsink</a> - 4TB</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Workstations-Compatible-Playstation-MZ-V9P4T0CW/dp/B0BHJGV9WR?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Samsung 990 Pro with heatsink - 1TB</a> -- $110 (<del>$140</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Workstations-Compatible-Playstation-MZ-V9P4T0CW/dp/B0BHJDY57J?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Samsung 990 Pro with heatsink - 2TB</a> -- $163 (<del>$210</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/SAMSUNG-Workstations-Compatible-Playstation-MZ-V9P4T0CW/dp/B0CHHFR1LG?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Samsung 990 Pro with heatsink - 4TB</a> -- $310.59 (<del>$385</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DBQP4F3Z?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">WD_Black SN850P with heatsink - 8TB</a> - $615 (<del>$650</del>)</li></ul><hr><p><strong>Sign up for GameSpot's Weekly Deals Newsletter:</strong></p><hr><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/nintendo-switch-2-powera-cheap-wireless-controller-super-mario-amazon-deals/1100-6535215/">Get Super Mario And Kirby Switch 2 Wireless Controllers For Up To 50% Off</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-audible-premium-plus-sign-up-prime-big-deal-days-black-friday-holiday-2025-deal/1100-6524536/">Audible Premium Plus Holiday Deal: Get 3 Audiobooks For $3</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/amazon-prime-big-deal-days-4k-blu-ray-best-deals/1100-6535093/">Get Popular Movies On 4K Blu-Ray For $15 Or Less At Amazon This Week</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/rog-xbox-ally-preorder-guide/1100-6535007/">ROG Xbox Ally X Preorders In Stock At Best Buy, Sold Out Everywhere Else (September 27)</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/final-fantasy-magic-the-gathering-trading-cards-restock-where-to-buy-amazon-walmart-best-buy-target/2900-6271/">New Magic: The Gathering Final Fantasy Chocobo Bundle &amp; Scene Boxes Up For Preorder</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/lego-game-boy-restocked-at-amazon-and-its-shipping-early/1100-6533358/">You Can Get The $60 Lego Game Boy Early From Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/history-of-middle-earth-5440-page-box-set-drops-to-all-time-best-price-for-big-deal-days/1100-6526926/">Complete History Of Middle-Earth Collector's Box Set Restocked With $170 Discount</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-shining-movie-4k-blu-ray-special-edition-steelbook-the-film-vault/1100-6534223/">The Shining's New Numbered Limited Edition Is Up For Grabs At Amazon</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/save-on-ps5-compatible-ssds-ahead-of-amazons-prime-big-deal-days/1100-6535148/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If Gaming Is in Your DNA, This Samsung G9 49″ OLED Curved Monitor Is $700+ Off on Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/if-gaming-is-in-your-dna-this-samsung-g9-49-oled-curved-monitor-is-700-off-on-amazon-2000631621</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/if-gaming-is-in-your-dna-this-samsung-g9-49%E2%80%B3-oled-curved-monitor-is-700-off-on-amazon.1316281/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Dual monitors are yesterday’s setup. Triple monitor arrays look impressive but waste desk space and demand GPU resources just to manage bezels. The real power move is one massive ultrawide that replaces everything while delivering an experience no multi-monitor rig can match. <strong>Samsung’s 49-inch Odyssey OLED G93SC</strong> solves the fundamental problem gamers face: you need maximum screen real estate, perfect image quality, and response times fast enough to matter in competitive play. This isn’t a compromise solution: It’s the endgame display that removes every excuse between you and peak performance. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3899/">Right now it’s dropped to $879 from its typical $1,599 price on Amazon, a 45 percent discount that brings premium QD-OLED technology within reach of gamers</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3899/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<p>The 49-inch curved display has 5120×1440 resolution which <strong>provides the equivalent of two 27-inch QHD monitors side-by-side</strong> without bezel interruption. That 32:9 aspect ratio dramatically reimagines the experience of games. Racing simulations wrap around your peripheral vision with opponents on each side of you simultaneously. First-person shooters give you situational awareness that is cheating-like, with flanking enemies in sight earlier than players in ordinary displays.</p>



<h2>Gamers Will Love It</h2>
<p><strong>Quantum Dot OLED is the current leader in display technology</strong>, combining OLED’s perfect blacks and infinite contrast with quantum dot color and brightness. Elder LCD screens have bleeder backlights that bleed through black areas, warping shadows and hiding enemies in the shadows. QD-OLED pixels are emitting and can be completely turned off and produce actual blacks with no light bleed. <strong>DisplayHDR True Black 400 certification</strong> means you can see into deep, rich darks but still have great highlights, so you’ll notice movement in dark corridors that other players just can’t spot on their lower-end panels.</p>
<p>The 0.03ms gray-to-gray response time is essentially click-by-click. For context, the majority of gaming monitors market 1ms response time, and a lot of LCD panels fail to even get close to actually providing that figure. This <strong>OLED screen responds 33 times faster</strong> and removes motion blur and ghosting even during high-speed camera pans or acrobatic action scenes. Combined <strong>with the 240Hz refresh rate</strong>, you get 240 separate frames per second with each frame gliding into the next. <strong>HDMI 2.1 and DisplayPort inputs</strong> provide this bandwidth in full so your GPU can send frames at full speed without disruption.</p>



<p>G-Sync and AMD FreeSync Premium Pro support guarantee the <strong>monitor works with both Nvidia and AMD graphics cards</strong>, synchronizing the refresh rate of the panel with the output from your GPU in frames. This eliminates screen tearing, stutter and input lag and produces smooth motion even when frame rates are changing during fast motion scenes.</p>
<p>The slim build is just 4.5mm thick at its thinnest, with a premium metal finish that feels expensive sitting on your desk. The height-adjustable stand means you can position the gigantic screen at perfect eye level, and the USB hub makes it simple to plug in peripherals without reaching behind to your PC.</p>
<p>At $879, this is the cheapest way to get into premium ultrawide QD-OLED gaming. This monitor normally retails for $1,599, and other ultrawides with such specs cost even more.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/3899/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/if-gaming-is-in-your-dna-this-samsung-g9-49-oled-curved-monitor-is-700-off-on-amazon-2000631621]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Multiplayer Review in Progress - Beta Impressions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-review-in-progress-beta-impressions.1316275/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">I look forward to the Call of Duty multiplayer beta each fall in the same way I look forward to the return of pumpkin spice lattes: I know exactly what I'm in for, and I always savor that first warm, familiar sip. This year's closed beta is the blast of violent, nutmeg-infused flavor I've been looking for since that first northerly chill swept across the land, and while it definitely feels like the CoD I’ve come to expect, there are a few new features I'm already really enjoying and a few more I'm really looking forward to unlocking.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">I installed the beta Thursday afternoon and had planned to play it well into the night, rallying my dedicated group of Call of Duty friends (the Beef Lords) to join in on the fun. In fact, playing with the boys is absolutely my favorite thing about CoD, and even a given year’s iteration is only so-so, we still have a good time together. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Sadly, and I can't really fault it since this <em>is </em>a closed beta, every time I tried to squad up with my friends, I had a hard crash. In fact, it felt like I spent more time waiting for BLOPS7 to restart than I did in matches. That's a huge bummer, because I just want to run around shooting strangers in the face with my bros. Eventually I was able to get into a few matches with one friends, and good old Call of Duty fun was had by all. It still crashed, but only after a few matches this time. I had initially planned to hit the level 20 cap last night, but with all the time I wasted rebooting not only the BLOPS7 beta but also my PC, I was only able to make it to level 14. I know. I'm not proud.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Crashing aside, and no surprise here, but I’ve had a blast with what I’ve been able to play so far. I mean, it's Call of Duty, where the whole point is either to rack up as many kills as possible, or hold an objective… while also racking up as many kills as possible. I truly believe no one does it better than CoD, at least when it comes to gunplay. It's razor-sharp every damn year. It works exactly how I want it to work, it feels exactly how I want it to feel. It's as dependable as the sun rising in the east each morning.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Omnimovement, Omnimprovement</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">The biggest and most immediate changes this year are updates to the Omnimove system first introduced in last year's Black Ops 6. If you're not familiar, Omnimovement is a control mechanic that lets you perform John Woo-esque flights of gun-firing fancy, while also allowing you to move around more naturally when you're on the ground. Previously, dropping prone would reduce your target size but would render your movement slow and cumbersome. Omnimovement lets you slide to prone and do sick dolphin dives, mantle walls, and look like an action movie star in everyone else's clips, firing your weapon with 360-degrees of aiming movement while on your back.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Call of Duty: Black Ops 7 Multiplayer Maps</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This year's Omnimovement system adds wall running and wall jumping to your arsenal. It basically lets you hop around the map like Jiminy Cricket, as you can chain up to three wall jumps together. It's really fun, though I haven't really used it tactically so far. Mostly I'm flying off walls just because it feels awesome, and if I happen to get the literal drop on an enemy, all the better.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It also makes moving around the map faster and gives you an advantage over mantling. When you mantle a ledge, your arms can't be used to shooting, on account of them being used to pull you up and onto that ledge. On top of that, it's kind of slow, and an opponent can use this to their advantage. You're basically a sitting duck until you get your feet all the way up, and those few moments can be the difference between life and death… well, usually death and a different kind of death.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Wall jumps change that, because rather than mantle over a ledge in the traditional way, you can just bounce off the wall and make your way to the top without using your arms. You never have to put away your weapon – heck, you don't even need to stop firing your weapon. It takes away that moment of complete vulnerability, and as long as there's a wall nearby and the next level up is reachable within three jumps, you can parkour your way to victory.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Wall jumping might be my favorite addition to BLOPS7 so far.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">It's easier said than done, mind you, and I'm not yet skilled enough to consistently hit shots when I'm going up or down from a wall jump. But it's still fun as hell, and might be my favorite addition to BLOPS7 so far.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">BLOPS7 Beta Maps</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">There are three maps in the closed beta: Cortex, The Forge, and Exposure. They're fine. They're not bad maps by any means, and I do like playing on them, but nothing about them really stands out to me in the way some of the maps from BLOPS6 did, either. Last year's Rewind map, with its super long corridors and building interiors, was one of my favorites, as was Skyline, with its secret passageway, various hiding spots, and multiple levels. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Then again, the maps in last year's beta were even worse (I’m looking at you, Babylon), so the middling nature of these is probably not an indication of overall quality.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Cortex is probably my favorite of the three this year just because it has everything I like in a map: outside lanes with the possibility of falling to your death, tight interiors to come face-to-face with opps, as well as medium-length interiors and exteriors that work well with LMGs, SMGs, and assault rifles. It lends itself really well to deathmatch and objective-based modes. Plus it has some sweet sci-fi incubator tanks where I presume the super soldiers of tomorrow are being grown from the cells of past heroes. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Exposure is a larger map, and has a lot of cool opportunities to really feel out the wall jumping and running. There's a dangling shipping container on the map that might as well have a Wile E. Coyote-esque sign on it saying "WALL JUMP HERE." Meanwhile, The Forge is pretty big, but it doesn't really have any super long, open lanes for snipers to trade lead back and forth. That's not to say there aren't some great opportunities to do just that, but it doesn't have the same feel as last year's Rewind, with its back alley and strip mall-front.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The Forge might not be my favorite map of the three, but it does have one of my favorite environmental features so far: a spinning, four-piece circular wall in the center of the map. During modes like hardpoint, the hardpoint will spawn in that area and people take turns either hiding behind or popping out from those spinning walls. It adds an extra layer of unpredictability when you're trying to hold an objective that I really like. You can't just lay prone with a sniper and peek around a corner, because the corner moves. That being said, there are a pair of lookouts on either side, so you can keep watch of the objective or just pick people off as they try to bumrush it. It's great. Even in deathmatch or Kill Confirmed it's fun, but it's really cool for Hardpoint and Domination.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The Forge has one of my favorite environmental features.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">According to the official BLOPS7 blog, there's a fourth map, Imprint. Either I've just had terrible RNG luck or they haven't actually turned that one on yet, because I haven’t seen it so far. I'm going to play the hell out of BLOPS7 over the weekend, so that could change.</p><h2 data-cy="title2">Guns and Guns</h2><p data-cy="paragraph">Once you unlock all the level requirements, there are a total of 16 available guns. Right now, and I hope Treyarch is reading this, the M10 Breacher, the default shotgun, is stupidly overpowered. You can nail enemies from way farther away than the laws of physics should allow right out of the gate, and they'll fall down dead when you do so. You barely need to aim it to get a kill across a large room. That sort of shotgun behavior is fine, even expected, at close range, or when you've leveled up and thrown a bunch of attachments on it. But as a default gun, it's just too powerful.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">On the flip side, and this is something I never expected I'd say, but the XR-3 ION sniper rifle is exactly where it should be, power wise. Usually I feel like sniper rifles lean toward being way too OP. Don't get me wrong, I still hate snipers, and I still think people who use snipers on small maps are weak and their bloodlines are weak. But when you get a kill with the XR-3 it feels earned. There's a level of finesse here I'm not accustomed to with previous sniper rifle iterations, and I've actually used it without feeling like a dirty sniperboy. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">I've always loved SMGs in Call of Duty, but none of the three available this year are doing it for me as of yet. They feel a tad too weak, which is usually the case, but it's generally made up for by a high rate of fire and lighting-fast speed of handling. I'm going to have to wait and see on the SMGs until progress is fully unlocked, but for right now, they don't feel quite like they should, as if it takes one or two bullets more than I’d expect to down an opponent. I also don't love the LMG, the Mk. 78. Similarly to the SMGs, it feels like it takes a millisecond or two too long to effectively down an enemy. I'm going to need more time with that one as well to see how it ends up running when it's fully kitted out, but for right now I'm not feeling it at all.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>The Assault Rifles this year are, much like last year, where it's at.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The Assault Rifles this year are, much like last year, where it's at. While in previous years I ran with SMGs or LMGs, in BLOPS6 I fell madly in love with my XM4 assault rifle. This year I've been grinding on the M15 MOD 0, but I'm a level away from unlocking the Peacekeeper Mk.1 in the beta, which might be the best weapon in multiplayer, hands down. At Call of Duty Next, it felt like everyone was using it, so I’m excited to try it out again from the comfort of my own desk. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">I've got an entire weekend with the closed beta, and I plan to hit that level cap and unlock as much as it will let me. The open beta next week will let you grind to level 30, and the best part is all your progress will carry over to the final game. I'm hoping CoD keeps to its promises, because the new features sound pretty sick: trading loadouts with friends and even copying them from enemies who killed you, XP carrying across all modes instead of on a per-mode basis, and the ability to re-roll the daily challenges, which I love. Also, the final game promises some of the sweetest gun camos yet, and I'm really excited to spend hours and hours of time I'll never get back just so I can have a gun that's all shiny. Until then, I'm really enjoying BLOPS7, and I’ll be back with a full review around launch.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Seth Macy is Senior Social Commerce Producer, and just wants to be your friend. You can find him online.</p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-7-multiplayer-review]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Video Games You Should Play This Weekend – October 3, 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://gameinformer.com/opinions/2025/10/03/the-video-games-you-should-play-this-weekend-october-3-2025</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-video-games-you-should-play-this-weekend-%E2%80%93-october-3-2025.1316272/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div property="schema:text"><p>No matter how you look at it, this was a wild week for the games industry. Electronic Arts, the massive publisher behind multiple sports franchises and BioWare games, has been acquired for $55 billion by an investment consortium that includes the Public Investment Fund of Saudi Arabia; Xbox announced it was overhauling Xbox Game Pass Ultimate and increasing its price by 50%; and Harmonix announced it is delisting Rock Band 4 this Sunday, meaning you only have two days left to buy it before it's gone forever.&nbsp;</p><p>But amidst all that news, <em>Game Informer </em>published reviews for EA Sports FC 26 and Hotel Barcelona, and...we launched The Outer Worlds 2 digital issue!! However, it's Friday and that means it's time for the weekend!</p><p>Like last Friday and the Friday before that and maybe the one before that, too, we're back to give you a selection of games we think you should play this weekend! If you check any of these out, or have suggestions of your own, let us know in the comment section below! Without further ado...</p><h2>Hey Listen*</h2>










<article data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="56a59d53-51be-42d6-bc80-675c9523c0d0" data-embed-button="image_browser_uploader" data-entity-embed-display="image:responsive_image" data-entity-embed-display-settings="{&quot;responsive_image_style&quot;:&quot;content_body&quot;,&quot;image_loading&quot;:{&quot;attribute&quot;:&quot;lazy&quot;},&quot;image_link&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_url&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;link_target&quot;:0,&quot;link_original&quot;:0,&quot;image_source&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_source&quot;:0,&quot;image_caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;embed_caption&quot;:0,&quot;content_warning&quot;:0}" data-langcode="en">

	
    <picture>
                  <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/body_default/public/2025/09/12/b9ba4afa/navi.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 851px)" type="image/webp" width="800" height="450">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/09/12/b9ba4afa/navi.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (min-width: 315px) and (max-width: 450px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
              <source srcset="https://gameinformer.com/sites/default/files/styles/content_default_mobile_/public/2025/09/12/b9ba4afa/navi.jpg.webp 1x" media="all and (max-width: 314px)" type="image/webp" width="450" height="253">
                  

  </picture>






</article>
<h3>*Read</h3><p>Below, we'll list the names of <em>Game Informer </em>editors and their thoughts for this week's edition of &nbsp;The Video Games You Should Be Playing This Weekend (official name <em>still </em>pending – naming things is hard, okay?).</p></div></div><br/><br/>https://gameinformer.com/opinions/2025/10/03/the-video-games-you-should-play-this-weekend-october-3-2025]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia’s Strategy Is Working Because Of Greed And Cynicism]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-ea-saudi-arabia-riyadh-comedians</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/saudi-arabia%E2%80%99s-strategy-is-working-because-of-greed-and-cynicism.1316269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>You do not love to see it, but it’s been a big week for Saudi Arabia, the <a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2025/08/11/saudi-arabia-executions-surge-in-2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">human rights abuse factory</a> that in recent years has taken to cosplaying as a cultural hub. Wielding checks that would probably turn the eyes of any normal person into Looney Tunes dollar signs, <a href="https://defector.com/grim-visions-emerge-from-the-riyadh-comedy-festival" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Riyadh Comedy Festival</a> has attracted the likes of Dave Chapelle, Louis CK, and even noted Guy Everybody Thought Wasn’t A Shithead Bill Burr. And of course, a consortium including Saudi Arabia <a href="https://aftermath.site/the-ea-sale-is-bad-news-for-everyone" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">purchased EA for $55 billion</a>. The one thing all these parties have in common? Deep, unabiding cynicism. On the latest Aftermath Hours, we talk about that.</p><p>This time around, we discuss the two latest signs that the video game industry is being chopped up and sold for parts: EA’s $55 billion sale and <a href="https://aftermath.site/microsoft-xbox-game-pass-price-increase" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Microsoft’s decision to up Game Pass’ price by 50 percent</a> – the latter of which follows <a href="https://aftermath.site/microsoft-layoffs-xbox-game-pass-unsustainable" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">multiple rounds of layoffs and studio closures</a> almost certainly intended to help pay for the company’s own $68.7 billion purchase of Activision Blizzard.&nbsp;</p><p>Who benefits from any of this, aside from executives and, now, a government that seeks to sportswash human rights abuses via not just sports themselves, but also some of the biggest video games about those sports? And what, really, is left of these once-unshakable juggernauts even before they <em>really </em>go through the most vicious iteration yet of the profit-ravenous meat grinder?&nbsp;</p><p>Then we discuss <em>Baby Steps</em>, a literal walking simulator about masculinity that Chris absolutely adores. Finally, we invent new candy bars, including, unfortunately, Dubai Twix.&nbsp;</p><p>You can find this week's episode below and on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/7qtlX6MNeEoyNuHBU0chUJ?si=a2f12b75911f43cb" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Spotify</a>, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/aftermath-hours/id1727407094" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Apple</a>, or wherever else you prefer to listen to podcasts. If you like what you hear, make sure to leave a review so that we can buy EA for $56 billion, get the old Maxis team back together, and forc– er, politely ask them to make <em>The Sims 5</em>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Here’s an excerpt from our conversation (edited for length and clarity):</p><p><strong>Gita: </strong>Bill Burr is the person that came the closest to having a reasonable throughline, but even he comes off as wildly racist, so it doesn’t matter.</p><p><strong>Nathan:</strong> Racist and also incredibly naive in a way that his entire persona does not seem to otherwise betray.</p><p><strong>Gita:</strong> Exactly. It’s like, man, you’re just dumb. If this is true, you’re just a dumb guy.</p><p><strong>Nathan: </strong>Yeah, but I don’t buy that. I don’t think he’s dumb. I think the check was so big that he was like “Alright, I’m gonna pretend to be someone else for a little bit.”</p><p><strong>Chris: </strong>They drove a truck of money to my house. I’m not made of stone.</p><p><strong>Nathan: </strong>Here are the quotes [from <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2025/sep/30/riyadh-comedy-festival-saudi-arabia" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a Guardian article about comedians’ decision to perform in Saudi Arabia</a>]. This shit’s nuts:</p><p>“Some comics were transparent about their willingness to ignore their moral convictions in order to play at the festival. ‘So what, they have slaves?’ asked Tim Dillon in a podcast segment that led to his firing from the festival. ‘They’re paying me enough money to look the other way.’ Pete Davidson offered a similar take, acknowledging in a chat with Von that people have asked him why, given his father’s death on 9/11, he would take a paycheck from the Saudi government. He did not address the criticism directly, but he did suggest he was happy to forget 9/11 for the right price: ‘I just know I get the routing, and then I see the number, and I go, I’ll go.’”</p><p><strong>Gita:</strong> It’s not “never forget” anymore. It’s “conditionally forget.”</p><p><strong>Chris:</strong> Now how many zeroes are we talking about?</p><p><strong>Nathan:</strong> This one knocked my brain out of my head:</p><p>“[Chris] Distefano, chatting with Halkias, joked that an upside to the kingdom’s repression of women is that his fiancee can’t come with him. Mark Normand, on the other hand, joked he would bring his wife to show her how good she has it in America: ‘I want to be like: You see? You think I’m an asshole? Well, they’ll cut your clit off, bitch.’’”</p><p>That’s a thing somebody said! That’s a thing somebody said publicly!</p><p><strong>Chris:</strong> Don’t do that! Don’t use those words.</p><p><strong>Gita: </strong>I don’t like that.</p><p><strong>Nathan:</strong> Absolutely insane. But the Saudi strategy is serving its purpose. I’m not sure it's ever gonna see the light of day because these things are really difficult to source, but I’ve been working with my former Washington Post colleague <a href="https://www.readergrev.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mikhail</a> on a piece about how much streamers and now also commentators were paid to be involved with the Esports World Cup, which is the Saudi government’s annual esports event. The numbers I’ve heard are big but not that big.</p><p>But the telling thing I heard from one of my conversations with a prominent <em>League of Legends</em> commentator is that this year they felt like one of the final holdouts. Last year, a lot of people in that scene took a principled stand and said “I’m not gonna engage with this. I’m not gonna take the money.” And this year there are just so many fewer that did that. Most of them took the money, and it’s been increasingly normalized in esports, as it has in all these other places. Money plus persistence wears people down.</p></div><div><h2>Stay in touch</h2><p>Sign up for our free newsletter</p></div><div><h2><span>More from Aftermath</span></h2><div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/wayward-netflix-martin"><h3>Wayward Is A Queer Exploration Of The Troubled Teen Industry</h3></a><p>Mae Martin's new Netflix show creates a *very* creepy small town</p></div><div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/candy-crush-saga-lawsuit-alleged-scam-tournament-king"><h3>Candy Crush Player Sues Activision Blizzard Over Alleged ‘Scam’ Tournament</h3></a><p>He says King tricked players into thinking they have a chance at the grand prize</p></div></div><a tabindex="0" href="https://aftermath.site/all">See all posts<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="#000" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><path d="M5 12h13m-6-7 7 7-7 7"></path></svg></a></div></div><br/><br/>https://aftermath.site/aftermath-hours-podcast-ea-saudi-arabia-riyadh-comedians]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pillars Of Eternity II And More Pulled From Stores After Unity Reveals Years-Old Security Exploit]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/unity-exploit-update-obsidian-pillars-eternity-2-removed-steam-2000631633</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pillars-of-eternity-ii-and-more-pulled-from-stores-after-unity-reveals-years-old-security-exploit.1316251/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Obsidian Entertainment is pulling&nbsp;<em>Pillars of Eternity II: Deadfire</em>, <em>Pentiment</em>, and more from Steam and other digital storefronts on Friday after Unity, the game engine used to make them, was revealed to have a years-old security flaw. The company behind it is now urging developers to update their games to avoid any issues.</p> <p>“A security vulnerability was identified that affects games and applications built on Unity versions 2017.1 and later for Android, Windows, Linux, and macOS operating systems,” former Xbox mascot Larry “Major Nelson” Hryb wrote on the <a href="https://discussions.unity.com/t/unity-platform-protection-take-immediate-action-to-protect-your-games-and-apps/1688031">Unity forum</a> earlier today. “There is no evidence of any exploitation of the vulnerability, nor has there been any impact on users or customers.”</p>

 <p>Hryb added that the company “proactively provided fixes that address the vulnerability, and they are already available to all developers” and is encouraging all of them to update their products as soon as possible. Windows, Steam, and others already implemented fixes at the platform level today. Now some studios are taking their games down while they get them patched. One of them is<em> Grounded 2</em> maker Obsidian Entertainment.</p>

 <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>A security vulnerability affecting our games that use Unity has recently been identified.&nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;As a precaution and to keep you safe, we have temporarily removed the following titles and products from digital storefronts while we implement the necessary updates to address the issue:…</p></div> <p>— Obsidian (@Obsidian) <a href="https://twitter.com/Obsidian/status/1974215697845923976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 3, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>“As a precaution and to keep you safe, we have temporarily removed the following titles and products from digital storefronts while we implement the necessary updates to address the issue,” it <a href="https://x.com/Obsidian/status/1974215697845923976">wrote</a> on X. In addition to <em>Pillars of Eternity II: Deadfire</em> and <em>Pentiment</em>, it also includes certain versions of <em>Grounded 2</em> and <em>Avowed</em> which include artbooks made with Unity.</p>

 <p>“We apologize for any inconvenience this may cause,” the studio wrote. “Our team is working on a fix and will restore these games as soon as possible. We will provide additional information once they are available again. We also encourage players who have already downloaded these games to update them as soon as a patch becomes available.”</p> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Hey everyone,</p> <p>We’ve rolled out a quick patch to address the Unity security vulnerability.</p> <p>Your saves and gameplay are safe! Just hit update and you’re covered.  And if you haven’t joined yet, No Rest for the Wicked is 30% off on Steam right now. This is the perfect moment to…</p> <p>— No Rest for the Wicked (@wickedgame) <a href="https://twitter.com/wickedgame/status/1974169075405533675?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 3, 2025</a></p></blockquote>  <p>Other developers have also started rolling out updates, some without temporarily removing their games from digital store shelves. <em>Pillars of Eternity II: Deadfire</em> and <em>Pentiment</em>, both great games, were currently discounted for <a href="https://kotaku.com/steam-fall-autumn-sale-2025-best-biggest-cheapest-deals-games-pc-steamdeck-2000629959">Steam’s autumn sale</a>. Hopefully, they’re back soon.</p>
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/unity-exploit-update-obsidian-pillars-eternity-2-removed-steam-2000631633]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>