<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 17:48:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iconic MMO Wizard101 To Be Released on Console]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/iconic-mmo-wizard101-to-be-released-on-console/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/iconic-mmo-wizard101-to-be-released-on-console.967578/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/iconic-mmo-wizard101-to-be-released-on-console/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Wizard101 is one of the <a href="https://www.wizard101.com/?utm_source=%C3%9CberStrategist+PR+List+-+Leading+Gaming+and+Tech+News+%282023%29&amp;utm_campaign=71122f979a-EMAIL_CAMPAIGN_2024_08_22_05_15_COPY_01&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_term=0_-9e9ced9085-%5BLIST_EMAIL_ID%5D" target="_blank" rel="noopener">most iconic MMOs</a> out there. It is set to be released on all console platforms, including PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X|S, and Nintendo Switch. This release comes after its first release on PC in 2008, making the game a whopping 16 years old.</p>
<p>If you've wanted to get stuck into an <a href="https://wccftech.com/fellowship-is-a-co-op-multiplayer-game-focused-on-mmo-like-dungeon-runs/">MMO</a> that takes you through a magical school with deckbuilding and strategic turn-based combat, Wizard101 is the way to go. There are over 20 magical worlds for players to explore, all with unique traits that make them memorable and special. You get to play as a student wizard, where you'll have to go on your journey, completing quests and meeting new people in bustling worlds full of active players. The game will also be fully voice-acted, giving each quest that personal touch.</p>
<p>Additionally, if you've been wanting to introduce your friends to this MMO but they are all on console, console users will share a server, allowing those on PlayStation, Xbox and Nintendo Switch to all play with each other via crossplay.</p>
<p>To celebrate the release of Wizard101 on console, they have released a short 26-second trailer to get dedicated players excited about finally being able to play the game on console, as well as players who don't have access to a PC being able to play it on console for the first time.</p>
<p><iframe title="Wizard101 Official Console Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PdH0cSINQlA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>At the moment, there isn't a set release date for when Wizard101 will be available on console, and KingsIsle Entertainment has yet to announce it. While Wizard101 has been around for a while, it was only added to Steam in 2018, with it being a much more efficient way of running the game.</p>
<p>Even though the game is relatively old, there are still millions of players getting stuck into Wizard101 regularly, and the game is home to over a thousand hours of questing to be done. This doesn't include the battles players can participate in, where they can participate in 1v1 duels or team-based battles to try and get a space on the leaderboard.</p>
<p>This MMO is still home to weekly rewards, praising players for their dedication to the game and rewarding them for their time and effort spent completing challenges set out for them in-game, with the events of Wizard101 rotating weekly to provide as much variety as possible for the players.</p>


				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shinji Mikami 'Surprised' To Learn Capcom Fans Want More Dino Crisis]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-creator-mikami-dino-crisis-capcom-monhun-1851635867</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/shinji-mikami-surprised-to-learn-capcom-fans-want-more-dino-crisis.967575/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/resident-evil-creator-mikami-dino-crisis-capcom-monhun-1851635867<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/shinji-mikami-tango-gameworks-evil-within-ghostwire-1850150056&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/shinji-mikami-tango-gameworks-evil-within-ghostwire-1850150056">Shinji Mikami</a></span>, the famous creator behind <em>Resident Evil </em>and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/exoprimal-dino-crisis-reboot-sequel-dinosaur-shooter-ca-1849066060&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/exoprimal-dino-crisis-reboot-sequel-dinosaur-shooter-ca-1849066060"><em>Dino Crisis</em></a></span>, doesn’t seem to think the world needs a new<em> Dino Crisis</em> game because <em>Monster Hunter</em> has “really nailed down” dinosaur action.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196790" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Why Everybody Hates This Dragon's Dogma 2 NPC" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="142" data-playlist="196790,194066,195027" data-current="196790"><div><p>Why Everybody Hates This Dragon's Dogma 2 NPC</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196790/196790_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196790/196790_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196790/196790_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196790/196790_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22347.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The last <em>Dino Crisis </em>game was released back in 2003 and it wasn’t a fan favorite. In the many years since, a lot of players have asked, even begged Capcom to make a new <em>Dino Crisis </em>game, or to at least remaster the original 1999 game, which was a tense survival horror game featuring dangerous dinosaurs. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/capcom-survey-dino-crisis-sequel-remake-onimusha-okami-1851235768&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/capcom-survey-dino-crisis-sequel-remake-onimusha-okami-1851235768">In a 2023 survey from Capcom</a></span> asking fans about what franchises should get new games, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.eurogamer.net/dino-crisis-is-the-series-most-capcom-fans-want-to-see-get-a-new-game&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dino-crisis-is-the-series-most-capcom-fans-want-to-see-get-a-new-game" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Dino Crisis </em>won it handily.</a></span> And yet, Mikami seemed surprised people still care about the series in 2024. </p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.eurogamer.net/no-space-for-dino-crisis-when-monster-hunter-exists-says-shinji-mikami&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/no-space-for-dino-crisis-when-monster-hunter-exists-says-shinji-mikami" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">In an interview with <em>Eurogamer </em>during Gamescom</a></span>, Mikami was told fans desperately wanted more <em>Dino Crisis</em> and he replied, “I’m very surprised to hear that.” He then elaborated, explaining that in his mind <em>Monster Hunter </em>offers plenty of dino action. </p><p>“The awesomeness of dinosaurs and the stuff you can do with dinosaurs, that’s been kind of really nailed down by <em>Monster Hunter</em> in recent years,” said Mikami. <br></p><p>“So even if I were to decide to make a remake or [create a] new version of <em>Dino Crisis,</em> I don’t really feel like there’s a whole lot of space for that kind of game right now, just since <em>Monster Hunter</em> has become such a big game. But yeah, it is surprising.”</p><p>When <em>Eurogamer </em>pointed out the existence of <em>Exoprimal</em>, a video game released in 2023 by Capcom that also featured dinos, Mikami said it was “pretty different” from <em>Dino Crisis</em>, but added: “I guess the fans got their expectations up, but here we are.”</p><p>Currently, Mikami is running his own independent game studio, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/shinji-mikami-founds-new-studio-kamuy-inc-&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/shinji-mikami-founds-new-studio-kamuy-inc-" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KAMUY</a></span>, after <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/shinji-mikami-tango-gameworks-evil-within-ghostwire-1850150056&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/shinji-mikami-tango-gameworks-evil-within-ghostwire-1850150056">leaving the last one he helped create in 2023</a></span>.</p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space Marine 2 Crossplay Details Announced]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/space-marine-2-crossplay-details-announced/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/space-marine-2-crossplay-details-announced.967554/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/space-marine-2-crossplay-details-announced/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The details surrounding crossplay in Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 have been announced a week before the game’s launch.</p>



<p>Developer Saber Interactive published their <a href="https://community.focus-entmt.com/focus-entertainment/space-marine-2/blogs/68-august-community-update" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">August Community Update</a> on Thursday, and with it came everything you need to know about how crossplay will work in Space Marine 2.</p>







<p>From launch day, Space Marine 2 will support “full crossplay” between PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, Steam, and Epic Games Store (EGS).</p>



<p>“You will be able to play the Campaign and PvE modes without any restriction,” the developers say. </p>



<p>When it comes to the PvP mode Eternal War, Saber Interactive says that things have to be split for “fairness and balancing purposes.</p>



<p>“[Crossplay] will be split between PC players in one pool (Steam &amp; EGS) and console players in the other one (PlayStation 5 &amp; Xbox Series X|S),” they said.</p>



<p>Lastly, players will have the ability to disable crossplay entirely should they only want to play with those on the same platform.</p>



<p>Warhammer 40,000: Space Marine 2 releases on September 6.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out the full details of the latest <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-college-football-25-title-update-released/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Title Update for EA Sports College Football 25</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for the Insider Gaming Wrap Up</a>, a once-a-week newsletter with exclusive columns, interviews, and more.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bloodless coming to Switch in 2024]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/bloodless-coming-to-switch-in-2024</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/bloodless-coming-to-switch-in-2024.967551/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/bloodless-coming-to-switch-in-2024<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>PC version out today.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > 3D Realms [75 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/saber-interactive/3d-realms">3D Realms</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Point N' Sheep [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/point-n-sheep">Point N’ Sheep</a> will release a <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,908 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> version of retro-style <a title="Genres > Action [2,129 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/action">action</a> <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,723 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure game</a> <em><a title="Games > Bloodless [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/bloodless">Bloodless</a></em> in 2024, the companies announced. <span id="more-911129"></span></p><p>The PC version of <em>Bloodless</em> launched via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1592490/Bloodless/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> today for $14.99, with an additional 15 percent-off launch discount available during the first week.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1592490/Bloodless/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Bloodless</em> is a retro stylish, action adventure featuring fast-paced combat staged at the atmospheric lands of Bakugawa. Help ronin Tomoe to confront ghosts of her past to end the reign of violence of Shogun Akechi, her former master.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <ul><li><strong>Precise Combat</strong> – Fight to disarm your old allies, Akechi’s samurai army, with nothing but your bare fists using Tomoe’s signature dash-counter mechanic. <a title="Companies > Enhance [31 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/enhance">Enhance</a> your abilities by drinking infusions of herbs scattered around the land.</li><li><strong>Moody Environments</strong> – Explore the sacred nature and suffered districts of Bakugawa, where its society lives under a violent and corrupt military regime, isolated from the world and shattered by the terrors of its past wars.</li><li><strong>Emotional Storytelling</strong> – Even as a coward and deserter through the eyes of her own people, ronin Tomoe returns to her former land after witnessing all the blood that a blade can shed, hoping to spark the hope and courage Bakugawa needs to fight back its violent political methods.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PC Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="BLOODLESS Trailer - Release Date Announcement" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/knzkSt-_Zcc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy partners with Annapurna for Control 2 and potential film and TV adaptations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/29/24231469/control-sequel-movie-tv-remedy-annapurna</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-partners-with-annapurna-for-control-2-and-potential-film-and-tv-adaptations.967536/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/29/24231469/control-sequel-movie-tv-remedy-annapurna<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article id="content"><div><div><div><h2>Remedy partners with Annapurna for Control 2 and potential film and TV adaptations</h2><p><span><span> / </span><h2>Annapurna will fund 50 percent of the sequel’s development and ‘will acquire an option to television, film, and selected audiovisual licensing rights’ for both Control and Alan Wake.</h2></span></p></div><div><p><span>By</span> <span><span></span> <span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-webster">Andrew Webster</a></span><span>, <span>an entertainment editor covering streaming, virtual worlds, and every single Pokémon video game. Andrew joined The Verge in 2012, writing over 4,000 stories.</span></span></span></p><p><time datetime="2024-08-29T16:43:00.081Z"> <!-- -->Aug 29, 2024, 4:43 PM UTC</time></p><div><h2>Share this story</h2></div></div></div><div><figure><span><span></span></span><div><figcaption>Control<em>.</em></figcaption> <p><cite>Image: Remedy Entertainment</cite></p></div></figure></div></div><div><div><p>Remedy Entertainment is teaming up with Annapurna Pictures to expand the world of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/26/20832997/control-review-creators-thriller-ps4-xbox-pc"><em>Control</em></a>. The most concrete part of the news is that Annapurna — which also has an indie game publishing arm — will be funding half of the development budget for <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/11/11/23453049/control-2-sequel-remedy-entertainment">the previously announced <em>Control 2</em></a>.</p><p>Beyond that, there’s the potential for Annapurna to create film and TV adaptations of both <em>Control</em> and <em>Alan Wake</em>, which <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23934662/alan-wake-2-review-ps5-xbox-pc">just got a long-awaited sequel last year</a>. No specific projects were announced. “Annapurna will take the lead in expanding <em>Control</em> and <em>Alan Wake</em> into new entertainment mediums,” <a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/announcements/remedy-entertainment-plc-inside-information-remedy-and-annapurna-announce-a-strategic-partnership-agreement-on-control-2-and-bringing-control-and-alan-wake-to-film-and-television/">the companies explain in a press release</a>, “enabling Remedy to focus on the development of <em>Control 2</em> and other upcoming games.”</p><p>Notably, the release also says that “Remedy will retain the full IP rights for <em>Control</em> and <em>Alan Wake</em>.” (The studio <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/28/24085807/remedy-is-now-in-control">purchased the rights for <em>Control</em></a> from publisher 505 Games earlier this year.)</p><div><p>Remedy has some track record with sneaking live-action moments into its games, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/4/1/11340794/quantum-break-review-xbox-one-time-travel">2016’s <em>Quantum Break</em> was an interesting exercise in merging TV and gaming</a>. The studio’s games — <em>Control </em>and <em>Alan Wake</em> included — are also heavily influenced by film and TV, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23906355/david-lynch-video-games">most notably the works of David Lynch</a>. So the expansion into these mediums makes a lot of sense, particularly as the various worlds of entertainment <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24126474/fallout-review-amazon-prime-video">continue</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23543145/hbo-the-last-of-us-review">to</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23669598/super-mario-bros-movie-review">crossover</a>.</p></div><p>“The future of storytelling requires seamlessly integrating gaming, film, and television,” Annapurna CEO Megan Ellison explained in a statement, “and this partnership will allow us to explore new ways of bringing these narratives to life.”</p></div><div><p>Most Popular</p><p>Most Popular</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/28/24230321/microsoft-windows-11-update-ryzen-cpu-performance-improvement"><h2>Ryzen CPU owners can now download better gaming performance thanks to a Windows 11 update</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/28/24230404/brilliant-nextgen-smart-home-company-buyers"><h2>Brilliant is back from the brink</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/28/24230490/google-custom-ai-chatbots-gems-launch"><h2>Google’s custom AI chatbots have arrived</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/26/24223957/apple-iphone-16-launch-event-date-glowtime"><h2>Apple’s iPhone 16 launch event is set for September</h2></a><hr></li><li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/24230628/star-wars-outlaws-review-ps5-xbox-pc"><h2>Star Wars Outlaws is a perfectly fine open-world game set in an incredible universe</h2></a><hr></li></ol></div></div></article></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Corsair Unveils New Ultrawide Monitor, The XENEON 34 QD-OLED]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/corsair-unveils-new-ultrawide-monitor/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/corsair-unveils-new-ultrawide-monitor-the-xeneon-34-qd-oled.967518/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/corsair-unveils-new-ultrawide-monitor/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Corsair has unveiled its new Ultrawide curved monitor, the XENEON 34 QD-OLED. </p>



<p>Retailing <a href="https://www.corsair.com/us/en/p/monitors/CM-9030005-NA/xeneon-34wqhd240-c-qd-oled-gaming-monitor-34-inch-3440-x-1440-wqhd-1800r-curvature-240hz-0-03ms-gtg-displayhdr-true-black-400-1-5m1-contrast-ratio-cm-9030005-na" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">for $1,199.99</a>, this new monitor has a 34-inch WQHD screen size featuring an 1800R Curve Quantum Dot OLED Display. It also has a 0.03ms response time with a 240Hz refresh rate.</p>



<p>“QD-OLED enhances response times and refresh rates, making the XENEON 34 QD-OLED an ideal partner for high-speed gameplay, whether it’s racing, FPS, or action games,” Corsair says. “With a refresh rate of up to 240Hz combined with an impressive response time of up to 0.03ms (GtG), the image on screen reacts to inputs faster than you can perceive.”</p>



<p>The monitor also includes support for both Nvidia G-Sync and AMD FreeSync Premium.</p>



<p>The rear of the monitor features a number of I/O ports. Those include two HDMI 2.1, DisplayPort 1.4, USB-C 3.1 DP ALT with 65W PD, USB-C 3.1 DP Upstream with 15W PD, four USB-A 3.1 with KVM, and a 3.5mm headphone jack. As far as on-screen display is concerned, that is activated by placing your hand near the bottom of the monitor.</p>



<p>Lastly, the monitor has burn-in prevention features like “an image retention refresh after eight hours of use and an Orbit feature that shifts the entire image by one pixel every three minutes”. </p>



<figure></figure>



<hr>



<p>Are you going to pick up Corsair’s new Ultrawide curved monitor? For more Insider Gaming tech, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/category/tech/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">check out our Tech Hub</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 Will Seemingly Usurp Baldur's Gate 3 as the Game With the Longest Script]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-will-seemingly-usurp-baldurs-gate-3-as-the-game-with-the-longest-script</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-will-seemingly-usurp-baldurs-gate-3-as-the-game-with-the-longest-script.967515/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-will-seemingly-usurp-baldurs-gate-3-as-the-game-with-the-longest-script<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/baldurs-gate-iii">Baldur's Gate 3</a> currently holds the world record for the video game with the longest script, but <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a> will seemingly take that award for itself when it launches in 2025.</p><p>Dan Vávra, co founder and creative director at Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 developer Warhorse Studios, said on <a href="https://x.com/DanielVavra/status/1829121370845773942" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter</a> that the game script currently totals 2.2 million words. Baldur's Gate 3 developer Larian Studios said on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1086940/view/3657534571513526776" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam</a> its game totalled "roughly 2,000,000 words" at launch, meaning Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 could be the new champ.</p><p>"Yesterday, we were counting with our lead designer Prokop Jirsa how much we actually wrote for KCD2," Vávra said. "So guess how big the script is? 2,200,000 words! Or 11,000 typical screenwriting pages. That's a 100 scripts for a typical two-hour movie, or about 25 average novels."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 - Gamescom 2024 Screenshots</h3></div></output><p>Some further context sees Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 come in at almost four times the length of famously long novel War and Peace by Leo Tolstoy, which sits at 587,287 words long, and all the A Song of Ice and Fire books combined, which total 1,736,054 words from A Game of Thrones to A Dance With Dragons.</p><p>All those words seemingly come at a cost, however, as Warhorse recently announced <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-delayed-to-february-2025">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2 has been delayed</a> from 2024 to February 11, 2025.</p><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/02/17/kingdom-come-deliverance-review">In IGN's 8/10 review of the original</a>, we said: "Kingdom Come: Deliverance is an RPG that does the medieval era right with a refreshingly small-scale story and strong realistic combat."</p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Has a New Feature Fans Are Saying Will Get People Banned or Make Them Go Viral — or Both]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-has-a-new-feature-fans-are-saying-will-get-people-banned-or-make-them-go-viral-or-both</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-has-a-new-feature-fans-are-saying-will-get-people-banned-or-make-them-go-viral-%E2%80%94-or-both.967509/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-has-a-new-feature-fans-are-saying-will-get-people-banned-or-make-them-go-viral-or-both<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">What could possibly go wrong?</h2></div><section><p>Amid the cacophony caused by Call of Duty Next, one new <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/call-of-duty-black-ops-6">Black Ops 6</a> feature flew under the radar — but it could end up as the most impactful of all.</p><p>Black Ops 6, out October 25, 2024, has a new Body Shield feature in multiplayer that lets you grab an enemy and hold them in front of you to soak up bullets, while firing off a few rounds of your own.</p><p>We’ve seen a body shield feature in plenty of shooters over the years, but what developer Treyarch has done here is enabled voice chat between the attacker and the victim.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>We heard you and can confirm that the Body Shield feature in Multiplayer will enable voice chat between the attacker and victim. </p><p>Be nice... <a href="https://t.co/KxyaDo7bAc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/KxyaDo7bAc</a></p></div>— Treyarch Studios (@Treyarch) <a href="https://twitter.com/Treyarch/status/1828884563986395607?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 28, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>“Be nice…” the studio tweeted, perhaps in hope more than expectation.</p><p>As you’d expect from the notoriously toxic Call of Duty community, reaction is a mix of disbelief and excitement. Disbelief in that some can’t believe Treyarch actually added voice chat to the feature knowing full well the toxicity it will probably enable, excitement in that some are delighted Treyarch actually added voice chat to the feature knowing full well the toxicity it will probably enable.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>You will be able to use Proximity Chat against players you turn into a human shield in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackOps6?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#BlackOps6</a></p><p>Imagine getting turned to a human shield and they start whispering in your ear. <a href="https://t.co/p4LjGHWNEf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/p4LjGHWNEf</a></p></div>— Tridzo (@Tridzo) <a href="https://twitter.com/Tridzo/status/1828896487004373038?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 28, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>And already there are fears that what’s said during Body Shield might end up getting you banned, if Activision’s AI-powered voice chat moderation picks up something it deems in breach of its rules. <strong>“</strong>What could go wrong?” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/blackops6/comments/1f3sdyo/comment/lkgg919/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wondered redditor Evisra over on the Black Ops 6 subreddit</a>. A lot, most fans seem to predict.</p><p>Call of Duty sort of has this feature already in Warzone. In that game, The battle royale spin-off enables voice chat for deaths, so players can hear their opponent scream into the mic when they’re killed. This Body Shield feature for Black Ops 6, however, feels altogether more intimate.</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/08/29/cod-bo6-needtoknowbeta-012-1724941507665.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: Activision Publishing.</figcaption></figure></output><p>Anyone who’s played Call of Duty multiplayer recently will know that there tends not to be much voice chat going on. Most play with their mic off, or are in a party chat with their friends. With this feature, Black Ops 6 might change that.</p><p>Check out <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/call-of-duty-next-everything-announced-for-black-ops-6-and-warzone">everything announced at Call of Duty Next</a> to find out what else is coming from the world of Call of Duty, including information about <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/verdansk-is-finally-returning-to-call-of-duty-warzone-and-fans-are-delighted">the return of Verdansk to Warzone</a>. We also reported on <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/world-first-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-nuke-achieved-before-the-beta-even-launches">the world first Black Ops 6 nuke</a>, which one player managed to get before the beta even launched.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CD Projekt Has Fun Over Cyberpunk Stars Keanu Reeves and Idris Elba Appearing in Sonic 3 Together]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/cd-projekt-has-fun-over-cyberpunk-stars-keanu-reeves-and-idris-elba-appearing-in-sonic-3-together</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cd-projekt-has-fun-over-cyberpunk-stars-keanu-reeves-and-idris-elba-appearing-in-sonic-3-together.967506/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/cd-projekt-has-fun-over-cyberpunk-stars-keanu-reeves-and-idris-elba-appearing-in-sonic-3-together<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/movies/sonic-the-hedgehog-3">Sonic the Hedgehog 3</a> stars Cyberpunk 2077's most famous actors in Keanu Reeves and Idris Elba, and developer CD Projekt is loving it.</p><p>Using its <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/cyberpunk-2077">Cyberpunk 2077</a> X/Twitter account, CD Projekt replied to a post from the Sonic the Hedgehog account sharing <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/first-sonic-the-hedgehog-3-trailer-reveals-keanu-reeves-shadow-dr-robotniks-father-and-a-whole-bunch-more">the first trailer for Sonic the Hedgehog 3</a>. "Remember Knuckles and Shadow's first meeting? In Dogtown," it said.</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Remember Knuckles and Shadow's first meeting? In Dogtown 🔥</p>— Cyberpunk 2077 (@CyberpunkGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/CyberpunkGame/status/1828447271530164298?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">August 27, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 features the regular cast of anthropomorphic beasties such as Tales and, of course, Sonic himself, but also features Knuckles and the brand new character of Shadow. These latter two will be familiar to fans of Cyberpunk 2077, as <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/knuckles-sonic-spinoff-paramount-plus-announcement">Knuckles is voiced by Elba</a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-the-hedgehog-movie-seemingly-foreshadowed-keanu-reeves-involvement">Shadow is voiced by Reeves</a>.</p><p>Both previously starred as the most recognisable faces in Cyberpunk 2077. Reeves plays the personality inside protagonist V's mind, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cyberpunk-2077-now-features-the-sad-keanu-reeves-meme">terrorist rocker Johnny Silverhand</a>, while <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/cd-projekt-spent-roughly-125-million-turning-cyberpunk-2077-around-post-launch">Elba plays secret agent Solomon Reed</a> in expansion Phantom Liberty.</p><p>Elba called the team up "destined" in an interview with IGN, below, in which he said he's a big fan of Keanu and hears Keanu is a big fan of him: "We are destined to make something together."</p><blockquote data-theme="light"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Idris Elba reacts to Keanu Reeves as Shadow the Hedgehog 👀 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Knuckles?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">#Knuckles</a> <a href="https://t.co/lGiEmnRDRY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/lGiEmnRDRY</a></p>— IGN (@IGN) <a href="https://twitter.com/IGN/status/1780743736919822479?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">April 17, 2024</a></blockquote> <p>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 will therefore act as a reunion for the pair, and they're joined by a wealth of other famous faces including Ben Schwartz as Sonic, <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/jim-carrey-returning-as-robotnik-for-sonic-the-hedgehog-3">Jim Carrey as Doctor Eggman</a>, and more.</p><p>"Sonic, Knuckles, and Tails reunite against a powerful new adversary, Shadow, a mysterious villain with powers unlike anything they have faced before," treads the official synopsis. "With their abilities outmatched in every way, Team Sonic must seek out an unlikely alliance in hopes of stopping Shadow and protecting the planet." <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-release-date-cast-story-trailer-details">It arrives in theatres on December 20, 2024</a>. </p><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doomsday Paradise coming to Switch on September 12]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/doomsday-paradise-coming-to-switch-on-september-12</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/doomsday-paradise-coming-to-switch-on-september-12.967503/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/doomsday-paradise-coming-to-switch-on-september-12<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Multiplayer dating simulation game currently available for PC.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Astrolabe Games [37 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/astrolabe-games">Astrolabe Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Lemonade Flashbang [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/lemonade-flashbang">Lemonade Flashbang</a> will release a <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,908 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> version of <a title="Genres > Multiplayer [375 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/multiplayer">multiplayer</a> dating <a title="Genres > Simulation [557 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/simulation">simulation game</a> <em><a title="Games > Doomsday Paradise [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/doomsday-paradise">Doomsday Paradise</a></em> via <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/doomsday-paradise-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo eShop</a> on September 12, the companies announced. <span id="more-911123"></span></p><p><em>Doomsday Paradise</em> first launched for PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1603420/Doomsday_Paradise/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on November 8, 2023.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Astrolabe Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>Can you get a date before the end of the world?</p><p><em>Doomsday Paradise</em> is a goofy, multiplayer dating sim about finding love before the apocalypse. With over 100 different endings and 12 different singles to woo, no two games will ever be the same.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>Don’t Die Single</strong> – Hang out with a cast of absurdly beautiful hunks and hunkettes. Date a vampire, who thinks he’s got magic powers. A monster girl, who’s in love with Halloween despite not knowing when it is. Or explore your villainous side and romance the Spider Queen herself. The game features 13 hot singles, all looking for love!</li><li><strong>Play with Your Friends!</strong> – Bring in some friends to really dial things up a notch! Everyone’s choices affect group narratives in this dating sim, meaning things get more chaotic and interesting the more people you add! Team up to take on demons, or sabotage each other to claim the title of Legendary Hero!</li><li><strong>Write Your Own Story!</strong> – The game features over 400 goofy scenarios and 120 different endings! With plenty of enemies, bosses, and costumes to unlock, this game is designed to be played over and over and over and over and over again!</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>Switch Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Doomsday Paradise - Switch Announce Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oqoCdVsw96M?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo ends New 3DS repair support after draining parts supply]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-ends-new-3ds-repair-support-after-draining-parts-supply</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-ends-new-3ds-repair-support-after-draining-parts-supply.967500/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-ends-new-3ds-repair-support-after-draining-parts-supply<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Nintendo has said it will no longer provide repairs for its New Nintendo 3DS systems, effective immediately. In a </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/nintendo_cs/status/1828950227056836814">translated</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> social media post, it explained it had "run out of parts necessary for repairs."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In mid-</span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://support.nintendo.com/jp/information/2024/0213.html">February</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the publisher said it would continue to repair the New 3DS and its XL and 2DS offshoots until its parts stock had dwindled. According to its website at time of writing, the 2DS' XL successor can still be repaired.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Nintendo repairs drying up for older systems">Nintendo repairs drying up for older systems</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This past July, Nintendo also stopped repairing the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/the-end-of-days-has-arrived-for-the-wii-u">Nintendo WiiU</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> after also running out of parts. The New 3DS had a more staggered rollout compared to the WiiU, launching over the course of nearly a year across the world.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/en/finance/hard_soft/index.html">June 30, 2024</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the Nintendo 3DS has sold 75.94 million units. However, it's unclear if that covers just the 3DS itself or its entire family, and if so, how much can be attributed to the New 3DS.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Still, the 3DS is Nintendo's fourth best-selling dedicated handheld behind the Nintendo DS' 154.02 million units, Nintendo Game Boy (118.69 million), and the Game Boy Advance (81.51 million), all by that same June 30 date.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">At time of writing, the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-makes-switch-joy-con-repair-free-indefinitely-in-the-uk">Nintendo Switch's Joy-Controllers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> may be the only device the publisher is still offering repairs for. In the UK and other countries, that service comes at no charge.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy partners with Annapurna to finance Control 2 and develop transmedia projects]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/remedy-and-annapurna-enter-strategic-agreement-on-control-2-and-transmedia-push</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-partners-with-annapurna-to-finance-control-2-and-develop-transmedia-projects.967497/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/remedy-and-annapurna-enter-strategic-agreement-on-control-2-and-transmedia-push<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Remedy Entertainment.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://investors.remedygames.com/announcements/remedy-entertainment-plc-inside-information-remedy-and-annapurna-announce-a-strategic-partnership-agreement-on-control-2-and-bringing-control-and-alan-wake-to-film-and-television/">Annapurna Interactive</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> is putting its wallet behind Remedy Entertainment's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Control 2, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and will help the Finnish developer turn its two franchises into transmedia properties.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Both studios have entered a "strategic partnership agreement" wherein Annapurna will cover 50 percent of the sequel's development budget. In turn, it now has the rights to "expand" Control and Alan Wake into film, TV, and "selected audiovisuals."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This follows on from Remedy CEO Tero Virtala saying both franchises would be </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/alan-wake-ii-has-written-up-1-3-million-copies-sold">expanded upon</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> earlier this year, and Remedy gaining the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/remedy-entertainment-gets-control-s-full-franchise-rights-from-505-games">full franchise rights</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to Control back in February.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Remedy and Annapurna strike a deal">Remedy and Annapurna strike a deal</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to the terms of the deal, Remedy gets a greater revenue share from </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Control 2's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">sales after initial investments are recouped. Meanwhile, the future "audiovisual productions" will yield greater revenue on Annapurna's end.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"This strategic partnership between Annapurna and Remedy is an important milestone and an exciting opportunity for us," wrote Virtala. "This ensures we can develop </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Control 2</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> into the best game possible, allow us to move into self-publishing for selected titles and expand our franchises to other mediums."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For Annapurna, this technically marks its second game to adapted into film or TV. Last year, it revealed it would be bringing BlueTwelve's sci-fi cat adventure </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bluetwelve-s-i-stray-i-is-becoming-an-animated-movie">Stray</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">to the big screen, and indicated other titles could be adapted.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">As of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/remedy-s-2024-2025-opens-with-revenue-boost-focus-on-non-alan-wake-projects">early August</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Control 2 </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">was in the production readiness stage. However, Remedy's immediate focus on its multplayer spinoff "Condor," along with contract work remaking the first two </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/remedy-is-remaking-the-first-two-max-payne-games-with-its-own-engine">Max Payne games</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> for Rockstar.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Earlier this week, the original </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/SamLakeRMD/status/1828440370251714958">Control</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">turned five years old. As far as which medium it or Alan Wake will go to, the press release is tight-lipped.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alan Wake and Control film and television rights acquired by Annapurna]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/alan-wake-and-control-film-and-television-rights-acquired-by-annapurna</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alan-wake-and-control-film-and-television-rights-acquired-by-annapurna.967494/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/alan-wake-and-control-film-and-television-rights-acquired-by-annapurna<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>In exchange for financing half of Control 2.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Alan-Wake-2-Alan-at-desk.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Remedy</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Remedy Entertainment has announced a new partnership that'll see Annapurna Pictures financing half of <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/control-2">Control 2</a> in exchange for the film and TV rights to Control and Alan Wake.
</p>
<p>
Control 2 - the sequel to Remedy's acclaimed 2019 paranormal shooter - was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/remedy-officially-announces-sequel-to-control">officially announced back in 2022</a>. Earlier this month, the studio <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/max-payne-1-2-remake-enters-full-production-control-2-features-in-playable-form">revealed the project had now entered full production</a>, and that the Control 2 team was currently "working towards developing the game to an early functional state from beginning to end."
</p>
<p>
Remedy announced its new partnership in a <a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/announcements/remedy-entertainment-plc-inside-information-remedy-and-annapurna-announce-a-strategic-partnership-agreement-on-control-2-and-bringing-control-and-alan-wake-to-film-and-television/">statement shared on its website</a>, confirming Annapurna will finance 50 percent of Control 2's development budget and gain the rights to "expand the award-winning Control and Alan Wake franchises into film and television".
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Alan Wake 2's Night Springs expansion arrived in June.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EgRKLZtNSag" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Remedy notes the terms of the deal will see it retain full IP rights for Control and Alan Wake, but that revenue share from the deal will shift according to the release medium. Remedy will receive a greater revenue share from sales of the Control 2 game after initial investments have been recouped, while Annapurna will receive a greater revenue share from its audiovisual productions.
</p>
<p>
"The future of storytelling requires seamlessly integrating gaming, film, and television," Annapurna CEO Megan Ellison said of today's news, "and this partnership will allow us to explore new ways of bringing these narratives to life. By leveraging Remedy's innovative narratives and immersive worlds, we can push the boundaries of how stories are told and experienced across mediums."
</p>
<p>
Control and Alan Wake are, of course, set in the same universe, giving Annapurna significant flexibility in how the two properties might manifest for television and film.
</p>
<p>
Alongside Control 2, Remedy is currently developing its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/remedy-details-control-live-service-multiplayer-spin-off">live-service multiplayer Control spin-off Condor</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/max-payne-1-and-2-remake-in-the-works-remedy-confirms">remakes of Max Payne 1 &amp; 2</a>. The latter project is also now in full production. Remedy's next release, however, is <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/alan-wake-2-expansions-detailed-include-trip-inside-fictional-tv-show">Alan Wake 2's second DLC</a>, The Lake House, which arrives in October and sees players exploring a "mysterious facility situated on the shores of Cauldron Lake set up by an independent government organisation to conduct secret research".
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PS5 Pro design and announcement plans leaked]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/29/ps5-pro-design-and-announcement-plans-leaked/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ps5-pro-design-and-announcement-plans-leaked.967464/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/08/29/ps5-pro-design-and-announcement-plans-leaked/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ps5-pro">PS5 Pro’s</a> design and plans for an announcement in the first half of September have been leaked.</p>
<p>The impressively well-informed billbil-kun, who made their name on French deals site <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/voici-le-nom-le-design-de-la-nouvelle-console-de-playstation-avec-plein-dautres-details-inedits-59094">Dealabs</a> by very reliably leaking the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ps-plus">PS Plus</a> monthly games line up over the past two years, is the source of this latest scoop. They dig into the general marketing plan for September, confirming certain elements previously aired by Jeff Grubb on his <a href="https://youtu.be/o8TqCntkFPg?t=2131">Game Mess Morning</a> podcast, who says that a State of Play showcase will take place toward the end of September, likely tying in with Tokyo Game Show.</p>


<p>The PS5 Pro announcement, however, is expected before this in the first half of September, according to billbil-kun.</p>
<p>Another juicy element regards the console’s design, which… well it will look like a slightly glammed up PS5 Slim and PS5. You still have the popped collar style, but the divide in panels will have four grooves to it – Sony will probably note the four grooves as opposed to the three stripes between them, so as not to get Adidas’s lawyers excited.</p>

<p>It’s obviously difficult to talk about absolute dimensions from a sketch, but they note that the PS5 Pro looks thicker than the PS5 Slim, which makes sense. However, the multi-panel design matches up in style with the Slim and it’s feasible that there is crossover with compatibility for the swappable panels. The added grooves would make the Pro a bit longer, and if there’s a little more filling to the sandwich, that will bring the cooling capacity back closer to the original PS5’s power threshold.</p>
<p>Of note, there is no sign of a disc drive in the sketch, and billbil-kun cannot confirm if the console will have an SKU that features physical media support out of the box. Sony is very likely, however, to build in support for the PS5 Slim’s detachable disc drive as a cost-cutting measure.</p>
<p>So, basically, watch this space for a big PS5 Pro reveal within the next couple of weeks!</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/voici-le-nom-le-design-de-la-nouvelle-console-de-playstation-avec-plein-dautres-details-inedits-59094">billbil-kun at Dealabs</a></em></p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy Teams Up with Annapurna for Control 2, TV and Movie Projects]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-annapurna-control-2-tv-movies</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-teams-up-with-annapurna-for-control-2-tv-and-movie-projects.967461/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-annapurna-control-2-tv-movies<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Remedy has announced that it's teaming up with Annapurna for&nbsp;<em>Control 2&nbsp;</em>financing, as well as to bring&nbsp;<em>Control&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Alan Wake&nbsp;</em>to the worlds of TV and film.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.remedygames.com/article/remedy-and-annapurna-announce-a-strategic-cooperation-agreement" rel="noopener" target="_blank">an announcement</a> on Remedy's official website, the Finnish studio says Annapurna will "co-finance the development" of&nbsp;<em>Control 2</em>, and that Annapurna will also take "the&nbsp;<em>Control&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Alan Wake&nbsp;</em>franchises to film, TV and beyond".</p>
<p>The developer says this partnership will allow it to make&nbsp;<em>Control 2&nbsp;</em>"exactly the game we want it to be". Contrary to what you might expect, Annapurna won't be publishing&nbsp;<em>Control 2</em>, either; that responsibility will still fall to Remedy itself.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/control-2-remedy-annapurna-rocks.jpg?itok=XE-12wYB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/control-2-remedy-annapurna-rocks.jpg?itok=KP3PyMII 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The upcoming&nbsp;<em>Control&nbsp;</em>sequel will be partially financed by Annapurna.</figcaption></figure><p>If you're wondering how far along in the development process&nbsp;<em>Control 2&nbsp;</em>is, Remedy says the development team is "working full steam ahead on the game".</p>
<p>The studio goes on to say that it knows fans are eager for news on both this and <i>Condor</i>, Remedy's upcoming multiplayer&nbsp;<em>Control&nbsp;</em>spinoff, but that you'll "have to wait a while for that".</p>
<p>Last we knew,&nbsp;<em>Control 2&nbsp;</em>was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/max-payne-remakes-control-spinoff-remedy">sitting in the "production readiness stage"</a>, which likely indicates that it'll begin full production in the coming months. It's likely we'll hear from the&nbsp;<em>Max Payne&nbsp;</em>remakes and&nbsp;<em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-trademark-fbc-firebreak">Condor</a>&nbsp;</em>before that; they're both in "full production", according to Remedy.</p>
<p>Of course, we still don't know exactly when we'll be able to play&nbsp;<em>Control 2</em>, nor do we know when the&nbsp;<em>Max Payne&nbsp;</em>remakes will arrive. We'll just have to wait for more from Remedy on that.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/max-payne-remakes-control-remedy.jpg?itok=LsLuYEh3 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/max-payne-remakes-control-remedy.jpg?itok=hcUDKASI 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Remedy's&nbsp;<em>Max Payne&nbsp;</em>remakes are moving full steam ahead.</figcaption></figure><p>It feels appropriate for Remedy to be self-publishing&nbsp;<em>Control 2</em>, given that the studio <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-control-franchise-rights">acquired the franchise rights</a> from former publisher 505 Games back in February.</p>
<p>Additionally, this extra injection of funding will no doubt come as a relief to Remedy, especially with the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-codename-kestrel-canceled">cancellation of Tencent collab&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/remedy-codename-kestrel-canceled">Codename Kestrel</a>&nbsp;</em>and the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/alan-wake-2-budget-remedy-financials">lack of&nbsp;profitability for&nbsp;</a><em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/alan-wake-2-budget-remedy-financials">Alan Wake 2</a>&nbsp;</em>looming in the background.</p>
<p>We'll have to wait and see what Remedy has in store for us with regards to&nbsp;<em>Control 2&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Condor</em>. Stay tuned for more.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy Creator’s Pick For The ‘Most Complete’ Entry In The Series May Surprise You]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-creator-s-pick-for-the-most-complete-en-1851635714</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-creator%E2%80%99s-pick-for-the-%E2%80%98most-complete%E2%80%99-entry-in-the-series-may-surprise-you.967434/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-creator-s-pick-for-the-most-complete-en-1851635714<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="32841f5f8a7e5805e1312a30339a3bde" data-recommend-id="image://32841f5f8a7e5805e1312a30339a3bde" data-format="jpg" data-width="1276" data-height="716" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A warrior in blue armor and a yellow cap holds out a sword in front of him" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A warrior in blue armor and a yellow cap holds out a sword in front of him" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Square Enix / Yoshitaka Amano</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="32841f5f8a7e5805e1312a30339a3bde" data-recommend-id="image://32841f5f8a7e5805e1312a30339a3bde" data-format="jpg" data-width="1276" data-height="716" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A warrior in blue armor and a yellow cap holds out a sword in front of him" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>With nearly forty years of incredible stories stretching across sixteen mainline entries and numerous spinoffs, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/best-final-fantasy-games-rpg-7-6-10-12-square-enix-ff-1850560934&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/best-final-fantasy-games-rpg-7-6-10-12-square-enix-ff-1850560934"><em>Final Fantasy</em></a></span> is a truly singular video game franchise. While they all have their own strengths and weaknesses, and there are some generally accepted as “best” entries, there’s an argument to be made for every one of them. But when it comes to the most complete realization of the franchise’s original idea, <em>Final Fantasy</em> creator <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/things-are-much-different-for-the-creator-of-final-fant-1629514442&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/things-are-much-different-for-the-creator-of-final-fant-1629514442">Hironobu Sakaguchi</a></span> has a surprising choice—none other than the game that started it all, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-the-kotaku-retrospective-1773438013&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-the-kotaku-retrospective-1773438013">1987’s <em>Final Fantasy</em></a></span>.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195519" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="I Didn’t Play Final Fantasy XVI ‘Right,’ And That’s OK" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="148" data-playlist="195519,196411,196055" data-current="195519"><div><p>I Didn’t Play Final Fantasy XVI ‘Right,’ And That’s OK</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195519/195519_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21013.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>This revelation comes from a sweeping interview with <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.inverse.com/gaming/hironobu-sakaguchi-interview-final-fantasy-fantasian&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.inverse.com/gaming/hironobu-sakaguchi-interview-final-fantasy-fantasian" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Inverse</em></a></span><em> </em>that touches on Sakaguchi’s long career at Square Enix and later his own studio Mistwalker. The original <em>Final Fantasy</em> is the “most complete” entry, in that it “is closest in its final form based on what we set out to achieve,” he says. Famously, the game helped skyrocket the popularity of the then-struggling company Square and spawned a now-iconic series.</p><p>Beyond its importance in terms of cementing Square’s legacy, <em>Final Fantasy 1</em> is essentially the platonic ideal of RPGs. It doesn’t have the complexity either narratively or mechanically that the series would become known for in later entries, but it is a distillation of a delightful fantasy adventure with satisfying turn-based combat and a compelling party system. When you play the first <em>Final Fantasy</em> you can tell that there is no fat, no excess, nor is the game lacking features that would compromise its vision. Even nearly forty years later you can feel the<em> Final Fantasy 1</em> core within every subsequent game. </p><p>As the series grew in popularity and became more ambitious, itsfirst entry has largely fallen by the wayside. It’s often seen as the game that started a series that would very quickly grow into something greater, and many people would say you should ignore it outright. However, as Sakaguchi notes, <em>Final Fantasy</em> feels like the most complete game in the series, the best example of what he and Square were trying to achieve all those years ago. y. And as for a runner-up? Well, Sakaguchi did give a more people pleasing answer, saying <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-vi-retrospective-simply-the-best-1792398695&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/final-fantasy-vi-retrospective-simply-the-best-1792398695"><em>Final Fantasy</em> <em>6</em> </a></span>comes close and “stands out” above the rest of the series.</p><p>.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fallout 76 Milepost Zero Roadmap Released by Bethesda]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-76-milepost-zero-roadmap/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fallout-76-milepost-zero-roadmap-released-by-bethesda.967431/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/fallout-76-milepost-zero-roadmap/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Fallout 76’s next major update is on the horizon and almost ready to be released. It’s called Milepost Zero – Country Road, and it’ll bring about a fresh host of changes to the Fallout 76 platform, including new camp mechanics, an interesting quest loop, and various quality-of-life upgrades and tweaks.</p>



<p>Bethesda Game Studios has just published a roadmap that highlights what’s happening in Fallout 76 until the end of 2024.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-what-s-next-for-fallout-76">What’s Next For Fallout 76?</h2>



<p>Fallout 76 has a stacked roadmap ahead, but fans will be displeased to notice that it’s the same old events on repeat. Aside from the deployment of Milepost Zero, there’s nothing <strong>too special </strong>on the cards for Fallout’s MMORPG title.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Fallout 76 - Season 18: Milepost Zero - Country Road" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MXrFWx_jwKo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>On September 3, Milepost Zero rolls out worldwide, and midway through the month, users will flock to the platform to take advantage of a Double XP Weekend event. In October, it’s all about Halloween, with Spooky Scorched stalking the hills of Appalachia. It’s also the month when ‘Fallout Day’ arrives, with fans celebrating ‘Bombs Drop Day’ on October 23.</p>



<p>Moving into November, an Invaders From The Beyond event begins, followed by Fallout 76’s regularly scheduled birthday celebration. That takes place on November 14. Finally, in December, players can enjoy the typical Holiday Scorched event, along with Double Mutations and Double XP events aplenty.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to anything in particular going forward?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news about the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-partner-annapurna-control-alan-wake/">Control and Alan Wake live-action adaptations</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Remedy Partners With Annapurna To Bring Control and Alan Wake To Film and Television]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-partner-annapurna-control-alan-wake/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/remedy-partners-with-annapurna-to-bring-control-and-alan-wake-to-film-and-television.967428/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/remedy-partner-annapurna-control-alan-wake/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Remedy Entertainment has announced a strategic partnership with Annapurna Pictures, the core purpose of which is to have the latter company ‘finance 50% of the development budget for the upcoming Control 2.’ This partnership will also give Annapurna the production rights for Control and Alan Wake, to create live-action adaptations of both franchises.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-more-adaptations">More Adaptations</h2>



<p>Alan Wake and Control will translate nicely into live-action adaptations. The former franchise already features plenty of live-action sequences, particularly in the 2023 release of Alan Wake 2.</p>



<p><a href="https://investors.remedygames.com/announcements/remedy-entertainment-plc-inside-information-remedy-and-annapurna-announce-a-strategic-partnership-agreement-on-control-2-and-bringing-control-and-alan-wake-to-film-and-television/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Speaking on the deal</a>, Megan Ellison, the CEO of Annapurna, said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>The future of storytelling requires seamlessly integrating gaming, film, and television, and this partnership will allow us to explore new ways of bringing these narratives to life. By leveraging Remedy’s innovative narratives and immersive worlds, we can push the boundaries of how stories are told and experienced across mediums.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This deal will see Remedy Entertainment earn a greater revenue share from the sales of subsequent releases – primarily Control 2 – while Annapurna will reap the larger revenue share from any ‘audiovisual productions’. </p>



<p>Remedy’s CEO, Tero Virtala, said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>This strategic partnership between Annapurna and Remedy is an important milestone and an exciting opportunity for us. We know Annapurna shares our passion for our IPs and the universes we have created. With award-winning movies such as Zero Dark Thirty and games like Stray, Annapurna’s expertise across film, TV, and video games makes them an ideal partner for us. This agreement will ensure we can develop Control 2 into the best game possible, allow us to move into self-publishing for selected titles and expand our franchises to other mediums.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Do you think we need more live-action adaptations of video game franchises, or should they start to slow down?</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-script-record/">Kingdom Come Deliverance 2 might have the longest script in gaming history</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>
    
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>