<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 13:45:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cities: Skylines 2 Continues Renovations and Delays More Content]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cities-skylines-2-economy-rework-creator-packs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cities-skylines-2-continues-renovations-and-delays-more-content.879357/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cities-skylines-2-economy-rework-creator-packs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Paradox and Colossal Order have revealed that the&nbsp;<em>Cities: Skylines 2&nbsp;</em>economy rework patch is almost ready, but as a result, the game's upcoming Creator Packs have been delayed.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://www.paradoxinteractive.com/games/cities-skylines-ii/news/upcoming-patch-and-content" rel="noopener" target="_blank">new post on its official website</a>, Paradox says that the economy patch is currently set for release somewhere between June 3rd and June 19th. The patch "will not address everything", but internal and beta testing suggests the studios are "heading in the right direction".</p>

<p>Sadly, it's going to be a little longer before you can get your hands on&nbsp;<em>Cities: Skylines 2</em>'s Creator Packs. That's down to the extra feedback and adjustment the patch will need, as well as Sweden and Finland's "summer lock" system, which gives employees the right to four consecutive vacation weeks in summer.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/cities-skylines-2-economy-rework-creator-packs-city.jpg?itok=PlWZpxR6 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/cities-skylines-2-economy-rework-creator-packs-city.jpg?itok=poZfdijX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Cities: Skylines 2</em>'s economy rework is almost here.</figcaption></figure><p>Paradox also says it's making progress with some of the technical issues that are preventing it from releasing the&nbsp;<em>Cities: Skylines 2&nbsp;</em>asset editor, although that feature isn't ready yet and might not be for a while.</p>

<p>As regards the&nbsp;game's console release, which has been <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cities-skylines-2-console-delay">delayed</a> more <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cities-skylines-2-ps5-xbox-delayed-apology">than once</a> since its initial announcement, Paradox says internal testing has shown the studio is "not hitting the stability and performance targets" it wants to hit for&nbsp;<em>Cities: Skylines 2&nbsp;</em>on PS5 and Xbox Series X|S.</p>

<p>As a result, Paradox says it's hoping to keep to the October release window for the console versions, but that they "might have to be delayed further" to allow for more technical tweaking.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/cities-skylines-2-economy-rework-creator-packs-tram.jpg?itok=jOQCymkv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/cities-skylines-2-economy-rework-creator-packs-tram.jpg?itok=a_tsxIvv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Paradox is working on the&nbsp;<em>Cities: Skylines 2&nbsp;</em>console versions, but it might be a while before they're released.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Cities: Skylines 2&nbsp;</em>is the sequel to 2015's hugely successful city-builder&nbsp;<em>Cities: Skylines</em>.</p>

<p>Released in October last year,&nbsp;<em>Cities: Skylines 2&nbsp;</em>suffered from <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cities-skylines-2-gets-first-of-several-patches-to-improve-performance-following-flawed">technical issues on release</a>, leading Paradox and Colossal Order to promise that <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cities-skylines-2-paid-dlc-performance">no paid DLC would be released for the game</a> until those issues were fixed.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, players didn't feel the studios had kept that promise when the "Beach Properties" DLC pack launched earlier this year, and the resulting outcry led Paradox to pull the pack from sale and incorporate its content into the base game instead.</p>

<p>Updates for&nbsp;<em>Cities: Skylines 2&nbsp;</em>are still coming; back in April, the game received <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/cities-skylines-2-update-dlss-super-resolution">DLSS support and a ton of bug fixes</a>, and the next patch is set to introduce a major rework for the game's economic systems.</p>

<p>You can grab&nbsp;<em>Cities: Skylines 2&nbsp;</em>right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/949230/Cities_Skylines_II/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC</a>. It's also available via PC Game Pass or Xbox Game Pass Ultimate.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for five years, and in those five years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['Don't worry! I'm a murderer!'  - award-winning comedy Anthology of the Killer is out next week]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-worry-im-a-murderer-award-winning-comedy-anthology-of-the-killer-is-out-next-week</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dont-worry-im-a-murderer-award-winning-comedy-anthology-of-the-killer-is-out-next-week.879354/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/dont-worry-im-a-murderer-award-winning-comedy-anthology-of-the-killer-is-out-next-week<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/anthology-of-the-killer-thecatamites-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Stephen "thecatamites" Gillmurphy</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>In <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/anthology-of-the-killer">Anthology of the Killer</a> you do not exit the game using a pause menu. You exit it by walking down a back alley into the quavering arms of two hungry bears. This is just one of many laughs your diaphragm will endure as you navigate "the escalating adventures of a girl trying to make zines in a town of giallo-style masked serial murderers". The horror comedy already won its creators the <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/venba-wins-igf-grand-prize-for-2024">Nuovo Award at the Independent Games Festival</a> this year, recognition that has been a long time coming for prolific creator Stephen <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/thecatamites">"thecatamites"</a> Gillmurphy. If you're unfamiliar with his work, you can get acquainted next week, when Anthology of the Killer gets its <a href="https://thecatamites.itch.io/anthology-of-the-killer/devlog/735392/releases-28th-may">full release on Itch.io</a> on May 28th.  At which point you can explore its unsettling urban hell of shady corporations and cops who think they're cool. There's a trailer below.</p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Anthology of the Killer (Trailer)" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_iNgSWbzAgg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Anthology of the Killer (Trailer)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_iNgSWbzAgg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_iNgSWbzAgg?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_iNgSWbzAgg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>In the first of the nine-part series, protagonist BB is an employee of a life insurance call centre were everyone wears sheets over their head. When you sit at BB's desk to work, the usual office chatter slows to a haunting warble, like listening to a cassette tape submerged in a bathtub of jam. A TV in the break room is set to a news channel reporting that 1000 bodies have been found somewhere ("Same news as always," remarks BB.) In the printer room a sign yells: "Remember! We don't pay out if the corpse is unidentifiable!" When you walk into the complaints department, the doors lock behind you. What follows is... well, I'll let you figure it out.</p>
<p>Many point to the likes of <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a> or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/baldurs-gate-3-class-list">Baldur's Gate 3</a> as examples of excellent writing in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-adventure-games">adventure games</a>.  I will point to <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/topics/thecatamites">the entire body of work by thecatamites</a>.  As ever, it's the combination of DIY MS Paint visuals and a surreal comic voice that draws me in. The sea's breathy waves are caused by geology, "the baleful science". When our zine-printing heroine is nabbed by the cops she reflects that "Rule #1 of making a zine is never talk to the police." She lives in an apartment block with metal shutters that clamp closed at night which is "far beneath today's superior anti-murderer technology". I could basically pick any dialogue box that appears in any of these games and it would have something worth smiling at, or frowning at, or feeling <em>something</em> at.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/anthology-of-the-killer-thecatamites-4.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Stephen "thecatamites" Gillmurphy</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Thecatamites has been making short games for over a decade now. At this stage I have lost count. Many of us at RPS have been fans of his work. After a period of tinkering away he tends to compile a bunch of his games together, as with <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/10-beautiful-postcards-is-some-new-craic-from-thecatamites">10 Beautiful Postcards</a> or <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/thecatamites-commercial-collection-50-short-games">50 Short Games</a>. In the same vein (blood joke) Anthology of the Killer compiles a bunch of games he's made in the last few years. This time it's a clear serial format though, the story continuing its bloody theme with each new installment: Hands of the Killer, Face of the Killer, Drool of the Killer. You might have already been playing through BB's story as each episode was released, but if not, this collection handily puts them all in one place, all complimented by <a href="http://harmonyzone.org/press/html/ad/face.jpg">poster art by A. Degen</a>. </p>
<p>In today's tempest of game releases, small games sometimes slip past our ever-watchful eyes. So it's a good thing Gillmurphy got in touch with RPS to let us know the murder mystery compilation was due out soon. </p>
<p>"I believe the concept of 'death' will be a big hit with the readership," he said, "as why else would they be playing video games."</p>
<p>A valid observation. I am interested in this innovative approach. </p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/anthology-of-the-killer-thecatamites-3.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Rock Paper Shotgun / Stephen "thecatamites" Gillmurphy</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Gillmurphy calls the murderthon a "comparatively straight narrative", somewhat underselling his skill as one of the homegrown scene's most creative storytellers. Playing through thecatamites work after a long time of consuming clinically polished "story rich" blockbusters is like having the language centers of your brain treated with a batch of medicinal maggots. It looks horrible! But once the maggots roll away, holy shit, what a sparkling temporal lobe you've got. It is writing as a controlled explosion, but the detonator is one of those fake Pringles cans with a spring snake inside. Text as the rediscovery of a forgotten species that doesn't quite match the other amphibians, but yes, is (probably?) still a frog. It's worth reading his musings on <a href="https://myfriendpokey.tumblr.com/post/705461201521573889/personal-aesthetics">art as a lucky bag</a>, if nothing else.  </p>

<p>One might say I am exaggerating, or that thecatamites' writing is an acquired taste, but you may easily acquire it in any of the following methods: </p>
<ul>
<li>suffering the Irish psyche</li>
<li>subsisting for years on an auditory diet of avant-garde music</li>
<li>playing his games</li>
</ul>
<p>That last method is easy. You can start next week with <a href="https://thecatamites.itch.io/anthology-of-the-killer">Anthology of the Killer</a>. Or else...</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Concord, Firewalk Studios’ Upcoming Sci-fi PVP Multiplayer FPS, Expected to Get Gameplay Reveal Soon – Rumor]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/concord-firewalk-studios-gameplay/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/concord-firewalk-studios%E2%80%99-upcoming-sci-fi-pvp-multiplayer-fps-expected-to-get-gameplay-reveal-soon-%E2%80%93-rumor.879351/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/concord-firewalk-studios-gameplay/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Concord, the upcoming sci-fi&nbsp;PVP multiplayer FPS from PlayStation's Firewalk Studios, is expected to receive a gameplay reveal soon.</p>
<p>At least, that's what reputable deals leaker 'Billbil-kun' has said. In a <a href="https://www.dealabs.com/magazine/du-nouveau-a-propos-de-concord-la-prochaine-exclusivite-de-playstation-51320" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new article</a> on French deals website Dealabs, the leaker writes that a second announcement for the game is expected to be made within 15 days from now. Although the exact date isn't sure, the leaker writes that new details will be shared during either the rumored PlayStation showcase or the Summer Game Fest 2024 on June 7. "This announcement is expected to feature at least some of the playable characters&nbsp;in the game with a preview of&nbsp;the gameplay", 'Billbil-kun' writes on Dealabs. "Let's also remember that we had stated that the game was inspired by the universe of&nbsp;<em>Marvel's Guardians of the Galaxy</em>, following the first elements we had in our possession."</p>
<p>Concord from Firewalk was first announced back in May of last year. Interestingly enough, 'Billbil-kun' already suggested <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-state-of-play-january-31st/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">that Sony would be showing off the game during the State of Play broadcast back in January of this year</a>. "The ad was even ready to be presented during State of Play which took place last January", the leaker writes. "However, this announcement did not take place&nbsp;for reasons that we do not yet know although&nbsp;we believe it was because of some problems encountered on the PC version."</p>
<p>Sony has yet to confirm a new PlayStation showcase, but <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-showcase-is-planned-for-this-month-jeff-grubb-reiterates-could-happen-at-any-moment/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">recent rumors suggest that the event will take place later this month</a>. We'll update you as soon as we learn more about either Concord or the rumored PlayStation event.</p>
<p>Concord has yet to receive an official release date, but according to Firewalk Studios, the game is coming to both PS5 and PC later this year. We've included the teaser trailer for Concord, as revealed last year, below:</p>
<p><iframe title="Concord - Teaser Trailer | PS5 &amp; PC Games" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Zb-xvCPecps?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus’ Batman is still Kevin Conroy ‘for the foreseeable future’]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24162612/multiversus-pve-rifts-batman-kevin-conroy-death</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus%E2%80%99-batman-is-still-kevin-conroy-%E2%80%98for-the-foreseeable-future%E2%80%99.879348/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24162612/multiversus-pve-rifts-batman-kevin-conroy-death<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="fMligV">Earlier this month, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2022/9/13/23345074/multiversus-opinion-dodge-cooldown-meter-ui-player-first-games"><em>MultiVersus</em></a> developer Player First Games announced <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24158526/multiversus-pve-mode-rifts-video">a new PvE mode</a> for its fighting game. That mode, called Rifts, will feature unique battle scenarios and minigames, as well as cinematics and story elements, the developer says. It will be updated seasonally with new content.</p>
<p id="YaO4bB">We’ll see characters interact in mode-specific ways in Rifts, and Player First promises to keep adding to the PvE mode season to season. With a fully voiced cast featuring the talents of John Dimaggio, Matthew Lillard, Tara Strong, and others, the game will bring a long list of beloved characters together for some first-of-their-kind interactions.</p>
<p id="nyjsXO">One notable issue the developers face is the <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23453290/batman-kevin-conroy-actor-obituary">death of Kevin Conroy</a>, the iconic voice of Batman and Bruce Wayne in animated features and video games. In <em>MultiVersus</em>, Conroy is reunited with fellow <em>Batman: The Animated Series</em> actor <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24155348/multiversus-joker-gameplay-mark-hamill-powerpuff-girls">Mark Hamill, the famous voice of the Joker</a>. In an interview with Player First Games co-founder and <em>MultiVersus</em> game director Tony Huynh, I asked him how the studio plans to approach future content featuring Batman in the wake of Conroy’s passing.</p>
<p id="V5CvNy">“Kevin Conroy was a big part of my childhood,” Huynh told me before addressing the issue, “and Batman is my favorite fictional character, period. Kevin’s passing really affected me personally. And I think that the pairing of Mark Hamill and Kevin Conroy in our game is special.</p>
<p id="hBdNgI">“I actually don’t know what we’re gonna do going forward. We have to figure that out. No matter what though, we want to be respectful of Kevin and the legacy that he left behind. A big reason why, I think, Mark Hamill is in the game is because Kevin is as well. So Kevin is extremely important to our game, and the work that he’s done for our game will persist. Going forward, I don’t know fully what we’re going to be doing. We do plan on updating the game regularly and have to come up with plan for that, but that isn’t finalized yet.”</p>
<p id="1rd69b">A representative for Warner Bros. Games added that “there was a lot of voiceover work that was done” by Conroy, “so, for the foreseeable future, that’s who Batman will be in <em>MultiVersus</em>.”</p>
<p id="PCBaaa"><a href="https://www.polygon.com/23933735/multiversus-announcement-relaunch-release-date-warner-bros"><em>MultiVersus</em> will return, with many new additions, on May 28</a>. The free-to-play game will be available once again on PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Windows PC, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X.</p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cooking and management game Magical Bakery announced for PS5, Xbox Series, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/cooking-and-management-game-magical-bakery-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/cooking-and-management-game-magical-bakery-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc.879345/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/cooking-and-management-game-magical-bakery-announced-for-ps5-xbox-series-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Due out in 2024.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > SOEDESCO [80 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/soedesco">SOEDESCO</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Superlumen [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/soedesco/superlumen">Superlumen</a> have announced single-player <a title="Genres > Cooking [9 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/cooking">cooking</a> and <a title="Genres > Management [19 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/management">management game</a> <em><a title="Games > Magical Bakery [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/magical-bakery">Magical Bakery</a></em> for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,048 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,339 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,123 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2595940/Magical_Bakery/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a>, <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/p/magical-bakery-57f8e8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Epic Games Store</a>). It will launch in 2024. <span id="more-884346"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via SOEDESCO:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Magical Bakery</em> is a cooking and management, single-player game, set in an enchanted bakery that sells all sorts of sweets and pastries with a twist—they may contain traces of magic!</p><p><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> a life full of magic, challenges, and the joy of creating sweets that will leave a spellbinding impression on your customers. Become the ultimate magical baker and prove yourself worthy to inherit the Magical Bakery!</p><p><strong>Develop Your Skills in Preparing Magical Confections</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>As a young magical baker trainee of the Academy of Magical Bakers, it’s time to put your magical skills to the test! Create delectable treats and decorate them with magical sprinkles to solve your customers’ problems, warm their hearts, or simply make their day brighter.</p><p><strong>Unlock New Ingredients and Upgrade Your Shop</strong></p><p>Mix, knead, bake, and decorate with flair! Unlock new ingredients and upgrade your bakery with the help of two special NPCs. The merchant and blacksmith are ready to assist you in your quest to make your bakery the go-to spot for magical indulgence!</p></blockquote><div id="carousel_884358"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div><blockquote><p><strong>Prove Yourself Worthy to Inherit a Magical Bakery</strong></p><p>Your destiny awaits! Prove your mastery by passing exams at the Academy of Magical Bakers. Every Sunday, the examiner will visit to check your progress, so rise to the challenge and show your magical skills! Level up to unlock recipes and ingredients, and even harness the power of elementals. Inherit the shop from the old witch owner and bring new life to this magical haven!</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Experience a cozy management game where you run a magical bakeshop.</li><li>Bake all sorts of sweets and pastries infused with magic to solve your customers’ problems and bring them joy.</li><li>Develop skills, unlock new ingredients, and upgrade the bakery to your heart’s desire.</li><li>Pass exams at the Academy of Magical Bakers to prove mastery and inherit the shop.</li><li>Enjoy an adorable and whimsical visual style that is sure to delight players of all ages.</li><li>Customize your character into your ideal magical baker look.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch the announcement trailer below. View the first screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/magical-bakery/may-23-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Announce Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Magical Bakery - Announcement Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PWhaOaC-1IU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus – Jason Voorhees gameplay trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/multiversus-jason-voorhees-gameplay-trailer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-%E2%80%93-jason-voorhees-gameplay-trailer.879339/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/multiversus-jason-voorhees-gameplay-trailer<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Warner Bros. Games [623 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/warner-bros-games">Warner Bros. Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Player First Games [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/player-first-games">Player First Games</a> have released the official gameplay trailer for <a title="Genres > Free-to-Play [268 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/free-to-play">free-to-play</a> platform fighting game <em><a title="Games > MultiVersus [13 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/multiversus">MultiVersus</a></em>‘ <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/multiversus-adds-jason-voorhees-agent-smith">newly announced</a> playable character Jason Voorhees from the <em>Friday the 13th</em> franchise. <span id="more-884339"></span></p><p>Here is an overview of the character, via Warner Bros. Games:</p><blockquote><p>Jason towers over the competition as a Tank class character with a scary moveset that incorporates his axe and machete weapons, teleporting ability to show up right behind opponents and stuff them into a sleeping bag, fatally folding a bed in half to launch enemies off the map, and more. The video also shows off a glimpse of the “Uber Jason” character variant based on his appearance from the <em>Jason X</em> film.</p></blockquote><p><em>MultiVersus</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,048 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,339 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [26,713 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,167 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,123 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1818750/MultiVersus/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> on May 28.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Jason Voorhees “Weirdo in a Mask” Gameplay Trailer</span></h2><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><iframe title="MultiVersus - Official Jason Voorhees &quot;Weirdo in a Mask&quot; Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NTfo4vRWD5Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon Go Ultra Space Wonders: Blacephalon, Stakataka, Bonuses, And More]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-ultra-space-wonders-blacephalon-stakataka-bonuses-and-more/1100-6523528/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-go-ultra-space-wonders-blacephalon-stakataka-bonuses-and-more.879336/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-ultra-space-wonders-blacephalon-stakataka-bonuses-and-more/1100-6523528/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523528">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/pokemon-go/">Pokemon Go</a>'s World of Wonders season is wrapping up in a few days, and it's going out with a literal bang. The Ultra Space Wonders event is now underway, introducing the Fireworks Pokemon Blacephalon and two other Ultra Beasts to the game. On top of that, special Pokemon are appearing more frequently in the wild and as raid bosses, and the final part of this season's Special Research story is now live.</p><p dir="ltr">To help you get up to speed, here's everything you need to know about the Ultra Space Wonders event.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pU9JVo3GIRM" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/pU9JVo3GIRM" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2 dir="ltr">Event Schedule</h2><p dir="ltr">The Ultra Space Wonders event begins <strong>May 23 at 10 AM local time</strong> and ends on <strong>May 28 at 8 PM local time</strong>.</p><h2 dir="ltr">New Ultra Beasts</h2><p dir="ltr">Three new Ultra Beasts have arrived as part of the Ultra Space Wonders event: <strong>Blacephalon</strong>, <strong>Stakataka</strong>, and <strong>Naganadel</strong>.</p><p dir="ltr">Blacephalon and Stakataka are both appearing in five-star raids throughout the event, but each is exclusive to a specific hemisphere. Blacephalon is only available in the Western Hemisphere, while Stakataka is only appearing in the Eastern Hemisphere.</p><p dir="ltr">Naganadel, meanwhile, is the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-how-to-evolve-poipole-into-naganadel/1100-6523415/">evolved form of Poipole</a>, the Ultra Beast you encounter upon completing the first step of the World of Wonders Special Research story. To get Naganadel, you must first set Poipole as your buddy and then catch 20 dragon-type Pokemon. Once you've met that requirement, you can evolve the Ultra Beast using 200 Poipole Candy.</p><h2 dir="ltr">Wild Pokemon</h2><p dir="ltr">In addition to the new Ultra Beasts, certain Pokemon are appearing more frequently during the Ultra Space Wonders event. Various poison types such as Croagunk, Trubbish, and Skrelp are spawning in the wild, as is the rare dragon Pokemon Dratini. On top of that, <strong>Shiny Mareanie</strong> is also available, marking your first chance to catch one in Pokemon Go.</p><p dir="ltr">You can find the following Pokemon in the wild during the event:</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Ekans</li><li dir="ltr">Zubat</li><li dir="ltr">Tentacool</li><li dir="ltr">Koffing</li><li dir="ltr">Stunky</li><li dir="ltr">Croagunk</li><li dir="ltr">Trubbish</li><li dir="ltr">Skrelp</li><li dir="ltr">Mareanie</li><li dir="ltr">Dratini</li></ul><h2 dir="ltr">Raids</h2><p dir="ltr">The following Pokemon are appearing as raid bosses throughout the Ultra Space Wonders event:</p><p dir="ltr"><strong>One-star raids</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Paldean Wooper</li><li dir="ltr">Hisuian Qwilfish</li><li dir="ltr">Hisuian Sneasel</li><li dir="ltr">Bagon</li><li dir="ltr">Deino</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Three-star raids</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Galarian Weezing</li><li dir="ltr">Druddigon</li><li dir="ltr">Turtonator</li></ul><p dir="ltr"><strong>Mega raids</strong></p><ul><li dir="ltr">Mega Pidgeot</li></ul><h2 dir="ltr">Bonuses</h2><p dir="ltr">On top of the increased Pokemon spawns, a few bonuses are also available during the Ultra Space Wonders event. First, you'll earn <strong>double XP for winning Ultra Beast raid battles</strong>, giving you an extra incentive to battle Blacephalon and Stakataka.</p><p dir="ltr">On top of that, new Field Research tasks will be available throughout the event. Complete these tasks to earn various rewards, including potential encounters with the following Pokemon:</p><ul><li dir="ltr">Nidoran (F)</li><li dir="ltr">Nidoran (M)</li><li dir="ltr">Trubbish</li><li dir="ltr">Mareanie</li><li dir="ltr">Goomy</li><li dir="ltr">Jangmo-o</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Pokemon Go's World of Wonders may be coming to an end, but there are still plenty of events on the horizon for the mobile game, including Pokemon Go Fest 2024. The multi-date celebration kicks off in June and finally introduces the <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-go-fest-adds-new-forms-to-a-legendary-pokemon/1100-6523408/">legendary Pokemon Necrozma</a>. Developer Niantic has also outlined Pokemon Go's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/pokemon-gos-community-day-schedule-revealed-for-next-season/1100-6523578/" data-ref-id="1100-6523578">Community Day schedule for next season</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Here's Everything Returning MultiVersus Players Will Receive When They First Log In]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-everything-returning-multiversus-players-will-receive-when-they-first-log-in/1100-6523592/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/heres-everything-returning-multiversus-players-will-receive-when-they-first-log-in.879333/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/heres-everything-returning-multiversus-players-will-receive-when-they-first-log-in/1100-6523592/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523592">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">Player First Games and Warner Bros. made a risky decision last year by deciding to put its platform fighter MultiVersus on hiatus and pull it from digital stores--especially when some players had spent real-world money on characters and cosmetics. With MultiVersus set to return next week, Player First has revealed what returning players can expect to see when they log in to the game for the first time.</p><p dir="ltr">Speaking with GameSpot during a recent preview session, Huynh confirmed that "all characters and cosmetics players purchased before May 28 will still be there when [players] come back to the game." That's not all, however, as Huynh also confirmed some new content will be offered free of charge to those who choose to return.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="1948683612" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464115,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;MultiVersus%20-%20Official%20Cinematic%20Launch%20Trailer%20%22Stars%20Collide.%20Pies%20Fly.%22&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:181,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/multiversus-official-cinematic-launch-trailer-stars-collide-pies-fly\/2300-6464115\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464115\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464115\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464115\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464115&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464115,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6523592&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;multiversus&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;2d,action,fighting&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-4,xbox-one&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;warner-bros-games,warner-bros-interactive-entertainment,warner-bros&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464115},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464115\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4305391-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/DJHdW6My.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1716211140,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="DJHdW6My" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> MultiVersus - Official Cinematic Launch Trailer "Stars Collide. Pies Fly."</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Also, any players who return within the first two weeks of the game's relaunch--from May 28 to June 11--will also receive the first battle pass and its 70 levels of cosmetics, currency, and characters for no additional charge. That includes an instant unlock of the pass's level one perk: Jason Voorhees as a playable character.</p><p dir="ltr">Essentially, if they unlocked the entire roster during the open beta period, any returning players who log into the game before June 11 will only have to unlock one character, Joker, once they're in the game. All previously unlocked characters, as well as two brand-new characters, will be available on day one. "We understand how players would feel," Huynh said when asked about this "welcome back" package, "and we're trying to make good on that."</p><p dir="ltr">During our preview session, we got to try out Joker, Jason, and Banana Guard, as well as run through a few challenges in Rifts, MultiVersus's new PvE mode. We also spoke to Huynh about the risks in going on a long hiatus, how development has changed in the year since the game was removed, and more.</p><p dir="ltr">MultiVersus returns to digital storefronts May 28 on Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115235460361630065469?rel=author">Jason Fanelli</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How the developers of Afterlove EP continued the game after its creator's death]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/how-the-developers-of-afterlove-ep-continued-the-game-after-its-creators-death</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-the-developers-of-afterlove-ep-continued-the-game-after-its-creators-death.879330/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/how-the-developers-of-afterlove-ep-continued-the-game-after-its-creators-death<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>"We all agreed that our hearts could not let Mohammed Fahmi's vision go to waste"</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>The difficulties of game development means it's not uncommon for the original creator to depart from the project before it's finished, for one reason or another. It's not often as tragic as is the case of Afterlove EP.</p>
<p>The music-centric narrative game was first announced in December 2021 on Nintendo's Indie World showcase. Just a few months later, the game's creative director <a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/coffee-talk-creator-fahmi-dies-at-32">Mohammed Fahmi passed away</a>.</p>
<p>His sudden passing felt like a huge loss, especially as his breakout game Coffee Talk had made him a beacon for Indonesia's growing indie scene, while Pikselnesia, the studio he assembled for Afterlove EP, was also a remote team with people from across the country. It could have then been all too easy for it to all collapse afterwards but if anything, it was a catalyst for the surviving members to finish what Fahmi had started.</p>
<p>"We stopped work to grieve for three months and then we all agreed that our hearts could not let his vision go to waste and we had to finish the game, no matter what," says game director and programmer Dany.</p>
<p>After going under relative radio silence, Afterlove EP recently re-emerged at this year's LudoNarraCon with a free Steam demo, and a release window for Q3 2024. It would have nonetheless felt very raw given that the game's premise is also about grief and trying to move on after a loved one's untimely passing.</p>
<blockquote><p>"In everything we've done [on Afterlove EP], we hold Fahmi close to our hearts and think about what he would say if he was here"</p>
<cite>Dany, Pikselnesia</cite></blockquote>
<p>The cause of Fahmi's death had never been publicly confirmed, although Coffee Talk publisher Toge Productions had said he had been suffering from asthma. When Afterlove EP starts and players get a glimpse of protagonist's Rama relationship with Cinta, who also has signs of respiratory problems, followed by urgent messages on his phone that he receives too late, it's hard not to draw eerie parallels with what the team would have personally experienced.</p>
<p>"With Fahmi's passing, we were all experiencing the feeling that Rama feels and we understand what he is going through very intimately," says Dany. "It's hard to point to any specific elements where it has changed but in everything we've done, we hold Fahmi close to our hearts and think about what he would say if he was here."</p>
<p>But even with Fahmi's passing early in Afterlove EP's development, it wasn't as if the team was at a complete loss.</p>
<p>"One thing I like from working with Fahmi is that he doesn't leave anything in a grey area – either it's black or white," game producer Ivor Dwitomo explains. "He knew what he wanted for sure. The story outline was well documented before he passed away and the big direction decisions for Afterlove EP from start to end were very clear."</p>
<p>There was still a big task for that narrative to be broken down into scenes and dialogue, with writing totally over 100,000 words. "There are always changes as you go from planning to actually writing, and seeing it in the game then rewriting and so on, so we could not keep everything set in stone," Dwitomo adds.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/afterlove-ep1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>One of the songs in Afterlove EP is dedicated to Fahmi</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Fortunately, Fahmi was not Afterlove EP's only writer at the time, having also worked closely with Sasha Ariana, who was also a writer on his previous game What Comes After as well as A Space for the Unbound. She naturally stepped in to be the game's narrative lead.</p>
<p>"She is the keeper of the vision for the story and has helped guide the new writers to ensure we maintain Fahmi's vision for the story," Dwitomo says. "Whilst being open to feedback and making changes to some of the details to help the game achieve that vision and be as good as possible."</p>
<p>Another team member that really aided in pooling the team's knowledge from working with Fahmi was lead programmer Giri Prahasta Iruma. "He's like a human database," says Dany. "If we have questions about direction on something he can always find links to old chats with Fahmi discussing it, and Fahmi's answers even then were so clear – the why, the direction, the target experience. So it's been both Fahmi's outlines and vision and Giri's knowledge to help us never get off track."</p>
<p>Pikselnesia's personal experiences won't mean there is an authored version of how Rama processes his grief. This is still a choice-based narrative game where there will be different outcomes on how he will move on or not, whether he can find new love, or keep his band together. Those choices in what you can do are also under the constraint of a Persona-inspired calendar structure as the story takes place over a 30-day period.</p>
<blockquote><p>"We don't know what will happen in the future but I have the feeling the team will meet again to make something"</p>
<cite>Ivor Dwitomo, Pikselnesia</cite></blockquote>
<p>More importantly, Afterlove EP's not about wallowing in grief. There's even a light touch to it given that Rama's basically hearing and talking to the cheery voice of his deceased girlfriend inside his head, leading to some awkward but humorous moments with his friends.</p>
<p>"Sadness and grief will not dominate in the story – all emotional aspects will be there," says Dwitomo. "This is more about Rama's future than his past. The game starts one year after Cinta's passing and Rama is just starting to come out of his shell and become open to the world again. He wants to move forward but he's nervous and scared and not sure how to – does he want to try to make music seriously? What sort of relationships and friendships does he want to have? Can he love again? How can he honour Cinta's memory and do these things at the same time?"</p>
<p>One of Fahmi's key goals was for Afterlove EP to also help put Indonesia's capital of Jakarta, the setting of the game, on the map. That's still very much the case where players will primarily be exploring areas in the city's W Bloc, based on Jakarta's real life M Bloc as both a thriving space for shopping and nightlife.</p>
<p>Also giving an authentic flavour of the local culture, the game also includes songs from Jakarta-based band L'alphalpha, who are also a key plot point in the story. We're told that four of the tracks contributed had also been recorded after Fahmi's passing, with one song dedicated to him specifically.</p>
<p>"That song is called Mimpi, and the lyrics are very much dedicated to Fahmi. The lyrics hit us very hard," Dany adds.</p>
<p>But if finishing Afterlove EP is fulfilling Fahmi's last wish, then what comes after? While Pikselnesia was his studio and legacy, it's most likely that the team will disband once the game is complete.</p>
<p>"Before Fahmi passed away, I had a discussion with him about the next project for Pikselnesia," Dwitomo explains, though those ideas were never shared. Hopefully its members will be able to move on once the game is released and in turn have new stories to tell.</p>
<p>"We don't know what will happen in the future but I have the feeling the team will meet again to make something."</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Monopoly GO: All Map of Fortunes rewards and milestones]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/monopoly-go-all-map-of-fortunes-rewards-and-milestones/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=monopoly-go-all-map-of-fortunes-rewards-and-milestones</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/monopoly-go-all-map-of-fortunes-rewards-and-milestones.879324/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/monopoly-go-all-map-of-fortunes-rewards-and-milestones/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=monopoly-go-all-map-of-fortunes-rewards-and-milestones<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="244" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><em>Monopoly GO’s</em> Map of Fortunes banner event is here for the first time. During it, you’ll travel around your Monopoly board, land on points tiles, and claim up to 50 rewards. Here’s the complete list of Map of Fortunes rewards.</p> <h2 id="h-all-monopoly-go-map-of-fortunes-event-rewards-and-milestones" data-injectable="false">All Monopoly GO Map of Fortunes event rewards and milestones</h2> <p data-characters="251" data-current-count="251" data-injectable="false"><em>Monopoly GO’s</em> Map of Fortunes event has 50 rewards to claim until May 25. Finishing every milestone gives you 13,925 dice, nine sticker packs, and 185 pickaxes for the Sunken Treasures dig event. Below is the entire Map of Fortunes rewards list.</p> <figure data-found-rows="50" data-items-injection="true" data-current-count="2551" data-injectable="true"><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Event Level</th><th data-align="center">Points Required</th><th data-align="center">Rewards</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr data-index="0"><td data-align="center">1</td><td data-align="center">25</td><td data-align="center">One-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="1"><td data-align="center">2</td><td data-align="center">40</td><td data-align="center">25 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="2"><td data-align="center">3</td><td data-align="center">20</td><td data-align="center">Four pickaxes <br>(Sunken Treasures)</td></tr><tr data-index="3"><td data-align="center">4</td><td data-align="center">50</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="4"><td data-align="center">5</td><td data-align="center">150</td><td data-align="center">90 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="5"><td data-align="center">6</td><td data-align="center">45</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="6"><td data-align="center">7</td><td data-align="center">50</td><td data-align="center">One-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="7"><td data-align="center">8</td><td data-align="center">40</td><td data-align="center">Five pickaxes <br>(Sunken Treasures)</td></tr><tr data-index="8"><td data-align="center">9</td><td data-align="center">55</td><td data-align="center">10 minutes of Cash Grab</td></tr><tr data-index="9" data-injectable="true"><td data-align="center">10</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">225 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr><td colspan="3">
</td></tr><tr data-index="10"><td data-align="center">11</td><td data-align="center">40</td><td data-align="center">Seven pickaxes <br>(Sunken Treasures)</td></tr><tr data-index="11"><td data-align="center">12</td><td data-align="center">60</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="12"><td data-align="center">13</td><td data-align="center">70</td><td data-align="center">One-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="13"><td data-align="center">14</td><td data-align="center">80</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="14"><td data-align="center">15</td><td data-align="center">85</td><td data-align="center">Eight pickaxes <br>(Sunken Treasures)</td></tr><tr data-index="15"><td data-align="center">16</td><td data-align="center">850</td><td data-align="center">475 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="16"><td data-align="center">17</td><td data-align="center">90</td><td data-align="center">Two-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="17"><td data-align="center">18</td><td data-align="center">100</td><td data-align="center">15 minutes of Rent Frenzy</td></tr><tr data-index="18"><td data-align="center">19</td><td data-align="center">120</td><td data-align="center">10 pickaxes <br>(Sunken Treasures)</td></tr><tr data-index="19" data-injectable="true"><td data-align="center">20</td><td data-align="center">140</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr><td colspan="3">
</td></tr><tr data-index="20"><td data-align="center">21</td><td data-align="center">1,200</td><td data-align="center">600 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="21"><td data-align="center">22</td><td data-align="center">150</td><td data-align="center">12 pickaxes <br>(Sunken Treasures)</td></tr><tr data-index="22"><td data-align="center">23</td><td data-align="center">180</td><td data-align="center">Three-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="23"><td data-align="center">24</td><td data-align="center">200</td><td data-align="center">70 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="24"><td data-align="center">25</td><td data-align="center">250</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="25"><td data-align="center">26</td><td data-align="center">2,000</td><td data-align="center">850 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="26"><td data-align="center">27</td><td data-align="center">250</td><td data-align="center">10 minutes of High Roller</td></tr><tr data-index="27"><td data-align="center">28</td><td data-align="center">275</td><td data-align="center">16 pickaxes <br>(Sunken Treasures)</td></tr><tr data-index="28"><td data-align="center">29</td><td data-align="center">300</td><td data-align="center">Four-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="29" data-injectable="true"><td data-align="center">30</td><td data-align="center">400</td><td data-align="center">100 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr><td colspan="3">
</td></tr><tr data-index="30"><td data-align="center">31</td><td data-align="center">1,600</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="31"><td data-align="center">32</td><td data-align="center">500</td><td data-align="center">18 pickaxes <br>(Sunken Treasures)</td></tr><tr data-index="32"><td data-align="center">33</td><td data-align="center">600</td><td data-align="center">140 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="33"><td data-align="center">34</td><td data-align="center">700</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="34"><td data-align="center">35</td><td data-align="center">800</td><td data-align="center">20 pickaxes <br>(Sunken Treasures)</td></tr><tr data-index="35"><td data-align="center">36</td><td data-align="center">3,800</td><td data-align="center">1,300 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="36"><td data-align="center">37</td><td data-align="center">900</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="37"><td data-align="center">38</td><td data-align="center">1,000</td><td data-align="center">Five minutes of Cash Boost</td></tr><tr data-index="38"><td data-align="center">39</td><td data-align="center">2,000</td><td data-align="center">Five-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="39" data-injectable="true"><td data-align="center">40</td><td data-align="center">1,500</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr><td colspan="3">
</td></tr><tr data-index="40"><td data-align="center">41</td><td data-align="center">7,000</td><td data-align="center">2,200 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="41"><td data-align="center">42</td><td data-align="center">1,600</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="42"><td data-align="center">43</td><td data-align="center">1,550</td><td data-align="center">35 pickaxes <br>(Sunken Treasures)</td></tr><tr data-index="43"><td data-align="center">44</td><td data-align="center">1,700</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="44"><td data-align="center">45</td><td data-align="center">1,800</td><td data-align="center">550 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="45"><td data-align="center">46</td><td data-align="center">6,000</td><td data-align="center">Cash</td></tr><tr data-index="46"><td data-align="center">47</td><td data-align="center">2,000</td><td data-align="center">600 Dice Rolls</td></tr><tr data-index="47"><td data-align="center">48</td><td data-align="center">4,000</td><td data-align="center">50 pickaxes <br>(Sunken Treasures)</td></tr><tr data-index="48"><td data-align="center">49</td><td data-align="center">6,000</td><td data-align="center">Five-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr><tr data-index="49"><td data-align="center">50</td><td data-align="center">16,000</td><td data-align="center">6,700 Dice Rolls<br>Five-Star Sticker Pack</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
 <p data-characters="312" data-current-count="312" data-injectable="false">Sunken Treasures pickaxes are especially helpful, as you can use them to claim additional prizes during the ongoing digging event. Sunken Treasures has its&nbsp;own&nbsp;rewards, ranging from dice to a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.destructoid.com/how-to-get-wild-stickers-in-monopoly-go/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wild Sticker</a>. Take advantage of Map of Fortunes’ prizes to advance further in Sunken Treasures, and vice versa.</p> <h2 id="h-how-to-score-points-in-the-monopoly-go-map-of-fortunes-event" data-injectable="false">How to score points in the&nbsp;<em>Monopoly GO</em>&nbsp;Map of Fortunes event</h2> <p data-characters="137" data-current-count="449" data-injectable="true">Scoring points during the Map of Fortunes event by landing on Chance, Community Chest, and Railroad tiles. Below are the points for each:</p>
 <ul data-found-items="3" data-current-count="120" data-injectable="false"> <li>Chance: Two points</li> <li>Community Chest: Three points</li> <li>Railroad: Five points</li> </ul> <p data-characters="400" data-current-count="520" data-injectable="false">Out of every&nbsp;<em>Monopoly GO</em>&nbsp;event, these are the types that require the most points, making it more&nbsp;important&nbsp;than ever to manage your dice rolls. You can increase your dice multiplier to raise the points you receive at the cost of using more dice with each roll. Of these three tiles, Chance and Railroad are your best bet, as Chance can lead you into Railroad, giving you the most points possible.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus is back, but is it bigger and better?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/23/multiversus-2024-preview-back-but-is-it-better/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-is-back-but-is-it-bigger-and-better.879303/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/23/multiversus-2024-preview-back-but-is-it-better/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>It was an odd and almost unheard of situation when Warner Bros. Games closed off free-to-play platform fighter MultiVersus last year. What was a seemingly live and active online fighting game with two seasons of content released was taken away from players less than a year after its initial release. Sure, it was technically branded as an “open beta” thoughout, but it was baffling to see it go offline with a promised relaunch for 2024. Why shut the game down for that long?&nbsp;It didn’t seem to be in crisis, since there was an active playerbase and even plans for community tournaments. Fans of the mashup brawler weren’t sure what big revamps or additions necessitated the year of complete lack of access to the game. After spending some time with the new version of MultiVersus that’s set to launch on 28th May, I’m still not sure I understand the logic behind this.</p>
<p><iframe title="MultiVersus - Official Launch Trailer &quot;Stars Collide. Pies Fly.&quot;" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qX5AUVIAg_o?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>If you’re a returning player from the initial version of the game, everything that was there is back – all 23 playable characters, every stage, and even any cosmetics or items you unlocked and purchased. Of course there’s also new additions, with a Mark Hamill voiced Joker, Agent Smith from The Matrix, a hockey masked Jason, and more naturally on the way.</p>


<p>Back when MultiVersus was first online, it featured a loaded cash shop, and multiple premium battle passes stuffed with cosmetics and currency, and none of this has changed in the new version of MultiVersus – well, <a href="http://multiversus.com/en/news/multiversus-developer-series-welcome-back-rewards-battle-pass-and-economy-changes">they’ve rejigged the currency names and what they do a bit</a>. If you’re a fan of collecting daily rewards, multiple currencies, and hundreds of tiered Battle Pass unlocks, the system at play here won’t bother you one bit. If you’re someone who’s a little exhausted by every game being turned into a job, though, it feels weird to boot up this big new relaunch of MultiVersus after a year and be greeted by the same slightly overwhelming seasonal objectives and mission lists that were there last time.</p>


<p>Some aspects of the experience are harder for me to directly compare to the open beta version of MultiVersus – a year out from the shut down of that version, and I don’t really remember the nuances of how combat felt or how the netcode performed, nor do I have any way to quickly revisit that version of the game for reference. Here’s what I came away from this new version of MultiVersus with, though: this game is now slow.</p>
<p>Combat, according to developer blog posts, has been reworked significantly to take the focus away from a constant flow of attack inputs and make everything much more deliberate, readable and possible to react to. The result is a platform fighter with next to no momentum. Every attack animation has a slow, winding start that completely cancels out the visual momentum of the move that came before it. Instead of stringing together a combo of basic and special attacks as Wonder Woman, I’m waiting and watching her perform a neutral attack, then waiting and watching her perform a neutral side attack, and then waiting some more as she busts out the Up Special I feel like I input hours ago.</p>

<p>This shift in speed and stilted animation momentum don’t necessarily make the game easier, but rather a lot less exciting. On harder difficulties and in full 2v2 matches against AI, I still found myself sweating to dodge projectiles and maintain control over the platform edges, but I wasn’t having fun anymore. I remember MultiVersus originally being entertaining to pick up and play with friends for the simple yet consistently breezy chaos of each match. That feeling hasn’t returned with this reworked version of the game.</p>
<p>One big change that adds a bit of depth to the game is a new PvE Rift mode. Instead of queuing up for standard battles, you’re given thematic Chapters with webs of individual encounters to dive into, each with their own unique modifiers, hazards, and more. It’s a lot like the Spirit mode of Super Smash Bros. Ultimate, giving you dozens of uniquely modified parameters under which to fight the various characters. Some battles have minor yet entertaining changes, like equipping you with infinite-jump Angel Wings or rendering the entire screen in Matrix-style green and black wireframe. Other stages throw entirely unique minigames at you, like getting in a jumprope competition or fending off a giant boss mech.</p>

<p>It’s paired with a new Gem system – beat Nodes in this mode to unlock and upgrade Gems of different categories that grant you a variety of minor combat buffs or ability changes. Some are basic boosts like a chance at receiving a 10% attack damage buff before battle, while others let you customize your character kit a bit by activating the powers of other characters. Early on I found a gem that triggered Black Adam’s lightning whenever I dodged with a full meter, adding some interesting new utility to that move. As far as I could tell, there wasn’t a mode available to take your Gem-equipped character into battle against other players – but even with this locked away in a singleplayer mode, it’s a pretty solid way to spend time with the game and get some experience with the systems and characters before you try to head online.</p>
<p>While the new singleplayer mode is a pretty significant addition for the game, MultiVersus ultimately doesn’t feel much better off from where it was just over a year ago. In some ways it actually feels worse – with combat feeling far more sluggish and lethargic than I ever remembered it being in the open beta version of the game. Hopefully these combat reworks aren’t set in stone, and the team can take on board feedback and readjust when this new and not-entirely-improved version of MultiVersus goes live on 28th May.</p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Embracer Group Has Over 70 Projects in the Works]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-group-financials-70-projects</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/embracer-group-has-over-70-projects-in-the-works.879300/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-group-financials-70-projects<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Embracer Group has released its financial statement for both the last fiscal year and the final quarter of said year, and it includes a tease for the impressive amount of projects the group currently has in its pipeline.</p>

<p>According to an Embracer <a href="https://embracer.com/releases/embracer-group-publishes-interim-report-q4-january-march-2024-adjusted-ebit-increased-by-56-to-sek-1426-million/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">press release</a>, the group has more than 70 projects in the works across its many subsidiaries right now, and that number includes "at least three important unannounced titles".</p>

<p>Those projects are slated to be released across the next financial year, which ends in March 2025. The lineup includes games like&nbsp;<em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</em>, which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-leak">was announced recently</a>, as well as&nbsp;<em>Killing Floor 3</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-embracer-group-financials.jpg?itok=2VCPE5D_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/kingdom-come-deliverance-2-embracer-group-financials.jpg?itok=MDFZBbV8 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2&nbsp;</em>is just one of the 70-plus games Embracer Group is planning to release this year.</figcaption></figure><p>Embracer says that across the year, it saw a 12% increase in sales, driven largely by its tabletop and entertainment sectors (although its gaming sectors also returned modest sales increases).</p>

<p>In gaming terms, those increases were driven by&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/games/tomb-raider-1-3-remastered"><em>Tomb Raider 1-3 Remastered</em></a>, which Embracer says "performed above management expectations", as well as&nbsp;<em>Star Wars: Battlefront Classic Collection</em>, which sold well despite the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-battlefront-classic-collection-aspyr-response">controversy surrounding its release</a>.</p>

<p>Another big earner for Embracer was&nbsp;<em>Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor</em>, with the&nbsp;<em>Vampire Survivors</em>-esque&nbsp;<em>Deep Rock Galactic&nbsp;</em>spinoff outperforming management's expectations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It's not all sunshine and roses, though. Some of the games released during this period underperformed, according to Embracer, including survival horror reboot&nbsp;<em>Alone in the Dark&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Outcast: A New Beginning</em>, a sequel to the 1999 cult classic open-world adventure.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/outcast-a-new-beginning-embracer-group-financials.jpg?itok=H2dhbAQA 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/outcast-a-new-beginning-embracer-group-financials.jpg?itok=sxwaoeN6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Outcast: A New Beginning&nbsp;</em>wasn't the success Embracer Group and THQ Nordic hoped for.</figcaption></figure><p>Earlier this year, Embracer announced its intention to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-group-splitting-three-companies">split into three separate entities</a>: Coffee Stain and Friends, Middle-earth Enterprises and Friends, and Asmodee (the latter of which will <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/asmodee-group-saddled-with-eu900-million-debt-by-embracer-group">inherit a pretty hefty euro debt</a> as a result).</p>

<p>Embracer CEO Lars Wingefors says he's "confident" that this decision will unleash "significant untapped potential" within Embracer, and according to the latest report, the group's shareholders largely agree.</p>

<p>That untapped potential includes projects outside of the gaming space, including an upcoming&nbsp;<em>Tomb Raider&nbsp;</em>live-action series that forms part of the brand's continuing expansion into streaming and film.</p>

<p>In gaming, Embracer's upcoming slate includes the&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/amazon-to-develop-and-globally-publish-tomb-raider-game"><em>Tomb Raider&nbsp;</em>game</a> currently being developed in conjunction with Amazon, as well as a new&nbsp;<em>Painkiller&nbsp;</em>title, the&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/gothic-1-remake-collectors-edition"><em>Gothic&nbsp;</em>remake</a>, and <em>Metro Awakening</em>.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/gothic-1-remake-embracer-group-financials.jpg?itok=98rlJnkg 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/gothic-1-remake-embracer-group-financials.jpg?itok=Pzj-4pT6 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Gothic 1 Remake&nbsp;</em>is one of Embracer's many upcoming projects, although it still doesn't have a release date.</figcaption></figure><p>All of this is taking place against the backdrop of a major restructuring effort at Embracer, which has seen <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-has-laid-off-8-of-its-employees-and-it-isnt-done-yet-despite-record-quarter">many employees lose their jobs</a> and several studios either closed or <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nearly-100-employees-laid-off-at-eidos-montreal-as-embracers-job-killing-spree">severely downsized</a>.</p>

<p>Affected studios include Gearbox, which was <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/grand-theft-auto-publisher-take-two-to-acquire-gearbox-from-embracer-new-borderlands-in">sold to Take-Two in March</a>, as well as&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-group-saber-interactive"><em>Space Marine 2&nbsp;</em>publisher Saber Interactive</a>&nbsp;and more. Studios closed down by Embracer include&nbsp;<a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/embracer-shuts-down-saints-row-developer-volition"><em>Saints Row&nbsp;</em>developer Volition</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>TimeSplitters&nbsp;</em>studio <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/probable-images-of-free-radicals-timesplitters-game-revealed-after-studio-closure-by">Free Radical</a>.</p>

<p>Embracer acknowledges these closures and layoffs in its financial report, calling them "necessary but difficult decisions" and emphasizing the "compassion, respect and integrity" with which the layoffs and closures were apparently carried out.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more info on all things Embracer.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for five years, and in those five years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GeForce NOW Adds Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II to Its Cloud Library]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-adds-senuas-saga-hellblade-ii-to-its-cloud-library/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/geforce-now-adds-senua%E2%80%99s-saga-hellblade-ii-to-its-cloud-library.879297/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/geforce-now-adds-senuas-saga-hellblade-ii-to-its-cloud-library/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, NVIDIA announced the new games added this week to its GeForce NOW cloud platform. The library now has over 1,900 games, including Senua's Saga: Hellblade II, which launched just a couple of days ago.</p>
<p>GeForce NOW users subscribed to the Priority tier can enable NVIDIA DLSS Super Resolution or NVIDIA DLAA as well as NVIDIA Reflex. GeForce NOW users subscribed to the Ultimate tier can also enable DLSS Frame Generation to get the best performance in the game.</p>
<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/senuas-saga-hellblade-ii-the-perfect-game-pass-experience/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">In my review of the game</a>, I wrote:</p>
<p><em>Senua's Saga: Hellblade II keeps virtually the same scope and structure of the independent triple-A game made in 2017 by Ninja Theory. The story is just as poignant, the visuals are stunning, and the experience is one that every Game Pass user should check out for themselves. However, those hoping for a more traditional game in the vein of the God of War reboot will inevitably be disappointed, and this is unlikely to have nearly that level of success, which is what Microsoft still desperately needs.</em></p>
<p>Here's the full list of GeForce NOW games added this week:</p>
<p>● Synergy (New release on Steam, May 21)<br>
● Senua’s Saga: Hellblade II (New release on Steam and Xbox, available on PC Game Pass, May 21)<br>
● Crown Wars: The Black Prince (New release on Steam, May 23)<br>
● Serum (New release on Steam, May 23)<br>
● Ships at Sea (New release on Steam, May 23)<br>
● Exo One (Steam)<br>
● Phantom Brigade (Steam)</p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paper App Dungeon Review]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/paper-app-dungeon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/paper-app-dungeon-review.879294/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/paper-app-dungeon<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Have you ever sat on a long journey, and thought, I wish I was roleplaying right now? Or gone camping or hiking and not wanted to take a huge board game or tons of RPG books? Lucy Duck Games and Tom Brinton have your back, with <em>Paper App Dungeon</em>, the travel roleplaying, dungeon exploring notebook.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/paper-app-dungeon-2.jpg?itok=u5wCEk_u 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/paper-app-dungeon-2.jpg?itok=2nNUthll 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Each <em>Paper App Dungeon</em> box comes with a notebook and a special P6 pencil.</figcaption></figure><h2>What Do You Get With Paper App Dungeon?</h2>

<p><em>Paper App Dungeon</em> comes with a unique dungeon notebook, which are procedurally generated so that no two notebooks are the same, and a special P6 pencil. The P6 acts as your writing implement, and your dice, with 1 through 6 printed on the sides of it, which you roll to move during the game. The only issue is that the pencil can roll forever, especially if you're traveling. The idea of it is awesome, and it keeps the whole experience simple and portable, but I found myself using my own six-sided dice (D6) so that I didn't have to chase the pencil around.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/paper-app-dungeon-3.jpg?itok=cVZkAUuF 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/paper-app-dungeon-3.jpg?itok=RTrlgzC5 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Each&nbsp;<em>Paper App Dungeon </em>notebook comes with 45 maps to play through.</figcaption></figure><h2>How Do You Play Paper App Dungeon?</h2>

<p><em>Paper App Dungeon </em>comes with the rules printed on the first three pages of the notebook, but a much more robust and easier-to-understand rulebook is available <a href="https://kind-jackson-99b826.netlify.app/files/Paper-Apps-DUNGEON-Guide.pdf">here</a>. For each map, you find the starting space and roll the P6. If you get 1, 3, or 5, you can move diagonally, 2, 4, or 6 and you move&nbsp;orthogonally. You have to move your complete distance rolled in a straight line, marking on the map as you go, and if you hit a wall, you can change directions.</p>

<p>On your travels, you will come across enemies, who take away your hit points, and treasure in the form of coins and chests. As you take damage or gain coins, you total them at the bottom of the page, and once you reach the exit, you total both up. If you have a negative health number, you start the next page with 10 health and 0 coins, but if you have a positive health number, you carry it over, along with your coins.</p>

<p>Occasionally, you can also come across stores, where you can increase your starting health, and also buy potions to use during maps. The final page in the book has a tally for your deaths and your final HP and Coin total, so you can compare them against your next <em>Paper App Dungeon</em> journey.</p>

<p>The challenge in <em>Paper App Dungeon</em> is predicting the dice rolls, and trying to avoid putting yourself in a position where you will move through enemies regardless of the roll. Sometimes calculated risks pay off, or if you know that between you and the exit are limited enemies (in our Floor 1 image below, you can see we headed straight through the enemy at the top of the map because it was a straight line to the exit after). T</p>

<p>There doesn't feel like a big payoff for taking risks for coins, because if you end up on negative health points at the end, you lose all of your coins, and even putting yourself on low health going into the next map makes that map even harder. You can play however you want, but I found that taking the simple routes, with calculated risks and minimal coins to keep my death tally down was the way I played through the maps.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/paper-app-dungeon-4.jpg?itok=n_sGSVcO 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/paper-app-dungeon-4.jpg?itok=GsYxwWZY 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Our first&nbsp;<em>Paper App Dungeon </em>adventure was very straightforward. Fought an enemy, got some loot, and made for the exit.</figcaption></figure><h2>How Long Is Paper App Dungeon?</h2>

<p><em>Paper App Dungeon </em>includes 45 maps total to play through. Each one can take as little as a few minutes (if you roll well), or much longer if the dice are against you and you end up bouncing around tight rooms on the map. Because each map is procedurally generated, some can be very easy, and some have particularly testing moments, but that's the nature of adventuring, and nothing is fair in the gloom of the dungeon.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/paper-app-dungeon-6.jpg?itok=7gEgqUPh 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/paper-app-dungeon-6.jpg?itok=Y2ibVX1y 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>The final page of the&nbsp;<em>Paper App Dungeon </em>notebook includes a tally tracker for deaths, along with your final health and gold total.</figcaption></figure><h2>What Are Our Final Thoughts On Paper App Dungeon?</h2>

<p><em>Paper App Dungeon </em>is a fun little game and incredible for travel adventures, or for introducing younger players to tabletop games. The P6 while a great concept, isn't great for travel, and can roll forever, so we ended up using a standard 6-sided dice. The rulebook, while well condensed into 3 pages at the front of the notebook, is much easier to understand in the full format we linked to above. Once understood, you won't require it again, but that initial read of the condensed 3 pages can be confusing. It's a fun little package though overall, and I will be picking up another next time I travel.</p>

<h2>Should I Buy Paper App Dungeon?</h2>

<p>If you want a quick pick-up-and-play game for travel, or to introduce younger players, then <em>Paper App Dungeon</em> is perfect in terms of size, portability, fun, and ease of use (take your own dice with you on travel though). If you're looking for a roleplaying game or dungeon exploring board game with depth or character development, then&nbsp;<em>Paper App Dungeon </em>isn't that.</p>

<hr><p><em>The copy of</em> <strong>Paper App Dungeon</strong>&nbsp;<em>used to produce this review was provided by Lucky Duck Games.</em></p>


</div><div><p><span><div>
  <div>
            <h2>Review Summary</h2>
                    
                <p>
                            Paper App Dungeon is a fun little game and incredible for travel adventures, or for introducing younger players to tabletop games. The P6 while a great concept, isn't great for travel, and can roll forever, so we ended up using a standard six-sided dice. The rulebook, while well condensed into 3 pages at the front of the notebook, is much easier to understand in the full format we linked to above. Once understood, you won't require it again, but that initial read of the condensed 3 pages can be confusing. It's a fun little package though overall, and I will be picking up another next time I travel. (<a href="https://techraptor.net/review-score-policy">Review Policy</a>)
                    </p>
      </div>
  <div>
    <div>
                  <h3>Pros</h3>
          <div><ul><li>A solid and fun time filler</li></ul></div>
            </div>
    <div>
                <h3>Cons</h3>
          <div><ul><li>Full rules online are easier to understand than those in the notebook</li><li>Pencil rolls forever, especially during travel</li></ul></div>
          </div>
  </div>
</div></span></p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Adam is a Tabletop Specialist for TechRaptor. He started writing for TechRaptor in 2017 and took over as Tabletop Editor in 2019 and has since stood down… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/adam-potts">More about Adam</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MultiVersus is relaunching — here’s what’s new and what’s changing]]></title>
            <link>https://www.polygon.com/24162522/multiversus-relaunch-banana-guard-agent-smith-jason-vorhees</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/multiversus-is-relaunching-%E2%80%94-here%E2%80%99s-what%E2%80%99s-new-and-what%E2%80%99s-changing.879288/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.polygon.com/24162522/multiversus-relaunch-banana-guard-agent-smith-jason-vorhees<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p id="0LQCJU">Warner Bros.’ fighting game <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2022/9/13/23345074/multiversus-opinion-dodge-cooldown-meter-ui-player-first-games"><em>MultiVersus</em></a> returns on Tuesday, May 28 with its <a href="https://www.polygon.com/23933735/multiversus-announcement-relaunch-release-date-warner-bros">long-awaited relaunch</a>. The <a href="https://www.polygon.com/22789132/multiversus-warner-bros-dc-game-of-thrones-bugs-bunny">Super Smash Bros.-inspired platform fighter</a> is getting a big overhaul next week, with an expanded roster, new visuals, and improved netcode, which developer Player First Games designed to make online multiplayer matches feel just like local, four-folks-on-the-same-couch matches.</p>
<p id="saFRQT">There’s a long list of changes coming with the official launch of <em>MultiVersus</em> — the previous version was labeled an open beta, you see — and we’ll break down what’s new below.</p>
<h2 id="a0hbSW"><strong>New fighters</strong></h2>
<p id="48SUpV">Four new characters are confirmed for <em>MultiVersus</em> in season 1, which kicks off May 28. They are <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24155348/multiversus-joker-gameplay-mark-hamill-powerpuff-girls">DC’s Joker</a> (once again voiced by Mark Hamill), <em>Adventure Time</em>’s Banana Guard, <a href="https://www.polygon.com/24160800/multiversus-trailer-matrix-agent-smith-jason-voorhees"><em>Friday the 13th</em>’s Jason Voorhees, and <em>The Matrix</em>’s Agent Smith</a>.</p>
<p id="jvfzn2">Tony Huynh, Player First Games co-founder and game director on <em>MultiVersus</em>, told Polygon in a video interview that Joker is “full of gadgets” and steeped in references to the long history of the character. “We’re realizing that character in a way that I think fans of the Joker will be extremely happy with,” Huynh said. Joker is a mage-type fighter, a class that is currently “not really well-represented in <em>MultiVersus</em>,” Huynh said, “and so [he] also pushes our diversity of the player experience pretty far.”</p>
<div id="N2fV7H"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sT1zXiYqcfA?rel=0" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="sEueKJ">Banana Guard may be the most unexpected new addition to <em>MultiVersus</em>, given that <em>Adventure Time</em> is already represented in the game by Finn the Human and Jake the Dog. Huynh said that Banana Guard’s addition to the roster came from “an individual on our team that was very passionate about [the character],” and shows that “anything’s possible” in <em>MultiVersus</em>. “We aren’t just going to do the expected,” Huynh said. </p>
<p id="GWieaN">Banana Guard will be free at launch for players who complete the game’s new tutorial. A Lady Banana Guard variant will also be free to unlock.</p>
<p id="Mvqe3F">Jason Voorhees brings a new tank-class character to the <em>MultiVersus</em> roster. Jason will be big, and more importantly <em>heavy</em>, dwarfed only by the Iron Giant. “The big challenge there is, if you understand [the fighting game] genre, is that large characters are typically not viable, but [we] looked at it from that experience, like, ‘How <em>do</em> we make a viable large character in the game?’” Huynh said. “And I think we’ve done a really good job of that.”</p>
<p id="N7H2iw">Jason will be available through the game’s season 1 premium battle pass.</p>
<p id="s0Zwhv">Details on Agent Smith are still forthcoming. The recurring villain of The Matrix franchise is due to arrive sometime during season 1 of <em>MultiVersus</em>.</p>
<h2 id="gMMDfu"><strong>New visuals and new netcode</strong></h2>
<div id="byQ4zu"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/W1Yx-Cz0l9U?rel=0" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="bR2DMf">Player First Games says it has rebuilt <em>MultiVersus</em> from the ground up. That includes a tech upgrade, moving from Epic Games’ Unreal Engine 4 to Unreal Engine 5. Expect better-looking, larger characters and improved lighting.</p>
<p id="PJXqxg">More important, from a competitive standpoint, is <em>MultiVersus</em>’ new multiplayer netcode. That means the fighting game community’s tech solution of choice: rollback netcode. Here’s how Player First Games explains it:</p>
<blockquote><p id="RPMgIZ">Simply put, rollback netcode still sends player inputs back and forth, but each button press is accompanied by a precise timestamp, marking the exact moment of activation. This allows the client to reconstruct what would have happened had it received the input at the intended time. By leaping backward, then instantaneously simulating back to where you were, the game delivers an experience that feels smooth and enjoyable. With rollback netcode you’re seeing exactly the same thing as your opponent, meaning that their position and frames of animation are always updated to the most accurate position which continues to be predicted from there.</p></blockquote>
<p id="wrUshn">Huynh told Polygon that the game’s open beta period “really was about us learning as much as possible,” and that the dev team did learn a lot. “Now we have absolute world-class netcode,” he said, “so that players can play with their friends all across the country, and have just an amazing experience that almost feels offline.” Based on my hands-on with a pre-release version of <em>MultiVersus</em>’ new netcode, Player First has delivered. Even intercontinental matches felt surprisingly smooth and lag-free.</p>
<h2 id="RC0wXt"><strong>Rifts, a new PvE mode</strong></h2>
<div id="WA8Yn3"><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3h4Zex58TLo?rel=0&amp;start=93" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></p></div>
<p id="YsdzhE">For players just getting their feet wet in <em>MultiVersus</em> (and those who may want some less-heated competition) there’s something new: rifts, aka battles against computer-controlled opponents. Rifts will provide seasonal challenges and bits of narrative for the game’s ongoing story. Here’s how Player First explains the new PvE mode:</p>
<blockquote><p id="gp8jDO">Each Rift will have a sequence of battles or challenges around a particular theme, whether it’s The Joker infiltrating the Batcave or Batman and Velma teaming up to decide who’s the best detective. These themes will be organized around seasonal “Attunements,” such as Chaos<em>,</em> for the Clown Prince of Crime that is joining our cast in season 1. The same way every <em>MultiVersus</em> battle is bubbling with character interactions, we wanted to make each Rift “uniquely <em>MultiVersus,</em>” every season.    </p></blockquote>
<p id="E29chx">Rifts will have built-in cinematics and story elements, with “characters interacting with each other, tons of minigames, [for] a really diverse kind of experience,” Huynh said. “I think it does a really good job of teaching players how to play the game as well, but also has a lot of novel kind of experiences.”</p>
<p id="Q9VX2y">Player First promises to keep developing and expanding Rifts: “Anything that we can imagine, we can build, and deliver that [...] to players,” Huynh said. He added that, thanks to the game’s new netcode, <em>MultiVersus</em> Rifts can be played in their entirety cooperatively with friends.</p>
<h2 id="I5DGpu"><strong>New currencies</strong></h2>
  <figure>
  <span>
    
    <span data-original="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25459961/MVS_CURRENCY_REDUX_5.jpg">
      
        <picture data-cid="site/picture_element-1716469211_8956_256946" data-cdata="{&quot;asset_id&quot;:25459961,&quot;ratio&quot;:&quot;*&quot;}">
  


  <source srcset="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VDjVIKqCDcmDJ0JZt7w38FuNnw4=/0x0:1920x1080/320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25459961/MVS_CURRENCY_REDUX_5.jpg 320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ks8HS-DkoicbkXLAbcnt8p9PZmo=/0x0:1920x1080/520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25459961/MVS_CURRENCY_REDUX_5.jpg 520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Ennvq6stCnvXS-Y5WGIYrstKG1k=/0x0:1920x1080/720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25459961/MVS_CURRENCY_REDUX_5.jpg 720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QIBOW0i17CBvpn2aTQsHnd6UPJ8=/0x0:1920x1080/920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25459961/MVS_CURRENCY_REDUX_5.jpg 920w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/i0xJ8HskPW9vNpXXyAaPmW-t0fs=/0x0:1920x1080/1120x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25459961/MVS_CURRENCY_REDUX_5.jpg 1120w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y2Sy5Dy0MErTGdxk_q7-kCuKNZQ=/0x0:1920x1080/1320x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25459961/MVS_CURRENCY_REDUX_5.jpg 1320w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/FKf060d82Cz75WLpgwdGwXvvV-4=/0x0:1920x1080/1520x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25459961/MVS_CURRENCY_REDUX_5.jpg 1520w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-ZOlYaDOIFOUVW-B8vucVOSo88I=/0x0:1920x1080/1720x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25459961/MVS_CURRENCY_REDUX_5.jpg 1720w, https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3TmmWCXZ6V4vrXcSWxnuMm2B4mA=/0x0:1920x1080/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:1920x1080):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25459961/MVS_CURRENCY_REDUX_5.jpg 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 1221px) 846px, (min-width: 880px) calc(100vw - 334px), 100vw" type="image/webp">




</picture>

      
    </span>
    
  </span>
  
    <span>
      
      
        <cite>Image: Player First Games/Warner Bros. Games</cite>
      
    </span>
  
</figure>


<p id="s3SmRc">Players who spent real money on <em>MultiVersus</em>’ premium currency, Gleamium, during the game’s open beta will keep that currency, which can be spent on character unlocks and future premium battle passes. Players will also retain character tokens and battle pass tokens earned during the open beta, but Player First and Warner Bros. will no longer offer those currencies.</p>
<p id="g5k0yT">With <em>MultiVersus</em>’ relaunch, in addition to Gleamium, there will be three new currencies:</p>
<ul>
<li id="WPANyb">
<strong>Fighter currency</strong>, which can be earned in-game and used to obtain fighters</li>
<li id="01Acix">
<strong>Perk currency</strong>, which can be earned in-game and be spent on perks, power-ups that players can attach to characters to give them buffs during combat</li>
<li id="tDEkuI">
<strong>Prestige currency</strong>, which rewards players for all of the items and cosmetics they collect for their favorite fighters. “Each cosmetic item you acquire awards its own Prestige currency value based on type and rarity,” <a href="https://multiversus.com/en/news/multiversus-developer-series-welcome-back-rewards-battle-pass-and-economy-changes">Player First wrote in a blog post</a>. “Eventually, you’ll use your Prestige currency to unlock Prestige cosmetics, which represent the rarest cosmetics in the game. These items can only be unlocked using Prestige currency.”</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="mCgLTR"><strong>Will MultiVersus still be free to play when it relaunches?</strong></h2>
<p id="B4iAb1">Yes. The <em>MultiVersus</em> relaunch will be a free download on PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Windows PC, Xbox One, and Xbox Series X. The game will be monetized through premium battle pass purchases and through direct purchases of Gleamium.</p>
  
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atari Acquires Intellivision Brand And Games]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/atari-acquires-intellivision-brand-and-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atari-acquires-intellivision-brand-and-games.879285/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/atari-acquires-intellivision-brand-and-games/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>In <a href="https://x.com/atari/status/1793616648890470410" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a new post</a> on Twitter/X today, Atari announced that it has officially acquired the Intellivision “brand and game library.” </p>



<p>Atari CEO Wade Rosen added that the acquisition is a “rare opportunity to unite former competitors.” Rosen also says it can “bring together fans of the golden age of gaming.” Intellivision will rebrand, but it will still continue distributing the Amico console.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>We acquired the Intellivision brand and game library. 👏</p><p>"This was a very rare opportunity to unite former competitors and bring together fans of the golden age of gaming.” – Wade Rosen</p><p>The former Intellivision will rebrand and continue distribution of the Amico console. <a href="https://t.co/jncWwKq3Go">pic.twitter.com/jncWwKq3Go</a></p></div>— Atari (@atari) <a href="https://twitter.com/atari/status/1793616648890470410?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>In a <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2024/05/23/2887219/0/en/Atari-Acquires-Intellivision-Brand.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wide press release</a>, Atari elaborated on the acquisition. Atari plans to “expand digital and physical distribution of legacy Intellivision games” and “potentially create new games.” </p>



<p>Fans will likely recognize Intellivision for its classic arcade titles, such as the home port of BurgerTime. Notably, Atari only purchased “certain games,” and did not identify the titles involved. </p>



<p>Atari will surely reveal more soon, since the purchase included rights to over 200 titles. It is also already selling merchandise with Intellivision T-shirts.</p>



<p>In today’s press release, Atari also confirmed it will “explore brand and licensing opportunities.” </p>



<p>Intellivision Entertainment CEO Phil Adam expressed trust in Atari regarding its brand. Adam also said that Intellivision looks forward to an “expanded collaboration,” including “a broad array of new Atari and Intellivision titles.”</p>



<p>Late last April, Atari also decided <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/atari-revive-infogrames/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">to revive Infogrames</a> as a publishing label. The move intends to gain IP and publish games outside of Atari’s core portfolio of games. Accordingly, Infogrames even purchased Totally Reliable Delivery Services from tinyBuild.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more of the latest Insider Gaming updates, you can read about the Call of Duty <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-logo-revealed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Black Ops 6 logo</a> surfacing in newspapers, and sign up to receive <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/visit/newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our official newsletter</a>.</p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alone in the Dark Reboot Flopped, Embracer Says After Laying Off Staff]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/alone-in-the-dark-reboot-flopped-embracer-says-after-laying-off-staff</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/alone-in-the-dark-reboot-flopped-embracer-says-after-laying-off-staff.879282/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/alone-in-the-dark-reboot-flopped-embracer-says-after-laying-off-staff<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/alone-in-the-dark">Alone in the Dark reboot</a> failed to meet sales expectations at the embattled Embracer Group, it has said.</p><p>In a financial report for the fiscal year ending March 31, 2024, Embracer said Alone in the Dark and Outcast: A New Beginning both endured “a softer-than-expected performance” and “performed below management expectations.” That’s corporate speak for failed to sell the required number of units to make money.</p><p>Alone in the Dark launched in March as a reimagination of the famous franchise and “a love letter to the 90’s cult classic horror game.” It featured performances from high-profile Hollywood actors Jodie Comer (Killing Eve, Free Guy) and David Harbour (Stranger Things, Black Widow) in their first video game roles, complete with captured likenesses.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Alone in the Dark Review Screens</h3></div></output><p>But despite this, Alone in the Dark failed to capture the attention of the wider gaming public. According to <a href="https://steamdb.info/app/1310410/charts/#max" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SteamDB</a>, it peaked with 1,628 concurrent players on Valve’s platform upon launch, but that figure has tumbled since. At the time of this article’s publication, just 23 accounts were playing Alone in the Dark, with a 24-hour peak of 52.</p><p>IGN’s <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/alone-in-the-dark-review">Alone in the Dark review</a> returned a 6/10. We said: “It’s not without its memorable moments, but Alone in the Dark fails to escape the shadows of the other contemporary survival horror titans that it helped spawn.”</p><p>Embracer’s comments about the commercial performance of Alone in the Dark come a month after its developer, the Embracer-owned Pieces Interactive, <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/a-month-after-the-alone-in-the-dark-reboots-release-it-looks-like-its-developers-are-suffering-layoffs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reportedly suffered a round of layoffs</a>. Embracer has yet to comment on those layoffs. </p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Embracer has laid off thousands of staff since the collapse of a $2 billion deal, reportedly with Saudi government funded company <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/embracer-groups-partner-who-walked-from-2-billion-deal-finally-revealed"><u>Savvy Games Group</u></a>, in 2023. In January it emerged that <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/embracer-group-reportedly-cancels-deus-ex-video-game-as-layoffs-hit-eidos-montreal"><u>Embracer had canceled a new Deus Ex game</u></a> that was two years in development and laid off some staff at Eidos Montreal. Some of the Embracer-owned studios to shut down include Saints Row developer <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/saints-row-developer-volition-shut-down-by-embracer-group"><u>Volition</u></a> and Timesplitters developer <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/free-radical-developers-mourn-as-timesplitters-studio-appears-to-shut-down"><u>Free Radical Design</u></a>.</p><p>Last month, after selling off multiple businesses including <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/take-two-buys-gearbox-from-embracer-confirms-development-on-new-borderlands-game"><u>Borderlands maker Gearbox</u></a> and <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/saber-interactive-splits-from-embracer-taking-38-video-game-projects-with-it"><u>Star Wars Knights of the Old Republic remake maker Saber Interactive</u></a>, Embracer announced its intent <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/embracer-splitting-into-three-companies-middle-earth-enterprises-friends-coffee-stain-friends-and-asmodee-group">to split into three separate companies</a>: Asmodee Group, Coffee Stain &amp; Friends, and Middle-earth Enterprises &amp; Friends. The largest shareholder, controversial CEO Lars Wingefors, intends to form a new long-term ownership structure, and “will remain a long-term, active, committed and supportive owner of all three entities,” Embracer said.</p><p>While Alone in the Dark and Outcast: A New Beginning both failed to set tills alight, Embracer said <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/tomb-raider-i-iii-remastered">Tomb Raider I-III Remastered</a> “was positively received and performed above management expectations”, and <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/star-wars-battlefront-classic-collection">Star Wars: Battlefront Classic Collection</a> “saw negative reviews from users, but performed in line with management expectations.” <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/south-park-snow-day">South Park: Snow Day!</a> saw “a mixed reception from critics and users but delivered within expectations.” Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor, “launched to great reception and outperformed management expectations.” Lightyear Frontier, meanwhile, “saw a positive reception and performed well-in-line with management expectations.”</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div><h3>Dead Island 2 - 10 Disgusting Ways To Tear Zombies Apart</h3></div></output><p>Dead Island 2, developed by UK studio Dambuster Studios, is a hit, selling over three million units and reaching over seven million players since launch, a figure boosted by the game’s release on Xbox Game Pass.</p><p>As for what’s coming up from Embracer, it has high hopes for open-world medieval RPG <a href="https://www.ign.com/games/kingdom-come-deliverance-ii">Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</a>, which is due out later in 2024. It said it expects the game will hit Dead Island 2 sales numbers. There’s also Killing Floor 3, Disney Epic Mickey: Rebrushed, Hyperlight Breaker, Gothic Remake, Titan Quest 2 alongside at least three other “important, unannounced releases,” Embracer said. In total, more than 70 game projects are currently expected to be released during the financial year ending March 31, 2025.</p><p>Embracer also owns Middle-earth Enterprises, and has licensed the Lord of the Rings IP to Warner Bros. Pictures and New Line Cinema <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lord-of-the-rings-the-hunt-for-gollum-to-explore-stories-peter-jackson-didnt-have-time-to-cover-in-past-films">for two new films</a>.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Naughty Dog's Neil Druckmann Teases Next Game And Shares His Belief In AI]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-teases-next-game-and-shares-his-belief-in-ai/1100-6523665/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-teases-next-game-and-shares-his-belief-in-ai.879279/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/naughty-dogs-neil-druckmann-teases-next-game-and-shares-his-belief-in-ai/1100-6523665/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523665">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Naughty Dog co-president Neil Druckmann has teased the company's next game and discussed how he believes artificial intelligence can help shape the future of video game development.</p><p>In an<a href="https://www.sony.com/en/SonyInfo/creative-entertainment-vision/interview/2.html" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow"> interview on Sony's website</a>, Druckmann said he's working on potentially the "most thrilling" game he's ever been part of. He didn't share specifics, but he said he believes it could "redefine mainstream perceptions of gaming." He didn't elaborate on that point specifically, but he did highlight how the success of HBO's The Last of US TV show demonstrates that there is a growing fondness for gaming that "transcends all age groups," which is a marked contrast from when Druckmann was growing up.</p><p>"This shift is highlighted by our venture into television with The Last of Us, which I hoped would bridge the gap between gamers and non-gamers. The show's success has spotlighted gaming, illustrating the rich, immersive experiences it offers. This visibility excites me not only for our current project but for the broader potential of gaming to captivate a global audience. I'm eager to see how this new game resonates, especially following the success of The Last of Us," he said.</p><p>Naughty Dog is working on multiple games currently, and they have been described as "<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/naughty-dog-has-two-single-player-games-in-development-described-as-ambitious-and-brand-new/1100-6519980/" data-ref-id="1100-6519980">ambitious" and "brand-new."</a> These will be single-player games. Naughty Dog previously planned to expand into multiplayer in a big way with its The Last of Us multiplayer game, but it was ultimately canceled.</p><p>Also in the interview, Druckmann spoke optimistically--as many have before him--about the prospects for how AI can potentially positively impact video game development in the future.</p><p>"AI is really going to revolutionize how content is being created, although it does bring up some ethical issues we need to address," he said. "With technologies like AI and the ability to do motion capture right from home, we're reducing both costs and technical hurdles, opening the door for us to take on more adventurous projects and push the boundaries of storytelling in games. This evolution is truly empowering creators to bring their visions to life without the traditional obstacles."</p><p>He added: "AI will allow us to create nuanced dialogues and characters, expanding creative possibilities. However, it's crucial to precisely direct these tools to achieve the intended outcomes."</p><p>Naughty Dog's new games have not been announced yet, and there is no word on when they might be. Many believe there could be another PlayStation Showcase event on tap soon, but Sony has yet to confirm anything on that front. Keep checking back with GameSpot for the latest.</p><p>As for the HBO series, The Last of Us Season 2 is filming now and is expected to release in 2025.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swap plants for arcane artifacts in Strange Antiquities, the follow-up to Strange Horticulture]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/swap-plants-for-arcane-artifacts-in-strange-antiquities-the-follow-up-to-strange-horticulture/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=swap-plants-for-arcane-artifacts-in-strange-antiquities-the-follow-up-to-strange-horticulture</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/swap-plants-for-arcane-artifacts-in-strange-antiquities-the-follow-up-to-strange-horticulture.879276/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/swap-plants-for-arcane-artifacts-in-strange-antiquities-the-follow-up-to-strange-horticulture/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=swap-plants-for-arcane-artifacts-in-strange-antiquities-the-follow-up-to-strange-horticulture<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="337" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><em>Strange Horticulture</em>‘s developer Bad Viking has today announced a follow-up to its occult plant investigation and puzzle title: <em>Strange Antiquities</em>. The sequel is set in the same location of Undermere but explores the arcane artifacts, which puts you in a position where you’ll be meeting those interested in acquiring them. </p> <p data-characters="380" data-current-count="380" data-injectable="false">In <em>Stange Antiquities</em>, you’ll take on the role of an antique store owner. Running the business requires you to interact with all sorts of characters from Undermere and help them solve their fairly unique problems through the use of arcane artifacts. Along the way, there are mysteries and puzzles to be solved that will see you dive deeper into the town’s murky lore. </p> <h2 id="h-strange-antiquities-is-a-dark-and-cozy-adventure-that-welcomes-players-into-its-mysteries" data-injectable="false"><em>Strange Antiquities</em> is a dark and cozy adventure that welcomes players into its mysteries</h2> <figure data-current-count="680" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>Image via Bad Viking</figcaption></figure>
 <p data-characters="330" data-current-count="330" data-injectable="false">The bulk of the gameplay in <em>Strange Antiquities</em> will revolve around solving puzzles and mysteries. You’ll do this by taking requests from customers in the store, helping them solve their problems with the artifacts you’ve procured so far, and uncovering as much information as you can about the local town, Undermere. </p> <p data-characters="473" data-current-count="803" data-injectable="true">There are books to leaf through in search of clues, information, and references you can use as you explore Undermere to help the locals in any way you can. The visuals make the game look like a cozy shop simulator, and I’m looking forward to seeing and feeling how the juxtaposition with cosmic horror elements pays off in action. I didn’t expect fishing and cosmic horror to go together so well in <em><a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-dredge-indie-pc-ps4-ps5-xbox-one-series-x-s-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dredge</a>,</em> so I’m hopeful this game will suck me right in. </p>
 <p data-characters="318" data-current-count="318" data-injectable="false">The game is a sequel to <em>Strange Horticulture</em>, taking place years after its story came to a close. However, <em>Stange Antiquities</em> is designed to be a standalone experience, so you don’t need to have played the first game to enjoy it. However, it’s probably worth doing so just to see how the town has evolved. </p> <p data-characters="371" data-current-count="689" data-injectable="true">With almost 10,000 positive reviews on Steam and over 500,000 copies sold, Bad Viking considers <em>Stange Horticulture</em> a massive success for an independent game developer. It hopes to live up to the reputation it built with that game and deliver yet another title that fans of the first will enjoy, but also welcome newcomers into its strange, cosmic horror-inspired world. </p>
 <p data-characters="190" data-current-count="190" data-injectable="false">There is no release date for the game at the time of writing, but you can wishlist it on Steam to keep up to date with all the news and hear about any release windows as they are announced. </p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wuthering Waves Hero of the Leap Quest – how to use the sensor for the optimal route]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/wuthering-waves-hero-of-the-leap-quest-how-to-use-the-sensor-for-the-optimal-route/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=wuthering-waves-hero-of-the-leap-quest-how-to-use-the-sensor-for-the-optimal-route</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/wuthering-waves-hero-of-the-leap-quest-%E2%80%93-how-to-use-the-sensor-for-the-optimal-route.879270/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/wuthering-waves-hero-of-the-leap-quest-how-to-use-the-sensor-for-the-optimal-route/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=wuthering-waves-hero-of-the-leap-quest-how-to-use-the-sensor-for-the-optimal-route<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="195" data-injectable="true" data-video="true">There are lots of side quests in <em>Wuthering Waves</em>, and because you are likely to run into the Hero of the Leap quest at a random point, you might be very, very confused as you try to complete it. </p> <p data-characters="170" data-current-count="170" data-injectable="false">One of the steps in the quest is to use the sensor to find the optimal route, but you might not even have the sensor yet. If this has happened to you, I can help you out.</p> <h2 id="h-how-to-use-the-sensor-for-the-optimal-route-in-wuthering-waves" data-injectable="false">How to use the sensor for the optimal route in <em>Wuthering Waves</em></h2> <p data-characters="327" data-current-count="497" data-injectable="true">You can find the <strong>Hero of the Leap quest</strong> in the center of Jinzhou. A young man by the name of Dashbon can be found near the pools in the town, and he will tell you about great heroes who used to jump from roof to roof in the city. He will then give you the chance to follow in their footsteps and take on the Overdash challenge.</p>
 <p data-characters="285" data-current-count="285" data-injectable="false">If you agree, you will be teleported to the top of a building and will need to make your way across the rooftops of the city. If you touch the ground at all, then it will restart. At this point, you can use the sensor to see the optimal route, but only if you actually have the sensor.</p> <p data-characters="570" data-current-count="855" data-injectable="true">If you don’t have the sensor yet, you need to continue through the main quest and do the <strong>Echoing Marche quest</strong>. As you play through this quest, you will meet a young guard at a small base outside Jinzhou. He will ask you to keep an eye out for a missing person, and this is when you get the sensor. You will be able to switch to the center by bringing up your Utility Wheel by using the Tab key on the keyboard or the left D-Pad button. Make sure it is set to Utility and not Function. In this wheel, you will find the Sensor, which will look like a small eye icon.</p>
 <figure data-current-count="300" data-injectable="false"><figcaption>Screenshot by Destructoid</figcaption></figure> <p data-characters="563" data-current-count="863" data-injectable="false">Select it, and it will then map to your controls the same way the grapple hook does. you can hold the left should button on the controller and then hit the Y button to use it. This will reveal the optimal route to you when you are performing the challenge in the Hero of the Leap quest and make your life much easier. Remember, you only need to have the grapple equipped to be able to use it for anything other than a prompted spot. If you have the sensor on, you can still grapple to the top of buildings and lamps with ease as long as you hover over the prompt.</p>

<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ghost of Tsushima: Director’s Cut PC Patch 1053.0.0522.1042 Introduces NVIDIA DLSS 3, AMD FSR 3 Fixes]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-tsushima-directors-cut-dlss-3-fsr-3-fixes/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ghost-of-tsushima-director%E2%80%99s-cut-pc-patch-1053-0-0522-1042-introduces-nvidia-dlss-3-amd-fsr-3-fixes.879258/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-tsushima-directors-cut-dlss-3-fsr-3-fixes/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The first Ghost of Tsushima: Director's Cut post-launch patch is now live on PC, introducing stability improvements and fixes for some NVIDIA DLSS 3 and AMD FSR 3 issues.</p>
<p>As mentioned above, the <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/2215430/view/4160841636412305229?l=english" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1053.0.0522.1042 patch</a> focuses on improving stability and fixing some NVIDIA DLSS 3 and AMD FSR 3 issues. Specifically, the patch fixes visual bugs that could show when transitioning from cutscenes to gameplay with DLSS 3 Frame Generation enabled, and fixed other visual issues that could show when combining AMD FSR 3 upscaling with Dynamic Resolution Scaling.</p>
<p>This Ghost of Tsushima: Director's Cut is only going the first one, as Nixxes and Sucker Punch confirmed they are working hard on future patches that will address issues raised by the community and further improve stability on specific hardware configurations for both the single-player campaign and the Legends multiplayer mode.</p>
<p>Despite some users having stability issues, Ghost of Tsushima: Director's Cut managed to become the most successful PlayStation launch on Steam, setting a new <a href="https://wccftech.com/ghost-of-tsushima-sets-new-concurrent-player-peak-record-for-sonys-single-player-games-on-steam/">concurrent player peak record for Sony's single-player games on Steam</a>, soundly beating the previous record holder, God of War. With Helldivers II also doing incredibly well, it's clear that Sony is finding more success with its PC releases, hopefully convincing the company to release their former PlayStation exclusives on PC sooner than it has been doing these past few years.</p>
<p>Ghost of Tsushima: Director's Cut is now available on PC, PlayStation 5, and PlayStation 4. You can learn more about the base game by checking out Alessio's <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ghost-of-tsushima-duty-heavier-than-a-mountain-death-lighter-than-a-feather/">review.</a></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paying Respects to Press F]]></title>
            <link>https://remapradio.com/articles/call-of-duty-advanced-warfare-paying-respects-to-press-f/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/paying-respects-to-press-f.879255/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://remapradio.com/articles/call-of-duty-advanced-warfare-paying-respects-to-press-f/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<h2 id="i">I.</h2><p>“One of my teachers recently passed away, and I wanted to make a little joke at his funeral… and say Press F to pay Respects. Would that be rude?”<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NoStupidQuestions/comments/9sg7in/is_it_rude_to_say_press_f_to_pay_respects_at_a?ref=remapradio.com"> <u>began a question</u></a> on Reddit.&nbsp;</p><p>Fellas, is it rude to eulogize a teacher with a video game meme? Is it rude to dunk on Call of Duty before the bereaved?</p><p>“Yeah, best not to meme at a funeral,” one Redditor replied.</p><p>“Saying it quietly to yourself would be fine, I guess,” said another. “The whole reason it ever became a meme at all was that it was so out of place for a supposedly serious moment. Don’t bring that into a situation that’s <em>actually</em> serious.”</p><p>The cultural legacy of the 2014 video game <em>Call of Duty: Advanced Warfare</em> is a single meme of its most awkward moment, and a ceaseless discourse over whether the meme can be both funny and a sincere gesture of grief.<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/unpopularopinion/comments/99g6n1/comment/e4zb7hy/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><u> “If you use F in real life, you suck”</u></a>;<a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/f-to-pay-respect-is-the-perfect-example-of-a-joke-turning-serious-when-used-often-enough.187857/page-2?post=31748376&amp;ref=remapradio.com#post-31748376"> <u>“Honestly prefer F to RIP because life and death should be something to laugh with since it affects us all”</u></a>;<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/teenagers/comments/cl0570/comment/evs1910/?ref=remapradio.com"> <u>“If I died and I didn’t get some Fs I would be kinda disappointed.”</u></a></p><p>More thought has been given to this question of decorum than to the creation of the <em>Call of Duty </em>moment itself. “I don’t remember whose idea it was, really,” <em>Advanced Warfare</em> level designer Steve Bianchi told me. “It was not something that we really put a lot of thought into.”</p><p>“I’m pretty sure it was me, and I'm pretty sure that I wrote it,” says <em>Advanced Warfare</em> creative director Bret Robbins. “I’m the guy. I’m really the guy that was responsible for it.”</p><h2 id="ii">II.</h2><p>In <em>Call of Duty: Advanced Warfare</em>, you play a U.S. Marine in the year 2054, deployed with your comrade and best friend Will Irons to repel a North Korean incursion into Seoul, South Korea. In the game’s first half hour, you and Irons battle North Korean soldiers and drone swarms in the streets of the abandoned city, scurrying under quadrupedal tanks and jetpack-jumping over derelict buses. All the while, the game urges you along with various button prompts: <em>Hold Right Mouse to Aim Down Sights</em>; <em>Hold F While Falling to Safely Descend</em>;<em> Press Q to Throw a Threat Grenade.</em></p><figure></figure><p>After you find a demolition team killed in action, you must then finish their mission to blow up a mobile heavy weapons platform. You fight first to the demo team’s corpses—<em>Hold F to Grab Charges</em>—then to the target. Will slides open an access panel—<em>Hold F to Give Will the Charges</em>—and plants the explosive, but his arm is trapped when the panel closes.</p><p>“We’re outta time!” Irons shouts as the weapons platform begins to take off. “It’s okay. I’ll see you on the other side.”</p><p>You watch from the ground as Irons is consumed in the blast. “Why is one man spared while another one taken?” your character muses. “To this day I couldn’t give you an answer…. All I knew was my best friend was gone, and that part of me wished I had been taken instead.”</p><p>Two weeks later, you’re at Arlington National Cemetery, standing by Irons’ coffin. Irons’ father stands and—solemnly, silently—lays his hand upon the casket. Then it is your turn: <em>Press F to Pay Respects.</em></p><p>Muddling through <em>Advanced Warfare</em> for a segment on his former TBS show, Conan O’Brien stops and looks to the camera. “What does that mean?! That’s crazy! Is there a button for, ‘I’m here ‘cuz I thought I might meet somebody?’” The audience laughs; they laughed harder at the appearance of the prompt itself. “Okay, here we go. This is a really emotional moment for me,” O’Brien deadpans, as we watch his index finger depress a button on an Xbox controller.</p><figure><iframe width="200" height="113" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b82idSYHSu8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="" title="Clueless Gamer: Conan Reviews &quot;Call Of Duty: Advanced Warfare&quot; | CONAN on TBS"></iframe></figure><p><a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/games/press-x-to-pay-respects-call-of-duty-advanced-warfare-s-funeral-scene-is-so-call-of-duty-9837696.html?ref=remapradio.com"><u>The Independent</u></a> called it “gleefully tasteless”; <a href="https://www.pastemagazine.com/games/the-qte-is-deadlong-live-the-qte?ref=remapradio.com"><u>Paste</u></a> said it was “transparently lazy”; <a href="https://kotaku.com/nothing-says-funeral-like-a-quick-time-event-1653938147?ref=remapradio.com"><u>Kotaku</u></a> just called it “very odd”. “It was a valiant attempt at pathos,” <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2014/11/4/7151865/call-of-duty-press-x-to-mourn?ref=remapradio.com"><u>wrote Polygon</u></a>, “the first time in a long time that a triple-A game was trying to communicate to me at a higher level. But at the same time, it felt hollow. Voyeuristic. Tawdry.”</p><p>But why did it elicit this kind of response? In 2011, the video game <em>Batman: Arkham City</em> featured an almost identical scene, inviting the player to “Pay Your Respects” to the chalk outlines of Bruce Wayne’s murdered parents. Only two months prior to <em>Advanced Warfare</em>’s release, <em>Middle-Earth: Shadow of Mordor</em>, directed players to enter stealth mode and press X to kiss their wife. Neither was considered “the dumbest interactive moment in gaming”, <a href="https://www.gq.com/story/call-of-duty-advanced-warfare-press-to-pay-respects?ref=remapradio.com"><u>per <em>GQ</em></u></a>.</p><p><a href="http://www.thegia.com/2014/11/03/all-due-respect-press-f-for-farce/?ref=remapradio.com"><u>In an article for the now-defunct Gaming Intelligence Agency</u></a>, game developer Andrew Vestal examined an important syntactic distinction between <em>Advanced Warfare </em>and <em>Arkham City. </em>“Arkham City asks the player to ‘[A] Pay Your Respects’ – a complete action, with the contextual button prepended as a UI element. <em>Call of Duty</em> asks the player to ‘Press [F] to Pay Respects’ – to push a button in a video game in order to perform the action. With this small change, the player’s action (push a button) now overwhelms the in-game result (Pay Respects).”</p><p>“Press F to Pay Respects” is a ludicrous and sticky bit of language. It can be read to suggest that pressing ‘F’ is not the keyboard shortcut for the gesture of respect, but the gesture itself. R.I.P., sorry for your loss, thoughts and prayers, hearts go out, I really am sincerely sorry, F.</p><p>This is how it’s been interpreted, anyway, in the decade since <em>Advanced Warfare</em>’s release. A Twitch streamer who inadvertently trips Arthur Morgan into the path of a train, or eldritch blasts a goblin off a roof, might ask viewers to throw some F’s in the chat. Lost 10,000 runes in <em>Elden Ring</em>? F. Stream goes down? That’s an F.</p>
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<blockquote data-embed-height="740"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/halo/comments/phrhnp/press_f_for_feelings/?ref=remapradio.com">Press F for feelings</a><br> by<a href=""></a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/halo/?ref=remapradio.com">halo</a></blockquote>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<p>Is it rude to say ‘F’ at your favorite teacher’s funeral? Perhaps, but it ought to be consolation that ‘F’ can be used just about anywhere else, from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/pressftopayrespects/comments/q18714/f/?ref=remapradio.com"><u>accidentally deleting a <em>Breath of the Wild</em> save game</u></a> to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dankmemes/comments/9zj6ty/press_f/?ref=remapradio.com"><u>saluting people working retail on Black Friday</u></a>,<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/facepalm/comments/t77216/300_for_a_haircut_press_f/?ref=remapradio.com"> <u>paying $300 for a Karen haircut</u></a>, or just the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/media?url=https%3A%2F%2Fi.redd.it%2Ffg371evkmhl71.jpg&amp;ref=remapradio.com"><u>possibility that gamers might never live in a golden age of <em>Halo</em> ever again</u></a>. If it could fit in a verse of the Alanis Morissette song “Ironic”, you can press ‘F’ to it.&nbsp;</p><p>The respects once meant for brave Will Irons are now itinerant keystrokes: stray Fs in search of a host, seeking a headshot in a deathmatch, or at least<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/pressftopayrespects/comments/gsp7lg/somebody_dropped_their_cigarette_in_the_bathroom/?ref=remapradio.com"> <u>a dropped cigarette on a public toilet floor</u></a>.&nbsp;</p><h2 id="iii">III.</h2><p>“It became a joke!” cries Glen Schofield from his car, stuck in traffic. “People laughed at us!”</p><p>Schofield is the co-founder of California studio Sledgehammer Games, which developed <em>Advanced Warfare</em>. To date, Activision has published a major <em>Call of Duty </em>every year since 2005. Initially, the studios Infinity Ward and Treyarch alternated titles; after Sledgehammer assisted on Infinity Ward’s <em>Modern Warfare 3 </em>to good results, Schofield’s studio was promoted into the rotation as a primary developer, with <em>Advanced Warfare</em> as its first Call of Duty assignment.</p><p>“Suddenly we had a three-year window to do our own game, almost like a new IP within the <em>Call of Duty</em> universe, the opportunity to write our own epic summer blockbuster,” Robbins says. “We were flush with victory on [<em>Modern Warfare 3</em>] and ran into <em>Advanced Warfare</em> really pretty confident and feeling pretty good about the studio and our place in [the franchise].”</p><p><em>Advanced Warfare</em> broke from the series’ historical and contemporary theaters of war, looking to a futuristic fantasy of action and military tech that Schofield enthusiastically portrayed with walking tanks and rocket jumps. “When I first pitched it, they were like ‘What the fuck are you thinking? That’s so crazy, that’s not <em>Call of Duty</em>. You can’t use a walking tank. No such thing as that,’” Schofield recounts. “I go to NASA, and the guy goes, ‘Oh, by the way, you’re in for a surprise today. We’re gonna show you a walking tank.’ And they lowered this giant metal tank, I got pictures of it somewhere. So, you know, the executives, they’re like, ‘Okay, man, go ahead and make it.’”</p><p>“The end of the first level is a banger,” says Robbins. Not only does Will Irons die, but the player loses his arm, pretext for outfitting the player with a robotic prosthesis and seducing him into a nightmarish world of private military contractors. Irons’ funeral, which immediately follows the intro, shoulders heavy narrative responsibility. First, the player must look down at the coffin, which is really an excuse for them to see that they are still missing their arm. Second, the player must meet Irons’ father — ultimately the game’s villain — who will recruit the player into his PMC. Thirdly, the player must have a moment to mourn Irons.&nbsp;</p><p>“We really wanted you to have that emotional connection,” Bianchi remembers. “I don’t think you necessarily got that a lot in <em>Call of Duty </em>games, where you really take the time to mourn someone’s loss and move forward.”</p><p>“That was the intent,” development director Anthony Schmill says. “To, at some level, show that loss is part of combat and warfare, that people sacrifice themselves in these situations, and that the community of people who experience war are deeply impacted by the loss of comrades and soldiers and partners in battle.”</p><figure><figcaption><p><span>Was Advanced Warfare this trend's greatest offender? Photo credit: Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment, Rocksteady Games</span></p></figcaption></figure><p>At funerals for Navy SEALs, there is a tradition of pounding a gold trident pin, which depicts an eagle with a cocked-back flintlock pistol and symbolizes fraternity between SEALs, into the lid of a coffin. The <em>Advanced Warfare</em> developers envisioned a similar beat for Irons’ funeral. The player would be prompted to walk up and hammer in a pin, and in doing so, conveniently reconfirm the absence of their arm. “We could have done it in a cinematic,” says Robbins, “but I always like it when things are a little more immersive.”</p><p>However, the pin idea was nixed by a military advisor late in development because Irons was a Marine, not a Navy SEAL. “They were really adamant that we couldn’t have that in there,” Bianchi remembers. Not wanting to lose the emotional beat, Robbins cast around for alternatives — would the player put a flag on the coffin instead? a medal? a photograph — but there was no time. But maybe that was okay; maybe all the moment needed to be was a hand resting on Irons’ coffin — briefly, meaningfully — and then having the player wal away.</p><p>“Yeah, okay, that sounds fine,” Schofield remembers telling Robbins. “That’s all we have time for.”</p><p>It is Call of Duty house style that there is never a button prompt without text. “Anytime there’s a prompt, it’s gonna say, ‘plant bomb,’ ‘activate,’ ‘open door,’ you know. There’s just text. Flat out,” Robbins explains. Near the end of development, Robbins went through a spreadsheet supplying text for any “naked” prompts. “The coffin was a blank,” he says. “And you’re just going through and writing them all out, and innocently, you know, it has to say something here, that seems like an appropriate phrase to use.”</p><p>The response was “a little surprising,” Robbins says dryly, “to say the least.”</p><p>Schofield thinks that the mockery hurt the game’s Metacritic score. “It showed up in so many articles: ‘Press F for respects?’ That’s the stupidest shit!’” Caught off-guard, the developers at Sledgehammer deliberated whether or not to patch the offending phrase out of the game, ultimately landing on the side of… oh, well.</p><p>“There was great combat, there were epic moments, right and left… but that’s what people remembered,” says Anthony Schmill. “I’m sure that lots of people enjoyed the game, but if that’s what the biggest thing they took away from it? Oh, well.”</p><p>“I thought, if that’s the thing that people rip on,” says Bianchi, “the weak moment, then that’s… you know, fine. It is sort of funny.”&nbsp;</p><p>Ten years later, Robbins (now the head of Ascendant Software, developer of <em>Immortals of Aveum</em>) chooses his words carefully, given past experiences.</p><p>“It’s not what I wanted everyone to be talking about,” he says evenly. “I still think <em>Advanced Warfare</em> has some of the best level design and is one of the most beautiful Call of Dutys ever made. And it really felt like the internet had just decided to grab a small thing — which clearly wasn’t a small thing. It wouldn’t have happened if it was small. But in my mind, at the time, it was a small thing that overshadowed a lot of really great work. I was really surprised. I was like, ‘Why is this such a big deal? Why are people so laser focused on this?’ I asked friends, I asked people on the team, ‘What is this?’</p><p>“I think it was a criticism of a game overreaching. There’s nothing offensive about paying respects to your best friend who was just killed in front of you… If it had been in a cinematic, no one would have blinked an eye. If the text had been different, no one would have blinked an eye. It’s specifically those words, and specifically the action. It’s not a criticism of the scene. It’s a criticism of what the game was trying to make you feel. I think that’s the closest I can get to why this even was a thing. I don’t think if you did that today — honestly, I don’t think if you did it today, anyone would care. There was something about that time and where Call of Duty was at that time that just hit a nerve.”</p><p>Robbins knew about the moment in <em>Batman: Arkham City </em>when he was making <em>Advanced Warfare</em>; he thinks it might have been in the back of his mind. “I’m a huge fan of those games. I had seen it done. And it resonated. I had no problem with that. You put it maybe in the military context, maybe that ruffled more feathers? I don’t know. Maybe it was unearned. Maybe you didn’t feel that close to your friend that died. So don’t try to force it. You’re being clumsy.”</p><p>Robbins has more to say, more possibilities for why people reacted so poorly. There’s only one thing he is absolutely certain about. “I’m glad that my name wasn’t directly attached to it in any kind of way to start with,” he says. It is one thing to have your work go viral for all the wrong reasons, and another to be clearly identified as the author of it. “The internet is a strange and terrible place.”</p><h2 id="iv">IV.</h2><p>Almost 10 years on from <em>Advanced Warfare</em>, the meme has eclipsed its master. “Press F to Pay Respects” is an organism in and of itself. Its origins are forgotten and, actually, not important. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/OutOfTheLoop/comments/2pp5mz/comment/cmyyx54/?ref=remapradio.com"><u>One Reddit user said</u></a> they thought it was “a reference to Half-Life where the f button turns on the flashlight.” The details get all tangled, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/OutOfTheLoop/comments/8ydijf/comment/e2alelr/?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3"><u>with one user saying</u></a> that they had “seen people claiming that ‘it's actually disrespectful because in the scene what happens when you do that is you piss on the coffin’.”</p><p>In April, 2020, Rick May, who voiced the Soldier in Valve’s enormously popular shooter <em>Team Fortress 2</em>, died of complications from COVID-19. In tribute, Valve placed a statue of his character in the game, which reappears every April.<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/tf2/comments/g11thm/press_f_to_pay_respects/?ref=remapradio.com"> <u>On Reddit</u></a>, in <em>Team Fortress 2</em>, and elsewhere, fans pressed ‘F’. Just the letter ‘F’, in chats and comment sections, pressed sincerely to pay respects. (Or for other reasons: “I was pressing F expecting some secret or free item lol,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/tf2/comments/16h44ve/comment/k0dshpr/?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3"><u>said one <em>Team Fortress</em> player</u></a>.)</p>
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<blockquote data-embed-height="594"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/tf2/comments/g11thm/press_f_to_pay_respects/?ref=remapradio.com">Press F to pay respects</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Classy_Corpse/?ref=remapradio.com">u/Classy_Corpse</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/tf2/?ref=remapradio.com">tf2</a></blockquote>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<p>In August, 2018, two <em>Madden</em> esports players — Eli Clayton and Tyler Robertson — were killed in a shooting at a <em>Madden </em>event in Jacksonville, Fla. During an EA Sports memorial Twitch stream, the following month, fellow gamers filled the chat with ‘F’s.&nbsp;</p><p>“As a generation that grew up with meme culture and social media,” <a href="https://dotesports.com/culture/news/maddens-jacksonville-tribute-stream-and-a-new-language-of-digital-mourning?ref=remapradio.com"><u>wrote Nicole Carpenter at Dot Esports,</u></a> “the Twitch community was genuine in its expression, using the tools it has—memes—to mourn. It’s an extension of social media mourning, which is growing more and more common as our population faces mass tragedy and the loss of public figures.”</p><p>The meme is controversial, however. When news of streamer Desmond “Etika” Amofah’s death by suicide in 2019 hit the internet, some Redditors also took the ‘F’, although it caused some friction on the post. While some said the statement was in poor taste (<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SmashBrosUltimate/comments/c5bl28/comment/es1alxi/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><u>one poster called it</u></a> “awful” and “disrespectful”), others said it was appropriate. “He would have loved it. it is to pay respects,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SmashBrosUltimate/comments/c5bl28/comment/es171uz/?ref=remapradio.com"><u>said one Redditor</u></a>.<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SmashBrosUltimate/comments/c5bl28/comment/es171uz/?ref=remapradio.com"> </a>“Of anyone out there Etika is the right person to be honouring with memes,” <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/SmashBrosUltimate/comments/c5bl28/comment/es1qevj/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button"><u>said another</u></a>.</p><p>“Press F to Pay Respects” us still a meme; <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/f-to-pay-respect-is-the-perfect-example-of-a-joke-turning-serious-when-used-often-enough.187857/page-2?post=31748376&amp;ref=remapradio.com#post-31748376"><u>one might say</u></a> that it’s one generation’s equivalent of RIP — a brief, if perfunctory, expression of sincere sympathy. What has happened in the last 10 years is not that “Press F” went “serious”; rather, death went online. If you are online, you do not learn of Etika’s death in the newspaper or of Rick May’s from a mutual friend at a grocery store. You learn online, in your space, with your friends, where you are comfortable, but you still don’t know exactly what to say. This has not changed: it is not as if before the internet condolences were always expressed appropriately. </p>
<!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<blockquote data-embed-height="630"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/pressftopayrespects/comments/r5dgm7/rip/?ref=remapradio.com">R.I.P</a><br> by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/InternationalAdvice5/?ref=remapradio.com">u/InternationalAdvice5</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/pressftopayrespects/?ref=remapradio.com">pressftopayrespects</a></blockquote>
<!--kg-card-end: html-->
<p>What’s changed is that news of a school shooting comes to you in the same feed as a meme of<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/memes/comments/b8utpx/press_f_to_pay_respect/?ref=remapradio.com"><u> Ant-Man flying into Thanos’ asshole.</u></a> To both, you respond with an ‘F’. To Thanos, you say sorry for your loss as a joke; to the victims, you are sorry for real. Maybe you say it in both cases because it’s something you’ve seen people say before. Maybe you’ve internalized that “Press F to Pay Respects” only works as a joke because of the juxtaposition of sincere condolences with absurd circumstances. Maybe you don’t even know what you’re saying. Maybe you’re just grieving.</p><p>“The F meme seems kinda disrespectful in my opinion”, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/tf2/comments/g11thm/comment/fndx6yd/?ref=remapradio.com"><u>one poster in the <em>Team Fortress </em>subreddit said</u></a> of the tributes to Rick May.</p><p>“The old man would’ve found it humourous,” someone replied. “Y’all obviously didn’t know the legend”.</p><p>“Dude literally no one would think it’s funny for their death to be respected with an ‘f’ meme. And you wouldn’t even know if he found it humorous because you didn’t even know him personally.”</p><h2 id="v"><strong>V.</strong></h2><p>In February 2020, Rick May suffered a stroke, and was moved to a nursing home. Two months later, he was gone. After his death, Jeremiah Foglesong, a gamer, whose father-in-law was May’s cousin, informed the family of the wealth of tributes that had been posted online: art, poems, Valve’s memorial inside <em>Team Fortress 2. </em>For Diana Lilly, May’s widow, an actor herself who wasn’t particularly tech-savvy, Foglesong printed hard copies of everything. “I did have to explain the lists of ‘F, F, F, F,” Foglesong says. He didn’t know the reference was from a Call of Duty game, but he told her it was “like throwing up a heart emoji, or a thumbs up.”</p><p>The concept of an internet community was fairly alien to Lilly, but the sentiment was clear, and she loved it. “It really meant a lot to me,” she says softly. “I was in such mourning at that time. And it was so nice to hear that other people were thinking about Rick, too. I knew he would just love that, because that meant so much to him: his voice work. Something that was so special to him, to think that other people thought it was special, too.”</p><p>It’s nice to be remembered. “In a way, I’m glad [Press F] got a little bit of attention,” says Robbins. “If that’s what it takes for people to remember that game, fine, because it’s a great game. It’s something I’m really proud of. I think everyone that worked on it really felt like we were making something special.”</p><p>It’s also hard to be remembered. “As we get further and further away from the date that he died, you hear his name less, just a little less,” says Foglesong. Still, every April, he returns to <em>Team Fortress 2</em>, a game he doesn’t play as much as he used to, to see May’s statue. “I think that’s beautiful, that they’re doing that.”</p><p>May was the artistic director at the Renton Civic Theatre in Renton, Wash. when he met Diana Lilly. In 1994, he appeared opposite her in a production of the Ira Levin play <em>Deathtrap</em>, where they played husband and wife. In the play, May’s character conspires to and kills Lilly’s character. Lilly’s mother was “disgusted” that she would date a man who kills her on stage. “He was somebody who was very talented and always fun to be around,” Lilly remembers of her husband. “If he showed up anywhere, people were always so happy to see him. He was always so funny, and had fun stories, and was just a good person to be around.”</p><p>“Rick would really love this,” she says. “He would love to be remembered.”</p><p>What a blessing it is to be remembered at all.</p>
		<p>Duncan Fyfe is a writer and game designer. He lives in England.</p>
			</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atari acquires Intellivision brand]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/atari-acquires-intellivision-brand</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atari-acquires-intellivision-brand.879252/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/atari-acquires-intellivision-brand<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>Intellivision Entertainment to rebrand.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Atari [155 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/atari">Atari</a> has acquired the Intellivision brand and certain games from Intellivision Entertainment, the company <a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2024/05/23/2887219/0/en/Atari-Acquires-Intellivision-Brand.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-884321"></span></p><p>Intellivision Entertainment will rebrand and continue its business of developing and distributing the Amico brand game console, with a license from Atari to continue to distribute new versions of the Intellivision games on the Amico console.</p><p>Through its purchase, Atari aims to expand digital and physical distribution of legacy Intellivision games, as well as potentially create new games, and explore brand and licensing opportunities.</p><p>The first Intellivision home game console was released by Mattel Electronics in 1979 and sold an estimated five million units through 1990. Atari and Intellivision fought what Atari calls “the first console war” in the late 1970s and early 1980s.</p><p>“Uniting Atari and Intellivision after 45 years ends the longest-running console war in history,” said Atari subsidiary <a title="Companies > Digital Eclipse [24 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/digital-eclipse">Digital Eclipse</a> studio head Mike Mika in a press release.</p><p>Atari CEO and chairman Wade Rosen added, “This was a very rare opportunity to unite former competitors and bring together fans of Atari, Intellivision and the golden age of gaming.”</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Intellivision Entertainment CEO Phil Adam said, “Atari has been a valuable partner and we have every confidence they will be a responsible steward of the storied Intellivision brand. We look forward to our expanded collaboration and bringing a broad array of new Atari and Intellivision titles to the Amico and Amico Home family gaming platforms.”</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony's Idea For A Future PlayStation Controller Looks Like It Came Straight Out Of Minority Report]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sonys-idea-for-a-future-playstation-controller-looks-like-it-came-straight-out-of-minority-report/1100-6523664/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sonys-idea-for-a-future-playstation-controller-looks-like-it-came-straight-out-of-minority-report.879249/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sonys-idea-for-a-future-playstation-controller-looks-like-it-came-straight-out-of-minority-report/1100-6523664/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523664">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>As part of its long-term strategy, Sony briefly showed a concept for a high-tech PlayStation controller in a new promotional video. To detail its Creative Entertainment Vision strategy designed to show what its products could look like a decade from now, the video showed off a controller with a radical redesign compared to the current DualSense model.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mq7Jg_1hGTo" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mq7Jg_1hGTo" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>"Ten years from now, we will be living in a more multi-layered world where physical and virtual realities overlap without boundaries," Sony said in the video synopsis. "If Sony, as a creative entertainment company, would be filling the world with new <a href="https://www.sony.co.uk/alphauniverse/stories/kando-attitude" rel="nofollow ">Kando</a>--a Japanese word meaning 'emotional involvement' or 'deep impression'-- in that future, what kind of experiential value would we be offering to make that happen? To explore this question, we conducted a prototyping exercise under the concept of Creative Entertainment Vision."</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4307191-sony-controller.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4307191" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4307191-sony-controller.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4307191"></a><figcaption>We'll miss you, traditional D-pad.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/scale_super/1601/16018044/4307191-sony-controller.jpg"></figure><p>This controller still has analog sticks and a familiar shape, but regular face buttons and the D-pad have been replaced entirely by new inputs. There's also a floating screen above the controller--accessed via a fancy virtual- and mixed-reality headset in the video--and gameplay of a character exploring space. Someone at Sony is clearly a big fan of Minority Report.</p><p>Of course, this is just a brief snippet of what Sony <em>wants </em>to aim for in the future, and technology like this rolling out on a large scale will likely be a lot more than just a decade away.</p><p>Looking toward the more immediate future, it has been reported that Sony is preparing to launch a mid-gen refresh of the PS5, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-leaked-specs-reportedly-show-huge-graphical-leaps-forward/1100-6522652/">dubbed the PS5 Pro</a>. Recent leaks suggest that it will have a more powerful GPU and a slightly faster CPU mode, and Sony is reportedly asking game developers to create an enhanced- graphics mode in their games so that these titles can have a <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/sony-wants-new-ps5-pro-enhanced-mode-in-games-report/1100-6522687/">PS5 Pro "Enhanced" label</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[George Miller Criticizes 2015's Mad Max Game, Developer Responds With Heated Messages]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/george-miller-criticizes-2015s-mad-max-game-developer-responds-with-heated-messages/1100-6523661/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/george-miller-criticizes-2015s-mad-max-game-developer-responds-with-heated-messages.879246/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/george-miller-criticizes-2015s-mad-max-game-developer-responds-with-heated-messages/1100-6523661/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6523661">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Mad Max director George Miller wants Metal Gear designer Hideo Kojima to make a Mad Max game, and he also sounded off on 2015's Mad Max game and why he didn't love it.</p><p>Speaking to <a href="https://www.gamingbible.com/news/mad-max-director-hideo-kojima-game-adaptation-960558-20240523" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Gaming Bible</a>, the Australian filmmaker said Kojima would be a top choice of his to make a Mad Max game, though he said he "would never ask him" because Kojima already has so much "fantastic stuff in his own head" that keeps him busy.</p><p>Miller also spoke candidly about 2015's Mad Max game from Just Cause studio Avalanche. He said plainly, "It wasn't as good as I wanted it to be." Upon reflection after that game came out, Miller said, "I'm one of those people that I'd rather not do something unless you can do it at the highest level."</p><p>2015's Mad Max was a tie-in of sorts with Miller's Mad Max: Fury Road, and Miller said his team gave "all our material" to Avalanche to make the game. GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/mad-max-review/1900-6416232/" data-ref-id="1900-6416232">Mad Max review</a> scored the game a 6/10. Reviewer Peter Brown said, "Mad Max is too focused on providing you with an open-world that's filled with missions, and not focused enough on making those missions worth your time."</p><p>Former Avalanche boss Christofer Sundberg <a href="https://x.com/CHSundberg" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">reacted to Miller's comments on social media</a>. He said the game suffered from releasing at a "terrible" time, and his efforts to convince Warner Bros. to move the date were not successful. The game released on the same day as Metal Gear Solid V, and Sundberg reflected that Warner Bros. "blamed us for the bad sales" and canceled DLC for the game that was "just sitting there waiting to be released."</p><p>Sundberg added that Avalanche pitched an open-world Mad Max game but was forced to convert the experience to be more linear in structure.</p><p>"We threw away a year of work and got to hear that 'players want autonomy in this day and age.' Well, no shit," he said. "I'm sure Hideo Kojima would make an awesome Mad Max game, but it would be a completely different experience."</p><p>In other Mad Max news, Furiosa: A Mad Max Saga comes to theaters on May 24. It stars Anya Taylor-Joy as Furiosa and is a prequel set before the events of Fury Road.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Atari acquires Intellivision brand and over 200 games]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/atari-acquires-intellivision-brand-and-over-200-games</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/atari-acquires-intellivision-brand-and-over-200-games.879243/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/atari-acquires-intellivision-brand-and-over-200-games<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Amico games console not included but still in development</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Atari has a picked up the Intellivision brand name and 200 games from Intellivision LLC.</p>
<p>Details on the games were not shared, but Intellivision LLC will continue to develop the Amico games console separately with a license from Atari to distribute games on the platform.</p>
<p>The Amico console was originally due to release in October 2020, but a lack of funds has caused a delay to the product and as of November 2023, the firm stated it didn't have the money needed to distribute the machine.</p>
<p>Atari says it will continue to digitally and physically distribute Intellivision titles, explore licensing opportunities and 'potentially create new games'.</p>
<p>Atari and Intellivision were once fierce console competitors in the 1970s and early 1980s.</p>
<p>“This was a very rare opportunity to unite former competitors and bring together fans of Atari, Intellivision and the golden age of gaming,” said Atari CEO Wade Rosen.</p>
<p>Intellivision Entertainment CEO Phil Adam added: "Atari has been a valuable partner and we have every confidence they will be a responsible steward of the storied Intellivision brand. We look forward to our expanded collaboration and bringing a broad array of new Atari and Intellivision titles to the Amico and Amico Home family gaming platforms."</p>
<p>It is part of Atari's continued investment in its retro games business, including the acquisitions of Digital Eclipse, Nightdive, RetroAge and numerous games IP.<a href="https://www.gamesindustry.biz/ataris-re-focus-on-retro"> We spoke to CEO Wade Rosen last year on the firm's retro focus.</a></p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When is XDefiant Season 1? Possible release date and what to expect]]></title>
            <link>https://www.destructoid.com/when-is-xdefiant-season-1-possible-release-date-and-what-to-expect/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=when-is-xdefiant-season-1-possible-release-date-and-what-to-expect</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/when-is-xdefiant-season-1-possible-release-date-and-what-to-expect.879240/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.destructoid.com/when-is-xdefiant-season-1-possible-release-date-and-what-to-expect/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=when-is-xdefiant-season-1-possible-release-date-and-what-to-expect<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p data-characters="280" data-injectable="true" data-video="true"><em>XDefiant</em> may have just launched, but that doesn’t mean we can’t look towards the future, and when we can get our hands on Season 1 and all the goodies that will be included in it. Check out what we know about a possible release date, and what the update will include. </p> <p data-characters="197" data-current-count="197" data-injectable="false">Ubisoft has packaged 14 maps, 24 weapons, and five modes into <em>XDefiant</em> at launch, but as the weeks go by, we’ll all get used to what we’ve got so far, and be looking for new additions. </p> <p data-characters="166" data-current-count="363" data-injectable="false">Thanks to the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-roadmap/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Year 1 Roadmap</a>, we already know what will be included in the game’s first season, and we can make an educated prediction about when it will drop. </p> <figure data-current-count="663" data-injectable="true"><figcaption>New content is on the way, and sooner than you might think. Image via Ubisoft</figcaption></figure>
 <h2 id="h-xdefiant-season-1-expected-release-date" data-injectable="false"><em>XDefiant</em> Season 1 expected release date</h2> <p data-characters="123" data-current-count="123" data-injectable="false"><strong>While Ubisoft hasn’t announced the Season 1 release date, we do expect that it will launch on Tuesday, July 2, 2024. </strong></p> <p data-characters="295" data-current-count="418" data-injectable="true">This is because the game’s Season 0 Battle Pass, which is active right now, expires on July 1. Therefore, it would make a lot of sense that the first official season would start straight after. We’ll be sure to keep this article updated and confirm the date as soon as Ubisoft does. </p>
 <h2 data-injectable="false">What will <em>XDefiant</em> Season 1 include?</h2> <p data-characters="138" data-current-count="138" data-injectable="false">Ubisoft hasn’t gone into too many specifics about what Season 1 will feature, but we know the <em>XDefiant</em> update will definitely bring:</p> <ul data-found-items="4" data-current-count="298" data-injectable="false"> <li>Faction: Codename Ruby</li> <li>Three new weapons</li> <li>Three new maps</li> <li>A new Battle Pass featuring 90 tiers</li> </ul> <p data-characters="211" data-current-count="509" data-injectable="true">Unfortunately, we don’t know what the maps will look like, what guns they are adding, or even what the Battle Pass will include, but we’ll likely hear more about these additions in the coming weeks. </p>
 <p data-characters="69" data-current-count="69" data-injectable="false">For more, check out the <a href="https://www.destructoid.com/xdefiant-best-pc-settings-for-high-fps/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">best <em>XDefiant</em> PC settings to boost your FPS</a>. </p>
<hr>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic"> Destructoid is supported by our audience. When you purchase through links on our site, we may earn a small affiliate commission.&nbsp;</i><i data-stringify-type="italic"><a href="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-stringify-link="https://destructoid.com/affiliate-policy" data-sk="tooltip_parent">Learn more</a></i> </p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Sims rival Life by You delayed indefinitely]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/23/the-sims-rival-life-by-you-delayed-indefinitely/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-sims-rival-life-by-you-delayed-indefinitely.879222/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/05/23/the-sims-rival-life-by-you-delayed-indefinitely/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Having already faced several delays ahead of a planned Early Access release, Paradox Interactive has now delayed their The Sims rival <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/life-by-you">Life By You</a>&nbsp;indefinitely.</p>
<p>Where previous delays had been accompanied by a video, this latest delay has been done with a simple statement on the Paradox Interactive website:</p>


<blockquote>
<p>After much consideration, we regret to announce that we have decided to retract Life by You’s Early Access release date, previously set for June 4th. This was not an easy decision, especially since we understand the anticipation and excitement that many players have for the game. However, we believe that additional development time is needed.</p>
<p>While we would have preferred to commit to a new release window, we believe it is more prudent to hold off while we plan ahead, rather than committing to a new date that we cannot be certain to meet.</p>
<p>We will provide more information as soon as possible, until then we want to sincerely thank you for your continued support and patience.</p>
<p>Mattias Lilja, Deputy CEO of Paradox Interactive</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Developed by Paradox Tectonic, a team led by The Sims veteran Rod Humble, Life By You is an ambitious attempt to take on the life sim juggernaut that is The Sims.</p>
<p>Life By You would naturally cover all of the main bases of the genre, but Paradox Tectonic planned to go even further by adding a far deeper degree of customisation and control for the player. You’ll be able to build your person’s home, with ingrained customisation for colour palettes and designs, and then guide your humans through life, through careers, love and more. You’ll be able to take direct control of people (any person in the world) and move them in the world, and be able to engage in contextually generated conversations with other people. Pretty much all of this can then be modded, from creating custom styles to writing your own dialogue, create events, items, shops, careers, skills, traits and more.</p>

<p>It’s very ambitious in that regard, and seems that Paradox Tectonic need longer to make all of this hang together. Early Access releases were once synonymous with very early builds of games that were severely lacking in features, but as time has gone by, expectations for what an Early Access release offers have grown – not least when it’s a fairly large publisher using this business model. With the quality of Paradox’s game launches currently very much in the spotlight, it makes sene to hold off until Life By You and meet as many expectations as possible.</p>
<p><em>Source: <a href="https://www.paradoxinteractive.com/media/update-on-life-by-yous-early-access-release-date">Paradox</a></em></p>


<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[After almost 28 years, Super Mario 64 has been beaten without using the A button]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/after-almost-28-years-super-mario-64-has-been-beaten-without-using-the-a-button</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/after-almost-28-years-super-mario-64-has-been-beaten-without-using-the-a-button.879216/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/after-almost-28-years-super-mario-64-has-been-beaten-without-using-the-a-button<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>An intrepid Super Mario 64 player with far more skill and patience than I can ever hope to obtain has done the once unthinkable. They have completed the game without pressing the A button - you know, the one that makes Mario jump and therefore is pretty darn useful when navigating the platform and enemy laden world - once. Not one single time. Really.</p>
<p>While Super Mario 64 first released in 1996, the <a href="https://ukikipedia.net/wiki/A_Button_Challenge">Super Mario 64 A Button Challenge</a> started picking up traction in the 2000s. And, while there have been many attempts at completing the game without that pretty essential button, no one has managed to complete the game without using A. Until now.</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Newscast: Is the closure of Hi-Fi Rush and Redfall's studios a sign the Xbox Game Pass publishing model is failing?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Dx4fu4H6us" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>This Super Mario 64 feat was achieved a couple of days ago by a streamer known as <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/marbler">Marbler</a> (thanks, <a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/platformer/for-the-first-time-in-28-years-super-mario-64-has-been-beaten-without-using-the-a-button-and-it-only-took-86-hours/">GamesRadar</a>). Thanks to a number of glitches, secrets (like green shells and air currents) and countless heroic dives, Marbler managed to complete the world's first no A button run on the Wii Virtual Console version of the game. Apparently this is the only version that it is actually possible to complete the game without pressing A. They did not remap any buttons to achieve their goal.</p>
<p>You can see the moment Marbler completes their Super Mario 64 A button challenge in the video below. Is this something you fancy trying out for yourself?</p>
<div data-domain="clips.twitch.tv"><p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span></p></div>
<p>Super Mario 64 has had quite the month. Along with this week's achievement, earlier in May, an unopenable door in Super Mario 64 - which was thought to be impenetrable from the outside without the use of mods - <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/after-27-years-super-mario-64s-last-remaining-locked-door-has-finally-been-opened">was finally opened</a>.</p>
<p>I wonder what else the community will achieve before Super Mario 64 turns 30 (which, honestly, I am still trying to wrap my head around, because I am still only 21...).</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ryujinx Already Runs Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door Remake at 60FPS]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/ryujinx-paper-mario-the-thousand-year-door-60fps/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/ryujinx-already-runs-paper-mario-the-thousand-year-door-remake-at-60fps.879213/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/ryujinx-paper-mario-the-thousand-year-door-60fps/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Ryujinx, one of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-emulator-yuzu-shut-down-nintendo-gets-paid-2-4-million/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">last remaining major Nintendo Switch emulators</a>, is already able to run today's Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door remake at 60FPS.</p>
<p>Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door is out today for the Nintendo Switch, but those owning the Remake's ROM were already able to successfully run and play the game on PC through the Ryujinx Switch emulator. Not only that, but the emulator managed to run the game at 60FPS, whereas, on Nintendo's platform, the game is locked at 30FPS. In addition, the game runs in higher resolutions on PC than on the Switch. We've included a video of Ryujinx running the game emulated on PC below (courtesy of '<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q2IhbStna8E&amp;amp;t=1s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reznoire</a>') below:</p>
<p><iframe title="Ryujinx 1.1.1319 3xIR | Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door (60fps Mod) Gameplay" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q2IhbStna8E?start=1&amp;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>As most of you will know, this isn't the first time that a Switch title is playable on PC on launch day - as a matter of fact, <a href="https://wccftech.com/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a> and<a href="https://wccftech.com/super-mario-wonder-pc/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Super Mario Wonder</a> could already be played ahead of their global Switch release.</p>
<p>In other Paper Mario-related news - as covered earlier today - <a href="https://wccftech.com/paper-mario-the-thousand-year-door-remake-4k-switch-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo's remake seemingly contains a 4K performance profile</a>, which might be related to <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-announce-march-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nintendo's upcoming Switch successor</a>.</p>
<p>As said, Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door Remake is out today for the Nintendo Switch. Here's what we wrote about the game in our<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/paper-mario-the-thousand-year-door/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> launch review from earlier today:</a></p>
<p><em>"While the new Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door preserves the gonzo charm that made the original game a cult classic, not a lot has been done to deal with its padding and other design quirks. If you’re a hardcore Thousand-Year Door fan, worry not, you’re going to love this spiffy new version. If you’re new to the game or weren’t entirely sold the first time around, you’re still likely to find plenty to enjoy here, but you may also notice a few tattered edges."</em></p>

				

			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rise of the Ronin Update Adds New Features and Missions Including 'the Most Difficult Thus Far']]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/rise-of-the-ronin-update-adds-new-features-and-missions-including-the-most-difficult-thus-far</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rise-of-the-ronin-update-adds-new-features-and-missions-including-the-most-difficult-thus-far.879210/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/rise-of-the-ronin-update-adds-new-features-and-missions-including-the-most-difficult-thus-far<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Major changes to cat collecting too.</h2></div><section><p><a href="https://www.ign.com/games/rise-of-the-ronin">Rise of the Ronin</a> version 1.05 is now available and brings some major changes to the game by adding new missions (including the most difficult one so far), applying quality of life improvements, and making a big change to cat collecting.</p><p>Detailed in an update on <a href="https://x.com/TeamNINJAStudio/status/1793211873892147225?failedScript=vendor" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">X/Twitter</a>, the extensive patch notes are headlined by the addition of new content, including five new ally missions while playing on the Midnight difficulty. Three missions have the player "team up and improve local security in Unruly Areas", while one called Path of Chaos presents different enemies on each playthrough.</p><p>Hardcore fans may be most interested in Eternal Night, however, which developer Team Ninja called "the most difficult mission thus far."</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"></output><p>Set bonuses have also been added to Ferocious Tiger and Prodigious Dragon, with the former receiving the Blade Flash attack, an upgraded forward dodge, and more. The latter is receiving the Last Ditch Counterspark, Neutral Combat, and more.</p><p>Formidable Foes of the Foreigner faction will now have a chance of dropping new glider appearances too, and players can otherwise test their skills against new training opponents such as their Blade Twin and bosses previously only available through bond missions.</p><p>Players can now manually reset Unruly Areas too, sync missions that have been completed on Midnight difficulty, equip two of the same weapons individually (allowing for different styles in each hand), and more. Perhaps most importantly, progressing cat collecting will now place cats that can be pet around Usugumo Dayu.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>These changes come on top of a wealth of balance updates and bug fixes. The full patch notes can be seen below.</p><p>Rise of the Ronin arrived March 22, 2024 as an open-world action role-playing game exclusive to PlayStation 5 where players take on the role of a wandering samurai at the dawn of a new era in Japan. <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/rise-of-the-ronin-review">It earned a 7/10 in IGN's review</a>. "Rise of the Ronin marries a cool setting, Team Ninja’s mastery of tough-but-fair combat, and smart RPG design, even when map clutter and junk loot can get in its way," we said.</p><h2>Rise of the Ronin Version 1.05 Patch Notes</h2><p><strong>NEW CONTENT</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Midnight difficulty: Added new Ally Missions<ul data-cy="list"><li>Team up and improve local security in Unruly Areas - Thugs: Honmachi, Thugs Honjo, and Thugs: Honnoji</li><li>Path of Chaos - Each play through will have different enemies</li><li>Eternal Night - The most difficult mission thus far</li></ul></li><li>Added new set bonuses Ferocious Tiger and Prodigious Dragon. Masterwork armor and accessories will now have a chance to drop with these new Set Bonuses separately from other set bonuses<ul data-cy="list"><li>Ferocious Tiger set bonuses:<ul data-cy="list"><li>Blade Flash Attack</li><li>Upgraded Forward Dodge</li><li>Attack ↑ (Martial Skill Swap)</li><li>Ki Regeneration (Blade Flash)</li></ul></li><li>Prodigious Dragon set bonuses:<ul data-cy="list"><li>Last Ditch Counterspark</li><li>Enemy Max Ki ↓ (Grapple Attack)</li><li>Neutral Combat</li><li>Upgraded Counterspark</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>Added new training opponents, such as your Blade Twin, and bosses that were only available in bond missions</li><li>Added new glider appearances that can be obtained from Formidable Foes of the Foreigner faction: Glorious Crimson, Elegant Brown, and Imperial Blue</li></ul><p><strong>NEW FEATURES</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Added feature to manually reset Unruly Areas that is unlocked by completion rate of a chapter on Midnight difficulty</li><li>Added system where you can level sync missions that you have completed on Midnight difficulty</li><li>When equipping the same two main weapon type (for example two katanas), you can now equip different styles for each weapon individually</li><li>Can now register Jizo Statuette for item preset loadouts</li><li>Number of times Martial Skills hit is now added to technical points in Training</li><li>Now shows difficulty in the results screen of Training, as the higher the difficulty, the higher the possible score will be</li><li>Added filtering for Training</li><li>Progressing cat collecting will now place cats that can be pet around Usugumo Dayu in Yokohama, Edo, and Kyoto</li></ul><p><strong>WEAPON ADJUSTMENTS</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted so Violent Gale and Flash attack is easier to do after certain martial skills</li><li>Katana: Yagyu Shinkage-ryu - Follow-up attack after counterspark is now easier to land</li><li>Katana: Nioh-ryu - Adjusted so you are less likely to accidentally trigger Nioh-den: Iai Quickdraw when performing Veiled Arts after Blade Flashing</li><li>Katana: Nioh-ryu - Nioh-den Iai Quickdraw consumes less Ki, and overall increase in damage and Ki damage</li><li>Katana: Aisu Kage-ryu - Crimson Light consumes less ki, and at max blood gauge, damage, and Ki damage is increased</li><li>Saber: British Training - Reduced Ki consumption of throwing knife, and increased damage</li><li>Bayonet: Mumyo-ryu - Bone Shatterer now easier to follow up with critical hits on enemies with depleted Ki</li><li>Bayonet: French Training - Follow-up show after counterspark is now easier to hit</li><li>Oxtail Blade: Mumyo Kaishin-ryu - Midnight Banquet now easier to follow up with critical hit on enemies with depleted</li><li>Great Sword: Mumyo Kaishin-ryu - Midnight Mist is now easier to hit</li><li>Unarmed: Mumyo-ryu - Raging Wolf is now easier to hit</li></ul><p><strong>CHARACTER ADJUSTMENTS</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Adjusted player knockback distance on successfully countersparking enemy attacks</li><li>Now possible to switch styles when: Guarding enemy attacks, during some animations of being hit by enemy attacks, and during Flash Attack</li><li>Calling your horse while sprinting will continue the sprint after mounting the horse</li><li>Adjusted and improved stats of unique attacks of Ally characters across the board</li><li>Adjusted so that you will no longer switch lock on targets when controlling the right stick with the combat style UI showing during Critical Hits</li></ul><p><strong>ENEMY ADJUSTMENTS</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Shortened flaming area that certain bosses create</li><li>Adjusted and nerfed Bayonet bullet damage and state of certain enemies</li></ul><p><strong>OTHER ADJUSTMENTS</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Increased chance of obtaining Masterwork equipment from formidable foes</li><li>A portion of main weapons and sub weapons can now have set bonuses</li><li>Adjusted so that specific equipment that had limited ways of obtaining to now drop from enemies as well</li><li>Can now overwrite set bonuses when bond transferring on Masterwork equipment</li><li>When selecting equipment for bond transferring, equipment that cannot be selected is now filtered to not show</li><li>Items that heal status ailment are now affected by Skill Bolster Duration ↑ and Technology Development Inventory ↑</li><li>Can now obtain the unique accessories by triggering the Veiled Vow dialogue event, and no longer need to commit to the Veiled Vow</li><li>Dialogue lines played after breaking a Veiled Vow now resets after certain conditions</li><li>Fertilizer purchased from Robert Fortune is now cheaper</li><li>Increased the types of material you can purchase from Robert Fortune and Alexandria Moreau</li><li>Increased Red Nuts gain when gardening</li><li>Can now change the time in the Redesign menu</li><li>Midnight difficulty, Edo: Location hubs - Yoshinobu Tokugawa, Taka Murayama, and Hachiro Kiyokawa will now appear in their hubs</li><li>Shintaro Nakaoka will now appear at Choshu Clain Estate in Kyoto when using the Testaments of the Soul</li><li>Adjusted to increase chance of encountering other player's ronin avatars at towns or roads</li></ul><p><strong>BUG FIXES</strong></p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Fixed bug where you could transfer despite lacking materials or money through an unconventional method</li><li>Fixed bug where you could not purchase Coal from blacksmiths</li><li>Fixed bug where Blade Twin's Kimono and Modernizing Vassal's Kimono - Belt were not shown as selectable pieces</li><li>Fixed bug where each equipment sometimes were shown in different colors each</li><li>Fixed bug where Current Equipment showed default appearance under certain conditions</li><li>Fixed bug where saving and loading before arriving at Kannai disabled Chance Encounters until arriving at Kannai</li><li>Fixed bug where Veiled Arts set for other styles would have different stats compared to the original</li><li>Fixed bug where some Martial Skills would ignore guard</li><li>Fixed bug where you would be forced into swimming when performing certain Martial Skills nearby water</li><li>Fixed bug where while using Martial Skill Blossom Blizzard, if you take damage from certain enemy skills will make you unable to dodge out of it</li><li>Fixed bug where in Niph-ryu, switching to middle stance would sometimes switch to high stance</li><li>Fixed bug where after drop down assassinations, performing certain martial skills would cause you to take fall damage</li><li>Fixed bug where Ki Blaze effect would vibrate excessively</li><li>Fixed bug where when using Ally Alexandria Moreau, her grapple throws were not matching the indicator</li><li>Other minor fixes</li></ul><p><em>Ryan Dinsdale is an IGN freelance reporter. He'll talk about The Witcher all day.</em></p></section><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Might a PlayStation Controller Look Like 10 Years From Now? Sony Has an Idea]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/what-might-a-playstation-controller-look-like-10-years-from-now-sony-has-an-idea</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what-might-a-playstation-controller-look-like-10-years-from-now-sony-has-an-idea.879207/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/what-might-a-playstation-controller-look-like-10-years-from-now-sony-has-an-idea<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>What will playing a video game look like 10 years from now? Will video games be something we beam directly into our brains? Or will be still be gaming in front of a big television, monitor, or mobile much as we do today?</p><p>In a new <a href="https://youtu.be/mq7Jg_1hGTo?feature=shared" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">video</a>, Sony has imagined what a PlayStation controller might look like 10 years from now, and it's something straight out of Star Trek.</p><p>"Sony’s Creative Entertainment Vision" YouTube video showed a number of designs for futuristic devices including a gaming controller. Now, while Sony makes a point of saying the content in this video is not directly related to any existing Sony product, it’s fun to imagine playing a video game with this:</p><output><figure><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/05/23/screenshot-2024-05-23-112707-1716460830447.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a><figcaption>Image credit: Sony / YouTube.</figcaption></figure></output><p>The image shows a PlayStation controller connected to what looks like a floating and curved screen. Is the screen merely a projection from the controller, or an actual physical screen that floats in space, perhaps via the power of magnets? Sony doesn’t explain, and it doesn’t have to. This isn’t a prototype, just a fanciful imagination brought to life with special effects.</p><p>Here’s the official blurb on the video:</p><blockquote>10 years from now, we will be living in a more multi-layered world where physical and virtual realities overlap without boundaries. If Sony, as a creative entertainment company, would be filling the world with new Kando in that future, what kind of experiential value would we be offering to make that happen? </blockquote><blockquote>To explore this question, we conducted a prototyping exercise under the concept of “Creative Entertainment Vision.” Envisioning through the lens of Sony’s creativity and technology, here we present the future as an extension of our lives today.</blockquote><p>Reaction to the controller is a mix of disbelief and mockery, with some likening it to real-life PlayStation prototypes that never saw the light of day, such as the unreleased PS3 controller affectionately called the '<a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2008/12/01/the-boomerang-what-might-have-been">Boomerang</a>.'</p><a href="https://assets-prd.ignimgs.com/2024/05/23/what-if-sony-stuck-with-the-ps3s-boomerang-controller-20081201033209544-000-1716461081594.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><output><figure><span></span></figure></output></a><p>It’s all a bit of fun, of course, but let’s entertain the idea for a moment. In a decade from now, so in 2034, we will perhaps be on the PlayStation 7 generation, assuming Sony is still pumping out consoles. But perhaps Sony will have gone down the hybrid console route, ala Nintendo Switch, by then. All you’d need to game on the go is a lightweight controller, looking something like the controller we see in the video, that projects a screen to look at wherever you are. Perhaps PS7 <em>is</em> the controller.</p><p>Which Call of Duty will we be on by then? That’s quick math I can’t quite wrap my head around. As long as the ping is low and the k/d high, I’ll be there.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p>Back in the world of the present, Sony is reportedly preparing to release a <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/ps5-pro-specs-leak-online">PS5 Pro</a>, and last year it released the <a href="https://www.ign.com/tech/playstation-portal">PlayStation Portal</a> peripheral. Maybe we should take the PlayStation Portal and this video as a hint that PlayStation’s future is wherever we want to take it.</p><p><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Quest Keshi Keshi! to end service on July 31]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/dragon-quest-keshi-keshi-to-end-service-on-july-31</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-quest-keshi-keshi-to-end-service-on-july-31.879201/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/05/dragon-quest-keshi-keshi-to-end-service-on-july-31<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
  
  <article>

    
<header>

  <div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/mobile/smartphone">Smartphone</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Puzzle game ran for just over 2.5 years.</span>
      </p></div>

  

</header>  

<!-- Moved from templates/posts/default.php -->

    <div><p>Puzzle game <em><a title="Games > Dragon Quest Keshi Keshi! [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/dragon-quest-keshi-keshi">Dragon Quest Keshi Keshi!</a></em> will end service on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20240731T0600" rel="noopener" target="_blank">July 31 at 15:00 JST</a> after over two-and-a-half years of operation, <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,255 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> <a href="https://keshikeshi.dragonquest.jp/thanks_cp/letter/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-884317"></span></p><p><em>Dragon Quest Keshi Keshi!</em> first launched for iOS via <a href="https://apps.apple.com/jp/app/id1569014144" target="_blank" rel="noopener">App Store</a> and Android via <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.square_enix.android_googleplay.dqkeshikeshijpn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Play</a> on December 1, 2021 in Japan. A western release was planned, but never materialized.</p><p>All gold (in-game currency) sales have ended as of today.</p></div>

        
    
  </article>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega veterans form publisher-agency hybrid Alibi]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamesindustry.biz/sega-veterans-form-publisher-agency-hybrid-alibi</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sega-veterans-form-publisher-agency-hybrid-alibi.879198/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamesindustry.biz/sega-veterans-form-publisher-agency-hybrid-alibi<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <p>Co-founders discuss their plans to create a sustainable company and how they want to champion indie developers</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Sega veterans Jarvis Crofts, Luke Greenaway, and Mark Dallamore have formed a new publisher-agency hybrid, Alibi.</p>
<p>Based in London, Alibi draws on the three co-founders' experiences in data analytics, publishing, and more to help support developers in pitching and publishing games.</p>
<p><em>GamesIndustry.biz </em>spoke with two of its founders, CEO Jarvis Crofts and CSO Luke Greenaway, about the formation of Alibi and why they believe a publisher agency hybrid is a sustainable way forward in the industry.</p>
<p>Alibi formed at the beginning of last year after Greenaway looked back at his time working in the music industry. He noted the importance of scouting in that industry, and wondered why it wasn't of bigger importance in games.</p>
<p>"You live and die by the success of your titles, the same way record labels do with their artists," he notes. "I had that idea in my head for a while, and when I left PTW I thought, 'You know what, I'm going to build this out."</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/jarvis-crofts.PNG?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Jarvis Crofts, Alibi CEO</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"It's obviously incredibly challenging because there is no science to making successful games, and I think publishers struggle to be sustainable because innately they almost feel like hedge funds," Greenaway continues. "You have to have a quantity to balance the successes from those that aren't going to succeed. And I think the way we looked at it was actually, you can do this better."</p>
<p>Crofts, Greenaway, and Dallamore have over fifteen years of experience in the games industry. Crofts worked as a data analyst at Sega for a decade, moving from a junior to senior position on the publishing side before moving to Curve Games to head up portfolio and strategy.</p>
<p>Dallamore worked at Sega for six years as a project lead and product launch executive, with experience in product development. Greenaway worked in QA for fifteen years before moving outside the industry working in music software and business development. He then came back to work for PTW as director of commercial strategy.</p>
<p>Greenaway adds that publishing is high risk, which is why he wants Alibi to stay small and to be selective about the developers it works with and the games it signs. That way, the team can pour their focus onto a select few and help them succeed. So far, Greenaway says that the developers they've spoken with have been "very receptive" to that.</p>
<p>"Our approach is that we're not necessarily pursuing representation super proactively – it's more of an emergent thing," Crofts adds. "Our objective first and foremost is to meet great developers. If there's a great game there and a mutual desire for us to work together, we'll ensure there's a way for us to work together no matter what.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/luke-greenaway.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Luke Greenaway, Alibi CSO</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>"So if we can sign a title and publish it, brilliant, let's do it. If our slate is full but the team wants to work with us, we can help represent or consult them, help them self-publish and get this stuff built up. It's really about maximising and being really efficient with the limited focus that we have."</p>
<p>Greenaway agrees that efficiency is the key to being sustainable in this industry, which Crofts says is at the core of what they hope to achieve with Alibi.</p>
<p>"If you're speaking to a developer and you don't sign a game, you've still invested a lot of time and resources into that negotiation," he explains. "Whereas for us, we can pivot into representation and consultancy and maintain that relationship and still generate revenue. But, more importantly, we can help a developer take their game to market through publishing partners."</p>
<p>For Crofts, this is what sets Alibi apart in such a competitive space among other publishers and agencies.</p>
<p>"It's all about being a smart first person to reach out to, and hopefully that gives us opportunities to help games really early to make sure their pitches are the best and make sure they get the best funding and release."</p>
<p>Greenaway adds that what separates Alibi from other companies is its small team, and how it can be laser-focused on giving constructive feedback.</p>
<p>"I know it's cheesy in a way, but one of the reasons we set Alibi up is that we often have those conversations of 'Why hasn't anyone made this game?'," he says. "And then you think about it, it probably has but no one's seen it and they haven't been given the guidance.  That's what separates us from other agencies, as well as our ability to fully fund the title as well.</p>
<blockquote><p>"It's about maximising and being really efficient with the limited focus that we have"</p><cite>Jarvis Crofts</cite></blockquote>
<p>"So it's really the developer's choice of how they work with us, rather than Alibi being an agency that will take your game to several publishers and just get you a deal. We can sign your title, we can help you achieve this part better and guide you through the process. For developers the legal side and the contracts are quite daunting – they don't want to focus on that. They want someone to assist them so they can make their game."</p>
<p>As for the sort of developers Alibi intends to focus on, the co-founders are passionate about championing indie developers and giving them the support they need to succeed in the industry.</p>
<p>"I feel like these developers are the vanguard of creativity in this industry," Greenaway notes. "The accessibility for indie developers now has never been greater. We really want to work with them and give them a better platform, provide them with the opportunity to succeed."</p>
<p>Crofts adds: "The great thing about these games is they're not asset-intensive or massively multiplayer. The best games in these segments are often from individuals or small teams, so it's mutually beneficial and that's a really sustainable model to be right now. Especially when you're looking for smaller titles because capital is really difficult without compromising a game like that."</p>
<p>That's not to say Alibi won't work with bigger, AAA titles in the future.</p>
<p>"While we may not be signing first-party titles ourselves, we can absolutely help them," Crofts adds. "Just to prove it, even a little bit, to get over that threshold and get signed by a publisher or an investor."</p>
<p>Greenaway describes this sustainable approach as "liberating" as it enables them to be selective about the titles they pick and not worry about how they're going to achieve revenue objectives.</p>
<blockquote><p>"We have a responsibility as publishers to be sustainable and to ensure that we're not letting people go or cancelling projects. These are people's dreams and their passion"</p><cite>Luke Greenaway</cite></blockquote>
<p>"We can sell the games when we can, which allows us to be liberal and work with the developers that we really want to work with," he explains.</p>
<p>However, he also feels that sustainability as a whole in the industry is a long way off.</p>
<p>"We're quite open with our model, because we just want the industry to improve," he says. "We can see our model being replicated by other people, but the irony is that while sustainability is so far off, developer opportunities and creativity are so accessible – it's never been better. There are so many brilliant games and so many people working in the industry and so much creativity.</p>
<p>"I think we have a responsibility as publishers to be sustainable and to ensure that we're not letting people go or cancelling projects. These are people's dreams and their passion."</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>