<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 15:54:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grand Theft Auto VI Mission Design Will Give Players Freedom; Rockstar Has “Raised the Bar Again”]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-raised-the-bar/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/grand-theft-auto-vi-mission-design-will-give-players-freedom-rockstar-has-%E2%80%9Craised-the-bar-again%E2%80%9D.1027998/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-raised-the-bar/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>With Grand Theft Auto VI, Rockstar Games has raised the bar again in terms of realism and NPC behavior while offering players more freedom than before, according to a former developer of the game.</p>
<p>Speaking With <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@GTAVI-oclock" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GTAVIoclock</a>, former game designer at Rockstar Games, commented on the next entry in the open-world series launching next year, saying that the developer has raised the bar again in terms of realism and NPC behavior, which will blow everyone away and will be talked about many years after launch. The former developer also talked about mission design, saying that it will be what makes the game good, granting players freedom. As for the current state of the game, Grand Theft Auto VI is in the bug-fixing phase, so hopefully, it won't take much longer to see more of it.</p>
<p><iframe title="Ex-Rockstar Designer Interview  - GTA VI O'clock - Episode 47" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/R5mzJsGhmr4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>It has been almost a year since we last saw Grand Theft Auto VI, thanks to its official announcement trailer, which provided a very quick look at the two protagonists and the state of Leonida, where Vice City is located. Since then, Rockstar Games has been pretty silent about the game, leaving plenty of room for rumors and speculation regarding its precise release date, which hasn't slipped to 2026 as of <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-not-delayed/">September</a>, leaving fans plenty of time to put together documents going over everything that is currently known about what will be the <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-is-expected-to-be-the-biggest-entertainment-launch-of-all-time-but-a-performance-below-expectations-could-impact-the-entire-industry/">biggest entertainment launch of all time, according to analysts.</a></p>
<p>Grand Theft Auto VI is in development for PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S. It will be released sometime next year.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Star Wars Outlaws Gets New Creative Director for Future Updates]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-outlaws-new-creative-director</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/star-wars-outlaws-gets-new-creative-director-for-future-updates.1027995/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-outlaws-new-creative-director<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Ubisoft has announced that&nbsp;it has appointed a new&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws&nbsp;</em>creative director, and he'll be helming what will be the game's biggest update yet.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/star-wars/outlaws/news-updates/7n2akTSlEV3Wk1aRRwONFZ/star-wars-outlaws-dev-update-1-pushing-into-hyperdrive" rel="noopener" target="_blank">a blog post</a> on the official&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws&nbsp;</em>website, Drew Rechner will be stepping up to the plate as the game's new creative director. Whether previous directors Julian Gerighty and Mathias Karlson will still be playing a role in the game's ongoing development remains to be seen.</p>

<p>In the blog post, Rechner says he's identified "three key areas" in which he and the team would like to improve&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws</em>, namely combat, stealth, and character control.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/star-wars-outlaws-creative-director-new-combat.jpg?itok=G116zB68 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/star-wars-outlaws-creative-director-new-combat.jpg?itok=YZ6CPU3O 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Ubisoft still wants to improve&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws&nbsp;</em>across the board, it seems.</figcaption></figure><p>With regards to combat, Rechner says the studio is looking to add "more depth and excitement to the experience" in order to further reward players' "tactics and precision".</p>

<p>When it comes to stealth, the plan is to improve the "readability and consistency of enemy detection" and to provide more "choice" in how you want to approach encounters.</p>

<p>Finally, character control improvements will apparently involve "improving the reliability of cover, increasing the responsiveness of climbing and crouching, and generally improving the consistency of the controls".</p>

<p>These are areas in which <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-outlaws-update-112">previous</a>&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws&nbsp;</em>updates have <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/star-wars-outlaws-update-130-stealth-speeder">sought to make improvements</a> as well, particularly in the case of stealth, but Rechner says the forthcoming update 1.4 will be&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws</em>' "biggest yet" when it lands on November 21st.</p>




<p>If you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws</em>, it's an open-world action-adventure game developed by Ubisoft and set, believe it or not, in the&nbsp;<em>Star Wars&nbsp;</em>universe.</p>

<p>You play scoundrel Kay Vess, who must wheel and deal her way through the underworld's crime syndicates as she plans the heist of a lifetime. The game mixes shooter-style combat, stealth, and open-world exploration.</p>

<p>Despite the popularity of its IP,&nbsp;<em>Star Wars Outlaws&nbsp;</em><a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/assassins-creed-shadows-delayed-february">underperformed for Ubisoft financially</a>, leading to the company rethinking some of its strategies; Ubisoft games will be released on Steam on day one from now on, and the company is also dropping the season pass model for future releases.</p>

<p><em>Star Wars Outlaws&nbsp;</em>is available right now on <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/star-wars/outlaws" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X|S</a>, and it's also coming to Steam on November 21st, the same day the next update arrives. You can <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/star-wars-outlaws-review">read our review of the game here</a> to find out if this is a Kessel run worth making.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Swears Its Switch 2 Announcement Plans Haven't Changed With the Console Still MIA]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-announcement-date-pokemon-legends-z-a-1851689577</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-swears-its-switch-2-announcement-plans-havent-changed-with-the-console-still-mia.1027986/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-announcement-date-pokemon-legends-z-a-1851689577<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="bf75458e356ae519ce8ab96d4e10c47b" data-recommend-id="image://bf75458e356ae519ce8ab96d4e10c47b" data-format="png" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Switch sits in front of a red background. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A Switch sits in front of a red background. " data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Nintendo</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bf75458e356ae519ce8ab96d4e10c47b" data-recommend-id="image://bf75458e356ae519ce8ab96d4e10c47b" data-format="png" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A Switch sits in front of a red background. " data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/switch-2-nintendo-reveal-date-n64-mini-ocarina-remake-1851686263&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/switch-2-nintendo-reveal-date-n64-mini-ocarina-remake-1851686263">The Switch 2 is still nowhere in sight</a></span>, but Nintendo promises that it hasn’t changed its announcement timeline for the new console. Nintendo President Shuntaro Furukawa said on Tuesday in an online press conference that a reveal of the new hardware was still on track for this fiscal year ending March 2025.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195905" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Three Things We Learned From The Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth Demo " data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="121" data-playlist="195905,194907,194141" data-current="195905"><div><p>Three Things We Learned From The Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth Demo </p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195905/195905_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195905/195905_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195905/195905_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195905/195905_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21419.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>A reveal seemed imminent weeks ago, after the company skipped its big annual September Nintendo Direct. October was when it announced the original Switch, before launching it the following spring. But with no further news on the next console, despite plenty of other Nintendo announcements, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-reveal-mario-screen-specs-features-1851653104&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-2-reveal-mario-screen-specs-features-1851653104">a look at the Switch 2</a></span> before the end of 2024 is looking less likely. </p><p> “Making an announcement this year has gotten quite difficult,” Toyo Securities analyst Hideki Yasuda <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.reuters.com/technology/nintendo-cuts-annual-operating-profit-forecast-switch-sales-slow-2024-11-05/&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/nintendo-cuts-annual-operating-profit-forecast-switch-sales-slow-2024-11-05/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">told <em>Reuters</em></a></span>. “You would not want to divert attention to an upcoming console in the middle of the critical year-end shopping season.”</p><p>Indeed, Nintendo is already losing ground on this year’s ambitious sales plan for the nearly eight-year-old Switch. The company previously aimed to sell <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-limited-edition-zelda-echoes-sales-1851611733&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/nintendo-switch-limited-edition-zelda-echoes-sales-1851611733">13.5 million consoles in 2024</a></span>. It cut that projection by <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2024/241105_5e.pdf&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2024/241105_5e.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">1 million in today’s earnings report</a></span>, which is still an ambitious goal given the lack of any major first-party blockbusters this holiday. Nintendo’s only sold 4.72 million Switch consoles year-to-date. </p><p>Despite a steady stream of smaller, mid-sized games like <em>The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</em>, and ports like <em>Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door</em>, the original Switch is clearly running out of gas. Outside of <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em> and <em>Metroid Prime 4</em>, Nintendo seems to be holding the next round of upcoming heavy-hitters until the Switch 2 is out, and who knows when that will be.<br></p><p>At this point, I wouldn’t be surprised if the company holds its big reveal showcase until the standard February Nintendo Direct. Diehard fans just need to hang on for a bit longer. A surprise release of <em>Pokémon Legends: Z-A</em> in January might help with that.  After all, that’s when the first <em>Pokémon Legends</em> game hit. </p><p> .</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starship Troopers: Extermination, As Told By Steam Reviews]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/starship-troopers-extermination-steam-reviews-1851688404</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starship-troopers-extermination-as-told-by-steam-reviews.1027983/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/starship-troopers-extermination-steam-reviews-1851688404<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>It would always be a tough call, following the deeply <em>Starship Troopers</em>-inspired <em>Helldivers 2</em> into the online co-op multiplayer space. However, through its early access, Offworld’s licensed horde shooter has performed impressively well. But how is it fairing with the harsh critics on Steam?</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196394" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="The Week In Games: Killing Your Heroes, And More New Releases" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="97" data-playlist="196394,196013,196646" data-current="196394"><div><p>The Week In Games: Killing Your Heroes, And More New Releases</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196394/196394_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21942.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The horde shooter is easily one of my favorite genres, much to my wife’s chagrin. You see, I take them far too seriously and, not to toot my own horn, I’m good. I routinely top the leaderboard for kills and objectives. So, after growing up reading and watching <em>Starship Troopers</em>, the basic concept of slaughtering bugs on xeno planets across the galaxy—specifically in a horde shooter setting—immediately caught my attention the day the Early Access began. Like thousands of players since its EA launch, <em>Starship Troopers: Extermination</em> kept me playing through countless updates until we finally hit 1.0 in October, 2024. With new players refilling the ranks, it’s time to reflect on the experience and see how it fares on Steam.</p><p>While I’m enamored with the game and its genre, not everyone feels the same way. As of writing, despite <em>overall</em> positive reviews, <em>Starship Troopers: Extermination</em> sits at ‘Mixed’ on Steam. Many players take issue with the game’s performance following full release. They say it feels like an Early Access title, full of bugs, glitches, and stuttering performance issues that ruin the experience. That’s not to mention the long queue times and crashes-to-desktop frequently plaguing the matchmaking experience.</p><p>All that said, look at many of the game’s positive reviews. While you’ll find the usual, “The only good bug is a dead bug,” type of reviews, mimicking lines from the film, most come from genuine fans—some of which have hundreds or thousands of hours of game time. They tout the class variety, PvE gameplay, co-op experience within the community, and the hordes of bugs you can slaughter atop the walls of a FOB. It’s an experience unlike most others.</p><p>Whether you’re on the fence, or seeking validation about your current favorite first-person shooter, here’s a look at <em>Starship Troopers: Extermination</em>, as told by Steam reviews.</p><figure id="" data-id="f6ace86d3e595c69b8d525224f141dcb" data-recommend-id="image://f6ace86d3e595c69b8d525224f141dcb" data-format="png" data-width="618" data-height="290" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f6ace86d3e595c69b8d525224f141dcb" data-recommend-id="image://f6ace86d3e595c69b8d525224f141dcb" data-format="png" data-width="618" data-height="290" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="eec3b858f11825a16076265a2169fe80" data-recommend-id="image://eec3b858f11825a16076265a2169fe80" data-format="png" data-width="611" data-height="305" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="eec3b858f11825a16076265a2169fe80" data-recommend-id="image://eec3b858f11825a16076265a2169fe80" data-format="png" data-width="611" data-height="305" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="1a1c39599e39d06077acd4766aa3d43b" data-recommend-id="image://1a1c39599e39d06077acd4766aa3d43b" data-format="png" data-width="612" data-height="398" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="1a1c39599e39d06077acd4766aa3d43b" data-recommend-id="image://1a1c39599e39d06077acd4766aa3d43b" data-format="png" data-width="612" data-height="398" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="df10aefcc2496c721501adf803644281" data-recommend-id="image://df10aefcc2496c721501adf803644281" data-format="png" data-width="616" data-height="302" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="df10aefcc2496c721501adf803644281" data-recommend-id="image://df10aefcc2496c721501adf803644281" data-format="png" data-width="616" data-height="302" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="13cd46eea02db5c5533be113161b6121" data-recommend-id="image://13cd46eea02db5c5533be113161b6121" data-format="png" data-width="612" data-height="399" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="13cd46eea02db5c5533be113161b6121" data-recommend-id="image://13cd46eea02db5c5533be113161b6121" data-format="png" data-width="612" data-height="399" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="bcb283d2d89941104548598d346aafc3" data-recommend-id="image://bcb283d2d89941104548598d346aafc3" data-format="png" data-width="622" data-height="311" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="bcb283d2d89941104548598d346aafc3" data-recommend-id="image://bcb283d2d89941104548598d346aafc3" data-format="png" data-width="622" data-height="311" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="12c810d885ca4bdc5fe350d318bc49ab" data-recommend-id="image://12c810d885ca4bdc5fe350d318bc49ab" data-format="png" data-width="615" data-height="481" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="12c810d885ca4bdc5fe350d318bc49ab" data-recommend-id="image://12c810d885ca4bdc5fe350d318bc49ab" data-format="png" data-width="615" data-height="481" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="93c64dafc3de359700d780bf11c98c2c" data-recommend-id="image://93c64dafc3de359700d780bf11c98c2c" data-format="png" data-width="614" data-height="320" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="93c64dafc3de359700d780bf11c98c2c" data-recommend-id="image://93c64dafc3de359700d780bf11c98c2c" data-format="png" data-width="614" data-height="320" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="15355a4ed15e710585cc68ebf0e58ebd" data-recommend-id="image://15355a4ed15e710585cc68ebf0e58ebd" data-format="png" data-width="618" data-height="296" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="15355a4ed15e710585cc68ebf0e58ebd" data-recommend-id="image://15355a4ed15e710585cc68ebf0e58ebd" data-format="png" data-width="618" data-height="296" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="91084f0e81df570db1c4c3556da57c26" data-recommend-id="image://91084f0e81df570db1c4c3556da57c26" data-format="png" data-width="611" data-height="307" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="91084f0e81df570db1c4c3556da57c26" data-recommend-id="image://91084f0e81df570db1c4c3556da57c26" data-format="png" data-width="611" data-height="307" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="35421d8dbce9c446223f74136800a35b" data-recommend-id="image://35421d8dbce9c446223f74136800a35b" data-format="png" data-width="618" data-height="274" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="35421d8dbce9c446223f74136800a35b" data-recommend-id="image://35421d8dbce9c446223f74136800a35b" data-format="png" data-width="618" data-height="274" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="444fc391c9271c8425424093c424a579" data-recommend-id="image://444fc391c9271c8425424093c424a579" data-format="png" data-width="621" data-height="273" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="444fc391c9271c8425424093c424a579" data-recommend-id="image://444fc391c9271c8425424093c424a579" data-format="png" data-width="621" data-height="273" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="872ae3d74db5327a1d13177fa983c51e" data-recommend-id="image://872ae3d74db5327a1d13177fa983c51e" data-format="png" data-width="618" data-height="306" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="872ae3d74db5327a1d13177fa983c51e" data-recommend-id="image://872ae3d74db5327a1d13177fa983c51e" data-format="png" data-width="618" data-height="306" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="e692e26663555c605b1110c7d12212a2" data-recommend-id="image://e692e26663555c605b1110c7d12212a2" data-format="png" data-width="613" data-height="348" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e692e26663555c605b1110c7d12212a2" data-recommend-id="image://e692e26663555c605b1110c7d12212a2" data-format="png" data-width="613" data-height="348" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="f217450cf301d5147c22a63525e7c08c" data-recommend-id="image://f217450cf301d5147c22a63525e7c08c" data-format="png" data-width="610" data-height="305" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="f217450cf301d5147c22a63525e7c08c" data-recommend-id="image://f217450cf301d5147c22a63525e7c08c" data-format="png" data-width="610" data-height="305" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="e9fcd268b13c91fe36e064201d31ae57" data-recommend-id="image://e9fcd268b13c91fe36e064201d31ae57" data-format="png" data-width="616" data-height="311" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e9fcd268b13c91fe36e064201d31ae57" data-recommend-id="image://e9fcd268b13c91fe36e064201d31ae57" data-format="png" data-width="616" data-height="311" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="dde967edc2201386212bf7b899c59e67" data-recommend-id="image://dde967edc2201386212bf7b899c59e67" data-format="png" data-width="624" data-height="362" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="dde967edc2201386212bf7b899c59e67" data-recommend-id="image://dde967edc2201386212bf7b899c59e67" data-format="png" data-width="624" data-height="362" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="12918c16095f65ef3711e7c198694ca0" data-recommend-id="image://12918c16095f65ef3711e7c198694ca0" data-format="png" data-width="617" data-height="355" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="12918c16095f65ef3711e7c198694ca0" data-recommend-id="image://12918c16095f65ef3711e7c198694ca0" data-format="png" data-width="617" data-height="355" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="fd8857ff7bec2af8e26c42603c59fcc6" data-recommend-id="image://fd8857ff7bec2af8e26c42603c59fcc6" data-format="png" data-width="608" data-height="345" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="fd8857ff7bec2af8e26c42603c59fcc6" data-recommend-id="image://fd8857ff7bec2af8e26c42603c59fcc6" data-format="png" data-width="608" data-height="345" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="0d9604cf9a3936d9a5d703fe7fb1c375" data-recommend-id="image://0d9604cf9a3936d9a5d703fe7fb1c375" data-format="png" data-width="615" data-height="322" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="0d9604cf9a3936d9a5d703fe7fb1c375" data-recommend-id="image://0d9604cf9a3936d9a5d703fe7fb1c375" data-format="png" data-width="615" data-height="322" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="9f3c7242af8844d5c8e997bee70e2fe6" data-recommend-id="image://9f3c7242af8844d5c8e997bee70e2fe6" data-format="png" data-width="614" data-height="274" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="9f3c7242af8844d5c8e997bee70e2fe6" data-recommend-id="image://9f3c7242af8844d5c8e997bee70e2fe6" data-format="png" data-width="614" data-height="274" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><figure id="" data-id="36e809edcfb744321cefde217dd4c811" data-recommend-id="image://36e809edcfb744321cefde217dd4c811" data-format="png" data-width="614" data-height="292" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Valve / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="36e809edcfb744321cefde217dd4c811" data-recommend-id="image://36e809edcfb744321cefde217dd4c811" data-format="png" data-width="614" data-height="292" data-lightbox="true" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age Remaster Unlikely, Creative Director Says]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-remaster-unlikely-creative-director-says/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-remaster-unlikely-creative-director-says.1027980/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-remaster-unlikely-creative-director-says/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Dragon Age: The Veilguard is out and it’s been a <a href="https://opencritic.com/game/17037/dragon-age-the-veilguard">well received game overall</a>. It’s launch 10 years after the last mainline Dragon Age game has had people wondering if the original games could get the remaster treatment. </p>



<p>While Creative Director John Epler would like it to happen, he doesn’t see it likely. In an interview with <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/dragon-age-the-veilguard-john-epler-interview-1235147001/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Rolling Stone</a> around the game’s launch, Epler was asked about seeing the first three games remastered in some way. </p>



<p>“I think I’m one of about maybe 20 people left at BioWare who’s actually used Eclipse,” Epler told the outlet. “It’s something that’s not going to be as easy as Mass Effect, but we do love the original games. Never say never, I guess that’s what it comes down to.”</p>



<p>While he does say “never say never”, the technology of the original games could prove a sticking point. The first two Dragon Age games from 2009 and 2011 were built with the custom Eclipse engine. The third game, Dragon Age: Inquisition ultimately moved to the Frostbite Engine, making it more likely for a remaster than the others. </p>



<p>Rolling Stone mentioned the Mass Effect games getting remastered. Those games were built on Unreal Engine, making it an easier task to bring forward with newer technology.</p>



<p>If it were to happen, it would almost be a certainty that the first two games would have to be built from scratch in Frostbite, or a different engine.</p>



<p>Do you think the original Dragon Age games get remastered? Let us know below, or in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our full <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/interview-maximum-football-wants-to-fill-the-void-for-players/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">interview with Maximum Football Game Director Micah Brown</a>. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk is Somehow a Top 20 Diablo 4 Player]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/elon-musk-top-20-diablo-4-player/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/elon-musk-is-somehow-a-top-20-diablo-4-player.1027977/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/elon-musk-top-20-diablo-4-player/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>If you spend any amount of time online, specifically on X (formerly Twitter), then you know Elon Musk enjoys the sound of his own voice. More specifically, the look of his opinions in text format, as the man tweets constantly. It’s downright amazing <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elon-musk-diablo-4/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how he has time for anything else besides posting online</a>. Still, in his spare time, he’s quickly risen through the ranks to become a top 20 Diablo 4 player—one of only two in the United States. It’s absolutely shocking and entirely true.</p>



<p>It’s well known that Elon Musk plays video games. It wasn’t long ago that players online tore apart his Elden Ring build, after all, but he appears to favor RPGs with grind involved. In Diablo 4, he’s previously complained about how overpowered Barbarians are, and as a Barb main, please cry about it, Elon. Oh, but he plays a Barbarian primarily. Go figure!</p>



<p>During his appearance on the Joe Rogan podcast, Musk kickstarted the conversation by bragging about becoming one of the top 20 Diablo 4 players in the world. He’s one of only two Americans currently on the list, with the other topping the leaderboards in the number one spot. Currently, Musk sits in 19th.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Now, this ranking revolves around Pit runs. He’s achieved the 19th best timed run through Pit 150, which is an absolutely challenging grind and, honestly, a little impressive.</p>



<p>Instead of playing his usual Barbarian, Musk ranked with the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/diablo-4-reveals-new-spiritborn-class/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new Spiritborn class</a>, part of the Vessel of Hatred expansion. Furthermore, he’s running a Quill build.</p>



<p>Alongside Diablo 4 and Elden Ring, Musk is also a long-time fan of Cyberpunk 2077.</p>



<p>Do you think Musk managed to hit the leaderboards in Diablo 4 legitimately or not? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<hr>



<p>On the topic of Elon Musk, did you know he’s considered <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/elon-musk-stream-success/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">one of the most successful streamers ever</a>? He broke records in a single hour!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starship Troopers? Terminator? Warhammer 40,000? Helldivers 2 Creative Director Reveals His Dream Crossovers]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/starship-troopers-terminator-warhammer-40000-helldivers-2-creative-director-reveals-his-dream-crossovers</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/starship-troopers-terminator-warhammer-40-000-helldivers-2-creative-director-reveals-his-dream-crossovers.1027974/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/starship-troopers-terminator-warhammer-40000-helldivers-2-creative-director-reveals-his-dream-crossovers<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Smash hit co-op shooter <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii">Helldivers 2</a> seems ripe for a crossover, but which franchises might it partner with? That’s a fun conversation players have been having ever since the game’s explosive launch earlier this year. Now, Helldivers 2’s creative director has had his say, revealing a number of intellectual properties he’d love to work with.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In a <a href="https://x.com/Pilestedt/status/1853793032249765932" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweet</a>, Arrowhead CCO and Helldivers 2 creative director Johan Pilestedt cautioned against doing too many crossovers, saying “it would dilute the IP and make it a ‘not Helldivers’ experience.” However, he also published an extended list of IPs he “really would love to do a take on!”</p><ul data-cy="list"><li>Aliens</li><li>Starship Troopers</li><li>Terminator</li><li>Predator</li><li>Star Wars</li><li>Fifth Element</li><li>Blade Runner</li><li>Warhammer 40k</li><li>Trench Crusade</li><li>Mutant Chronicles</li><li>Dropzone Commander</li></ul><p data-cy="paragraph">It’s easy to see how many of these franchises would work within Helldivers 2. Starship Troopers is the obvious choice, given Helldivers 2 riffs so heavily on the cult classic sci-fi flick. Terminator, too, seems an easy fit, given the Automaton alien enemy are basically Terminators themselves. Aliens, Predator, and Star Wars are fun to think about, but my favorite is Warhammer 40,000.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It would be amazing to drop down into a planet overrun by Tyranids or Necrons as an Imperial Guard soldier, complete with lore-accurate weapons, vehicles, and, of course, dialogue. Yes, Warhammer 40,000 fans have the wonderful and hugely successful <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/warhammer-40000-space-marine-ii">Space Marine 2</a> to play right now, but that's a Space Marine game. Helldivers 2 is near enough an Imperial Guard game already. I’d drop a dollar or 10 on an Imperial Guard crossover in a heartbeat.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Which brings us on to the next question: how might Helldivers 2 do crossovers if it ever came to it? In a <a href="https://x.com/Pilestedt/status/1853793858959634504" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">subsequent tweet</a>, Pilestedt suggested it could come in the form of a Warbond (Helldivers 2’s take on a battle pass) or even individual super store items.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">“Having a full Starship Troopers Warbond with mobile infantry armor, voices and weapons would also be cool!” Pilestedt said, before stressing: “Nothing decided yet. Just musings :)”</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Can Arrowhead do a deal for a crossover? Helldivers 2 has certainly done well enough to draw out some big hitters. Let’s not forget that Helldivers 2 is the fastest-selling PlayStation Studios game of all time, selling an incredible 12 million copies in just 12 weeks. And while player numbers on Steam aren’t what they once were, they’re still extremely healthy.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">For now, though, crossover dreams remain just that. In the shorter term, Arrowhead continues to update Helldivers 2 with new Warbonds and patches, with the threat of a new alien faction looming over the galactic horizon.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Wesley is the UK News Editor for IGN. Find him on Twitter at @wyp100. You can reach Wesley at wesley_yinpoole@ign.com or confidentially at wyp100@proton.me.</em></p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Slug Tactics Review]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-slug-tactics-review</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-slug-tactics-review.1027968/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/metal-slug-tactics-review<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph">Metal Slug Tactics lives up to its stone-cold classic namesake from SNK’s golden era with its painstakingly detailed pixel art, head-bopping soundtrack, and snappy structure. It magnificently translates the run-n-gun series into its first turn-based tactics game, but doesn’t sacrifice substance for cheap nostalgia, either. Aside from a few annoying quality-of-life issues and bugs, Metal Slug Tactics’ excellent retro-inspired shell houses a well-made, distinct, grid-based tactics roguelite that cleverly adapts its frantic roots into a more orderly genre without missing a step. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Like pretty much every mainline Metal Slug game (the most recent being 2009’s <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2008/11/13/metal-slug-7-review">Metal Slug 7</a>), Tactics puts you in command of the Peregrine Falcons, an elite fighting force within The Normal Army. This spin-off takes full advantage of Metal Slug’s legions of varied enemy types, distinct locations, expansive arsenal, and fleet of awesome vehicles. Sprinkle in clever spins on series mainstays, like rescuing hostages to add some extra objectives on the battlefield, and it’s not hard to see why this seeming left turn was a logical next step.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Metal Slug Tactics Screenshots</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Before starting out on a run, you’ll have to pick three out of this surprisingly diverse cast of nine characters. Every character has four different unlockable loadouts, with each one catering to a slightly different approach. Marco is an all-arounder whose status as leader means lots of his abilities focus on teamwork in both offensive and defensive scenarios, but one of his loadouts lasers in on ranged moves to help maximize the amount of Synchronized attacks he can execute with his teammates in one turn. Alternatively, Trevor is a glass cannon who exposes his targets to death by a million cuts with movement and offensive-focused tactics, but one of his unlockable loadouts ditches ranged versatility to double down on close combat. Meanwhile, Fio is a support character with a ton of helpful mobility tools that make her a reliable ally for setting up all sorts of flashy combos who can also become a self-healing tank.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">This system helped me build my teams around specific goals. One time, I put Fio, Trevor, and a trap-based specialist named Nadia on the same team and picked loadouts that let me exert greater control over the map, allowing me to chase a defensive strategy that revolved around lining up my targets and satisfyingly knocking them all down in one fell swoop.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Tactics squeezes every inch of your screen for all the charm it can display.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">Calling Metal Slug’s unified fighting force “The Normal Army” isn’t Shakespeare, to say the least — nor should it be. The premise and plot serve the “rule of cool,” a master that demands dieselpunk machines, chunky guns, tons of explosions, and bad guys that feel ripped from an ‘80s action movie and usually make no sense. Metal Slug Tactics knocks this out of the park thanks to its art style, which squeezes every inch of your screen for all the charm and character it can possibly display. Tanks and battleships chug and buckle under the sheer force of their destructive horsepower, explosions crash onto the grid with a satisfying flourish, and your characters are never still, even when they’re hiding behind cover. To say Metal Slug Tactics “oozes personality” would be a disservice; it spurts out of every pixel.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Subtle touches that nail Metal Slug’s fun, cartoonish vibes are peppered all over its screens. If you look to the sidelines of a map, you might find soldiers sunbathing just off a desert battlefield or notice the video game Peregrine Falcon member Ralf is playing on a tiny TV in the barracks, which is so well-animated you can tell exactly which 2D fighter he’s playing. This attention to detail is so consistent that I’m still finding new stuff to chuckle at in between turns every time I try a roughly 45-minute run.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Yet another stellar soundtrack from composer Tee Lopes, whose work on <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2017/08/14/sonic-mania-review">Sonic Mania</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/teenage-mutant-ninja-turtles-shredders-revenge-review">TMNT: Shredder’s Revenge</a>, and <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/streets-of-rage-4-review">Streets of Rage 4</a>, has codified him as the king of retro revitalization by way of bumping drum and bass backing wailing guitars. It’s a delight to just jam out and pick up on all the small flourishes.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">When you think of turn and grid-based tactics games, you might think of <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2016/02/01/xcom-2-review">XCOM</a>, <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/gears-tactics-review">Gears Tactics</a>, or <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/mario-rabbids-sparks-of-hope-review">Mario + Rabbids</a>’ lengthy encounters that can last for dozens of in-depth turns. Instead, Metal Slug Tactics sacrifices some of the satisfaction you might get from carefully weaving a web to catch unsuspecting prey over multiple turns for smaller engagements that condense and speed up that same satisfying process. Tactics draws a lot of water from <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/2018/02/27/into-the-breach-review">Into The Breach’s</a> well; most battles take place on a much tighter grid, with attack and movement range scaled down to match. This keeps the turnover rate between levels pretty quick, no matter the objective, ensuring things stay fresh from battle to battle. Still, it does a good job of differentiating itself from the genre-defining 2018 classic thanks to its slightly more expansive battlefields, lower difficulty, and movement-focused mechanics.</p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>It draws a lot of water from Into The Breach’s well, but still does a good job of differentiating itself.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">The goals of each fight here are fun but standard stuff you’d find in just about any tactics game, including the usual eliminating all or some of the enemies on the field, taking out an enemy convoy, protecting civilians, surviving a certain amount of turns, reaching a checkpoint on the map, or escorting an NPC to a certain point. Most of these will still only last about three to five turns and net you some helpful loot to beef up one of your three characters’ attack power, buy a new upgrade in a shop, or get reinforcements that can be used to revive a downed teammate. Secondary objectives reward and encourage skilled play with compelling extra challenges, like missions that task you with taking minimal damage, setting up your squad to chase assists with each other, or completing a level within a certain number of turns to earn bonus loot.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Metal Slug Tactics matches the standard run-based structure of your garden-variety roguelite by offering semi-randomized runs, each divided into four stages that end with a big boss fight. You can opt into taking on just one of the three starting stage options, or pursue all of them before venturing into a final fourth area. Each of these stages will subtly scale its challenge with sightly stronger enemy types depending on which level you took on before, ensuring a consistent sense of progress no matter where you start, but the maps and pace of each of these four regions remains the same. A banner at the top of the screen even constantly reminds you that there are only “X Missions Remaining Until The Boss Arrives.”</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">This is where Tactics feels more like an arcade game more than a roguelite. Although there are secret bosses and optional extra objectives to chase, it doesn’t give you any tools to break the rules. There aren’t any opportunities to, say, take on the remaining handful of missions left on the map of any given section for higher risk with the promise of a better reward. When a boss does crash onto the Super Mario Bros. 3-like overworld map, you have no choice but to engage, which is frustrating. I wish Tactics offered some extra challenge or special conditions to meet that allowed me to complete the area.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Each boss fight does a good job of testing your mastery over Tactics’ movement and teamwork-heavy mechanics. The first boss, for example, has you fighting against a battleship that can barely fit all the guns it has on its deck. It targets your squad with homing missiles, tasking you with getting endangered units to cover while making sure they build up enough Adrenaline to avoid taking damage. Every few turns, the ship will also shoot down one of the platforms your squad is using to target them, forcing you to make sure your team is able to rotate from platform to platform while also dishing out damage from sufficient cover.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Adrenaline and Synchronization, which are Metal Slug Tactics’ shining mechanical innovations, help to justify its smaller scale. The Falcons can accumulate Adrenaline by moving, earning bonuses for jumping between elevations and clearing small gaps. This versatile resource powers a character’s ability to dodge incoming attacks and use special abilities. Linking these two crucial tools for success on the battlefield doesn’t just make for a challenging and rewarding push-and-pull between defense and offense, it also forces you to keep your party in motion. This brilliantly translates the series’ run-n-gun roots into… well, running and gunning, just within the context of a turn-based tactics game. Even characters like the heavy Ralf, who might be slower or tankier in other tactics games, are highly mobile, with limitations placed on their attack range or ability set rather than their range of motion. </p><div data-cy="quoteBox"><p>Sync attacks double down on the satisfaction of lining up a Rube Goldberg machine of bullets.</p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">This meshes exceptionally well with the Synchronization mechanic, which helps Tactics take advantage of its relatively short skirmishes. Whenever one character attacks an enemy or destructible part of the level, other characters within range automatically join in. Lining up the optimal Rube Goldberg machine of bullets and explosions has always been my favorite part of tactics games, and this mechanic doubles down on that satisfaction, with the only limit on sync attacks being placed on Tactics’ boss characters, as they can only be targeted with a sync attack once per turn. Thankfully, each team member can still attack them one at a time without the extra teamwork. Most Adrenaline-fueled special abilities tie into a specific character’s strengths and weaknesses in a way that underlines Tactics’ surprisingly diverse nine-character cast.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Unfortunately, a few annoying bugs in Metal Slug Tactics sometimes blocked me from executing my master plan. One bug I ran into when Ralf was turned into a mummy, which is supposed to temporarily alter your soldiers’ abilities, prevented him from using normal attacks even after transforming back into his regular self. Resetting the turn normally flushes out anything gumming up the works, but that didn’t help here, and I was forced to take my turn hoping the problem would pass after he got behind some cover. Thankfully it did, but I’ve infrequently run into a few issues like that here and there, which hasn’t a huge deal but can be pain all the same. Mercifully, it’s easy enough to work around most problems since Tactics is constantly creating save states after every move, and quitting to the main menu and hopping back into the fray is helpful without being too time-consuming.</p></section><div data-cy="verdict"><h3 data-cy="title3">Verdict</h3><p data-cy="article-verdict-paragraph">From its lively, cartoonish sprites to its energetic soundtrack, Metal Slug Tactics is a meticulously crafted ode to the arcade classic that never gets lost blindly chasing its adoration for the series without understanding what makes Metal Slug great. Instead, it introduces a handful of distinct innovations to the tactics genre that masterfully meld Metal Slug’s action-packed platforming and shooting onto a tactics grid. Even though it’s hampered by some frustrating bugs, I’m still having plenty of fun with each run as I experiment with new strategies and team compositions.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How devs can spot AI-generated 3D models]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/art/how-devs-can-spot-ai-generated-3d-models</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-devs-can-spot-ai-generated-3d-models.1027962/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/art/how-devs-can-spot-ai-generated-3d-models<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game developers have had </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/near-half-of-game-devs-say-they-re-working-with-generative-ai-tools">mixed reactions</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to the advance of generative AI in video game development. Some are eager for machine learning-based tools that help solve complex problems, others are tired of being told AI will replace workers or make their lives easier (when it might just make more work).</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A wrinkle with the rollout of generative AI tools is the transparency (or lack thereof) of when a game or game asset was made using AI. Hiding this fact can create surprises in the hiring process or publishing side if an asset unexpectedly appears in a game. It can also create difficulties when purchasing 3D assets off of stores like Fab. It's become common knowledge that developers can spot AI-generated 2D art by "looking at the fingers" (or other common cues), but how do you do the same for 3D models?</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If modelers making 3D assets with generative AI were required to tag their models as AI-made, it would be easy. But on Fab, they aren't.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Over on Bluesky, veteran 3D artist Liz Edwards answered that question. In a short thread, she broke down common traits in AI-generated 3D models—and how those traits often make said models inferior for general game development usage. She was kind enough to allow Game Developer to recreate her insights to help you learn how to spot the work of machines.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a data-discover="true" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/audio/stellaris-new-ai-characters-are-powered-by-ai-voices" target="_self">Stellaris' new AI characters are powered by AI voices</a></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Bad textures and jumbled UVs">Bad textures and jumbled UVs</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Edwards began by scrutinizing a 3D model of a penguin model she spotted on Fab, which at a first glance, may not seem that odd. Veteran developers may look closer and notice some oddities like the shape of the feet and weird lines on the stomach, but Edwards called out deeper flaws.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The model, she wrote, has "telltale signs" of AI generation. 3D generated models made by AI usually have baked-in lighting, she explained, and the textures are projected from a 2D image. Artifacts from that 2D image remain on the skin.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Image by Liz Edwards via Bluesky</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Edwards accessed the model and looked at the wireframe and UV maps, noting that the wireframe looks like a "dense automesh" and the maps were automatically unwrapped, leaving a "jumbled mess" in their wake.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Image by Liz Edwards via Bluesky</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">She </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/lizaledwards.bsky.social/post/3l7yfj7j26u2b">compared it</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to another penguin model made by "Pinotoon," which possessed more familiar traits, such as a clean UV layout and better-positioned eyeballs and beak.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Edwards used another example of a strange cabinet hybrid to illustrate a common trait with 3D generated models: an insanely high polygon count. Elsewhere on Bluesky, she's spotlighted how the creators of genAI 3D models will put objects like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/lizaledwards.bsky.social/post/3l7cdlnrowl23">crates</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> on the Fab marketplace that have 50,000 triangular polygons, where the average crate in a video game only needs 500 triangular polygons at the very upper end.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Image by Liz Edwards via Bluesky</span></span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="3D models made with generative AI can create confusion">3D models made with generative AI can create confusion</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Edwards warned, the traits above alone don't automatically identify a model as being generated by AI tools. For instance, 3D models captured using photogrammetry share the same traits. The difference is that those models have natural textures, are usually free of artifacts, and have coherent, naturalistic details.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Image by Liz Edwards via Bluesky</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If you aren't animating a given 3D asset or aren't bothered by its polygon count, you might shrug off a model that looks like it was created with photogrammetry—but beware. As Edwards showed, those models can still have incoherent details that look unsettling or inappropriate when viewed up close.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Image by Liz Edwards via Bluesky</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">She also explained that meshes on generative AI-made 3D models are "rarely" symmetrical, and are often melded together into "featureless blobs." Those "blobs" often weld together feet or arms, on animals, monsters, and humanoids, making it impossible to pose or animate them.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Image by Liz Edwards via Bluesky</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This problem spotlights a major risk of using models that trade quality for efficacy in creation—if the object looks "good enough" but either has too many polygons or is impossible to animate, an object could interfere with the rest of the work a team needs to make a great game.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Know how to spot the machines">Know how to spot the machines</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Should game developers have to make their own </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bladerunner.fandom.com/wiki/Voight-Kampff_test">Voigt-Kampf tests</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to identify if visual art is made by generative AI? For now, that would be a "yes." There all kinds of ways that an art asset made with generative AI might slip into your pipeline, and if it's not caught quick, it could cause problems for a team not ready to catch them.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Not all generative AI tech is made with deception in mind. But it's been pointed out that a broad usecase for generative AI is to deceive others, especially when using image, text, or video generation.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A developer in search of a solid penguin model might waste valuable time trying to get this flawed version to work. A recruiter inexperienced in 3D modeling might forward a candidate with AI-generated models if they can't see the machine-made imperfections. For now, all developers can do is arm themselves with the necessary tools and make a judgment call if an AI-generated model fits their needs.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">If you need to do your own sorting a little bit faster, make sure to review Edwards' full thread (and other posts about 3D art) </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://bsky.app/profile/lizaledwards.bsky.social/post/3l7yeogufe42z">over on Bluesky</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Senior Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Bryant Francis is a writer, journalist, and narrative designer based in Boston, MA. He currently writes for Game Developer, a leading B2B publication for the video game industry. His credits include Proxy Studios' upcoming 4X strategy game Zephon and Amplitude Studio's 2017 game Endless Space 2.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2 reveal now "very unlikely" before 2025, analyst says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-reveal-now-very-unlikely-before-2025-analyst-says</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-reveal-now-very-unlikely-before-2025-analyst-says.1027959/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-reveal-now-very-unlikely-before-2025-analyst-says<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"For 2024, the ship has sailed."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Untitled-1_f4yLlpq.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Nintendo</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Nintendo is now "very unlikely" to reveal its hotly-anticipated <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-switch-2-everything-we-know">Switch 2</a> hardware this year, a games industry analyst has told Eurogamer. 
</p>
<p>
This morning's financial results from Nintendo revealed a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-cuts-switch-sales-forecast-as-the-wait-for-new-hardware-continues">larger-than-expected drop in hardware and software sales for the current Switch</a>, as the console ages and its release calendar quietens. 
</p>
<p>
The results also passed by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-says-switch-2-still-on-course-for-announcement-before-end-of-fiscal-year">without even a whiff of Switch 2 being shown</a> - and perhaps, with Nintendo's new hardware not due to arrive until sometime in 2025 - for good reason. 
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Nintendo has announced new hardware, but it's not Switch 2 - so what's the point of Alarmo?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GdNKD3U-4AY" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Speaking to Eurogamer today, industry analyst Serkan Toto, CEO of Japanese game industry consultancy Kantan Games, said any mention of Switch 2 now would only further impede Switch 1 sales during the console's last holiday season.
</p>
<p>
"Nintendo is unpredictable, but I do believe a reveal before the end of the year is very unlikely," Toto said. 
</p>
<p>
"Sales of the current model are cratering, more than Nintendo had already anticipated. They would implode even further if a Switch 2 announcement came before the holidays, so why would they do that?
</p>
<p>
"Instead, Nintendo is a lot more likely to wait until early January to show the new device. For 2024, the ship has sailed."
</p>
<p>
Nintendo's Switch 2 reveal plans have been the subject of a frenzied rumour mill of gossip and speculation amongst fans of the company and the video game industry at large. Throughout all this, Nintendo has remained silent, busy launching its final slate of Switch 1 games, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/inside-the-nintendo-museum-a-joyful-celebration-of-machines-magic-and-the-art-of-play">opening a museum</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-just-unveiled-an-alarm-clock-that-plays-mario-coin-noises-when-you-roll-over">releasing a £99 alarm clock</a>.
</p><p>For its part, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-makes-first-switch-2-announcement">Nintendo has stated it will unveil Switch 2 before the end of its current financial year</a> - 30th April 2025. Eurogamer understands <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hopes-fade-for-switch-2-launch-in-early-2025">Switch 2 will not launch before that point, either</a> - even if it was revealed on 1st January.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enshrouded Souls of the Frozen Frontier Update Is Its Biggest Yet]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/enshrouded-souls-of-frozen-frontier-update</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/enshrouded-souls-of-the-frozen-frontier-update-is-its-biggest-yet.1027944/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/enshrouded-souls-of-frozen-frontier-update<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Open-world survival-crafter&nbsp;<em>Enshrouded&nbsp;</em>has received a brand new update, and it's being described by developer and publisher Keen Games as the game's biggest update yet.</p>

<p>The Souls of the Frozen Frontier update follows on from other major content drops like <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/enshrouded-melodies-of-mire-update">Melodies of the Mire</a> and the <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/first-major-enshrouded-update-hollow-halls">Hollow Halls</a>, and it's seemingly on a similar scale, introducing a whole new biome, a new dynamic weather system, and more.</p>

<p>First up, the Albaneve Summits, a "breathtaking new mountain region", are now yours for the exploring. They're packed with "fresh challenges, discoveries, and opportunities", according to Keen Games, so you should have plenty to keep you busy.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/enshrouded-souls-of-the-frozen-frontier-update-snow.jpg?itok=m-ss7dI_ 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/enshrouded-souls-of-the-frozen-frontier-update-snow.jpg?itok=msiYLG7J 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Enshrouded</em>'s new update has a whole new biome for you to explore.</figcaption></figure><p>As well as the new biome, you can also look forward to a brand new dynamic weather system that sees weather patterns change as you explore. The higher you go, the more snow and cold you'll encounter, and you'll need to accommodate that change with food and clothing.</p>

<p>You can also now tame non-hostile animals and take them back to your base, and just in case you're wondering, it is possible to pet non-hostile animals as well. That alone should be reason enough to head back into&nbsp;<em>Enshrouded</em>.</p>

<p>The game's level cap has been increased to 35, and new crafting resources have been added as part of the new biome's appearance, along with new crafting stations and new armor sets.</p>

<p>In short, there's lots to discover as part of the&nbsp;<em>Enshrouded&nbsp;</em>Souls of the Frozen Frontier update. You can read the full list of changes (which, as you'd expect from a large update like this, is extensive) <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1203620/view/4461471496628338725" rel="noopener" target="_blank">right here</a>.</p>




<p>In case you're not familiar with&nbsp;<em>Enshrouded</em>, it's an open-world survival-crafting game which sees you exploring a vast world, gathering resources to craft a base, and venturing into dangerous mist in order to collect powerful rewards from dangerous enemies.</p>

<p>The game is available right now on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1203620/Enshrouded/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PC via Steam Early Access</a>, and if you want to know what we think of this ambitious survival-crafter, you can <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/previews/enshrouded-final-preview-survival-progression-at-its-finest">check out our preview here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo’s music app has great ideas and frustrating limitations]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/5/24288201/nintendo-music-streaming-hands-on-impressions</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo%E2%80%99s-music-app-has-great-ideas-and-frustrating-limitations.1027941/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/5/24288201/nintendo-music-streaming-hands-on-impressions<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Listening to Nintendo music isn’t easy. It’s not available on streaming platforms, so I usually end up scouring YouTube for songs from <em>Animal Crossing</em> and <em>Metroid</em>. Because of this, I was hoping that Nintendo Music, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/30/24284073/nintendo-music-streaming-app-switch-online-subscribers">a new app that surprise-launched last week</a>, would be my one-stop shop for listening to Nintendo soundtracks. But while it features some clever ideas, there are lots of frustrations and weird choices from Nintendo that mean it isn’t quite what I was hoping for.&nbsp;</p><p>Navigating the app, which is available on iOS and Android but only accessible to Switch Online subscribers, feels a lot like other music services like Apple Music or Spotify. You can browse tracks from individual games or hand-curated playlists themed around things like characters, <em>Pokémon</em> battle songs, or tracks you might want to listen to on an extended loop.&nbsp;It’s organized in a thoughtful way on a per-game basis. The fictional bands in <em>Splatoon 3</em> all get artist pages with bios. The page for <em>Animal Crossing: New Horizons</em> features playlists for K.K. Slider performances <em>and</em> instrumentals, and if you want to listen to a full playlist of Kapp’n’s sea shanties, that’s available, too.</p><p>The extended loop feature is my favorite part. For some songs, you can choose to extend them out to 15, 30, or 60 minutes. I’ve already used it quite a bit to work to music from <em>The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild;</em> the calming piano sounds of “The Great Plateau” are still exquisite seven years later. I also like that you can add games to a “spoiler prevention” list to hide information about a game you might not have played yet, which could be a good way to keep yourself in the dark about a final boss for a game you might want to play.</p><div><p>There just aren’t many games on the app</p></div><p>But Nintendo Music doesn’t have many game soundtracks to listen to. Nintendo has more than 40 years’ worth of titles it could have included, and right now, there are only 25 games to pick from. There are just two <em>Zelda</em> games: <em>Breath of the Wild </em>and <em>Ocarina of Time</em>. <em>Fire Emblem</em> is the only Game Boy Advance game. There are three NES games, and two of them are <em>Metroid</em>. Technically, one of the “games” is Wii Channels music (which, to be fair, is full of bangers).</p><p>I could go on, but the point is that Nintendo Music isn’t a comprehensive collection of the company’s enormous musical history. Given that most of the soundtracks are for Nintendo Switch games, it’s more of a collection of Nintendo’s <em>recent</em> musical history, but it seems like a huge miss that I can’t listen to anything from <em>Super Mario World</em> in the app.</p><p>That will start to change, and probably slowly, if the drip-feed of Switch Online retro games is any indication. A day after the service launched, Nintendo added <a href="https://x.com/Nintendo/status/1852215844421669245">the soundtrack to <em>Super Mario Bros. Wonder</em></a>, and on Monday, <em>Donkey Kong Country 2: Diddy’s Kong Quest</em> became available, too. In the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DQ5EeImWYaI">Nintendo Music reveal trailer</a>, the company showed that <em>Wii Sports</em>, <em>Super Mario 64</em>, <em>The Legend of Zelda: Skyward Sword</em>, <em>The Legend of Zelda: The Wind Waker</em>, <em>Splatoon 2</em>, and <em>F-Zero X</em> are all set to arrive on the service, but only on a vague “over time” schedule.</p><p>Nintendo Music also doesn’t credit the real humans involved in making a song. That means, curiously enough, that the fictional bands in <em>Splatoon 3</em> have more prominence in Nintendo Music <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/4/12/23680052/super-mario-bros-theme-music-us-library-of-congress-nintendo">than the legendary Koji Kondo</a>. (Nintendo has kind of a weird thing <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23860180/mario-new-voice-actor-super-bros-wonder-nintendo">about credits at the moment</a>.)</p><p>The app has some other issues, too. You can’t extend some songs, and there’s no indication why, which is really annoying. One of the first songs I wanted to try the feature with was <em>Metroid Prime</em>’s<em> </em>soothing “Phendrana Drifts” music, but it’s not possible — which, given that it’s one of the main songs you hear on loop while exploring that area of the game, doesn’t make sense to me. Sure, you can just set the song to repeat, but that’s not quite the same as an hour-long extension. And when you select the duration of how long you want to extend a song, the whole song starts over; it’s a little thing, but I wish the app could just make the extension happen without the brief but jarring halt.&nbsp;</p><p>And disappointingly, Nintendo Music is currently only available on iOS and Android — there’s no desktop or web app. I’d really like to listen to Nintendo Music from a Mac app or in my desktop browser; it isn’t compatible with <a href="https://support.m.nintendo.com/hc/en-us/articles/10684349809807-Is-Nintendo-Music-compatible-with-CarPlay-and-Android-Auto">CarPlay or Android Auto</a>, either.</p><p>For the songs that are currently available, Nintendo Music is great. But so much is missing that part of me wonders if Nintendo pushed this service out the door ahead of the launch of the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24051677/nintendo-switch-2-pro-rumors-news">successor to the Switch</a> so that it could add to the service later. It’s a similar feeling to the frustrations with other recent not-Switch things from Nintendo, like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24273422/nintendo-alarmo-review-alarm-clock">the Alarmo clock</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/27/24256070/nintendo-museum-kyoto-tour-shigeru-miyamoto">skin-deep Nintendo Museum</a>; they all have good ideas but also some weird limitations.</p><p>Nintendo Music just isn’t as deep as I would like it to be. It means I’m going to have to keep tracking a lot of music down on YouTube.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch Sells Over 146 Million Units]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-sells-over-146-million-units/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-sells-over-146-million-units.1027935/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-sells-over-146-million-units/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Nintendo Switch has released its dedicated video game unit sales, and the Switch has managed to cross the 145 million mark.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to the <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/en/finance/hard_soft/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">financial report</a>, Nintendo Switch has now sold 146.04 million units of hardware and 1,306.10 million units of software. However, it’s not all good news for Nintendo. According to the report, hardware sales were down 31.0% (4.72 million), and software sales were down 27.6% (70.28 million) year-on-year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of other Nintendo Hardware, the Wii U has sold 13.56 million units, the Wii has sold 101.63 million units, the DS with 154.02 million, the Game Boy Advance has sold 81.51 million units, the Game Boy has sold 118.69 million units, the GameCube sold 21.74 million units, Nintendo 64 sold 32.93 million units, the SNES sold 49.10 million units and the NES sold 61.91 million units.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of Nintendo Switch software sales, new games like Paper Mario Thousand-Year Door have sold 1.94 million units since May 2024, Luigi’s Mansion 2 HD has sold 1.57 million units since June, and&nbsp; The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom has sold 2.58 million units since September. Mario Kart 8 Deluxe also sold 2.31 million units during this period, bringing the cumulative sales to 64.27 million units.&nbsp;</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Welcome to Nintendo Switch!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WniaKJzCNRI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<p>In other news, Nintendo says that the Switch 2 <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">will still be announced before April 2025</a>. Also, the <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-online-playtest-program-has-been-datamined/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">online playtest program</a> for the console was recently datamined. What are your thoughts on the Nintendo Switch selling over 146 million units in its lifetime?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-has-already-earned-over-12-million/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pokemon TCG Pocket earning over $12 million</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RS34 announces The Clean Rooms Project – Karous ports for modern hardware and Karous 2: The Diffused Sanguis]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/rs34-announces-the-clean-rooms-project-karous-ports-for-modern-hardware-and-karous-2-the-diffused-sanguis</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/rs34-announces-the-clean-rooms-project-%E2%80%93-karous-ports-for-modern-hardware-and-karous-2-the-diffused-sanguis.1027932/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/rs34-announces-the-clean-rooms-project-karous-ports-for-modern-hardware-and-karous-2-the-diffused-sanguis<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Ports crowdfunding campaign begins November 11.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > RS34 [17 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/rs34">RS34</a> has announced “<a href="https://rs34.co.jp/game/tcrp/karous.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Clean Rooms Project</a>,” a new initiative to bring back its 2006-released <a title="Genres > Arcade [65 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/arcade">arcade</a> vertical-scrolling <a title="Genres > Shoot 'Em Up [739 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/shoot-em-up">shoot ’em up game</a> <em><a title="Games > Karous (2025)" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/karous-2025">Karous</a></em> with ports for <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,273 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a> and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,635 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> (Steam), as well as a brand-new sequel, <em><a title="Games > Karous 2: The Diffused Sanguis" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/karous-2-the-diffused-sanguis">Karous 2: The Diffused Sanguis</a></em>, for unannounced platforms. <span id="more-925961"></span></p><p>The Tokyo-based developer will open a <a href="https://camp-fire.jp/projects/798386/view" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Campfire crowdfunding campaign</a> for the&nbsp;<em>Karasu</em> ports on <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?iso=20241111T1200" rel="noopener" target="_blank">November 11 at 21:00 JST</a>. It will seek 2.5 million yen (approx. $16,464 USD) to fund the Switch port, which is targeting a September 2025 release in Japan, with a stretch goal of three million yen (approx. $19,760 USD) to fund the PC port, which is targeting a November 2025 release. There will also be stretch goals for a physical edition for Switch at five million yen (approx. $32,938 USD), and <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,310 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a> and <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,407 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a> ports at six million yen (approx. $39,518 USD).</p><p><em>Karous</em> first launched for <a title="Platforms > Arcade [374 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/arcade">arcades</a> on November 15, 2006 in Japan. Ports were released for <a title="Platforms > Dreamcast" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/sega/dreamcast">Dreamcast</a> on March 8, 2007, <a title="Platforms > Wii [241 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/wii">Wii</a> on April 10, 2008, and <a title="Platforms > Xbox 360 [9,999 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-360">Xbox 360</a> via&nbsp;<em>Sakura Flamingo Archives</em> on November 27, 2014. A separate entry, <em>Karous The Beast Of Re:Eden</em>, was also released for <a title="Platforms > 3DS [3,973 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/3ds">3DS</a> on January 23, 2014. The game is notable for its various distinctive elements, such as black-and-white graphics, drum and bass-based music, a growth system, and friendly difficulty for shoot ’em up beginners.</p><p>Watch teaser trailers for both projects below.</p><h2><span><em>Karous</em> Ports</span></h2><p><iframe title="THE CLEAN ROOMS PROJECT - KAROUS" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XNiuYHS-67I?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <h2><span><em>Karous 2: The Diffused Sanguis</em></span></h2><p><iframe title="THE CLEAN ROOMS PROJECT - KAROUS2" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mro4xsG8V6U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA 6 Will "Blow People Away," Former Developer Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-will-blow-people-away-former-developer-says/1100-6527581/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/gta-6-will-blow-people-away-former-developer-says.1027929/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/gta-6-will-blow-people-away-former-developer-says/1100-6527581/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527581">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Game designer Ben Hinchliffe worked at Rockstar Games for more than a decade, and he contributed to games like Grand Theft Auto V, Red Dead Redemption II, and <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/grand-theft-auto-6-everything-we-know/1100-6503729/" data-ref-id="1100-6503729">Grand Theft Auto VI</a> before leaving the company in 2022. In a new interview, Hinchliffe briefly discussed GTA VI, saying he believes the game will "blow people away" and be a smashing success when it comes to sales.</p><p>"It will sell an absolute ton, as it always does. People will be talking about it for ages afterwards, just like they do with GTA 5," Hinchliffe told <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R5mzJsGhmr4" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GTA VI O'clock</a>. "I think they've raised the bar again. They always do, and they have done again with GTA 6."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/GTAVI_Countdown/status/1853287550774804935" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">Ex-lead designer Ben Hinchliffe stated that GTAVI is in the bug fixing phase and that mission design, which gives players freedom is what makes the game good.<br>He’s also excited to see how much the game has changed since he left in 2021.<br>Full interview:<a href="https://t.co/UiV1h1YWof" rel="nofollow ">https://t.co/UiV1h1YWof</a> <a href="https://t.co/79rzROWHee" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/79rzROWHee</a></p>  — GTA 6 Countdown ⏳ (@GTAVI_Countdown) <a href="https://twitter.com/GTAVI_Countdown/status/1853287550774804935?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 4, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>Asked what he's most excited about for GTA VI, Hinchliffe said he's keen to see how the game has evolved since he <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ben-hinchliffe-204a202b/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">left in 2022</a>. He didn't give much away, though, which is to be expected for such a secretive project. Hinchliffe now works at Sniper Elite VR studio Just Add Water.</p><p>GTA VI is set for release in Holiday 2025 for PlayStation 5 and Xbox Series X|S. The game is set in Vice City, which is a stand-in for Miami, Florida. The game's first trailer was released in early December 2023, and to date, Rockstar Games has not released any additional footage or official details about the game.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="1681093858" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6462992,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;GTA%206%20%28Grand%20Theft%20Auto%20VI%29%20Official%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:90,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-vi-official-trailer\/2300-6462992\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6462992\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6462992\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6462992\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6462992&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6462992,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6527581&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;grand-theft-auto-vi&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;action,adventure&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;rockstar-games&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;grand-theft-auto&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;grand-theft-auto&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6462992},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6462992\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1352\/13527689\/4230000-grandtheftautovitrailer1.mp4.00_01_18_07.still003.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/AZDVIclg.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1701732660,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="AZDVIclg" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6462992" data-src="/videos/gta-6-grand-theft-auto-vi-official-trailer/2300-6462992/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>GTA 6 (Grand Theft Auto VI) Official Trailer</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p>GTA VI is coming to market with an enormous amount of hype and expectation behind it. After all, GTA V has sold <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/as-gta-6-approaches-gta-5-passes-200-million-copies-sold/1100-6523542/" data-ref-id="1100-6523542">more than 200 million copies</a>. Parent company Take-Two will releases its next earnings report on November 6, but there is no word yet on if there will be any news about GTA VI.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enshrouded’s Biggest Update To Date Is Out Now, Adding New NPCs, Animal Companions & More]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/enshrouded-biggest-update-to-date-is-out-now-adding-new-npcs-animal-companions-more/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/enshrouded%E2%80%99s-biggest-update-to-date-is-out-now-adding-new-npcs-animal-companions-more.1027914/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/enshrouded-biggest-update-to-date-is-out-now-adding-new-npcs-animal-companions-more/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Since the release of Enshrouded, Keen Games has been nonstop on adding quality-of-life changes to the game and major content updates for the title to keep it fresh in the Early Access period. When it comes to value for money, Enshrouded is undoubtedly it. Today, the fourth content update, Souls of the Frozen Frontier, is out and available. This is their biggest update yet and adds a ton of new content to explore, as well as bug fixes and quality-of-life improvements. The full 1.0 launch of Enshrouded is edging ever closer, as the full release is planned for 2025 on PC, PlayStation, and Xbox. This title has been in Early Access since <a href="https://wccftech.com/enshrouded-hits-30-million-players-since-january/">January 2024</a>, and Keen Games is showing no signs of slowing down. If you are getting stuck into the latest update, there is a lot to look forward to.</p>
<p>To celebrate the release of the new update, Keen Games has released two videos to show off the features, with one being a general trailer and the other being a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VpK-BZdngOc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">feature spotlight</a>.</p>
<p><iframe title="Enshrouded - Souls of the Frozen Frontier | Official Update Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PogZ1u9mGSM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>First and foremost, there is now a new region to explore named the Albaneve Summits. Here, you'll get to experience the brand-new dynamic weather system, which will be featured throughout the entirety of Embervale and will take you through snowy tundras, ice plains, and plenty of new quests. The Summit is home to a lot of new monsters and creatures, as well as materials that you can bring back to your base and use for crafting.</p>
<p>For some, the most important things that are being added to Enshrouded are pets and farm animals. You can now have furry friends to keep you company at base. Anything non-aggressive can be tamed, and you can then help escort them back to your base. To make sure they're safe and happy, you can provide them with a home and some treats to keep them happy. If you are keeping farm animals, they will also drop resources that you can use every once in a while.</p>
<p>That's not all, as there are also new NPCs that you can find throughout Embervale, which can now be asked to return with you to your base to assist with crafting recipes and other tasks. Along with this comes new armor sets that you can equip to remain fashionable as you explore the expansive world of Enshrouded, with the player level cap now being increased to level 35 in the new update. This will allow you to access new spells, skills, and additional perks to help you survive the frozen areas of Embervale.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy XVI Producer Reckons the Idea of an Exclusive Is Disappearing Altogether]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-producer-reckons-the-idea-of-an-exclusive-is-disappearing-altogether/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/final-fantasy-xvi-producer-reckons-the-idea-of-an-exclusive-is-disappearing-altogether.1027911/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-producer-reckons-the-idea-of-an-exclusive-is-disappearing-altogether/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p><span>Final Fantasy XVI producer and Final Fantasy XIV director Naoki Yoshida was recently&nbsp;<a href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/811/G081112/20241010055/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">interviewed</a> by the Japanese website 4Gamer alongside series creator Hironobu Sakaguchi to discuss the upcoming game <a href="https://wccftech.com/fantasian-neo-dimension-launches-december/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FANTASIAN Neo Dimension</a>, which will be available next month on PC and consoles after an exclusive debut on Apple Arcade.</span></p>
<p>When asked whether he'd ever want to make a game for Apple's platform, Yoshida-san replied that in his mind, the idea of a platform exclusive is disappearing altogether.</p>
<p><em>Now the biggest gaming platform is the PC, and with the streaming boom, PC-based gamers are becoming mainstream. But on the other hand, smart devices are becoming a platform that everyone has for the younger generation. Given that, if possible, it would be better to make it playable on any platform rather than making it for a specific platform in order to reach a much larger audience. With that as a basic idea, I decide whether the game I'm trying to make will run properly on smart devices.</em><br>
<em>If the parts that can't be run are equal to the fun of the game, I'll give up on smart devices and make it fun. On the other hand, if it fits within the specs and can be played without the device getting too hot to touch, it's definitely better to make it for smart devices as well. In my mind, the idea of ​​a platform exclusive is disappearing altogether.</em></p>
<p>Final Fantasy XVI certainly suffered from that. It was only available on PlayStation 5 for over a year, which <a href="https://wccftech.com/final-fantasy-xvi-fell-short-high-end-sales-goal-slow-ps5-adoption-blamed/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">led</a> to weak sales, similar to Final Fantasy VII Rebirth. Now, Square Enix has largely <a href="https://wccftech.com/square-enix-unveils-new-business-plan-with-aggressive-multiplatform-strategy-and-quality-over-quantity-focus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">switched</a> to a multiplatform strategy that will take Xbox into much greater account. Yoshida reiterates the shift later in the aforementioned interview:</p>
<p><em>This time, we will also release the Xbox Series X|S version (of FANTASIAN: Neo Dimension) at the same time. In the future, Square Enix titles will be released simultaneously on each platform more and more, but since this is close to the first release, we would like Xbox users to play it as well.</em></p>
<p>Xbox fans are hoping Square Enix will eventually bring Final Fantasy XVI to their favorite platform, too, after the recent debut on PC.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revel In The Horror Of Death With Diablo 4's Ultimate Necromancer]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/necromancer-build-guide-diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-1851688127</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/revel-in-the-horror-of-death-with-diablo-4s-ultimate-necromancer.1027905/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/necromancer-build-guide-diablo-4-vessel-of-hatred-1851688127<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The Necromancer has long been a staple of the <em>Diablo</em> games, and if you want to wield death and decay as your chosen elements in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://howl.link/6oubm4eye5j6r&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://howl.link/6oubm4eye5j6r" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Diablo IV: Vessel of Hatred</em></a></span>, this build guide will help you, whether you’re starting out or getting ready to tackle the endgame.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195326" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Diablo IV's Strongholds Are A Great Way To Level Up This Season" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="326" data-playlist="195326,195150,194907" data-current="195326"><div><p>Diablo IV's Strongholds Are A Great Way To Level Up This Season</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195326/195326_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20784.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The Necromancer is a hero who revels in death because it’s the source of their power. Raise skeletal minions to fight for you, fashion bones and blood into weapons, and embrace the macabre to destroy the demonic forces that stand against you.<br></p><h2 id="h78631"><a id=""></a><strong>Beginner Leveling Build - Necromancer</strong></h2><p>As with the other classes, there are tons of options for the Necromancer to level up with. I typically go for “minion” builds, but their power seems a bit under-baked in <em>Diablo IV</em>, so I went back to my <em>Diablo II</em> standard: Bone Spear. Always a classic, that build sacrifices your minions to increase your solo damage capabilities, and I’ve listed it below as the “Endgame” build since it is very similar to what you’ll use once you begin Torment difficulties.</p><p>As for the minion build, a good starting point is this beginner build right here. Keep in mind you’ll need to be careful when engaging bosses, making sure to keep raising new minions (they will die often, even when buffed) and keep yourself healed.</p><figure id="" data-id="ffe226d207ef99c5deab364a79aa3dbd" data-recommend-id="image://ffe226d207ef99c5deab364a79aa3dbd" data-format="png" data-width="2560" data-height="1440" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Necromancer skill tree in Diablo IV Vessel of Hatred" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Necromancer skill tree in Diablo IV Vessel of Hatred" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="ffe226d207ef99c5deab364a79aa3dbd" data-recommend-id="image://ffe226d207ef99c5deab364a79aa3dbd" data-format="png" data-width="2560" data-height="1440" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Necromancer skill tree in Diablo IV Vessel of Hatred" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><strong>Basic Skills</strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Bone Splinters 1/5 - Enhanced</li></ul><p><strong>Core Skills</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Bone Spear 5/5 - Supernatural</li><li>Unliving Energy 3/3</li><li>Hewed Flesh 3/3</li><li>Imperfectly Balanced 2/3</li></ul><p><strong>Corpse &amp; Macabre Skills</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Corpse Explosion 5/5 - Plagued</li><li>Grim Harvest 3/3</li><li>Fueled By Death 3/3</li><li>Skeletal Warrior Mastery 3/3</li><li>Blood Mist 1/5 - Enhanced</li></ul><p><strong>Curse Skills</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>None</li><li>Iron Maiden (Optional)</li></ul><p><strong>Corpse &amp; Macabre Skills (2nd)</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Serration 3/3</li><li>Compound Fracture 3/3</li><li>Evulsion 3/3</li></ul><p><strong>Ultimate Skills</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>None</li></ul><p><strong>Key Passive</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Ossified Essence</li></ul><p><strong>Book Of The Dead</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Skeletal Warriors (Reaper)</li><li>Skeletal Mages (Cold)</li><li>Golems (Blood)</li></ul><h2 id="h78632"><a id=""></a>Beginner Endgame Build - Necromancer</h2><p>The endgame build is very similar to the leveling build I ended up using, so this is absolutely another option for you if you want to avoid dealing with how underpowered minion builds currently are in <em>Diablo IV</em>. </p><p>Otherwise, use this as a launching point for your endgame activities, as it scales very well with better gear. The basic idea is to cast Corpse Tendrils to gather enemies up, then cast Iron Maiden on them and spend your Essence on Bone Spear. Use Bone Splinters to gain Essence back, use Soulrift when you are getting overwhelmed (or are facing Elites), and repeat as necessary.<br></p><figure id="" data-id="b7eccbddbc485d43e8fef8fc6cff2965" data-recommend-id="image://b7eccbddbc485d43e8fef8fc6cff2965" data-format="png" data-width="2560" data-height="1440" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Necromancer gameplay in Diablo IV Vessel of Hatred" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Necromancer gameplay in Diablo IV Vessel of Hatred" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="false" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->Blizzard / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="b7eccbddbc485d43e8fef8fc6cff2965" data-recommend-id="image://b7eccbddbc485d43e8fef8fc6cff2965" data-format="png" data-width="2560" data-height="1440" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Necromancer gameplay in Diablo IV Vessel of Hatred" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><strong>Basic Skills</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Bone Splinters 1/5 - Enhanced</li></ul><p><strong>Core Skills</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Bone Spear 5/5 - Supernatural</li><li>Unliving Energy 3/3</li><li>Hewed Flesh ?/3</li><li>Imperfectly Balanced ?/3</li></ul><p><strong>Corpse &amp; Macabre Skills</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Blood Mist 1/5</li><li>Corpse Explosion 1/5</li><li>Grim Harvest 3/3</li><li>Necrotic Fortitude 3/3</li><li>Titan’s Fall 1/3</li></ul><p><strong>Curse Skills</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Death’s Embrace 3/3</li><li>Iron Maiden 1/5 - Enhanced</li><li>Amplify Damage 3/3</li><li>Death’s Approach 3/3</li><li>Precision Decay 3/3</li></ul><p><strong>Corpse &amp; Macabre Skills (2nd)</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Corpse Tendrils 1/5 - Plagued</li><li>Serration 1/3</li><li>Compound Fracture 1/3</li><li>Evulsion 1/3</li></ul><p><strong>Ultimate Skills</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Stand Alone 3/3</li><li>Memento Mori 3/3</li><li>Soulrift 5/5 - Prime</li></ul><p><strong>Key Passive</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Affliction</li></ul><p><strong>Book Of The Dead</strong><br></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Skeletal Warriors (Skirmisher) - SACRIFICED</li><li>Skeletal Mages (Cold) - SACRIFICED</li></ul><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Golems (Bone) - SACRIFICED</li></ul><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Your First Look at Planet Coaster 2 Achievements and How to Unlock Them]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/planet-coaster-2-achievements-unlock-them/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/your-first-look-at-planet-coaster-2-achievements-and-how-to-unlock-them.1027902/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/planet-coaster-2-achievements-unlock-them/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>If you’re as excited as I am about Planet Coaster 2, then you’ll likely want to check out the achievements coming to the creative park building and management game. There aren’t too many, but enough to challenge you and keep you working toward a goal beyond the most beautiful park imaginable. </p>



<h2 id="h-all-planet-coaster-2-achievements-and-how-to-unlock-each">All Planet Coaster 2 Achievements and How to Unlock Each</h2>



<p>The clear majority of Planet Coaster 2 achievements revolve around progressing through the game’s story mode, completing various challenges, and exploring the game’s core mechanics. They don’t appear overly tricky to unlock, so I’m confident you can 100% the game this year.</p>



<figure><table><thead><tr><th data-align="center">Achievement</th><th>Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Ancient Achievements</strong></td><td>Earn a Silver Medal on Parks and Restoration</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>What Lurks Beneath</strong></td><td>Earn a Bronze Medal on Labyrinth Secrets</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Park Half Full</strong></td><td>Earn a Bronze Medal on Double Trouble</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Sunken Pleasures</strong></td><td>Earn a Bronze Medal on Paradise Lost</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>People Person’s Person People</strong></td><td>Have 10 Hired Staff simultaneously in any park</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>On a Roll</strong></td><td>Open your first Coaster in any park</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Get Your Feet Wet</strong></td><td>Open your first Flume in any park</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Time to Ride</strong></td><td>Open your first Flat Ride in any park</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Showstopper</strong></td><td>Build a 3 Star Park</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>First Drop</strong></td><td>Complete the Prologue</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Rolling With It</strong></td><td>Complete Chapter 1</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Wheel-y Good Time</strong></td><td>Complete Chapter 2</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>What a View!</strong></td><td>Spend $50,000 on Scenery in a single park</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Ride the Waterfall</strong></td><td>Build and open a Water Slide or Flume with a Drop of at least 100m</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Quite the Crowd</strong></td><td>Have 1000 Guests in a park simultaneously</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Not For The Faint-Hearted</strong></td><td>Build and open a Coaster with Excitement at 7 or above</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>In a Word, Whoooosh</strong></td><td>Build and open a Coaster that reaches at least 100 mph / 161 kph</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Satisfaction Guaranteed</strong></td><td>Achieve 70% of Guests in a Positive Mood at the End of a Day With At Least 2,500 Guests In The Park</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Slip ‘n Slide</strong></td><td>Have 30 Guests riding Water Slides or Flumes simultaneously</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>No Track Required</strong></td><td>Have at least 250 Guests on Flat Rides simultaneously</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Mess Without Stress</strong></td><td>Earn a Gold Medal on Thrills’n’Spills</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Envy of the Gods</strong></td><td>Earn a Platinum Medal on The Garden of Edith</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Water Wonderful World</strong></td><td>Earn a Platinum Medal on A Shore Thing</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Crowd Pleaser</strong></td><td>Build a 4 Star park</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Twisting Tracks</strong></td><td>Complete Chapter 3</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Final Plunge</strong></td><td>Complete Chapter 4</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Eugene Would Be Proud</strong></td><td>Unlock all Research</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Splashing Around</strong></td><td>Have 500 Guests in Pools simultaneously</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Test of Endurance</strong></td><td>Build and open a Coaster with at least 2,500m of track</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>All the Slides</strong></td><td>Have 20 Water Slides or Flumes open in a single park</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Down Is Up</strong></td><td>Build and open a Coaster over 500m in length with at least 10 inversions</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Golden Oldies</strong></td><td>Have 5 Rides achieve “Classic” status in a single park</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>What Even Is Interest?</strong></td><td>Take out a Loan of at least $20,000</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Best of the Best</strong></td><td>Build and open a Coaster with 2,500m of Track and Excitement greater than 9</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Against the Odds</strong></td><td>Build a 5 Star Park in Sandbox Mode</td></tr><tr><td data-align="center"><strong>Fully Loaded</strong></td><td>Unlock all 72 Career Medals in the base game</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>







<h2 id="h-is-there-a-planet-coaster-2-platinum-trophy-on-ps5">Is There a Planet Coaster 2 Platinum Trophy on PS5?</h2>



<p>As Planet Coaster 2 launches simultaneously on PC and PlayStation 5, along with the Xbox Series X|S, it does indeed have a platinum trophy to unlock. It’s called “Heir to the Throne,” and of course, requires you to unlock all other trophies in the game to acquire.</p>



<p>It’s quite the challenge, but savvy fans with experience in previous “Planet” titles should have no issue meeting the unlock requirements for each of the above-mentioned Planet Coaster 2 achievements and trophies!</p>



<p>Don’t forget to show off your park in <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our community forums</a>! We love to see screenshots of your latest gaming sessions!</p>



<hr>



<p>Did you know Insider Gaming recently sat down with <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hannah-telle-interview-life-is-strange-double-exposure/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hannah Telle on her return as Max in Life is Strange: Double Exposure</a>? It’s an interview worth checking out before you leave!</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pokemon TCG Pocket Has Already Earned Over $12 Million]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-has-already-earned-over-12-million/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/pokemon-tcg-pocket-has-already-earned-over-12-million.1027899/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-tcg-pocket-has-already-earned-over-12-million/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Pokemon TCG (Trading Card Game) Pocket is off to a solid start, raking in over $12 million within 4 days of release.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to data provided by <a href="https://appmagic.rocks/iphone/pokemon-tcg-pocket/6479970832" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">AppMagic</a> (via <a href="https://mobilegamer.biz/pokemon-tcg-pocket-is-earning-over-3m-per-day-with-over-12m-banked-to-date/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">mobilegamer.biz</a>), Pokemon TCG Pocket earned $3 million per day during the opening weekend, accumulating a sum of $12 million within just four days. The game was released on the iOS App Store and Android Play Store on October 30, and since then, it has amassed over 10 million downloads globally.&nbsp;</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>Pokemon TCG Pocket is an application that allows you to enjoy your card-collecting and trading passion digitally. The game is available in 89 countries worldwide, allowing players to open packs, collect cards, battle other players, and more. The collection features nostalgic illustrations as well as some completely new ones that have been specifically designed for the game.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Players can open two booster packs for free each day; they also have the option to showcase their collections in files and boards to share them with the world. A new Pokemon card experience has been designed explicitly for TCG Pocket, which features ‘Immersive Cards’ with three-dimensional illustrations. Lastly, it features battles that are easy to understand and don’t take too long.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, check out <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/how-to-get-flair-in-pokemon-pocket-tcg/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to get ‘Flair’</a> in Pokemon Pocket TCG. Also, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/game-freak-leaks-pokemon-movie/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Game Freak leaks revealed</a> an ‘adult’ Pokemon movie and a new anime in production. What are your thoughts on Pokemon TCG Pocket earning over $12 million in the first four days of release? Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-switch-2-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nintendo Switch 2 being on course for an announcement before April 2025</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Interview – Maximum Football Wants To Fill The Void For Players]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/interview-maximum-football-wants-to-fill-the-void-for-players/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/interview-%E2%80%93-maximum-football-wants-to-fill-the-void-for-players.1027896/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/interview-maximum-football-wants-to-fill-the-void-for-players/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Maximum Football is a game years in the making from Maximum Entertainment. As the game heads into early access, Insider Gaming Senior Editor Mike Straw caught up with Game Director Micah Brown to talk all things Maximum Football.</p>



<p>In this nearly 30-minute talk, Straw and Brown talk about the state of the game, the decision behind pricing, future plans and updates, its console release, getting Madden fans to try it, and much more. </p>







<p>You can watch the interview in full down below. Time stamps are also provided if you’d like to skip directly to a specific topic. And don’t forget to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@insider_gaming?sub_confirmation=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">subscribe to Insider Gaming on YouTube</a>.</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="INTERVIEW - Maximum Football Wants To Fill The Void For Players" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XeL0DATuV6E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>



<ul>
<li><strong>0:00 –</strong> Intro </li>



<li><strong>0:22 –</strong> How are you feeling about the state of the game? </li>



<li><strong>1:25 –</strong> What has the development experience been like? </li>



<li><strong>3:40 –</strong> Feedback from Steam Next Fest Demo </li>



<li><strong>5:19 – </strong>How much time went into getting animations done?</li>



<li><strong>7:58 –</strong> Dealing with the comparisons to Madden NFL and potential criticism? </li>



<li><strong>10:37 –</strong> How do you appeal to Madden players and those skeptical? </li>



<li><strong>11:36 –</strong> Having both college and pro rules and leagues in Maximum Football </li>



<li><strong>13:19 –</strong> What went into deciding on the pricing model? </li>



<li><strong>15:40 –</strong> What didn’t get in for early access? </li>



<li><strong>18:35 – </strong>Schedule for Maximum Football Early Access Updates? </li>



<li><strong>19:40 – </strong>How long will Maximum Football stay in Early Access and when will a console release happen? </li>



<li><strong>20:28 – </strong>Canadian rules? </li>



<li><strong>21:27 –</strong> Not having College Football competition on PC? </li>



<li><strong>22:25 –</strong> Maximum Football feature Micah Brown is most excited about? </li>



<li><strong>24:59 –</strong> How have things changed over the years? </li>
</ul>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/hannah-telle-interview-life-is-strange-double-exposure/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sit down with the actress behind Max Caulfield</a> in Life is Strange, Hannah Telle. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fairy Tail 2 details game-original story]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/fairy-tail-2-details-game-original-story</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fairy-tail-2-details-game-original-story.1027893/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/11/fairy-tail-2-details-game-original-story<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PS4</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Unlocked after clearing the main story.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Publisher <a title="Companies > Koei Tecmo Games [3,029 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games">Koei Tecmo</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Gust [797 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/koei-tecmo-games/gust">Gust</a> have released new information, video, and screenshots for <em><a title="Games > Fairy Tail 2 [5 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/fairy-tail-2">Fairy Tail 2</a></em> introducing its game-original story that unlocks after clearing the main story. <span id="more-925939"></span></p><blockquote><p><strong>Features a Game-Original Story You Can Only See in this Title!</strong></p><p>See what happens after the Alvarez Empire Arc in the original story “Key to the Unknown”!</p><p>Also experience new sides to the characters from <em>FAIRY TAIL</em> only found in this game through “Character Stories”!</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_002.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_003.jpg"></a></figure><!-- AD: content -->
        <p><strong>Key to the Unknown</strong></p><p>After clearing the main story, a new journey that spans across the sprawling world map, the “Key to the Unknown,” begins. All four of its chapters can only be experienced through this game-original story.</p><p><em>—Visit areas previously unobtainable in the main story as the <a title="Genres > Adventure [1,849 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> expands! Taking place in the west, “Investigating the Golden Tales”! has you locating a restaurant in the forest in order to obtain a hidden treasure. has you locating a restaurant in the forest in order to obtain a hidden treasure. You have to pretend to be a couple to get in, though…</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_004.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_005.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—A restaurant tucked away somewhere in the forest of Fiore, run by a “<a title="Games > Monster Chef" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/monster-chef">Monster Chef</a>,” is said to hide a certain “treasure” that is rumored to be hidden in the restaurant; but it seems that only lovebirds can enter..? Find out the secrets of this restaurant, which can only be discovered through this game.</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_006.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Monster Chef is a mysterious monster who runs a restaurant in the forest. He is a romantic who lives for love, but a strange incident causes him to run amok. Can Lucy and her friends bring him back to his senses and get to the “treasure” in the restaurant?</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_007.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_008.jpg"></a></figure><p><em>—Gildarts, who has consumed a drink that “deepens your feelings for the person you love,” is even more concerned about Cana than usual, and searches for her from east to west. However, the seemingly foolish parental figure has deep feelings that only Gildarts and Cana can share… This is a story that also offers a glimpse into the feelings of each team member towards their “parents.”</em></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Fairy Tail 2 - Original Story Clip (English)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KvNW0LAG-38?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Fairy Tail 2 - Original Story Clip (Japanese)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AmxXn2mOW_Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><em>—After the battle, we head over to <a title="Games > Aka [2 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/aka">Aka</a>ne Beach… The “Key to the Unknown” arc, which takes place after the main story, includes an encounter with an unexpected character. Apparently, she is not the only member of the Spriggan 12 visiting the beach…</em></p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_009.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_010.jpg"></a></figure><p><strong>A Moment with Your Companions</strong></p><p>At the campfires in each area, episodes of Fairy Tail’s members are depicted fully voiced. (Voices are in Japanese only.) As you progress through the story or level up your characters, new episodes are unlocked.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_011.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_012.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_013.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_014.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_015.jpg"></a></figure><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/FAIRY-TAIL-2_2024_11-05-24_016.jpg"></a></figure></blockquote><p><em>Fairy Tail 2</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [8,310 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,407 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [16,273 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [21,635 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/3002850/FAIRY_TAIL_2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on December 12 in Japan and December 13 worldwide. Because of the time difference, the PC version will be available on December 11 in the west.</p><p>Watch a new trailer below. View the screenshots <a href="https://www.gematsu.com/gallery/fairy-tail-2/november-5-2024/">at the gallery</a>.</p><h2><span>Original Game Story and Character Stories Introduction</span></h2><p><strong>English</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="FAIRY TAIL 2 - Original Game Story and Character Stories Introduction" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZlD7GuMYaAo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p><strong>Japanese</strong></p><p><iframe loading="lazy" title="ゲーム『FAIRY TAIL２』ゲームオリジナルストーリー＆キャラクターストーリー紹介映像" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U5xzZx6LlQ0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2><span>Screenshots</span></h2><div id="carousel_925941"><ul><li><span>❮</span></li><li><span>❯</span></li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why A Dragon Age Trilogy Compilation May Never Happen]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/why-a-dragon-age-trilogy-compilation-may-never-happen/1100-6527580/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/why-a-dragon-age-trilogy-compilation-may-never-happen.1027890/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/why-a-dragon-age-trilogy-compilation-may-never-happen/1100-6527580/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527580">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>BioWare released a compilation package for its Mass Effect series bundling the original trilogy, but could the studio do the same for the Dragon Age franchise? Don't get your hopes up, but nothing has been ruled out.</p><p>BioWare creative director John Epler said in an interview that this would be especially difficult because the first two Dragon Age games were made on the Eclipse engine before Dragon Age: Inquisition shifted to Frostbite.</p><div tabindex="0" data-id="651784245" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6465422,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;The%20Good%20and%20The%20Bad%20of%20Dragon%20Age%3A%20The%20Veilguard&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:1479,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:false,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/the-good-and-the-bad-of-dragon-age-the-veilguard\/2300-6465422\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465422\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465422\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6465422\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6465422&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6465422,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6527580&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;dragon-age-inquisition,dragon-age-origins,dragon-age-ii,dragon-age-the-veilguard&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;3d,action,adventure,role-playing,third-person&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;xbox-one,playstation-3,xbox-360,pc,playstation-4,macintosh,playstation-5,xbox-series-x&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;electronic-arts,sony-dadc-brasil&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;dragon-age&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;dragon-age&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6465422},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6465422\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;GameSpot&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4391345-reviewinprogress_daveilguard_v1_site.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/mqLC3cXY.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1730127600,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="mqLC3cXY" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle" data-embed-type="video" data-ref-id="2300-6465422" data-src="/videos/the-good-and-the-bad-of-dragon-age-the-veilguard/2300-6465422/" data-width="100%" data-height="100%" data-video-start="0"><div><p>The Good and The Bad of Dragon Age: The Veilguard</p><div><p>         Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?       </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!       </p></div></div><p>       Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.     </p><p>       This video has an invalid file format.     </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div><p>Epler told <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/rs-gaming/dragon-age-the-veilguard-john-epler-interview-1235147001/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Rolling Stone</a> that he's one of maybe 20 people still working at BioWare who has experience with Eclipse, which could make putting together a compilation package difficult. For comparison, the Mass Effect trilogy was made using the Unreal Engine, which made it easier to put all three games together in 2021's Mass Effect Legendary Edition.</p><p>"It's something that's not going to be as easy Mass Effect, but we do love the original games. Never say never; I guess that's what it comes down to," Epler said.</p><p>Dragon Age: The Veilguard launched on October 31 and is putting up <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-is-biowares-biggest-launch-ever-on-steam/1100-6527529/" data-ref-id="1100-6527529">big numbers on Steam</a>, though neither BioWare nor EA has revealed any hard sales data. EA CEO Andrew Wilson said on an <a href="https://s204.q4cdn.com/701424631/files/doc_financials/2025/q2/Q2-FY25-Earnings-Call-Transcript-FINAL.pdf" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">earnings call this week</a>, "The team feels really energized by what they have delivered. And my sense is that, yes, it has breakout capabilities."</p><p>GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/dragon-age-the-veilguard-review/1900-6418294/" data-ref-id="1900-6418294">Dragon Age: The Veilguard review in progress</a> scored the game a 7/10. If you're just getting into the game, you might want to check out GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-veilguard-guides-hub/1100-6527490/" data-ref-id="1100-6527490">The Veilguard guides hub.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lost 2003 E3 Halo 2 demo coming to Master Chief Collection via Steam Workshop mod]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/lost-2003-e3-halo-2-demo-coming-to-master-chief-collection-via-steam-workshop-mod</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lost-2003-e3-halo-2-demo-coming-to-master-chief-collection-via-steam-workshop-mod.1027887/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/lost-2003-e3-halo-2-demo-coming-to-master-chief-collection-via-steam-workshop-mod<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



            <p>As part of celebrations for <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/halo-2">Halo 2</a>'s 20th anniversary this November, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/halo">Halo</a> Studios is releasing a recreation of that lost E3 demo from 2003, via a <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/workshopsubmitinfo/">Steam Workshop</a> mod for the Master Chief Collection.</p>
<p>"The buzz and hype going into that event was off the charts and the stakes were higher than ever," reflected Halo's community director Brian Jarrard, in an anniversary blog post.</p>
<p>"I have fond memories of so much playtesting and practising, internal challenges to see who could take out every single enemy in a flawless playthrough."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Halo: The Master Chief Collection - Eurogamer Let's Play LIVE" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6XrAZVSnSbs?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Halo: The Master Chief Collection - Eurogamer Let's Play LIVE</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6XrAZVSnSbs?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6XrAZVSnSbs?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Halo: The Master Chief Collection - Eurogamer Let's Play. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6XrAZVSnSbs" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Jarred spoke about the "electric" response to Halo 2's E3 demo. "None of us ever would have expected that 20+ years later, a group of passionate community modders would bring this demo to life as a full-fledged mission," he continued.</p><p>As for why it has taken so long for the demo to be playable to the wider Halo community, this was due to 'snags with technology'. Thankfully, the original files and assets have now been recovered, although work still needed to be done to make the demo playable today. This was because the 2003 demo was built in a version of the Halo engine that doesn't actually exist any more, and assets weren't compatible with other existing versions of Halo 2.</p>
<p>"This put us in a bit of a quandary," Halo senior franchise writer Kenneth Peters explained. "Even the original executable is difficult to work with, as you need an Xbox developer kit to get it to boot, which is in increasingly short supply even within the studio. But now, in 2024, we have the Digsite-developed tools to analyse and automate up-porting old assets, and the unearthed knowledge to know why Bungie built things the way they did in the demo."</p>
<p>The free Halo 2 E3 demo mod will be released on 9th November, via Steam Workshop, and include gameplay that didn't make it into the final release.</p>
<p>Additionally, <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/halo-infinite">Halo Infinite</a> players will be able to revisit recreations of Halo 2 multiplayer maps and gameplay in Halo Infinite's Delta Arena Playlist from today, 5th November. Further details can be found via <a href="https://news.xbox.com/en-us/2024/11/04/20-years-of-halo-2-new-maps-e3-demo/">Microsoft</a>.</p>
<p>For more, last month a former member of Texas-based support studio Certain Affinity confirmed reports the team was working on a battle royale mode for Halo Infinite, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/former-halo-infinite-dev-confirms-cancelled-battle-royale-mode-says-it-could-have-been-a-game-changer">calling the cancelled project a potential "game changer"</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open Thread: Election Day]]></title>
            <link>https://aftermath.site/open-thread-election-day</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/open-thread-election-day.1027875/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://aftermath.site/open-thread-election-day<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>If you're in America, today's the day: yet another hugely consequential, incredibly terrifying election. Let's get through it together.</p><p>What's going to happen today? Who knows. Will we know who won tonight? Almost certainly not. Is that going to stop me from obsessively inhaling every possible snippet of information and guesses and talking heads for the next god knows how many days? Nope! I am going to have very bad boundaries and experience every possible emotion and generally drive myself bonkers.</p><p>I hope you are making far more healthy choices. I also hope that you are voting, especially in regards to your local elections. If you're in New York City, we have six ballot propositions, five of which <a href="https://www.nyclu.org/commentary/why-new-yorkers-should-vote-no-on-proposals-2-through-6" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sound good on paper</a> but are actually power grabs by <a href="https://aftermath.site/eric-adams-phone-indictment" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Eric Adams</a>, a man who does not need any more power. Research your local politicians and any local proposals--that stuff is important!</p><p>Let us know how you're spending the day, what your plans are, and any tips for keeping yourself together--or, failing that, tips for falling apart in a cathartic way.   </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Legend of Heroes: Trails Through Daybreak II Preview – The Return of Arkride Solutions Office]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-legend-of-heroes-trails-through-daybreak-ii-preview-the-return-of-arkride-solutions-office/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-legend-of-heroes-trails-through-daybreak-ii-preview-%E2%80%93-the-return-of-arkride-solutions-office.1027863/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-legend-of-heroes-trails-through-daybreak-ii-preview-the-return-of-arkride-solutions-office/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Legend of Heroes series has quickly become a household name in JRPG since the release of the Trails in the Sky games, which offered not only extremely engaging stories but a level of worldbuilding that is hardly found in Japanese role-playing games. Despite some tweaks and changes to the formula originally introduced in the game starring Estelle and Joshua, the Trails series formula has seen its first major shakeup with Trails Through Daybreak, especially in regard to combat, introducing a field combat option that expanded the experience considerably and truly set the game apart from all its predecessors. Building upon the new features introduced in its predecessor, The Legend of Heroes: Trails Through Daybreak II may not seem to be as innovative, but this isn't going to make it a worse game. If anything, the refinement of features and mechanics, such as field combat, will possibly make the experience even more engaging.</p>
<p>During a press event hosted last week by NISA, I was able to check out the Western version of the latest entry in the Trails series ahead of its launch this coming February. Set three months after the events of Trails Through Daybreak, Van Arkride is informed by his old friend Elaine Auclair about the mysterious Crimson Grendel terrorizing Edith, who seems to be related to him in some way. At the same time, Swin and Nadia are in the capital of Calvard to find a certain someone, an apparently unrelated issue that will eventually link up with the other during the course of the game.</p>
<p>Bringing back the full team from the Arkride Solutions Office, Trails Through Daybreak II also sees the introduction of new characters and the return of others from previous entries in the series, including some fan favorites that haven't appeared in the series for a while. To give all of these characters their time to shine, the game takes a page from the Trails through Reverie's book, offering different viewpoint characters between chapters, which will also allow for an interesting combination of characters. Storytelling is further evolved by the introduction of a time factor which will see players travel back in time to explore different outcomes of different events. This, however, is only a storytelling twist and has no real impact on gameplay, so the narrative and gameplay flow of Trails Through Daybreak II won't be all that different from what we have seen in the past entries in the series.</p>
<figure>
<div>

<div>
		
		
		<p><span>2 of 9</span>
	</p></div></div>
</figure>


<p>Combat, on the other hand, has been enhanced significantly in Trails Through Daybreak II. In the previous game, field combat was a little on the simple side, but in the new entry in the series, characters are able to cast magic, do a Cross Charge attack with the proper timing and more. Generally, field combat feels snappier, more varied, and definitely more fun, further bridging the gap with Falcom's other mainstay series, the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/ys-x-nordics-one-more-memorable-adventure/">Ys series</a>. Command battle plays mostly the same as in the previous game, with player and enemy taking turns unleashing a variety of special attacks, but there have been improvements here as well, with an improved interface and better customization options with way more Drivers with different Arts layouts and New Holo Cores. Additionally, it will be possible to unleash flashy Dual Arts special attacks involving multiple characters that are as powerful as they look spectacular.</p>
<p>With the return of the Gourmet and LGC Alignment systems from the previous game thrown into the mix, Trails Through Daybreak II promises to feel like a familiar experience right from the beginning for those who completed the previous game. With returning characters from the Trails series as a whole, the upcoming game will also be better connected to the narrative at large, so it is definitely setting out to be a game that no fan of the Trials series who has played through most of them, if not all, should skip. Being the second entry of a new chapter in the bigger story, however, Trails Through Daybreak II won't be a good way to start exploring the Falcom franchise, as, while the game attempts to bring players up to speed regarding past events with an in-game glossary and a recap, it can never make up for the story and characters introduced in the past 11 games.</p>
<p><iframe title="Trails through Daybreak II - Story Overview Trailer (Nintendo Switch, PS4, PS5, PC)" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fTYMzZdyGno?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>The Legend of Heroes: Trails Through Daybreak II launches on February 14th on PC via Steam, Epic Games Store, GOG, PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, and Nintendo Switch.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metal Slug Tactics Review - Turn-based Tedium]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/metal-slug-tactics-review-turn-based-tedium</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/metal-slug-tactics-review-turn-based-tedium.1027860/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/metal-slug-tactics-review-turn-based-tedium<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Like some sort of elusive cryptid, we've been given bits and pieces of gameplay and screenshots of <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em> throughout the years. With fans chomping at the bit to see more, it was a surprise to see this highly-anticipated <a href="https://techraptor.net/genre/turn-based-tactics">turn-based tactics</a> game launching in 2024. Finally, <em>Metal Slug </em>and strategy fans alike can get their hands on this title.</p>

<p>I went into <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em> very excited -- after all, its superb pixel art style and retro-inspired soundtrack really speaks to the care <a href="https://techraptor.net/companies/leikir-studio">Leikir Studio</a> put into crafting this game. And indeed, while it looks and sounds great, I'm a bit more lukewarm on the gameplay. There's a solid tactics game mechanics-wise, but well... the rest of it feels like a slog.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-gameplay.jpg?itok=xlemNZ1P 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-gameplay.jpg?itok=mMmvlSf0 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This minigun guy has got to go.</figcaption></figure><h2>Going the Distance in <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em></h2>

<p>As a veteran of turn-based tactics titles, I tend to play on the defensive with my units. Let enemies come to me, and I'll pick them off as they clash against my hardy frontline and have the backline of ranged units pick them off. I'll tell you right now, slow and steady is <em>not</em> going to fly in <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em>, and the gameplay is designed to rewire the way you think of this genre.</p>

<p>In this regard, <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em> stands out among other turn-based tactics titles, as it incentivizes speed. Leikir Studio makes a valiant effort in attempting to replicate the running and gunning that's so iconic to the series.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-city.jpg?itok=XjptimU5 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-city.jpg?itok=TjPH-JPZ 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Settin' up a sync with my boy Tarma.</figcaption></figure><p>Here's the rundown: players gain dodge the more they move, and gain even more damage mitigation if they position units behind cover. Ordering units to stay still will very likely end with their doom, since they're out in the open with no protection whatsoever. I'm constantly on the move in <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em>, since your units only have 10 HP.</p>

<p>This is a fresh concept and introduces challenges in a natural way. Constantly being on the move means you'll come across more enemies within range, so positioning is vital. So yes, maximizing your dodge and cover is essential, but so is the proximity of your own units to each other.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metal-slug-tactucs-vehicle.jpg?itok=PY9SxUdv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metal-slug-tactucs-vehicle.jpg?itok=cLGUwytM 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>You can drive a Metal Slug!</figcaption></figure><p>There are sync attacks that allow your units to attack units in unison, allowing you to deal more damage. This is something that <em>needs</em> to be used throughout or, even on the lowest difficulty, you'll run into trouble. So when we combine the damage mitigation mechanics (dodge and cover) with sync attacks, combat flows pretty well and is very fast-paced.</p>

<p>The more you move, the more adrenaline you get, as well. That's your primary resource to activate abilities unique to your character. Fio, for example, excels at buffing allies with shields, or she can even move enemy or friendly units around the battlefield to gain an advantage. Ally units definitely have their niche, so there's a range of support, DPS, and tank-like archetypes.</p>

<p>Units also stand out with a set of different loadouts, featuring different primary and secondary weapons, as well as abilities. So as you progress and unlock more and more with currency gained from missions, you can tune your team to a decent degree.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-ui.jpg?itok=kPmz93m2 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-ui.jpg?itok=hRJIqpDh 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>This UI realllly isn't helping.</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Metal Slug Tactics</em> Gets Lost in the Sauce</h2>

<p>I tried my best to explain the mechanics in a concise way, but <em>Metal Slug Tactics </em>is actually quite overwhelming, even for someone like me who is used to the genre. The intro frontloads all the mechanics in a short, five-minute or so tutorial. It's far too much information in such a short time, so the first few hours can feel like a struggle.</p>

<p>There are dozens of too-similar terms like "special action", "bonus action", "bonus move" and... <em>so</em> much more. The developers added a way to read more about highlighted terms, but these tutorials branch out into even more tutorials. It's truly a case of information overload.</p>

<p>It doesn't help that the user interface is exceedingly messy and disorganized. <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em> doesn't really help you learn to navigate through various menus to upgrade and unlock new gear, and it's displayed in a generally unpleasant and disjointed way -- this is both during and outside of combat.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-stages.jpg?itok=41bEtT8p 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-stages.jpg?itok=_AdxHwvv 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Conquer up to three different zones, then make it to the final boss in the final area.</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Metal Slug Tactics</em>: Part Strategy, Part Roguelite</h2>

<p>Let's address the elephant in the room: <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em> is a roguelite. At least, it incorporates roguelite elements into its gameplay, but it feels needlessly tacked on. This leads to a repetitive, RNG-fueled gameplay loop. I can't help but think that a linear campaign would have been a <em>much</em> better choice.</p>

<p>Here's how the roguelite elements come into play: <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em>' overworld is split into four separate regions, and you must complete at minimum one of three to move onto the final area. Within these regions are missions that grant a random pair of awards by completing a random set of objectives, up until the boss level spawns.</p>

<p>Levels are hand-crafted and not generated, so there's some decent level design that'll challenge players. Levels are generally compact in size, but those are usually exclusively for missions that task you with wiping out all enemies or eliminating certain targets. Those are the best missions, by the way.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-boss.jpg?itok=b5ARS1nv 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-boss.jpg?itok=BdIxZmhk 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>One of four bosses, and that's all you're getting.</figcaption></figure><p>If there's a mission that asks you to escort Rumi, run away and don't look back. Escort missions suck, and that's no different in <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em>. Rumi's AI is not great and enemies will kill her in no time, meaning you fail your entire run instantly.</p>

<p>There isn't a great deal of variety in objectives and maps are used over and over again, so you'll come across the same scenarios each and every run you make in <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em>. This creates a very repetitive gameplay loop that grows stale quite fast.</p>

<p>Adding even more repetition are bosses. There are only four bosses in <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em>, and no matter what difficulty you play on, they're basically the same fight. I'd get this impending feeling of dread knowing I would have to fight them at the end of the zone since these are easily the least enjoyable enemies to fight.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-stages-1.jpg?itok=01bcsI64 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-stages-1.jpg?itok=NP2p91iX 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>Choose your path wisely, as your rewards depend on it.</figcaption></figure><p>Throughout your run, you're able to gain mods to your weapons and level up your characters for new abilities, which makes things only a tad more engaging. There is an overabundance of passive abilities that all seem to be the same exact thing, perhaps because of how confusing the jargon is. As a result, abilities feel the same, and mods only slightly change the behavior of your weapons.</p>

<p>You're given a currency that can be used after each run to unlock more character abilities, weapon loadouts, and more, and that's <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em>' way of adding metaprogression. There's nothing super exciting about unlocking these since, again, most abilities and even weapons feel similar to one another. Unlocking new characters is fun, sure, but there is a limited roster.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-story.jpg?itok=Mcvec5_z 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/metal-slug-tactics-story.jpg?itok=tKm6DxM0 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption>There <em>is</em> a story in <em>Metal Slug Tactics, </em>but it is very much an afterthought.</figcaption></figure><h2><em>Metal Slug Tactics</em> Review | Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>I also came across a surprising number of bugs during my time with <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em>. The most annoying was one that made me unable to use buttons on my controller for certain actions. Calling in a Metal Slug you can hop in and drive around is cool and all, but it sucks when doing so means I can't use my Xbox controller to fire or select abilities for the rest of the battle.</p>

<p>At one point during dialogue, I had to completely exit my game because, for whatever reason, it wouldn't let me progress. A funny glitch that was pretty consistent throughout my entire time playing was that reviving characters brings them back without their arms. It doesn't affect the gameplay, it just looks goofy.</p>

<p>While I'm critical of <em>Metal Slug Tactics</em>, it's still a fun game. Once you understand the obtuse mechanics and make your way into higher difficulties, there's some real strategy and planning required to succeed. Unfortunately, it doesn't change things up enough to stay consistently enjoyable, and the roguelite elements and the same four bosses are the chief offenders of this.</p>

<hr><p><em><strong>Metal Slug Tactics</strong> was reviewed on PC with a copy provided by the developer over the course of 16 hours of gameplay - all screenshots were taken during the process of review.</em></p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Austin cut his teeth writing various&nbsp; fan-fiction stories on the RuneScape forums when he was in elementary school. Later on, he developed a deep love for… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/austin-suther">More about Austin</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom Sold 2.5m Copies in Four Days]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-sales-nintendo-financials</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-sold-2-5m-copies-in-four-days.1027857/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-sales-nintendo-financials<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nintendo has released its financial figures for the second quarter of the fiscal year, and they give us some interesting insights into how the company's games and hardware are doing as Switch 2 speculation ramps up.</p>

<p>According to Nintendo's financial report, net sales are down 34.3% this quarter compared to the same period last year, while operating profit is down a whopping 56.6%. In general, Nintendo's numbers aren't looking too great this quarter, but there's arguably a good reason for that.</p>

<p>Last year, Nintendo was riding high on the release of a new tentpole&nbsp;<em>Zelda&nbsp;</em>game in&nbsp;<em>Tears of the Kingdom</em>, which was a <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-has-shipped-13246-million-units-tears-of-kingdom-sold-almost-20-million">phenomenal sales success</a> for the company. We're also getting closer to <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/nintendo-switch-2-announcement-confirmation">news of the Switch 2</a>, and so many gamers are probably being cautious with regards to buying new hardware.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-nintendo-financials-combat.jpg?itok=8IwiAy2g 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/the-legend-of-zelda-echoes-of-wisdom-nintendo-financials-combat.jpg?itok=dU4Sp25p 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>The Legend of Zelda: Echoes of Wisdom</em>&nbsp;has done pretty well for Nintendo.</figcaption></figure><p>It could be argued that a new&nbsp;<em>Zelda&nbsp;</em>game was also released within the operating period for this report, which ends on September 30th, but&nbsp;<em>Echoes of Wisdom&nbsp;</em>isn't on the same budget and marketing scale as&nbsp;<em>Tears of the Kingdom&nbsp;</em>was.</p>

<p>Even still,&nbsp;<em>Echoes of Wisdom&nbsp;</em>did pretty well for Nintendo, it seems. The financial report confirms that the game had sold 2.58 million units by the end of the operating period, which means it achieved that milestone within just four days.</p>

<p>Elsewhere,&nbsp;<em>Mario Kart 8 Deluxe&nbsp;</em>sold 2.31 million units within the operating period, the&nbsp;<em>Paper Mario: The Thousand-Year Door&nbsp;</em>remake sold 1.94 million, and the&nbsp;<em>Luigi's Mansion 2&nbsp;</em>remaster sold 1.57 million.</p>

<p>Hardware sales dropped 31% year-on-year, although sales of the base Switch and its Lite model were actually slightly up. In general, it's probably not a surprise that Nintendo's numbers are down given its position in the market right now, although things are perhaps slightly more gloomy than the company expected.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/paper-mario-the-thousand-year-door-nintendo-financials.jpg?itok=V5CXkunB 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/paper-mario-the-thousand-year-door-nintendo-financials.jpg?itok=wd_Xky3K 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Paper Mario: The Thousand Year Door&nbsp;</em>hasn't sold too badly for Nintendo either.</figcaption></figure><p>Technically speaking, from a hardware perspective, sales increased from Q1 to Q2, but overall, on a six-monthly basis, hardware was down. Nintendo attributes this quarterly increase to a&nbsp;<em>Zelda</em>-themed Switch Lite bundle, as well as "releases of hardware bundled with software titles".</p>

<p>You can check out Nintendo's <a href="https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2024/241105_5e.pdf" rel="noopener" target="_blank">full financial report here</a> if you want to. It's got plenty more numbers and stats if you like to get stuck into the mathematical side of things.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>