<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 19:44:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Good News Chooms, Cyberpunk Nexus is Coming To Demiplane]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/good-news-chooms-cyberpunk-nexus-is-coming-to-demiplane</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/good-news-chooms-cyberpunk-nexus-is-coming-to-demiplane.947304/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/good-news-chooms-cyberpunk-nexus-is-coming-to-demiplane<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Official <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/reviews/cyberpunk-red-review" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Cyberpunk Red</em></a> support is coming to the VTT Demiplane. R Talsorian Games has announced Cyberpunk Nexus for the platform, providing players with convenient compendiums and character options all to help them start their journey in Night City on the right foot.</p>
<h2>The Cyberpunk Nexus Announcement</h2>
<p>The Cyberpunk Nexus announcement was made by a <a href="https://x.com/DemiplaneRPG/status/1821229253188350161?t=EbPKc85AglPujTYgMDt9tw&amp;s=19">social media post</a> on X (formerly Twitter) by the official R Talsorian Games account. The post simply states that Cyberpunk Red will have a new home on the platform this Fall. There is no mention of price or what content will be supported.</p>
<picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/cyberpunk-red-martial-artist-artwork.jpg?itok=oXYhO5Q- 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/cyberpunk-red-martial-artist-artwork.jpg?itok=N8Of2kAF 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><p>This announcement is important given Demiplane's prominence in the tabletop space. The platform is known for putting all material for supported TTRPGs in one convenient spot. There's no need to keep multiple supplements tabbed; it's all in one space. Whether it's <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/paizo-and-demiplane-announce-pathfinder-nexus" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Pathfinder</em></a>, <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/world-of-darkness-nexus-embraces-partnership-with-demiplane" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>World of Darkness</em></a>, or <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/demiplane-partners-with-darrington-press-to-launch-candela-obscura-nexus" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Candela Obscura</em></a>, you were covered.</p>
<p><em>Cyberpunk Red</em> is the latest edition of the dark future sci-fi TTRPG created by Mike Pondsmith. This TTRPG full of cyborg ninjas, brain-melting hackers corporate espionage, and lethal car chases has received plenty of support since launch. These include the <em>Interface RED</em> volumes, the <em>Tales From The Red</em> anthology book, and a mission kit based on the Netflix anime <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/cyberpunk-edgerunners-mission-kit-announced" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>Cyberpunk Edgerunners</em></a>.</p>
<p>The responses to the Cyberpunk Nexus announcement did include one pertinent question. If someone already owns <em>Cyberpunk Red</em> material on Roll20. will they need to pay again for that content on Demiplane? This is an honest question since Roll20 officially <a href="https://techraptor.net/tabletop/news/roll20-demiplane-acquisition-officially-announced" rel="noopener" target="_blank">acquired Demiplane</a> back in June.</p>
<p>The official Demiplane account's response was brief and diplomatic. They are still in talks with R Talsorian Games regarding how purchases will be handled across platforms. Given it's an issue of whether or not dedicated players will need to double dip, it is something both companies are taking seriously.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>

<p>Ever since he was small, Tyler Chancey has had a deep, abiding love for video games and a tendency to think and overanalyze everything he enjoyed. This… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/tyler-chancey">More about Tyler</a></p>
</div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite will bring battle pass rewards back around]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/7/24215375/fortnite-battle-pass-rewards-back-around-item-shop</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-will-bring-battle-pass-rewards-back-around.947301/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/7/24215375/fortnite-battle-pass-rewards-back-around-item-shop<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Epic Games is making a major change to <em>Fortnite</em>’s<em> </em>battle passes that should remove some angst if you can’t buy or complete a pass before the end of a season.</p><p><em>Fortnite</em>’s battle passes offer a bunch of exclusive in-game rewards that you can only obtain during an individual season, but that means you might miss out on rewards entirely if you can’t level up enough or don’t buy the pass before it expires. To help alleviate that pressure, Epic <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/change-to-item-exclusivity-in-future-fortnite-battle-passes">announced on Wednesday</a> that items from future battle passes might be available for purchase in <em>Fortnite</em>’s item shop at least 18 months after the pass expires.</p><p>Epic’s battle pass policy adjustment is intended in part to let people buy outfits featuring licensed crossovers, even if they miss a season’s battle pass, the company writes in its blog post. (Some of the game’s best skins, like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/27/21402707/fortnite-chapter-2-season-4-marvel-nexus-war-thor-iron-man">Iron Man</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/2/22028767/the-mandalorian-fortnite-perfect-character-season-5">the Mandalorian</a>, have only been available to players who bought previous battle passes featuring those characters.)</p><p>Every type of item in a battle pass is eligible to show up in the shop, Epic says, including “Outfits, Back Blings, Pickaxes, Emotes, Instruments, Decals, Wraps, Loading Screens, Banner Icons, and more.” However, items from battle passes won’t be guaranteed to show up in the item shop after that 18-month window, so if you see something you want, you should probably get it while the pass is still available.</p><p>This change will kick in with the game’s next season, Epic spokesperson Stephanie Thoensen tells <em>The Verge</em>. The <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/24/24163374/fortnite-chapter-5-season-3-wrecked-battle-pass-fallout-magneto">current season</a> ends on August 16th. The new season is <a href="https://x.com/HYPEX/status/1781230707559256172">rumored to be Marvel-themed</a> and could feature Doctor Doom, which <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/30/24209499/marvel-robert-downey-jr-doomsday-russo-bros-salaries">would make some sense</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What’s on your desk, Jess Weatherbed?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/24212190/work-home-desk-cthulhu-msi-logitech</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/what%E2%80%99s-on-your-desk-jess-weatherbed.947298/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/24212190/work-home-desk-cthulhu-msi-logitech<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><p>Jess Weatherbed, news writer for <em>The Verge</em>, started her professional career in a way she describes as “a bit strange for a journalist” — in prosthetics and wig making. However, she was no stranger to tech. For around 16 years, she’s been using drawing tablets to support her design hobbies, everything from digital illustration and animation to 3D sculpting. “I initially learned to build computers to support my nerdier gaming hobbies,” she says, “and my love of tech and gadgets has grown from there.”</p><p>We asked Jess to talk about her workspace.</p><p><strong>That’s quite a setup. Where in your home is it?</strong></p><p>This is technically our second bedroom or “guest room” — though it mostly serves as my permanent home office and gaming den. My partner and I purchased our first apartment a couple of years ago now. It’s super dinky, so there’s not much room for privacy! We wanted to keep our work areas completely separate to avoid distracting each other, so this is the best use of the space we have until we can move somewhere bigger. I’m also fully remote, so having everything set up in here gives me an extra space to frequent besides the bedroom or lounge.</p><div><p><figcaption><em>Green gives the home office a restful but nicely gothic atmosphere.</em></figcaption></p></div><p><strong>That’s a lot of green.</strong></p><p>Would you believe me if I said my favorite color is actually orange? I really love green, though, and I’ve wanted a gloomy, gothic space since I was in my teens. I knew I would be spending a lot of time in here, and after years of renting, I just decided to go all in.&nbsp;</p><p>I had two main motivations. First, I wanted to see if I could put together a witch-themed setup that contrasts with the usual pastel palettes I see released for hardware that targets female gamers (which is lovely but isn’t at all my vibe).</p><p>The second was that I just find green to be a very calming color. I once <a href="https://hms.harvard.edu/news/green-light-migraine-relief">read a study that green light can help reduce migraines</a>, and while I wasn’t aware of that at the time of decorating, it’s certainly correlated with my own experience as a chronic sufferer. I have a dimly lit space to hide in when needed, and with all the color-addressable lighting available these days — the ceiling lights being <a href="https://twinkly.com/en-gb/products/strings-multicolor?srsltid=AfmBOoq4hinjryybQU-smY33FrTQG0VYPbL0-GbKV8HRjqAWFr3vh6cj&amp;variant=42970659094750">Twinkly’s Strings</a> — I can switch it up if I want a brighter environment.</p><div><p>Twinkly has the best selection of holiday string lights in sizes ranging from 26 to 158 feet and with options that include just color, color and white, or just white. The lights are bright and colorful, and the effects you can find and create in the Twinkly app are very impressive. But the app is fiddly, and these Wi-Fi lights suffer from connectivity issues.</p></div><p>The entire apartment is, shall we say, “eclectically” decorated, so there’s a lot going on. It certainly isn’t for everyone, but I’m super happy with it. (And my partner has yet to veto any of my decorative choices, so it’s a win-win.)&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Tell us about your desk.&nbsp;</strong></p><p>This is the <a href="https://friskadesk.com/products/stockholm-height-adjustable-corner-desk">Friska Stockholm corner desk</a>, an electric sit-stand option I hoped would encourage me to stand more frequently during the day. Alas, I am a creature of bad habits. It does, however, give me plenty of space to create a sort of split workspace — I sit on the right when using my main two displays for work, while the left-hand “monitor” is actually a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/HUION-Graphics-Drawing-Full-Laminated-Anti-Glare/dp/B099555ZBZ?tag=theverge02-20">Huion Kamvas 24 Pro 4K display drawing tablet</a>. If I want to focus on creative stuff, I can just swivel around.</p><p>If I can get around to sorting out the jungle of cables underneath, I’ll start looking for a compact electric treadmill that I can use to get some steps in to make full use of the desk’s sit / stand capabilities.</p><div><p>4K UHD (3840 x 2160) resolution tablet with a 23.8-inch screen.</p></div><p><strong>And your chair?</strong></p><p>The chair is a <a href="https://razer.a9yw.net/c/482924/642901/10229?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.razer.com%2Fgaming-chairs%2Frazer-enki-pro">Razer Enki Pro</a>, which was an old review sample I retained a couple of years ago before joining <em>The Verge</em>. It’s taken a beating since then, having moved apartments and been dragged to various <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LAN_party">LAN events</a>, but it’s holding up well aside from a few scratches. You can see I’ve started concealing them using stickers. The upholstery is still in good condition, though, and I can see this lasting me several years. I certainly wouldn’t advocate spending this much on a gaming-style chair unless you had specific comfort requirements, but I’m happy with it overall. Plus, it’s black and green!</p><div><p><figcaption><em>The green lighting is echoed by the mechanical keyboard.</em></figcaption></p></div><p><strong>Here’s the big one: tell us about the various tech devices you’re using.&nbsp;</strong></p><p>My main monitors are an <a href="https://us.msi.com/Monitor/Optix-G271/Specification">MSI Optix G271</a> and a hand-me-down <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/https://store.acer.com/en-ie/predator-xb1-gaming-monitor-xb271hk">Acer Predator XB271HK</a> 4K — both 27 inches. The PC itself is running an Intel i9-11900K, an MSI RTX 3080 GPU, and 64GB of DDR4 RAM. I’ll upgrade to DDR5 at some point, but for now, this is more than enough to handle both my gaming and creative hobbies.</p><p>The keyboard is a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Huntsman-Optical-Gaming-Keyboard/dp/B09C12L49Z?tag=theverge02-20">Razer Huntsman V2</a>, which is… fine. I really like how plush the wrist rest is, and the built-in audio controllers at the top right feel nice and tactile. The mechanical keys are a tad clunky, though, so I’ll be looking to go the DIY kit route when this eventually bites the dust. The mouse is a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Razer-Basilisk-Customizable-Ergonomic-Gaming/dp/B09C13PZX7?tag=theverge02-20">Razer Basilisk V3</a>, which is one of the more ergonomic gaming mice I’ve used. I’d opt for a vertical mouse, but I really hate switching my gear around between work and gaming-optimized peripherals, and this hasn’t given me any reason to make the switch.&nbsp;</p><div><p>This wired gaming mouse from Razer is a favorite among gamers. It features 11 programable buttons,  optical mouse switches, and even an ergonomic thumb rest. You can cycle the scroll wheel between three different modes and, of course, customize the RGB to your heart’s content.</p></div><p>I’m still recovering from my “RGB in all of the things” phase, so if I’m being honest, I mostly just appreciate that I can synchronize the lighting effects across my Razer Synapse-supported gear (as janky as it is) without messing with third-party apps. Are they the best? Far from it, but they work for me and my black / green theming!</p><p>I frequently play<em> D&amp;D</em> online, so a lot of the other equipment supports both that and attending virtual meetings. My webcam is a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Calling-Noise-Canceling-Correction-Microsoft/dp/B01N5UOYC4?tag=theverge02-20">Logitech Brio</a>, which has been super reliable and still holds up against more specialized “streaming” webcams like Elgato’s facecam series. There’s a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Logitech-Streaming-TrueSoft-adjustable-brightness/dp/B097QZGRCQ/ref=sr_1_1?tag=theverge02-20">Logitech Litra Glow</a> light atop my monitors and an <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elgato-Key-Light-Professional-app-adjustable/dp/B07L755X9G?tag=theverge02-20">Elgato Key Light</a> to keep me illuminated in the dark environment. I use an old <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Rode-Anniversary-Cardioid-Condenser-Microphone/dp/B002QAUOKS?th=1&amp;tag=theverge02-20">Rode NT1-A XLR</a> microphone for my audio input, which my partner has had knocking around for years, and an <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.elgato.com%2Fus%2Fen%2Fp%2Fstream-deck-mk2-black">Elgato Stream Deck</a> that houses custom profiles for my creative applications and <em>D&amp;D</em> games.</p><p>More generally, I have a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Belkin-3-Wireless-Charger-Compatible/dp/B086KNLM5M?th=1&amp;tag=theverge02-20">3-in-1 Belkin charger</a> on the left to keep my phone and Apple Watch topped up during the day and an <a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-New-release-Smart-speaker-Charcoal/dp/B09B8V1LZ3?tag=theverge02-20">Amazon Echo Dot</a> smart speaker. We have several around the flat to control various smart home settings, but having one in my office also keeps me alerted to any deliveries. I even use it as a speaker output for my PC when I can’t be bothered to wear headphones.</p><p><strong>You have several interesting figures on your shelves.</strong></p><p>The majority were actually gifted! I’d never call myself a hoarder, but I used to have a real issue with accumulating unnecessary stuff that would just pile up around me. I had a cull of figurines and cuddly toys a few years ago, so I’ve been trying to keep on top of it since. The <a href="https://razer.a9yw.net/c/482924/642901/10229?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.razer.com%2Fsneki-snek%2Fanimated-series">“Sneki” Razer</a> mascot and <a href="https://lovecraft.fandom.com/wiki/Cthulhu">Cthulhu</a> squishmallow really suit the green theme of the room, and I commissioned the crocheted <a href="https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Gengar_(Pok%C3%A9mon)">Gengar</a> plushie from a friend because it’s been my favorite pokémon since Gen 1.</p><div><div><p><figcaption><em>A crocheted Gengar grins from a shelf.</em></figcaption></p></div><div><p><figcaption><em>The crow lamp in the corner is named “Dick.”</em></figcaption></p></div></div><p>The crow lamp is affectionately called “Dick,” after both DC’s Nightwing and a real crow I rescued last year who was <em>very</em> unhappy about being rehabilitated for an injured wing. I think my fingers are still recovering from the pecking he gave me.</p><p><strong>That’s a really snazzy shelf to the left of your window — it’s almost a work of art in itself.</strong></p><p>Thank you! That was actually <a href="https://go.skimresources.com/?id=1025X1701640&amp;xs=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dormify.com%2Fproducts%2Fmoon-3-tier-wall-shelf%3Fvariant%3D41724506701995">a very recent purchase</a> from TK Maxx (the UK version of T.J. Maxx). I wanted something to fill that space, and it was a perfect fit. It also gives me more space to display some smaller knickknacks, like the to-scale 3D-printed animal skulls (that I still need to paint gold) and the beautiful beaded fox figurine my parents gifted me for Christmas. There are a lot of moons and stars throughout the space, too, so to quote the Big Lebowski himself, I think it really ties the room together.</p><p><strong>I also admire the framed drawing to the left of your monitor (the one with the animal skull) and its motto.&nbsp;</strong></p><p>It’s a print by artist <a href="https://www.instagram.com/scarygorgon/">Sarah Gordon</a> (aka ScaryGorgon) that I purchased at London’s MCM Comic Con last year. I really vibe with macabre art as a weird kid who was often told my own illustrations were “a bit morbid,” so I love supporting other artists where I can. The gilded crow prints from <a href="https://katiewhittleillustration.com/">Katie Whittle</a> were purchased at the same event, and I’d say around 80 percent of the artwork around the apartment generally has been sourced from small online creators. Check out the artist alleys at your own local events where you can; there’s treasure to be found!</p><div><p><figcaption><em>The framed drawing of a talking skull is by artist Sarah Gordon.</em></figcaption></p></div><p><strong>Is there anything else in your workspace / room that I didn’t call out and should have?</strong></p><p>I’m still filling the bookcases behind my desks, but we have a healthy collection of tabletop roleplay and 5e <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> sourcebooks right now. The book collection generally is a bit all over the place and not well organized. I try to keep all my art references and illustration magazines together, but it’s kind of blending with my small collection of comics and graphic novels.</p><p>The blanket situation under the desks is also usually where our dog Dylan, an elderly cocker spaniel, spends his day hanging out with me, but it’s too hot for him there at the moment!</p><div><p><figcaption><em>Dylan keeps watch over the tech, the books, and Jess.</em></figcaption></p></div><p><em>Photos by Jess Weatherbed / </em>The Verge</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta shuts down Quest developer Ready at Dawn]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/meta-shuts-down-quest-developer-ready-at-dawn</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/meta-shuts-down-quest-developer-ready-at-dawn.947295/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/meta-shuts-down-quest-developer-ready-at-dawn<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via Ready at Dawn/Meta.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">According to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.androidcentral.com/gaming/virtual-reality/ready-at-dawn-studios-closing">Android Central</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, developer Ready at Dawn is no more.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The elimination of the studio was reportedly made to keep the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/report-employee-bingo-driving-heavy-losses-at-meta-s-reality-labs">equally</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> struggling </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/water-is-wet-the-pope-is-catholic-and-reality-labs-continues-to-lose-billions">Reality Labs</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> within new budget restraints. A Meta representative also told the outlet these cuts were not heralding a larger culling for its first-party studios.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Ready at Dawn was founded in 2003 by Naughty Dog and Blizzard Entertainment alums Ru Weerasuriya, Andrea Pessino, and Didier Malenfant. Somewhat fittingly, the studio's debut title was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Daxter, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">a PlayStation Portable spinoff for Naughty Dog's platformer series.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the first half of its lifetime, the studio created PSP spinoffs (and collected bundles) for Sony Santa Monica's God of War franchise, and the Nintendo Wii port for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Okami. </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">In 2015, it launched its own original project: PlayStation 4's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The Order: 1886.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">After the console multiplayer brawler </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ready-at-dawn-shuts-down-i-deformers-i-servers">Deformers</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">in 2017, Ready at Dawn pivoted to VR. Within that same year, it simultaneously released the adventure games </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Echo Arena </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Lone Echo </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">for the Meta Quest and Oculus Rift.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Oculus Studios </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/-i-lone-echo-i-developer-ready-at-dawn-acquired-by-facebook">acquired</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> the studio in 2020, where it made </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Echo Combat </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Lone Echo II</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. Last year, it and fellow developer Downpour Interactive </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/ready-at-dawn-and-downpour-interactive-impacted-by-meta-layoffs">cut staff</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> as part of a larger Meta restructuring.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Around this time last year, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/meta-and-ready-at-dawn-are-shutting-down-echo-vr">Echo VR</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">was shut down so Ready at Dawn could focus on "other projects" which will now never come to fruition.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">This marks the second studio to close down today, preceded by Finnish studio </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/mobile-dev-shipyard-games-shuts-down">Shipyard Games</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Lord of the Rings: Return to Moria Releases on Steam and Xbox]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/the-lord-of-the-rings-return-to-moria-gets-official-release-date/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-lord-of-the-rings-return-to-moria-releases-on-steam-and-xbox.947292/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/the-lord-of-the-rings-return-to-moria-gets-official-release-date/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>The Lord of the Rings: Return to Moria has an official release date. The crafting game developed by Free Range Games and published by North Beach Games. This game is set in the Fourth Age of Middle Earth, the beloved fantasy world created by legendary J.R.R. Tolkien. For those who have been eagerly awaiting the release of The Lord of the Rings: Return to Moria, this game will be releasing on August 27 for PC and Xbox Series X|S for a huge discounted price of $19.99.</p>
<p>Due to the release of the game on new platforms, The Lord of the Rings: Return to Moria will also be getting <a href="https://wccftech.com/the-lord-of-the-rings-return-to-moria-qa-dev-talks-post-launch-roadmap-and-having-the-genres-best-combat/">the update</a> "The Golden Update," which includes crossplay across all platforms, as well as a Sandbox Mode. There will also be plenty of more content throughout the new update, as well as updates and quality-of-life improvements that have been implemented since the release of the game on the Epic Games Store.</p>
<p>These updates have been live on PC via the Epic Games Store since October 24, 2023. The updates have been live on PlayStation 5 since December 5, 2023.</p>
<p>The Sandbox Mode has been in beta via the EGS version of the game, and is now fully launched across all platforms for players. It allows players to have the full potential of the procedural generation system, with the game generated through a wide range of random seeds. Every playthrough has the potential to have significant difficulty changes, with layouts varying massively.</p>
<p>As this Sandbox Mode is highly unpredictable, it's recommended that people play this mode once they are familiar with Return to Moria or other survival games that are similar.</p>
<p>With the crossplay elements, players on any platform can now host a game, with players on Steam able to host 8-player sessions, with players from any platform being able to join.</p>
<p>Along with the Sandbox feature and the Crossplay feature, there are also new armors and weapons that have been added to the game. There are 14 new weapons and armor in total including a Wolf Skin Hat, Gondorian Shield, Khazad Halberd and much more. These items are only discoverable through the Sandbox Mode, but they can be transferred to the player's campaign as long as the Dwarf is equipped with the items as they transfer over.</p>
<p>One of the most important functions added in this update is the ability for players in single-player game modes to pause the game. In addition to this, players can also fine-tune their difficulty settings, which includes how aggressive enemies are, combat <a href="https://www.returntomoria.com/news" target="_blank" rel="noopener">and more</a>.</p>

				

						
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quick, Go Play Call of Duty’s WWE Mode Before It Goes Away Tonight]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-mw3-summerslam-slam-deathmatch-mode-1851615853</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/quick-go-play-call-of-duty%E2%80%99s-wwe-mode-before-it-goes-away-tonight.947286/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/call-of-duty-mw3-summerslam-slam-deathmatch-mode-1851615853<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>As with any <em>Call of Duty</em> game, my interest in <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/modern-warfare-3-mw3-2023-multiplayer-maps-1851017710&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/modern-warfare-3-mw3-2023-multiplayer-maps-1851017710"><em>Modern Warfare III</em></a></span> waxes and wanes depending on what modes or gimmicks the FPS is offering at any given moment. Last summer, when <em>Warzone</em> added a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/warzone-super-powers-season-4-reloaded-the-boys-update-1850636608&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/warzone-super-powers-season-4-reloaded-the-boys-update-1850636608">mode themed around the Amazon Prime series <em>The Boys</em></a></span>, I jumped back in for a few weeks to roast some people with my laser eyes. Now, a new WWE game mode, called Slam Deathmatch, along with several wrestling legends available as operators, has once again pulled me back into the <em>MW3</em> fray.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196923" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="355" data-playlist="196923,196922,196918" data-current="196923"><div><p>Kotaku’s Hopes For Spyro The Dragon’s (Reported) Comeback</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196923/196923_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/22494.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Season 5 of <em>Warzone </em>and <em>MW3</em> added new base weapons, a new battle pass that includes WWE superstar Rhea Ripley, two other famous wrestler skins available to purchase (Cody Rhodes and Rey Mysterio), and a temporary new game mode called Slam Deathmatch running as a cross promo with WWE SummerSlam (which aired on August 3). It’s that last bit (and Rhea Ripley) that got me to jump back into the shooter after months away, and boy, am I glad I did. Slam Deathmatch is absolutely bananas, and a great way to get a feel for the current (and ever-shifting) <em>CoD</em> gun meta.<br></p><p>Slam Deathmatch is simple: it’s regular Team Deathmatch on smaller-sized maps, but you down enemies like in <em>Warzone </em>rather than outright killing them, and your grenades are disabled. When you down a player, a WWE logo will appear over their head, and you can run over and long-press your right joystick to do a finishing move on them while a WWE announcer shouts in disbelief. These aren’t the same finishing moves as the traditional <em>CoD </em>ones, but wrestling-themed maneuvers that include bringing a folding chair down on someone’s neck or pulling off Cody Rhodes’ famous Cross Rhodes finisher. </p><p>The first time I pulled one of these moves off, I let out a shocked little laugh—especially because I was using the Farah operator skin, who is portrayed by <em>The Boys</em> actor Claudia Domit. The rest of the match was predictably chaotic, with players flipping and slamming each other all over the map and bullets flying everywhere (you can’t take damage while doing a finisher, but they can be interrupted by enemies), and voice comms full of players laughing and groaning like the crowd at a major wrestling event. The next match, I was able to do a Rhea Ripley finisher while using my Rhea Ripley skin, and yeah, it was as satisfying as you’d imagine.<br></p><p>Slam Deathmatch is a great reminder that <em>Call of Duty</em> can be fun sometimes. Your last chance to play it is today, so get to it. </p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro Is Getting A Thank-You Update For Free In 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/balatro-is-getting-a-thank-you-update-for-free-in-2025/1100-6525614/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-is-getting-a-thank-you-update-for-free-in-2025.947283/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/balatro-is-getting-a-thank-you-update-for-free-in-2025/1100-6525614/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525614">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Balatro developer LocalThunk has revealed that the game's first major gameplay update will come in 2025, and that it will have two more announcements coming later this summer.</p><p>"This update will bring new ideas and strategies to the game and as a token of huge appreciation to the game’s brilliant and passionate community," LocalThunk said on Twitter. "The update will be completely free." The developer decided to announce the update today as a way of thanking the community as the game has sold two million copies.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/BalatroGame/status/1821184855876804841?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Etweet" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">The first major gameplay update is coming to Balatro in 2025!<br>This update will bring new ideas and strategies to the game and as a token of huge appreciation to the game’s brilliant and passionate community, the update will be completely free. <a href="https://t.co/xS8ZQrTZGi" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/xS8ZQrTZGi</a></p>  — Balatro (@BalatroGame) <a href="https://twitter.com/BalatroGame/status/1821184855876804841?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 7, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>The developer also teased that there are two more surprises coming this summer, as indicated by the remaining two face-down cards. Some fans are speculating what the other announcements could be, such as a <a href="https://x.com/beigelow/status/1821185130678939895" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">mobile port</a>, <a href="https://x.com/AaronCurryDish/status/1821197642485084172" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">movie adaptation</a>, or <a href="https://x.com/tmaccoftime/status/1821205696890687558" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">cross-progressio</a>n functionality between platforms.</p><p>Balatro has been a huge hit to the point that LocalThunk put in their <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/balatro-creator-stipulates-in-will-that-game-cant-be-used-for-gambling/1100-6525562/" data-ref-id="1100-6525562">will that the game can't be used for any real gambling</a> even after their death. In GameSpot's <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/balatro-review-one-more-blind/1900-6418192/" data-ref-id="1900-6418192">Balatro review</a>, we said, "Balatro's ingenious combination of poker and roguelite gameplay creates an intoxicating combination that's hard to pull away from."</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/115776530127739146123?rel=author">George Yang</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525431&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/playstation-plus-free-games-august-2024\/1100-6525431\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525559&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/james-sa-corey-the-expanse-writer-new-series-captives-war-the-mercy-of-gods-book-one\/1100-6525559\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6518504&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/2024-upcoming-games-release-schedule\/1100-6518504\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525554&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/john-wick-blu-ray-box-set-is-only-18-at-amazon-and-walmarts-4k-steelbook-set-is-50-off\/1100-6525554\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525460&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-prime-members-get-22-free-games-in-august-including-one-of-2023s-best-games\/1100-6525460\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525417&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fanatical-summer-sale-includes-hundreds-of-steam-games-for-big-discounts\/1100-6525417\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525547&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-leaks-continue-this-time-with-a-graphic-new-ability\/1100-6525547\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6507171&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/disney-dreamlight-valley-recipes-list\/1100-6507171\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525574&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/godzilla-minus-one-4k-blu-ray-limited-edition-preorder-amazon-walmart\/1100-6525574\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525520&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/get-rare-disney-lorcana-promo-card-with-villainous-board-game-while-supplies-last\/1100-6525520\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525513&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/grab-up-to-18-games-for-less-than-3-each-with-fanaticals-august-platinum-bundle\/1100-6525513\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525496&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/jurassic-worlds-baby-bumpy-finally-gets-the-adorable-lego-set-it-deserves\/1100-6525496\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525567&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/metal-gear-solid-nendoroid-preorders-restocked-at-amazon-low-poly-snake-and-naked-raiden\/1100-6525567\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525570&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/transformers-gi-joe-movie-isnt-a-crossover-exactly-producer-explains\/1100-6525570\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525561&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/shin-megami-tensei-tabletop-rpg-finally-up-for-preorder-at-amazon-releases-next-month\/1100-6525561\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525507&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/this-16-lego-star-wars-set-transforms-luke-skywalkers-x-wing-into-a-mech\/1100-6525507\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525467&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fellowship-is-a-co-op-adventure-game-thats-all-dungeons-all-the-time\/1100-6525467\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6525535&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/final-fantasy-vii-remake-part-3-will-include-queens-blood\/1100-6525535\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6524714&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/legos-jaws-set-has-arrived-build-it-while-watching-the-new-and-steeply-discounted-4k-collection\/1100-6524714\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You Play This Bullet Hell With Just One Button And It’s Terrific]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/one-btn-bosses-bullet-hell-indie-steam-impressions-1851615829</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/you-play-this-bullet-hell-with-just-one-button-and-it%E2%80%99s-terrific.947274/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/one-btn-bosses-bullet-hell-indie-steam-impressions-1851615829<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Everything you need to know about the new <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/watching-other-people-play-bullet-hell-shooters-is-hell-1840975959&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/watching-other-people-play-bullet-hell-shooters-is-hell-1840975959">bullet hell</a></span> game <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/steam-next-fest-june-must-play-demos-demonschool-1851530214/slides/8&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/steam-next-fest-june-must-play-demos-demonschool-1851530214/slides/8"><em>One Btn Bosses</em></a></span> is right there in the title. You press one button and you take on a series of bosses. It’s a simple premise that developer Midnight Munchies delivers on and then some. With just one button, you might think that the game would get boring quickly or lack depth—but it’s just the opposite. <em>One Btn Bosses</em> is an enthralling game that constantly adds new challenges to master.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="196307" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="10 Minutes From The Last Of Us Part II’s Roguelike Mode " data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="657" data-playlist="196307,196789,195410" data-current="196307"><div><p>10 Minutes From The Last Of Us Part II’s Roguelike Mode </p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/196307/196307_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/21857.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>I already explained the premise and it truly doesn’t go much further than that. Each level gives you control of a moving object stuck on a track. The one button you use changes your direction of movement along the track (which can be shaped like a circle, square, a straight line, and more) so as to get out of the way of oncoming attacks from enemies. You also have the ability to attack, but with your singular input already taken by directional control, <em>One Btn Bosses</em> ties attacks to movement speed. The faster you move, the more projectiles you fire back at your opponent; switching directions lowers your speed, after which point it must be built up again. This creates a balancing act in the deceptively simple game. You have to avoid hazards but you also want to make quick work of enemies, which means you have to strategically choose exactly when to shift direction in order to maintain your highest speed as long as possible.</p><p>Staying true to its name, <em>One Btn Bosses</em> never gives you more than a single input, but each level still changes things up thanks to differences in enemy attack patterns. At the start you’ll face enemies who just shoot projectiles back at you, but over time they’ll start launching bombs with large areas of effect, missiles that home in on you, and special bullets that ricochet around a track—and that’s only a few of the tactics you can expect to encounter. It turns what could be a repetitive gameplay loop into a frantic fight for your life. Not long into the game, you’re faced with situations in which the screen is almost entirely filled with attacks you have to avoid with just one button at your disposal. But to give you a fighting chance, <em>One Btn Bosses</em> does offer up alternatives to your basic direction switch.<br></p><p>By collecting GP (Grind Points) after completing levels, you slowly unlock different abilities to equip that change what your button press does. One early skill you acquire can switch out your basic directional movement for a dash that lets you speed through attacks instead of having to turn around to avoid them. But new abilities don’t just alter how you move; they can also change how you attack, replacing your bullets with a laser or allowing you to bounce enemy attacks back. Midnight Munchies boasts that there are over 100 combinations of abilities to try out. However, the game’s levels feel tailored to the basic setup you start with. I spent a lot of time trying other skills, and really liked how the dash felt in certain levels, but I found myself returning to the default abilities often as they felt best suited for every challenge.</p><figure id="" data-id="d8b247ffb63d87073bf24b05ffb6002d" data-recommend-id="image://d8b247ffb63d87073bf24b05ffb6002d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A yellow ship runs along a track and avoids large pink hazards" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A yellow ship runs along a track and avoids large pink hazards" data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="other-license" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Image<!-- -->: <!-- -->Midnight Munchies / Outersloth</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="d8b247ffb63d87073bf24b05ffb6002d" data-recommend-id="image://d8b247ffb63d87073bf24b05ffb6002d" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A yellow ship runs along a track and avoids large pink hazards" data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p><em>One Btn Bosses</em> has a short, four-hour campaign that’s mostly an extended tutorial to get you into the game’s headspace. There’s a cute—if basic and unimportant—plot about working your way up the cutthroat corporate ladder, but gameplay is king here. That’s why <em>One Btn Bosses</em>’ <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/i-guess-i-actually-like-roguelikes-now-1845131675&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/i-guess-i-actually-like-roguelikes-now-1845131675">roguelike</a></span> mode might be the best thing about it. Once unlocked in the first fifteen minutes or so, you can dive into roguelike levels at any time. As per genre conventions, you run through a series of levels and unlock random skills after each boss to use on the next level. While abilities don’t always seem that useful in the campaign, the roguelike mode makes using and mastering each new skill fun. <em>One Btn Bosses</em> is all about momentum and the roguelike mode perfectly distills that. Yet even when going through the campaign, the game’s tight level design never ceases to amaze.<br></p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Game Informer Editor-In-Chief Says Goodbye After GameStop Deletes Previous Message]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-informer-editor-in-chief-says-goodbye-after-gamestop-deletes-previous-message/1100-6525613/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/game-informer-editor-in-chief-says-goodbye-after-gamestop-deletes-previous-message.947271/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-informer-editor-in-chief-says-goodbye-after-gamestop-deletes-previous-message/1100-6525613/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525613">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Last week, it was announced that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/game-informer-is-shutting-down-after-33-years/1100-6525508/">Game Informer would be closing its doors</a> after 33 years in operation, a decision made by the site's parent company, GameStop. Shortly thereafter, a former staffer used the publication's official Twitter account to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/former-game-informer-staffer-offers-an-actual-farewell-be-well-play-well/1100-6525532/">offer a "genuine goodbye,"</a> but Game Informer's Twitter account was deleted within minutes of the post. Now, former editor-in-chief Matt Miller has taken to Twitter to share his own official goodbye message with readers and former colleagues alike.</p><p dir="ltr">"33 years is a long time," Miller stated. "When thinking about saying goodbye to Game Informer, I felt that a few days of consideration were warranted to get my thoughts in order. I’m glad I waited. The outpouring of affection, support, and appreciation the team has received in recent days is humbling, it has reminded me how much this long-running magazine has meant to so many."</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/MatthewRMiller/status/1821219698886713829" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">I've never been big into posting social media, preferring to let our official channels speak for themselves. But I wanted to share a final message from this departing Editor-in-Chief. <a href="https://t.co/QEDv2b1RcK" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/QEDv2b1RcK</a></p>  — Matthew Miller (@MatthewRMiller) <a href="https://twitter.com/MatthewRMiller/status/1821219698886713829?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 7, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">Miller's post goes on to thank the long-running publication's many employees, contributors, and collaborators for their work, and also provides a glimpse into Miller's plans for the future.</p><p dir="ltr">"After 20 years of monthly issues, I plan to take a bit to catch my breath and consider what’s next," Miller said of his two-decade stint at Game Informer. "I still love games, and I hope to find a new way to stay connected to them through my work."</p><p dir="ltr">Game Informer first launched in August 1991, and was acquired by GameStop in 2000. According to the publication's displaced staff, employees were informed of GameStop's decision to shut down Game Informer the same day it was announced to the public. The magazine's writers, editors, and other staffers were reportedly given no warning, and were <a href="https://x.com/KyleMHilliard/status/1819403288980132298" rel="nofollow ">in the midst of working on the next issue</a> of Game Informer's print magazine--which will not be completed--when the announcement was made. <a href="http://www.gameinformer.com/" rel="nofollow ">Game Informer's website</a> was also taken down almost immediately after the news broke, but parts of the site can still be accessed via online archival tools like the <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/gameinformer.com/" rel="nofollow ">Wayback Machine</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">368 issues of Game Informer were printed and published during its 33-year run.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2XKO Alpha Lab Playtest Players Can Expect A "Decent Amount Of Jank," Riot Says]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2xko-alpha-lab-playtest-players-can-expect-a-decent-amount-of-jank-riot-says/1100-6525611/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/2xko-alpha-lab-playtest-players-can-expect-a-decent-amount-of-jank-riot-says.947268/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2xko-alpha-lab-playtest-players-can-expect-a-decent-amount-of-jank-riot-says/1100-6525611/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525611">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Developer Riot Games will soon be running the first at-home playtest for its <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/league-of-legends/" data-ref-id="5000-40335">League of Legends</a> fighting game <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/2xko/" data-ref-id="5000-503365">2XKO</a>, and is warning players to expect "a decent amount of jank" in addition to detailing all the characters, features, and work-in-progress elements players will be able to go hands-on with from August 8-19.</p><p dir="ltr">The playtest for the free-to-play fighter, Riot says in a <a href="https://2xko.riotgames.com/en-us/news/announcement/whats-in-2xko-alpha-lab/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">blog post</a>, is a "super early build." As such, not everything will be polished, with Riot saying players will "probably encounter a decent amount of jank" and that some features might not work as intended. Players may also experience crashes and other errors.</p>



    
  <div>

    <div tabindex="0" data-id="2004980711" data-promo-id="0" data-user-has-ads="1" data-video="{&quot;id&quot;:6464562,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;2XKO%20-%20Official%20Braum%20Champion%20Gameplay%20Reveal%20Trailer&quot;,&quot;lengthSeconds&quot;:86,&quot;startTime&quot;:0,&quot;autoplay&quot;:true,&quot;share&quot;:{&quot;linkUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/2xko-official-braum-champion-gameplay-reveal-trailer\/2300-6464562\/&quot;,&quot;embedUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464562\/&quot;,&quot;embedHtml&quot;:{&quot;640&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464562\/\&quot; height=\&quot;360\&quot; width=\&quot;640\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;,&quot;480&quot;:&quot;\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n<iframe src=\&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/videos\/embed\/6464562\/\&quot; height=\&quot;270\&quot; width=\&quot;480\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;\&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen><\/iframe>&quot;}},&quot;device&quot;:&quot;other&quot;,&quot;isDevice&quot;:false,&quot;isLiveStream&quot;:false,&quot;videoType&quot;:&quot;video-on-demand&quot;,&quot;countdownTime&quot;:0,&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;gs-2300-6464562&quot;,&quot;ageGateCookieName&quot;:&quot;videoAgeGateBirthday&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieName&quot;:&quot;watchedVideoIds&quot;,&quot;watchedCookieDays&quot;:1,&quot;postPlayMax&quot;:100,&quot;adCall&quot;:{&quot;host&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/pubads.g.doubleclick.net\/gampad\/ads?&quot;,&quot;params&quot;:{&quot;iu&quot;:&quot;\/5441\/vaw-gamespot\/desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;impl&quot;:&quot;s&quot;,&quot;gdfp_req&quot;:1,&quot;env&quot;:&quot;vp&quot;,&quot;output&quot;:&quot;xml_vmap1&quot;,&quot;unviewed_position_start&quot;:1,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;[referrer_url]&quot;,&quot;correlator&quot;:&quot;[timestamp]&quot;,&quot;description_url&quot;:&quot;[description_url]&quot;,&quot;cmsid&quot;:2566084,&quot;vid&quot;:6464562,&quot;pp&quot;:&quot;vpaid_js&quot;},&quot;custParams&quot;:{&quot;ptype&quot;:&quot;news_article&quot;,&quot;cid&quot;:&quot;gs-1100-6525611&quot;,&quot;game&quot;:&quot;2xko&quot;,&quot;genre&quot;:&quot;2d,action,fighting&quot;,&quot;con&quot;:&quot;pc,xbox-series-x,playstation-5&quot;,&quot;publisher&quot;:&quot;riot-games&quot;,&quot;embed&quot;:&quot;autoplay&quot;,&quot;franchise&quot;:&quot;league-of-legends&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;games&quot;,&quot;franchiseRoot&quot;:&quot;league-of-legends&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;vid&quot;:6464562},&quot;soundBasedSize&quot;:{&quot;normal&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;,&quot;muted&quot;:&quot;640x483&quot;,&quot;none&quot;:&quot;640x480&quot;},&quot;daiSsbUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/dai.google.com\/ondemand\/hls\/content\/2572465\/vid\/6464562\/master.m3u8&quot;,&quot;daiMidRollHost&quot;:2500176},&quot;uvpHi5Ima&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/s0.2mdn.net\/instream\/html5\/ima3.js&quot;,&quot;cuePoints&quot;:null,&quot;uvpc&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;partner&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;adPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop\/gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;desktopAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;mobileAdPartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;,&quot;mapp&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;,&quot;cms&quot;:&quot;pi&quot;,&quot;seekablePlaybacks&quot;:[&quot;html5&quot;,&quot;uvpjs&quot;],&quot;tracking&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;SiteCatalyst&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;charSet&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;UTF-8&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;currencyCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;USD&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteType&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;trackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;saa.gamespot.com&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;visitorNamespace&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsinteractive&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatTrackingServer&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;newimagitasinc.hb.omtrdc.net&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;heartbeatVisitorMarketingCloudOrgId&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;3C66570E5FE1A4AB0A495FFC@AdobeOrg&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;siteCode&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;brand&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;account&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;edition&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;ComScore_ss&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c2&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;31824268&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;publishersSecret&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;2cb08ca4d095dd734a374dff8422c2e5&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c3&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;partnerID&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;c4&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;gamespot&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;NielsenTracking&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;tracking&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;host&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/secure-us.imrworldwide.com\/cgi-bin\/m?&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scCI&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;us-200330&quot;},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;scC6&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;vc,c01&quot;}]},{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;MuxQOSPluginJS&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;qos&quot;,&quot;enabled&quot;:true,&quot;params&quot;:[{&quot;name&quot;:&quot;propertyKey&quot;,&quot;value&quot;:&quot;b7d6e48b7461a61cb6e863a62&quot;}]}],&quot;trackingAccount&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;trackingSiteCode&quot;:&quot;gs&quot;,&quot;trackingPrimaryId&quot;:&quot;cbsigamespotsite&quot;,&quot;videoAssetSource&quot;:&quot;Publisher Asset&quot;,&quot;uvpjsHostname&quot;:&quot;\/\/www.gamespot.com&quot;,&quot;siteType&quot;:&quot;responsive web&quot;,&quot;startMuted&quot;:false,&quot;screenMediumThumb&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.gamespot.com\/a\/uploads\/screen_medium\/1574\/15746725\/4330468-11.jpg&quot;,&quot;videoStreams&quot;:{&quot;adaptive_stream&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/cdn.jwplayer.com\/manifests\/xjV685xE.m3u8&quot;},&quot;userId&quot;:0,&quot;premium&quot;:false,&quot;datePublished&quot;:1720538460,&quot;videoAdPartner&quot;:&quot;desktop%2Fgamespot.com&quot;,&quot;videoAdMobilePartner&quot;:&quot;mobile_web%2Fgamespot.com_mobile&quot;}" data-non-iframe-embed="1" data-jw-context-name="gamespot" data-jw-media-id="xjV685xE" data-jw-player-url="https://cdn.jwplayer.com/libraries/VXc5h4Tf.js" data-jw-video-token="" data-has-youtube="" data-youtube-icon-path="https://www.gamespot.com/a/bundles/phoenixsite/images/core/loose/icn-youtube-30x30.png" id="video-rectangle"><div><p>
        Want us to remember this setting for all your devices?
      </p><p><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/signup/">Sign up</a> or <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/login/">Sign in</a> now!
      </p></div><p>
      Please use a html5 video capable browser to watch videos.
    </p><p>
      This video has an invalid file format.
    </p><p>Sorry, but you can't access this content!</p></div>
          <p><em>Now Playing:</em> 2XKO - Official Braum Champion Gameplay Reveal Trailer</p>
      </div>
<p dir="ltr">Six characters will make up the playtest's roster: Ahri, Braum, Darius, Ekko, Illaoi, and Yasuo. Each will be unlocked from the start, but Riot says future playtests may require players to unlock additional fighters through missions or with credits. There will be four stages to choose from, as well as a battle pass for players to progress through that includes skins for Ahri and Yasua alongside additional rewards like currency, avatar emotes, stickers, and other customization options. Casual and private matches will be available with cross-play enabled for those playing in the same region. A tutorial, as well as a training mode, will also be playable. This playtest will not include an offline or local play option.</p><p dir="ltr">The Alpha Lab playtest will be the first good look at how 2XKO handles its in-game lobbies, and will see players creating customizable chibi avatars that can be used to run around a virtual arcade filled with 2XKO cabinets, similar to lobby systems seen in games like <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/street-fighter-6/" data-ref-id="5000-558635">Street Fighter 6</a>.</p><p dir="ltr">"We think playing with friends and making new ones is an amazing part of the fighting game experience, so our lobbies are built to bring that vibe to an online space," Riot says.</p><p dir="ltr">None of the progress made towards the Alpha Lab playtest battle pass or currency earned will carry forward to future playtests, of which Riot says there will be more later this year. At the end of the playtest, players will receive a feedback survey the developer is encouraging every participant to fill out.</p><p dir="ltr">"Testing at this stage will give us time to incorporate feedback before launch," Riot says. "Basically, this is your chance to actually shape 2XKO with your notes."</p><p dir="ltr">2XKO is being planned for a 2025 launch, and it's looking to bring some <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/2xko-looks-to-bring-tag-based-fighting-games-into-a-new-era/1100-6525311/" data-ref-id="1100-6525311">major changes to the tag-based fighter formula</a>, including its support for up to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/project-l-league-of-legends-fighting-game-lets-you-play-2v2-with-four-players/1100-6516321/" data-ref-id="1100-6516321">four players in its 2v2 matches</a>. Those interested in signing up for future playtests can register via the 2XKO <a href="https://alpha.2xko.riotgames.com/en-us/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">website</a>.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Destiny 2 Fortunate Star God Roll Guide]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-fortunate-star-god-roll-guide/1100-6525580/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/destiny-2-fortunate-star-god-roll-guide.947229/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/destiny-2-fortunate-star-god-roll-guide/1100-6525580/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525580">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/destiny-2/" data-ref-id="5000-463450">Destiny 2</a>'s <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/destiny-2-solstice-2024-start-date-rewards-and-everything-we-know/2900-5615/" data-ref-id="2900-5615">Solstice of Heroes</a> has kicked off for 2024, and with it comes Fortunate Star, a new weapon you can only earn during the summertime event. Fortunate Star is a new bow with perks that can make it very effective in PvE play, especially if you're using Void or Prismatic builds that take advantage of Void debuffs. Here's everything you need to know about Fortunate Star, from where to get it to what rolls you want to chase.</p><div data-embed-type="toc"><p><span><strong>Table of Contents</strong> [<a data-toggle="collapse" href="#toc_list">hide</a>]</span></p><ul id="toc_list"><li><a href="#How_To_Get_Fortunate_Star">How To Get Fortunate Star</a></li><li><a href="#Fortunate_Star_God_Rolls">Fortunate Star God Rolls</a><ul><li><a href="#Fortunate_Star_PvE_God_Roll">Fortunate Star PvE God Roll</a></li><li><a href="#Fortunate_Star_PvP_God_Roll">Fortunate Star PvP God Roll</a></li></ul></li></ul></div><h2 dir="ltr" id="How_To_Get_Fortunate_Star">How To Get Fortunate Star</h2><p dir="ltr">Fortunate Star is specifically part of the Solstice loot pool, which means you won't get it from playing other activities. The quickest and easiest way to get one is by taking part in Bonfire Bash activities. You'll have a chance to get Fortunate Stars as you complete each run, alongside other Solstice weapons like Compass Rose, Something New, and Crowning Duologue.</p><p dir="ltr">There are also chances to get Fortunate Stars from Solstice packages, which you can earn from completing Solstice and Forge bounties as part of the event and from completing certain Triumphs on the Solstice event card. Generally, though, you're going to get tons of Fortunate Stars from Bonfire Bash, which should make chasing good rolls easy enough.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4346529-20240806172120_1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4346529" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4346529-20240806172120_1.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4346529"></a><figcaption>Fortunate Star</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1581/15811374/4346529-20240806172120_1.jpg"></figure><h2 dir="ltr" id="Fortunate_Star_God_Rolls">Fortunate Star God Rolls</h2><h3 dir="ltr" id="Fortunate_Star_PvE_God_Roll">Fortunate Star PvE God Roll</h3><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Bowstring</strong>: Polymer Bowstring / Agile Bowstring  <ul><li dir="ltr">Polymer Bowstring: +5 Accuracy, +10 Charge Time, -36 Draw Time</li><li dir="ltr">Agile Bowstring: +15 Handling, +5 Stability</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Arrow</strong>: Fiberglass Arrow Shaft / Compact Arrow Shaft  <ul><li dir="ltr">Fiberglass Arrow Shaft: +15 Accuracy, -5 Stability</li><li dir="ltr">Compact Arrows Shaft: +10 Handling, +10 Reload Speed</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>First Perk</strong>: Repulsor Brace  <ul><li dir="ltr">Defeating a Void-debuffed target grants an overshield.</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Second Perk</strong>: Destabilizing Rounds  <ul><li dir="ltr">Final blows cause nearby targets to become Volatile.</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Masterwork</strong>: Draw Time / Handling</li></ul><p dir="ltr">You can get a couple of decent combinations with Fortunate Star, but the most useful one is going to be a Void-centric roll best utilized with Void and Prismatic builds. That means you want Destabilizing Rounds and Repulsor Brace, which give the one-two punch of turning enemies Volatile and then rewarding you with an overshield for killing them. Alongside a Void or Prismatic build that utilizes invisibility or Devour, you can get a lot of awesome synergy from this role.</p><p dir="ltr">Alternatively, a combination like Successful Warmup or Archer's Tempo and Golden Tricorn will speed the Draw Time on Fortunate Star while boosting its damage. Coupled with a focus on Draw Time in the bowstring, arrows, and Masterwork, you can get the bow firing relatively quickly. A better focus might be the Handling stat, though, which you can boost up all the way to 100, making Fortunate Star very smooth to use with other weapons for a more rounded build.</p><h3 dir="ltr" id="Fortunate_Star_PvP_God_Roll">Fortunate Star PvP God Roll</h3><ul><li dir="ltr"><strong>Bowstring</strong>: Polymer Bowstring  <ul><li dir="ltr">+5 Accuracy, +10 Charge Time, -36 Draw Time</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Arrow</strong>: Fiberglass Arrow Shaft  <ul><li dir="ltr">+15 Accuracy, -5 Stability</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>First Perk</strong>: Hip-Fire Grip / Archer's Tempo  <ul><li dir="ltr">Hip-Fire Grip: Increases accuracy, stability, and precision-hit targeting when firing from the hip.</li><li dir="ltr">Archer's Tempo: Precision hits decrease Draw Time by 25% for 3 seconds.</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Second Perk</strong>: Archer's Gambit  <ul><li dir="ltr">Hip-fire precision hits grant a massive draw-speed bonus for a short period of time.</li></ul></li><li dir="ltr"><strong>Masterwork</strong>: Draw Time</li></ul><p dir="ltr">Fortunate Star is best used in PvE with its Void synergy, but it has some decent PvP rolls as well. Combining Hip-Fire Grip and Archer's Gambit gives you some serious benefits if you can land hits when firing from the hip--you get a boost to accuracy and then a major boost to draw time, allowing you to fire fast and land hits quickly. Alternatively, Archer's Tempo can do the job without requiring you to fire from the hip exclusively, and can be great when paired with Precision Instrument to help you land headshots and win duels.</p><p dir="ltr">Generally, you want to focus on decreasing the draw time of Fortunate Star and increasing its accuracy with your bowstring, arrow, and Masterwork choices, as well, to make this as accurate a weapon as possible that you can fire as quickly as possible.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Balatro creator says he will never let it be licensed for gambling, even after death]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/balatro-creator-says-he-will-never-let-it-be-licensed-for-gambling-even-after-death</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/balatro-creator-says-he-will-never-let-it-be-licensed-for-gambling-even-after-death.947196/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/balatro-creator-says-he-will-never-let-it-be-licensed-for-gambling-even-after-death<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="captioned-content" data-testid="featured-image"><p><span>Image via LocalThunk/Playstack.</span></p></div><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Balatro </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">creator LocalThunk is determined to make sure his smash hit deckbuilder never falls into the wrong hands. So much so that he's put his life on it.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">On </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/LocalThunk/status/1820752209765961746">Twitter</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, the developer revealed he recently wrote into his will that the game can "never be sold or licensed to any gambling company/casino." In recent months, he had been approached with potential license deals which </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/LocalThunk/status/1821169682373861736">presumably to</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> "reimplement the original mechanics as a gambling game itself."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">But despite its use of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/localthunk-knew-balatro-needed-to-draw-players-in-with-poker">poker cards</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Balatro </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">has nothing to do with gambling. In March, it was </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/gambling-fears-get-balatro-delisted-after-ratings-board-mixup">delisted</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in non-US regions due to concerns that it would influence young players to gamble. LocalThunk and publisher PlayStack refuted this during the ratings process.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Even so, </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Balatro </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">has become one of the biggest indie successes of the year. It recently surpassed </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/BalatroGame/status/1821184859974344853">two million copies</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, and will get its first major update in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/BalatroGame/status/1821184855876804841">2025</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">"Thank you all for helping us reach this absurd milestone," wrote</span><br><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/LocalThunk/status/1821186700783358286">LocalThunk</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. "I’m so grateful that this weird game has been such a hit and allowed the Playstack team and I to do what we do!"</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Earlier in the summer, he revealed an </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/balatro-dev-gives-look-at-first-prototype-joker-poker">early prototype</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Balatro, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">along with some thoughts on how the game </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/balatro-creator-unveils-a-few-slick-signposting-strategies">signposts</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> to players and gets them to learn the game's mechanics.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite ditches long-standing promise Battle Pass items won't be available to buy later]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-ditches-long-standing-promise-battle-pass-items-wont-be-available-to-buy-later</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-ditches-long-standing-promise-battle-pass-items-wont-be-available-to-buy-later.947193/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-ditches-long-standing-promise-battle-pass-items-wont-be-available-to-buy-later<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>"This change lets us continue investing in new and exciting...rewards".</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/fortnite-swole-fish.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Epic Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
Epic Games has announced it's ditching a long-standing <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fortnite">Fortnite</a> promise that Battle Pass items will never be made available to buy at a later date - although it's implementing an 18-month wait period before items can appear in its in-game shop.
</p>
<p>
It's a rule Epic has been accused of breaking before, specifically when it <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fortnite-fans-furious-summer-drift-style-being-sold">released a beachwear version of Fortnite's season 5 poster boy Drift</a> for purchase in 2019 - but the practice of releasing paid variants of previous Battle Pass characters has become commonplace in the years since.
</p>
<p>
Now, though, Epic is ditching the rule entirely so that any item released as part of a Battle Pass in the future can be sold in the Fortnite Shop, provided 18 months have passed since the Battle Pass' release. "This change lets us continue investing in new and exciting Battle Pass rewards" the developer wrote in a <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/change-to-item-exclusivity-in-future-fortnite-battle-passes">blog post</a>, "while enabling players down the road to also enjoy the content, including Outfits based on popular licensed characters."
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PlayStation live-service Concord won't sell you a battle pass - would it be better if it did?" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PlayStation live-service Concord won't sell you a battle pass - would it be better if it did?</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1LcpqnUgV5E?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Concord won't sell you a battle pass - but would it be more successful if it did?<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1LcpqnUgV5E" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Epic notes there's "no guarantee" a Battle Pass item will come to the Fortnite Shop following these changes to its exclusivity rules, adding it'll let players know if it releases a future Battle Pass item that'll "never" appear in the shop.
</p>
<p>
An accompanying FAQ confirms the rule changes apply to all Battle Pass items, meaning Outfits, Back Blings, Pickaxes, Emotes, Instruments, Decals, Wraps, Loading Screens, Banner Icons, and more. Bonus Rewards and Quest Rewards, as well as items earned from mid-season Battle Pass quests, will also be eligible to purchase after 18 months - as will any item alt Styles, but the number available may vary each time the item comes to the shop.
</p>
<p>
Epic adds the changes will not impact the pricing of Fortnite's Battle Passes, which will continue to cost 950 V-Bucks and provide the opportunity to earn 1500 V-Bucks by levelling up.
</p>
<p>
In other news, developer Mediatonic's <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fall-guys-is-now-in-fortnite">bean-based battle royale Fall Guys now exists within Fortnite</a>, some nine months after the UK studio was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fall-guys-developer-hit-hard-by-epic-games-layoffs-but-studio-to-remain-open">severely impacted</a> by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/epic-games-is-reportedly-laying-off-900-employees">job cuts at Epic Games</a> that ultimately affected 830 workers. Epic insists it currently doesn't "have anything to announce" when asked if it plans to move <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fall-guys">Fall Guys</a>' development solely into Fortnite.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Borderlands Movie First Impressions Call It 'Lifeless' And 'Really Bad']]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-reviews-impressions-bad-good-negative-1851615664</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/borderlands-movie-first-impressions-call-it-lifeless-and-really-bad.947187/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-reviews-impressions-bad-good-negative-1851615664<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>After a very long wait, the live-action <em>Borderlands</em> movie finally arrives in theaters this weekend. But before that, the movie was screened for fans and critics in Los Angeles. And, based on the first impressions being posted online, the <em>Borderlands </em>movie sounds like a complete mess.<br></p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195371" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Long-Lost Halo Demo Comes To Life" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="109" data-playlist="195371,196215,195752" data-current="195371"><div><p>Long-Lost Halo Demo Comes To Life</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195371/195371_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195371/195371_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195371/195371_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195371/195371_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20829.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p><em>Borderlands</em>, which hits theaters around the country on August 9, is based on the popular looter shooters developed by Gearbox and published by 2K Games. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/eli-roth-will-try-and-direct-a-borderlands-movie-1841804020&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/eli-roth-will-try-and-direct-a-borderlands-movie-1841804020">First announced back in 2020</a></span>, the PG-13-rated live-action movie directed by Eli Roth <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-hbo-last-of-us-craig-mazin-crombie-1850623951&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-hbo-last-of-us-craig-mazin-crombie-1850623951">spent years in production hell</a></span>. <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-first-scene-ign-live-clip-trailer-1851527486&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-movie-first-scene-ign-live-clip-trailer-1851527486">And every time we got a peek at it</a></span>, the movie looked pretty bad! But there was always a chance that the fully finished film would surprise us all and be amazing. Well, that doesn’t seem to be the case, based on the overwhelmingly negative first impressions online. </p><p> “<em>Borderlands </em>is a disaster,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://twitter.com/AdriCaporusso/status/1821041077018882518&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://twitter.com/AdriCaporusso/status/1821041077018882518" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted critic Adriano Caporusso</a></span>. “Filled with every cliché you can ponder, this film swaps the mayhem and imagination of the games for a lifeless, unfunny, and visually repulsive dud with annoying characters and a cast with not one ounce of chemistry.” </p><p>Matthew Simpson, a critic at <em>Movies We Texted About</em>, <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://twitter.com/SmatthewAF/status/1821056580751913225&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://twitter.com/SmatthewAF/status/1821056580751913225" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted</a></span>: “[The movie] is really bad. I really wanted to like it, but an uninspired plot + several phoned-in performances + being stuck in a weird place where it looks both expensive and cheap at the same time make it a huge misfire.” Simpson did offer one positive note, saying Jack Black is “great” in the film and the only actor who “matches the energy of the games.”<br></p><p><em>“Borderlands </em>feels like what an out-of-touch executive thinks the ‘cool kids’ find appealing,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://twitter.com/edgorteg/status/1821068763921576391&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://twitter.com/edgorteg/status/1821068763921576391" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweeted film critic Edgar Ortega</a></span>. “There is not a single earnest character moment here, just obnoxious quips that feel dated as soon as they leave the actors’ mouths. It’s not even so bad it’s good, just a complete mess.”</p><p> “<em>Borderlands </em>is easily one of the worst movies of the year,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/ShakExcellence/status/1821185896693297591&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/ShakExcellence/status/1821185896693297591" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted critic Shak Lambert</a></span>. “Fans will be pissed off with how much they get the characters wrong (especially Tina) [and] casual moviegoers will be unimpressed at how much it feels like a half-baked [<em>Guardians of the Galaxy</em>] rip-off.” </p><p>Similarly, freelance film critic <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://twitter.com/SKonMovies/status/1821041076167377236&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://twitter.com/SKonMovies/status/1821041076167377236" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sean Patrick Kelly posted</a></span> that while the film has an “exceptional level of detail for those who have played the video games,” it’s likely that most people will still accuse it of “<span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/borderlands-live-action-movie-trailer-cate-blanchett-1851274665&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/borderlands-live-action-movie-trailer-cate-blanchett-1851274665">being a <em>Guardians of the Galaxy</em> rip-off.</a></span>”<br></p><h2 id="h133106"><a id=""></a>Not <em>everyone </em>completely hated the <em>Borderlands </em>movie...</h2><p>There were some slightly more positive reactions, though. Many critics praised Jack Black and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/cate-blanchett-borderlands-why-is-she-in-it-pandemic-1851573135&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/cate-blanchett-borderlands-why-is-she-in-it-pandemic-1851573135">Cate Blanchett’s performances</a></span> and suggested fans of the franchise will get a kick out of Easter eggs and references sprinkled throughout the movie. </p><p>“<em>Borderlands </em>is a fun PG-13 action movie,” <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/HollywoodHandle/status/1821054567552786508&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/HollywoodHandle/status/1821054567552786508" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">posted <em>Hollywood Handle</em></a></span>. “It completely relies on Cate Blanchett’s star power to carry itself to the finish line — and she delivers.  While there’s nothing that particularly makes it stand out from the crowd, the film is enjoyable from start to finish and has decent pacing throughout. Jack Black is also a comedic powerhouse.  Aside from some corny flashback scenes and acting decisions that don’t always land, <em>Borderlands</em> is nothing to complain about but nothing to rejoice over.”</p><p><span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://x.com/Ki11ersix/status/1821185478043037947&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://x.com/Ki11ersix/status/1821185478043037947" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Borderlands </em>content creator Killer Six said</a></span> the movie was “better” than they expected, adding: “The plot is kinda a mess in true <em>Borderlands </em>fashion, but the humor and heart are there. Lots of fan service moments, but ultimately I don’t know if it will resonate. 6.75/10"</p><p>So yeah, it sounds like the <em>Borderlands </em>movie isn’t very good. I’ll be curious to see how it fares at the box office, especially with the big, similar action-comedy movie <em>Deadpool &amp; Wolverine</em> already in theaters and doing very well. Will <em>Borderlands</em> continue the recent trend of video game adaptions being pretty good and successful, or will it burn out and flop? We’ll know soon enough. </p><p> .<br></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Dragon Age: Inquisition Sex Scenes, Ranked From Worst To Best]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-inquisition-sex-scene-iron-bull-solas-cullen-1851615735</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-dragon-age-inquisition-sex-scenes-ranked-from-worst-to-best.947184/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-inquisition-sex-scene-iron-bull-solas-cullen-1851615735<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure id="" data-id="75d3814a340a0d1f6dcc73f3a57be1a6" data-recommend-id="image://75d3814a340a0d1f6dcc73f3a57be1a6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The Inquisitor and Dorian sit on their bed." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="The Inquisitor and Dorian sit on their bed." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->BioWare / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="75d3814a340a0d1f6dcc73f3a57be1a6" data-recommend-id="image://75d3814a340a0d1f6dcc73f3a57be1a6" data-format="jpg" data-width="1280" data-height="720" data-lightbox="false" data-alt="The Inquisitor and Dorian sit on their bed." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>The <em>Dragon Age</em> series loves to spotlight sex and romance. It’s a big part of developer BioWare’s marketing for the upcoming <em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em>, which will <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-4-veilguard-romance-options-dreadwolf-1851524102&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-4-veilguard-romance-options-dreadwolf-1851524102">include romantic routes</a></span> for each of its <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-companions-party-members-dreadwolf-1851530857&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-companions-party-members-dreadwolf-1851530857">seven companions</a></span>. With romance comes sex scenes, and those are always a pillar of what BioWare fans have come to expect in their love stories.<br></p><p>So with <em>The Veilguard </em>on its way this fall, we figured we’d look back at sex and romance in the <em>Dragon Age </em>series and see who is the best lover in Thedas. We’re ranking each game separately, so we’re starting with 2014’s <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-inquisition-the-kotaku-review-1659833205&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-inquisition-the-kotaku-review-1659833205"><em>Dragon Age: Inquisition</em></a></span>, which had some of the more elaborate sex scenes BioWare had ever put out at that time. Let’s see which member of the Inquisition knows how to lay down pipe.</p></div></div><div><p>The only reason <em>Inquisition</em>’s elven mage ranks at the bottom of the list of bangin’ is because he doesn’t have a sex scene. In fact, his romantic relationship is the only one that doesn’t reach a, well, climax. Solas breaks things off with the Inquisitor before things get hot and heavy. In the <em>Trespasser </em>DLC, he lays bare (sorry) that he didn’t want things to go that far while still hiding the truth of his nature as the elven trickster god the Dread Wolf. Thanks, I guess? Sorry to the Solasmancers for your decade-long slow burn. Wishing you well in <em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard </em>this fall.<br></p></div><div><p>It’s pretty fitting that Josephine’s love scene is one of the more tame ones in <em>Inquisition</em>. She’s meant to be the group’s prim and proper political face, and her romance follows suit. So while it might not be as steamy as the rest of this list, it’s still delightful watching her come to the realization that the Inquisitor harbors feelings for her. The scene’s writing has the cadence of a poem as the Inquisitor and Josephine flirt and wax on about each other, then solidify it with a kiss. The closest Josie gets to a sex scene is a cuddle by the fire that could likely have led to something else. But you get no points for implications around these parts.<br></p></div><div><p>Blackwall, or somebody going by that name, has a romance full of broody angst as he attempts to prevent the Inquisitor from getting too close. But like all will they/won’t they love stories, that makes the eventual culmination of the relationship all the sweeter. When it comes to doing the deed, Blackwall tries to dissuade the Inquisitor once more, telling her there’s no future with him as a Grey Warden, as his time is inherently much more limited than the average person. He’s not worthy of her. She can do so much better. They <em>shouldn’t</em>. But they <em>should</em> and will. Then he climbs on top of her in the biggest, puffiest, awkward coat. Blackwall’s angst is delectable, but he loses points for dipping without any pillow talk.<br></p></div><div><p>I find Sera’s romance scene to be a breath of fresh air compared to the dramatic gravitas and sexy flirtatiousness of others in <em>Inquisition</em>—it’s the one that recognizes sex can be silly and stupid, too. Sera’s sex scene begins with the Inquisitor trying to find a present for her elven lover after gifted gave her. You spend time walking around your base at Skyhold asking for advice on what to give her. Vivienne, ever the ideas woman, will suggest the Inquisitor shave her pubic hair into some crude shape. If you do this and bring her back to your quarters to show her, the Inquisitor tells Sera that she went all around the Inquisition asking for suggestions. The mere idea that the party knows that she and Sera are together is enough to delight her. It’s a surprisingly sweet admission that being known and seen as the Inquisitor’s partner is enough of a gift for her, especially from a character who typically approaches situations with snark and irony-poisoned indifference. The two start going at it, then we see Sera remarking on the pubic hair art the Inquisitor has made for herself. She laughs about it so hard she falls off the bed. It’s great!<br></p></div><div><p>Dorian Pavus’ sex scene can go one of two ways. The Tevinter mage either will slink into his lover’s quarters, say that he’s bored of the chit-chat, and wants to move onto something more “primal.” His sultry voice whispers at the Inquisitor’s ear and asks “how bad” he wants to be. If you choose to indulge, Dorian starts aggressively kissing the Inquisitor and the two go to town. Or, if you choose to slow things down a bit, Dorian is bewildered by this and says they’ve been “chaste” by his standards. It’s clear Dorian’s used to the breakneck pace of a gay man’s sex life in a populated city and unfamiliar with someone wanting to get to know him and be in a relationship. This approach may keep you from having sex at that very moment, but if that’s how you want to roleplay, that’s your prerogative. But I do think reaching the relationship is much better written, acted, and directed as a scene when you choose to have at it. Plus, you get to see his butt that way, and it’s a good one.<br></p></div><div><p>The Cullen romance ticks so many boxes that I almost wish I could explore it myself, but I’m a loyal king to my one true love, Dorian. So instead I just have to admire it from afar. Like Blackwall, Cullen’s romance is full of angst, as you’re trying to fix a broken man. Then you fuck on his office desk, and he knocks all that work shit off and onto the floor. It’s hot, but what’s hotter is what comes after. You fall asleep together and he starts having a nightmare about his tortured past watching all the traumatic things that happened in the <em>Dragon Age </em>series unfold. Then you’re like “oh, I can fix this man,” and your relationship becomes all about helping him overcome his demons. This is an AO3 user’s wet dream. Now if only we could <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/shitty-dragon-age-voice-actor-has-me-considering-deleti-1845854728&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/shitty-dragon-age-voice-actor-has-me-considering-deleti-1845854728">redub it with a different actor</a></span>.<br></p></div><div><p>One of Seeker Cassandra Pentaghast’s best quirks is her love of poetry and showboaty romantic gestures. So when her sex scene begins with the Inquisitor surprising her in a forest while he’s reading poetry, you know she is about to go from a hardened warrior to twitterpated girl at a moment’s notice. The scene is so saccharine and cheesy but, by god, it fucking works. The way she shoves the Inquisitor as he circles her and turns the pages of his book of ballads as she blushes? How he walks up behind her as she steals the book and reads a passage of her own, the quickness with which they abandon the performance and then just jump each other’s bones on the dirty forest ground, it’s all perfect. The two finish the night stargazing and wondering about the future. You’re free to either lean into or kill the mood from there. But the Inquisitor has game in this scene. Y’all ate that shit up, heterosexuals.<br></p></div><div><p>The Qunari warrior Iron Bull has two major sex scenes in <em>Dragon Age: Inquisition</em>, and if we were to rank them separately, they’d both be the top scenes on this list. The first is one where Iron Bull establishes that he doesn’t believe the Inquisitor is ready to “ride the bull.” If you insist you are, he holds your wrists together and pins you against the wall. “Last chance,” he whispers. Then he gives you what you asked for. As he leaves, spymaster Leliana approaches the bedroom to give the Inquisitor some intel before the Iron Bull tells her to let hero “rest” after what transpired. The couple has a follow-up conversation in which you establish the ground rules of your BDSM relationship. He’s dominant, knows what you need, and after leading the Inquisition throughout Thedas, maybe you require someone to tell you what to do from time to time.</p><p>The second, perhaps most important scene in the Iron Bull romance is the one in which Cullen, Josephine, and Cassandra walk one-by-one into the aftermath of one of your trists, remarking at the size of that thang. Good for you, Iron Bull. Maybe don’t <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/olympic-pole-vaulter-breaks-silence-after-his-own-pole-broke-the-internet_n_66b27dcfe4b0b3da47531f05&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/olympic-pole-vaulter-breaks-silence-after-his-own-pole-broke-the-internet_n_66b27dcfe4b0b3da47531f05" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">try to do any pole vaulting</a></span> at the Thedas Olympics.</p><hr><p>If you’ve never played a <em>Dragon Age</em> game, <em>Inquisition </em>is probably <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-inquisition-origins-what-to-play-1851538846&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-inquisition-origins-what-to-play-1851538846">the most required reading</a></span> before <em>The Veilguard </em>launches this year. Despite some widely-remembered issues like its open world bloat, I still think it’s probably BioWare’s best story across its history. That shit holds up real well. I might be due for a replay before <em>The Veilguard</em>. I gotta kiss Dorian before I start playing a different hero in the new game this fall.<br></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World’s First Ferrari Esports Arena Opens This Month]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/world-first-ferrari-esports-arena/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/world%E2%80%99s-first-ferrari-esports-arena-opens-this-month.947181/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/world-first-ferrari-esports-arena/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
																										
<p>Ferrari has just announced plans to open an esports arena in Abu Dhabi later this month, on August 29. In a post on social media, the team invited esports fans to ‘step into the driver’s seat and brace for a new era in virtual racing’. The Ferrari Esports Arena is a brand-first, and it comes equipped with a whopping <strong>twenty </strong>state-of-the-art driving simulators as well as a range of professional gaming stations.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-modern-gaming">Modern Gaming</h2>



<p>Ferrari isn’t the first motor brand to engage in the world of esports, and it certainly won’t be the last, but this is a huge investment that’s a sure step in the right direction. With ‘simracing’ and driving-based esports experiencing a boom, Ferrari has capitalised on the growth and built a stunning esports arena in Abu Dhabi. </p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true">— Ferrari World™ Yas Island, Abu Dhabi (@FerrariWorldAD) <a href="https://twitter.com/FerrariWorldAD/status/1820730669565141253?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>







<p>In a statement, Faisal Al Nuaimi, the GM at ‘Ferrari World Yas Island’ said:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>We are thrilled to introduce our latest innovation. This state-of-the-art facility is designed to&nbsp;immerse&nbsp;visitors in the exhilarating world of virtual racing like never before. Our goal is to continuously enhance the park’s offerings, catering to diverse preferences and ensuring there is always something new to experience at the world’s leading&nbsp;theme park.</p>



<p>This new attraction emphasises our commitment to strengthening tourism in&nbsp;Abu Dhabi&nbsp;and beyond, aligning with the city’s tourism objectives. Whether you’re a seasoned gamer or a first-time visitor, we strive to deliver an unparalleled mix of technology, realism and thrilling competitions.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Ferrari World has existed in Abu Dhabi since 2010, and in that time, it has welcomed hundreds of thousands of visitors. It’s home to the fastest roller coaster on the planet, and it sits just a few hours away from where the Esports World Cup is being held in Riyadh. </p>



<p>Esports is coming up in the Middle East, but it’s not a trend that has sat well in the minds of gamers worldwide. It’s going to take time and heavy, ongoing investment, but the governments of the UAE and Saudi Arabia are intent on making the region a spearhead of the competitive gaming market.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming Esports, check out the news <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/guild-esports-takeover-offer-bid/">that Guild is facing a takeover</a></p>

									</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Symphonia launches in late 2024 for PS5, Xbox Series, PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/symphonia-launches-in-late-2024-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/symphonia-launches-in-late-2024-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc.947178/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gematsu.com/2024/08/symphonia-launches-in-late-2024-for-ps5-xbox-series-ps4-xbox-one-switch-and-pc<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Side-scrolling <a title="Genres > Platformer [499 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/platformer">platformer</a> <em><a title="Games > Symphonia [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/symphonia">Symphonia</a></em> will launch for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [7,598 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [5,787 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, <a title="Platforms > PS4 [27,018 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps4">PlayStation 4</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox One [13,370 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-one">Xbox One</a>, <a title="Platforms > Switch [15,750 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch">Switch</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [20,814 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1865960/Symphonia/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam</a> in late 2024, publisher <a title="Companies > Headup [102 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/headup">Headup Games</a> and developer <a title="Companies > Sunny Peak [1 article]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/sunny-peak">Sunny Peak</a> announced. <span id="more-903967"></span></p><p><em>Symphonia</em> was previously announced for release in early 2024, but missed that window. This is also the first time specific platforms have been confirmed by the publisher.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1865960/Symphonia/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Steam page</a>:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p>In the realm of Symphonia, music acts as a source of life and energy. But since the founders and their orchestra vanished the inhabitants are divided, and the world slowly falls into silence. What if there was a way to gather a new orchestra? That’s the question Philemon, the mysterious musician in Symphonia, will have to answer.</p><p><strong>Embody a Mysterious Violinist</strong></p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Embody a mysterious violinist, brought back to life in a declining world. Your violin and bow are both your instrument and a means of transport. Catapult yourself through the world, and complete levels by solving exciting platforming challenges while re-activating the machinery that brings life and energy back to this world.</p><p><strong>Discover a Musical World</strong></p><p>Discover a musical world, based on the symphonic orchestra, and filled with colorful characters. Each area in Symphonia has its own distinct feel and characters, and each room is hand-crafted. Meet prodigious musicians and try to convince them to join the orchestra.</p><p><strong>A Unique Soundtrack</strong></p><p>A unique soundtrack, based on the romantic musical period, crafted by composer Olivier Esman. Enjoy the performance of the Scoring Orchestra Paris, recorded specifically for Symphonia and written by composer Olivier Esman and his team. Play engrossing concerts, each centered around one of the families of instruments—strings, brass, and woodwinds.</p><p>Explore, navigate, play the violin, gather musicians. Awaken Symphonia.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><a title="Companies > Experience [210 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> and overcome great platforming challenges with all of Philemon’s abilities.</li><li>Discover various environments which combine music and machinery.</li><li>Play the violin to activate level elements and bring life to the realm.</li><li>Gather musical Prodigies and play breathtaking concerts to bring music, joy, and glory, back to the land.</li></ul></blockquote><p>Watch a new trailer below.</p><h2><span>PC Demo Launch Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="Symphonia - PC Demo Launch Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wij7SsdH2SY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite Ends Exclusivity For Future Battle Passes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-ends-exclusivity-for-future-battle-passes/1100-6525606/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/fortnite-ends-exclusivity-for-future-battle-passes.947175/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/fortnite-ends-exclusivity-for-future-battle-passes/1100-6525606/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525606">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Epic Games is <a href="https://www.fortnite.com/news/change-to-item-exclusivity-in-future-fortnite-battle-passes" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">making one of its biggest changes ever</a> to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/fortnite/" data-ref-id="5000-125765">Fortnite</a> next week--the items on the upcoming Chapter 5 Season 4 battle pass will be the first in the game's history that aren't exclusive to the season they belong to. Starting with the upcoming season that begins on August 16, battle-pass cosmetics can be made available for sale in the Fortnite item shop starting 18 months after the end of the season.</p><p>This is a massive change because all previous battle-pass cosmetics have been sold under the pretense that they will never be available. Skins like Darth Vader and Optimus Prime are permanently unobtainable because of this longstanding exclusivity. While those past skins will remain exclusive, new battle-pass items will not be. This change marks a necessary long-term shift in Epic's strategy for Fortnite as it continues to grow into a larger ecosystem. Battle pass exclusivity made sense for a fledgling battle royale, but it makes less sense for a full-blown metaverse.</p><p>In it's announcement about the change, Epic specifically noted licensed characters as a reason for the move. "We want players down the road to enjoy battle-pass content such as Outfits based on popular licensed characters," Epic's statement read.</p><p>So here's the nitty gritty of this. Starting with the Chapter 5 Season 4 battle pass, Epic will have the option to sell battle-pass cosmetics 18 months after the season ends. It doesn't mean it definitely <em>will</em> sell everything in the shop right way or at all, but they'll have the option to do so. They may also declare that certain items in a pass <em>will </em>be exclusive, but they will be clearly labeled as such when that happens.</p><p>Meanwhile, it sounds as though purchasing battle-pass skins in the shop will be expensive--Epic indicates that each style of a skin will have to be purchased separately. But even though this change is being announced now, it'll be nearly two years before we actually see how this works. It's not currently even possible for Fortnite to sell skins the way this announcement describes, so there's some major work to be done.</p><p>While it would be easy to blame to recent item shop anomalies for forcing this change--namely the accidental sale of a battle-pass song last week, and the accidental return of The Paradigm on Tuesday--it could be that this was already a planned change ahead of the new season. Chapter 5 Season 4 has long been rumored to be a new Marvel-focused season, with a pass consisting entirely of Marvel characters--exactly the sort of situation that would warrant this change.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/112115755814061051052?rel=author">Phil Owen</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Baldur's Gate 3 Players Have Smooched Their Companions 75 million times]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-players-have-smooched-their-companions-75-million-times/1100-6525605/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/baldurs-gate-3-players-have-smooched-their-companions-75-million-times.947172/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-players-have-smooched-their-companions-75-million-times/1100-6525605/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6525605">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>So it seems like we've all been playing<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/baldurs-gate-3/"> Baldur's Gate 3</a>… for the plot. Larian Studios has just revealed what players have been doing since the game came out, and it turns out players have collectively kissed their companions over 75 million times.</p><p dir="ltr">We know which party members players preferred over the others thanks to a series of posts on the <a href="https://x.com/baldursgate3/status/1821186927779004770" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Larian Twitter account</a> that showcased what players did throughout their playthroughs. Leading the charges when it came to kisses was everyone's favorite goth princess, Shadowheart, with 27 million kisses, followed by Astarion, with 15 million kisses. If you're wondering who came in last, it was Minthara, with only 169,937 kisses.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/baldursgate3/status/1821186927779004770" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">It’s been a year since Baldur’s Gate 3 was released, and you know what we’ve realised?<br>Over a quarter of you can’t be trusted to not pick a fight with a djinni, and a surprising amount of you enjoy bear sex and tentacles.<br>Who’d have thought? <a href="https://t.co/kU9fAH6tnZ" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/kU9fAH6tnZ</a></p>  — Baldur's Gate 3 (@baldursgate3) <a href="https://twitter.com/baldursgate3/status/1821186927779004770?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 7, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">Interestingly enough, a little over half a million people also decided to romance Halsin. 70% of those who did chose to have him stay in human form, while the other 30% picked his bear form. Meanwhile, 1.1 million people also romanced the Emperor, and 63% decided to have them stay in their Guardian form, while 37% had them revert to their true form.</p><p dir="ltr">The post also revealed that Astarion was the most-picked Origin character, Paladins were the most-played class, and Elfs were the most-played race. Other information included how often players petted the Owlbear cub and Scratch, and which endings players received.</p><p dir="ltr">As a part of the one-year launch, the CEO and founder of Larain Studios, Swen Vincke, also shared a<a href="https://x.com/LarAtLarian/status/1820849069922607153" rel="nofollow "> statement on X/Twitter</a> in which they thanked players for all the positive feedback.</p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/LarAtLarian/status/1820849069922607153" data-has-image="false"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><p dir="ltr">You have no idea how much of an impact you had on all of us. You've made us better developers and gave us so many reasons to continue doing what we do. <br>Thank you for all the energy! <a href="https://t.co/tJRbW8ALim" rel="nofollow ">https://t.co/tJRbW8ALim</a></p>  — Swen Vincke @where? (@LarAtLarian) <a href="https://twitter.com/LarAtLarian/status/1820849069922607153?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p dir="ltr">This isn't the only thing Larian Studios has been up to lately. Recently,<a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/baldurs-gate-3-dev-launches-community-focused-youtube-channel/1100-6525534/"> the studio announced that it had launched a new "community-focused" YouTube channel called Larian: Channel From Hell,</a> which will post behind-the-scenes content.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
        
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam increases Store image requirements, details phase-out of old specs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/steam-increases-store-image-requirements-details-phase-out-of-old-specs</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/steam-increases-store-image-requirements-details-phase-out-of-old-specs.947154/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/steam-increases-store-image-requirements-details-phase-out-of-old-specs<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Valve has rolled out a new update for </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/group/4145017/view/4354502761457447460">Steam</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that bumps up the size requirements for banner images. The changes were made to help developers "show off their game in the best light," particularly on high-res monitors and the Steam Deck OLED.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The OLED was further cited as the first place where the new size would be most noticeable, as the smaller sizes stood out on the updated handheld.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Under the new template, assets for the Steam store (small, header, main, and vertical capsules) and library (header) will doubled in size. New high-resolution asset usage will roll out over the next few months, while the previous sizes lose support on November 1.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Until that date, Valve is accepting asset uploads with the previous size to avoid "disrupting developers that are in the process of building and shipping games."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">For previous releases, developers aren't required to update graphical assets with the new size. Past capsules will remain supported even after November 1.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Valve has already posted the latest </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fo/cvkwbosmrimklcl9h0qko/AF5IPErKP-mQM_3YO1Dw2lA?rlkey=b3ad0izykq367g4luasrinw9z&amp;e=1&amp;dl=0">asset templates,</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> along with a detailed overview of the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://partner.steamgames.com/doc/store/assets">new specifications</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author(s)</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Persona 3 Reload Expansion Pass Trailer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-persona-3-reload-expansion-pass-trailer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-persona-3-reload-expansion-pass-trailer.947151/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-persona-3-reload-expansion-pass-trailer/<br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Today, ATLUS released a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=53PsLN1z-6A" target="_blank" rel="noopener">brand-new trailer</a> for Persona 3 Reload, which showcases Metis, the new android companion that will join players in Persona 3 Reload: Episode Aigis -The Answer-. This is the third and final addition to the pre-existing Persona 3 Reload Expansion Pass.</p>
<p>This trailer showcases some of what players can expect to see when interacting with Metis, as the new expansion pass is set to give players 30 new hours of game play to dive into. Along with the generous amount of game play, players can expect to get their hands on new costumes and get to experience new background music.</p>
<p>For more context, Metis claims to be Aigis' sister. She appears before the S.E.E.S members, who are stuck in a March 31st time loop. Once she has met with them, she leads them to the Abyss of Time, which has somehow appeared in the basement of the dormitory. Her unique Persona is Psyche, with a specialization in Ice, Physical and Wind skills.</p>
<p>In this trailer, players are also introduced to the person who breathes life into Metis. This person is Lizzie Freeman who voices characters such as Sparkle in Honkai: Star Rail, Toby in My Time At Portia and Kitra in Unicorn Overlord.</p>
<p>For those excited for the release of Episode Aigis -The Answer-, the release date is officially September 10, 2024. This expansion pass will be available on Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, PC, Xbox Game Pass Ultimate, PlayStation 5 and PlayStation 4.</p>
<p>For those who will be playing the game via Xbox Game Pass Ultimate, the Expansion Pass will be completely free to you.</p>
<p>The Persona 3 Reload: Expansion Pass is available for purchase at a price of $39.99, which also includes the Persona 5 Royal EX BGM set, the Persona 4 Golden BGM set, the Velvet Costume set and BGM set.</p>
<p>For those looking for something to showcase their love for Persona, GameStop is doing an Aigis edition of <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/persona-3-reload-review/">Persona 3 Reload</a> for $199.99. This includes the base game, an artbook, the soundtrack, an Aigis statue and the Persona 3 Reload DLC pack.</p>
<p>The trailer for the latest addition to the Persona 3 Reload Expansion Pass is now available on YouTube, with a length of one minute and 11 seconds. She is showcased to have a cutesy and excitable personality who is happy to be able to call Aigis her sister.</p>
<p>The trailer also showcases Metis' powers and abilities during battle, where she can be prompted by Aigis during combat. Her abilities are very colorful and have a lot of flair, where she can shoot off into the sky to make a butterfly.</p>


				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>