<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 21:06:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New STALKER 2 Gameplay Trailer Showcases Weapons, Attachments and Upgrades]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/new-stalker-2-gameplay-trailer-showcases-weapons-attachments-and-upgrades/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/new-stalker-2-gameplay-trailer-showcases-weapons-attachments-and-upgrades.1030314/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/new-stalker-2-gameplay-trailer-showcases-weapons-attachments-and-upgrades/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>In a new gameplay trailer shared by IGN, players get a glimpse at what's to come in STALKER 2 and what weaponry and ammo will be available. It also shows off the gun attachments you'll get access to throughout the game. Since the original STALKER came out, it's been 17 years, and there have been major technological advancements since then. STALKER 2 is set to use Unreal Engine 5, and so far, all teasers and trailers have showcased amazing graphics. However, games using Unreal Engine 5 have been known to be temperamental. Despite this, <a href="https://wccftech.com/stalker-2-will-keep-a-stable-frame-rate-at-all-times-promises-developer/">the developers have promised</a> that the game will remain stable at all times. If you want to know what weapons and kit you can expect in STALKER 2, make sure to check out the video below.</p>
<p><iframe title="Stalker 2: Heart of Chornobyl - Exclusive Smoking Barrels Gameplay Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NAz3_4uvG0k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>In the video, the graphics and environments shown are absolutely stunning and are extremely detailed. It shows off how you can loot from bodies on the ground, as well as what your inventory will look like, something that can be a huge deterrent in games, depending on how it's handled. In the video, it seems as if each item you pick up is a specific shape or size, and you will be required to do a bit of Tetris to be able to fit items together. This sort of inventory is often seen in survival games and is commonly seen in the Resident Evil franchise. This can be fun but also serves as its own challenge. Each item also has its own weight, which can lead to over-encumbrance if you carry too much, as shown in the video.</p>
<p>The video also shows off some of the combat that you can expect in STALKER 2, as well as methods of self-preservation, which includes quickly bandaging yourself in sticky situations. The video released by GSC Game World shows how the world can go from derelict and barren to chaotic and dangerous in seconds, always showing that you have to be on your guard.</p>
<p>There are a variety of weapons that will be available and a lot of different attachments you can get, including 2x and 4x Scopes if you're someone who likes to use Sniper Rifles or want to be stealthy about your kills and take out your enemies from a vantage point.</p>
<p>The release date for STALKER 2 ebbs ever closer and is set for release on November 20 on Game Pass, Xbox Series X|S, and <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1643320/STALKER_2_Heart_of_Chornobyl/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PC via Steam</a>, the Epic Games Store, and GOG.</p>
<p>Will you be diving into STALKER 2: Heart of Chornobyl?</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A whole bunch of Sega classics are being delisted]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/7/24290671/sega-classic-games-delisted</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-whole-bunch-of-sega-classics-are-being-delisted.1030311/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/7/24290671/sega-classic-games-delisted<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Sega is planning to delist a lot of its classic games from digital storefronts as of December 6th at 11:59PM PT.</p><p>Steam will be affected the most, losing 62 titles including <em>Crazy Taxi</em>, <em>Dr. Robotnik’s Mean Bean Machine</em>, <em>Jet Set Radio, NiGHTS into Dreams, </em>and<em> Sonic 3D Blast.</em> Sega is pulling 12 titles from the Xbox store. The Nintendo eShop and the PlayStation Store will “just” lose <em>SEGA Genesis Classics — </em>but that title includes more than 50 old Genesis games, so it still means a lot will be unavailable. You can see the full lists of what’s getting pulled on <a href="https://support.sega.com/hc/en-us/articles/29776767664145-SEGA-Classics-FAQ#h_01JBWBD2TRQDGP79RFEAY1YVBZ">a Sega support page</a>.</p><p>Any games that you have purchased will still be available to download and play after they’re delisted from the storefronts, so if you’ve had your eye on any of them, you might want to buy them before they’re gone.</p><p>The delistings are happening ahead of Sega’s planned reboots for <em>Jet Set Radio</em>,&nbsp;<em>Shinobi</em>, <em>Golden Axe</em>,&nbsp;<em>Streets of Rage</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Crazy Taxi</em>, but those revivals aren’t expected <a href="https://www.theverge.com/games/2023/12/7/23992993/sega-is-bringing-back-some-classics">anytime soon</a>. And it wouldn’t be the first time Sega has delisted games ahead of releasing them in a different form: the company <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/26/23043398/sega-pulls-classic-sonic-the-hedgehog-games-digital-stores-origins">pulled the vast majority of classic <em>Sonic</em> games</a> from digital stores&nbsp;before it <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/20/23033583/sonic-origins-sega-hedgehog-ps5-xbox">launched <em>Sonic Origins</em></a>.</p><p>Hopefully, the games getting removed in December will be available to buy again at some point down the line — keeping video game classics alive <a href="https://www.theverge.com/23850347/video-game-preservation">is already hard enough</a>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roblox is limiting access to social hangouts and unrated games for children aged under 13]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roblox-is-limiting-access-to-social-hangouts-and-unrated-games-for-children-aged-under-13</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/roblox-is-limiting-access-to-social-hangouts-and-unrated-games-for-children-aged-under-13.1030308/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/roblox-is-limiting-access-to-social-hangouts-and-unrated-games-for-children-aged-under-13<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
  

        <p>New safety measures to "keep our younger users safe"</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/sushi-0.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>best tycoons studio</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/roblox">Roblox</a> is making changes in an attempt to keep younger players safe in the online platform. Beginning later this month, children under the age of 13 will no longer be able to search, discover or play unrated experiences within Roblox, and will be unable to access social hangout experiences.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"Parents and young users need accurate information about the experiences they are playing. Moving forward, all creators must complete a questionnaire for each experience they want available for users under 13. This means that all unrated experiences will be filtered out of search and any public or recommended sorts for users under 13," says <a href="https://devforum.roblox.com/t/updating-experience-guideline-policies-to-keep-our-younger-users-safe/3249079">the announcement</a>.
</p>
<p>Creators have until December 3rd to fill out the questionnaire if they want their content rated for play for those under the of 13. After that point, the unrated content will be filtered out.
</p>
<p>The changes to social hangouts will take effect earlier, on November 18th.
</p>
<p>"We are also updating our policies to address user behavior that can potentially pose a risk to our youngest users," says the post, desperately trying to avoid using words like 'pedophiles' or 'predators'. "Starting November 18, experiences with certain types of interactive features, specifically social hangouts and free-form 2D user creation, will only be playable to users over the age of 13. Creators will always be able to play their own experience or any experience they have edit access to."
</p><p>Earlier this year, a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2024-roblox-pedophile-problem/">report by Bloomberg</a> addressed the scale of child safety issues within Roblox, highlighting 13,316 instances of child exploitation reported on the platform in 2023. The following month, Hindenberg Research - an organisation which reports on businesses in order to profit from short-selling - published its own report <a href="https://hindenburgresearch.com/roblox/">labelling Roblox a "pedophile hellscape"</a>. Roblox responded to claims in both reports, saying Bloomberg's coverage featured "glaring mischaracterisations" and that it "rejects" Hindenberg's report.
</p>
<p>It's arguably worth putting that number in context, since Roblox is vastly successful with 78 million daily active users as of earlier this year. It's also worth noting that if you perfectly set the parental controls and dodge the predators, the reward is that your kid gets to safely play some of the worst, most exploitatively-designed video games imaginable. You think the skinner box design, FOMO and gambling tactics are bad in mainstream free-to-play games? Wait until you see what they're like when they're created by companies with no public reputation or licensors to protect.
</p>
<p>My kid's school recently sent home a leaflet about Roblox, explaining what it is and how parents can keep children safe in it. Part of the leaflet explained the concept of "ODers", which apparently stands for "Online Daters", who in this context are adults who use Roblox to find an adult romantic partner. I looked it up and this is apparently a real thing and I've been spiralling ever since. I always thought I'd be the sort of person to keep up with technological and social trends, but I'm sloping into middle age and realising that no, I can't, I won't. They've changed what 'it' is and now what's 'it' seems weird and scary to me. 
</p>
<p>I tell every parent I meet what I'll tell you: under 13 or over 13, safe or not safe, don't let your kids play Roblox. Teach them to have taste.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Full Details on New Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Maps Released]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/full-details-on-new-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-maps-released/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/full-details-on-new-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-maps-released.1030296/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/full-details-on-new-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-maps-released/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Season 1 starts on November 14, and with it comes plenty of additions for players. From weapons to modes to general content, there’s no shortage of new things coming to the game. One area that many fans were excited to learn more about after their tease were the new multiplayer maps for Black Ops 6.</p>



<p>As part of its blog detailing everything for Season 1, Activision gave full details on the new maps coming to the game. In total, there will be four new maps, one remastered map, and one variation coming during Black Ops 6 Season 1. </p>



<h6>RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-weapons-black-ops-6-coming/">Every New Weapon in Black Ops 6 Season One (and How to Get Them)</a></h6>



<p>The four new maps are Hideout, Heirloom, Extraction, Racket. Hacienda&nbsp;returns from Black Ops 4, and Nuketown gets a Holiday season variant. Three of the maps will be available at launch while the other three come mid-season.</p>



<p>You can get full details on the new maps below <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-one-mp-zombies-maps-modes-announcement#Maps" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">via Activision</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-1-maps">Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 Season 1 Maps</h2>



<h3 id="h-hideout-launch-6v6-medium-sized">Hideout (Launch) – 6v6, Medium-sized</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p><em>Sharpen your combat skills in this mid-sized Multiplayer map featuring an extensive training site including target practice, an obstacle course, and a lifelike recreation of a vault and security room to help plan for the next mission to hit the Luttazzi crime family.</em></p>



<p><em>The vault and blueprints buildings offer intense, multi-level indoor combat while the armory and open bus set the stage to ambush passing enemies.&nbsp;</em></p>



<h3 id="h-heirloom-launch-2v2-6v6-medium-sized">Heirloom (Launch) – 2v2, 6v6, Medium-sized</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p><em>Crash a private showing of Luttazzi family art to create a diversion for the other Rogue Black Ops team as they execute the real job. Navigate in and around a huge sculptural centerpiece in the main exhibit or branch out into the lobby or a side exhibit for a closer fight.</em></p>







<figure></figure>



<p><em>All hell has broken loose in the aftermath of a Crimson One ambush when the attack on the Luttazzis goes sideways. The burning rubble of a downed helicopter and a dead pilot signal an attack on the Avalon Heliport, a typically peaceful tourist destination where clients can book sky high views of Avalon’s breathtaking landscape.</em></p>



<h3 id="h-racket-mid-season-2v2-6v6-small-sized">Racket (Mid-Season) – 2v2, 6v6, Small-sized</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p><em>Time to crack open the heart of the Luttazzi money laundering operation and hit them where it really hurts. Breach the premises in this small-sized underground bank vault, a line of broken tiles marking the path of the center bulldozer placed before the vault of golden bars. Defaced pieces of art and the crossed-out emblem of the Luttazzi family indicate not just greed but malicious intent.</em></p>



<h3 id="h-hacienda-mid-season-6v6-medium-sized">Hacienda&nbsp;(Mid-Season) – 6v6, Medium-sized</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p><em>Last seen in&nbsp;<em>Black Ops 4</em>, the iconic competitive map returns, sending Operators back to the infamous vineyard estate. Battle within the open-air, two-story mansion with surrounding views of the pristine courtyard below. From the grand foyer past the lion statue, head toward the showroom garage or move out to the garden to keep the fight outside. On the other end of the estate, marvel at the built-in aquarium above the vault.</em></p>



<h3 id="h-nuketown-holiday-mid-season-6v6-small-sized">Nuketown Holiday (Mid-Season) – 6v6, Small-sized</h3>



<figure></figure>



<p><em>A Holiday-themed version of Nuketown with snow, decorations, and more.</em></p>



<p>What do you think of the new maps coming to Black Ops 6? Let us know down below, and join the discussion in the official <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/forums/call-of-duty.12/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming forums</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, check out our extensive&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/inzoi-game-director-talks-inspiration-the-sims-the-life-simulator-genre-appealing-to-the-west-and-more/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">interview with inZOI Director and Producer</a>&nbsp;Hyungjun “Kjun” Kim. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Lets You Become A Gruesome Killer With Power Drill Melee Weapon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-lets-you-become-a-gruesome-killer-with-power-drill-melee-weapon/1100-6527640/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-lets-you-become-a-gruesome-killer-with-power-drill-melee-weapon.1030293/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/black-ops-6-lets-you-become-a-gruesome-killer-with-power-drill-melee-weapon/1100-6527640/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527640">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Activision has announced what's coming to Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 in its upcoming Season 1 update, and there are multiple new melee weapons on the way, including a power drill.</p><p>The two-hit-kill melee weapon is effective at very short range and has a fast attack speed, Activision said. The melee weapon has multiple attack vectors, including sweeps, jabs, uppercuts, and a heavy attack when pressed straight on. "This weapon is ideal for putting a hole in the competition when the going gets tough," Activision said.</p><p>The power drill can be unlocked via en event reward sometime during Season 1, but Activision didn't reveal exactly how it can be unlocked. In any event, the drill itself has 30 levels and mastery badges available, and it can be customized with unique skins. Death by power drill sounds particularly gruesome, but no footage of the drill in action has been released thus far.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4396577-powerdrill.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4396577" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4396577-powerdrill.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4396577"></a><figcaption>Say hello to the power drill. </figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4396577-powerdrill.jpg"></figure><p>Another new melee weapon in Black Ops 6 Season 1 is the cleaver. The one-hit-kill melee weapon is effective at short or medium range, Activision said, and it has a medium attack speed. The cleaver can take down multiple enemies at once, and it has a particularly devastating heavy attack. It can be swung side to side or head-on. Whether or not the cleaver can be thrown is unknown but that seems unlikely.</p><p>The cleaver has 30 levels and mastery badges, and can be customized with skins. Like the power drill, the cleaver can be unlocked as an event reward.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4396578-cleaver.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4396578" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4396578-cleaver.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4396578"></a><figcaption>The cleaver comes to Black Ops 6 in Season 1</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4396578-cleaver.jpg"></figure><p>In addition to these new melee weapons, Season 1 adds <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-dutys-the-replacer-is-becoming-a-playable-operator-in-black-ops-6/1100-6527638/" data-ref-id="1100-6527638">Peter Stormare's The Replacer</a> as a playable operator, as well as new maps, modes, and weapons, along with a new Warzone map, Area 99. You can <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-one-mp-zombies-maps-modes-announcement" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">read Activision's extensive blog post</a> to get up to date with everything coming in Season 01.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard's first patch slips in some Mass Effect armour as an N7 Day treat]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguards-first-patch-slips-in-some-mass-effect-armour-as-an-n7-day-treat</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguards-first-patch-slips-in-some-mass-effect-armour-as-an-n7-day-treat.1030287/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguards-first-patch-slips-in-some-mass-effect-armour-as-an-n7-day-treat<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>Plus DLSS fixes and more.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/veilguard-mass-effect-armour-lightened.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>BioWare/EA</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
With Dragon Age: The Veilguard's one-week anniversary now here, BioWare has released its first big patch for the well-received fantasy action-RPG; and as an added treat, the studio has tossed in some <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mass-effect">Mass Effect</a> themed armour to mark this year's N7 Day.
</p>
<p>
The Veilguard's first patch isn't admittedly, a particularly sexy one in terms of fixes. Its <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/1845910/view/4453590197273100466?l=english">release notes</a> suggest an update primarily focussed on massaging away some relatively minor annoyances - but given Digital Foundry called the game's initial release an "attractive, technically solid" one <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-dragon-age-the-veilguards-pc-port-is-polished-performant-and-scales-well-beyond-console-quality">on PC</a>, and "polished [and] performant" <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/digitalfoundry-2024-dragon-age-the-veilguard-on-consoles-is-an-attractive-technically-solid-release">on consoles</a>, there didn't appear to be anything particularly egregious in need of attention.
</p>
<p>
Still, if you're an owner of an Nvidia 40-series GPU who couldn't access Dragon Age: The Veilguard's DLSS options, or were finding Harding and Taash's banter looping endlessly, then those - alongside exactly 43 additional issues - should now be remedied on PC and consoles.
</p>
<figure><div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div><figcaption>Here's a video version of our Dragon Age: The Veilguard review.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9f0BX-JXzek" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Perhaps the most exciting part of the patch, then, is the inclusion of the aforementioned Mass Effect-inspired armour - a surprisingly dashing blend of practical chest plate, dinner jacket overcoat, and N7 helmet - that can be acquired via a new chest in the Lighthouse, and which you can see at the top of the page. This, of course, has been released to commemorate the return of BioWare's annual N7 Day - celebrations that have also seen a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effect-is-officially-getting-a-tv-adaptation-at-amazon">Mass Effect TV show officially announced</a>, plus <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/no-mans-sky-rolling-out-cross-save-support-from-today-as-ps5-pro-enhancements-arrive">returning collaborations with No Man's Sky</a> and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/destiny-2">Destiny 2</a>.
</p><p>
In a <a href="https://x.com/bioware/status/1854577078806429869">message shared on social media</a>, BioWare wrote, "November 7 has arrived once again, and as always, we're grateful for the opportunity to celebrate all things Mass Effect! This year is a little different, as we just launched Dragon Age: The Veilguard as a studio; so we're purposefully keeping things lighter as we celebrate the launch of the game... Although we're a little quieter this year, we couldn't be more excited for what's to come."
</p>
<p>
Eurogamer's Robert Purchese had a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/dragon-age-the-veilguard-review">lot of good things to say about BioWare's latest Dragon Age in his five star review</a>. "From head to toe, wing to wing, The Veilguard is exquisitely realised and full of sophistication across systems and storytelling," he wrote. "It's warm and welcoming, funny and hopeful, gentle when it needs to be, and of course it's epic - epic in a way I think will set a high bar not only for BioWare in years to come but for role-playing games in general."
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Mirage Enhanced for PS5 Pro, Runs At 4K60 with PSSR]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-mirage-enhanced-for-ps5-pro-runs-at-4k60-with-pssr/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-mirage-enhanced-for-ps5-pro-runs-at-4k60-with-pssr.1030269/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-mirage-enhanced-for-ps5-pro-runs-at-4k60-with-pssr/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Assassin's Creed Mirage is now enhanced for the PS5 Pro, just a year after it was initially released on PS4 and PS5. Ubisoft Bordeaux has been working to release a patch for the game so that it will be enhanced for PS5 Pro when the console officially releases. To make it worth playing on the PS5 Pro, they've made some changes to how the game will run in both Quality and Performance mode on the PS5 Pro. Here is everything you can expect from the Assassin's Creed Mirage Enhanced patch.</p>
<p>Should you be picking up the game for the PS5 Pro, you will be able to play the game in 4K60 with PSSR as the upsampling software to provide "more faithful 4K details at 60 FPS." Quality Mode is now the default setting for the game at 60FPS rather than the 30FPS that it was for the original PS5 version of the game.&nbsp; The improvements have been showcased in a <a href="https://x.com/assassinscreed/status/1854569510272905389" target="_blank" rel="noopener">short video</a> that was posted by the official Assassin's Creed account on X.</p>
<p>As a whole, graphics are said to be generally improved, with better shadows and reflection fidelity, as well as higher texture resolution and improved draw distance. Whether this will be enough for people to pick up the game for the PS5 Pro remains to be seen.</p>
<p>While the Assassin's Creed franchise is quite expansive, when it comes to recent titles, Assassin's Creed Mirage wasn't as revered compared to other titles in the franchise, like Black Flag and Valhalla, for example. Despite this, Assassin's Creed Mirage was still the third best-selling retail game in Japan when it was released.</p>
<p>The main issue with Assassin's Creed Mirage was that people felt that the game was too short, and it is listed as one of the lowest-rated games in the franchise. Although it received a ton of positive buzz from critics when the game launched, it's tied for the third lowest-rated Assassin's Creed game in the whole series. Mirage tried to return to the stealthy roots of the fan favorites but didn't quite have the sparkle and charm that the original Assassin's Creed games had.&nbsp; You can read the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/assassins-creed-mirage/">review by Nathan Birch here</a>.</p>
<p>The latest Assassin's Creed game, named Assassin's Creed Shadows, was due for release on November 15 but has since been pushed back for a release on February 15, 2025. Despite not being out yet, the game has caused a significant stir in the community, and people have been actively trying to push for Ubisoft to either scrap the game or remake it entirely away from the story that they were initially trying to create.</p>
<p>Will you be picking up Assassin's Creed Mirage for the PS5 Pro?</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sega are delisting over 60 'classic' games from Steam, including Crazy Taxi and Streets Of Rage]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sega-are-delisting-over-60-classic-games-from-steam-including-crazy-taxi-and-streets-of-rage</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/sega-are-delisting-over-60-classic-games-from-steam-including-crazy-taxi-and-streets-of-rage.1030266/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sega-are-delisting-over-60-classic-games-from-steam-including-crazy-taxi-and-streets-of-rage<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

        <p>You've got until December 6th to buy them</p>

    </div><div>



            <p>Sega are delisting several bundles of 'classic' games from digital stores, along with "select individual" games. On Steam specifically, this adds up to over 60 games in total, including several actual classics including the original Streets Of Rage trilogy, Crazy Taxi, and Jet Set Radio. 
</p>
<p>The games will be removed on December 6th but will remain playable to those who already own them.
</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"We've got some news to share regarding our Classics bundles. As of December 6th, 2024 we'll be saying farewell to new purchases of the SEGA Mega Drive and Genesis Classics &amp; Dreamcast Classics. Both of these great bundles and select individual games will be delisted on Steam December 6th," says <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/games/205950/announcements/detail/4483990132492337189">the announcement</a>, which seems to rather undersell the number of games being delisted.
</p>
<p>"No worries if you already own a game or bundle. These gems will still live in your Steam library. You can download and play SEGA Classics games whenever you want, as long as you own them before December 6th."
</p>
<p>The full list of games being delisted on Steam is <a href="https://support.sega.com/hc/en-us/articles/29776767664145-SEGA-Classics-FAQ#h_01JBWBCN80ZHHPAEQYX1C1M3M9">listed on a Sega support FAQ</a>, but I'll include it below:
</p>
<blockquote><ul><li>Alex Kidd in the Enchanted Castle</li>
<li>Alien Soldier</li>
<li>Alien Storm</li>
<li>Altered Beast</li>
<li>Beyond Oasis</li>
<li>Bio-Hazard Battle</li>
<li>Bonanza Bros</li>
<li>Columns</li>
<li>Columns III</li>
<li>Comix Zone</li>
<li>Crack Down</li>
<li>Crazy Taxi</li>
<li>Decap Attack</li>
<li>Dr. Robotnik’s Mean Bean Machine</li>
<li>Dreamcast Collection Bundle</li>
<li>Dynamite Headdy</li>
<li>Ecco Jr.</li>
<li>Ecco the Dolphin</li>
<li>Ecco: The Tides of Time</li>
<li>ESWAT: City Under Siege</li>
<li>Eternal Champions</li>
<li>Fatal Labyrinth</li>
<li>Flicky</li>
<li>Galaxy Force II</li>
<li>Gain Ground</li>
<li>Golden Axe</li>
<li>Golden Axe II</li>
<li>Golden Axe III</li>
<li>Gunstar Heroes</li>
<li>Jet Set Radio</li>
<li>Kid Chameleon</li>
<li>Landstalker: The Treasures of King Nole</li>
<li>Light Crusader</li>
<li>Mega Drive and Genesis Classic Bundle</li>
<li>NiGHTS into Dreams</li>
<li>Phantasy Star II</li>
<li>Phantasy Star III: Generations of Doom</li>
<li>Phantasy Star IV: The End of the Millennium</li>
<li>Ristar</li>
<li>SEGA Bass Fishing</li>
<li>Shadow Dancer</li>
<li>Shining Force</li>
<li>Shining Force II</li>
<li>Shining in the Darkness</li>
<li>Shinobi III: Return of the Ninja Master</li>
<li>Sonic 3D Blast</li>
<li>Sonic Spinball</li>
<li>Space Channel 5: Part 2</li>
<li>Space Harrier II</li>
<li>Streets of Rage</li>
<li>Streets of Rage 2</li>
<li>Streets of Rage 3</li>
<li>Super Thunder Blade</li>
<li>Sword of Vermilion</li>
<li>The Revenge of Shinobi</li>
<li>ToeJam &amp; Earl</li>
<li>ToeJam &amp; Earl in Panic on Funkoton</li>
<li>VectorMan</li>
<li>VectorMan 2</li>
<li>Virtua Fighter 2</li>
<li>Wonder Boy in Monster World</li>
<li>Wonder Boy III: Monster Lair</li>
</ul></blockquote>
<p>Sega offer no reason for why the games are being removed from sale, but typically delisting happens for one of three reasons: expiring licenses; new exclusivity to a different storefront; or an intent to re-release the games in a new form (eg. an enhanced edition, typically with a higher price).
</p><p>This time last year, Sega announced their intent to make <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sega-announce-new-jet-set-radio-crazy-taxi-streets-of-rage-golden-axe-and-shinobi">new games based on Jet Set Radio, Crazy Taxi, Streets Of Rage, Golden Axe and Shinobi</a>, and previously signalled their intent to produce <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/sega-plan-more-remakes-and-remasters-but-still-aiming-to-create-revolutionary-super-game">more remakes and remasters</a> of their classic games.</p>
<p>For the avoidance of doubt: delisting is bad and I hate it. Even if these games are to return in an improved format, and even if that new format is universally beloved by all, I still wish the existing versions weren't sent to the attic.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard Gets First Patch]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-gets-first-patch/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-gets-first-patch.1030260/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-the-veilguard-gets-first-patch/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-67498">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>EA and BioWare have released the first patch for Dragon Age: The Veilguard. The update comes a week after Dragon Age: The Veilguard released to a <a href="https://opencritic.com/game/17037/dragon-age-the-veilguard" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">mostly strong response</a>.</p>



<p>“Whether you’ve already been playing or are jumping in for the first time, we have our first patch releasing today with a few quality of life improvements and bug fixes,” BioWare wrote on <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/dragon-age/dragon-age-the-veilguard/news/patch-1-0-0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">the game’s website</a>. “We’ll also be supporting the game with additional patches in the future to help make your playing experience even better.”&nbsp;</p>



<h6>RELATED: <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/dragon-age-remaster-unlikely-creative-director-says/">Dragon Age Remaster Unlikely, Creative Director Says</a></h6>



<p>You can check out the full patch notes below via EA.</p>



<h2 id="h-dragon-age-the-veilguard-patch-notes">Dragon Age: The Veilguard Patch Notes</h2>



<h3>N7 Day Content:&nbsp;</h3>



<ul>
<li>Rook can find a new N7 day appearance in the Lighthouse. This is a cosmetic only armor.</li>
</ul>



<h3>Bug Fixes:</h3>



<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where DLSS options could end up “grayed-out” on a 40-series Nvidia GPU. (PC Only)</li>



<li>Eliminated the cause of a small number of crashes. (PC Only)</li>



<li>Updated XeSS version to 1.3.1. (PC Only)</li>



<li>Fixed an issue where some customizations were not applied to the Inquisitor correctly in one of the ending scenes.</li>



<li>Fixed a bug that caused Companion Skill Points to reset.</li>



<li>Adjusted Companion Approval notifications so they remain on-screen longer as scenes end.</li>



<li>Harding now has arrows in her quiver and is ready for battle.</li>



<li>Global banter should no longer start too early.</li>



<li>Harding and Taash banter no longer repeats indefinately.</li>



<li>Fixed potential issues that could occur if a player fast traveled during a quest.</li>



<li>Changing your party members on the way to certain quests no longer breaks the camera for in-world missions.</li>



<li>Updated a number of assets to improve visual performance over long distances.</li>



<li>Fixed several distance “pop-ins” on level art assets.</li>



<li>Added collision to several assets that were missing it.</li>



<li>Fixed a minor texture issue with codex art.</li>



<li>Added haptics to a number of interactions and events.</li>



<li>Fixed lip sync in some ambient scenes.</li>



<li>Adjusted audio balance on several assets.</li>



<li>Changing equipment no longer disables helmet voice processing.</li>



<li>Fixed several objective markers that were spawning improperly.</li>



<li>Cleaned up certain interactions between Skills that caused them to not behave as described.</li>



<li>Apparitions generated by Iron Veil will now attack Razikale.</li>



<li>Entropic Spheres now behave properly on vertical surfaces.</li>



<li>Fixed a bug where Taunt would sometimes be cleared early, which caused enemies to ignore it.</li>



<li>Fixed a rare issue where Rogues would not hold their bow while aiming down sights.</li>



<li>Made the detailed-stats screen more readable.</li>



<li>Balance changes made to certain fights to match design intent.</li>



<li>Balance adjustments made to several player skills.</li>



<li>Fixed leashing exploits on major encounters.</li>



<li>The Rage Demon’s Ring of Fire should now be appropriately dodgeable in all situations.</li>



<li>Slowed down the speedy raven in Hossberg.</li>



<li>Adjusted creepy corpse movement while they moved on/off-camera.</li>



<li>The Dalish elf in the Unwanted Guests quest is now an actual elf.</li>



<li>Fixed a rare blocking issue in the Sea of Blood quest.</li>



<li>Halla should no longer float during the In Entropy’s Grasp quest.</li>



<li>Fixed a blocking issue in the Pinnacle of Its Kind quest.</li>



<li>Adjusted timing on epilogue text cards.</li>



<li>NPC necks no longer grow unexpectedly.</li>



<li>Corrected instances where NPCs would not properly look at each other or at Rook.</li>



<li>Long hair should now properly mesh with certain armor.</li>



<li>Fixed several issues with makeup in character creation.</li>



<li>Venatori crystal VFX should now disappear properly.</li>



<li>Added scroll wheel support to the sell screen.</li>



<li>Opening the journal while on the map no longer causes it to continue scrolling.</li>



<li>The Faction Achievements will now be gained properly upon reaching max Faction Strength instead of the Faction Cap.</li>
</ul>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-receives-a-ps5-pro-enhanced-mode/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-receives-a-ps5-pro-enhanced-mode/">God of War: Ragnarok Receives a PS5 Pro Enhanced Mode&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>God of War: Ragnarok’s patch 6.00 introduces PS5 Pro Enhanced features, new gameplay options and bug fixes. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-177-weapons/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-177-weapons/">Warzone Will Soon Have 177 Weapons, Most of Them Useless</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Soon enough, Warzone will have a staggering 177 weapons to choose from, which is just far too many. Which weapons do you use?</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gears-of-war-e-day-dimaggio-and-ferro/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gears-of-war-e-day-dimaggio-and-ferro/">John DiMaggio and Carlos Ferro Return in Gears of War: E-Day</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The original voice actors for Marcus Fenix and Dom Santiago will be returning in Gears of War: E-Day, it has been revealed.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-ranked-play-everything/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-ranked-play-everything/">Everything You Need to Know About Black Ops 6 Ranked Play</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Black Ops 6 Ranked Play is being added to the game from November 14 – here’s everything you need to know about the mode.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[God of War: Ragnarok Receives a PS5 Pro Enhanced Mode]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-receives-a-ps5-pro-enhanced-mode/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/god-of-war-ragnarok-receives-a-ps5-pro-enhanced-mode.1030257/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-ragnarok-receives-a-ps5-pro-enhanced-mode/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>God of War: Ragnarok now has the PS5 Pro Enhanced label, with ver 6.00 going live today. The new patch also introduces some new gameplay options and bug fixes.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-god-of-war-ragnarok-ps5-pro-features">God of War: Ragnarok PS5 Pro Features</h2>



<p>God of War: Ragnarok has a new PS5 Pro Enhanced Mode, providing Favour Quality mode features while running at 60 FPS. High Frame Rate mode will have an unlocked frame rate on monitors with variable refresh rates. The Favour Performance mode from the base PS5 receives a boost on the Pro. Lastly, a PSSR upscale option is available in addition to Temporal Anti-Aliasing.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-reduced-puzzle-hints-in-ragnarok-nbsp">Reduced Puzzle Hints in Ragnarok&nbsp;</h2>



<p>God of War: Ragnarok’s <a href="https://support.sms.playstation.com/hc/en-us/articles/31642737345293-Patch-Notes-v-06-00" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">update 6.00</a> will introduce a Reduced Puzzle Hints option, decreasing the number of times the companion provides a hint while solving puzzles. Moreover, a new accessibility option that adds audio descriptions to all game cinematics was added in the same patch.</p>



<h2 id="h-bug-fixes">Bug Fixes</h2>



<p>God of War: Ragnarok’s patch 6.00 also arrives with bug fixes. Firstly, an issue where Brock would not path correctly to the shop in Freyr’s camp was fixed. Also, an issue where Hilts could not be crafted if crafted before an NG+ run was fixed. Lastly, Special Resources required for crafting Hilts cannot be sold now, and if sold by accident, the items will drop again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, the God of War TV Series is “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/god-of-war-tv-series-redone/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">starting from scratch</a>” as executive producers have left. Also, games like <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/no-mans-sky-has-an-8k-at-30-fps-mode-on-the-ps5-pro/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">No Man’s Sky</a>, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/stellar-blade-pr5-pro-features/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stellar Blade</a> and <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/baldurs-gate-3-receives-4k-native-and-60-fps-on-the-ps5-pro/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Baldur’s Gate 3</a> received their PS5 Pro updates today. What are your thoughts on God of War Ragnarok’s PS5 Pro Enhanced Mode?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mass-effect-tv-series-officially-in-development-at-amazon/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the Mass Effect TV series officially being developed at Amazon</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard Adds Free Mass Effect Items For N7 Day; Here's How To Unlock It]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-adds-free-mass-effect-items-for-n7-day-heres-how-to-unlock-it/1100-6527639/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard-adds-free-mass-effect-items-for-n7-day-heres-how-to-unlock-it.1030254/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-adds-free-mass-effect-items-for-n7-day-heres-how-to-unlock-it/1100-6527639/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527639">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>Mass Effect fans know that November 7 has been designated by BioWare as N7 Day to celebrate the franchise. And while a new Mass Effect game is still likely years away, this year's N7 Day includes some Mass Effect content that you can find in BioWare's latest title, <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/reviews/dragon-age-the-veilguard-review/1900-6418294/" data-ref-id="1900-6418294">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a>.</p><p>There are three items that can be found, all of which reference Commander Shepard from the original Mass Effect trilogy:</p><ul><li>Command Helmet</li><li>Paragon of Leadership</li><li>Specter of Battles Past</li></ul><p>These N7 pieces are just cosmetic, so don't expect the armor to have any stats. The good news is that it's extremely easy to find this free content drop. After players finish The Singing Blade mission within the main quest, the Mass Effect armor will be waiting in a new chest located beside the Caretaker in the Lighthouse. If you've already beaten The Singing Blade and the chest isn't there, exit the game and make sure it's been updated. The chest should be there when you resume play.</p><p>Unfortunately for Dragon Age fans, BioWare recently confirmed that <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-not-getting-expansions-team-shifts-to-next-mass-effect/1100-6527554/" data-ref-id="1100-6527554">The Veilguard won't get any story expansion DLC</a> because the team is now focused on the next Mass Effect game. But if <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-streamer-spent-almost-a-whole-day-making-sure-her-rook-was-a-smokeshow/1100-6527593/" data-ref-id="1100-6527593">the numerous create-a-character options in The Veilguard</a> are any indication, Mass Effect's next title will give players even greater control over their character's appearance than before.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mass Effect TV Series in Development at Prime Video with Fast and Furious 9 Writer]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/mass-effect-tv-series-in-development-at-prime-video-with-fast-and-furious-9-writer/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mass-effect-tv-series-in-development-at-prime-video-with-fast-and-furious-9-writer.1030245/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/mass-effect-tv-series-in-development-at-prime-video-with-fast-and-furious-9-writer/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>It's been nearly three years since Deadline first <a href="https://wccftech.com/mass-effect-tv-series-deal-nearly-completed-by-amazon-says-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reported</a> that Amazon was closing on a deal to adapt Mass Effect into a TV series for its Prime Video channel. Today, Variety <a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/mass-effect-tv-series-amazon-writer-marvel-1236203755/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">says</a> that the deal is finally done, featuring Daniel Casey as the writer and executive producer of the show. Casey is known primarily for the screenplay of 2018's Kin, a sci-fi feature film, and 2021's Fast &amp; Furious 9. Neither of which were exactly masterpieces, unfortunately.</p>
<p>Anyway, Variety also reports that Karim Zreik will executive produce under his Cedar Tree Productions banner. Ari Arad and BioWare's Michael Gamble will also executive produce. Zreik has worked on several successful TV series, such as Jericho and a plethora of Marvel shows (Jessica Jones, Daredevil, Luke Cage, Iron Fist, The Defenders, Runaways, The Punisher, The Gifted, Cloak &amp; Dagger, Legion, and Helstrom). Ari Arad has produced several feature film adaptations, such as 2004's The Punisher, 2007's Ghost Rider, 2008's Iron Man, 2017's Ghost in the Shell, 2022's Uncharted, and 2024's Borderlands. Finally, Michael Gamble is a BioWare veteran who has worked on every Mass Effect game since the second. He is also leading the project for the next game installment and recently <a href="https://wccftech.com/mass-effect-next-will-stay-photorealistic-and-mature-confirms-executive-producer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">commented</a> that it would retain the photorealistic style and mature tone of the previous entries.</p>
<p>No details are currently available on the plot or on the casting. For Prime Video, this is yet another gaming adaptation. They've had massive success with Bethesda's Fallout, of course, and they also <a href="https://wccftech.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza-is-a-live-action-tv-adaptation-of-the-game-series-due-this-october-on-amazon-prime-video/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> Like a Dragon: Yakuza last month. Amazon has two more heavy hitting gaming TV series on the way: <a href="https://wccftech.com/god-of-war-tv-series-officially-coming-from-amazon-prime-video/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">God of War</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/tomb-raider-series-confirmed-to-be-coming-to-amazon-prime-video/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tomb Raider</a>.</p>
<p>As for Mass Effect, today is N7 Day, so it's a good day for fans to get this near-announcement. There won't be much else, given that BioWare has just <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/dragon-age-the-veilguard-biowares-back/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">released</a> Dragon Age: The Veilguard, beyond a return of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/no-mans-sky-adds-cross-save-brings-back-mass-effects-normandy-on-n7-day/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">collaboration with No Man's Sky</a>.</p>

				

			
	<div>
		<h2>Products mentioned in this post</h2>
		
		<!--<p class="story-notice text-center">The links above are affiliate links. As an Amazon Associate, Wccftech.com may earn from qualifying purchases.</p>-->
	</div>

			
			

		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dragon Age: The Veilguard’s First Patch Brings Mass Effect Crossovers And Bug Fixes]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-patch-adds-mass-effect-crossover-1851692503</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/dragon-age-the-veilguard%E2%80%99s-first-patch-brings-mass-effect-crossovers-and-bug-fixes.1030236/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-patch-adds-mass-effect-crossover-1851692503<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="" data-id="e95cbf15d56a784f716de0df3eb32fab" data-recommend-id="image://e95cbf15d56a784f716de0df3eb32fab" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Rook is shown wearing the N7 Day Mass Effect armor." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="Rook is shown wearing the N7 Day Mass Effect armor." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->BioWare / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="e95cbf15d56a784f716de0df3eb32fab" data-recommend-id="image://e95cbf15d56a784f716de0df3eb32fab" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="Rook is shown wearing the N7 Day Mass Effect armor." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><div><p>We already knew <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-4-review-dreadwolf-rook-action-rpg-1851681954&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-4-review-dreadwolf-rook-action-rpg-1851681954"><em>Dragon Age: The Veilguard</em>’s</a></span> first patch was coming this week, but since it landed on N7 Day, it also came with a few surprises. The fantasy RPG is one of BioWare’s more polished games, but even so, there are plenty of bugs for the team to squash, based on the patch notes it just put out.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="195150" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Diablo IV - Bear Bender Build" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="526" data-playlist="195150,195326,196742" data-current="195150"><div><p>Diablo IV - Bear Bender Build</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195150/195150_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195150/195150_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195150/195150_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/195150/195150_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"><track kind="captions" label="English" src="https://kinja.com/api/videoupload/caption/20607.vtt" srclang="en"></video><div><ul><li data-label="">Off</li><li data-label="English">English</li></ul></div></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>The headliners of <em>The Veilguard</em>’s first patch are the addition of a <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-mass-effect-n7-day-armor-location-1851692131&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-mass-effect-n7-day-armor-location-1851692131"><em>Mass Effect</em>-themed armor set</a></span> as part of BioWare’s N7 Day celebrations. The team said it didn’t want to steal <em>The Veilguard</em>’s thunder, so it’s tightlipped on the upcoming fifth game in its science fiction series. But now, your Rook can wear some armor that pays homage to Commander Shepard’s red-and-black fit. On top of this, there’s a series of bug fixes, most notably, the one that caused the Inquisitor, <em>Dragon Age: Inquisition</em>’s protagonist, to show up <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;Internal link&quot;,&quot;https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-patch-notes-custom-inquisitor-face-1851689815&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://kotaku.com/dragon-age-veilguard-patch-notes-custom-inquisitor-face-1851689815">without all the character customization</a></span> players implement at the beginning of the game during some scenes at the final act. The full patch notes read as follows:</p><p><strong>N7 Day Content: </strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Rook can find a new N7 day appearance in the Lighthouse. This is a cosmetic only armor.</li></ul><p><strong>Bug Fixes:</strong></p><ul data-type="List" data-style="Bullet"><li>Fixed an issue where DLSS options could end up “grayed-out” on a 40-series Nvidia GPU. (PC Only)</li><li>Eliminated the cause of a small number of crashes. (PC Only)</li><li>Updated XeSS version to 1.3.1. (PC Only)</li><li>Fixed an issue where some customizations were not applied to the Inquisitor correctly in one of the ending scenes.</li><li>Fixed a bug that caused Companion Skill Points to reset.</li><li>Adjusted Companion Approval notifications so they remain on-screen longer as scenes end.</li><li>Harding now has arrows in her quiver and is ready for battle.</li><li>Global banter should no longer start too early.</li><li>Harding and Taash banter no longer repeats indefinately.</li><li>Fixed potential issues that could occur if a player fast traveled during a quest.</li><li>Changing your party members on the way to certain quests no longer breaks the camera for in-world missions.</li><li>Updated a number of assets to improve visual performance over long distances.</li><li>Fixed several distance “pop-ins” on level art assets.</li><li>Added collision to several assets that were missing it.</li><li>Fixed a minor texture issue with codex art.</li><li>Added haptics to a number of interactions and events.</li><li>Fixed lip sync in some ambient scenes.</li><li>Adjusted audio balance on several assets.</li><li>Changing equipment no longer disables helmet voice processing.</li><li>Fixed several objective markers that were spawning improperly.</li><li>Cleaned up certain interactions between Skills that caused them to not behave as described.</li><li>Apparitions generated by Iron Veil will now attack Razikale.</li><li>Entropic Spheres now behave properly on vertical surfaces.</li><li>Fixed a bug where Taunt would sometimes be cleared early, which caused enemies to ignore it.</li><li>Fixed a rare issue where Rogues would not hold their bow while aiming down sights.</li><li>Made the detailed-stats screen more readable.</li><li>Balance changes made to certain fights to match design intent.</li><li>Balance adjustments made to several player skills.</li><li>Fixed leashing exploits on major encounters.</li><li>The Rage Demon’s Ring of Fire should now be appropriately dodgeable in all situations.</li><li>Slowed down the speedy raven in Hossberg.</li><li>Adjusted creepy corpse movement while they moved on/off-camera.</li><li>The Dalish elf in the Unwanted Guests quest is now an actual elf.</li><li>Fixed a rare blocking issue in the Sea of Blood quest.</li><li>Halla should no longer float during the In Entropy’s Grasp quest.</li><li>Fixed a blocking issue in the Pinnacle of Its Kind quest.</li><li>Adjusted timing on epilogue text cards.</li><li>NPC necks no longer grow unexpectedly.</li><li>Corrected instances where NPCs would not properly look at each other or at Rook.</li><li>Long hair should now properly mesh with certain armor.</li><li>Fixed several issues with makeup in character creation.</li><li>Venatori crystal VFX should now disappear properly.</li><li>Added scroll wheel support to the sell screen.</li><li>Opening the journal while on the map no longer causes it to continue scrolling.</li><li>The Faction Achievements will now be gained properly upon reaching max Faction Strength instead of the Faction Cap.</li></ul></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warzone Will Soon Have 177 Weapons, Most of Them Useless]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-177-weapons/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warzone-will-soon-have-177-weapons-most-of-them-useless.1030233/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/warzone-177-weapons/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>In a blog post highlighting everything coming to Warzone and Black Ops 6 in season one, it was revealed that the battle royale platform will have <strong>177 weapons </strong>for players to choose from. The funny thing is that they’re almost entirely useless as a collective, and players will split their time between just a handful of them.</p>



<p>That collection includes a whopping 33 assault rifles and 30 SMGs.</p>



<p>When is enough enough?</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-too-many-weps">Too Many Weps</h2>



<p>Warzone needs something of a reset. Over the years, games have fused with the Warzone ecosystem and had their weapons pulled into the fray, but as time has gone on, it has become increasingly ridiculous. Now, with the delivery of season one, Warzone will have 177 weapons to choose from.</p>



<p>That breakdown looks something like this:</p>



<ul>
<li>Assault Rifles – 33</li>



<li>Battle Rifles – 10</li>



<li>SMGs – 30</li>



<li>Shotguns – 13</li>



<li>LMGs – 16</li>



<li>Marksman Rifles – 17</li>



<li>Sniper Rifles – 16</li>



<li>Pistols – 17</li>



<li>Launchers – 9</li>



<li>Melee – 15</li>
</ul>



<p>The split includes 60 weapons from Modern Warfare III, 77 from MW II, and 40 from Black Ops 6. At some point, something has to give, because surely keeping up the balancing and maintenance on all 177 weapons is getting a bit tiresome for Activision’s teams.</p>



<p>On November 14, Warzone will also get a new Resurgence map named Area 99, a small-form map inspired by Nuketown. It’s set in the Nevada desert and replicates a top-secret weapons testing facility that was built in the 1950s. It’s almost post-apocalyptic in how it looks, and it should play pretty nicely as well.</p>



<p>Also in the season one update, Urzkistan and Rebirth Island will be returning to the Warzone ecosystem.</p>



<p>Next year, we should have our first return to Verdansk since 2021, which will be a monumental moment for Warzone fans worldwide.</p>



<p>What weapons do you use in Warzone? Let us know in the comments.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gears-of-war-e-day-dimaggio-and-ferro/">John DiMaggio and Carlos Ferro are returning to Gears of War: E-Day</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[John DiMaggio and Carlos Ferro Return in Gears of War: E-Day]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/gears-of-war-e-day-dimaggio-and-ferro/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/john-dimaggio-and-carlos-ferro-return-in-gears-of-war-e-day.1030227/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/gears-of-war-e-day-dimaggio-and-ferro/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>It has been five months since Gears of War: E-Day was revealed at the Xbox Games Showcase, and not much else has been said about the project. Today, The Coalition revealed that both John DiMaggio (Marcus Fenix) and Carlos Ferro (Dom Santiago) will be returning to reprise their characters in E-Day.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-the-glory-days">The Glory Days</h2>



<p>Gears of War surfaced in 2006, and since it dropped, it has spawned several follow-up titles, widely becoming known as one of the best Xbox-exclusive franchises ever created. It has been five years since the last major release in the series, and it could still be a while yet until the next one drops, given that Gears of War: E-Day doesn’t have a release window.</p>



<p>In June, the next game in the Gears of War series was revealed:</p>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Gears of War: E-Day | Official Announce Trailer (In-Engine) - Xbox Games Showcase 2024" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EC20gLfUHeA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>







<p>In a post on social media, the team at The Coalition revealed that both John DiMaggio and Carlos Ferro will be reprising their iconic roles in E-Day:</p>



<blockquote>
<p>On today’s 18th anniversary of Gears of War, we’re proud to share that John DiMaggio and Carlos Ferro are reprising their roles as the iconic voices of Marcus Fenix and Dominic Santiago in Gears of War: E-Day.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It wouldn’t have been right to have anyone else voice them – especially Marcus Fenix. That gravelly, foreboding tone has been instantly recognisable for almost twenty years.</p>



<p>E-Day will be a prequel of sorts, taking players back to the beginning of the storyline that saw the Locust rise up and lay siege to the world of Sera. The first Gears of War game was the closest we got to that part of the timeline, but now we’re going even further back.</p>



<p>Are you looking forward to Gears of War E-Day? Let us know your expectations in the comments.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-ranked-play-everything/">Black Ops 6’s Ranked Play mode</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Call Of Duty's The Replacer Is Becoming A Playable Operator In Black Ops 6]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-dutys-the-replacer-is-becoming-a-playable-operator-in-black-ops-6/1100-6527638/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/call-of-dutys-the-replacer-is-becoming-a-playable-operator-in-black-ops-6.1030224/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/call-of-dutys-the-replacer-is-becoming-a-playable-operator-in-black-ops-6/1100-6527638/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527638">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The centerpiece of Activision's Call of Duty: Black Ops 6 marketing campaign--Peter Stormare's The Replacer--is coming to the game as a playable character in the upcoming Season 1 update.</p><p>The Replacer tracer pack operator bundle comes with two skins for The Replacer, including a standard version and a bonus version for people who own the new Season 1 BlackCell bundle. The package also includes weapon blueprints for guns called Quick Wit and Ramifications, along with the "Aura +5000" animated calling card, the "Many Hats" animated emblem, the "Replacement Killer" finishing move, and a vehicular weapon charm.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4396348-screenshot2024-11-07at2.21.57pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4396348" data-ratio="0.55862068965517" data-width="725" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4396348-screenshot2024-11-07at2.21.57pm.png" data-ref-id="1300-4396348"></a><figcaption>The Replacer comes to Black Ops 6</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1179/11799911/4396348-screenshot2024-11-07at2.21.57pm.png"></figure><p>For the BlackCell version of The Replacer, Activision warned that players need to buy the BlackCell bundle first; the skin won't work if you buy the BlackCell bundle after buying the Replacer bundle. Activision did not announce the price points for any of the new Season 01 store bundles.</p><p>Stormare himself voices The Replacer for this operator bundle.</p><p data-embed-type="video" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gORamyqb1G0" data-width="100%" data-height="100%">          <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/gORamyqb1G0" height="100%" width="100%" scrolling="no" frameborder="" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><p>Activision created more than two dozen Replacer ads for Black Ops 6, featuring Stormare replacing all manner of people, including TV hosts, the Pope, the NFL's Kyler Murray, boxer Canelo Alvarez, podcast host Joe Rogan, and political analysts. You can <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@CallofDuty/videos" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">see all the spots on the Call of Duty YouTube page.</a></p><p>Stormare's The Replacer debuted in 2013 and has been a mainstay for Activision's Black Ops marketing campaigns over the years. The first in the series of commercials for Black Ops 6 featuring The Replacer <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/activision-brings-back-popular-character-for-black-ops-6-marketing-and-he-pretends-to-be-the-pope/1100-6526771/" data-ref-id="1100-6526771">went live during NFL matchups back in September.</a></p><div data-embed-type="tweet" data-src="https://x.com/CallofDuty/status/1854585151059108182" data-has-image="true"><blockquote data-conversation="none" data-mce-disable-toolbar="true"><div dir="ltr"><p>“I’m your daddy now.” – The Replacer</p><p>There’s no substitute for greatness. The Replacer has concluded his whirlwind <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BlackOps6?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BlackOps6</a> takeover tour and has freed up some time to appear in-game. Tracer Pack: The Replacer will be available shortly after Season 01 launch. <a href="https://t.co/oXr2iXybSt" rel="nofollow ">pic.twitter.com/oXr2iXybSt</a></p></div>  — Call of Duty (@CallofDuty) <a href="https://twitter.com/CallofDuty/status/1854585151059108182?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote>              </div><p>The Replacer has even replaced an in-game Call of Duty: Warzone character, Graves, prompting some to theorize Activision would eventually put him in the game--now that's happening. Activision said the Replacer bundle will be available "shortly" after Season 01 begins on November 14.</p><p> In addition to the Replacer bundle, players are getting new maps, modes, and weapons, along with a new Warzone map, Area 99. You can <a href="https://www.callofduty.com/blog/2024/11/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-season-one-mp-zombies-maps-modes-announcement" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">read Activision's extensive blog post</a> to get up to date with everything coming in Season 01.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
  
  
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Mass Effect TV show is blasting off to Prime Video]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/a-mass-effect-tv-show-is-blasting-off-to-prime-video</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-mass-effect-tv-show-is-blasting-off-to-prime-video.1030218/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/a-mass-effect-tv-show-is-blasting-off-to-prime-video<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">BioWare's Mass Effect series is making a relay jump to television.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Per </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/mass-effect-tv-series-amazon-writer-marvel-1236203755/">Variety</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, Prime Video is adapting the series for live-action, with the franchise's executive director </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/GambleMike">Mike Gamble</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> attached as an executive producer. (Gamble, it should be noted, is also directing the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lg-Ctg6k_Ao">untitled fifth game</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> in the series.) Also on hand as executive producer? </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/nintendo-taps-morbius-producer-for-live-action-legend-of-zelda-movie">Avi Arad</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, whose credits include Morbius, the Super Mario film and the upcoming Zelda movie.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Dan Casey, writer of F9: The Fast Saga and 10 Cloverfield Lane, will write and executive produce the series, whose plot details are currently unknown.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Legendary Pictures attempted to make a Mass Effect film in the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100528123610/http://www.heatvisionblog.com/2010/05/mass-effect-video-game-on-way-to-movie-screen.html">2010s</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, which never came to fruition. More recently, it was reported in </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://deadline.com/2021/11/the-wheel-of-time-premiere-ratings-amazon-prime-video-mass-effect-lort-of-the-rings-jennifer-salke-qa-1234879517/">2021</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> that Amazon was looking to develop a show, and no information about it has been made public in the last three years.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Mass Effect has been semi-MIA as a series since 2017's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/production/-i-mass-effect-andromeda-i-single-player-development-comes-to-an-end">Mass Effect Andromeda</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The first three games were re-released for PlayStation 4 and Xbox One back in 2021 as part of an active effort by BioWare to refocus after the collapse of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/bioware-cancels-plans-for-i-anthem-i-rework-shifts-focus-to-i-dragon-age-i-and-i-mass-effect-i-">Anthem's </a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/game-platforms/bioware-cancels-plans-for-i-anthem-i-rework-shifts-focus-to-i-dragon-age-i-and-i-mass-effect-i-">rework</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">While developing </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/dragon-age-the-veilguard-opens-as-bioware-s-best-steam-launch-with-70k-concurrent-players">Dragon Age: The Veilguard</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>, </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">the studio has used November 7 (aka, N7 Day) to annually tease out the </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XefLOWmcFpY">next Mass Effect</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> and reaffirm that the franchise would </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://x.com/bioware/status/1722011793856598386?lang=en">move forward</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"> beyond those remasters. Both franchises are now BioWare's </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bioware-to-offload-i-star-wars-the-old-republic-i-to-refocus-on-single-player-games">core focus</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, since it handed off development of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/business/bioware-confirms-developer-change-for-i-star-wars-the-old-republic-i-">Star Wars: The Old Republic</a></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">to Broadsword.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Interestingly, history repeats itself: Netflix released an animated Dragon Age series prior to </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Veilguard's </span></span><span data-testid="content-text">release (back when it was still subtitled </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Dreadwolf</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">), and here's Prime Video with a Mass Effect show, with a new game somewhere in the stars.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="contributor-summary-subtitle">Contributing Editor, GameDeveloper.com</p><div><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">A Kansas City, MO native, Justin Carter has written for numerous sites including IGN, Polygon, and SyFy Wire. In addition to Game Developer, his writing can be found at io9 over on Gizmodo. Don't ask him about how much gum he's had, because the answer will be more than he's willing to admit.</span></p></div></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mass Effect is Amazon’s next video game adaptation]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/7/24290596/mass-effect-tv-show-amazon-fallout</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mass-effect-is-amazon%E2%80%99s-next-video-game-adaptation.1030209/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/7/24290596/mass-effect-tv-show-amazon-fallout<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>After its success with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24126474/fallout-review-amazon-prime-video"><em>Fallout</em></a> and the recently released <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/25/24278893/amazon-like-a-dragon-yakuza-prime-tv"><em>Like A Dragon: Yakuza</em> show</a>, <em>Mass Effect</em> is the next game Amazon wants to adapt. According to <a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/mass-effect-tv-series-amazon-writer-marvel-1236203755/"><em>Variety</em></a>, a show based on BioWare’s military space opera RPG is officially in production at Amazon MGM Studios. <em>Variety</em> has reported that <em>F9: The Fast Saga </em>writer Daniel Casey has signed on to write the show with BioWare producer Mike Gamble serving as executive produce along with Ari Arad.</p><p>Though BioWare released the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/2/22256806/mass-effect-legendary-edition-pc-ps4-xbox-one-mac-walters-release-date"><em>Mass Effect Legendary Edition</em></a> — a collection of the first three games updated for modern consoles — back in 2021, the <em>Mass Effect</em> series hasn’t had an original entry since the release of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/20/14961928/mass-effect-andromeda-review-xbox-ps4-pc"><em>Mass Effect: Andromeda</em></a> back in 2017. After <em>Andromeda</em>, BioWare released <em>Anthem</em>, a live-service action game that was significant departure from the studio’s tradition of making single-player, story-driven RPGs. In 2020, BioWare announced that a new <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/10/22168973/mass-effect-returns-teaser-trailer-game-awards-2020"><em>Mass Effect</em> game was in-development</a>.</p><p>News of a <em>Mass Effec</em>t TV show comes on what is known as N7 Day, a semi-official, fan-created holiday that celebrates all things <em>Mass Effect</em>. On previous N7 Days, BioWare has teased information about the next game in the series including <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/7/23951253/mass-effect-5-helmets-confirmed">a trailer that possibly suggested the return of fan-favorite protagonist Commander Shepard</a> whose story ended with the original trilogy. Though no story details have been revealed about the show, it’s a pretty safe bet to guess it’ll focus on the Commander and I personally can’t wait to see <em>her.</em></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mass Effect TV Series Officially in Development at Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/mass-effect-tv-series-officially-in-development-at-amazon/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mass-effect-tv-series-officially-in-development-at-amazon.1030194/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/mass-effect-tv-series-officially-in-development-at-amazon/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>According to a report by <a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/mass-effect-tv-series-amazon-writer-marvel-1236203755/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Variety</a>, the Mass Effect franchise is receiving a TV adaptation at Amazon MGM Studios. Daniel Casey from F9: The Fast Saga will write and executive produce the series. Karim Zreik, Ari Arad, and Michael Gamble from EA will join as executive producers. At the moment, the plot details haven’t been revealed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mass Effect TV’s Karim Zreik has experience with Marvel TV shows like Daredevil, The Punisher, and more. Ari Arad has worked on other game adaptations, such as Borderlands, Uncharted and more, along with Marvel Movies like Iron Man.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mass Effect is a third-person shooter franchise set in a distant future, where humans and aliens have colonised the Milky Way. Microsoft Game Studios previously published the game series, which EA later acquired.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The main series features four titles: Mass Effect (2007), Mass Effect 2 (2010), Mass Effect 3 (2012) and Mass Effect: Andromeda (2017). The original trilogy follows the journey of Commander Shepard as the character tries to save the galaxy from the hands of the Reapers. Andromeda was unrelated to the trilogy and featured a new setting and fresh characters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Mass Effect 5 is <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mass-effect-5-veterans/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">currently being developed by trilogy veterans</a>. Also, Mass Effect fans should have <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/mass-effect-fans-should-have-low-expectations-for-n7-day-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">low expectations for N7 Day 2024</a>. What are your thoughts on the Mass Effect TV series?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or our new&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/new-weapons-black-ops-6-coming/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">every new weapon in Black Ops 6 Season One</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every New Weapon in Black Ops 6 Season One (and How to Get Them)]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/new-weapons-black-ops-6-coming/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/every-new-weapon-in-black-ops-6-season-one-and-how-to-get-them.1030191/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/new-weapons-black-ops-6-coming/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-67470">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Black Ops 6 is getting a stacked roadmap for season one. It all starts on November 14, and Treyarch has well and truly outdone itself in preparing a sumptuous content drop. There are seven new weapons and new attachments coming to Black Ops 6 from November 14, with some dropping midway through the season just to stagger things a little.</p>



<p>Without further ado, here is every new weapon coming in Black Ops 6 season one.</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-guns-guns-guns">Guns, Guns, Guns</h2>



<p>There are seven major weapons being added to Black Ops 6 in season one, but they won’t all be easy to obtain. Some will only be available to unlock during special events, while others will be battle pass rewards – so you’ll need to grind a little to get to them.</p>



<p>Here’s the full breakdown of new weapons in Black Ops 6 with a note on how to unlock them:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Krig C </strong>(AR) – Battle Pass unlock</li>



<li><strong>SAUG</strong> (SMG) – Battle Pass unlock</li>



<li><strong>SIRIN 9MM </strong>(SMG) – Event unlock</li>



<li><strong>Power Drill </strong>(Melee) – Event unlock</li>



<li><strong>Maelstrom </strong>(Shotgun) – Event unlock</li>



<li><strong>Cleaver </strong>(Melee) – Mid-season unlock</li>



<li><strong>AMR MOD 4 </strong>(Sniper Rifle) – Mid-season unlock</li>
</ul>



<p>And here are the two new attachments coming to the game:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Buffer Weight Stock</strong></li>



<li><strong>Dragon’s Breath</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>That’s right, Treyarch is adding <strong>Dragon’s Breath </strong>to Black Ops 6. In case you’ve never heard of that, it’s the incendiary shotgun attachment that turns each shot into a blast of pure heat, lighting your enemies up in a ball of fire.</p>



<p>There are also two new conversion kits coming: XM4 and Kompakt 92 Burst Fire.</p>



<p>Treyarch has promised that there’s more to come as the season unfolds, so this might not be it.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-ranked-play/">Black Ops 6 Ranked Play is coming on November 14</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-ranked-play/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-ranked-play/">Black Ops 6 Ranked Play Starts Next Week</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Black Ops 6 is getting Ranked Play from November 14, per the season one update from Treyarch. Get the full story here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prop-hunt-black-ops-6/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prop-hunt-black-ops-6/">Prop Hunt is Coming Back to Call of Duty on November 14</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Prop Hunt is coming to Black Ops 6 on November 14 with the season one update. Get the full scoop on the mode here.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warhammer-40000-darktide-drops-for-ps5-this-december/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/warhammer-40000-darktide-drops-for-ps5-this-december/">Warhammer 40,000: Darktide Drops for PS5 This December&nbsp;</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Warhammer 40,000: Darktide releases for PS5 on December 3, 2024. Check out the pre-order details, game editions and more. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-replacer-operator-black-ops-6/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-replacer-operator-black-ops-6/">The Replacer Will Be In a Black Ops 6 Tracer Pack From November 14</a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>The Replacer is being added to Black Ops 6 as a playable skin in a new tracer pack that’ll surface in the game from November 14.</p>
                    </div>

                                                </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Black Ops 6 Ranked Play Starts Next Week]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-ranked-play/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/black-ops-6-ranked-play-starts-next-week.1030188/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/black-ops-6-ranked-play/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Competitive fans are celebrating as Treyarch announces the impending arrival of Ranked Play in Black Ops 6. It’s bizarre that it’s surfacing before the Call of Duty League’s 2025 season has been formally announced but never mind.</p>



<p>From November 14, Ranked Play will be live in Black Ops 6, giving the more talented players a place to flex their abilities. Let’s just hope it doesn’t end up like Modern Warfare III and have the Top 250 ranks overflowing with cheaters, right?</p>



<hr>



<h2 id="h-where-will-you-rank">Where Will You Rank?</h2>



<p>Treyarch revealed the roadmap for season one of Black Ops 6 and Warzone, all of which kicks off on November 14.</p>



<p>There’s a stacked content drop coming, including new maps, a fresh Resurgence experience, new modes (including Prop Hunt), and a massive host of new weapons. It’s an exciting time to be a Call of Duty fan, and hopefully, you’ve finished your Dark Matter grind in time to pick up everything that season one has to offer.</p>



<p>It’ll be as typical a competitive system as you could hope for.</p>



<p>It’s good to see that Activision has learned from past mistakes. In previous games, Ranked Play didn’t arrive for several months. Last year’s Call of Duty – Modern Warfare III – was released in October, but Ranked Play didn’t arrive until February. That was an insane gap that left ambitious fans hungry for a bigger challenge, and it harmed the game’s ecosystem to no end.</p>



<p>Will you be diving into Ranked Play when it arrives? Let us know in the comments.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming coverage, check out the news that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/prop-hunt-black-ops-6/">Prop Hunt is coming back to COD</a></p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    Subscribe to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8BitDo's New Full-Sized Keyboards Are Up For Preorder]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/8bitdos-new-full-sized-keyboards-are-up-for-preorder/1100-6527630/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/8bitdos-new-full-sized-keyboards-are-up-for-preorder.1030185/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/8bitdos-new-full-sized-keyboards-are-up-for-preorder/1100-6527630/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">

      
                    
  
              <header id="masthead"><nav></nav></header>      
                            <div id="site-wrapper" role="main">
          <div id="default-content">
        
          <p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p>
  
    <article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6527630">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>8BitDo has released some great keyboards, but so far, they've all been tenkeyless (TKL) models that don't include a traditional numpad (although these are <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Supports-Calculator-Bluetooth-Gaming-Console/dp/B00PN9S6JU?tag=gamespot-primeday-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">sold separately as add-ons</a>). However, that's about to change as 8BitDo is finally launching full-size models of its Retro Keyboards based on its popular<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKXH5WCD?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="nofollow "> NES</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKXDH8BG?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="nofollow ">Famicom</a>-inspired designs. Priced at $120 each, they'll be available starting December 12.</p><div title="6527630 - 8BitDo Full-Size Retro Keyboards Preorders" data-embed-type="buylink" data-ref-id="2803" data-template="4" data-size="buylink__listicle" data-title="6527630 - 8BitDo Full-Size Retro Keyboards Preorders" data-collection="">             <h2>                    <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKXH5WCD?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DKXH5WCD?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKXH5WCD?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">8BitDo Full-Size Retro Mechanical Keyboards</a>       </h2>                                   <h3>                      <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKXH5WCD?tag=gamespot-preorders-20" rel="sponsored nofollow" target="_blank" data-event-tracking="{&quot;destUrl&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/www.amazon.com\/dp\/B0DKXH5WCD?tag=gamespot-preorders-20&quot;,&quot;dwLinkTag&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;,&quot;leadType&quot;:&quot;deal&quot;,&quot;linkLocation&quot;:&quot;BuyButton&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;seamlessScrollPage&quot;:&quot;1&quot;,&quot;searchDim&quot;:&quot;listicle|button&quot;}" data-track-page-event="{&quot;eventName&quot;:&quot;Monetization Link Clicked&quot;,&quot;merchantName&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;merchantPrice&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-vars-buy-link="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DKXH5WCD?tag=gamespot-preorders-20">$120 | Release December 12</a>         </h3>                                                                                                                      <p>While the design is inspired by console classics, the hardware itself is pretty modern. With these keyboards, you're getting a 108-key layout, V2 Kailh Box white switches, dye-sub PBT keycaps, hot-swappable PCB for easy key switch replacement, and support for N-key rollover. Like other 8BitDo products, these keyboards can also be heavily customized using the company's in-house Ultimate Software program, or if you're in a hurry, fast-mapping on programmable buttons won't require booting up the 8BitDo client.</p>                      </div><p>These also support wireless connections via 2.4GHz and Bluetooth as well as wired via USB-C, and the included Super Buttons are a pair of big microswitch keys that can be customized to serve a wide selection of functions. The form factor on these keyboards are also very ergonomic, as the contoured design makes them feel great to work on. If they're anything like the smaller models, these will work great on not only Windows and Android devices, but also wirelessly on iOS, Mac, and Steam Deck.</p><hr><h2>More 8BitDo Keyboard Deals</h2><p>Alternatively, you can grab the current TKL models as well, as these are available in a wider selection of retro-inspired designs. In addition to the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Keyboard-Bluetooth-Swappable-Gaming-Console/dp/B0CCP8KYGG?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">NES</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Keyboard-Bluetooth-Swappable-Gaming-Console/dp/B0D4QB5HMZ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Famicom</a>-influenced models, you can pick up keyboards sporting old <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Keyboard-Bluetooth-Swappable-Gaming-Console/dp/B0D4QB5HMZ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">IBM</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Keyboard-Bluetooth-Swappable-Gaming-Console/dp/B0CYSQWYZP?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Commodore 64</a> aesthetics. You can also pick up the 8BitDo N30 wireless mouse at a discounted price, as this is on sale for $19.80 (normally $30). While it has a barebones design, it includes a customizable D-Pad on the side--something you won't find on other wireless mice. Check out even more 8BitDo keyboard deals below.</p><h3>8BitDo Mechanical Keyboards</h3><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Keyboard-Bluetooth-Swappable-Gaming-Console/dp/B0CYSQWYZP?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo C64 Edition Retro Mechanical Keyboard</a> -- $90 ($<strike>110</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Keyboard-Bluetooth-Swappable-Gaming-Console/dp/B0D4QB5HMZ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo Fami Edition Retro Mechanical Keyboard</a> -- $100</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Keyboard-Bluetooth-Swappable-Gaming-Console/dp/B0CCP8KYGG?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo NES Edition Retro Mechanical Keyboard</a> -- $90 ($<strike>100</strike>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Keyboard-Bluetooth-Swappable-Gaming-Console/dp/B0D4QB5HMZ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo IBM Edition Retro Mechanical Keyboard</a> -- $100</li></ul><h3>8BitDo Numpad Add-ons</h3><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Supports-Calculator-Bluetooth-Gaming-Console/dp/B00PN9S6JU?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo C64 Mechanical Numpad</a> -- $40.49 ($<del>45</del>)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Supports-Calculator-Bluetooth-Gaming-Console/dp/B0D4QGX9QB?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo Fami Mechanical Numpad</a> -- $45</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Supports-Calculator-Bluetooth-Gaming-Console/dp/B0D4QPC1GG?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo M Mechanical Numpad</a> -- $45</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mechanical-Supports-Calculator-Bluetooth-Gaming-Console/dp/B0D4QC8R4P?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo NES Mechanical Numpad</a> -- $41.39 ($<del>45</del>)</li></ul><h3><strong>8BitDo's Wireless Mouse</strong></h3><ul><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/8Bitdo-Wireless-Mouse-Windows-macOS/dp/B07ZH874DQ?tag=gamespot-promos-20" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">8BitDo Wireless N30 Mouse</a></li></ul><div data-embed-type="pinbox" data-ref-id="4304">  <ul>                              <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-disc-drive-is-sold-out-at-most-retailers-but-walmart-has-it-for-now/1100-6526391/">PS5 Pro Disc Drive Is Sold Out At Most Retailers, But Walmart Has It (For Now)</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/ps5-pro-preorders-live-at-amazon-walmart-and-best-buy/1100-6526406/">The PS5 Pro Is Available Now And Eligible For One-Day Delivery At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/zelda-games-on-sale-for-great-prices-tears-of-the-kingdom-for-45-echoes-of-wisdom-for-50/1100-6527148/">Zelda: Tears Of The Kingdom And Echoes Of Wisdom Get Stellar Discounts</a></li>                          <li>         <span>+ Show More More Gaming, Tech, and Entertainment Deals &amp; Preorders Links (5)</span>       </li>          <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/dragon-age-the-veilguard-collectors-edition-preorders-available-ahead-of-this-weeks-launch/1100-6525830/">Dragon Age: The Veilguard Collector's Edition In Stock On Launch Day For PS5 And Xbox</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/special-edition-lord-of-the-rings-trilogy-4k-gift-set-releases-this-holiday-preorders-live-at-amazon/1100-6527414/">Lord Of The Rings 4K Gift Set Releases This Holiday, Comes With One Ring Collectible</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/targets-exclusive-shadow-the-hedgehog-lego-set-is-discounted-just-weeks-after-its-release/1100-6525229/">Target's Exclusive Shadow The Hedgehog Lego Set Is Discounted Just Weeks After Its Release</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/new-lego-super-mario-and-peach-starter-sets-get-first-discounts-at-amazon/1100-6525381/">New Lego Super Mario And Peach Starter Sets Get First Discounts At Amazon</a></li>                         <li><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/elden-ring-official-art-books-are-b1g1-50-off-at-amazon-get-both-for-only-59/1100-6527378/">Elden Ring Official Art Books Are B1G1 50% Off At Amazon - Get Both For Only $59</a></li>   </ul> </div>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                              
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/108490194306897153177?rel=author">Darryn Bonthuys</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article>

    
  

</div>
                      <meta itemprop="seamless-content-list-items" data-list-items="[{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527594&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/horis-official-steam-controller-is-up-for-preorder-at-amazon-ahead-of-holiday-release\/1100-6527594\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527551&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/best-preorder-deals-for-2024-macbook-pro-mac-mini-and-imac\/1100-6527551\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527547&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/fortnite-servers-are-down-when-will-fortnite-servers-be-back-up-for-remix-chapter-2\/1100-6527547\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527608&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/criterion-collection-blu-rays-are-50-off-at-amazon-for-a-limited-time\/1100-6527608\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527563&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cod-black-ops-6-teaser-reveals-new-mp-maps-for-season-1\/1100-6527563\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527558&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-pokemon-monopoly-includes-cute-figures-releases-just-in-time-for-christmas\/1100-6527558\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527555&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/assassins-creed-shadows-will-introduce-a-new-direction-for-its-modern-day-story\/1100-6527555\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527584&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/amazon-b1g1-50-off-game-sale-includes-new-releases-for-switch-ps5-and-xbox\/1100-6527584\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527189&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/the-new-ipad-mini-is-already-100-off-at-amazon-but-probably-not-for-long\/1100-6527189\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527610&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/one-of-the-most-popular-books-for-aspiring-game-designers-is-getting-a-new-edition\/1100-6527610\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527528&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/arcade1up-limited-edition-pac-man-cabinet-new-countercade-available-at-amazon\/1100-6527528\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527501&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/new-super7-godzilla-minus-one-collectible-toy-roars-to-life\/1100-6527501\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527185&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/8bitdos-new-wireless-n64-controller-works-on-analogue-3d-nintendo-switch-and-pc\/1100-6527185\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6526406&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/ps5-pro-preorders-live-at-amazon-walmart-and-best-buy\/1100-6526406\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527586&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/these-budget-friendly-arcade-cabinets-are-perfect-holiday-gifts\/1100-6527586\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6476419&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/free-games-epic-games-store\/1100-6476419\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6465178&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/assassins-creed-odyssey-update-adds-new-game-plus\/1100-6465178\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527593&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/dragon-age-streamer-spent-almost-a-whole-day-making-sure-her-rook-was-a-smokeshow\/1100-6527593\/&quot;},{&quot;guid&quot;:&quot;1100-6527587&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;\/articles\/cod-black-ops-6-and-warzone-season-1-start-date-and-details\/1100-6527587\/&quot;}]">
            </div>
              
    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mass Effect is officially getting a TV adaptation at Amazon]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effect-is-officially-getting-a-tv-adaptation-at-amazon</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mass-effect-is-officially-getting-a-tv-adaptation-at-amazon.1030179/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/mass-effect-is-officially-getting-a-tv-adaptation-at-amazon<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

    <div>
        

        <p>With Fast &amp; Furious 9 writer onboard.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/mass_effect_brighter.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>BioWare / Mass Effect</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div>



            <p>
It's been a good few years since reports surfaced Amazon was looking to adapt <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/mass-effect">Mass Effect</a> for television, but finally - as N7 day rolls around once more - the show has been made official.
</p>
<p>
A Mass Effect TV show was first touted back in 2021, when former BioWare lead writer Mac Walters explained various factors has contributed in the company <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/bioware-explains-why-the-mass-effect-movie-fell-by-the-wayside">shifting its initial vision of a movie adaptation toward something for the smaller screen</a>. Later that same year, reports surfaced claiming <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/amazon-nearing-a-deal-for-mass-effect-tv-series">Amazon was "nearing a deal" for a Mass Effect TV series</a>, as part of its ongoing push into sci-fi and fantasy storytelling.
</p>
<p>
And now those reports have been confirmed. Variety <a href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/mass-effect-tv-series-amazon-writer-marvel-1236203755/">says</a> a Mass Effect TV series is now officially in development at Amazon, with Fast &amp; Furious 9 (AKA F9: The Fast Saga) scribe Daniel Casey on writing and executive producer duties. Casey isn't a complete stranger to sci-fi, having previously written 2018 movie Kin and done rewrites for 2016's 10 Cloverfield Lane.
</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Let's Play Mass Effect Legendary Edition PS5 Gameplay - CHECKING OUT THE FIRST HOUR OF EACH GAME!" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lVU4QsuxGWU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Let's Play Mass Effect Legendary Edition PS5 Gameplay - CHECKING OUT THE FIRST HOUR OF EACH GAME!</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lVU4QsuxGWU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/lVU4QsuxGWU?autoplay=1">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Eurogamer's Ian Higton players Mass Effect: Legendary Edition.<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lVU4QsuxGWU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>
Also executive producing are Karim Zreik, EA's Michael Gamble, and Ari Arad, who's served as producer on everything from the <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/uncharted">Uncharted</a> movie and last year's terrible Borderlands adaptation, to the Spider-Verse series and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/legend-of-zelda-film-releases-some-time-within-this-decade-so-thats-something">Nintendo's upcoming Zelda film</a>.
</p>
<p>
Beyond that, details of Amazon's Mass Effect adaptation are limited, but we do know ardent gamer and former Witcher Henry Cavill at one time had an interest in the project. Back in February 2021, Cavill was <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/henry-cavill-teases-secret-project-that-appears-to-be-related-to-mass-effect">snapped alongside a script</a> apparently related to Mass Effect; then in December that year, not long after Amazon was said to be nearing a deal, Cavill casually <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/henry-cavill-would-love-to-discuss-being-in-the-mass-effect-tv-series">revealed</a> he'd "love to have a conversation" about it. However, with Cavill now <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/henry-cavill-reportedly-set-to-star-in-a-warhammer-40k-series-at-amazon">confirmed to be involved with Amazon's Warhammer adaptation</a>, it's likely things have change.
</p>
<p>
One person probably <em>not</em> excited about a Mass Effect TV series is ex-Bioware lead writer David Gaider, who <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/former-bioware-writer-mass-effect-tv-show-cringe">previously said</a> the idea of BioWare television adaptations made him "cringe".
</p>
<p>
"For starters, Mass Effect and Dragon Age had a custom protagonist," he explained. "Meaning said TV show will need to pick whether said protagonist will be male or female. Boom, right off the bat you've just alienated a whole bunch of the built-in fan base who had their hopes up... Secondly, those protagonists are designed to be a bit of a blank slate, one that the player fills out with their decisions. That's not going to work for a passive medium. So, suddenly, the protagonist will have their own personality... and their own <em>story</em>. That will be weird."
</p><p>
"Both Mass Effect and Dragon Age's plots were, at best, serviceable," he continued. "Those plots had to take into account the player's agency. They were kind of the shell upon which that player's emotional engagement was delivered - usually through the companions and the choices themselves. Choice heightened engagement. Interactivity was the star, not the plot."
</p>
<p>
"Take all that out, lose most of the companions, and you potentially end up with... a pretty run-of-the-mill fantasy or science-fiction show, one where a lot of the built-in audience has possibly been turned into outraged, howling malcontents before it's even released."
</p>
<p>
Amazon has, of course, already navigated similar issues with this year's <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/fallout">Fallout</a> TV adaptation, and that ended up releasing to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/fallout-review">significant acclaim</a> and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/amazons-fallout-tv-show-was-watched-by-65m-people-in-its-first-two-weeks">commercial success</a>. So time will tell if Gaider's concerns prove warranted.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Warhammer 40,000: Darktide washes onto PS5 in December]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/07/warhammer-40000-darktide-washes-onto-ps5-in-december/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/warhammer-40-000-darktide-washes-onto-ps5-in-december.1030164/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/11/07/warhammer-40000-darktide-washes-onto-ps5-in-december/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Warhammer 40,000: Darktide, the grimdark sci-fi successor to Fatshark’s popular <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/03/25/vermintide-2-review-worth-playing-2022-warhammer-games/">Vermintide</a> series, is coming to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PlayStation 5</a> on 3rd December, the studio has announced.</p>
<p><iframe title="Warhammer 40,000: Darktide - Coming to PS5 December 3 | Announcement Trailer" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8_XqYUfiY7Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>Darktide on PS5 will have all of the content and improvements made to the game since the PC launch, and on top of that comes with the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ps5-pro">PlayStation 5 Pro Enhanced</a> marker. That means you’ll see the following performance targets:</p>
<ul>
<li>Frame rate of 60 FPS on a 4K resolution for PlayStation 5 Pro</li>
<li>Performance mode (60FPS on a 1440p resolution) for PlayStation 5</li>
<li>Quality Mode (30FPS on a 4K resolution) for PlayStation 5.</li>
</ul>
<p>The PS5 version will likely be a pretty close match to the game on Xbox Series X, but there’s naturally that further step available for the game when playing on PS5 Pro that matches Sony’s vision for the best of both worlds between Quality and Performance modes.</p>
<p>Darktide first launched for PC in November 2022, but was met with no small amount of negativity from the Vermintide community over performance, bugs and the game progression in general. <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2023/01/25/warhammer-40k-darktide-xbox-release-delayed-as-developer-focusses-on-improvements/">Fatshark postponed the Xbox Series X|S release in order to address those problems</a>, eventually launching the game on console in October 2023. Now, whether there was an exclusivity contract or not, the game is coming to PS5.</p>

<p>Warhammer 40,000: Darktide sees you joining a team of Inquisitorial Operatives, embarking on a series of missions, attempting to free a city from the clutches of the corrupted forces of Chaos. The twist is that, where you might expect to be a loyal member of the Space Marines in most 40K games, you’re actually a criminal given a chance at redemption after saving the life of an Imperial Guard officer from Chaos worshippers. That means that you won’t have all the best weapons and gear that you’d see in something like <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/09/04/space-marine-2-review-warhammer-40k/">Space Marine 2</a>, so there’s still a fair bit of melee combat alongside the gunplay.</p>
<p>We rather enjoyed the game, with Dom saying in <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2022/12/19/warhammer-40000-darktide-review/">our review</a>, “Darktide is an absolute blast. Its heavyweight blend of melee and gunplay ensure that the flow of frantic runs into the hive city just keep on coming.”</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>