<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:03:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Styx: Blades of Greed Won’t Be For Everyone, But That’s Okay – Hands-On Preview]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/styx-blades-of-greed-wont-be-for-everyone-but-thats-okay-hands-on-preview/</link>
            <guid>1397266</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p>Over the years, the Styx series has become the series for those looking for involving stealth gameplay. Cyanide's hardcore approach to stealth mechanics prevented the series from being popular among audiences that weren't the stealth games fanatics, but it's undeniable that this approach, combined with a dark fantasy setting and a chatty, irreverent main character, made the series what it is.</p>



<p><a href="https://wccftech.com/styx-blades-of-greed-gamescom-hands-on-preview-not-for-the-faint-of-heart/"><strong>After having had the chance to try out Styx: Blades of Greed</strong></a>, the next entry in the series, <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-style-link dracula-processed" href="https://wccftech.com/styx-blades-of-greed-delayed-out-of-2025-now-set-to-arrive-in-february-2026/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">now set to launch this February on PC and consoles</strong></a>, I couldn't help but notice how Cyanide wasn't going to compromise on its hardcore approach to widen the series' appeal. The contrary, actually. </p>



<p>While Styx continues to be the likeable goblin rogue he has always been, everything else has been expanded considerably, with an open-world setting with sandbox features that provides new challenges, but also new tools to dispose of surprisingly attentive enemies that leave no stone unturned if they believe to have spotted something suspicious. This early build was unsurprisingly a little rough around the edges, but the experience's potential was evident.</p>



<p>Last month, I was given a second chance to try out Styx: Blades of Greed before its release. While in terms of content this new build wasn't different from the one I tried during Gamescom 2025, except for a new intro sequence teaching the game's basics while setting up the story, the prior experience (and the more relaxed testing environment) made me appreciate even more the focus on verticality, and the sandbox design of the Slums, where the build's main mission takes place.</p>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Styx-Blades-of-Greed-January-Hands-On-Gameplay.jpg"></a></figure>



<p>As part of this build's main mission, Styx is supposed to talk with a drunken dwarf who is staying at a nearby tavern to recover the Zeppelin. With little knowledge of the game mechanics, in my Gamescom 202 test, I went through the tavern's main door, using every opportunity to distract enemies to make it to the dwarf's room, with some difficulty, as the enemies have solid AI that makes them smarter than your usual enemy in non-stealth-focused games. However, now knowing where the room is, I took a completely different approach. </p>



<p>Taking advantage of the map's verticality, I climbed the tavern from the outside, making sure to crouch under windows to avoid enemies spotting me. This approach provided not only a different experience but also highlighted how the sandbox design of Styx: Blades of Greed will allow players to complete missions in any way they like.</p>



<p>The second part of the mission, which involved taking down all enemies in a somewhat closed-off location with an intricate design with multiple passages between rooms, likewise showed how many options are at Styx's disposal to take enemies out, even without using any of the special abilities that can be learned via the different skill trees or new tools like the grappling hook and the glider. One option I didn't see back in the Gamescom 2025 build is the ability to poison food, which highlights once more how varied the player's approach can be to clear missions.</p>



<p>Besides being able to appreciate better what Styx: Blades of Greed tries to do, the new build also showcased a higher degree of polish over the Gamescom 2025 demo, with little to no visual and gameplay glitches. Unfortunately, I can't really evaluate the game's performance, as the preview was conducted via cloud streaming; however, things felt smooth enough, even with multiple characters on screen.</p>



<p>While I don't expect Styx: Blades of Greed to set the market on fire, as its hardcore stealth approach is still going to leave anyone who isn't a stealth game fanatic frustrated, the new entry in the series by Cyanide seems to evolve the series' formula considerably, providing a sandbox stealth experience that works incredibly well with its wealth of options. </p>



<p>As such, I am looking forward to seeing what the game will offer beyond what I have already experienced twice, and whether the map and encounter design will hold up as well as they do in these missions when it launches on February 19 on PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X, and Xbox Series S.</p>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/styx-blades-of-greed-wont-be-for-everyone-but-thats-okay-hands-on-preview/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomba! Special Edition Switch 2 Version Shadowdropped by Limited Run]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tomba-special-edition-switch-2</link>
            <guid>1397263</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Limited Run Games has shadowdropped a version of remastered platformer <em>Tomba! Special Edition </em>on Switch 2, and it comes complete with a host of improvements specific to the platform as well.</p><p>As revealed by Limited Run on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/limitedrungames.com/post/3mboiujxgzj2x" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">Bluesky</a>, <em>Tomba! Special Edition</em>'s Switch 2 version features "increased resolution", "improved performance", and "higher quality assets", as well as a "downsampled display mode". If you've got a Switch 2, this sounds like the perfect way to experience the game.</p><p>Unfortunately, it doesn't look like owners of the game on Switch 1 will get any kind of upgrade or even a discount, at least according to a <a href="https://x.com/Senator_Cthulu/status/2008168415274385672" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">couple</a> of <a href="https://x.com/TheOnlyGamerLP/status/2008168668165734542" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">users</a> in Limited Run's replies on X. Limited Run itself has been quiet about whether there's an upgrade or not, so it's safe to assume you'll have to buy this one again.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption><em>Tomba! Special Edition </em>is now available for Switch 2.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>If you're not familiar with <em>Tomba!</em>, it's a rather curious game from the halcyon days of the original PlayStation, having launched in Japan in 1997, followed by a release in America and Europe the following year.</p><p>The game is essentially a Metroidvania platformer that follows the titular Tomba, a feral child who must defeat a battalion of pigs in order to recover a sacred bracelet belonging to his grandfather.</p><p>To do so, he'll have to explore a large non-linear map filled with areas to explore in both the foreground and background, as well as quests to complete in the course of exploration.</p><p>Since release, <em>Tomba!</em>, which was released as <em>Tombi! </em>in Europe, has attracted a cult following, leading to the launch of a sequel, <em>Tomba! 2: The Evil Swine Return</em>, in 1999. The sequel netted itself a release for modern systems, including the Switch 2, in December last year.</p>
<p>You can check out <em>Tomba! Special Edition </em><a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/tomba-special-edition-switch-2/" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">right now on Switch 2</a>. Stay tuned for more.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/tomba-special-edition-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The best tech announced at CES 2026 so far]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/854159/ces-2026-best-tech-gadgets-smartphones-appliances-robots-tvs-ai-smart-home</link>
            <guid>1397260</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="zephr-anchor"><p>Ahead of the CES show floor officially opening on Tuesday, January 6th, many companies have already announced new tech, gadgets, concepts, and AI-powered upgrades that will be released over this year.</p><p>Yesterday’s CES Unveiled event delivered even more announcements and reveals. If you’re already struggling to keep on top of all the news coming out of the show, we’ve rounded up some of the best hardware and upgrades that have debuted so far. But there’s still more to come, so you can check back here every day, or catch up on all of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/836627/ces-2026-news-gadgets-announcements"><em>The Verge</em>’s CES 2026 coverage here</a>.</p><div><p><cite>Photo: Allison Johnson / The Verge</cite></p></div><p>First <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/835525/samsung-z-trifold-announcement-us-availability">announced last month</a>, <em>The Verge</em>’s Allison Johnson finally got some hands-on time with the Galaxy Z TriFold that uses a pair of inward-folding hinges to expand from a chunky phone to a large tablet. For now it’s only available in Korea, but the Z TriFold is expected to be available in the US sometime in Q1 2026 for what will most likely be a hefty chunk of change. Its biggest selling point, according to Johnson, is the potential to carry around a laptop replacement in your pocket. “The thing that makes the TriFold feel like it could finally be The One — the one device you can carry around, leaving all others behind — is none other than DeX. On the TriFold, DeX isn’t just a desktop environment when you pair it with an external display. It’s a whole standalone mode with windowing to your heart’s content.”</p><p>If you always seem to remember what groceries you need <em>after</em> you get home from the store, GE Appliances’ new package-scanning fridge can help you create a comprehensive shopping list. Launching in April 2026 for $4,899, the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/851934/ge-appliances-smart-fridge-barcode-scanner-tablet">GE Profile Smart 4-Door French-Door Refrigerator with Kitchen Assistant</a> has a scanner on the front you can use to scan empty packages, and you can manually add items to a shopping list using an 8-inch tablet on the door. There’s even a camera inside the fridge you can remotely access through an app to check if you’ve run out of something while you’re shopping.</p><p>Clicks is best known for its <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/617479/clicks-blackberry-keyboard-case-android-motorola-google-pixel-samsung-galaxy-availability">smartphone cases that add a physical BlackBerry-style</a> compact keyboard. Its latest creation has that same keyboard, but also a 4.03-inch OLED screen, front and rear cameras, a headphone jack, and a 5G data connection, and it runs Android 16. The Clicks Communicator is designed to be an alternative to your daily driver smartphone that you can limit to essential apps to minimize distractions. At $499 it’s priced similarly to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/phone-review/646135/google-pixel-9a-review-a-midrange-phone-done-right">Pixel 9A</a>, but <a href="https://clicksphone.com/communicator">you can reserve one now</a> for a limited time to get a discount.</p><p>As TCL and Hisense have done, LG is looking to usurp the dominance of Samsung’s The Frame in the art TV category. Its new LG Gallery TV leverages the <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8836598/type/dlg/https://www.lg.com/global/newsroom/lg-story/beyond-news/how-true-wireless-and-lg-gallery-transform-the-tv-into-a-digital-art-masterpiece/" rel="sponsored">company’s Gallery+ service</a> that launched earlier this year to display everything from art to gaming scenes. The Gallery TV is a mini-LED TV with what is likely a matte coating, but LG describes it as having a “specialized screen that reduces glare and minimizes reflections for an art-like viewing experience.” It comes with a white frame, and while you can purchase additional wood-colored frames, pricing for the LG Gallery TV hasn’t been announced.</p><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/854082/lg-cloid-home-robot-fold-laundry-ces">LG’s CLOiD</a> is a home robot that can potentially do more than just clean your floors. The robot features a pair of articulated arms with seven degrees of motion mounted to a mobile base with a torso that can tilt and bend. LG says CLOiD can perform household tasks like folding and stacking laundry, putting food in the oven, or fetching something from your fridge. Can it do that faster or more reliably than you can? That remains to be seen, but CLOiD could be even more useful as a mobile smart home hub you can converse with as it follows you around the house.</p><p>Samsung’s Family Hub smart fridges aren’t new, but the company will soon be introducing a new feature for added convenience: <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/853758/shut-the-fridge-door">voice-activated door opening and closing</a>. When your hands are full of groceries, or are dirty while you’re whipping up a meal, you’ll be able to ask Bixby to “Shut the fridge door,” or “Open the door,” and it will open over 90 degrees giving you full access. If your mouth is full of food and you can’t properly articulate what you want, the door can also be opened or closed using a tap of your palm or the back of your hand.</p><p>If you pulled a <em>Honey, I Shrunk the Kids</em> on the Las Vegas Sphere, you’d end up with something like <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/853234/switchbot-obboto-ai-globe-desk-light-ces-2026">SwitchBot’s new dome-shaped Obboto RGB desk lamp</a>. It’s wrapped in over 2,900 color-changing LEDs and can display preset animations, animated GIFs, AI-powered “mood animations,” music visualizers, or just the local weather and time if you want to be practical. Pricing and availability haven’t been announced yet.</p><p>Petkit’s new automatic pet feeder that can dole out up to seven days of wet food isn’t just about alleviating guilt about leaving your furry friend behind while you travel. The <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/850992/petkit-ai-camera-yumshare-daily-feast-automatic-wet-food-feeder-eversweet-ultra-fountain">Yumshare Daily Feast</a> uses an NFC tracking system to remove meals that haven’t been eaten in 48 hours and UVC lighting to sanitize the system for delivering fresh ones. What’s potentially even more useful is an AI-powered 1080p night vision camera that tracks when and how much your pet eats to provide insights on their diet and possible health issues. It’s expected to launch in April 2026 and will be sold through pet food companies.</p><p>Six years after its first <a href="https://www.theverge.com/ces/2017/1/4/14155650/lg-oled-4k-tv-w-ces-2017-specs-release-date">Wallpaper TV debuted in 2017</a>, LG has revived the line with its new <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/853886/lgs-wallpaper-oled-tv-returns-to-ces-and-its-wafer-thin">LG OLED evo W6</a>. The TV is 9mm thick thanks to its redesigned internal architecture and features a new mount so it can sit completely flush against a wall. Further improving installation is the W6’s use of LG’s Zero Connect Box which wireless sends a video signal from up to 33 feet away. The only physical cable you need to route to the W6 is for power. It will be available in 77 and 83-inch sizes.</p><p>GameSir may have already clinched the title for weirdest controller at CES 2026. The company shared more details about its upcoming <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/851259/gamesir-switch-turbo-drive-controller-steering-wheel-wireless-force-feedback">Swift Drive gamepad</a> that features a small steering wheel in the middle of the controller. The wheel’s connected to a high-precision Hall effect encoder and an equally small direct drive motor that provides force feedback effects while playing racing games and sims. There are additional haptic motors located in the gamepad’s Hall effect triggers to simulate effects like ABS braking, and it’s got RGB lighting effects that can be synced to your game. Pricing and availability haven’t been revealed yet.</p><p>It’s not quite as adorable as the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/5/24325152/yukai-engineering-mirumi-robot-ces">furry Mirumi robot</a> that debuted at last year’s CES, but <a href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/849367/yukai-engineering-baby-fufu-robot-fan-kids-cooling-ces-2026">Yukai Engineering’s new Baby FuFu</a> is potentially more practical. It looks like a cuddly cat that’s huffing and puffing and features an internal fan that will keep young kids cool while preventing tiny fingers from reaching any dangerous moving parts. It’s expected to arrive in mid-2026 for $50 to $60.</p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li id="follow-author-article_footer-dmcyOmF1dGhvclByb2ZpbGU6MTYw"><span aria-expanded="false" aria-haspopup="true" role="button" tabindex="0"><span><span><svg width="9" height="9" viewBox="0 0 9 9" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" aria-label="Follow"><path d="M5 0H4V4H0V5H4V9H5V5H9V4H5V0Z"></path></svg></span><span>Andrew Liszewski</span></span></span></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.theverge.com/tech/854159/ces-2026-best-tech-gadgets-smartphones-appliances-robots-tvs-ai-smart-home]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ASUS TUF 27″ Gaming Monitor Drops to All-Time Low to Compete With Samsung Odyssey]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/asus-tuf-27-gaming-monitor-drops-to-all-time-low-to-compete-with-samsung-odyssey-2000656520</link>
            <guid>1397254</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Want to add a new monitor to your technology arsenal? Whether you are a serious gamer or someone looking into serious gaming, a good gaming monitor is a key part of your arsenal. We’ve found one that you can both save a significant amount of money on and also experience some fantastically deep immersion with.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5755/">Thanks to Amazon, you can pick up the ASUS TUF Gaming 27” 1440P HDR Monitor for only $179 which is a $70 discount (28% off) compared to the monitors’ normal price of $249.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5755/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A hardy monitor that’s great for any home office or gaming setup</h2>
<p>The ASUS TUF Gaming 27” 1440P HDR Monitor combines a 27” QHD (2560 x 1440) Fast IPS panel with a super-fast 180Hz refresh rate into a monitor designed to bring a high level of smoothness and clarity to your gaming action. A 1ms gray-to-gray response time along with support for HDR visuals help to ensure your games remain clear even as the action increases. Adaptive sync technology can help eliminate stuttering or tearing while maintaining a smooth frame pace so you don’t have to worry about a sluggish picture.</p>
<p>This monitor also has FreeSync Premium and G-Sync compatibility to allow your graphics card to match frame output to the panel’s refresh rate. ASUS’ Extreme Low Motion Blur Sync is a feature that combines with variable refresh rate technology by utilizing backlight strobe to eliminate ghosting while maintaining smooth motion. The result is a clearer picture of fast moving objects, detailed game worlds, and detailed HUD elements when you are panning or tracking around in-game.</p>



<p>The Fast IPS panel used in the monitor can cover 130% of the sRGB color space and support HDR10 content. That means you’ll get brighter highlights, darker shadows, and more vivid colors than a standard SDR monitor. The 2560 x 1440 native resolution also gives more real estate than 1080p.</p>
<p>ASUS also includes GamePlus and GameVisual preset modes, which let you switch between different visual profiles and on-screen overlays optimized for the type of content you are viewing. Using DisplayWidget Center allows you to access and control monitor settings from your computer rather than having to go back and forth switching between on-screen menu options and physically adjusting monitor controls.</p>
<p>When taken together, these specifications combine to make a 27-inch gaming monitor that offers a balance of high-quality QHD resolution, ultra-high refresh rates and helpful customization capabilities at a price that won’t break the bank. So if you’re truly looking for quality that you don’t have to compromise on, this might very well be the monitor you add to your setup. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5755/">At the very least, grab it while it’s discounted because someone in your brood may want it other than you.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5755/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/asus-tuf-27-gaming-monitor-drops-to-all-time-low-to-compete-with-samsung-odyssey-2000656520]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 2025 Steam Awards—All Award Winners]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/2025-steam-awards-all-award-winners/</link>
            <guid>1397251</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-168020">

    <header>
        

        

    </header>

    


    <div>
        
<p>To kick off the new year, Valve has announced the winners of the 2025 Steam Awards. The awards come after weeks of community voting during the recently completed Steam Winter Sale.</p>



<p>This year had 11 awards up for grabs, all of which were chosen by the Steam community. According to Valve, over 43 million votes were cast across all of the available categories. </p>







<p>From Game of the Year to Most Innovative Gameplay and more, there were plenty of great games nominated. But, as always, only a select few could take home the awards. Check out the list of winners along with the finalists for each category. And be sure to leave your thoughts on the games that one down in the comments and join the discussion in the <a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<h2 id="h-the-steam-awards-2025-winners">The Steam Awards 2025 Winners</h2>



<h3>Game of the Year</h3>



<ul>
<li>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</li>



<li>ARC Raiders</li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</li>



<li>Dispatch</li>



<li><strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong – WINNER</strong></li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-vr-game-of-the-year">VR Game of the Year</h3>



<ul>
<li>F1 25</li>



<li>Pavlov</li>



<li><strong>The Midnight Walk – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Emissary Zero</li>



<li>Le Mans Ultimate</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-labor-of-love">Labor of Love</h3>



<ul>
<li>No Man’s Sky</li>



<li><strong>Baldur’s Gate 3 – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Rust</li>



<li>DOTA 2</li>



<li>Helldivers 2</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-best-game-on-steam-deck">Best Game on Steam Deck</h3>



<ul>
<li>BallxPit</li>



<li>Deep Rock Galactic: Survivor</li>



<li>Clover Pit</li>



<li><strong>Hades II – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Digimon Story: Time Stranger</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-better-with-friends">Better With Friends</h3>



<ul>
<li><strong>PEAK – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Schedule I</li>



<li>R.E.P.O</li>



<li>Battlefield 6</li>



<li>Split Fiction</li>
</ul>







<h3 id="h-outstanding-visual-style">Outstanding Visual Style</h3>



<ul>
<li>My Little Puppy</li>



<li><strong>Silent Hill f – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Dream BBQ</li>



<li>DOOM: The Dark Ages</li>



<li>Final Fantasy VII Rebirth</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-most-innovative-gameplay">Most Innovative Gameplay</h3>



<ul>
<li>Blue Prince</li>



<li>Escape From Duckov</li>



<li>Europa Universalis V</li>



<li><strong>ARC Raiders – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Mage Arena</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-best-game-you-suck-at">Best Game You Suck At</h3>



<ul>
<li>Elden Ring Nightreign</li>



<li>Where Winds Meet</li>



<li><strong>Hollow Knight: Silksong – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Marvel Rivals</li>



<li>Path of Exile 2</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-best-soundtrack">Best Soundtrack</h3>



<ul>
<li>Marvel’s Spider-Man 2</li>



<li>Deltarune</li>



<li><strong>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>Rift of the NecroDancer</li>



<li>Tokyo Xtreme Racer</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-outstanding-story-rich-game">Outstanding Story-Rich Game</h3>



<ul>
<li>The Last of Us Part 2: Remastered</li>



<li>Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2</li>



<li>Dying Light: The Beast</li>



<li><strong>Dispatch – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>No, I’m Not A Human</li>
</ul>



<h3 id="h-sit-back-and-relax">Sit Back and Relax</h3>



<ul>
<li>Chill With You: Lo-Fi Story</li>



<li><strong>RV There Yet – WINNER</strong></li>



<li>PowerWash Simulator 2</li>



<li>Slime Rancher 2</li>



<li>Megabonk</li>
</ul>



<hr>



<p>For more Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indie-game-awards-disqualifies-clair-obscur-expedition-33-gen-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 having its award for Game of the Year</a>&nbsp;at the Indie Game Awards stripped over AI usage. And don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-x-chainsaw-man-could-be-the-next-anime-collaboration-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-x-chainsaw-man-could-be-the-next-anime-collaboration-its-claimed/">
                                Fortnite x Chainsaw Man Could Be the Next Anime Collaboration, It’s Claimed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new claim states that Fortnite’s next anime collaboration is with Chainsaw Man. Here’s what you need to know.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-3-will-receive-a-new-dlc-in-may-2026-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-3-will-receive-a-new-dlc-in-may-2026-its-claimed/">
                                The Witcher 3’s New DLC is Expected to Release in May 2026, It’s Claimed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new claim states that The Witcher 3 is expected to receive a new paid DLC by May 2026. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-to-re-release-geforce-rtx-3060-in-q1-2026-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-to-re-release-geforce-rtx-3060-in-q1-2026-its-claimed/">
                                NVIDIA to Re-Release GeForce RTX 3060 in Q1 2026, It’s Claimed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new claim states that NVIDIA will bring back GeForce RtX 3060 GPUs in Q1 2026 to battle the ongoing memory shortage. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sims-4-royalty-and-legacy-final-expansion-pack/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/sims-4-royalty-and-legacy-final-expansion-pack/">
                                The Sims 4: Royalty &amp; Legacy is the Game’s Upcoming 21st Expansion Pack                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>It has been revealed by a South Korean ratings board that the 21st (and final) Sims 4 expansion pack is named Royalty &amp; Legacy.</p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/2025-steam-awards-all-award-winners/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders may have just surpassed over 12m lifetime sales, analyst estimates]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-12-million-sales</link>
            <guid>1397242</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ARC-Raiders-_-Release-Date-Reveal-Trailer-1-25-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ARC-Raiders-_-Release-Date-Reveal-Trailer-1-25-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ARC-Raiders-_-Release-Date-Reveal-Trailer-1-25-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ARC-Raiders-_-Release-Date-Reveal-Trailer-1-25-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ARC-Raiders-_-Release-Date-Reveal-Trailer-1-25-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ARC-Raiders-_-Release-Date-Reveal-Trailer-1-25-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ARC-Raiders-_-Release-Date-Reveal-Trailer-1-25-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ARC-Raiders-_-Release-Date-Reveal-Trailer-1-25-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ARC-Raiders-_-Release-Date-Reveal-Trailer-1-25-screenshot-(1).png?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Embark Studios</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a> may have surpassed 12m sales at the start of 2026, according to video game industry analysts.</p>
<p>According to Rhys Elliot from Alinea Analytics, the game passed the milestone through PC, Xbox, and PS5 sales combined. Alinea also claims that the 4th January was the game's biggest day in terms of daily active users: roughly 3.2 million players across all platforms.</p>
<p>According to Elliot, the cause of this new peak of daily active users stems from a well-timed sale that coincided with the Christmas holidays, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/superhys.bsky.social/post/3mbocqp3vzc2w">writing on Bluesky</a>: "Daily copies sold started to stabilise by early Dec, but a well-timed 20 percent discount across all platforms - and the holiday boost - reversed that."</p>
<figure>
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<figcaption>Watch Eurogamer's Arc Raiders review here!<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oXigyRsVeB0" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Alinea Analytics obviously are not privy to internal data from Embark Studios, but it has made accurate estimates on game sales before. These include <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-may-have-already-sold-25m-copies-according-to-industry-analyst">accurately deducing when Arc Raiders passed 2.5m sales</a>, as well as noting when <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/battlefield-2025">Battlefield 6</a> passed 7m sales only five days after it launched. So while a grain of salt should be taken with such estimates, there's a history of accuracy here.</p><p>Elliot also highlighted other interesting figures from Alinea Analytics estimates of Arc Raiders, including the fact that over 50 percent of players can be found on Steam. Alinea also claims that by passing 12m sales, the game will have made at least over $350m in revenue.</p>
<p>Arc Raiders indeed appears to be maintaining its strong momentum ever since launching last year. <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-was-steams-best-selling-game-over-the-holiday-period">It was confirmed to be the best-selling game over the holiday period</a>, all while new information keeps creeping out about how the popular extraction shooter works, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/yes-aggression-matchmaking-is-now-a-thing-in-arc-raiders">such as its aggressive matchmaking system</a>.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/arc-raiders-12-million-sales]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Arc Raiders has aggression-based matchmaking to push pugnacious PvPers together, but it's "not a full science"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-has-aggression-based-matchmaking-to-push-pugnacious-pvpers-together-but-its-not-a-full-science</link>
            <guid>1397227</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>A little nudge into the sights of someone equally scrap-happy</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-server-issues-free-tokens-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-server-issues-free-tokens-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-server-issues-free-tokens-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-server-issues-free-tokens-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-server-issues-free-tokens-01.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-server-issues-free-tokens-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-server-issues-free-tokens-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-server-issues-free-tokens-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/arc-raiders-server-issues-free-tokens-01.jpg?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Embark</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>If you can't resist taking cheeky potshots at your fellow players in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/arc-raiders">Arc Raiders</a>, the shooter's matchmaking can now neatly shuffle you into a session where you're more likely to get a taste of your own medicine. Developers Embark have confirmed that some "aggression-based matchmaking" has been sprinkled into the game's systems as of late, making PvP-prone players a bit more likely to be funnelled towards each other.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Said confirmation comes directly from the mouth of Embark CEO Patrick Söderlund during a recent interview with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vY3u7wOmm4w">Games Beat</a>. "Obviously first it's skill based, of course," the exec said of how <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-best-guns-tier-list">Arc Raiders</a> handles shifting folks where they need to go to start a game. "Then you have solos, duos, and trios. Also since a week ago or so, we introduced a system where we also matchmake based on...how prone you are to PvP or PvE.</p>
<p>"So, if your preference is to do PvE and have less conflict with players, you'll get matched up [in line] with that [more often]. Obviously, it's not a full science," Söderlund added, before agreeing that it'd be accurate to dub this aggression-based matchmaking.</p>
<p>While the exec was clear this new element is just part of the equation the game turns to when deciding where to shuffle which players, it'll be intriguing to see how folks' willingness to turn their guns on each other being taken into account shapes things going forwards. Söderlund didn't shed any light on how exactly the game measures your PvPness and the exact weight it's given in where you get funnelled - possibly because he was busy playing Arc Raiders as he gave this interview.</p><p>From what he did say, though, it sounds like something simply designed to gently nudge different players towards an experience which mirrors how they play. Whether that's as desirable as filtering by skill level or to shift away folks who show annoying habits like griefing or regularly dropping out of matches at awkward times - <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/gta-online">GTA Online</a> springs to mind in terms of the latter - is the question.</p>
<p>In the short-term, running into less folks gunning for your head might be ideal if you're <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-is-a-good-shooter-but-its-also-where-i-go-for-a-walk-and-relax">keen to keep things a bit more chill</a>. However, in the long run, maybe it'll dull down some of the unpredictability which helps keep any online game - but especially <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/best-fps-games">shooters</a> - feeling fresh. We'll see how things play out.</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/arc-raiders-has-aggression-based-matchmaking-to-push-pugnacious-pvpers-together-but-its-not-a-full-science]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xbox Just Set A Terrible New Record]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/xbox-just-set-a-terrible-new-record-2000656651</link>
            <guid>1397224</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Would Microsoft secretly be happier if people stopped buying the Xbox entirely? Would you risk breaking a $2,000 Samsung Galaxy Z Fold to chase a high score? And why was <em>League of Legends</em> unplayable for so many people over the weekend? You’ve stumbled onto another edition of Morning Checkpoint, <em>Kotaku</em>‘s daily roundup of gaming news and culture.</p> <p>Welcome to the first full week of 2026 where I am obsessed with the idea that the first act in <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> might have been even longer. Creative director Igor Sarzyński <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/srznsk.bsky.social/post/3mbokwdsals27">explains why that would have been a terrible idea</a>. “No it wouldn’t. It’s like saying we should spend more time on Tatooine with farmer Luke before he got involved with all this Jedi stuff.” RIP Jackie.</p>

 <h2>Not selling Xboxes must be intentional at this point</h2> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Sales of Xbox consoles were down 39% in the UK during 2025, making it comfortably the worst year on record for Xbox consoles. With the return of favourite Xbox franchises in 2026, might things improve this year?</p> <p>— Christopher Dring (@Chris_Dring) <a href="https://twitter.com/Chris_Dring/status/2007156688923836635?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 2, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p>The Game Business’ Chris Dring reports that 2025 was “comfortably the worst year on record for Xbox console” sales in the UK. They were down nearly 40 percent from the year prior, which was already far from stellar. I’m not sure how to square Microsoft’s seemingly complete abdication of hardware sales less than five years into the current generation with its promise to continue making consoles in the future.</p>

 <h2><em>League of Legends</em> was completely unplayable yesterday and the reason is very stupid</h2> <p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/leagueoflegends/comments/1q4ao9r/per_vandiril_apparently_the_login_issues_were/">According to YouTuber Vandiril</a>, Riot Games forgot to renew the client security certificate for the hit Moba game. There was a workaround, however. All players had to do to get back into the game was reset their system clock. Maybe it was just the Nexus’ way of telling fans it was time to take a break.</p>

 <h2>Finally, a Flappy Bird made just for folding phones</h2> <blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"> <p lang="en" dir="ltr">Phone companies: We've tested our hinge mechanism for 200,000 folds, so that should cover 5 years of use</p> <p>Users: <a href="https://t.co/jRzjFWB2Hk">https://t.co/jRzjFWB2Hk</a></p> <p>— Marques Brownlee (@MKBHD) <a href="https://twitter.com/MKBHD/status/2007546884794249262?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 3, 2026</a></p></blockquote>  <p><em>Foldy Bird</em> requires you to physically fold your super expensive phone over and over again to keep the bird flying through the familiar <em>Super Mario Bros.</em>-style environment. How neat! I still don’t want one.</p>

 <h2>Sega co-founder David Rosen has passed away</h2>   <p>Rosen was integral to the company’s amusement game operation, including the push into coin-operated arcade games like <em>Periscope</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>Monaco GP</em>, <a href="https://www.replaymag.com/segas-dave-rosen-passes-on-christmas-day-in-l-a/"><em>RePlay Magazine</em> reports</a>.</p>

 <h2><em>Resident Evil 4 Remake</em> originally began with a cut chapter starring Ashley</h2> <p>That’s according to modder Michael “Thekempy” Kemp who combed the game’s files and restored the lost content. “It would have started with Ashley in the woods at night,” Thekempy explained <a href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nXI-MrzgZXU?autoplay=1">in a recent video</a> (via <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/resident-evil-4-remake-cut-an-entire-opening-chapter-that-starred-ashley"><em>Eurogamer</em></a>). “She stumbles upon Los Illuminados in the middle of performing a ritual sacrifice.”</p>

 <h2>Brandon Sanderson’s <em>Mistborn</em> books could become a video game</h2> <p>The prolific fantasy author said multiple AAA game companies have expressed interest in his latest “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nOe7VV5T-hw">State of Sanderson</a>” video (via <em><a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/mistborn/brandon-sanderson-mistborn-game">PCGamesN</a></em>). “I’m trying to do things differently this time, in order to retain control of my videogame rights,” he told fans. “I already have interest from some major players in the videogame industry, who I like a lot. So, if you are a decision-maker at a triple-A studio or a major independent, and you’ve always wanted to make a <em>Mistborn</em> or <em>Stormlight</em> game, you would want to contact my reps now.” If someone bites, maybe we’ll see the actual game by 2032.</p> <h2>ICYMI:</h2> <ul> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/minecraft-donut-smp-server-farm-notch-2000656412">The 10-year journey to falling back in love with <em>Minecraft</em></a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/microsoft-ai-slop-satya-nadella-2000656473">Microsoft wants you to move beyond calling it AI slop</a></li> <li><a href="https://kotaku.com/star-wars-racer-revenge-ps4-ps5-port-hacker-limited-run-2000656482">An obscure<em> Star Wars</em> game is more expensive than ever thanks to a rumored PS5 hack</a></li> </ul> <h2>Watch this:</h2> 
                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/xbox-just-set-a-terrible-new-record-2000656651]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra Gets Cleared Out at Its Lowest Price Ahead of the S26 Series Launch]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-gets-cleared-out-at-its-lowest-price-ahead-of-the-s26-series-launch-2000656572</link>
            <guid>1397218</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Buying a new smartphone can be pricey, especially if you’re going with one that’s still relatively new. But with the deal we’ve sourced, you can get one that’s still well worth using without taking out a second mortgage. You’re likely familiar with it if you’re an Android user: the Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6661/">If you’re interested in changing up what you use for your daily driver phone, you can buy the Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra on Amazon right now for $1,049</a>. That’s $250 (or 19%) lower than the retail price of $1,299.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6661/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A newer smartphone that’s still well worth using</h2>
<p>The Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra comes in a Titanium Silverblue housing that has a massive 6.9″ display, a 5000mAh battery and a built-in S Pen. It also comes with a US 1-year warranty and runs with unlocked Android 15 and One UI 7 out of the box.</p>
<p>Inside, the phone has the Qualcomm Snapdragon 8 Elite processor and 12GB of RAM to make sure you have enough power to run your apps/games/multitask between them. The 256 GB of internal storage means you have enough room for all of your pictures/videos/downloads without having to constantly clear everything out.</p>
<p>For connectivity, you have Bluetooth, NFC, Wi-Fi and USB, so you can pair your accessories, pay for purchases using contactless payment methods and tether with other devices. Samsung’s One UI 7 sits atop Android 15 and utilizes the hardware specs along with AI tools and Samsung’s services.</p>
<p>The built-in S Pen lets you draw, write, and annotate screenshots and navigate their screen with accuracy, while the Always On Display provides access to important information at a glance at any time. Additionally, the high-resolution 2960 x 1440 resolution provides for clear text and images displayed on-screen and provides a lot of space for working in a multi-tasking mode or viewing high-definition video. The dimensions of the phone are 6.41 x 3.06 x 0.32 inches, providing a fairly small frame around the large display.</p>



<p>In terms of the camera capabilities of the Galaxy S25 Ultra, Samsung pushes hard on AI features, specifically on low-light and video recording. Samsung developed an AI Night Mode Camera to brighten dark areas and hold onto detail, so when taking a picture at night or indoors, the image does not immediately become blurry/noisy. Audio Eraser is a tool that can reduce background noise in your recorded videos, and there are a suite of other options you can use as well.</p>
<p>The Now Brief feature is intended to provide you with useful information prior to the time you would normally receive notifications for these same items (e.g. reminders/tasks), to help you keep up with everything going on in your life. Additionally, the Galaxy S25 Ultra is capable of rapid charging (and wireless charging), and the device is water-resistant, adding to its durability for everyday use.</p>
<p>If it’s been long past time to pick up a new smartphone,<a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6661/"> the Samsung Galaxy S25 Ultra is a fantastic choice that you won’t want to miss out on, especially since you can save some serious cash here</a>. Grab it and migrate over.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6661/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/samsung-galaxy-s25-ultra-gets-cleared-out-at-its-lowest-price-ahead-of-the-s26-series-launch-2000656572]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fortnite x Chainsaw Man Could Be the Next Anime Collaboration, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-x-chainsaw-man-could-be-the-next-anime-collaboration-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>1397212</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>A new claim states that Fortnite has already begun work on its next anime collaboration, and it’s none other than Chainsaw Man. </p>



<p>Fortnite is known for collaborating with franchises and properties across all media of entertainment. Some of their most popular collaborations have been anime-related, with the game bringing in characters from Dragon Ball Z, Naruto, <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/fortnites-next-big-anime-collaboration-for-chapter-7-season-1-has-leaked/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Bleach</a>, Jujutsu Kaisen, and more to the island across the years. It seems they will build on this foundation with another highly popular anime, Chainsaw Man. </p>







<h2 id="h-fortnite-x-chainsaw-man-in-the-works">Fortnite x Chainsaw Man in the Works</h2>



<p>The Fortnite x Chainsaw Man collaboration’s claim comes from SamLeaks on <a href="https://x.com/SamLeakss/status/2008156723803254943" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> (formerly Twitter); the leaker had previously accurately revealed the Bleach collaboration. However, no other details were revealed, such as the release window, the included characters, or the mythics. But the players have already started making their character wishlists, with Denji, Makima, Reze, and Power as the top contenders. Some are also praying for Pochita to arrive as a Sidekick in the game. </p>



<p>Epic Games has already gone the OG anime route by bringing in names like Dragon Ball Z, Naruto, and Bleach, with One Piece being the only one remaining from the big 3. However, they have been targetting more recent anime as well, with Jujutsu Kaisen, Kaiju No. 8 and My Hero Academia along with Chainsaw Man expected to join the lineup soon. </p>







<p>In other news, Chainsaw Man’s director was working on a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/chainsaw-man-director-is-working-on-a-new-horror-game-for-roblox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new horror game for Roblox</a> earlier in 2025. Additionally, Shroud has predicted that <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shroud-arc-raiders-fortnite-hot-take/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARC Raiders will be ‘bigger</a> than Fortnite’. What are your thoughts on Chainsaw Man x Fortnite? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-3-will-receive-a-new-dlc-in-may-2026-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Witcher 3 expected to receive a new DLC in May 2026</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/fortnite-x-chainsaw-man-could-be-the-next-anime-collaboration-its-claimed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['The Biggest Discovery in Red Dead Redemption 2 in Years' — Rockstar Fans Uncover Spiderweb Mystery Unnoticed Since Release, and Now the Hunt Is on fo]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-discovery-in-red-dead-redemption-2-in-years-rockstar-fans-uncover-spiderweb-mystery-unnoticed-since-release-and-now-the-hunt-is-on-for-answers</link>
            <guid>1397209</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/red-dead-redemption-2">Red Dead Redemption 2</a> fans are searching for answers to a newly-discovered mystery that's been hidden within Rockstar's cowboy sequel since its original release.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">After more than seven years, a group of Red Dead aficianados recently realized they'd stumbled on something no one had reported previously — a series of mysterious spiderwebs that began spawning on eight telegraph poles throughout the game's vast world, each during a specific hour of the night. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Two weeks on, more clues have now been found, and it's become clear that this is a deliberate secret included by Rockstar within the game, which players are now rushing to uncover the full meaning of.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">Similar to Red Dead Redemption 2's quest involving dreamcatchers (and a familiar spiderweb mystery in GTA 5), players discovered in late December 2025 that these newly-found spiderwebs contain a feather which can be shot free — though the webs themselves only appear for one hour of in-game time each night. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">An initial <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OSQPMaU7yz8" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">video</a> on the mystery by Rockstar fan channel Strange Man credits this discovery to a trio of fans, goldenplaysterraria, pariah87 and u/FL4VA-01, while comments on the video from others say they've checked and discovered this secret really has been there since the game's original launch — all the way back in 2018.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Fast forward to last week, and a fresh <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=taJ8GcB8hD4" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">update</a> detailed a second phase of the mystery's unravelling. Here, players discovered that the various spiderwebs lead to one central web that contained a cryptic direction in its web design: "N" and a symbol for another telegraph pole. Heading north (as directed by "N") leads to another wooden pole which, once found, can be shot at to reveal yet another direction under its bark.</p><output data-cy="article-slideshow"><div data-cy="slideshow-view-trigger"><h3 data-cy="slideshow-preview-title">Red Dead Redemption 2 Screenshots Show Off Rockstar's Epic Open-World</h3></div></output><p data-cy="paragraph">All of that brings us pretty much up to date, and up to a new <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0T4J8LYqUi0" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">video</a> published just yesterday which details where the mystery is at now. Currently, players are following one final cryptic telegraph pole message that depicts a final direction, and the symbol for a guitar. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">Where is this all leading? Players are not sure, but the sense is that there's definitely more to this mystery to solve. Players are now hurriedly searching the Fort Wallace location — which holds the nearest guitars to the mystery's most recent clue — and are mapping every other guitar found in the game, in case it sparks some new revelation.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">With this secret having existed for so long, there's little chance that Rockstar itself is teasing anything big or new at the end. (Though, what a way to reveal single-player DLC this would be!) For Red Dead Redemption 2 fans, though, this is an exciting moment — something new to ponder at last in their beloved game, as the wait for news of a re-release or new content stretches on.</p><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Tom Phillips is IGN's News Editor. You can reach Tom at tom_phillips@ign.com or find him on Bluesky </em><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/tomphillipseg.bsky.social" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tomphillipseg.bsky.social</a></p></section></div><br/><br/>https://www.ign.com/articles/the-biggest-discovery-in-red-dead-redemption-2-in-years-rockstar-fans-uncover-spiderweb-mystery-unnoticed-since-release-and-now-the-hunt-is-on-for-answers]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Code Vein II ‘Walkthrough’ trailer; ‘Character Creator Demo’ launches January 23]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/code-vein-ii-walkthrough-trailer-character-creator-demo-launches-january-23</link>
            <guid>1397206</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PS5</a></li><li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Eight minutes of footage.</span>
      </p></div><div><p><a title="Companies > Bandai Namco Entertainment [6,818 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/bandai-namco-entertainment">Bandai Namco</a> has released an eight-minute “walkthrough” trailer for <em><a title="Games > Code Vein II [10 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/code-vein-ii">Code Vein II</a></em>, as well as <a href="https://twitter.com/BandaiNamcoSEA/status/2008176806294347797" target="_blank">announced</a> that a “Character Creator Demo” will be available starting January 23. <span id="more-1017829"></span></p><p>The “Character Creator Demo” will allow users to create a customized character that can be transferred to the full game, as well as explore Magmell Institute, where both Photo Mode and the hot spring are available to use.</p><figure><a data-featherlight="image" href="https://www.gematsu.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Code-Vein-2-Demo_01-05-26.jpg"></a></figure><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Bandai Namco:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Code Vein II</em> features a deep narrative where players and characters are bound by blood, fate, and destiny, set in a future where the last remnants of humanity and Revenants struggle against a world on the verge of collapse. Following the sudden emergence of a threat known as the <a title="Platforms > Luna [68 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/cloud/luna">Luna</a> Rapacis, Revenants have succumbed to madness, transforming into terrifying creatures called <a title="Genres > Horror [798 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/horror">Horror</a>s. A Revenant Hunter, guided by a mysterious girl named Lou who possesses the power to travel into the past to rewrite the fate of the world. The player, as the Revenant Hunter, will intervene in key moments of history to alter key revenants’ destinies that reveal hidden truths and information to save the future.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>Players will embark on a journey through a world that spans across two eras, where decisions carry weight and every battle tests skill and resolve. <em>Code Vein II</em> features distinctive gameplay for an <a title="Genres > Action RPG [1,919 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/rpg/action-rpg">action RPG</a>, where players use blood drained from enemies to unlock a variety of powerful skills, build strategy for combat with Blood codes, and use unique weapons and equipment called Jails to overcome challenging foes and epic bosses. Players can also forge bonds with powerful Partner allies who fight alongside them and enhance their abilities. Each Partner offers distinct skills and deep narrative connections that shape the journey. Bandai Namco will reveal many more details about the rich universe and game play in <em>Code Vein II</em> in the future.</p><p><strong>Story</strong></p><p>In a future world where humans and Revenants coexist…</p><p>Due to the sudden appearance of the Luna Rapacis, Revenants have transformed into mindless monsters called Horrors. As a Revenant hunter, the player shall halt the world’s inevitable collapse by traveling to the past with a girl called Lou who possesses the power to manipulate time.</p><p>An epic <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,805 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> awaits, where you and your chosen partners explore a vast world, face fierce battles against powerful enemies, and uncover an epic story that transcends time.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li><strong>A Tale Across Time</strong> – Embark on a journey that spans both the present and the past as you search for clues to prevent the world’s destruction. Alter the fates of key Revenant characters you encounter in the past, while uncovering lost histories and the hidden truths of the world.</li><li><strong>Intense and Satisfying Combat</strong> – Dive into adrenaline-fueled battles where reading enemy moves and mastering your arsenal are key to <a title="Genres > Survival [499 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/survival">survival</a>. Unleash powerful skills, adapt on the fly, and conquer relentless foes in fights that deliver both intensity and triumph.</li><li><strong>Unique Battle System</strong> – <a title="Companies > Experience [212 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/experience">Experience</a> <em>Code Vein II</em>‘s unique gameplay mechanic, where the player drains and acquires blood from enemies to unleash a variety of skills. With the series’ new build system, you can freely customize weapons and skills to suit your own battle styles.</li><li><strong>Powerful Partner Characters</strong> – Explore the world with trusted and powerful allies who can fight alongside you or enhance your abilities. Each partner brings unique abilities and deep connections that shape your journey.</li></ul></blockquote><p><em>Code Vein II</em> is due out for <a title="Platforms > PS5 [11,147 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/playstation/ps5">PlayStation 5</a>, <a title="Platforms > Xbox Series [8,528 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/xbox/xbox-series">Xbox Series</a>, and <a title="Platforms > PC [25,195 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/pc">PC</a> via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2362060/CODE_VEIN_II/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Steam</a> on January 30.</p><p>Watch the trailer below.</p><h2><span>Walkthrough Trailer</span></h2><p><iframe title="CODE VEIN II - Walkthrough Trailer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fgzOuvav6_c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/code-vein-ii-walkthrough-trailer-character-creator-demo-launches-january-23]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Final Fantasy IX character designer Toshiyuki Itahana leaves Square Enix]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/final-fantasy-ix-character-designer-toshiyuki-itahana-leaves-square-enix</link>
            <guid>1397203</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
        </ul>

    
    <p><span>"From here on, I will be working as a freelance illustrator."</span>
      </p></div><div><p>Toshiyuki Itahana, one of the main character designers on <em><a title="Games > Final Fantasy (Pixel Remaster) [12 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/final-fantasy-pixel-remaster">Final Fantasy I</a>X</em>, as well as the character designer on the <em><a title="Series > Final Fantasy [146 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/series/final-fantasy">Final Fantasy</a> Crystal Chronicles</em> and <em>Chocobo</em> series, has left <a title="Companies > Square Enix [5,419 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> to work as a freelancer, he <a href="https://twitter.com/ItahanaT/status/2008164296916910442" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-1017828"></span></p><p>Here is the <a href="https://note.com/itahana/n/n277aa9cc7148" target="_blank">full message</a> from Itahana on his departure:</p><blockquote><p>As I began thinking seriously about preparing myself to continue drawing for many years to come, I decided to leave Square Enix at the end of last year.</p><p>Last year marked a major milestone with the 25th anniversary of <em>Final Fantasy IX</em>, a truly significant event, and I was deeply grateful to see so many people celebrating <em>Final Fantasy IX</em>.</p><p>To everyone who celebrated with us, and to those who visited the exhibitions, shops, and cafes—thank you so very much! (The Osaka collaboration café is still ongoing!)</p><p>With the illustration work and supervision related to the 25th anniversary now complete, I feel a strong sense of accomplishment in having fulfilled the role entrusted to me. At the same time, I felt this was the right moment to draw a line under this chapter and take on new challenges.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>From here on, I will be working as a freelance illustrator and character designer.</p><p>While remaining deeply grateful for all the connections I’ve been fortunate to receive through my work so far, I hope to draw upon my experience and continue creating a wide variety of new artwork.</p><p>At the moment, I’m still finding my way—listening to advice and learning from senior freelance illustrators—but if you happen to come across my work somewhere, I would be truly happy if you could support me.</p><p>To everyone who played the games I worked on at Square Enix, and to all those I had the pleasure of working with over the years, thank you very much. I would like to express my heartfelt gratitude, and I sincerely hope for your continued support in the future.</p><p>May this new year be an exceptionally happy one for all of you.</p><p>Toshiyuki Itahana<br>January 5, 2026</p></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/final-fantasy-ix-character-designer-toshiyuki-itahana-leaves-square-enix]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Code Vein II Tells A Time-Traveling Story That Will Tug On Your Heartstrings]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/code-vein-ii-tells-a-time-traveling-story-that-will-tug-on-your-heartstrings/1100-6537162/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1397200</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537162">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p dir="ltr">The souls-like genre has exploded in popularity since the dawn of From Software's Souls franchise, with multiple companies taking a stab at the format--and some companies taking multiple stabs. Bandai Namco, who publishes FromSoft's Souls games as well as Elden Ring, dropped an anime-style version of the genre in 2019's Code Vein, and now it's back for more in Code Vein II.</p><p dir="ltr">We spent a few hours with the next Code Vein adventure during The Game Awards week, and we came away impressed with its improved combat system and a new and interesting take on the genre's "summon" mechanic, but what surprised us most was an original story that carries some emotional weight. The original Code Vein was a solid first effort, but Code Vein II shows that the franchise may have, pardon the pun, cracked the code.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629230-pylon_exploration1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4629230" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629230-pylon_exploration1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4629230"></a><figcaption>Code Vein II</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629230-pylon_exploration1.png"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">A new code</h2><p dir="ltr">Code Vein II takes place in a world on the edge of ruin, and where humans and Revenants, a human-like species of beings with vampiric abilities, live amongst one another. Our demo picks up in the present, as the effects of the Resurgence--a cataclysmic event that slowly morphs Revenants into mindless beasts--are wreaking havoc on the world.</p><p dir="ltr">A century prior, a group of Revenant warriors tried to seal the Resurgence and save the planet, only to fail and bring on another phenomenon that insteads speeds up the process. Those fallen would-be heroes are trapped around the world, and our hero, with the help of a friend with time-traveling powers, must go back into the past, work with those warriors to figure out how to unlock that which traps them in the present, then come back and defeat them once and for all.</p><p dir="ltr">That's a lot to take in, and if you haven't played the original Code Vein before, you might rightfully assume you've missed something. Mercifully, Code Vein II is taking the Final Fantasy storytelling approach, as this is a standalone tale. Those new to Code Vein can jump in without needing background knowledge, which makes taking in all of the information presented easier.</p><p dir="ltr">Jumping into the game starts with creating a character, and the creator in Code Vein II offers a robust slate of choices for us to dig through. Dozens of skin colors, eye colors, hair styles, hair colors, accessories, and more are available right from the start, creating an experience that those with a creative imagination can sink hours into before even starting the game. Characters also have six attributes--strength, dexterity, mind, willpower, vitality, and fortitude--which can be enhanced by finding special perks called Blood Codes throughout the game.</p><p dir="ltr">After character creation, a small tutorial section offers a few brief moments of exploration, including our character meeting up with the time-traveling friend, and a cutscene establishing the story. We then travel via a sweet motorcycle to the time-travel access point, where we travel back in time to the Sunken Pylon dungeon, link with the fallen hero Josee Anjou, and the meat of the demo begins in earnest.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629229-formae_fallingsun.png" data-ref-id="1300-4629229" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629229-formae_fallingsun.png" data-ref-id="1300-4629229"></a><figcaption>Falling Sun Formae</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629229-formae_fallingsun.png"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">Form(ae)s of combat</h2><p dir="ltr">Once we're dropped into the dungeon, we are immediately presented with a wealth of combat options. Seven main weapons are provided for us to tinker with while in the dungeon, each with their own abilities and attributes. One-handed Swords served as a sort of baseline, as they acted like a standard sword would in any souls-like. Twin Blades allowed for faster strikes, while Greatswords and Hammers dealt massive damage--sometimes even one-shotting foes--with slower, more deliberate attacks.</p><p dir="ltr">The Bayonet was particularly interesting as the long-range weapon of the group, thanks to its allowing me to craft ammo on the fly whenever an opening presented itself, so long as I had the right materials. The floating Rune Blades looked really cool slashing through the air while I punched foes at the same time, though it quickly became clear that they would take more time to learn than the demo allowed--enemies kept getting between the blades and the character, leaving us open to big attacks.</p><p dir="ltr">Each weapon couples with two key components, Formae and Jails, in order to round out your abilities. Formae are weapon-specific abilities, like enhanced attacks, status effects, and more, that can be activated during battle. The Rune Blades, for example, included a Whirling Shredder Formae where the two blades spun like a buzzsaw in front of the character, hitting enemies caught in the circle multiple times.</p><p dir="ltr">Jails, meanwhile, function similarly to Blood Veils in the original Code Vein. Jail attacks are equipped separately from the standard weapons, and are used to drain Ichor from enemies. Ichor is the resource needed to use Formae, so routinely using Jail attacks will keep Formae attacks available for us when needed. Hound was our favorite Jail in the demo, as using it would produce two massive hound heads from either shoulder that would sink their teeth into a nearby enemy, but the massive hand called Ogre and the scythe called Reaper were also fun options.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629232-jos%C3%A9eanjou2.png" data-ref-id="1300-4629232" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629232-jos%C3%A9eanjou2.png" data-ref-id="1300-4629232"></a><figcaption>Josee Anjou in the past.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629232-jos%C3%A9eanjou2.png"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">Partner up</h2><p dir="ltr">As our character has joined with Rosee Anjou in the past, she becomes the poster child for Code Vein II's new Partner mechanic. As the hero meets with more fallen champions of the past, he can build relationships with them by bringing them into battle. The more frequently a hero is selected, the stronger that bond becomes.</p><p dir="ltr">The strength of the bond is most apparent in Link Points (LP), which are visible just below the playable character's health bar. Link Points serve as additional health, and it depletes before the main health bar is affected, which means that the stronger our bond is with Rosee, the more health we will have as we fight. This is a cool way to reward building relationships with characters, and one that's especially welcome in a genre known for its difficulty like the souls-like.</p><p dir="ltr">You can build your relationship with Rosee in one of two ways: Summon and Assimilation. Summoning Rosee adds her to the battlefield, where she can fight enemies on her own and serve as a distraction when we need to heal up or regain stamina. Assimilation adds Rosee's power to your own, leaving us alone on the battlefield, but greatly enhancing our abilities.</p><p dir="ltr">Offering these options is an ingenious way to cater to two different types of souls-like players, those who like summoning help and those who prefer to go it alone, while allowing both the benefits of relationship building. We stuck to Summoning, as we appreciated the distraction Rosee provided during boss fights, but Assimilation is just as valid, as the power boost is certainly worth considering. The Partner system stands out as one of the best new additions to Code Vein II, if only because the development team found a way to include both sides of that "to summon or not to summon" argument.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629233-vsjos%C3%A9e1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4629233" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="3840" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629233-vsjos%C3%A9e1.png" data-ref-id="1300-4629233"></a><figcaption>Josee Anjou in the present.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/3/37852/4629233-vsjos%C3%A9e1.png"></figure><h2 dir="ltr">Fixing the future</h2><p dir="ltr">The demo culminated in two massive boss fights, one in the past and one in the present. The boss in the past was called the Metagen Remnant, a spider-like creature with a human face. This was a tough fight, but one made more bearable thanks to having Rosee on the field as a summoned partner. Rosee drawing the Remnant away so we could get a few extra strikes in was a major part of our victory, even with the disgusting toxic green goop the Remnant would shoot onto the floor when we got in close. Just when we think we're avoiding the Remnant's swipes, green goop hits us with a poison effect; that's a souls-like for you.</p><p dir="ltr">After putting the Remnant down, our character says goodbye to Rosee and returns to the present, where the bindings of the now-monstrous Rosee are unlocked and must be vanquished. This fight is <em>much</em> tougher than the Remnant, and not just because of attack patterns or damage; halfway through the battle, Rosee remembers who we are, and begs us to mercifully end her life as her second phase begins.</p><p dir="ltr">Here is where Code Vein II's emotional weight comes into focus. Each time we go back in time to aid a warrior in their battle with the Resurgence, we will have to return to the present and battle against that very same hero--albeit in a more monstrous form. How will they react? What will they say? In Rosee's case, she shows immense grief for what she has become, and thanks our character for sending her into the afterlife as she fades away. The scene leaves us wondering if every hero will be so understanding, as the demo comes to a close.</p><p dir="ltr">With a separate story, a versatile partner system, and a variety of battle options, Code Vein II is shaping up to be a worthy entry in the crowded souls-like arena. The Formae and Jail system allow players to keep their most powerful attacks handy, while multiple weapon options will let them fight through the Resurgence-ruined world how they see fit.</p><p dir="ltr">Code Vein II is set to launch January 30 for Xbox Series X|S, PlayStation 5, and PC.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/code-vein-ii-tells-a-time-traveling-story-that-will-tug-on-your-heartstrings/1100-6537162/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Code Vein II Preview – Anime Soulslike of Future Past]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/05/code-vein-ii-preview-anime-soulslike-of-future-past/</link>
            <guid>1397188</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The end of the world is nigh in Code Vein II, as the calamitous Luna Rapacis progresses and corrupts the Revenants who had, until this point, been able to live in harmony with mankind. But there’s still time to fix this. With a story that’s somewhere between Quantum Leap and X-Men: Days of Future Past, you need to jump back in time to visit and team up with Revenant heroes of a century ago, looking for a way to reawaken them in the present and stop what’s coming.</p>
<p><iframe title="Code Vein 2 Preview –&nbsp;Anime Soulike of Future Past" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FxZSqlaieMM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Back in 2019, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2019/09/26/code-vein-review/">the original Code Vein</a> brought a whole host of interesting ideas to the Soulslike form, from the ability to jump between character build Blood Codes, to the Partner NPC characters that would fight alongside you throughout. And yes, it came with anime-style graphics too. The Soulslike subgenre already felt pretty full and saturated back in 2019, but now in 2026, it’s bursting at the seams with competition. Bandai Namco’s answer is to take the core of what worked well before, and then bring so, so much more player customisation to the table.</p>


<p>Code Vein II Producer Keita Iizuka explained, “Code Vein belongs to the soulslike genre, but even within the action RPG there are many more genres, for example, exploratory open world games. But there aren’t as clear-cut boundaries as before, I would say. So yes, probably you are right, it’s becoming even more competitive, however because of that, it’s very important for us to really be mindful of our strength. It’s because of their competition that we are more stimulated to create something even better. So that’s something that we have hopefully realised and achieved in this version.”</p>


<p>Take the Partner system in general. It’s still great to have another AI partner there to draw aggro from enemies, dish out some damage of their own, and be ready to revive you with a chunk of their own health should you fall –&nbsp;this Restorative Offering now puts them into a cooldown for a time – but now all of that is optional. This is now branded as Summoning, but you also have the choice to use Assimilation, to absorb you Partner and add their strengths to enhance your powers, stats and abilities. If you found the Partners a touch frustrating to in their behaviours before, then you can sideline them through the whole game now.</p>
<p>Iizuka-san explained, “The reason why we allowed Assimilation is because by just having two characters all the time for every fight, the fighting style became fairly set, so the Partner just takes on a certain role and the player would take a certain role. We wanted to remove that kind of boundary, so that’s why we have created the assimilation mode, to be able to really see the fights from a different angle.</p>
<p>“The emotional arc is an important one. So the characters, you will be able to really spend one-on-one time with them to learn more about their backstories, their emotions, really have very heartfelt conversations. So that’s something that we have really valued.”</p>

<p>You’ll spend time with these characters regardless of how you play. This new world and story sees your protagonist journeying back in time to team up with the Revenant heroes of legend, the Fallen Heroes of the Resurgence, and our hands-on saw us partnering with Josée Anjou back in the day. Battling alongside her through the Sunken City to find a source for the pollution within the Sunken Pylon dungeon that we played. Along the way, there’s various narrative interludes that explore Josée’s character, the relationship she had with her sister and what befell them.</p>
<p>“The preview that you have played focused on Josée’s as her main narrative of her arc,” Iizuka-san said, “but there are other arcs involving other characters, and the scenes that you would be able to experience. With the time travel axis as well, you would be able to go back in time and then meet the characters at different points in their lives, to change the outcome, but also to experience the weight of history as well. So I hope that the players get to enjoy that.”</p>
<p>Putting the narrative focus on a range of characters that aren’t your own is an interesting way to frame the story, especially with the potential to bounce back and forth between time periods, and it also makes sense with just how goofy you can make your custom character. There’s a huge range of visual customisation that lets you fully indulge your more absurdist impulses. Want to wear a top hat with a snowman sticking out the top of it? Well, I certainly did when fiddling with the character creator, and that’s just scratching the surface of what’s possible here.</p>
<div id="attachment_467552"><p id="caption-attachment-467552">Is that a snowman in your hat?</p></div>
<p>“It’s not something that we actively specifically ordered to the developing team […] but the customisation team really took on an active role in coming up with this even further evolved version of the customisation build system,” Iizuka-san told us.&nbsp;“ But something that, as a team, we were very conscious of, is that we wanted to deliver a system that is easy to build, customisable, and that the outcome is always great-looking anime-like characters. So there are many numbers of parts, but always the end result to something that is great. That is something that we want to aspire to create.”</p>
<p>The visual customisation is echoed within the combat builds, again taking the core of the ideas from the original Code Vein and expanding them greatly. The Blood Codes that you apply determine the attributes of your character through six categories, with the equipment and weapons that you then equip putting a burden on these figures, which can lead you to being overburdened and suffer penalties to your play, in turn pushing you to align your choice of weaponry and play style.</p>
<p>Talking about the new possibilities here, Iizuka-san said, “So we have added two new categories into the weapons, as well as two different drain attacks as well, and when it comes to Formae, there are many different varieties that we have added. So by combining them all, there are a lot more that the players could enjoy, so I hope they do.”</p>
<p>You’ll really want to make the most of your Formae abilities (formerly Gifts), the skills that you can use for offence or defence, building up to the Bequeathed Formae as your most powerful ability, summoning a special weapon to your hands to unleash hefty damage. That will require you to have enough Ichor, drawn from enemies by performing Jails (the rebranded Blood Veil) to drain their blood. There’s additional Boosters sprinkled on top for what is a particularly broad and complex system of stats, abilities and synergies for players to find.</p>

<p>It’s this depth of customisation that could end up being Code Vein II’s biggest strength. The Sunken Pylon dungeon felt a little by-the-numbers with its Soulslike structure and fairly samey abandoned, ruined industrial look. There is a more open overworld that can be navigated on a motorcycle, which I didn’t get to play, and I’d be curious to see just how the story handles bouncing between time periods and the character growth. There’s not too long to wait, though, with Code Vein II out later this month.</p>
<p>The opening of 2026 is a busy one for Soulslike fans, and Code Vein II is first in line with a refreshed take on the original’s anime visuals, more extensive character customisation, and a characterful time-travelling tale.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div><br/><br/>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2026/01/05/code-vein-ii-preview-anime-soulslike-of-future-past/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Rings In 2026 by Breaking Player Count Records Once Again]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-concurrent-user-count-record-january-2026</link>
            <guid>1397185</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Steam has rung in the new year by breaking concurrent player count records once again, and it's not just one, either. I'm sure Valve will be thrilled.</p><p>As spotted by <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/morwull.bsky.social/post/3mbm57ds7yk27" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">Bluesky user Alejandro LL</a>, Steam has broken its concurrent user (CCU) count record again, managing to reach a whopping 41.816 million users online at the same time and leaping past <a href="https://www.kitguru.net/gaming/joao-silva/steam-smashes-concurrent-player-record-with-over-41-million-users-online/" target="_blank" data-entity-type="external" rel="nofollow">October's record high</a> into the bargain.</p><p>Not only that, but a new record of users concurrently in games on Steam has been set as well, with that figure reaching almost 13.4 million as compared to March's 13.2 million record. Admittedly, these numbers aren't huge jumps, but they're still the highest on record.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>Steam has broken its concurrent user count record once again.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>As for why the record has been smashed, Valve almost certainly owes that to the ongoing Steam Winter Sale, which ends today at 10am Pacific and which features huge discounts on a number of popular games (as well as smaller discounts on newer or more evergreen titles).</p><p>Since many of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-best-of-2025" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="506dd7fd-a10c-4745-bcb4-ef7cfe0636c8" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">2025's best-selling games</a> on Steam are live-service titles as well, it's not unreasonable to assume that players are flocking to those games over the holiday period, which is probably why the concurrent in-game player count record has been broken too.</p><p>This news comes after what has been a rather checkered year for Steam, with Valve facing challenges from the likes of <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/horses-steam-ban-indie-horror" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="a4a11cd5-8771-4a5c-86ba-ff196e272f59" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Horses </em>developer Santa Ragione</a>, No More Robots' <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/no-more-robots-review-flag-rejection-valve" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="5b8f68ae-5137-4e39-9011-498f4b4b7c21" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">Mike Rose</a>, and <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/vile-exhumed-steam-removed-sexual-content" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="3d619c44-1572-4d4c-9fdf-64af4c3b37db" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow"><em>Vile: Exhumed</em>'s Cara Cadaver</a> over what appear to be contradictory censorship policies that seem to ignore important context.</p><p>With that said, legendary <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/rance-series-coming-to-steam" data-entity-type="node" data-entity-uuid="7bdd01fa-043a-41f0-af9b-a0305684ffa0" data-entity-substitution="canonical" rel="nofollow">eroge series <em>Rance</em></a><em> </em>is about to make its Steam debut, albeit in what will probably end up being a heavily censored form subsidized with a patch downloadable from its publisher's website. Suffice it to say Steam is a successful, yet strange beast.</p><figure role="group">
<article>
  
      
  

  </article>

<figcaption>Steam has faced some interesting challenges this year.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Of course, none of this means that Steam's dominance of the PC gaming market is likely to end anytime soon. Stay tuned for more on this and all other things PC gaming.</p></div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div><br/><br/>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/steam-concurrent-user-count-record-january-2026]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple Goes Full Clearance on MacBook Air (2025 M4, 13″) at Record Low to Make Room for the 2026 Laptop Lineup]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/apple-goes-full-clearance-on-macbook-air-2025-m4-13-at-record-low-to-make-room-for-the-2026-laptop-lineup-2000656510</link>
            <guid>1397176</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Now that its officially 2026, Apple waited no time at all to discount its 2025 model of the MacBook Air. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5068/">Amazon is currently Apple MacBook Air with the M4 chip, priced at just $799—down from the regular $999.</a> This 20% price cut saves you $200, making it one of the deepest reductions since its release last year. It’s a great opportunity to kick off the new year with a powerful, versatile laptop.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5068/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>Everyday Performance</h2>
<p>The 13-inch 2025 MacBook Air remains a top pick for those who want portability without compromising on performance. Weighing just 2.7 pounds and boasting a sleek design, it continues the Air’s legacy of being incredibly lightweight while delivering the power of larger machines. Despite its slim build, it comes with a 10-core CPU, up to a 10-core GPU, and supports up to 24GB of memory. With the new M4 chip, this laptop performs up to twice as fast as the M1 MacBook Air and is up to 23 times quicker than Intel-based versions of the Air.</p>
<p>Apple designed the M4 chip with Apple Intelligence in mind, optimizing the system for faster task execution, efficient information processing, and handling demanding workflows effortlessly. The MacBook Air stays smooth and responsive whether you’re working on reports, editing videos, or managing multiple tabs.</p>



<p>If you’re often on the go and need long-lasting battery life, the MacBook Air delivers. Apple claims it can last up to 18 hours on a single charge, easily getting you through an entire workday. The 12MP front camera, with 1080p video capability, is perfect for virtual meetings, classes, or chatting with friends and family. The three-microphone array ensures crystal-clear sound, eliminating the need for external microphones.</p>
<p>The backlit keyboard makes typing easy in low-light environments, and Touch ID gives you a quick and secure way to unlock your laptop. On the sides, you’ll find two Thunderbolt ports for fast data transfer and connecting peripherals. The MagSafe charging port keeps your power cable securely in place but detaches safely if pulled. Plus, after all these years, Apple has kept the headphone jack in tact—a nice bonus for those who prefer wired audio.</p>
<p>If you’re already part of the Apple ecosystem, the MacBook Air makes it easy to sync with your iPhone, iPad, or other Apple devices via features like AirDrop, iMessage, and Handoff.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5068/">The MacBook Air is discounted in several configurations. The 256GB model is the most affordable, priced at $799</a>. The 512GB version is now $999. For those who need more memory, the model with 24GB of RAM and 512GB of storage is $1,200. Each of these represent a $200 discount from their original list prices. Choose from four stylish colors: sky blue, silver, starlight, and midnight.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/5068/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/apple-goes-full-clearance-on-macbook-air-2025-m4-13-at-record-low-to-make-room-for-the-2026-laptop-lineup-2000656510]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Witcher 3’s New DLC is Expected to Release in May 2026, It’s Claimed]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-3-will-receive-a-new-dlc-in-may-2026-its-claimed/</link>
            <guid>1397170</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p>The Witcher 3: The Wild Hunt is reportedly set to receive new DLC in 2026, developed by Fool’s Theory. </p>



<p><a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-3-rumored-to-get-brand-new-dlc-in-2026-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reports</a> about a new Witcher 3 DLC have been circulating online since June 2025, when it was claimed that the third major expansion for the game would be announced in 2025; however, it never was. New details have now surfaced online thanks to a Polish Noble Securities Analyst, which provide an expected release window for the DLC as well as The Witcher 4. </p>







<h2 id="h-the-witcher-3-s-2026-dlc-will-kickoff-a-proper-marketing-campaign-for-the-witcher-4">The Witcher 3’s 2026 DLC Will Kickoff a “Proper Marketing Campaign for The Witcher 4”</h2>



<p>Spotted by <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/is-there-really-going-to-be-a-2026-witcher-3-expansion" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Eurogamer</a>, Polish Noble Securities Analyst Mateusz Chrzanowski <a href="https://strefainwestorow.pl/analizy/noblesecurities-cdprojekt-wiedzmin-dlc-orion-cyberpunk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">spoke about</a> The Witcher 3’s new DLC releasing in May  2026. Chrzanowski has stated that The Witcher 3’s next paid DLC will arrive in May 2026 and will be developed by Fool’s Theory, who are also working on the Witcher 1 Remake. The new expansion is expected to “kick off the proper marketing campaign for The Witcher 4.” The analyst also predicted that The Witcher 4 will release in Q4 2027. </p>



<p>Eurogamer also followed up on the original source, Borys Nieśpielak, who stated that the information about The Witcher 3’s 2026 DLC has been verified by “several” independent sources. Nieśpielak also pointed to a statement from CD Projekt RED’s recent earnings call, which states that “Given our current progress, there is a chance that new content hinted upon in recent calls and reports may see release in the coming year.” However, CD Projekt RED’s official response states that the company “does not comment on rumour or speculation”. </p>







<p>In other news, The Witcher’s <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/the-witchers-ciri-had-considered-leaving-with-henry-cavill/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ciri considered leaving</a> the Netflix series with Henry Cavill. Additionally, CD Projekt RED has brought on a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/cd-projekt-red-adds-senior-baldurs-gate-3-developer-to-the-witcher-4-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">senior Baldur’s Gate 3 developer</a> to The Witcher 4 team. What are your thoughts on The Witcher 3 receiving a new DLC in May 2026? Leave your thoughts down in the comments, and join the official&nbsp;<a href="https://discord.com/invite/vwj7zdWxaW" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Insider Gaming Discord server</a>.</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nvidia-to-re-release-geforce-rtx-3060-in-q1-2026-its-claimed/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NVIDIA reportedly re-releasing GeForce RTX 3060 GPUs in Q1 2026 to counter memory shortage issues</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.</p>
    

    <div id="ig-app-cta">
          <p><i></i> MOBILE APP</p>
          <h2>Level Up Your Gaming News</h2>
          <p>Real-time news, exclusive podcasts, push alerts, and a better reading experience.</p>
          
          <p><i></i> Available on iOS &amp; Android</p>
        <!-- <div class="ig-note"><i class="fa-solid fa-bolt"></i> Available on Android</div> -->

        </div>

    
    
    </div></div><br/><br/>https://insider-gaming.com/the-witcher-3-will-receive-a-new-dlc-in-may-2026-its-claimed/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tomba! Special Edition now available for Switch 2]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/tomba-special-edition-now-available-for-switch-2</link>
            <guid>1397167</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    <ul>
    <li><a href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a></li>    </ul>

    
    <p><span>Featuring increased resolution, improved performance, and more.</span>
      </p></div><div><p>A <a title="Platforms > Switch 2 [848 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/platforms/nintendo/switch-2">Switch 2</a> version of <em><a title="Games > Tomba! Special Edition [3 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/games/tomba-special-edition">Tomba! Special Edition</a></em> is now available for Switch 2 via <a href="https://www.nintendo.com/us/store/products/tomba-special-edition-switch-2/" target="_blank">Nintendo eShop</a> for $19.99, publisher <a title="Companies > Limited Run Games [222 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/companies/limited-run-games">Limited Run Games</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/LimitedRunGames/status/2008162845356167592" target="_blank">announced</a>. <span id="more-1017816"></span></p><p>Compared to the Switch version, the Switch 2 version features increased resolution, improved performance, higher quality assets, and a downsampled display mode.</p><p><em>Tomba! Special Edition</em> was previously released for PlayStation 5, PlayStation 4, Switch, and PC via <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2851150/Tomba_Special_Edition/" target="_blank">Steam</a>.</p><p>Here is an overview of the game, via Limited Run Games:</p><blockquote><p><strong>About</strong></p><p><em>Tomba!</em> returns in <em>Tomba! Special Edition</em>, the ultimate version of the legendary platforming masterpiece.</p><!-- AD: content -->
        <p>As the titular Tomba, you leap, bite, and throw your way across stunning 2.5D landscapes on a quest to overcome a deplorable cadre of nefarious pigs. Along the way, you’ll explore ancient relics, discover fascinating characters, unlock thrilling quests, and unearth hidden treasures. It’s a platforming <a title="Genres > Adventure [2,805 articles]" href="https://www.gematsu.com/genres/adventure">adventure</a> that perfectly fuses linear and nonlinear gameplay styles.</p><p><em>Tomba!</em> was first published in 1997, and is back today in a vastly-expanded special edition packed with quality of life improvements.</p><p><strong>Key Features</strong></p><ul><li>Save Anywhere! No more worrying about heading back to a checkpoint.</li><li>Rewind! Stuck on a difficult challenge? Try again!</li><li>Toggle for analog control</li><li>A museum crammed with classic print advertisements, original packaging and manuals, never- before-seen dev documents, and high-res original artwork.</li><li>A new remastered soundtrack.</li><li>Interview with the creator, Tokuro Fujiwara.</li></ul></blockquote></div></div><br/><br/>https://www.gematsu.com/2026/01/tomba-special-edition-now-available-for-switch-2]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Last Of Us Season 3 Loses Another Person, Role To Be Recast]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-3-loses-another-person-role-to-be-recast/1100-6537164/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>1397161</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6537164">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>The upcoming third season of HBO's The Last of Us will feature a different actor playing <a href="https://thelastofus.fandom.com/wiki/Manny_(HBO_series)" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">Manny</a>.</p><p>It's been <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/the-last-of-us-season-3-recast-danny-ramirez-1236619442/" data-target="true" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">confirmed by Variety </a>that Danny Ramirez, who joined the show in Season 2, will not return for <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-3-release-date-trailer-cast-story/1100-6534454/" data-ref-id="1100-6534454">Season 3</a> due to scheduling conflicts, with the role to be recast. It remains to be seen what actor may take over the role, however.</p><h2><strong>Spoilers for The Last of Us follow below.</strong></h2><p>Manny is a supporting character in the overall story of The Last of Us. He is a former member of the Fireflies who later joined the Washington Liberation Front. He was part a small group aiding Abby (Kaitlyn Dever) in tracking down and killing Joel (Pedro Pascal) following Joel's massacre at a Firefly hospital where Abby's father was among those murdered.</p><p>Outside of The Last of Us, Ramirez is known for his MCU role as Falcon in Captain America: Brave New World and The Falcon and the Winter Soldier. He's coming back to play the character again in Avengers: Doomsday.</p><p>Ramirez is not the only talent dropping out for Season 3, as Neil Druckmann left the show after Season 2 to <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/neil-druckmann-reveals-why-he-decided-to-leave-the-last-of-us-tv-show/1100-6534673/" data-ref-id="1100-6534673">focus on Naughty Dog's gaming output</a>, including the upcoming release of <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/gallery/intergalactic-the-heretic-prophet-trailer-story-setting-and-everything-else-we-know/2900-6082/" data-ref-id="2900-6082">Intergalactic: The Heretic Prophet</a>. Druckmann worked on the TV series as a co-showrunner, director, writer, and producer.</p><p>The Last of Us Season 3 is <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-3-release-date-trailer-cast-story/1100-6534454/" data-ref-id="1100-6534454">expected to debut in 2027</a>, with its narrative said to be focused on Abby. As for Naughty Dog's video game projects, the studio is making Intergalactic and possibly a second game, which could be <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-last-of-us-3-release-date-trailer-story/1100-6531075/" data-ref-id="1100-6531075">The Last of Us 3.</a></p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>


          
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div><br/><br/>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/the-last-of-us-season-3-loses-another-person-role-to-be-recast/1100-6537164/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo "intentionally held back" many aspects of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom so there was more content for Hyrule Warriors to work with]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-intentionally-held-back-many-aspects-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-so-there-was-more-content-for-hyrule-warriors-to-work-with</link>
            <guid>1397149</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20260105124117-01KE72R4F2ETRQ5FBDXA3RN9Z7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20260105124117-01KE72R4F2ETRQ5FBDXA3RN9Z7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20260105124117-01KE72R4F2ETRQ5FBDXA3RN9Z7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20260105124117-01KE72R4F2ETRQ5FBDXA3RN9Z7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20260105124117-01KE72R4F2ETRQ5FBDXA3RN9Z7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20260105124117-01KE72R4F2ETRQ5FBDXA3RN9Z7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20260105124117-01KE72R4F2ETRQ5FBDXA3RN9Z7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20260105124117-01KE72R4F2ETRQ5FBDXA3RN9Z7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/20260105124117-01KE72R4F2ETRQ5FBDXA3RN9Z7.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>On its release back in 2023, Nintendo kept the Imprisoning War Sages from <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-walkthrough-tips-9343">The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom</a> shrouded in a certain amount of mystery. In fact, despite them playing a fairly key role in terms of the overall backstory, we only saw them in the game very briefly.</p>
<p>That changed in last year's release, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment">Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment</a>, which was set before the events of The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom. Here, the Hyrule Warriors team was able to shine more of a light on the war's Sages, who we now know to be Ardi of the Gerudo, Qia of the Zora, Raphica of the Rito and Agraston of the Goron.</p>
<!-- code from Primis - Eurogamer.net - eurogamer.net -->
<div>
<p><span data-type="targeting">
<span>To see this content please enable targeting cookies.</span>
</span> </p>
</div>
<!-- code from Primis -->
<p>In Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment, players are able to take on the role of each Sage as well as the likes of Princess Zelda and Rauru, as they fight through waves upon waves of bokoblins, Lynels and more.</p>
<p>But, why did Nintendo keep Tears of the Kingdom's Imprisoning War Sages under wraps like it did until the spin-off prequel? Well, director Hidemaro Fujibayashi has now said if the developer had shown the Sages' faces and shared their names before then, the story of The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom "would have naturally grown too much" for the game.</p><p>"In Tears of the Kingdom there was a central theme running through the main story, and the Sages are depicted with their faces hidden by masks and without names," Fujibayashi said in a recent interview with <a href="https://www.4gamer.net/games/898/G089833/20251205029/">4Gamer</a> (translated by <a href="https://nintendoeverything.com/nintendo-explains-why-it-kept-the-imprisoning-war-sages-a-mystery-in-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom/">NintendoEverything</a>). The director then went on to state there were "many things" Nintendo "intentionally held back" for its <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/zelda-breath-of-the-wild-walkthrough-guide-tips-4857">Breath of the Wild</a> sequel.</p>
<p>"If we had shown [the Sages'] personalities and faces, the story would have naturally grown too much," Fujibayashi further explained. "That's why I'm truly happy that the Sages have been more carefully picked up upon here in the Imprisoning War."</p>
<figure>
 


<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Our <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-impressions-review-story-gameplay">Alex took Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment out for a spin</a> ahead of its release, calling it the series' "richest offering yet".</p>
<p>Since its release in November, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/hyrule-warriors-age-of-imprisonment-free-update-adds-more-weapons-and-enemies-to-the-chaos">updates for Hyrule Warriors: Age of Imprisonment have added additional weapons</a>, as well as new Vicious enemies.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/nintendo-intentionally-held-back-many-aspects-of-zelda-tears-of-the-kingdom-so-there-was-more-content-for-hyrule-warriors-to-work-with]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What do you want to happen to the Final Fantasy franchise? You've got a few days to tell Square Enix directly]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/what-do-you-want-to-happen-to-the-final-fantasy-franchise-youve-got-a-few-days-to-tell-square-enix-directly</link>
            <guid>1397146</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    


  <p>

  <figure>
      <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ff14-header_vyTkAPc.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ff14-header_vyTkAPc.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ff14-header_vyTkAPc.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ff14-header_vyTkAPc.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ff14-header_vyTkAPc.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ff14-header_vyTkAPc.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ff14-header_vyTkAPc.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ff14-header_vyTkAPc.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/ff14-header_vyTkAPc.jpg?width=570&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>Eurogamer</cite></span>
        </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p>There are a few series staples you can expect from <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/video-game-franchises/final-fantasy">Final Fantasy</a>: a guy called Cid, moogles, chocobos, that lovely arpeggio motif in the music, and… surveys? If you've been reading this site for a while - or, indeed, following the Final Fantasy series - you'll know that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/companies/square-enix">Square Enix</a> likes to lobby the fanbase to hear our thoughts about the series' identity and future.</p>
<p>The publisher <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-15-survey-hints-at-possible-future-updates">did it for Final Fantasy 15 back in 2017</a>, it did to find out <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/square-enix-polling-final-fantasy-fans-on-moogles-in-ff15">what we all thought about moogles in 2015</a>, Naoki 'Yoshi-P' Yoshida <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/naoki-yoshida-on-dawntrail-criticism-community-feedback-and-the-future-of-final-fantasy-14">regularly uses surveys</a> to poll <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/final-fantasy-xiv-a-realm-reborn">FF14</a> players, and Square Enix <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-16-successfully-expanded-the-series-audience-says-dlc-director">found out that more young people played Final Fantasy 16</a> via a survey in 2024. Keeping with tradition, then, we're seeing the Japanese company once again ask players about the storied series in a poll. And it closes on 9th January.</p>
<p>At the time of writing, we don't really know anything about where the mainline series is going. Yoshi-P said in an interview last year that <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/not-a-clear-cut-answer-whether-final-fantasy-17-will-be-turn-based-says-naoki-yoshida-following-clair-obscurs-success">the team isn't even sure whether the game will be turn-based or not</a> (though we do know, at least, Square Enix wants to keep whatever game comes out of its current work a 'cinematic experience').</p>
<p>If you've got big thoughts about what you want to see - something more turn-based, maybe? Something more in line with <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> or Metaphor Refantazio, perhaps? - then you can <a href="https://questant.jp/q/6K9FPT4N">head on over to the link</a> and have your say about what you'd like to see more (or less) of in the series going forward.</p><p>Personally, I was electrified by the comments Kazutoyo Maehiro, director of the <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/final-fantasy-tactics">Final Fantasy Tactics</a> remake, <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/final-fantasy-tactics-remake-could-open-the-door-to-a-sequel-if-it-sells-well-says-director">made in an interview last year</a>. Basically, he mentioned that if the re-release sold well, then it would "open the door" to a sequel and "prove the business viability of the strategy RPG genre."</p>
<p>There's an open field at the end of the survey where you can leave whatever comments you like. This is where I've opted to pop my interest in more Final Fantasy Tactics-related titles. Feel free to add what you want, but please, keep it civil.</p>

        </div>

  
      </article>



  



  

  <section>
    <span>Related topics</span>

    
  </section>
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.eurogamer.net/what-do-you-want-to-happen-to-the-final-fantasy-franchise-youve-got-a-few-days-to-tell-square-enix-directly]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Wccftech’s Most Anticipated Action Games of 2026 – Martial Artists, Spies, Super Heroes and Criminals]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-action-games-of-2026-martial-artists-spies-super-heroes-and-criminals/</link>
            <guid>1397131</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			
			<p><span>Action games have always been extremely diverse, offering intense experiences to suit the tastes of all sorts of gamers, and after&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-best-action-games-of-2025-a-relentless-year/" target="_blank"><strong>a packed 2025</strong></a>,<strong>&nbsp;2026 is setting out to be an even more diverse year.</strong></span></p>



<p>No matter if you prefer linear intense experiences, super-hero games, stealth games, or immersive open-worlds to lose yourself in, you are sure to find some great games to play in the next 12 months.</p>



<p>Here are our <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">five most anticipated action games releasing in 202</strong>6.</p>



<p><em data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">Other Wccftech's Most Anticipated 2026 Games per genr</em><em>e</em><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_secondary_bg_finder="rgba(38, 42, 43, 0.2)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-all dracula-processed">:</em>&nbsp;<em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-role-playing-games-of-2026-legends-and-legacies/">Role-Playing Games</a></strong></em>,&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-indie-games-of-2026/">Indie Games</a></em></strong>,&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-platformers-of-2026-new-adventures-in-familiar-worlds/">Platformers</a></em></strong>,&nbsp;<strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-dlc-expansion-of-2026/">DLC/Expansion</a></em></strong></p>



<h2 id="h-phantom-blade-zero-september-9-2026-pc-playstation-5">Phantom Blade Zero (September 9, 2026 - PC, PlayStation 5) </h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Phantom-Blade-Zero.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>With its intense action combat and incredible animations, Phantom Blade 0 is looking like the best "pure" action game launching this year</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><em>Phantom Blade Zero</em> made more than a few heads turn when it was <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/phantom-blade-0-is-a-new-unreal-engine-5-powered-dark-action-rpg-coming-to-playstation-5/">revealed in May 2023</a>,</strong> with its distinctive style <strong>blending traditional kung fu with steampunk and cyberpunk</strong>. However, many dismissed it as yet another <strong>soulslike</strong>. Fortunately, <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/phantom-blade-zero-not-soulslike/">this won't be the case</a></strong>.</p>



<p>Edging closer to a more <strong>traditional action game</strong> than a soulslike, the game in development by S-Game is setting out to be <a href="https://wccftech.com/phantom-blade-zero-gamescom-hands-on-preview-setting-up-for-greatness/"><strong>one of the best games of the current console generation</strong></a>, featuring intense action, linear yet articulate level design, exceptional enemy encounter design that forces players to employ every game mechanic effectively, epic boss battles and some of the smoothest animation in video games.</p>



<p>Though in the works by what is essentially an unproven team, <em>Phantom Blade Zero</em> truly has everything to <strong>succeed</strong> when <a href="https://wccftech.com/phantom-blade-zero-slashes-its-way-on-pc-and-playstation-5-this-september/"><strong>it launches this September.</strong></a></p>



<h2 id="h-marvel-s-wolverine-q3-q4-2026-playstation-5">Marvel's Wolverine (Q3/Q4 2026 - PlayStation 5)</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Marvels-Wolverine.jpeg"></a><figcaption><em>Starring one of the most iconic Marvel Comics characters ever, Marvel's Wolverine is set to become one of the most successful action games of 2026</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Following the success of the <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/marvels-spider-man-2-ultimate-incarnation/"><strong><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Marvel's Spider-Man</em> series</strong></a>, Insomniac Games is preparing to branch out with a new game starring <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">one of the most beloved Marvel Comics characters</strong> that shares very little with Peter Parker's and Miles Morales' adventures.</p>



<p>Seemingly <a href="https://wccftech.com/marvels-wolverine-hard-r-not-fully-open-world-2024-2025/"><strong>ditching the open-world</strong></a> of <em>Marvel's Spider-Man</em>, <em>Marvel's Wolverine</em> will take <strong>a third-person action adventure route</strong> where players control the legendary Logan, explore a variety of locations, meet an ensemble cast of Marvel Comics characters, and gruesomely take down enemies using his <strong>superior strength and Adamantium Claws</strong>. With the vehicle traversal and varied locations teased in <strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/marvels-wolverine-new-trailer-provides-first-look-at-gameplay-confirms-fall-2026-release-window/">last year's gameplay trailer</a></strong>, there are plenty of reasons to be excited about the game.</p>



<p>With <strong>Sony's first-party premier action-adventure game series not receiving new entries this year</strong>, <em>Marvel's Wolverine</em> is undoubtedly <strong>the game to look out for for fans of the genre</strong>, even those who aren't too keen on the Marvel Comics universe.</p>



<h2 id="h-crimson-desert-march-19-2026-pc-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s">Crimson Desert (March 19, 2026 - PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S)</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Crimson-Desert-scaled.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>Crimson Desert has been in development for a very long time, but 2026 is finally the year the game by Pearl Abyss finally sees the light of day</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><em>Crimson Desert</em> by Pearl Abyss, the developers of the popular MMO Black Desert Online, has been in the works for a very long time, but <a href="https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-has-release-date-recommended-requirements-reduced/"><strong>this year we will finally be able to experience</strong></a> Kliff's journey through the continent of Pywel ourselves.</p>



<p>With the political turmoil following the death of the Unifier of Lands in the background, players will get to <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">explore a really varied world</strong> with regions ranging from the pleasing plains of Akapen to the cold lands of Kweiden, <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">raid castles</strong>, <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">explore dungeons </strong>featuring puzzles, treasure and powerful enemies, <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">create alliances</strong> with other central characters and <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">master weapons and martial arts techniques</strong> to take down some <a data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" href="https://wccftech.com/crimson-desert-gameplay-shows-off-boss-fight-against-mechanical-dragon/"><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">rather impressive massive enemies</strong></a>.</p>



<p>For too long, <em>Crimson Desert</em> has been a huge unknown, but from what we have seen so far, the game has <strong>a high chance of being one of the best open-world action games </strong>in this packed 2026.</p>



<h2 id="h-007-first-light-may-27-2026-pc-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s-nintendo-switch-2">007: First Light (May 27, 2026 - PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch 2)</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/007-First-Light.jpg"></a><figcaption><em>007: First Light is the first new game by IO Interactive in a long time, and it is set to hit every mark for an epic spy game</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>After a long hiatus for the franchise following 2012's <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">007 Legends</em>, <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">IO Interactive</strong> - the masters of the stealth-sandbox genre - are finally bringing James Bond back to gaming with an action stealth title that promises to be among the best in the genre.</p>



<p><strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">007: First Light</strong> isn't just <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a href="https://wccftech.com/review/hitman-world-of-assassination-freelancer-mode-a-flawed-new-endeavor/"><strong>Hitman</strong></a></em> with a tuxedo. It’s a full-fledged <a href="https://wccftech.com/007-first-light-uncharted-x-hitman-qa-narrative-drives-things/"><strong>third-person action-adventure</strong></a> that explores a 26-year-old Bond as he earns his license to kill. <span>Blending IO's signature freedom of approach with cinematic set pieces, 007: First Light will allow players to seamlessly jump from eavesdropping on NPCs while concealed to fighting enemies head-on, en</span>gaging in intense car chases&nbsp;<a href="https://wccftech.com/new-007-first-light-trailer-shows-off-bonds-stylish-wheels/"><strong>driving a vintage Aston Martin</strong></a>, taking part in shoot-outs on cargo planes mid-flight, and more.</p>



<p>With a cast featuring <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Gemma Chan</strong> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/007-first-light-trailer-showcases-lenny-kravitz-as-latest-bond-villain/"><strong>Lenny Kravitz as the primary antagonist</strong></a>, Bawma, <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">007: First Light</em> is setting out to be the definitive spy fantasy and one of the best action games launching in 2026.</p>



<h2 id="h-grand-theft-auto-vi-november-19-2026-playstation-5-xbox-series-x-s">Grand Theft Auto VI (November 19, 2026 - PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S)</h2>



<figure><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Grand-Theft-Auto-VI-scaled.webp"></a><figcaption><em>Grand Theft Auto VI is set to shake the entire video games industry when it launches this year</em></figcaption></figure>



<p><em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">Grand Theft Auto VI</em> dominated every most anticipated game launching in 2025, but as is now tradition for <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Rockstar Games</strong>, <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-6-delayed-to-november-2026/"><strong>the game was delayed to late 2026</strong></a>, thus allowing it to dominate every list this year as well.</p>



<p>With the massive success of <em>Grand Theft Auto V</em> (now available across three console generations) and <em>Grand Theft Auto Online</em>, it's no surprise that the gaming community is <strong>eagerly anticipating the game</strong>, despite the <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-gets-surprise-second-trailer-as-rockstar-shares-first-info-and-many-gorgeous-images/"><strong>limited information available today.</strong></a></p>



<p>However, judging from <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-patents-revolutionize-open-world-forever/"><strong>the many patents filed in the past few years</strong></a>, <em data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">Grand Theft Auto VI</em> isn't just going to reiterate its predecessor with better graphics. It is set to <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)">improve every aspect of its open-world experience</strong>, introducing elements that could <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a href="https://wccftech.com/gta-6-could-evolve-into-an-mmorpg-as-many-of-its-planned-features-belong-to-the-genre-developer-has-heard/">evolve the entire experience into an MMO</a></strong>, and even <a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-may-allow-music-artists-to-upload-their-music-directly-in-the-game/"><strong>change how music is distributed online</strong></a>, turning it into an even more <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)"><a href="https://wccftech.com/grand-theft-auto-vi-7-billion-revenue-60-days/">epochal release</a></strong> not only for video games, but for entertainment.</p>



<div id="democracy-1508" data-opts="{&quot;ajax_url&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/wccftech.com\/wp-admin\/admin-ajax.php&quot;,&quot;pid&quot;:1508,&quot;max_answs&quot;:0,&quot;answs_max_height&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;anim_speed&quot;:&quot;400&quot;,&quot;line_anim_speed&quot;:1500}"><p><strong>Most Anticipated Action Game of 2026</strong></p></div>



<h2 id="h-honorable-mentions">Honorable Mentions</h2>



<p>The five above are only some of the noteworthy action games releasing in the next 12 months. Here are some more games to keep an eye on in this <strong data-dracula_alpha_bg="rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" data-dracula_preserved_classes="dracula-style-txt-border dracula-processed">action-packed 2026</strong>.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/onimusha-way-of-the-sword-gamescom-hands-on-preview-two-heavens-as-one/"><strong>Onimusha: Way of the Sword</strong></a> (TBA - PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/pragmata-gamescom-hands-on-preview-an-unexpected-surprise/"><strong>PRAGMATA</strong></a> (April 24, 2026 - PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch 2)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/romeo-is-a-dead-man-gamescom-hands-on-preview-subspace-emissary/"><strong>ROMEO IS A DEAD MAN</strong></a> (February 11, 2026 - PC, PlayStation 5, Xbox Series X|S)</li>



<li><a href="https://wccftech.com/new-saros-trailer-shows-provides-new-look-at-story/"><strong>SAROS</strong></a> (April 30, 2026 - PlayStation 5)</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://wccftech.com/yakuza-kiwami-3-dark-ties-0-directors-cut-announced/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Yakuza Kiwami 3 &amp; Dark Ties</a></strong> (February 12, 2026 - PC, PS4, PS5, Xbox Series X|S, Nintendo Switch 2)</li>
</ul>

			
			<p>Follow <a id="google_preferred_source_link_single" href="https://profile.google.com/cp/Cg0vZy8xMWM3NDB2MmIyGgA">Wccftech on Google</a> to get more of our news coverage in your feeds.</p>

		</div></div><br/><br/>https://wccftech.com/wccftechs-most-anticipated-action-games-of-2026-martial-artists-spies-super-heroes-and-criminals/]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GTA's Ned Luke gets swatted for the 8th time while streaming with Red Dead's Rob Wiethoff: "there's so many douchebags out there, Rob"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gtas-ned-luke-gets-swatted-for-the-8th-time-while-streaming-with-red-deads-rob-wiethoff-theres-so-many-douchebags-out-there-rob</link>
            <guid>1397128</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <article data-ads="true" data-article-type="news" data-article-group="news" data-paywalled="false" data-premium="false" data-sponsored="false" data-type="article">


<header data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Says he's taking at least one hoax caller to court</p>

    </div>


  <p>

  <figure>
        <picture>
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nedlukegettingswatted.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nedlukegettingswatted.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nedlukegettingswatted.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nedlukegettingswatted.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nedlukegettingswatted.png?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=3&amp;auto=webp" media="(max-width: 549px) and (max-resolution: 3dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nedlukegettingswatted.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nedlukegettingswatted.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.5&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.5dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nedlukegettingswatted.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=1.75&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 1.75dppx)">
        <source srcset="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/nedlukegettingswatted.png?width=690&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;dpr=2&amp;auto=webp" media="(min-width: 550px) and (max-resolution: 2dppx)">
        
      </picture>

        <figcaption>
          <span>Image credit: <cite>IceBladeNinja / Rock Paper Shotgun / Ned Luke</cite></span>
        </figcaption>

  </figure>
  </p>

    

</header>
  <div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/grand-theft-auto-v">GTA 5</a> voice actor Ned Luke - aka Michael de Santa - got swatted for the eighth time over Xmas. I don’t mean that somebody belted him on the nose with a rolled-up newspaper. I mean that somebody put in a hoax call to emergency services in a bid to have armed police sent to his house. The latest incident happened this December while Luke was streaming GTA Online with Rob Wiethoff, the voice of John Marston in <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/red-dead-redemption">Red Dead Redemption</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/red-dead-redemption-2">Red Dead Redemption 2</a>. YouTuber IceBladeNinja has the whole clip for you to watch below.</p><!--more-->

<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Ned Luke SWATTED Again (Michael from GTA)" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BbqBZ1v8BRg?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Ned Luke SWATTED Again (Michael from GTA)</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BbqBZ1v8BRg?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/BbqBZ1v8BRg?autoplay=1" title="Ned Luke SWATTED Again (Michael from GTA)">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BbqBZ1v8BRg" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>


<p>“Swatting” is, obviously, <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/first-ever-uk-swatting-sentence-passed-after-man-shot-in-face-by-armed-unit-due-to-hoax-call-13118559">very dangerous</a> in a country like the USA, where there are more guns than humans and the police are especially well-armed. It has gotten <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-ks/pr/ohio-gamer-pleads-guilty-swatting-caused-death">a couple</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/tennessee-man-targeted-his-twitter-handle-dies-after-swatting-call-n1274747">of people</a> killed, that I know about.</p>
<p>Thankfully, the cops seem pretty relaxed in the footage, possibly because they’re aware that Luke is a frequent target of such malevolent pranking - indeed, one of them can be heard saying "you've been swatted again". If it were me, I’d be lying on the floor nonetheless with all limbs extended at 45 degree angles, but Luke just gets up with a sigh and says hello to the fuzz, then goes back to playing GTA Online for an hour and a half. I guess it’s just as well he didn’t answer the door in character for Michael.</p><p>As reported by <a href="https://kotaku.com/gta-5-voice-actor-ned-luke-swatted-police-live-streaming-twitch-2000655992">Kotaku</a>, Luke says he was repeatedly swatted in late 2023, after his address was leaked online, and that at one point, the police ordered him to step outside his house. He's also initiated legal proceedings against some of the swatters, with one person due <a href="https://x.com/GTAVI_Countdown/status/2004926105275498972">to appear in court for sentencing</a> this month - we'll keep an eye out for that, I guess. It’s not clear there’s any real motivation for Luke's repeated swatting, beyond random people being spiteful.</p>
<p>This feels like the kind of morbid present-day cultural phenomena the forthcoming <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-everything-we-know">GTA 6</a> should parody, alongside <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6s-wholesome-boris-bike-docking-revealed-in-alleged-wip-rockstar-portfolio-video">Boris Bikes</a> and <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gta-6-appears-to-have-its-own-florida-man-parody">Florida Man</a>, but then again, that would only be encouraging the arseholes.

</p>

        </div>

      </article>

  



        
  </div></div><br/><br/>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/gtas-ned-luke-gets-swatted-for-the-8th-time-while-streaming-with-red-deads-rob-wiethoff-theres-so-many-douchebags-out-there-rob]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon Offloads This Ryzen 7 Mini PC at Its Lowest Price (32GB RAM, 1TB SSD), Cheaper Alternative to the Mac Mini]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/amazon-offloads-this-ryzen-7-mini-pc-at-its-lowest-price-32gb-ram-1tb-ssd-cheaper-alternative-to-the-mac-mini-2000656576</link>
            <guid>1397125</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Buying a new desktop computer can be a bit of a bear, especially if you want something that can both save you some space and money. But because we’re here to help, we’ve found something that satisfies both conditions and then some: the KAMRUI AM21 Mini Desktop wth an AMD Ryzen 7 processor.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6659/">You can purchase the KAMRUI AM21 Mini Desktop for $499 from Amazon (originally priced at $699), which nets you a discount of $200 or 29% off.</a> That’s nothing to sneeze at, so if you’re ready to plunk your cold, hard cash down on, it’s go time.</p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6659/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

<h2>A mini PC that has all the bells and whistles of its larger cousin</h2>
<p>The KAMRUI AM21 Mini Desktop features an AMD Ryzen 7 8745HS processor, 32GB of DDR5 5600 MHz memory, and a 1TB M.2 2280 NVME PCIe 4.0 SSD in a space-saving desktop chassis. This is an 8-core, 16-thread chip that runs up to 4.9 GHz and has integrated Radeon 780M graphics that provide smooth 1080P gaming resources. In other words, it’s deceptively powerful, despite its small size. And that means you can put it just about anywhere and still expect some serious performance.</p>
<p>Storage begins with a 1 TB M.2 2280 NVMe PCIe 4.0 x4 SSD, but there are two M.2 2280 slots available for expansion. These can accommodate up to 4 TB of NVMe storage. Although the listing mentions that SATA SSD expansion is not supported, users will need to utilize NVMe SSDs when expanding their storage.</p>



<p>This mini-desktop ships with Windows 11 Pro, KAMRUI Care support, and Amazon’s standard product support options. That means there are tons of ways to get help, so if you find yourself needing it, it’s there for you. You never know what kinds of issues can crop up when you’re setting up a new computer.</p>
<p>Pound for pound, this is a small but mighty computer that can replace a typical desktop or laptop, depending on which one you use regularly. And you can’t forget how much you’re saving on it, as well as how small it is in comparison to the commonly-accepted desktops on the market. You can get a ton done with it, and then some. Then you’ll even have some money left over to buy accessories or other items should you need to finish outfitting your work area. Or your casual home office, whichever ends up becoming true.</p>
<p>If your New Year’s resolution is to get a better PC that can improve your productivity and make things easier, this is an excellent pick. <a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6659/">Just act quickly, because this deal likely won’t be around for long, and it isn’t the type of discount you’ll not want to sink your teeth into.</a></p>
<p><a href="https://shop.kotaku.com/go/6659/" target="_self" rel="sponsored nofollow">See at Amazon</a></p>

                          </div></div><br/><br/>https://kotaku.com/amazon-offloads-this-ryzen-7-mini-pc-at-its-lowest-price-32gb-ram-1tb-ssd-cheaper-alternative-to-the-mac-mini-2000656576]]></content:encoded>
            <dc:creator>invalid@example.com (ResetEra_Newsbot</dc:creator>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>