<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>maGaming RSS Feed</title>
        <link>https://lukasz-gladek-av.github.io/custom-rss/gaming.xml</link>
        <description>A cleaned-up version of the original gaming feed</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 17:35:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A.I. Ruins Everything Part #473: Online Recipes]]></title>
            <link>https://kotaku.com/ai-recipes-facebook-how-to-cook-that-youtube-1851771932</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/a-i-ruins-everything-part-473-online-recipes.1143435/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://kotaku.com/ai-recipes-facebook-how-to-cook-that-youtube-1851771932<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Remember the science fiction of the 1950s, when people imagined the role robots and artificial intelligence could play, dramatically improving our lives by taking on menial tasks and unpleasant jobs so that we would have more spare time, not need to work every hour, and increase our personal luxury? Weird how, in the moment of this fiction being realized, we’re instead using it to force people into poverty and destroy all art. But also, it turns out, online recipes.</p><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><div data-video-id="197298" data-monetizable="true" data-position="sidebar" data-video-title="Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'" data-video-blog-id="9" data-video-network="kotaku" data-video-duration="108" data-playlist="197298,197284,197260" data-current="197298"><div><p>Live Forever in the Universe of 'New World: Aeternum'</p></div><video disablepictureinpicture="" muted="" playsinline="" width="100%" height="100%" crossorigin="anonymous" preload="none"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_240p.mp4" label="240p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_480p.mp4" label="480p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_720p.mp4" label="720p" type="video/mp4"><source data-src="https://vid.kinja.com/prod/197298/197298_1080p.mp4" label="1080p" type="video/mp4"></video></div><div><h4>Suggested Reading</h4></div><p>Online recipes have long been <em>weird</em>. Anyone who’s looked up the best way to make fluffier pancakes or slow roast a brisket will know that instead of just being told how, you’re treated to the author’s entire life story for page after page of utterly pointless text, before eventually reaching an ingredients list just before you’ve scrolled to the core of the Earth. Now imagine that, but the recipe at the end is entirely fictional, the images of the food are imagined into existence by a plagiarism machine, and the method is entirely untested and deeply unlikely to work. Welcome to now!</p><figure id="" data-id="437858c6502ad2565f424876914149dc" data-recommend-id="image://437858c6502ad2565f424876914149dc" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A plate of sad-looking churros based on an AI recipe." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false" contenteditable="false" draggable="false"><div contenteditable="false" data-alt="A plate of sad-looking churros based on an AI recipe." data-link-reference="" data-link-target="" data-syndicationrights="true" data-imagerights="fair-use" data-hide="false" data-hidecredit="false"><p><figcaption>Screenshot<!-- -->: <!-- -->How To Cook That / YouTube / Kotaku</figcaption></p></div><span data-id="437858c6502ad2565f424876914149dc" data-recommend-id="image://437858c6502ad2565f424876914149dc" data-format="jpg" data-width="1920" data-height="1080" data-lightbox="true" data-alt="A plate of sad-looking churros based on an AI recipe." data-recommended="false" data-hide="false"></span></figure><p>I always feel it’s important to distinguish what sort of AI we’re talking about when it comes to these rants because there’s the very real likelihood that “AI” could be bringing us massive breakthroughs in medicine, given its ability to manage vast amounts of information in ways humans, and even regular computation, cannot, and thus save millions of lives. This, however, is not the sort of “AI” techbros are currently losing their collective minds and wallets over. That’d be Large Language Models, which are fed all of human creativity and then spit out weird, gloopy slop. Whether it be ChatGPT and its incessant outpouring of drivel (if you know anyone who trusts it, get them to ask it to create an anagram), or image creating tools that can’t count to five, or the deeply unsettling sloppy videos in which no one’s face remains the same for more than a few seconds, LLMs are art-in-garbage-out machines, and they’re wrecking <em>everything</em>.</p><p>Including, as the wonderful YouTuber Ann Reardon points out in her latest video, recipes.</p><p>Reardon and <span><a data-ga="[[&quot;Embedded Url&quot;,&quot;External link&quot;,&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@HowToCookThat&quot;,{&quot;metric25&quot;:1}]]" href="https://www.youtube.com/@HowToCookThat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">her channel How To Cook That</a></span> is best known for her debunking videos, in which she is alerted to dubious recipes posted to the internet and then attempts to recreate them in her kitchen. It’s always a joy, as she not only demonstrates how content farms and wannabe TikTok influencers alike just make up any old crap they feel like for clicks but also then shows you how to successfully create the same food! But wow is her job about to get harder with the current flooding of socials with AI-created recipes, where every element, from ingredients to method to images, is the delusion of an LLM.</p><p>As Reardon points out, alongside trying to make a couple of the recipes, this is not only a problem social media companies aren’t trying to address, but rather one being actively encouraged! Facebook is working on something called “inverse cooking,” where its AI will “create” a recipe based on a photograph, driving such utter rubbish on its own site.</p><p>It’s worth noting that while there will almost certainly be examples of AI-generated recipes that would create lethal meals, the vast majority of them will be <em>almost</em> right. That’s the magic of plagiarism, as the LLMs have been fed every single legitimate recipe on the internet, and will approximate an average of them all. Ask it how to make pancakes, and via taking everyone else’s efforts without paying for it, it is capable of blindly reproducing an approximated median method for making pancakes. But, given it’s not “intelligence” in any meaning of the word, it’s also not capable of checking for accuracy. Hence the “not quite right” results in Reardon’s video above.</p><p>The issues arise because we now have no means of knowing what’s a legitimate, tested recipe written by a human and what’s an android dream with faked, photorealistic images before pages and pages of machine-generated life story atop a predictive-text recipe. It’ll only be in the act of trying to follow it will we realize we’ve been duped.</p><p>And thus, online recipes—unless posted by a writer you’ve followed for a long time and can trust—are ruined. Googling for the best way to make a butter chicken curry could be gambling with food poisoning, and that might just be the Gemini result it insists on forcing on you before you can click on any of the links. Thank god for actual, physical recipe books, but what a blow for a more recent massive convenience, even if you did wear through the skin on your finger scrolling to find the actual recipe.</p><p>.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1 Year Later, Helldivers 2 Players Fear a Return To Malevelon Creek Is On the Way]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/1-year-later-helldivers-2-players-fear-a-return-to-malevelon-creek-is-on-the-way</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/1-year-later-helldivers-2-players-fear-a-return-to-malevelon-creek-is-on-the-way.1143432/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/1-year-later-helldivers-2-players-fear-a-return-to-malevelon-creek-is-on-the-way<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section data-cy="article-content"><p data-cy="paragraph">Few places hold as much shared history for <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/games/helldivers-ii">Helldivers 2</a> players as Malevelon Creek. Around this time last year, it was the site of a massive Automaton incursion, with divers fighting through a hail of scrap and laser-fire. Now, it seems like we might be heading back to the Creek.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">In its most recent update, Helldivers 2 developer Arrowhead Studios announced in-game that players had failed the most recent Major Order. The Automaton Incineration Corps, armed with powerful flame weaponry, made significant gains.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"The enemy remains at large," the notification read. "Reports indicate the enemy's strategic goal is to seize old industrial assets in the Severin Sector, where the Automatons first emerged."</p><blockquote data-theme="light">— Helldivers NOW (@Helldivers_NOW) <a href="https://twitter.com/Helldivers_NOW/status/1903982258140422562?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">March 24, 2025</a></blockquote> <p data-cy="paragraph">The Severin Sector is home to several planets, chiefly Malevelon Creek, where players <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-players-liberate-malevelon-creek-in-hours-to-redeem-one-of-their-biggest-major-order-failures">took the planet back</a> in a last-ditch effort against the Automatons in April 2024. It was a stunning experience for anyone who dropped into it, as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-community-mourns-the-loss-of-space-vietnam-map-malevelon-creek-but-the-fightback-has-already-begun">players fought to re-take the Creek after initially losing it</a>.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">The phrase "<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1brm27h/i_finally_understand_why_malevelon_creek_is/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Robot Vietnam</a>" was tossed around, thanks to Malevelon Creek's dense jungle environment. It became so notable that Arrowhead <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-dev-gives-all-players-a-special-commemorative-cape-for-malevelon-creek-memorial-day">released a cape commemorating the fight</a> to reclaim the planet.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Now, with the prospect of Automatons returning the sector to take territory, potentially armed with flame weaponry, Helldivers are gearing up for a scrap.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">"A part of me is in fear as I was there but another part of me WANTS to go back," one Reddit user wrote, in response to a <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1jib6a8/theyre_heading_for_the_creek/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post about the Major Order update</a>. "... a part of me never left," another responded.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Some expressed terror at returning, while others are ready to hold out again. "I fought hard for that planet once, and I'm prepared to do so a second time," one user <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1jib6a8/theyre_heading_for_the_creek/mje4ou1/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">responded</a>.</p><output data-cy="article-video"></output><p data-cy="paragraph">The Major Order failure has raised another point of concern for Helldivers 2 players, though. As <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1ji5cwt/this_mo_was_designed_to_teach_us_defense_gambits/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one post outlined</a>, some Major Orders can feel frustrating to accomplish, organize around, or not feel incentivized. As responders note, the active player base can also vary, which can make quantity-driven Orders difficult if they're not based around the current average.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">One player <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Helldivers/comments/1ji5cwt/this_mo_was_designed_to_teach_us_defense_gambits/mjcv9ev/" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">puts it succinctly</a>: "Stop giving us kill quantity MOs when the player base can vary by up to 70k over the course of a single week." Further replies suggest percentage-based scaling.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Failure can make for interesting storytelling, as proven by the initial fight at Malevelon Creek. Heading into what feels like a major moment for Helldivers 2 though, it'll be interesting to see how Arrowhead handles it all. Alongside teasing a return to one of its most infamous battle sites, the team has <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/helldivers-2-players-are-looking-for-hidden-messages-amid-black-hole-disaster">also sent a black hole directly towards Super Earth</a>. There's no shortage of threats for the Helldivers these days.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">Eric is a freelance writer for IGN.</p></section></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LEGO Horizon Adventures Drops to Less Than $40 at Amazon Ahead of Spring Sale]]></title>
            <link>https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-horizon-adventures-early-amazon-spring-sale-deal</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/lego-horizon-adventures-drops-to-less-than-40-at-amazon-ahead-of-spring-sale.1143429/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-horizon-adventures-early-amazon-spring-sale-deal<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p data-cy="page-header"><h2 data-cy="article-sub-headline">Big discounts at Amazon already.</h2></p><div data-cy="article-content"><section data-cy="article-subtitle"><p data-cy="paragraph"><a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-spring-sale-2025-announced">Amazon's Big Spring Sale</a> starts tomorrow, and if you've been hoping to score some nice discounts on video games, you don't have to wait for the sale to start. There are a few <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-spring-sale-2025-best-early-deals">early deals</a> available right now that are worth checking out ahead of the sale event. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">One of our favorites at the moment is on <a href="https://zdcs.link/9yXOem?object_uuid=e3609b2b-0558-4063-9bd5-e9d50cd42e25&amp;t=article" data-cy="styled-link" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">LEGO Horizon Adventures for PS5</a>, which has dropped to $37.08 at the retailer. This is 38% off its list price of $59.99. If you've had this one on your shopping list, now's a great time to pick it up for your game library.</p><div catalogid="74a1460c-dc51-42b4-aee4-28a95bf6bf17" id="217376"><div id="217376" data-cy="productcard-view-trigger"><p data-cy="solo-product-name"><h3>LEGO Horizon Adventures – PS5</h3></p></div><p data-cy="paragraph">LEGO Horizon Adventures takes the magnificent mechanical world of Horizon and rebuilds it brick-by-brick <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/all-lego-games-on-nintendo-switch-in-order">with LEGO</a>. IGN's Jada Griffin said in our <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/lego-horizon-adventures-review">review</a> that the game, "reimagines Horizon Zero Dawn with a playful Lego twist, simplifying the story while keeping the heart of its key moments and characters."</p><p data-cy="paragraph">It isn't the only video game deal that's caught our eye recently, though. Right now you can also score a <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/final-fantasy-7-rebirth-drops-to-lowest-price-ever-2025">great discount on Final Fantasy 7 Rebirth at Woot</a> (an Amazon-owned online retailer). This one has just dropped to its lowest price yet, so if you've been waiting for your chance to jump into this excellent RPG, there's truly no better time than now to do it.</p><p data-cy="paragraph">As mentioned earlier, there are plenty more deals still to come as <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/amazon-spring-sale-2025-announced">Amazon's Big Spring Sale</a> kicks off tomorrow. This sale event is set to run from March 25 to March 31, so you'll have plenty of time to pick up the discounts that catch your eye. </p><p data-cy="paragraph">To see more gaming deals, have a look at our dedicated roundups of the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-playstation-ps5-deals">best PlayStation deals</a>, the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-xbox-deals">best Xbox deals</a>, and the <a data-cy="styled-link" href="https://www.ign.com/articles/best-nintendo-switch-deals">best Nintendo Switch deals</a>. Each of these features discounts on games, accessories, and hardware, so you can save on a variety of items for your preferred platform.</p><h3 data-cy="title3">More Game Deals at Amazon</h3><p data-cy="paragraph"><em>Hannah Hoolihan is a freelancer who writes with the guides and commerce teams here at IGN.</em></p></div></section><div data-cy="caption"><p>Originally posted: </p><!-- --><p>Mar 24, 2025 3:45 pm</p></div></div><div><h3 data-cy="object-summary-embed-title">In This Article</h3></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How a nephew’s CD burner inspired early Valve to embrace DRM]]></title>
            <link>https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/how-a-nephews-cd-burner-inspired-early-valve-to-embrace-drm/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/how-a-nephew%E2%80%99s-cd-burner-inspired-early-valve-to-embrace-drm.1143426/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/03/how-a-nephews-cd-burner-inspired-early-valve-to-embrace-drm/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                      
                      
          <p>Back in 2004, <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/11/how-half-life-2-helped-sell-steam-to-a-skeptical-pc-gaming-market/">the launch of <em>Half-Life 2</em> would help launch Steam</a> on the path to eventually becoming the de facto digital rights management (DRM) system for the vast majority of PC games. But years before that, with the 1998 launch of the original <em>Half-Life</em>, Valve cofounder and then-CMO Monica Harrington said she was inspired to take DRM more seriously by her nephew's reaction to the purchase of a new CD-ROM burner.</p>
<p>PC Gamer <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/valves-drm-was-inspired-by-the-cmos-nephew-who-used-a-usd500-check-id-sent-him-for-school-expenses-and-bought-himself-a-cd-rom-replicator-he-sent-me-a-lovely-thank-you-note/">pulled that interesting tidbit</a> from <a href="https://schedule.gdconf.com/session/how-valve-became-valve-an-insiders-account/911257">a talk Harrington gave at last week's Game Developers Conference</a>. In her remembering, Harrington's nephew had used funds she had sent for school supplies on a CD replicator, then sent her "a lovely thank you note essentially saying how happy he was to copy and share games with his friends."</p>
<p>That was the moment Harrington said she realized this new technology was leading to a "generational shift" in both the availability and acceptability of PC game piracy. While game piracy and DRM definitely existed prior to CD burners (anyone else remember the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S_Tz0YpDa6o">large codewheels</a> that cluttered many early PC game boxes?), Harrington said the new technology—and the blasé attitude her nephew showed toward using it for piracy—could "put our entire business model at risk."</p>
<p>Shortly after <em>Half-Life</em> launched <a href="https://www.pcgamingwiki.com/wiki/Half-Life">with a simple CD key verification system in place</a>, Harrington said the company noticed a wave of message board complaints about the game not working. But when Valve cofounder (and Monica's then-husband) Mike Harrington followed up with those complaining posters, he found that "none of them had actually bought the game. So it turned out that the authentication system was working really well," Harrington said.</p>

          
                      
                  </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exploring Quito, Ecuador (and soccer fever) in despelote]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/exploring-quito-ecuador-and-soccer-fever-in-despelote</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/exploring-quito-ecuador-and-soccer-fever-in-despelote.1143423/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/exploring-quito-ecuador-and-soccer-fever-in-despelote<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>The IGF (Independent Games Festival) aims to encourage innovation in game development and to recognize independent game developers advancing the medium. This year, Game Developer sat down with the finalists&nbsp; for the IGF’s Nuovo and Grand Prize nominees ahead of GDC to explore the themes, design decisions, and tools behind each entry. Game Developer and GDC are sibling organizations under Informa.</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>despelote</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> lets you explore the streets of Quito, Ecuador as an eight year old child caught up in soccer fever, kicking your ball all over town and using it to interact with the places and people you meet.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Game Developer sat down with Julián Cordero, lead developer of the multi-IGF Award nominated title, to talk about creating a game that focuses on things that happen around a sport as opposed to focusing on just the sport, the intriguing ways they captured the feel of Ecuador in 2001 when they were nearing qualification for the World Cup, and the thoughts that went into how the soccer ball would operate as players experience the world through kicking it all over town.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Who are you, and what was your role in developing </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>despelote</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I am Julián Cordero, lead developer and designer of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>despelote</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">. The rest of the team is Sebastián Valbuena who does the art and music, Gabe Cuzzillo who helps with production, and Ian Berman who does the sound design.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/achieving-creative-sobriety-in-game-design" target="_self" data-discover="true">Achieving 'creative sobriety' in game design</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What's your background in making games?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I studied game design at the NYU Gamecenter, made a bunch of games back as a student, and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>despelote</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> was actually my capstone project 6 years ago. We’ve been lucky enough to have received support from various sources to develop it all these years.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>How did you come up with the concept for </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>despelote</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The soccer culture in Ecuador is huge and I used to play so much of it growing up, but when I moved to NYC I stopped playing and engaging with it as much. When I realized this, I started to think about the role soccer had played in my life and I decided to make a game to explore this idea. I had always played big triple A sports games like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>FIFA</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but the soccer you play there didn't represent the kind of soccer I actually grew up playing which took place in neighborhoods and parks—not in big stadiums in front of millions of people. I found that everything that happens around the sport is just as interesting as the sport itself, so we set out to make a game that focused on that.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What development tools were used to build your game?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Unity, Fmod, Scaniverse and Polycam for 3D scanning, Blender, Ableton, and Photoshop.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/how-making-assassin-s-creed-shadows-strengthened-ubisoft-s-process-for-bringing-history-to-life" target="_self" data-discover="true">How Assassin's Creed Shadows strengthened Ubisoft's process for bringing history to life</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What thoughts went into creating a world that would offer so much fun, secret stories, and mischief for an eight-year-old to get into?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The game is set at a very particular time in the recent history of Ecuador. In 2001, the country had just gone through a big economic crisis and it was very easy for everyone to latch on to the national soccer team for hope since they were on the brink of qualifying to the world cup for the first time ever. This is one of my earliest memories, but it is very hazy and a lot of it is reconstructed from stories I've heard. So when designing the world, we decided to integrate many perspectives into this depiction by having friends and family improvise all the dialogue in the game. We came up with some basic scenarios and told people to pretend like they are 2001 so that they could bring whatever memories they had about it into the recording sessions. The results were always surprising and integrating them into the game became an interesting design challenge.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Not writing any of the dialogue allowed me to be a spectator of these moments, so it was very fun to pretend to be eight years old and come up with ways of being mischievous around them. For example, a couple having an anniversary picnic in the park was a lovely conversation from a real-life couple who brought stuff in from their actual relationship into the recording. Wouldn't it be great to be eight years old and use their orange juice as target practice? Maybe the fight that ensues after it splashes has a hint of their real relationship too.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/-it-s-okay-to-make-a-small-game-astro-bot-director-nicolas-doucet-says-tiny-ideas-contain-huge-potential" target="_self" data-discover="true">'It's okay to make a small game:' Astro Bot director Nicolas Doucet says tiny ideas contain huge potential</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Kicking the soccer ball is pretty satisfying (and not just because you've booted it at someone). What thoughts went into making the soccer ball kicking/dribbling mechanics fun and appealing on their own? Into making them fun in a first-person perspective?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I remember some of the balls I played with as a kid and how deeply I got to know them. A beaten-up soccer ball has so many stories to tell; it is such a simple object, but it is so versatile. When thinking about how to depict this, our instinct was to try to make it feel very physical. We tried to avoid using magic forces to keep the ball in front of you and instead embrace the unexpected nature of it. The ball bounces around your feet; you never have full control of it, but you can sort of guide it to where you want. The first-person perspective allows the player to have a direct connection and ensure that the ball is always in the foreground. And when the ball is in the foreground, the background conversations and ambiences can slowly seep in.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>despelote</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span> uses a striking mixture of stylized realistic visuals (drawn from photographs) and animated characters. What appealed to you about this visual mixture? How do these visuals work with your vision for this exploration of Ecuador in 2001?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Sebastián had been playing with this kind of aesthetic for a few years before I approached him to be part of the game. I was very inspired by some of his </span><span data-testid="content-text"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jyd7YLiWM1M">2D animations</a></span><span data-testid="content-text">, but he had never worked in 3D, so it was a challenge to bring his style into a first-person exploration game. However, when we started experimenting with the art, we quickly realized that the mix of black and white hand-drawn elements with a noisy background established a clear visual language that was intuitive for the player. We committed to this contrast and it gave us much liberty to play around with each style.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>What drew you to work with photographs while creating the world? What effect did you feel this had on the game and how the player will experience its vision of Ecuador in this time period?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Similarly to how we wanted to "source" the dialogue from the real world by having friends and family improvise, we wanted to "source" the environment from the real world. The design of the map is not exactly an actual place in Quito, but we bring in assets from the real world to try to ground the game in a specific setting. It made a lot of sense to use photographs and 3D scans because the textures have so much personality built into them already, which gives the environment a very raw feeling.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Games have a tendency of trying to avoid depicting the real world, probably because it is technically just as difficult to create a fantasy world as it is a real-life city block. But we have so many ways of capturing the world nowadays, and I think games are the perfect vessel to combine them together.&nbsp;</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>You also work with audio to give the player a real sense of place while exploring </span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>despelote</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>. Why was it important to capture the sounds of the world alongside the photographic visuals?</span></span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">I think that the more specific a depiction of a place is, the more relatable it can be even for people who have never been to that place. This is especially true for audio, because certain sounds can trigger nostalgic feelings without us fully understanding it. I live in NYC now, but hearing specific birds chirping that Ian recorded brings me back to being a kid in Quito. This is why we really wanted the game to sound like Quito, and Ian did an incredible job recording and mixing it all together.</span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disco Elysium staff say rival projects from former colleagues are "friendly competition"]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-staff-say-rival-projects-from-former-colleagues-are-friendly-competition</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/disco-elysium-staff-say-rival-projects-from-former-colleagues-are-friendly-competition.1143420/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-staff-say-rival-projects-from-former-colleagues-are-friendly-competition<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>"We're competing essentially against ourselves."</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/C4_6.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>ZA/UM</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>As <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/disco-elysium">Disco Elysium</a> studio ZA/UM continues development on its espionage follow-up C4, staff have described the friendly competition with rival projects from developers who have since left the studio in the wake of messy lawsuits.</p>
<p>Key team members from ZA/UM left in 2021 prior to <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-lead-files-lawsuit-against-developer-zaum">multiple lawsuits filed against the studio</a>, which have <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-studio-says-lawsuits-from-former-members-have-been-resolved">since been resolved</a>. In the wake of this, a number of studios have been newly founded and are releasing projects all claiming to be spiritual successors to Disco Elysium - that includes <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/more-disco-elysium-alumni-join-former-staff-at-longdue-working-on-spiritual-successor">Longdue and its "psychogeographic RPG" Hopetown</a>, and <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/detective-rpg-in-the-works-from-breakaway-group-of-former-disco-elysium-developers">XXX Nightshift from Dark Math Games</a>, a developer which describes itself as a "breakaway group from the original development team of Disco Elysium".</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-studio-zaums-new-rpg-c4-is-part-espionage-thriller-part-psychedelic-sci-fi">ZA/UM itself is working on C4</a>, as well as a <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/disco-elysium-is-being-reimagined-for-mobile-devices-to-captivate-the-tiktok-user">mobile adaptation of Disco Elysium</a> to "captivate the TikTok user". I had the chance to speak to lead producer Ruudu Ulas and principal writer Siim (Kosmos) Sinamäe at this year's Game Developers Conference (GDC).</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="PROJECT [C4] - Teaser Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kz9apwrMKi8?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>PROJECT [C4] - Teaser Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kz9apwrMKi8?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/kz9apwrMKi8?autoplay=1" title="PROJECT [C4] - Teaser Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>PROJECT [C4] - Teaser Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kz9apwrMKi8" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>"This, let's say, situation has really built the character of the team in a good way," said Sinamäe. "Each artist faces certain hardships in their artistic practice. This is what makes them better."</p>
<p>"But of course, I'm really excited to see what each one of the studios that has grown out of ZA/UM will show over the next months and years," added Ulas.</p>
<p>I asked the pair if there was friendly competition between the studios. "For us, always we think it's friendly competition," said Sinamäe. "We're going to really think about what the other writers are doing, or the studios... how can I be better at my own craft? We're competing essentially against ourselves in this way of can we take it further? Do we have to make any compromises? I think it absolutely sets us apart."</p>
<p>So what makes a ZA/UM game unique? For Ulas, it's the wide range of people with different skill sets that makes the team unique. "We have a lot of people who come from different walks of life, rather than just video games," she said. "I'm trained as a contemporary artist, there are people who come from a fashion background and traditional 2D art and so on.</p>
<p>"Working together is what sets us apart, I think, and also going through these difficult and challenging times as a studio and growing as a team throughout. When I wake up in the morning and log on to do my work, that's what motivates me."</p>
<p>In a presentation, the pair showed me the contrasting subjective and objective worlds of C4, each with their own art style and gameplay elements. The objective world, for instance, includes a greyed overlay as the player character checks his watch, while the subjective world is full of surreal art to convey the psychology of the player.</p>
<p>Indeed, with C4, the team is intending to explore the human mind and its complexities as the protagonist operant adopts multiple covers and struggles with his sense of self. Inside his thought cabinet, players will be able to reinforce or suppress thoughts, which will not only impact how the narrative plays out, but provide dissonances as it progresses - perhaps adopting a new cover will cause reinforced perceptions to change. Choices will be influenced not only by dice rolls but by three key limits: anxiety, deliriousness, and fatigue.</p>
<p>All of which is to say that C4 looks set to be another wildly intellectual video game from ZA/UM, with a gritty espionage tone far removed from the typical James Bond-esque fare. The remaining team at the studio seems capable of a worthy Disco Elysium follow-up, but whether it can stand above its peers remains to be seen.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Assassin’s Creed Shadows Biggest Physical Game of the Year in UK]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-biggest-physical-game-of-the-year-in-uk/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/assassin%E2%80%99s-creed-shadows-biggest-physical-game-of-the-year-in-uk.1143381/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-biggest-physical-game-of-the-year-in-uk/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Much to many people's surprise, Assassin's Creed Shadows is knocking it out of the park. While Monster Hunter Wilds was an incredibly big game, with it selling eight million copies in just a matter of days. On top of that, it reached 1.3 million concurrent players on Steam. However, Assassin's Creed Shadows is hot on the trails of Monster Hunter Wilds.</p>
<p>Assassin's Creed Shadows has already reached around<a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-shadows-has-reached-2-million-players-besting-origins-and-odyssey/"> two million players</a> and is continuing to increase. Compared to Monster Hunter Wilds, Assassin's Creed takes the lead in physical copies sold in the UK. At present, Shadows is the biggest physical launch of the year in the country, as noted by <a href="https://x.com/Chris_Dring/status/1903885728821674283" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GameIndustry.biz's Christopher Dring</a>.</p>
<p>This feudal Japan title saw it reach over one million players on launch day, despite the ongoing <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-responds-to-damning-reports-of-abuse-by-assassins-creed-shadows-studio/">controversy</a> throughout the advertising period of the game. It was also delayed multiple times, but it seems that was for a good reason, as most audiences who have played the game seem to be happy with what they've gotten from it.</p>
<p>With Assassin's Creed Shadows reaching over two million players, it means that it has now bested the performance of Assassin's Creed Origins and Assassin's Creed Odyssey, two of the newer titles that performed incredibly well for Ubisoft.</p>
<p>Dring also mentions that it has sold more boxed copies in one week than <a href="https://wccftech.com/star-wars-outlaws-has-only-sold-1-million-copies-since-launch-learning-curve-assassins-creed-shadows/">Star Wars Outlaws</a> did in three months, which is a bit of a harsh statistic for Ubisoft. However, for most, it won't come as a surprise, as even Ubisoft has acknowledged that Star Wars Outlaws did not perform in the way they wanted. In some aspects, Assassin's Creed Shadows was their final hope to produce something in recent years that had the chance to be majorly successful, as Assassin's Creed Mirage didn't quite hit the mark for some players, either.</p>
<p>However, there are still plans for the<a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-mirage-is-reportedly-getting-its-first-dlc/"> first DLC</a> to be released for Assassin's Creed Mirage, with ongoing support and <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-mirage-gets-a-free-dlss-3-mod-thanks-to-lukefz/">mods</a> being released for the title.</p>
<p>While the game holds this very impressive information at the moment, it is likely that it will have it snatched from them by releases such as Call of Duty, Mario Kart 9, or Grand Theft Auto VI, should it be released this year.</p>
<p>If you want to know more about this game, you can read <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/assassins-creed-shadows-a-gorgeous-dive-into-feudal-chaos/">Francesco De Meo's review</a> of the title, where he gave it a generous score of 8.7, calling it a "gorgeous dive into feudal chaos."</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minecraft is getting vibrant with its visuals]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/634690/minecraft-vibrant-visuals-update-minecraft-live</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/minecraft-is-getting-vibrant-with-its-visuals.1143378/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.theverge.com/news/634690/minecraft-vibrant-visuals-update-minecraft-live<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/ash-parrish">Ash Parrish</a> <span>is a reporter who covers the business, culture, and communities of video games, with a focus on marginalized gamers and the quirky, horny culture of video game communities.</span></p></div><div id="zephr-anchor"><p><em>Minecraft</em> is going to look very different soon. During the <em>Minecraft</em> Live event over the weekend, Mojang revealed a new update that will seriously transform the way we see the world of <em>Minecraf</em>t.</p><p><a href="https://www.minecraft.net/en-us/article/minecraft-vibrant-visuals">Vibrant Visuals</a> is the graphical update players have been waiting for. It’s got dynamic lighting, improved shadows, enhanced water reflections, volumetric fog, changes to underwater visuals, and more. The update is coming soon to <em>Minecraft: Bedrock Edition</em> and will be a toggle-able feature meaning every player will be able to turn it on and off as they wish. </p><p>Mojang shared a video of Vibrant Visuals in action and the difference between what the game looks like now and what it will with the update are subtle but stunning. Sunlight shines through trees and window panes. Shadows elongate or contract with the position of the sun and other light sources. Glowing light in caverns create a darker, spookier vibes along with glowing eyes for spiders, Endermen, and <em>Minecraft</em>’s other menacing creatures.</p><p>Mojang says Vibrant Visuals is still in the testing phase for<em> Bedrock Edition</em>, but that it plans rolling out the update for Java Edition devices soon.</p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Soaring city builder Laysara: Summit Kingdom is now a full-blown trading empire game]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/soaring-city-builder-laysara-summit-kingdom-is-now-a-full-blown-trading-empire-game</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/soaring-city-builder-laysara-summit-kingdom-is-now-a-full-blown-trading-empire-game.1143375/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/soaring-city-builder-laysara-summit-kingdom-is-now-a-full-blown-trading-empire-game<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Thanks to the new Sandbox update</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/1_u23q5Xr.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Future Friends Games / Quite OK Games</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>
Mountainous town-<a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-best-building-games-on-pc">builder</a> <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/laysara-summit-kingdom">Laysara: Summit Kingdom</a> has received a Sandbox update that, essentially, turns a game about settling the slopes of precisely <em>one</em> mountain into a lightweight trading empire simulator. Where the early access game's existing modes have you doing up one Bonsai Everest at a time, Sandbox lets you switch between several and export goods for other alpine mayors to buy. 
</p><!--more-->
<p>
It's a significant addition to an early access project that had our Nic Reuben in fits of ecstasy, smashing his Grinchy heart asunder to reveal the wholesome yak fanboi lurking within. "Possibly the prettiest city builder I've ever seen," he <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/laysara-summit-kingdom-is-a-stunning-mountainous-city-builder-thats-out-now-in-early-access">declared</a> back at the game's early access launch, like a judge at a yak contest waving around a yak-hair bagful of yak-hair rosettes. Nic is away this week, so I am reasonably safe from repercussions over painting him as a smelly weirdo yak enthusiast. That said, I might ban him from the comments in advance, just to be safe.
</p>
<p>
I played a bit of Laysara: Summit Kingdom's demo last year myself, and yeah, it's good, though its fantasy world seems heavily informed by caricatures about Himalayan communities and Tibetan monasteries. Its town construction is shaped by elevation, with different kinds of vegetation and other resources and perils at higher altitudes. There's the omni-present risk of avalanches, but you can fortify your towns and plant forests to redirect the vengeful ice.</p>
<p>I never did a lot of it in the demo, but I do like this subliminal "avalanche sculpting sim" element. It makes me wonder if Polish developers Quite OK Games harbour any systemic aspirations of the "get lava computers working inside <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/dwarf-fortress">Dwarf Fortress</a>" variety.
</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/2_tR1Z6WP.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption><span>Image credit: <cite>Future Friends Games / Quite OK Games</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>
<a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/1823950/Laysara_Summit_Kingdom/">As detailed on Steam</a>, Sandbox Mode adds a World Map for switching between towns. You'll have a few unlocked to begin with, expanding your empire of peakvilles by raising temples on summits. Building temples also increases your research level across your entire empire. "Six new mountains!" the Steam changelog adds, like somebody forgetting the lyrics for The Twelve Days of Christmas. If they'd put that in a footnote I could have made a joke about foothills.
</p>
<p>
The changelog includes various smaller tweaks. They've added the option to construct ice altars during Free Build on certain maps, "a more detailed UI research panel, showing where does research comes from", and "more precise cursor detection when clicking on Advanced Yak Breeding". Got to be surgical, when match-making yaks.
</p>
<p>
The developers comment in the post that Sandbox Mode is about "expanding your kingdom in whatever way you see fit" with only "a few tiny story bits and a single global objective to provide a general sense of purpose". That said, it's also a taste of their plans for the game's forthcoming campaign, which will be "a more 'directed' sandbox experience with more detailed objectives (similar to what you've seen in the Scenarios)". The campaign will arrive with the game's 1.0 release later this year.
</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palworld on Switch 2 is a Possibility If the Console is ‘Beefy Enough’]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-on-switch-2-is-a-possibility-if-the-console-is-beefy-enough/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/palworld-on-switch-2-is-a-possibility-if-the-console-is-%E2%80%98beefy-enough%E2%80%99.1143363/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-on-switch-2-is-a-possibility-if-the-console-is-beefy-enough/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-96976">

	<header>
        

        

	</header>

    


	<div>
		
<p>Pocketpair will consider releasing Palworld for the Nintendo Switch 2 if the console is ‘beefy enough’.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 id="h-is-palworld-coming-to-nintendo-switch-2">Is Palworld Coming to Nintendo Switch 2?</h2>



<p>Pocketpair communications director John ‘Bucky’ Buckley spoke about Palworld on the Nintendo Switch 2 during an interview with <a href="https://www.ign.com/articles/palworld-communications-director-says-nintendo-switch-2-version-100-worth-considering-if-the-console-is-beefy-enough" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">IGN</a> at GDC San Fransisco. Bucky first talked about the console’s specs, stating that he has been “walking around GDC”, hoping that someone will reveal Switch 2’s specs to him. However, everyone he has interacted with has said, “They haven’t even seen them”. He stated they couldn’t make the game for the original Switch as Palworld is “a beefy game”.</p>



<p>Bucky added that Palworld on Nintendo Switch 2 is “100% worth considering”, provided the console is “beefy enough.” The developers already have experience with handheld optimisations with their release on the Steam Deck and are “happy with how it turned out”, even though there’s still some work to do. Pocketpair would like to get Palworld “on more handhelds if possible.”</p>



<p>At the same time, Nintendo’s patent infringement lawsuit against Palworld continues, with recent updates stating that the former has received a <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/nintendo-anti-palworld-patent/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new patent</a> that might help their case. Pocketpair recently spoke about the lawsuit, saying it “<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworld-devs-were-shocked-by-nintendos-patent-infringement-lawsuit/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">came as a shock</a>” for them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other news, Pocketpair publishing has <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pocketpair-publishing-warn-not-more-palworld/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">warned players</a> not to expect ‘more Palworld’. Also, the game recently released its much-awaited <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/palworlds-cross-play-update-is-now-available-on-all-platforms/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cross-play update</a>. What are your thoughts on Palworld releasing for the Switch 2?&nbsp;Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle arriving for PS5 in April</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div>

</article><div id="post-container">
            
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month/">
                                Indiana Jones and The Great Circle Releases on PS5 Next Month                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle releases for PS5 this April. Check out the editions, pre-order bonuses and other details here. </p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/team-rocket-returns-to-pokemon-tcg-with-upcoming-destined-rivals-set/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/team-rocket-returns-to-pokemon-tcg-with-upcoming-destined-rivals-set/">
                                Team Rocket Returns to Pokémon TCG with Upcoming Destined Rivals Set                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Pokémon TCG’s new Destined Rivals set will bring back Team Rocket to the game along with over 240 cards. Here are more details.</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-mod-adds-gta-6-removed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/gta-5-mod-adds-gta-6-removed/">
                                Take-Two Interactive Copyrights GTA 5 Mod That Put GTA 6 Map Into The Game                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>Following a YouTube copyright strike from Take-Two Interactive, a GTA 5 modder has decided to remove his mod that adds GTA 6 into GTA 5. The video in question was a FiveM mod that added the GTA 6 map into GTA 5, which was based on the massive hack that Rockstar Games faced a couple […]</p>
                    </div>

                    
                    <div>
                        <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-will-bring-27-new-mega-evolutions-its-claimed/">
                            
                        </a>

                        <h2>
                            <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/pokemon-legends-z-a-will-bring-27-new-mega-evolutions-its-claimed/">
                                Pokémon Legends Z-A Will Bring 27 New Mega Evolutions, It’s Claimed                            </a>
                        </h2>

                        <p>A new claim states that Pokémon Legends Z-A is set to introduce 27 new Mega Evolutions. Here are more details. </p>
                    </div>

                                                    </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next Minecraft Update 1.25.5 Release Date - When Does Spring To Life Come Out?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-minecraft-update-release-date-1-25-5-spring-to-life-release-date/1100-6530316/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/next-minecraft-update-1-25-5-release-date-when-does-spring-to-life-come-out.1143360/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamespot.com/articles/next-minecraft-update-release-date-1-25-5-spring-to-life-release-date/1100-6530316/?ftag=CAD-01-10abi2f<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
    <span data-nosnippet="">GameSpot may receive revenue from affiliate and advertising partnerships for sharing this content and from purchases through links.</span>
  </p><article itemscope="" data-type-id="1100" data-guid="1100-6530316">

            
            
  


        

  


        
        
              <section>

                  
          <div data-content-element-selector="p, .js-buylink-item-container" data-allowed-classes-selector="js-buylink-item-container">
                <p>During the recent <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/games/minecraft/" data-ref-id="5000-73990">Minecraft</a> Live, players were treated to news on when the next Minecraft update will be released. Mojang has already promised more frequent updates to the blocky sandbox game, and the first one of 2025 is the Spring To Life update.</p><div data-embed-type="toc"><p><span><strong>Table of Contents</strong> [<a data-toggle="collapse" href="#toc_list">hide</a>]</span></p><ul id="toc_list"><li><a href="#Next_Minecraft_release_date">Next Minecraft release date</a></li><li><a href="#New_Minecraft_update_features">New Minecraft update features</a><ul><li><a href="#Mob_variants">Mob variants</a></li><li><a href="#New_Minecraft_blocks">New Minecraft blocks</a></li><li><a href="#World_generation">World generation</a></li><li><a href="#Sounds">Sounds</a></li></ul></li></ul></div><h2 id="Next_Minecraft_release_date">Next Minecraft release date</h2><p>The next Minecraft update will be released on <strong>Tuesday, March 25, 2025</strong>. The 1.21.5 update sees new mob variants, new audio features, and interesting plant additions.</p><p>For players using the game's Snapshots feature, where you can try out new additions in beta form, you may already be familiar with the update's contents.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464129-mc-live2025-springtolife.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4464129" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1280" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464129-mc-live2025-springtolife.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4464129"></a><figcaption>New mob variants are coming to Minecraft.</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464129-mc-live2025-springtolife.jpg"></figure><h2 id="New_Minecraft_update_features">New Minecraft update features</h2><p>Minecraft biomes are set to feel more different to one another with the Spring To Life update. New warm and cold mob variants, sounds, and flora are all set to appear in the game with the release date.</p><h3 id="Mob_variants">Mob variants</h3><p>Chickens, pigs, and cows now have more variants, and will spawn in specific areas. The three variants, Temperate, Cold, and Warm, have different colors and different biome specifications. The Temperate versions will spawn by default where Cold and Warm do not spawn. The Cold variants will spawn in, well, anywhere that's cold. That includes the Taiga, Windswept Hills, Snowy Plains, and even the Deep Dark and The End. The Warm variants spawn in the opposite, so places like the Savanna, Jungle, Badlands, Mangrove Swamps, and the Nether's biomes.</p><p>They're not the only mobs getting attention, as the Wolf gets six new sounds. Each wolf will receive a random sound variant when it spawns, and will stick with that for its existence. The existing wolf noises are used for the Classic variant, and Minecraft is adding Big, Cute, Puglin, Angry, Grumpy, and Sad.</p><h3 id="New_Minecraft_blocks">New Minecraft blocks</h3><p>As well as the attention to mobs, Minecraft's blocks are becoming more diverse. Bushes will generate in the Plains, Windswept Hills, River and Frozen River, and all Forest biomes. They are tinted by the grass color of the biome that they are placed or spawn in, and can be used in the composter. Using bone meal on a bush generates a neighboring bush if there is space. Harvesting bushes can be done using any tool with Silk Touch, or the shears.</p><p>The Cactus Flower is a new type of flower that has a chance of generating cacti. It can be placed on cactus blocks, or any block which has center support at the top. If a cactus is one or two blocks high, there is a 10% chance of a Cactus Flower growing on it, instead of the cactus getting taller. If the cactus is three or more blocks high, the growth chance increases to 25%, but they'll only grow if there is space on all sides. Any tool can mine it, and it can also be used to craft pink dye.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464147-minecraft-next-update.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4464147" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464147-minecraft-next-update.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4464147"></a><figcaption>Minecraft Firefly Bushes emit light and ambient sounds</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464147-minecraft-next-update.jpg"></figure><p>The Firefly Bush is a long-awaited addition after Minecraft controversially removed Fireflies from the game following concerns that they were toxic to frogs in real life, and that by eating them in-game, it was a potential issue. The Firefly Bush is being added now, which will generate in swamps, near rivers, near water in Mangrove Swamps, and rarely in the Badlands. When it's dark, you'll spot glowing firefly particles up to five blocks from a Firefly Bush. It will play immersive, ambient sounds as long as it's not blocked from above and it's nighttime. Using bone meal on a Firefly bush will generate a neighboring one as long as there is space. It also emits a light level of 2, but will be instantly broken without any particular tool.</p><p>Leaf Litter is another block being added to Minecraft to improve the immersive nature of the game. It's a decorative block that can be found in forests and wooded badlands biomes. It works in a similar way to the petals blocks, and up to four can be placed on the same block, increasing the density of the Leaf Litter the more you place per block. Smelting any type of leaves block will create Leaf Litter, and it can also be used as fuel for smelting. It also comes with unique block sounds--we can't wait to trample through the leaves in Fall.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464148-minecraft-next-update%281%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4464148" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464148-minecraft-next-update%281%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4464148"></a><figcaption>Minecraft Leaf Litter is a new decorative block</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464148-minecraft-next-update%281%29.jpg"></figure><p>Short Dry Grass is one block high and generates in the desert and badlands biomes. Tall Dry Grass is also one block high, but aesthetically taller. It can be placed on sand, terracotta, and dirt blocks similarly to the dead bush. You can collect Short or Tall Dry Grass using shears or any tool with Silk Touch. Using bone meal on Short Dry Grass turns it into Tall Dry Grass. Sheep can eat it to regrow their wool, too.</p><p>Wildflowers are a new type of flower exclusive to birch and old growth birch forests as well as meadows. You can have up to four Wildflowers per one block, similar to other petals and flowers decorations. They can be crafted into yellow dye.</p><p>The Test and Test Instance blocks are technical blocks used in game tests, also being added to the game.</p><p>The Blue Egg is a variant of the egg which is only laid by the cold chicken variant, and spawns another cold chicken when hatched. The Brown Egg is the warm chicken's alternative.</p><figure data-align="center" data-size="large" data-img-src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464149-minecraft-next-update%282%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4464149" data-ratio="0.5625" data-width="1920" data-embed-type="image"><a href="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464149-minecraft-next-update%282%29.jpg" data-ref-id="1300-4464149"></a><figcaption>Fallen trees decorated with mushrooms</figcaption><img src="https://www.gamespot.com/a/uploads/original/1850/18507742/4464149-minecraft-next-update%282%29.jpg"></figure><h3 id="World_generation">World generation</h3><p>Also being added to the game in 1.21.5 are fallen trees. These change the way that trees can appear throughout the game. Now, you may find Oak, Spruce, Birch, or Jungle trees horizontally across the ground. The Birch version can be short or long, and all variants can be found anywhere in the game apart from the Meadow, Bamboo Jungle, River, Grove, or Flower Forest. Fallen trees can even be decorated with mushrooms or vines.</p><h3 id="Sounds">Sounds</h3><p>New sounds being added to the game include dead bush blocks playing ambient sounds when placed on top of two blocks that are any color terracotta, sand, or red sand blocks in any biome. Those three blocks also have a chance of playing ambient sounds when surrounded by one of them at least three sides eight blocks away.</p><p>That's everything coming to Minecraft in the next update. Beyond that, there will be <a href="https://www.gamespot.com/articles/minecrafts-happy-ghasts-add-new-flying-mechanic-to-game/1100-6530284/" data-ref-id="1100-6530284">Happy Ghasts</a> in the second drop of 2025, which see a new spin on a formerly dangerous mob.</p>
  
                        
    
        
        
  
                                  </div>

          
        
                        
            <span>
        <a itemprop="reviewer" href="https://plus.google.com/100905401902076465889?rel=author">Cheri Faulkner</a> on Google+
      </span>
      
                    
  
    
          
            
  <div>
    <p><i>Got a news tip or want to contact us directly? Email <a href="mailto:news@gamespot.com?subject=Hi%20GameSpot!%20I%20have%20a%20news%20tip%20for%20you!">news@gamespot.com</a></i></p>

    
      </div>
        
      </section>
    
            
    </article></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 won't have a mini map to preserve its sense of discovery, says producer]]></title>
            <link>https://www.eurogamer.net/clair-obscur-expedition-33-wont-have-a-mini-map-to-preserve-its-sense-of-discovery-says-producer</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/clair-obscur-expedition-33-wont-have-a-mini-map-to-preserve-its-sense-of-discovery-says-producer.1143357/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.eurogamer.net/clair-obscur-expedition-33-wont-have-a-mini-map-to-preserve-its-sense-of-discovery-says-producer<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
        

        <p>On Dark Souls, French authenticity, and achieving AAA results.</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Clair-Obscur_-Expedition-33-_-Release-Date-Trailer-0-35-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Sandfall Interactive</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p><a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/clair-obscur-expedition-33">Clair Obscur: Expedition 33</a> won't include a minimap for its exploration, though a compass will be added to the explorable world map for release.</p>
<p>The game's producer, and developer Sandfall Interactive COO Francois Meurisse confirmed this to me at an Xbox event during this year's Game Developers Conference (GDC), following some <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/playing-clair-obscur-expedition-33-for-three-hours-has-confirmed-all-my-hopes-and-fears-about-this-gorgeous-new-action-rpg">criticism during previews that environments were hard to navigate</a>.</p>
<p>"There won't be mini maps in the levels," said Meurisse. "When there's a mini map, you can end up relying on it. And we want players to discover the world as the expedition does it. They don't have a map because every previous expedition failed. So yes, sometimes it can be difficult to find their way."</p>
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 | Release Date Trailer" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EsElVZ0sLtU?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 | Release Date Trailer</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EsElVZ0sLtU?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EsElVZ0sLtU?autoplay=1" title="Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 | Release Date Trailer">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<figcaption>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 | Release Date Trailer<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EsElVZ0sLtU" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>He continued: "What we added on the world map that wasn't in the preview demo is just a compass, so you can find north easily and get your direction more easily." There will also be an overview map of the entire game world.</p>
<p>Since the game's first reveal, much has been made of its JRPG influences from the likes of Final Fantasy and Persona, with its turn-based battle system and stylish menus. But what particularly struck me from the preview was the influence of FromSoftware, both from Dark Souls and <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/sekiro-tips-and-tricks-6009">Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice</a>. There are obvious parallels: the sense of satisfaction from a successful parry as the camera zooms for a big slow-motion hit, as well as the weapon attribute scaling based on character stats. But it's also there in the aforementioned level design - it may be more linear, but it offers a similar sense of getting lost in an overwhelming, dangerous environment.</p>
<p>Meurisse explained the game is balanced between fairly linear, or semi-open levels with side path opportunities, which are accessed through the JRPG-style explorable world map. This is intended to tell a focused story. "The design approach has some links with FromSoftware games," he said, "where it's very linear levels but really intense ones. We don't have the mastery of ideas that they have, but it was part of the inspiration."</p>
<p>The Souls influence was definitely intentional, said Meurisse. What's more, the game's director, Guillaume Broche, is not just a big fan of FromSoftware but was also a Sekiro speedrunner. "I hope we'll have some good feedback and players from that community playing the game," said Meurisse. "I can't wait to have some players doing no damage runs, because technically it's achievable."</p>
<p>The game's turn-based battles are heavily-inspired by RPGs, but with action elements to allow players to parry and dodge enemy attacks. And rather than mana or skill points for character abilities, the system gives characters a certain number of action points to spend each turn. This was inspired by deck-building games, as Broche is also a huge Magic the Gathering player.</p>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/Clair-Obscur_-Expedition-33-_-Release-Date-Trailer-1-16-screenshot.png?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
<figcaption>Clair Obscur will have a classic-style explorable overworld map full of secrets | <span>Image credit: <cite>Sandfall Interactive</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Beyond all these influences, though, the game has a distinctly and authentic French tone, from its costume design to the inclusion of French swear words in the script - after all, the Montpellier-based team is predominantly French. While the gameplay is clearly Japanese-inspired, the team didn't want to mimic manga or anime graphics, but instead find its own unique style. "When you tell a story or imagine a world, it's usually good to start with something you're familiar with," said Meurisse, which led to the Belle Epoque and Art Deco references.</p>
<p>"The will for searching for something more unique made it natural to link with the art references we knew the best, for being French," he added," but it wasn't a specific studio guideline to say 'we are French, we want to do something French'". Still, he's "happy and proud" of the French inspiration.</p>
<p>Unlike its 60-80 hour JRPG peers, Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is smaller in scope, despite its epic feel. After all, it's being made by just 30 people. Broche had a strong vision for the game from the start, with decisions like no online mode and no open world ensuring that vision remained achievable. What's more, advancements in technology can allow indie studios to achieve outstanding results.</p>
<p>"New technology allows smaller teams to do big AA 3D hits, whereas five or 10 years ago, it wasn't really achievable," said Meurisse. He cites <a data-keyword="true" href="https://www.eurogamer.net/games/hellblade">Hellblade</a>, A Plague Tale and Mortal Shell as examples of smaller teams creating AAA-looking realistic games, but outside of these most indie studios previously had to use stylised or 2D graphics. "Now, thanks to new studios and new tools and great people, it makes a game like this very possible," he said.</p>
<p>And while the game is coming to Xbox Game Pass and was first revealed during an Xbox Partner Showcase, which Meurisse described as "the right opportunity to reach new players", he stated it's not considered an "exclusive partnership". "The most important thing for us is most people that would like to play the game, or would like to know about it, have the opportunity to play it," he said.</p>
<p>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 will release across PC, PS5, and Xbox Series X/S on 24th April.</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle comes to PS5 on 17th April]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/24/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-comes-to-ps5-on-17th-april/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-comes-to-ps5-on-17th-april.1143333/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/24/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-comes-to-ps5-on-17th-april/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>Yup, <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/11/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-in-april-leaks/">the leaks were spot on</a>: <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a> is coming to <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/playstation-5">PlayStation 5</a> on 17th April 2025. Here’s Indy actor Troy Baker and Indy-like Nathan Drake actor Nolan North to string out opening a box:</p>
<p><iframe title="PS5 Date Reveal - Indiana Jones and the Great Circle" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0VdnmreE1X0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>


<p>The game will be available physically and digitally, with a pre-order bonus being a The Last Crusade cosmetic bundle of travelling suit and lion tamer whip. It’s a first person game, and single player, so… uh… I guess you’ll get to see the whip sometimes?</p>
<p>Further to that,&nbsp; a Premium version will feature two days early access from 15th April, in addition to a Temple of Doom outfit, digital art book and an upcoming The Order of Giants DLC – the target release date for that DLC is yet to be announced.</p>
<h2>Further Reading: <a title="Indiana Jones and The Great Circle is best experienced as a serial, just like the films that inspired it" href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/16/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-best-experienced-as-a-serial-just-like-the-films-that-inspired-it/">Indiana Jones and The Great Circle is best experienced as a serial</a></h2>


<p>Earlier this year, Microsoft proudly proclaimed that <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/01/30/indiana-jones-hits-4-million-players-but-xbox-revenue-and-hardware-sales-fall/">Indiana Jones and the Great Circle has brought in over 4 million players</a> across <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-series-x">Xbox Series X|S</a>, PC and through <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/xbox-game-pass">Xbox Game Pass</a> subscribers. We never get actual sales figures for Microsoft games anymore, but this was an encouraging amount of reach, and we’ll certainly see a big bump when the game arrives on PlayStation 5.</p>
<p>It will also be fascinating to see how the game is catering to the <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/tag/ps5-pro">PS5 Pro</a> hardware, which will be significantly more powerful than the Xbox Series X. Full path tracing is likely off the table even with this spec bump – <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/09/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-launch-day-update-adds-full-ray-tracing-on-pc/">though it is supported on PC</a> – but with the recent announcement of <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/02/27/forza-horizon-5-ps5-release-date-set-for-april-22nd-launching-alongside-horizon-realms-update/">Forza Horizon 5 for PS5</a>, Playground Games is able to feature ray-traced car reflections during races and free roam, which was not possible on Series X. Some kind of visual uplift could certainly be on the cards for Indy.</p>
<p>Either way, this game should be on many a PS5-owner’s wish list. Indiana Jones and the Great Circle is a great adaptation that defies the expectations of gun-heavy Uncharted-alike in favour of something more considered and true to the films. In <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2024/12/06/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-review/">our review</a> I said, “Indiana Jones and the Great Circle forges its own, distinctive path as an archeological adventure, excellently capturing the feel of the films with its visuals and performances. There’s a fun new story here as well, wrapped around its blend of exploration, puzzles and pugilism.”</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Indiana Jones and the Great Circle PS5 Release Date Revealed]]></title>
            <link>https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-revealed.1143330/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Bethesda and MachineGames have announced the&nbsp;<em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle&nbsp;</em>PS5 release date, with the legendary adventurer's latest jaunt coming to Sony's console next month.</p>

<p>As revealed in a <a href="https://x.com/PlayStation/status/1904186452851994817" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">post</a> on the official PlayStation X account,&nbsp;<em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle&nbsp;</em>launches for PS5 on April 17th. The game is already available for PC and Xbox Series X|S.</p>

<p>We're not yet sure whether the PS5 version of <i>Great Circle&nbsp;</i>will feature any kind of DualSense haptic support, but given that the PS5 version of racer&nbsp;<em>Forza Horizon 5&nbsp;</em><a href="https://support.forzamotorsport.net/hc/en-us/articles/39144665637651-Forza-Horizon-5-on-PS5-FAQ" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">does boast</a> some nice DualSense haptics, it wouldn't be unreasonable to expect something similar from MachineGames' latest.</p>
<figure role="group"><picture><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_desktop/public/images/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-whip.jpg?itok=T4JfCgAh 1x" media="(min-width: 992px)" type="image/jpeg"><source srcset="https://techraptor.net/sites/default/files/styles/content_inline_mobile/public/images/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date-whip.jpg?itok=i8jgUm36 1x" media="(max-width: 991px)" type="image/jpeg"></picture><figcaption><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle&nbsp;</em>is coming to PS5 in April.</figcaption></figure><p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle&nbsp;</em>is the latest in a string of Xbox games to get a PlayStation release. The first three - namely&nbsp;<em>Pentiment</em>,&nbsp;<em>Grounded</em>, and&nbsp;<em>Sea of Thieves&nbsp;</em>- were announced for PlayStation <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/news/sea-of-thieves-grounded-and-pentiment-officially-announced-for-playstation-platforms" rel="nofollow">back in February last year</a>.</p>

<p>Following that, it was revealed that&nbsp;<em>Forza Horizon 5&nbsp;</em>would be coming to PlayStation, and rumors currently <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/all-xbox-exclusive-games-coming-to-playstation/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">abound</a> that the&nbsp;<em>Gears of War&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Halo&nbsp;</em>games could be about to get themselves PlayStation ports as well.</p>

<p>Just in case you're unfamiliar with&nbsp;<em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</em>, it's a first-person action-adventure game developed by&nbsp;<em>Wolfenstein: The New Order&nbsp;</em>studio MachineGames. The game casts you as (who else?) Indiana Jones, who's investigating a characteristically complex mystery involving a cat mummy.</p>

<p>As you'd expect from an&nbsp;<em>Indiana Jones&nbsp;</em>game, you'll be visiting some pretty exotic locations throughout the course of the game, including Vatican City, Thailand, and more places besides.</p>




<p>Gameplay-wise,&nbsp;<em>Great Circle&nbsp;</em>blends scrappy melee combat, stealth, and exploration, and it's spread across a series of hub levels with plenty of distractions and sidequests to pursue. If you haven't played this one yet, you're in for a treat.</p>

<p><em>Indiana Jones and the Great Circle&nbsp;</em>launches on <a href="https://www.playstation.com/en-gb/games/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PlayStation 5</a> on April 17th, and it's also currently available on <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2677660/Indiana_Jones_and_the_Great_Circle/?curator_clanid=6754604&amp;utm_source=TechRaptor" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">PC</a> and <a href="https://www.xbox.com/games/store/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle/9n8fq28z6qx3" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Xbox Series X|S</a>. You can read our Andrew's <a href="https://techraptor.net/gaming/reviews/indiana-jones-and-great-circle-review-perfect-adaptation-of-original-ip" rel="nofollow">glowing review of the game here</a>.</p>
</div><div><p><span><div>
       
    <p>Joe has been writing for TechRaptor for several years, and in those years has learned a lot about the gaming industry and its foibles. He’s originally an… <a href="https://techraptor.net/author/joseph-allen">More about Joseph</a></p>
  </div></span></p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mechs and alien spiders run amok in the grim retro warfare of Beta Decay]]></title>
            <link>https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mechs-and-alien-spiders-run-amok-in-the-grim-retro-warfare-of-beta-decay</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/mechs-and-alien-spiders-run-amok-in-the-grim-retro-warfare-of-beta-decay.1143327/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/mechs-and-alien-spiders-run-amok-in-the-grim-retro-warfare-of-beta-decay<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-component="article-header">
  

    <div id="main-content">
  

        <p>Hitting early access this year</p>

    </div>


  <p>
  <figure>
  <a href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/beta-decay-early-access-release-announced-2025-3.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank" data-lightbox="true">
  
  </a>

      <figcaption>
        <span>
Image credit:          <cite>Rotoscope Studios</cite>
        </span>
      </figcaption>
  </figure>
  </p>

    

</div><div data-component="article-content">



            <p>Open world sci-fi RPG <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/beta-decay">Beta Decay</a> is being delightfully greedy. The game's retro PS1-inspired art style hides some furious ambitions. It will be a "dystopian RPG where you can build spaceships, join factions, and fight for territory in a newly discovered star system," according to the Steam blurb. The game's <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/beta-decay-is-a-low-poly-dystopian-rpg-whose-grimy-cover-shooting-shows-promise">previous trailer</a> showed some swish (if somewhat prototypey) cover shooter combat. But the game now plans to launch into early access this year, developers Rotoscope Studios have announced. And this time they've brought the big guns, literally. Mech some time for the trailer below. </p>
<!--more-->
<figure>
<p>
<a aria-label="beta decay | Early Access Teaser" data-lightbox="false" data-platform="youtube" href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YfG9D8hJVeA?autoplay=1" onclick="((e) => { e.preventDefault(); e.currentTarget.closest('.video_wrapper').innerHTML = e.currentTarget.querySelector('template').innerHTML; enableElements(); })(event)" title="Click to play video from YouTube">
<span>beta decay | Early Access Teaser</span>
<template>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YfG9D8hJVeA?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/YfG9D8hJVeA?autoplay=1" title="beta decay | Early Access Teaser">
</iframe> </template>
</a>
</p>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YfG9D8hJVeA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Watch on YouTube</a></figure>
<p>Ah. That is some primo PlayStation 1 polygoning. There's no tight release date for this early access shooter, just a loose "2025". The open world survivalist combat is already looking more polished, a smog-smudged peek at the factional warfare the developers are promising, which will see corpo jerks and syndicate scum clash "in an endless fight for territorial control of the Alpha Centauri star system."  </p>
<p>What this looks like in practice is a lot of diving and ducking and blasting off limbs. Miniguns, sniper rifles, thermal goggles, VTOL aircrafts, weird dudes commanding legions of insectoid horrors. What's not to like? Just look at that dithering. I could run my finger across the screen and it would feel like a tea strainer. Ah, beautiful.</p>
<figure data-count="4" role="group">
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/beta-decay-early-access-release-announced-2025-6.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/beta-decay-early-access-release-announced-2025-5.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/beta-decay-early-access-release-announced-2025-4.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figure>
<a data-lightbox="true" href="https://assetsio.gnwcdn.com/beta-decay-early-access-release-announced-2025-1.jpg?width=1920&amp;height=1920&amp;fit=bounds&amp;quality=80&amp;format=jpg&amp;auto=webp" target="_blank">
 </a>
</figure>
<figcaption>Mmmm. Low-resolution textures. | <span>Image credit: <cite>Rotoscope Studios</cite></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The game also plans to include a lot of other features, going beyond the firefights we see here. There are promises of survival mechanics that require you to eat, drink, and sleep. As well as the possibility of buying and selling goods (and even stocks) in a "player-driven" economy. Not to mention the spaceship tinkering.

</p><p>"Become an engineer repairing starships, a mech pilot commanding war machines, to a syndicate leader, executing raids deep within a labyrinthic neon city," say Rotoscope. "Trade products through physical shops on the streets to digital securities on the Centauri Exchange. Build spacecraft with complex sub-systems such as power grids, server networks, and life support systems to keep your crew alive in deep space..."</p>
<p>These are big promises for what looks like a small studio. Even one of these many features would constitute an entire game's worth of work. I'm also conscious of what happened last time I <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-mommy-mechs-of-the-forever-winter-are-stomping-into-early-access-next-month">expelled litres of drool</a> over an apocalyptic mech-stomped warzone. <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/games/the-forever-winter">The Forever Winter</a> was <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winter-struggles-into-early-access-with-poor-performance-and-a-deadly-thirst-for-your-time">much jankier than I'd hoped</a> (although to be fair it is <a href="https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/the-forever-winters-water-will-no-longer-drain-away-while-youre-offline">getting reliably updated</a> as its own early access continues). But never mind that. I am the mech appreciator. I live in a rusty state of eternal hope. I'll keep you informed of Beta Decay's progress.</p>



        </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Achieving 'creative sobriety' in game design]]></title>
            <link>https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/achieving-creative-sobriety-in-game-design</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/achieving-creative-sobriety-in-game-design.1143312/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/achieving-creative-sobriety-in-game-design<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-module="content" data-testid="article-base-body-content"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">We've all heard the saying "everything has already been done once" when it comes to art and creativity. Fawzi Mesmar challenged this concept at GDC 2025, explaining that ideas can be repeated, but it's our own experiences that take a common concept and make it creatively unique.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">One of the biggest hurdles in game development is coming up with a story. Whether you are trying to figure out the motivation driving your farmer in a cozy sim or flesh out the creepy world of a horror game, we are all aiming to be unique, original, and engaging.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">An original and creative idea could be the key to a successful game. But what makes an idea original? Mesmar has some specific advice for those looking to harness creativity and get away from accidentally building a hollow repeat.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="We are what we watch">We are what we watch</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Right from the start, Mesmar pressed listeners with the question "What is creativity?" He explained that the concept of creativity is often misunderstood as just "creating something." He instead broke it down as "an idea that is unprecedented." He stated that "what we do inspires us," and it is that inspiration that creates unique ideas.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In game development we see trends as certain concepts with outsize influence on writers and designers. It is especially noticeable in newer devs, who may have set out to make a game solely because they were inspired by a specific title when they were younger.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/consume-me-wins-grand-prize-nuovo-award-at-the-2025-igf-awards" target="_self" data-discover="true">'Consume Me' Wins Grand Prize, Nuovo Award at the 2025 IGF Awards</a></p><p>Via ConcernedApe</p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Via ConcernedApe</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">In the cozy genre, for example, it is a joke that almost every farming sim that has come out in recent years has a protagonist who is "trying to escape the big city" for a more provincial, relaxing life. This is due to how many cozy players were inspired by and grew up with games like Harvest Moon and </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Stardew Valley</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">However, just including the ingredients isn't enough. As we saw in the recent release of </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sugardew Island</span></span><span data-testid="content-text">, copying what works with other games isn't necessarily creative. However, titles like </span><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fields of Mistria</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> have exploded in popularity, and have been celebrated for their creative and fresh elements. The difference between the two is how the developers injected their own personal experiences into the title.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Sugardew Island</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> has all the right ingredients for a farming sim. Players can craft, farm, raise animals, and sell their crops and products. However, it lacks any depth beyond these core mechanics, leaving players bored and unsatisfied with the gameplay loop.</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text"><span>Fields of Mistria</span></span><span data-testid="content-text"> utilizes unique, 90s-inspired illustrations and anime-like plot points for its story while injecting adorable narrative elements like a "D&amp;D" tabletop game played at the pub on Fridays. It's original, unique, and charming, even if it has similarities to other farming sims.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/how-civilization-vii-s-powerful-narrative-system-helps-players-experience-unique-parts-of-history" target="_self" data-discover="true">How Civilization VII's powerful narrative system helps players experience unique parts of history</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">The takeaway here is that a creative idea has to be more than just building a game around a selection of popular mechanics from other games. It needs depth, originality, and intention. Mesmar says that "originality is making something novel," and he has a key bit of advice for those trying to achieve this.</span></p><h2 data-testid="content-text" id="Game designers need to create with intention">Game designers need to create with intention</h2><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Mesmar explained that "to achieve creative sobriety, you need to look into yourself and understand your own experiences and constraints."</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">To do this, creatives need to look at a concept and think about how their own experiences in life could be applied to it. Instead of making a farming game where you plant crops and sell them, maybe you make a farming game where you have to teach NPCs how to help in the gardens, as you may have with a family member as a child. The game could be centered around building a thriving community garden and selling crops at a co-op or outdoor market. By diving into personal experiences, creativity blooms into original and unique concepts, even if they are based on something common and relatable.</span></p><p data-component="related-article"><span data-testid="related-article-title">Related:</span><a href="https://www.gamedeveloper.com/design/-balatro-plays-winning-hand-at-gdca-2025-receiving-game-of-the-year" target="_self" data-discover="true">'Balatro' Plays Winning Hand at GDCA 2025, Receiving Game of the Year</a></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Additionally, Mesmar says that "original ideas need to have value." You could have a core memory of petting your childhood cat, but does this experience have value? If you made a cat petting game, how would it connect or provide something to a player? If you have a core memory of petting your cat and you turn it into a hyper-realistic pet-groomer simulator or a platformer where the goal is to reach cats and pet them for points, now we are talking about originality. Who wouldn't want to fight baddies to collect cat pets like reward tokens?</span></p><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Creative Sobriety is about being intentional and thoughtful about the ideas we develop. Mesmar encourages those trying to harness their creativity to pause, think, and meditate on the why behind their ideas. By taking the time to consider how a concept connects with you and how it could be used to reach others, you will have the ability to craft truly unique and interesting stories.</span></p></div><div><h2>About the Author</h2><div data-component="contributor-summary"><p data-testid="content-paragraph"><span data-testid="content-text">Laura Gray, known as Ezra when not putting pen to paper, is a D&amp;D enthusiast with a love of all things written. They are a collector of fantasy and sci-fi novels, a lover of cooking weird food, and a player of farming sims and Pokémon games. When not engrossed in a re-read of Anne McCaffrey or a deep dive into the Adventure Zone: Balance, they can be found sniffing the cats and napping in half-finished crochet projects.</span></p></div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Practice makes perfects in Forestrike’s martial arts brawler]]></title>
            <link>https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/24/practice-makes-perfects-in-forestrikes-martial-arts-brawler/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/practice-makes-perfects-in-forestrike%E2%80%99s-martial-arts-brawler.1143297/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2025/03/24/practice-makes-perfects-in-forestrikes-martial-arts-brawler/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
	
		<p>The Empire is under threat from within, and only the Order of Foresight has a chance to save it. The latest game from <a href="https://www.thesixthaxis.com/2021/01/28/olija-review/">Olija</a> developer Skeleton Crew, Forestrike is a martial arts brawler where you can see the future… kind of. Coming to Switch and PC later this year, <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2325930/Forestrike_Demo/">a demo is now available on Steam</a> to try and we’ve been hands on.</p>
<p><iframe title="Forestrike | Leaf School Combat Overview | Play the First Demo on Steam" width="780" height="439" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DQvhBv8kTlc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>You see, the power of Foresight is bestowed upon a select few, including our apprentice protagonist, Yu. When faced with a clutch of bad dudes that need defeating, Yu can only take a couple hits, but can enter into Foresight and unpick the chain of events that’s going to occur and how to turn it around in his favour. It’s a bit like he’s borrowed Doctor Strange’s time stone to have a peep at all the possibilities.</p>


<p>Foresight is basically a trial run, a practice arena where you can figure out the attacks coming your way and how to use your limited dodge, pickups and standard light and heavy attacks to defeat them. You’ll see what enemies emerge to surround you, and then learn to pick them apart one-by-one until you stand victorious.</p>


<p>If an enemy comes charging at Yu, he can engage a dodge mode that will pass that charing enemy straight through you and see them barrel into someone stood on the other side, dealing damage to both. Similarly, an enemy that is able to dodge can be tricked into using that either by a bullrushing enemy you’ve evaded or by triggering them with an attack for your own, opening themselves up for attack immediately after.</p>
<p>It’s essentially an action puzzle game where you need to try and figure out a path through and then execute your plan. Get it wrong and you’ll lose health pips or even die, sending you right back to the start of the game’s roguelite form.</p>
<p>The demo does a good job of slowly introducing you to these concepts before letting you go on a run and see the roguelite structure. Working your way from the countryside, through the mountains, the city and into the inner court of the Emperor, you’ll have a choice of levels to take on, many of which come with rewards and fresh abilities.</p>

<p>For example, one could make your light attacks spin enemies around, potentially disorient them to then turn and attack their allies. Or you could gain health from instances of friendly fire amongst them, or cancel out and steal their weapons. Levels that reward you with a new abilities present you with three to choose from, but others can also upgrade abilities – that turn-about ability can then stun enemies, if upgraded. There’s also a shop to spend coins – if not using those to open up a further path.</p>
<p>It comes to a head when facing a boss. Larger health bars, quickly recharging dodge abilities, and some audacious attacks – Master Ogai in the demo can tumble into one of his allies and just fling them at you – makes them a real task to figure out, come up with a plan and then pull it off. It’s not something that I managed in my exploratory run, despite well over a dozen efforts in Foresight.</p>

<p>The demo has one of Yu’s potential mentors, the old Master Talgun who pops up in your Foresight like a Jedi ghost and gives a little guidance. He rejects violence typically, but even he pushes for an attack-first principle in certain situations. He’s just one of a handful of masters that you’ll be able to choose from at the start of a run, each of which has a different school of combat, which you can master and ultimately combine.</p>
<p>For now, the demo provides a tasty morsel of the action that Forestrike will offer when it launches later this year. Unpicking the combat puzzles is sure to prove delectable to a particular cachet of players, ramping up to those ‘real’ battles where you have only one shot to pull off what you’ve been practicing, and leading to some gloriously slick combat sequences that would fit right into a martial arts movie.</p>


<!-- CONTENT END 1 -->

		
	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2, PlayStation 5 Will Get a Lot More Xbox Games in 2025]]></title>
            <link>https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-playstation-5-more-xbox-games/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/nintendo-switch-2-playstation-5-will-get-a-lot-more-xbox-games-in-2025.1143294/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://wccftech.com/nintendo-switch-2-playstation-5-more-xbox-games/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			

			
			
			
			<p>Multiple Xbox games will hit the Nintendo Switch 2 and PlayStation 5 consoles this year besides those that have already been announced, according to a new report shared online today.</p>
<p>Commenting on the release date announcement for the <a href="https://wccftech.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-is-out-on-april-17-for-ps5/">PlayStation 5 version of Indiana Jones and the Great Circle</a>, The Verge's Tom Warren <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/610817/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-ps5-release-date">stated</a> that 2025 will include a lot more titles appearing on PlayStation 5 and the next-generation Nintendo console. Which former Xbox console exclusives will make the jump has yet to be seen, but it wouldn't be surprising to see any of these games make an appearance during the Nintendo Switch 2 Direct scheduled for next week.</p>
<p>While Microsoft has yet to reveal which games will hit rival formats next, there's a very good chance that Starfield will be among the next to release at least on PlayStation 5. <a href="https://wccftech.com/starfield-playstation-5-release-imminent/">Earlier this month</a>, the console's logo appeared on Creation listings, suggesting that the game's announcement and release could be imminent.</p>
<p>The next entry in the Fable series could be a <a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-starfield-playstation-5-nintendo-switch-2/">multiplatform release</a> right from launch, as work on other console versions of the game has reportedly already begun. With the game having been <a href="https://wccftech.com/fable-delayed-2026-stunning-gameplay/">delayed</a> to 2026, a multiplatform launch has become even more likely, although it remains to be seen how the Nintendo Switch 2 will be able to handle the game, given its lower specs compared to the other current-generation systems.</p>

			
		</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marvel Rivals Esports is Already Building Strong Rivalries and Solid Viewership]]></title>
            <link>https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-esports-is-already-building-strong-rivalries-and-solid-viewership/</link>
            <guid>https://www.resetera.com/threads/marvel-rivals-esports-is-already-building-strong-rivalries-and-solid-viewership.1143285/</guid>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[https://insider-gaming.com/marvel-rivals-esports-is-already-building-strong-rivalries-and-solid-viewership/<br/><br/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>The Marvel Rivals esports scene is still in its very early days, but the early results have been very positive. The fledgling scene is attracting numerous organizations, strong viewership numbers (thanks to co-streaming), and some exciting rivalries.</p>



<p>The first competitive tournaments have featured plenty of highlights and trash talking, and there’s nowhere to go but up for Marvel Rivals esports.</p>



<h2 id="h-marvel-rivals-esports-is-heating-up-quickly">Marvel Rivals Esports is Heating Up Quickly</h2>



<p>After a month of action across the world, the Marvel Rivals Invitational series has ended, crowning five champions across each of the main regions. Arguably the most interest in Marvel Rivals esports has been in North America, which has attracted the most viewership and the most interest from established organizations.</p>



<p>Excluding the streamer-focused events like Creator Cup and Twitch Rivals, the Marvel Rivals event with the highest viewership peak was the NA Invitational that just concluded yesterday. The event <a href="https://escharts.com/tournaments/mr/marvel-rivals-invitational-north-america-2" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reached 71,099 concurrent viewers at its peak</a>, according to Esports Charts. This number was aided by co-streamers like Shroud, who has become so interested in Marvel Rivals that he <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/shroud-marvel-rivals-esports-roster-reveal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">founded a team that competed in the event: Shroud-X</a>. But the event included a trove of larger organizations with dedicated fanbases: Sentinels, Envy, FlyQuest, and 100 Thieves.</p>



<p>100 Thieves have been dominating the competition in North America. Since the squad formerly known as Mutants signed with Nadeshot’s brand, they haven’t lost a single match, thanks in part to <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/one-of-marvel-rivals-best-pro-tank-players-plays-on-controller/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">one of the few Vanguard players playing (and winning) on controller</a>. The rivalry between Sentinels and 100 Thieves in VALORANT has carried over to Marvel Rivals, complete with the<a href="https://x.com/MRivalsEsports/status/1903651194196676821" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> expected amount of social media back-and-forth</a>. The trash talk is at the perfect level: not too far to be deemed personal or inappropriate, but above the basic level of normal banter.</p>



<p>There’s still plenty of room for Marvel Rivals to grow, but NetEase has committed to investing in the game itself for “10 years and beyond.” And with seasonal tournaments baked into the game’s competitive mode itself, that implies that esports will be a priority for years to come.</p>



<p>What do you make of Marvel Rivals’ aspirations in esports? Let us know in the comments or on our&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/forum/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">community forum</a>!</p>



<hr>



<p>For more information from Insider Gaming, read about <a href="https://insider-gaming.com/indiana-jones-and-the-great-circle-releases-on-ps5-next-month/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Indiana Jones and The Great Circle’s PS5 announcement</a>. Don’t forget to&nbsp;<a href="https://insider-gaming.com/subscribe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up for our weekly newsletter</a>.&nbsp;</p>
    <div id="ig-newsletter-holder">
            <p><span>
                    SUBSCRIBE to our newsletter to receive the latest news and exclusive leaks every week! No Spam.
                </span>
            </p>
            
        </div>

	</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>